i would suggest we move on to the
um to the next talk on the schedule
and um that would be james talking about
identifying valuable pointers in in heap
data
can you try sharing your screen awesome
all right okay can everyone's
in full screen looks good please take
advantage oh it's gone
oh it's going oh it's back okay great um
okay
cool fingers crossed so hi everyone uh
my name is james roney and the title of
my talk today is identifying valuable
pointers in heap data
this work was done by myself troy pritik
and pratik
with the fantastic guidance and advice
of professor james mikkens
okay so i'm going to start with a high
level overview of my talk
so this talk is broadly concerned with
data oriented attacks
which are simply software exploits that
respect the control flow integrity of a
victim program
and the particular data oriented attack
that we'll be concerned with today is
called memory cartography
and so in a memory cartography attack an
attacker builds up a map of pointers
that connect
different regions of memory keeps stacks
and static data sections
and so with the setup if an attacker has
a read vulnerability in one of these
memory regions
they can sort of follow this network of
pointers between regions to leak data
from the program's entire address space
without triggering a segmentation fault
and this is really useful however for
this technique to work
these pointers need to be located at
constant offsets within each memory
region so the attacker knows where to
find them at attack time
and this can pose a problem since
regions like heaps and stacks often have
non-deterministic layouts
in this paper we'll show how an attacker
can recognize pointers to specific
destinations by looking for
particular signatures in memory and this
is going to allow for memory cartography
approaches to work
even in non-deterministic memory regions
okay so with that uh here are the main
sections of the talk
and we'll begin by discussing data
oriented attacks in more detail
um okay so a lot of classic attacks
involve using a memory bug to subvert
the control flow of a victim program
so for example here we have the control
flow graph of a simple program
that's going to authenticate a user over
a network by reading a packet containing
a password
and so in a classic buffer overflow
attack a malicious actor might use this
password buffer here
to overwrite a return address and open a
shell
and so this attack is going to involve a
jump that isn't present in the normal
control flow graph as you can see from
this extra edge here
and while that's great what's going to
end up happening is this control flow
violation is going to make this attack a
lot more difficult when modern
mitigations are present
for example safeguards like stat
canaries are going to detect this kind
of control flow violation and stop it
from happening
um so in contrast in a data oriented
attack
uh instead of overwriting a return
address the attacker can use this
vulnerable buffer to instead overwrite
this authentication flag
and so this isn't going to violate the
legitimate control flow graph of the
program in any way
so it won't trigger a lot of those same
modern defenses however it's still going
to let the attacker manipulate the
behavior of the program
in this case by sort of pretending to be
authenticated despite
never having provided a valid password
okay um so with that simple example we
can move on and talk about a particular
data-oriented attack called memory
cartography
um so memory cartography was first
reduced by rogowski and collaborators a
few years ago
and the basic setup is that an attacker
has a vulnerability that lets them read
arbitrary bytes from some region of
memory
and they want to read from the entire
address space of the victim program
without triggering a
segmentation fault and this is a hard
problem because the address space of a
complicated program is going to be
fragmented into a bunch of different
allocations
with unallocated areas in between so
even if the attacker has an
arbitrary read vulnerability they have
to be careful not to read from
unallocated areas and crash the entire
program
uh so this attack is designed to work
with modern control when modern control
flow guards like aslr
data execution prevention etc are
enabled
and crucially these memory cartography
attacks are going to depend on the
attacker being able to run the victim
program locally
so for instance knows they're exploding
firefox and they can do some
local analysis of moving to the attack
time
exploit um so to get a better idea of
how memory cryptography works
we'll consider a simple example
involving a web browser
so browser has a bunch of different
memory regions pertaining to things like
javascript engines html parsers and sort
of the renderer code and data itself
and in a realistic scenario an attacker
might be able to read arbitrary
addresses by specifying an offset from
some vulnerable
object within the javascript engine heap
however the attacker might want to steal
cookies from this dom renderer heap
which is in a different memory region
and so the attacker can't simply just
keep scanning the
the address space until they find a
cookie because eventually they're going
to sort of
go outside of one of these allocated
regions and trigger a segmentation fault
so the attacker is going to have to
figure out a way around this somehow
in a memory cartography attack the
attacker is going to solve this problem
by building a map of pointers between
different memory regions and so to build
this map of pointers the attacker is
going to run the binary locally
and scan the static data sections for
pointers that connect different regions
and so the memory scan locally can be
done using a tool like gdb or something
like that
and so each pointer that the attacker is
going to find
is basically just um a reference in one
of these memory regions it's going to
connect to a different memory region so
each pointer connects
an offset in a source region with an
offset and a destination region
and so when the attacker does this
locally they're going to look
specifically at static data sections
and the reason static data sections are
going to be the focus of this attack
is because um static data sections are
going to have a deterministic layout
so if the attacker sees a pointer
linking offset 64 in this javascript
section
with offset 32 in this html section uh
they can become
that pointer is going to be they're
linking those sets every time
including when they move to the attack
time um and the reason that that's going
to happen is because like i said
static data sections have this
deterministic layout
preserves relative offsets between
pointers even if the global offsets of
each section are changing between loads
however there's still one more problem
which is that some of these pointers
might simply be pointer sized regions
that happen to look like pointers to
external memory regions
for example a static data section might
contain a constant string
and that string for some aslr loads of
the program happens to look like a
pointer
somewhere else so to filter out those
false pointers the attacker can just
repeat this procedure from multiple
independent program loads
and look for links that are consistently
present so if
over multiple program loads we still see
this pointer connecting offset 64 in the
java section in the javascript data
section
and offset 32 in the html data section
we can be confident that's a real
pointer and it's going to be there at
attack time
so by doing this we can filter out the
bad pointers
and we're left with a reliable map of
pointers connecting different data
sections
and this results in the ability to
navigate through those data sections and
eventually reach a target heap which in
this case is this dom render
heap now this last pointer in the chain
might end up at a non-deterministic
offset within that heap because the
heaps don't have a fixed memory layout
and that's okay because the attacker can
just sort of scan the neighborhood
around that final pointer
until they find something sensitive like
a cookie
so this is all well and good uh however
one thing that we haven't talked about
is how we actually get to this java
section
javascript data section to begin with or
any uh or one of these other data
sections
and basically because our vulnerable
object is in the heap we somehow need to
find a way to
jump from the heap to this first data
section
and that's a not a trivial problem
because offsets of pointers within the
javascript heap are not going to be
consistent across runs because the heap
is subject to all sorts of
non-determinism
so the original memory cartography paper
of rogowski
they accomplished this by doing a heap
spray of easily recognizable objects
that contained a
known data section pointer so they could
simply read bites off the heap and look
for one of these recognizable objects
find a pointer follow it and end up in a
known offset in a data section and from
there they could continue doing the
memory cartography
however this approach might not be
viable for all applications where the
attacker can't
control what objects are being allocated
on the heap
so that's going to bring us to our
original contribution which is a method
to discover pointers to data sections
within non-deterministic memory regions
like heaps
and this is going to allow for these
types of memory cartography attacks to
work
without any sort of heap spray or
manipulation of the heap
okay so to get a bit more formal we're
going to consider a scenario where the
attacker has a local heat preed and
wants to return the entire address space
however unlike the original memory
photography setup this attacker has no
influence over the contents of the heap
so to find a pointer to another region
the attacker is going to have to scan
the heap at attack time and
recognize the pointer somehow and like
in the original setup we're going to
assume that modern control flow guards
like aslr are enabled
and that the attacker is going to be
able to run the program locally
so here's a high level overview of the
method that we're proposing
so first the attacker is going to run
the look program locally several times
and identify specific destinations
within data sections that are
pointed too often by pointers on the
heat
then they're going to look at the
pointers that reference those frequently
referenced destinations
and look at the bytes surrounding those
pointers of interest and use them to
compile a signature
then the attack time the attacker is
going to scan the heap using their local
heap read
and match bytes to the pre-compiled
signature from offline analysis
and when they get an aligned series of
bytes in a pointer size region that
match that signature
they know that they found a pointer to
that specific offset within that
specific data section and they can then
follow that pointer
to a known location and data section and
perform further memory cartography as
normal because the offsets from the data
sections are going to be deterministic
so let's get into this in a little bit
more detail so first the attacker is
going to run the program locally several
times and determine the boundaries of
the allocated regions
on linux you can determine these
boundaries by looking at the prop maps
file
um so in this example the attacker is
running the the exploit twice
they've identified this heap region and
the slim c region
and the bounds are going to change
between runs because of aslr but that's
okay because they can still
you know use proc maps to figure out
exactly what regions they're looking at
and this is a simple example but note
that in some more complicated examples
the heap that the attacker is going to
be interested in might actually be
multiple vmas
for instance if the the program is using
an map based allocator like je malin
okay um so the attacker after figuring
out the bounds of the heap
is then gonna scan that heap looking for
pointers to other regions
so basically they're gonna run over all
the memory in these heap regions
and look for things that look like
pointers so addresses that reside
in another external memory region in
this case loop c
so they're going to try to find the most
frequent destinations for pointers on
the heap
so in this case the most frequent
destination is this uh
this highlighted blue region on in lipsy
and the pointers with the green check
mark reference that uh most frequent
destination
and the most frequent destination is is
computed as the destinations that are
referenced frequently
across all of the heap from oh across
all of the runs so you see that in both
of these runs we've got lots of pointers
pointing to this particular offset
within blip c
um so those green checkmark pointers are
really pointers of interest that we want
to dig deeper and analyze
so uh the attacker next is going to look
at all those pointers to the frequent
destination
um so that means looking at all the
pointers with the green check marks from
run one and round two and sort of
looking at the bytes that surround them
and so basically you can expand these
pointers and look at the bytes that are
surrounding them we have the bytes that
proceed the pointer the byte to the
pointer itself and the bytes that trail
the pointer
and these are going to change for all
sorts of reasons the bytes of the
pointer itself are going to be changing
due to aslr
and they're going to take all of those
sort of windows of bytes around the
region around the pointers of interest
and compile them and use them to build a
filter
and so a filter is simply a sequence of
lower bounds and upper bounds on each
byte
in that window surrounding the pointers
of interest and the filter bound to
determine by just taking the highest and
lowest byte value observed in each
position during those local program runs
so for instance this position in run one
has a really low value
so that's going to become a lower bound
of the eventual filter
this position in run two has a very high
value so that's going to become an upper
bound in the filter
so a really simple filter algorithm for
constructing this filter
and then they're going to take that
filter and use it to do an attack time
memory scan
and so that's going to work like this so
basically the attacker is going to take
the pre-compiled filter and then start
leaking data off the heap using that
that local read vulnerability and then
they're going to match up
a aligned segments of memory with that
filter
and they're going to keep doing that
until they find
a sort of sequence of bytes from the
heap that fall in between the bounds
computed by the the precompiled filter
and basically that's going to mean that
uh in the middle there
we think we have a pointer to that known
destination with the libsy
so the attacker can then take that that
pointer follow it and end up somewhere
end up at a known location in the data
section and from there they can do
memory cryptography
and so now i'll talk about a series of
experiments where we tested this method
on a number of real world programs
okay so the general our general
methodology
was to run the program 10 times and dump
memory each time
and so we use the first nine program
runs to compute the filters as i just
described
we computed filters for the four most
frequent pointer destinations that we
saw
just to so we could benchmark more
pointers instead of just the most
frequent
um and then we used the holdout run to
test the accuracy of the filter
um and we basically just did standard
10-fold cross-validation so we held out
each run one by one
and so here a couple of basically so to
test the performance of the filter we
just
ran it over um basically all aligned
pointer size regions in the heap that we
dumped from the held out run
and so this is basically simulating that
local read vulnerability
um and so future work should uh use this
method
with an actual read exploit to um sort
of
uh create an end-to-end attack but uh in
this case we're just sort of
assuming that that read is there and
simulating it by dumping the heat
uh and so the important performance
measures we're going to talk about are
precision
which is basically the true filter
matches over
all of the filter matches and that's
representative of the probability that
the attacker is going to succeed
recognize a pointer to the correct
destination and get to the destination
they're expecting
and then we have recall which is um the
true filter matches divided by all the
true pointers scanned
uh this doesn't as directly correspond
to a success probability but it's still
you'd want it to be one so that all of
the uh
all of the true pointer all of the true
pointers to that destination that you're
scanning
you're going to recognize okay um so the
first program we tested on was vim and
we chose that because it's
single threaded and it has a single
well-defined heap region so it made it a
good early testbed
and we found that for the pointers to
the most frequent destinations in held
out runs we could identify those
pointers on the heap with extremely high
precision so for these first two we got
over 99 precision
which means that an attacker if an
attacker were trying to do this they
were going in with the pre-compiled
filter and looking for pointers to
specific destinations
they would be able to do that with very
high accuracy
next we looked at firefox and so for
firefox
firefox is a bit more complicated of a
memory allocation scheme than vim
so it uses je malek so it has lots of
different vmas
in its heap and so we resolved that by
just looking at all of the je malek
chunks that were the right size for the
javascript heap
and treating those their aggregate
contents as the effective program heap
and once again we found that um that for
the most frequent
pointers which referenced this libxul
library
we could we could identify them with
extremely high precision uh
in held out runs and then as sort of a
lower bound as our performance we also
looked at the precision in the worst
heap chunk which basically is like a
worst case performance bound
if the attacker were limited to reading
from a single randomly chosen sort of
chunk of the heap
and we saw that even in that case with
the most frequent pointers we could
still identify
them with very high precision and
finally we experimented on apache
which is a server side program uh and we
used openssl
1.0.1 which is vulnerable to harpley to
increase the realism of the attack so
we're reading from data that
was vulnerable to an actual read
vulnerability and once again we saw that
we could identify pointers with
extremely high precision
so the take-home point from our
experiments is that in all the programs
we tested we were able to identify
pointers to static data sections with a
very high precision furthermore the data
sections that we were able to reach
had a lot of connectivity with the rest
of the address space
which makes them ideal starting points
for real memory cartography attacks
and so this means that powerful memory
cartography attacks are possible even
when the attacker doesn't
have control of the heap layout and
can't do something like a heap spray
so finally some conclusions so basically
what i just said a
simple signature matching algorithm is
going to facilitate a powerful memory
cartography attacks even when the
attacker doesn't have control over heap
contents
so this hopefully expands the range of
programs that are vulnerable to
memory cryptography attacks and really
underscores the importance of having
separate address spaces for content from
like mutually distrusting origins
and there are some caveats to our work
um first like in the original memory
cartography of paper this is going to
assume that inner region pointers are
located at the same offsets on the local
machine versus the victim machine
this is sort of a stability assumption
that's essential for making sure that
that mapping approach is going to work
and also for our new approach time and
bandwidth constraints
might uh limit the attacker's ability to
scan the entire heap and find the right
pointers
and so we can assess how big of a
problem that is by uh
sort of building end-to-end exploits
with um with
sort of real read vulnerabilities which
we hope to do in future work
and uh that's my talk thank you
awesome that was a super cool talk thank
you very much james
um we do have a couple of questions here
um let me start by paraphrasing roland's
question because i had a similar one
um so so what are your your underlying
assumptions here
the the heat may not be continuous so if
you just scan the heap
end to end there may be crashes and
illegal memory accesses how do you make
sure that you only access
valid sections do you read proc self
maps or what's happening here
so um in the inline attack basically
your right hand the heat might not be
contiguous
um so the uh basically however
in most cases we're going to have uh the
attacker can sort of just read nearby
data and will almost certainly encounter
sort of a match to this filter before
running off the edge of the heap
um so that means that like in a jib drop
style
um i guess sort of uh like basically
the attacker will simply begin by
scanning bytes off the heap um and
eventually
uh and waiting until sort of they get a
match to this filter and
in almost all cases it's like there's
there's generally
the pointers that we're fingerprinting
have are occur very frequently
so the attacker's going to probably
encounter one before they run off the
heap and trigger segmentation fall
cool um roland if this did not answer
your question please follow up
um i had another another thought that um
like what i wondered regarding the
entropy to differentiate
different uh different targets did you
measure that
um how many pointers at most can you
differentiate what are the limitations
and so on
and also that's interesting um so
basically our approach was to sort of
focus on one pointer at one at a time so
the attacker since the attacker can
basically do the whole thing offline uh
given given stability assumptions they
could basically
um try a bunch of pointers they could
even do this whole
level and out thing and figure out which
one has the most satisfactory
performance and apply that
um we if you're trying to differentiate
between multiple pointers at a time
we haven't particularly looked at that
yet although given that
we have um we can get high precision uh
with all of the pointers individually it
gives me confidence that we might be
able to do it
differentiating between multiple
pointers at one time so future work
yeah cool thanks very nice work thank
you very much for the presentation
um there's a couple more questions in
the chat maybe you can follow up on
those
for sure