action
up
hi to my name is that Richard Smith I
read it heater site called
your bites man modest see her second
talk from
data talk yesterday a tracking criminals
on the Internet %uh
today's can be a little bit different
it's more gas track of Matthew wells and
it's beginning to
as a surprise publications gadgets as
wells
policies okay this is a
area I miss Holly for possible
more than a year half I'll which he got
into
are looking at stake face threatened
software
when reading the news stories about
forgot call this new purple
here %uh the Super Bowl was not this
year's
previous years Florida on had a this
recognition said
so that each person with turnstiles and
by
a certain missions it was a database
for about 3,000 people that area
explained
various kinds criminal warrants and said
they were
is the superbowl ads today
place around us criminals up shelters
convenient place to do this
it well they claim they match
got 19 matches but no arrests old the
company said it work
but the met was people's
calculations other I just I was arrested
%uh
anyway the the system was put in though
with the idea of
you know us us keeping us safe from the
terrorist was
forces camera even on the
the company decided the issue a press
release that this had happened
and sir created a the controversy more
than that probably expected
on it actually got a big brother war
from Privacy International Church
actually gave a nomination up
after that a after that system
others the next big controversy with a
scanning was
up again in Tampa in Tampa area where
the local police again won it around a
little
the usual suspects and today
face Kane system and you foresee which
is really entertaining area other
Tampa so the nightclub and restaurant
erasers
share and the same idea was to
to quell the the law the regular
closed-circuit TV systems
Witcher throughout their neighborhood a
equipped with face recognition so that
they can find the local criminals
and against us a convenience to bleach
it just makes it easier to spot people
and they have a in that particular
system a licensed
put up author 30,000 people the database
although only have a few thousand so far
I actually spoke to the
a the plea to the head the guy
Tampa Police farms editors project in
given the right at home
who's in their hands kinda interesting
it was you know people who wanna
askin ASEAN outstanding criminal
warrants
no sex offenders and on
just general bad people have been
arrested before for
you know pickpocket whenever they they
thought might hang out there
%uh money-losing things is they could
arrest the
people were wanting now sending rest
towards someone as a sexual offender
registry wasn't supposed to be in the
neighborhood
they weren't allowed to rest all the
haters much in same bed with the long
because it has jurisdiction over these
peoples assertive
the system's hazard also is up
interesting policy
decisions with them are however
face creating a face recognition %uh
software became
a really hot item after September 11 and
it's an interesting study in commerce
why that on this basically here the
nazis two companies for
with the big players in the face
recognition software business
one is the saws in Europe in the Boston
area around
brothers and the other company years
this highlights which
households again it's are and their they
have offices in
actually overtures insidious loss couple
other places around the country
and basically what happened is that
both look up the song of business
opportunity after
after nine 911 to of security services
for airports
and so they came up with this idea love
using face recognition systems affecting
every airport with them
to look for the the bad terrorist and
I but became skeptical skeptic on this a
lot of different loves a lot I hope to
do today
is certain parts that skepticism here
la know what I see is a problem with the
system's
and is very interesting you know they're
very for a high taking products in the
sense that they take video images
an attempt to match a features on
people's faces
work with databases lottery Anderson
technology
on but there's also a lot of very
interesting real-world problems alone
must deal with points on the system's
and consider you know how they can
really be use
and I'll its Anderson said he also how I
and that in times as River
troubles here terrorism companies are
for taking
mangers situation making pitches on
these problems
on
water for 20 a for some uses for the
pace kansas's airport one is
the one that's getting all across the
one that's making like you know peter
jennings easing news and so on is
is spotting suspected terror tears in
the terms
themselves so the basic idea is you have
you take your your CC haiti needs to
work other
a video camera she set up any other
databases
known terrorist thing looking for them
at the airport and
the idea she has bottomed here
warranties he see Selena database
officially confirmed by a person in this
by Donna was really one of those
terrorists
he got tackled in the term sleaze here
on
nothing can be done here's the thing:
talk about is in some background checks
and money
before going on the airplane other juror
they
they a again the same thing spot in
tears for the ones russia trying to get
on the airplanes
%uh work additional applications for
face getting the access controls
to restricted areas you today at the
airport you know we're all familiar with
the swipe cards at the the place isn't
here
for were sometimes he had to leave you
may be in for advance the fingerprint
system
which lost his face came to that so
that's a reversing database has the good
guys
here you looking for them and
another another one is background checks
for new hires
at airports now you know
no hi Jeff Turnbull work the air force's
la concerned about
employees at airports they have access
to live
luck with them in the airlines and
needed do background checks on says
minimum
other governments forcing all airports
to
rock singer chest people but interface K
yes and Davis bad people atop
10 questions is what has has a face
gaming system work
it's it's actually pretty
straightforward which is better in too
much trouble
understanding the basic idea up but
you really have to to basic him to basic
components as you have a video camera
you have a computer with the video video
Bergeron converse digitizes Korea
digital camera begin
so basically have a a
the video camera setup some location
they can get good shots
people's faces you know pointing in the
right the right level for
a shot and that goes into is fed into
the computer
converted little street us official
into it digital format and then on
what the face scanning software does is
it looks for the odds
interest first spot this face uses
algorithms for looking with the bases
then within that us where it looks for
the two oz
he says her me one then on
it recognize other features on the face
who knows
where your mouth is cheats and so on and
that takes various measures
a and from this it creates additional 10
which is a certain card along number
which represents who you are
%ah euthanasia take pictures and get a
little bit different numbers were there
but
four people up you tended end up with
the same traditional
him but all the time then the second
component
issue have a database a pitchers and
photos that she's somehow taken as a
mother
preview point time in the house out with
takes a template the G just measured
picture taken any matching
each person day
come up with a list teachers it seem to
be close to that to that person and if
you have a
looking for the bad guys it sounds the
alarm in says we meet a bad guy
here if you get a good guide system you
know where you're letting access into
Sayeed enclosed area it unlocks the door
yes it can kill you direction the whole
ideas lar
he get closer match yes
yeah well I will I will talk about that
as a whistle
propitious here that these guys thought
about those like up
is one of the problems doings I
so but that we have this concept though
the alarm in the alarm for me to be a
little warmer than
depending trying to build on
now into the matching system and I'm
actually played around with the busy on
its face it software
and you know each of a package works a
little differently but this is the year
the same idea
across the different vendors up if we
have two photos with him when he met
measure we have achieved helpless more
taken all these measurements
and
gotta writing templates her body this
particular maybe
80 bytes up but what we do is we have
algorithm that matches two templates
together then rates
the match on a scale from 0 to 10 40
means no match whatsoever
in 10 identical match and
I we then have a a
threshold value where we say if the
matching value
is greater than or equal to the
threshold then we probably
this picture these two pitchers
represent the same person and in the
case if that is the onyx ever
default values 8.5 I
however you can adjust that you can just
add value one way or the other
you have a quick question your session
start of this but I don't remember this
I'll a good deal on water fans here crap
show news TV program up front end her
show
few weeks back here whistles take a
where these face recognition system
you see the show where they had this the
hack this is the hacker guy
his stocking the the woman with with
video cameras and
yeah but it was a it yes it is really
appropriate for the site is a hacker guy
was thought in Islam and
in her apartment video cameras and
up they the cops discovered the cameras
that dinner who put him in there anyway
trace all that get a website
is observing journalists to on but s
ironic
moment is the way that they caught him I
was using a face recognition system
and so certain you know they're Hughes
video taken by me haha the video video
system
and in the in the in the show they did a
pretty good job on the face recognition
part because he said
oh yeah we crave the thing down really
loves hola
so the end up having to false positives
for state they gradually guys who was in
the guide
third internet Matthew person other
shows you know
and they said right on the show he said
that personal down really love just to
make sure we
catch I
so you know there's little bit of our if
you will
choosing a right threshold values he
said too high
you'll miss the bad guys or if you're
building a good guy system you all a
good guy
you know in through the door naturally
bad you know if you got me trying to a
job make it through the door to
get to the place that's bad I also but
you know if he had a bad guy sitting
that citizens and their catch people I
he said it to love you get a reverse
problem
which is a system cries wolf and and it
will
say to people with the same person that
really not that's that what happened
there
on a lot more they had two people today
name is identified yeah
on
I'm sorry has largely here use the
microphone
clue please when you have a question go
to the Mikes
news well I guess some system flightless
some systems have that but
yeah
I rushed my mother systems I know the
only
don't have the cash yeah hazardous
there's watching a video signal a time
trying to grab grab the pictures
yeah I but that's another
will get into summer this summer the the
problems here making this all work
so a if he said the threshold to lull
will will finger innocent people or a
lot the is
the wrong guys to the door for the gas
system and everything everything is just
right
and then we a up we got a system or
subprime world
Roseland right people and the trial is
this really have a possible come up with
just right value so we end up trying
sir balance out between two line
to load hitting on application on
now playing around with the other face
and software
I'll I found that the matching
algorithms are very sensitive
and you you have to have a really good
images
for the system to work I so
some other things that would affect a
the ability to match what one is
lighting
the had to have good lighting went when
you're taking a picture
I also the background one like a clean
background and the other a
objects in the background the mess
things up which is so strange physically
10 spots in the face the sorts of
problems a
face opposition expression matter
you know so that as I smiler or
turn my head that would affect the
operatives I
even is wearing wear glasses or
sunglasses sunglasses a particular
really bad basically
with the busy on a system you cannot
wear sunglasses
sleepy it's all presentation on this is
Naveen Saini
have to take certain classes of now
airport even tell people
you know you're gonna have to do that
whenevers the cameras around
as you're doing something else lives a
life anymore City
maybe have a luxury I yasser camera
position yes we already mentioned that
weathers suffered and whatever so
there's a lot of there's a lot of
factors ago in here
when you set up a face recognition
system you basically have to control the
environment where the cameras
on and this is a this is very poor
this is very important for this to work
is can't for camera many places hope it
works
on I wanna go over here now
system actually I'll some other tests
that Iran here just give you some ideas
here
a this is a
these are various pictures that I took
my head like a little database in bed
guess this is a bad guy database which
went with this is but
I'll have databases three pitchers
myself and I would try out
various poses and think in various
situations
the sea have that effect matching so you
can see the top there
I'll the top two pitchers you know came
in pretty good 7.8
in in a actually lowered the lighting in
a book little bit better
arm with a database you know pictures I
had on
he put a hand on you can see that drop
dropping damn thing and the seven 7 they
were classes in
7.6 and no compare to some point it so
there's a little bit of fact here
but if we said Aiea thrust hola 752
woodstock casualties are suppose it
doesn't matter that my wife would kill
me if I shared
I can run that test you know my life to
swim i'd
I but you can see here I look up
my eyes are looking up that ross et if I
smile that you're upset
up
close the eyes remember eyes are you
seeing her point so that had a pretty
real or effectively look down but you
know you can see really want sunglasses
just kill the system all said we go from
72 59 here on this
so you this is why does the onyx and you
must take certain classes of
for their system were the more
interesting cases really
are down here as easy as you look away
as a
United measure that 20 degree turn but
you can see I see still see my eyes and
let me turn that far away from
when the camera and an assist holy mess
a system a
so in in a at in a situation where
you're looking for the tears she may
have an opportunity to look at two or
three or four frames so
but as they get their head turned away
from from from from
from from the camera at just the right
time in the system's not gonna
not recognize
are I don't know I among expert at that
at their software so that would be a
good question and i cant
came I can answer that question but it
would seem to me was
I'll with what's interesting here is in
the day-to-day
the database that I have had all the
pictures of myself
you know they were posed pictures that I
was you like you do for driver's license
or something like that saw a lot of the
same factors kickin
on the database photos we know what if
your head is turned 18 for the photo the
database
so but I have found is that it did match
up better
if I had two pitchers where they're both
turned away that gave a fairly decent
match that's you know so the chances
looking this way
this way the other time you know there
be no match possible install
yeah okay
that's a good question I have a I i'm
gonna be like the sun glasses
but I didn't think that one yeah Sep at
I think people have a look at you yet at
the airport but sunglasses 11 pretty
pretty normal normal thing
and so they say you got you got taken
off yeah
if that's a big question in SL it has
passed another test I made it
clearly if you wanna put on the system's
and as the concert SAT
Iran I just think the follows you know
had you know
like hatchery are thicker glasses
anything like that those are kinda
testing wanna run here for for real
insulation could you guys use a
microphone please
when you get recorded okay I'll try it
say the questions
your question is if you use make up any
player a bit like a fake
fake nose on or something like that
digital system up front that might that
may
it depends on if it's something being
measured but I know the facial hair
doesn't look too much at the mouth
so you know see-saw affair with a smile
that change things on sale of
past for something bad to happen cap
have on the shaker heights your
interests
hahaha message yes it's so what does
that say to address me on the terrace at
as a only be there face recognition for
that but yes
yeah
well first to the study I should huh
trial second-hand boats
as is Tess yeah yeah
me we have in Holland have a nice your
system in place
really most states last speaker
nice bright yellow letters sp
letters thought meanwhile nice our
so i think im I doing how's the checks
for the check
sheet over a trajectory tech change your
last getting outta iris
given range highway I'm I thought ash
devices come home back car
which consists all these lights comments
splattered yeah in one giant explosion
just saw this is work by scoring
different elements
what's the chance your eyes as opposed
to that
his last sounds like me
be home she's streamline yeah well we
don't have the terrace too much less I'm
getting any ideas
yeah other hole will get it I think
there's plenty of other problems in our
yeah on Amy elite forgive me
yes this is but stresses
Amy this is used 1 photo per person of
you can have multiple phones has the
same you wouldn't be possible
say device taking average all he's
different pictures say head down eyes
closed
all columns there may be that
possibility the system doesn't
have only has one for doesn't have this
concept the mobile phones per person he
can put me in that there's no
correlation between them
between so I that's a good question for
the onyx but I just
a triples okay but you can't feel awful
photos
and so some some photos made track
better than other ones
yeah I mean if you have multiple phones
first different positions then it will
match
Yahoo that pero
it Natraj runs at so this
with him and he G
are getting that everybody's ass
first
assist French systems
you said missus what is
liability does this message
okay I are getting to that but if I
don't remind me
okay as well we'll that's harder so the
catch
catching okay so up
in on this part here annual meeting you
can see
that this is not for that perfect
technology by any stretch of the
imagination
yeah I and
by the way to actually show that the
stock honey
for Boston Logan Airport use consider
buddy
system yeah at up I
early on was given 10 minutes and but
anyway the
one lady said thank you very much they
weigh a ton of the stage was
it she says you know I was you know I
really she says
I H and five my pitches were less than
flattering light say
and a and bull there was a bitch up at
the time it was it was
a slight nothing here I'm at this using
my smile pictures here
but as you can see this year turning
into a different at different places you
get different Nationals
and then these are the database bitches
here some of them
you know that one having room is switch
yeah i i didnt you know home have the
but those are all those are all good
things missing see other hola matchup
you think here's our big party alarm
I don't know I don't police I don't
believe their part the other okay
okay
okay there was a question about age and
so what I did was I took to various
pitchers
that I it's Natasha happened you know in
in the shoebox in my house
scan demand and then just directed that
check HERE
now arm what it what it look like
you know so I have these pictures here
you know 8389 8390 698 2008 across
that all a cross between a here and my
feeling was
on another great statistician and eyes
here a little bit bad it seem like
this they're still good matches between
different years but the closer the
pictures were in time the better the
matches were
the certain look at that %ah perot you
get the best match in a
wanna just 75 it goes back up but I
you know there's some exceptions here
but up you know the
there there is a major factor it's not
that bad you know the song was a 20-year
span on here we're getting pretty good
match fans
yeah
I not really know not there to set up
there's two matches a template so
up there may be is there are some people
that work
were any kind Obama check system works
worse than
than other people and so there may be
ethnic groups that can work
were spent pretty much does not really
any at
Seitzer biases built in yes as far as I
know yeah you can
you know I for one think there's no way
saying lifestyle yards for are spot on
style for it you can do that yeah well
maybe
to some degree I think be yeah you think
that that you could probably do without
with this software you have to have
difference offer
K
it's just basically this area a I la
there's something claim up to 18 points
but its order that here
just give you an idea that pitches
hearing
all the same fears as I don't have any
non
here once his passport photo yeah
they they they they they do you say that
yes is after about age 16 are that they
have faced stabilizes
okay
I here's some the hijacker test page is
kinda fun
up I
grab these photos of the FBI website and
you can see
we've got a pretty good match 8.4
between these two photos and into
my Isaac the one on the left you know he
gave some way he was the leader there
on but 8.46 a good match so you can see
just that you know aging effect doesn't
matter
here there's another one as a very
different pictures I think a lot of
people would say
literally the same guy but they came out
pretty good there
and you know we had a lower had lower
quality pictures are even less want to
claim tax
I don't think anybody call an excellent
but tell you know that's that's true
love
K the next
the next thing here yes
all think there's two different s
minded to gather a so
match me up against the hijackers air
7.4 that's a pretty good match
yeah yes
you know what's kinda scary though is
that cute matching up to that same guy
yeah he feels
yeah I love he's dead good he was
so I I probably would set the alarms of
here but
you like and came came kinda close close
that someone or so close right yeah I
kinda thought
7.5 threshold be a good one miss camper
pretty pretty darn close their on these
here but these are the ones they were
not that to get a message like that come
up
this guy I'm take a lot of Holland much
a while
of these values are not scale courts
days large Chris
lists all tests little right yes
right so the probability of this
mishmash is gonna rocky knows the size
avis gets better
probability members okay
okay I
so that what I gave you you know what my
actual results where they're here and
these are some other
here some %uh the so things I noticed
I'll you know lighting makes a big
difference a
makes a big difference in image quality
I'll
a good neutral background is good
sunglasses system which busy onyx now
says publicly
that in Houston's an interesting in
didn't mention that problem now they do
on I get said I got many false negatives
of the recommended default threshold of
8.5
I that way too I never even got closer
match Unohana
at some point files was pretty good
pacify had 7.5 for a show like that no
real false Matt positive but then he
will extensive testing
on and so for same
people you know I you know I definitely
saw system to work and you know which is
I just had to get some got 19 value
so for the same person I got mashed race
between seven and nine different people
typically saw you know five-and-a-half
27 yes even see
system color doesn't match up with
people as long as you have good quality
images
arm
but let's move on out away from the so
the techie cited
things answer looking at the system
issues here on
in order for the face recognition face
recognition system the spot
terrace at the airport you had to build
a database is the bad guys
so our that's an immediate problem here
we think about home but say okay to my
as
today I was just reading the newspaper
5,000 members
that are still in Pakistan com
the the question is is this
we're gonna get the pictures for those
people mean
they're not exactly lining up to have
their pictures taken you know you have a
pitcher been logged
we have pitchers have his this
lieutenants
but is here I seriously doubt we have
pitchers are those other five thousand
members
so to the system to catch the terrorists
that the airport
um doesn't seem possible because we're
just not going to have the pictures for
those people
so this idea they were in the UC system
shares as it seems very reasonable
I'll now is to go to the ER September 11
hijackers
I'll week they actually do
two of them were suspected terrorist so
you know how little better luck there
there was a kind in a while
us army and co-lead I'll parliament are
and they may have I wrote here they have
photos
one up on the play as far as a tool what
happened is in late nineteen ninety 90
observe these two guys in Malaysia
I'll having the meeting someone who is
known to be a member of
Qaeda and this is the Malaysian other
you know intelligence folks you know
observe this mean it recorded
there were probably pitchers from a
meeting but not 100 percent sure
but haha hijackers had they were allowed
in this country after that meeting on
and they actually entered the the
country twice the left and came back
again
on now what's sort of interesting here
if you want if I knew of
on
he was pretty easy to find as the white
page in the phone book
palm so this this idea that we are
facing missions as the catch is that
seems kinda silly
at four so what happened was a CAA
recognize this guy was probably in their
terminology
dirty near in the year two thousand they
didn't hole
let the FBI and INS now until August
a 2001 so for 18 months he's got a
running around known dirty guys but for
some reason the CIA did
did mention this to anyone on buttface
Canyon Mine parties guys it was possible
you know which should discount that but
this phone other ways
catches guys you know beforehand
on
some things about setting up a scanning
systems the airport
I wrote this before they it's all the
systems and it turns out the rules are
exactly what they did you gently can use
existing set sail scammers you need to
set up new cameras
you've got to have a walkway where the
system is years
were lighting a strictly control there's
no windows is best way to do it and
split in artificial I'm
on and then you force people to walk and
a single file line
and cameras must be kinda head
you know it at head to head height he
should I walk into a wall with cameras
and and passengers muscle strain
and a guy with sunglasses and then
he human being that when you get ahead
to verify okay with two people here that
the computer says match to the really
matter actually need really have been a
backup
on night ended a airport security
conference two weeks ago or three weeks
ago where is the onyx
made a presentation to installation at
statue Liberty
on over we can win or some terrorists
been terrorist threats against statue
Liberty and
the John from the CRS describe the set
up there
so I could enable those less site hey
there even professionally installed on
the system so you can just see
from from just using the software that
the systems are
earlier work and a DVD need has special
care
this is the simplest they had now
when we get into I when we get into
a the actor see question
up which was asked earlier on
overall my guess is if you had a scare
us walk through any had
good hit %um good pitches %uh them in
the database that you have about a 50
percent chance of getting a match
the vendors claim or around like many
percent
but it feels more like 15 these files
fell
at the a international by net mentors
crew
the vendor id: ok cold conditions is in
six assistant succeeded in identifying
individuals from getting database
on a little more than half the time to
vendors are claiming like ninety percent
independent Esther seen the end up
around 50 percent but that his
is predicated on one very important
thing he can control everything at the
airport
but he gotta have good pitchers at the
terrorist
and you don't control that situation not
even let you know even if you've got a
pitcher at the terrace it doesn't mean
it's going to be up to the standard
being able to that database work well so
that so that's why this is effing
a/c unit good guy system reducing access
control we allow somebody go through the
door
you enrolling them into the system and
you control both sets of photos you know
when they're at the doors walls and then
roll to different different problem
but when you're looking for terrace you
don't control a speech to the database
was extremely interesting years there's
been about a half a dozen
Chester these these systems at airports
I actually
got scanned at Boston Logan Airport
because I set one up for the
the order love it so I was flying out to
Salt Lake and I got scan their
on the I the way they test the systems
is they put in their
into their quote-unquote that got data
basic rates and had a bad guy database
which I understand as they just download
pictures from the FBI website like I did
so the relatively small few hundred 300
photos
but then they take input employees at
the airport into the database also
but actually tried at least SS is an
actual trying to catch it but its key
statistics
and so they put in pitchers have
employees in these databases and they
measure
you know the count how many times a
recognize employees course those
pictures
employees are good control pitchers turn
on what you have for terrorists
so they claim all these great your
success rates in the United percent but
it's kinda
cope with cookbooks I am in my opinion
nice talking with someone who actually
is supervising some other stuff who
works
for the TSA the group this looking at
putting the system said this is how you
had done it to
said the same I same saint petersburg
they they put in the cops into the
database
and Turkish is exactly the same place at
the same cameras that they use for
scanning
natchez not only what the way it is for
terrace so the one needs to be very
skeptical longer
hear about the singer
right %uh and that any
any customized under here thanks
%uh yeah things up you get that means I
think that and that's exactly the point
years if you start looking at all this
you're gonna suck you we maybe it's all
the systems in airports
and we can catch terrorists with
embedded that same thing doesn't we
definitely have much shots
%uh local bad guys so that's who opposed
to the database
and it'll be just like the Super Bowl
but we have
a you know we just simply use the
airport is a convenient place the low
round up the usual suspects and this is
exactly the point that I made in Logan
Airport
what I said presented to them acid is
Logan Airport
right place to be look you know rounding
up the local bank robbers you have
enough problems security already
you want to take on a whole other local
police tomorrow
and in the answer what they said was a
health
had a head at Logan Airport says yeah we
don't care that's a you know that sounds
fine dust
ices the reason that we want these
systems and
is for the term effect that the next
time that there's a hijacking it isn't
that from Bossier paper
for because the bad guys that we have
this isn't a catcher and
that seems to be at the same sentiment
was echoed at this airport security
conference that I wanted
that is more scared people than than
anything else is
is is a bad guys think it's gonna work
another the stairwell
in that they may have had they met there
may be something to that I don't say
that its wholly
total votes: but what I do you think is
the systems as far as catching
terrorists go
probably aren't going to work is going
to be much more
let's just logo you'll obey robbers or
day dacha whatever the size Prime
Minister who who were gonna
who are you going with the sisters yeah
Adam cable difficult
are supposedly casinos are using this a
lot
years past stage this
special status of National get I said
yes Chiefs for raided another another
guy ed
another guys will have no effect because
I was perfect timing
that up I think the casinos if you look
at that application it really shows you
how technology is fine the ecological
niche
on that face recognition has all the
certs
problems or limitations are so
the casinos with they bought into the
idea of a scanning to look for
you know known she's so what they do is
the casinos get together they build a
database of all the bad guy
weapons are the cheats now leading cause
I'll show you why
midwifery quotes and they have companies
who run the systems with them
so are for them you talk to see you
might pay twenty thousand dollars a year
to run the service
but if the as long as it
if it's awesome million dollars with
cheating it's paid for itself
the RR of that is quite good and so
for their standpoint there's work of
Statistics so even if this system only
has 10 percent that she's a walk anybody
you have to be higher because if you
control the pitchers want people on the
database it should be higher
it's just something like that get return
on investment know what's interesting
about the systems as well
late well who goes ahead database and
I'm
you know who like who decides well you
certainly he got somebody is stealing
chips on the table
or you know it how you know you what's
the Discovery Channel HA all those cheap
you know
you know cheap physical cheater the
graph circular cross you know so we can
say well those are okay
within but they also consider car
cameras crux
in car trailer to serve the people who
know how to play blackjack betting that
the scene and us
and they're labeled by the casino
sprouts and they get you know excluded
from going in and playing blackjack
and so you can really see you know this
release
uncertain the inserts a civil rights
issue cited the same here
is is left to the casinos and you know
they're asleep
people that I don't think should be
excluded units because have to memorize
cards in your head
you learn how to suck at least mas your
head you know on the right and the bad
not bad
that doesn't seem like she to me so
anywhere using this is the keepers and
people are a civil rights attorney
December misuse the system are just
learning thing ever
white-collar criminals to the database a
lot of CEOs not be able to
take their place anymore yeah great
place around the block but not because
that's his body of this people file
brother South billion but no that's the
point is these systems
on finally gets down to who gets to make
that decision
because in database you know what's the
the legal standard for putting people in
there
in a mostly talk about yes people who
are
wanted you know four you know jumping
bail for this an outstanding arrest
warrant for them
it is not you know with the session one
thing I heard your city it's not for
people just known to be bad
as people who actually you know they're
looking for but also opens up
to of for misuse my personal experience
with it in use
the tissues videotapes is a
demonstration by the City Hall
me off %uh in Sin City Hall New York and
they use
videos of past administrations in a
thought the quote someone that was
supposedly being a public haha
unfortunately
demonstrators got hold of me about the
massive as the National Lawyers Guild
way down to the police station and the
two cocks the holding the minute he even
look
like the guy in the video with a
spokesman for the system with a police
lineup
and for sure he was really nice but this
could be really use just harass people
to stop them like ours missing what
flights whatever
yeah it's to me is very scary that's
another techno fixin
yeah we have to be wary of misuses
right here there's no doubt about these
a
depending on what level they get put
into a
you know tim has some very very you know
really bad effects
on mean that's that's that's what my
concern is in they're going under the
guise of the Los
page keeping us safe from terrorists but
that is all they can be used that way
the other part in this too is somebody
travels on airplanes a lot
others to error rates that we need to
talk about we were talking about the
system's
one is the the you miss somebody that's
really the bad guy
but then the other reverses the finger
somebody and say this is a bad guy
money really is so the question is what
happens in that situation how do you
handle it well the first thing you do is
you need a human being
to go and nm agitation sale yet they
looked like to look the same
well then what you do you know if they
do you mean you know the human beings is
a mess and you need to send
some security people over and talk to
that person
well what a few runs or whatever you
know you know there's a lot of what ifs
here
how you handle that situation and and he
can be pretty disruptive at the airport
he have to consider that the number
terror certainly want to it
through the airport there are going to
be the database is gonna be in 1 $500
million maybe
but the number of false positives you're
going to get is about one person
the system business offers to say about
once once every one or two airplanes is
is the rating error rates
there around anywhere close to half a
percent of the two percent
see how this whole question of you know
love other
you know one or two planeloads of
somebody being figured as a terrorist
and so you start thinking about that
what's gonna happen is it
that the security people just don't give
up on this is a lot of people go because
they'd there they're never going to see
a terror syndicate seeing all these
all the system causing crime were off so
there's a lot of variation policies
decisions that have to be worked out
and this came up with this airplane
security happens people design
securities
sure boards in similar kinds of systems
have various
have similar problems so it's it's not
hot dry hey make these things were
yeah to have the
on twins or family members PCs
official its a
I her ok it's has
I'm sorry it happened but that's another
good one to run the right to sleep on a
twin
to questions about you okay how
susceptible system to disguise another
countermeasures
well the the at the clearness
your sunglasses you know a kills it but
if you add a fake beard on or whatever
that should its is it physical area Faso
it you know like a fake nose but i
thinkI people can notice it
now that when they were
now sneeze
the still this discussion they on the
things differently when you're talking
about
seems is on ongoing theme
in American public life is the
privatization of previously public
spaces like malls
am wondering what if any protections in
place for
images collected in public spaces or
dislike was in public spaces like malls
what are these images gone once the
system's
got a picture him walking to the airport
with the access changes behind that the
security company and then
okay well in the the face recognition
systems
what is the onyx lots to say is
a no match no no memory they
automatically discard the image after
that
however you know for a in general for
CCTV systems a security cameras
in general there's is usually a recorded
on some
I never you no slouch a slow a
v VHS tape in illegally special VHS
recorders that say that sucks away
it in general %uh you know it's in the
security department have the states they
they might recycle once every few weeks
once every few months depending on the
on the retention policy the company
after that the discarded on so
you know the bad news yet assess your
images say the law
%uh but that's that is the good news is
nobody
actually almost ever looks at them that
there are no human being actually is is
looking at them
that's what's interesting about face
recognition is now you have a computer
that actually and look at the
mean that the images yes you can imagine
also to Big Brother applications for
this stuff way beyond what these
companies are currently talking about
now
it's very very intersting there's an
article in the New York on Sunday
magazine
were the gentleman and just Vatican
who is president of the onyx said don't
worry
will never go the really bad route on
the system's
because I want right I will write the
software to to make this happen
and unite a level
you know this is a very arrogant his
first saying you know I
you know I'm no I and the neverland Big
Brother I'm not gonna do bad things and
I'm a techie am in control here
you know don't were on in pretty clearly
I there are some very interesting policy
decisions need to be made about the
system's
are in this time you know I
skeptical do that seem to be having more
towards a lot more surveillance
but this play is you know problems such
as general surveillance cams
you know today South we got five minutes
so that
time for a few more questions
T
on PC
since more
over lines subsidized research
sconce large systems and then ask them
to bring products to market
proceeded to test the product some Hans
33 Sturgis just
and did Barbie
spread mission gender tests ask results
sucks showers
see see procedures
from apps
they just
the only fibers original 3 dropped out
they're running again finished
s results website this is the
this this we'll see
this year this fifty companies
this just are to
CEO two companies see
its tells he retired
posts
coach term products
that's
fortunes stance the
this test a very interesting because
this is a tent
about to do a systematic study these
systems I'll
how long lines that I was doing the air
looking at various
no false-positive false negative rates
the effects that lighting he said two
things
now was gonna be interesting here's on
when the vendors when the results come
out they're gonna continue my penis
result
on their uses other this test is a
as as an amo to say hey we're ready to
go on airports now
I know that's going to happen are why I
think this tester probably gonna have
not be applicable for the terrorists
application is the
really look you're not really getting
into this question of how to pitch in
tears
we have one other quality those bitches
yeah
yeah there's an actress special really
really love him
that and that's all that's like a
lawnmower but yeah
II scene also US Army test was done this
is done more informally
and they were sisters similar similar
kinds results here
and that's thinking after have to fight
so that part time for one more question
here
yeah okay I don't know if your
intentions to the game
halfway through but I'll I do remember
reading something in the New York Times
vaults
a England in this specifically London
for the most part talking about their
implementation cameras
all over the city and the they I guess
they've been doing it for
quite a few years now these two years
because they're really afraid of
terrorism
no in all our problems are limited one
thing that they said is that in three
years
%uh the only people they've ever caught
are
you know known criminals who looked a
little pale the burglaries
weather looking for those terrorists but
almost all the terrorists the
you know that we do it suicide bombings
it was the first crime
that is so yeah it in three years I have
been caught nobody
yeah that I mean its agenda the UK is
have been on the vanguard a solid
security cameras its was in the early
nineties it was related I R
IRA bombings of in in there are there is
a face scanning system in 10 the town
squares in England but they're mostly
just
installing regulars old security saddam
security cameras if you will
rather than smart security cameras like
this other is one place where they've
done it
these young sluts have crime went down
in that area it's unclear why
on that they never caught anybody you
know with assistance
okay thank you very much again my left
side is computer bites man I do have
more information out there
face kenny also because it's
on