within joke about the police lineup card
tried all the bare mein time thank you
it's one say we have many many giveaway
so that's where you're staying warm
six we'd almost have the feedback
problems are
we're gonna take a little time
in many many people that were involved
and ah... on the stage here are some
don't necessarily realize
three-day conference
is that we've been planning this
the six months
and uh... lot of work weekends
by many many people
and even had com
essentially anytime
someone for help
during setup
will be able to turn to someone sixty
helps
people i've had
so we want to say thank you get one who
attended
we also want to get recognition
people that help
missus some
do you guys rock
so i think our our jobs for me so much
easier by the attendees who helped us
out every step of the way and he has a
lot of work involved in the a fifty
thousand square feet to deal with
middlemen hatton street-level
call kinds of things could have happened
and ah...
we we made it uh... we made it work
really really well
the panels are great people were
were interesting on
they're very stop it to be discussed and
that the crowds everybody comet and how
great the crowds were how interested
they weren't things
interested in something that
i think
i think the whole conferences have had a
good history with that kind of thing and
that's why i hope we we're able to
continue
and our plans to do this again two years
her
filtrate
it'll be the tenth anniversary of the
whole conferences with the first was
nineteen ninety four the was to be the
twentieth anniversary twenty six hundred
magazine if you can believe that
so off
i'm looking for a clever names at
restricted portrayed as stanley
regarding returning
the more you need name
so well
we're open to suggestions
bernice here and uh... bernie's voices
completely shot as a result of all the
talking he's been doing this weekend i
think that's why he should be the mc
tonight but this is it
just really kind of
personified off
profound field manual for uh...
stressing label words even
it's been phenomenal
every time we do want to be said
uh... we think this is this you can't
get any better
spitzer lighting bright-eyed
anyway
this exceeded my expectations i have
exceeded yours
and d
we had uh...
we had a great crowd and uh... i've got
a lot of were still here
we got it thank uh... some of the we've
got a faculty face that we got it thanks
for the core organizers here
many of whom or not here in italy for
various reasons but uh...
uh... if you uh... who are able to
remain on
certainly pick up a fight
about this one working over there i just
what you did
talk briefly about what now
how do you help make this happen some of
the couple of libya
anecdote to
things that were dis
it just worked out just through
good fortune
both window we have no way
people
uh... pile up
electric about until i got
what do you have written
from active one
other people experience
uh... going up
uh...
group
carrier
carry also did a phenomenal job managing
and volunteers here
scores of volunteers but running around
the blue shirts
cup but you might want to raise your
hands you at least herzog brought cheers
and uninsured oscar bets over that
carries a coordination and she just
really got on things immediately we take
care settler
got hearing region
todd
well i think that you're prepared to put
what would never go back to earth
with dot
where there will be a link
it completely
it can't be too dot
like to have a good bit betty no medlar
the dignity of it
other correct
it by
paperback article
email catcher
emailed hopefully
who's responsible for
you're getting in here frankly isn't
managed registration
which i gotta say with manage very well
and uh... we had two houses badges to t
to distribute and at complicate things
we'd fight streets
which will probably go to a later date
how how that was arrived at
but uh... gesture whatever
nightmares that you did you have to
overcome to uh... to make all that
happened registration
greatly gettle
everyone either one
dispersed out or actually i think
bibi bibi bibi
if you were here in nineteen ninety four
allies
finger registration then
that was something that's a first time
we did it we had no was going on so
uh... yeah and uh... to uh... to the
registration forms
getting it done right this year
we've heard from other states every
single time it's just going to get
better
happy registration being
notes keeps improving settler
never go back to play with press
conferences one will be getting better
it will look
uh... come together and email exam that
uh...
wheatley stuck to a low-tech
distribution system you could have some
pretty banter have people looked up
cuter frankly i think people your wife
we did that for your privacy
i don't see uh... roddy up here but i
think really begin for security for
really doing a great job this year
procure make it
place running smoothly they kept things
here and they uh...
basically
we break they were nicer human beings
are part of us which is what it's all
about
re we take care of ourselves
uh... we on the outside influences
we're uh...
you know we're working meeting and i
think they'd be
who personify victory
uh... animus here from uh... the network
peru
theater-goers know how that worked up
and up
well i wish the network for a little
supports move them
it was
or at least asking that was last year
minds t one
t one worked great but they'll couple of
really
czar logistical problems we have
last night we got punched holes
i think uh... next year's net
each ticket for
who have ah...
britain will do better
joe palca sent the commands
it in advance to actually tested those
probably problem
as far as getting network wanting
deletes think that the other guys
and treatment u
split special frank and i see people
katelyn
i don't see anybody from the public's
remove wants to hear that those guys who
can expatica
really meeting or two
beating at the time to really uh...
patch of sparks of somebody actually
spark
streisand nobody really money and abuse
to your
spark it's moving webserver
and stuff so
that was pretty decent
indicates you rolling
captains movement was moving so i
thought i was a five people could get on
the wireless network
wired networks
i'd like everybody turned their
attention over to the uh... counsel over
their workers has been working
endlessly for four days and uh... sound
issues in predetermine
it's probably the biggest challenge of
running a conference just to to keep the
whites keep the speakers keep that
microphones give everything working all
at the same time
which is really unbelievable to me
uh... so again thanks so much for for
volunteering in being part of that
believable without leaving people out
i don't know i can't remember how many
times i sent
mr uelmen off the left here over the
radio shack at the last minute
got to have this you know in ten minutes
or less any
you must have sent sms at land speed
records going over there and back
thank you for that
lawyers it's also hosting the retro
computing panel and and setting up over
two competing
neighbor downstairs japan carry a chance
to check out the edinburgh pvd dancers
what i find stuff passionate last night
i was up so that
you're for the morning
and spent three hours of fixing up
thirty
and that we got it going and we played
we've got a movie on a real we'll take
them now
russian spies anyhow that was that i was
pretty they've got to be doing
goddard jack
for his music downstairs for uh...
effort
yes entertainer and on friday night
its elections i think
of whom i could go to match
say when it looks like i'll check for
managing all the p_j_ say were playing
in foresaw the d_j_s who played as well
i drop by the crop losses a couple of
things drop from holland who are
inspired us with oh... galactic pack a
party and b_t_u_ and all those other
recovers as really suggest people get
out to don't just go to the conferences
here in the states
next year is going to be something in
germany
which will be heavily involved in
three years they'll be another one in
holland
and uh... those are the ones that really
inspired us to putting together here in
this country sab got together
that the community
and really uh...
progress learned things got together
so i think we'll take care
meat
lead a fairly modest
whatever experience we could offer
little things that might help
what we need to realize
realizes
but it's a circle it's a circle that
that those people organizing stuff
coming meeting
up to some of these issues that we
going out of organizing stuff on their
own realizing that some parts of that
circle of really good
in the end of may turn out to
one person
stacy manual
maxi got his credit cards risking his
things mortgage payments or whatever
to get this thing
going trying to keep it going
or a small group
the skill set it takes to
just sent a payment
to do things for this
people together
then by all means do we need
meaning together
possess these skills organization
business sense
any of these same important skills took
to get the
things like this billing just completely
complete ignorance of personal risks
go for it
do things like this that's
it's great that security through our who
really did a great job keeping us ah...
everybody happy
very thanks so much for all your efforts
all
many people here had a good time
that's what counts make how many people
had a really good time
and
clearly to encourage these guys to do
this again
we need to have another one of these
products
hatred i would like to out
tell you that
the only pranks and gone on let's say
you were
maybe a couple of tagging incidents in
the end of the day
the letters from downstairs got stolen
by
you distracted the security team that's
one of one them
uh... yeah
we were killed by kids that was the only
thing they could figure to spell out
what the letters
why do the security force to point b_
camp near the tapes
from the cameras
that were in the elevators
that was like
i'd say maybe about an hour
lots of help
but other than that it was great we've
gotten all the radios back
shearson
real happy about that
and nothing else so far it's been a
while
maybe a couple of you lost items
other than that it was a break calmer
so you want to do this again
took her first so we are so that they go
tell which i think really had a really
whatever wafer
the reverse this time
elders actually worked
way organizing safely get together with
them bit there you see where the normal
conferences
what can you be running from nine to
five what what you want
that's strange
but they worked with us uh...
you know would not like any other
conferences place has ever seen
they accepted that accepted aunts and
make it was the space we need literally
it worked out great
really work that grace i think uh... we
owe the hotel the ground because and i
think this place
assorted throughout somebody else was
being here perilously throughout the
entire weekend great newbie who is uh...
greatest
making sure things run smoothly and all
different areas
also uh...
also a great rest timecard best-dressed
more problems here
professor real life
some well
people are so willing
staples
gets down level
pfizer
next slide
and they are the speakers
couple of other routes
but was simply yet speakers
uh... the speakers that we have had a
manual them
well over seventy because accounting the
third tractor a lot of people in there
doing kings as well
it was just amazing nobody cancelled and
you know there is none of these uh...
holes in the schedule everybody should
have a very good
i think a really good job in your
of any panel where the person did a
lousy job
it was great we're in communication with
them out
months before hand weeks months before
hand getting things together
i think that's what i think if i was
really well the only complete so i heard
was that there is too much good stuff
and it's happening at the same time you
couldn't get through it all
i was just so happy to see so many
people getting into negative land jello
arun recruiter people like that who are
not really for the hacker community
but appreciate it
and you guys appreciated and i think
that's really cool
except manual czars
yet another
amazing recognition
managing the speakers
truly can't imagine what it takes to
seventy different people
comments be factories topics is not just
it's not just getting speak you have to
uh...
coordinates and different tells them
scheduling that britain's tuesday was
elitist
and i i wouldn't want to take job on so
if you can imagine
how much work that would it take to
manage content seven different people
what more to it
speaking of logistical nightmare
the infrastructure you see around it was
set up into
is planned for much longer needs to go
out of here
less than a day
maybe have already volunteered or
what you're talking about lol
it's like you know
the last couple of nights uh... and you
can
spend a few extra hours tonight helping
carry stuff down
helping package things through trash out
by all means this is your chance to
really make a difference missus
mix is a community is a you also please
places up
and not leave a small group
with all the stuff
so please help us
we could not make fun
dismissed just chill out
duplicate joke to god said
did not return to take your did you get
it
uh... went to carry advisory system
anyway
quick work
using a
risk a
uh... or keep using at risk assessments
a
strategy but in any case
be configured that used to work
uh... somewhat followed this is this
crazy scheme of uh...
risk of uh...
risk terrorist attacks from severe high
above elevated started down the road i
want anybody feel that'd
as it
dated their lowest terrace tax bracket i
would prefer
firstly it loaded
of terrorist attack
tag anybody effective so
anyhow i'm
argued for weeks how we're going to
right wrist levels signed what
back-to-basics weakest but the point of
view
so well
if you look at your pet also others
couple things i want to point out to you
mag stripe on the back
with some liberally chosen to
publicized wanted figured out on usable
at your hotel
uh... to same type retract straight
hotsync level culver city and uh...
underway if you still have a romantic
checked out here
that front desk and i have been encoded
essentially here
course the technician insert the right
way
i saw several people you three sticking
to that his has been
there's also a chip on his part
you can't figure out what that's for
yourself that sort of a something been
you can just write figure
what purpose that might have and uh...
yet we had a ill effects
ed every it's less than markets and
seattle
who uh... was on our design team
mail myself and it came up with these
designs
definetly using the brain dot that was
pretty ritualistic featured side
agreement shit implant
but we thought this kind of a better
word ship
linked to the brain
redistricting
also at the front of the batch there is
a hidden message
but you're not gonna be although it's
not human readable bt orkut message
so budget axes orkut readers through the
day
it right because that as anyone not
conference decoder that park again
not a one i've got a couple of market
because down in the year
rector competing area and i went back to
or i couldn't find somebody keys
so what would my give we had a few extra
we didn't have enough postage frankly we
don't have time to put them
wanna get these way
is and that you probably noticed the
national security agency here
military
infos acting for security purposes and
put around the escalators
uh... you can't get there should be in a
second try
leading date yet they're only getting
into
military uh...
military agencies
thanks to just let ours
some people think those were uh... those
who are
posters that we made as a telling people
that uh... to me
security begins with you
yet we might believe that but we would
never come up with something such easy
is that
this can only
but it looks like straight out of the
nineteen fifties
but we couldn't get these ourselves we
have to basically take this from their
website
and um...
uh... jeff lasted an amazing job reserve
for their amazing job
steve
interested there
because we've never believed that this
is something that was taken off the
website like that
thanks thanks to him now everyone has
seen it
and daddies are actually actual posters
from the n_s_a_ also there were a
uh... we could make out the yes
uh... one of the logos the bottom of the
singer place to be a huge pages
therefore to parity and therefore we
don't violate any
in copyright
uh... some of the vendors who came here
uh... were generous enough to you
give us some of the things they were
selling
yet we've got a pile of stuff up here
also riley associates uh... it's never
been here but uh... obviously is a big
supporter of the actor community
publications
uh... again as they did eighty k
status and i certainly oppose pictures
so well we want make sure the people get
those
and uh... we're gonna have to figure out
some fair way to do this so
the badges uh... all have unique serial
numbers on them so
get out your badges
but you have to be where he was really a
year
and uh...
let's just uh...
start out with that
about the last two digits will start
with the last week in a single disk
eleven
you select it that way
ticket ticket number
when he said
somebody has a suggestion by the way of
uh... above liquidity that's prolly got
about fifty things to give away
so we want we want to see taking our
between
fifteen minutes
twenty six it was but was a grabber they
demand or at all
forty six pm twenty-six
elastic at the last two digits
are twenty six and a patch tamanna
not the first to order with a lot of we
have a big rush on our hands
fifty two with an excellent
uh... is the mentor in the house
cement or here's another here here
because the mentor everyone
the pre-operative conscience of a hacker
which uh...
many of us know by harding which has
been
quoted in such films as hackers
we'd like to make a special uh...
a special presentation here a lot of
people been asking about the the banners
that hang up and i know
uh... mentor he was interested in that
i'd like to say that the better in the
front here at this table is yours
take it back
refuted
well
uh... mota digit number
required
that's easy
what are we giving way
but they're going to others as welfare
organics giveaway is the uh... is the
poster
uh... actually with two people have the
same number of giveaways
fretboard
three digit number
zero zero
either somebody
two people for the same price has gone
to work there
all right we have to have a little
competition there are some sort
financially secure being questioned so i
guess that
this trivia with zero zero okay
what was
if you can only answer reach your hand
and nobody shot out please
what was the month
your attitude
gain
mister olmos you like the way party
peter
before that happens he wants me
we're getting reports first
made but i was asking you the question
of their security for trivia for
ministers anyways requested
what month and year
was the first issue of twenty six
hundred
any of you know that maybe three
than if you can all go sit back down
then
not all of the the three-way tie for for
okay
you against
april eighteenth
no you guessed wrong
i guess that means you're you have minus
one downing of zero
all right with some of the questions
as escape from reply
when you placed a blue box home
you would get the point
vp
was houston
as friends or something
system i did
i think that's something you get
something but gave dressy disqualify
vertical
we'll give you here
myself and the
thank you all carried out the two
without the two
about your your question three question
last
gency right for example
yet the same from for example to do
something else
unix operating systems
like that
what issue of twenty six hundred
of twenty six hundred magazine
that also into them
forbes magazine
uh... anybody coast guard
about this
what this twenty six hundred
it haha either one of you to know
what twenty six hundred means
you really regret having zero zero mt
and
hideouts phone three they had no idea
where
however settled
this is what is known as sudden death
over time we're going to settle this
that's what's come up with
with more of a
than trivia question involving
what it's all things are
that's all for the not easily the extra
hard
computers may be
including zero
what is the fourth
number of the technologies
were such crestor tracker
it
kalpakkam
fourth retreats europe
to it gets it
enough of that
train twisting trivia
uh... we've got a bunch of t-shirts and
uh...
uh... some books and now
but research in bags from
in each
which is uh...
crypto organization it rock and that
they re our
or find speakers here
were are involved in
and at the church
located
what was it like this
image collision dark so uh...
answer phone with us in a time
so i have out uh...
seventeen eight you're back into the
tickets one seven
come on down
ities
no one sevens
a'bad eighteen
seventeen and or eighty
or
favorably
it whatever your resistant to please
title that
in their rooms of dell
laptop black with a link sis or a s_n_c_
whales that record
it just disappeared
along with the power supply
so if anyone saw anyone coming out of
that room
little black laptop i was in the other
room i didn't see don't go out
if you saw him please let me know
it was uh...
inspiration eight thousand
edit at it came up with the
we put up with those property of the
actual inc
self-pity one sees it
we stand by me when it's too early
the ball
here's visiting
if
no one has seen anyone
protects
as for the next number nineteen
i know that uh...
another one of people have been asking
the and others have what we do you
with all the videotapes that we've made
and uh...
substring that we've done
and then your wife tell people about
what might happen in the future with
availability of car
uh... well what might happen is that
uh... will
spent many many weeks going through all
of this in putting it together at her
attorneys to package
uh... but will put up on the internet
certainly can but who wasn't here can
hear at everybody who was here can
and um... eventually will make
videotapes out of the two issue really
want to relive it
you know when your house
takes takes a little bit of time you
know so i will
will be making a spell posters with him
okay we have we have more giveaways
bernie what else do we have
for deborah few books uh... couple
texaco rightly says he's playing cards
uh... in each six after bags
uh... searched generously donated by
it didn't really partners downstairs a
collaboration of center for the public
domain and
u_n_c_ chapel hill biblio dot org
a lot of people are
uh... useless
if you have recd outlook it never
downloaded lennox he probably at least
at one point or other downloaded from
what used to be the first onsite that
later on became metal lab analysis call
about biblio and a m they change their
name and i got the pics
redhat foundation open-source
principles opening
they resort village church then
i have a computer to give away
stetson atari excel
it's got to get strives
marker and software
and uh... if you're interested
yet what you want it
freed
poor people
we have a rather unique at giveaway
hearing yet
crypto device and until i can uh...
describe what it is and we're going to
big winner for that
this device here is a high speed
crypto lesser repeats the
this is a standard pci-x slot
as drivers for everything from when x
to uh... the espy's and maybe even
windows you can find
to hike and chill
and would you like sixteen megabytes of
three deaths
per second
also deloris say single bass
uh... couple but they are driven it's
made by hyphen
manufactured these cords for people that
actually like to have secure
communications over the internet
discards valued at about a hundred
dollars
and uh...
they're available from p_m_ bsd dot or
demands for a number of years
actually
if somebody can
worthless
yes question
everybody's appearing your ok to get the
questioner on your first uh...
raise you know if you don't know
click
westerdam's
what was the first word
first
here
the correct answer was boy
very close monopoly alike
brucella
second question is
how many picture on it
quieter
figure stricter carter to give away
disobedience recruitment weston so
consistently
news of the record them
at best
yet right
backwards
it's pretty
uh...
cabinets were any regional
implementation
d_e_s_
the original implementation of genius
either by setup
are rationing and wanted retention
buster interesting or something
with the question is do
what company was involved
whatever privately was involved
uh... within the city developing
the original implementation
yes
is that the emperor's
biggest i guess it
it was already a m
and uh... idea proposed to be sixty
four-bit
and uh... n_s_a_ pressured him to uh...
make it down to fifty six-page suit they
could
take a crack it easily
i'd like to know i could just one of our
for speakers in the first of conference
read from a quarter
who uh...
who was uh... for the moment reporting
as well give us a pledge of like metro
cards they all have uh...
the grandmothers and acts like this that
it would
generator and
yeah i figured i'd get up and say
something because
possible likely awarded it's cooper
he got the idea parade bumper generators
because a replacement either gallery the
last couple of abridged
sotsass like picking out a defective
parts were going to pick out of the deck
of
that your cards
added to your illustrious digits on your
margaret was two digits on the back your
card
experiences
reviews remember every
where students issue
i've been up here
you've heard it before but not for most
ninety seven
we'd also like to point out that some
people are obviously automatically and
eligible
really really sorry
and something else to do
it's a thier cd color
it's only computers nothing else
housing based on that one
surfaces to come up with last night
okay people interested in that
peaceably and
will ask you a question and see if you
can
past the fence
running during a break come down
that would have the last couple of years
and i want to return
that's it ricardo
you know the answer to the question
richard andrew went in the polls answer
them
wins
this uh... protectionist words
so even when we were too
these main
of the experts
your first
recently is correct
you repeat we try a fraction of a second
sorry please
if there was a
either mastercard uh... africa right
bernie will cut the cards
well that's that's why i would be proud
of progress toward recovery
uh...
reason
reserve though
three zero
there
europe
everyone
i think that um...
some people from the conference
information has been speaking i'm not
licked in san francisco
and just
the
nothing
utility
contacted me
without parking though just sitting in
on other people's cannot i think the
impact mentioned these happens
so you god
buying everyone in this
no matter what city
so
i actually don't have membership forms
of
everyone
mothered for
for that particular church
well it's interesting week work with the
works workers and or
four zero
no there if they are not consecutive
them would come out of there from all
over the place i don't worry about that
him
e
cancer
uh... k
bothered
sixty three
or
i was just a few more things
thirty-five
anymore records
well
well were added shirts we've got uh...
no rightly perot conference proceedings
and we got
prohibited
products
it's it's like it or sector work because
there's noticed what that want to go
carried out by wherever everybody stay
where you are
we're gonna have
are for it
mister almost more stuff will figure out
how we're going to give away the
barracks
there is the opening yada
got some world u
i think i have another laboratory
couples equaled so
it
all you did
is the best now
v
so ridiculed await atari eight hundred
another one
what it is great
if you want it at this point
well
about
your question
weekly dude
whatcha
in the way to get your
about what i had acutely
edward i haven't with a camera for him
question
it
some expedite starting next year
but
what's the maximum value of the intended
now
if
cancer rate
yeah
yet
the kid k
this is going to ask kim
what do you get your mission
okay cokie
after this
i'm not quite sure what we have left so
just
structured can
orca wicket writes this stuff
life
the