my name's really have run out
little ISP in San Francisco called
monkey brains
and have been running that since I 1990
and
provide I love web hosting and
colocation
people up here answers and last
down October FBI now says
here policing in New plug into their
hard work project hold back
called magically injured it's basically
keystroke logging program
and a week after that announcement
a virus came out with call the patrons
section that change virginity
there's an earlier one birch earlier in
the year but this
new over version came out and
it started sir Declan
dated keystroke logging data from people
and
he would collect the data here on mail
that information back
is emailed 10 twenty different address
and one is at rest happen to be on
wanted the domains that a person who's
that 314 service today
answered emailer email anything
and is subtyping
I just got fired up com Acer to get a
puncher
ymail.com his son my mail server is down
appliances can drag acting
what the hell's wrong answer to look in
the
the mail login all ships coming in and
only
about us family for sites shut off the
the email thing answer to store all
India Anna mills
profile and all the emails and then I
looked at it I opened up a circle around
like wow this is an
spam applies I read attorney users it
said
keystroke logging data never seen such a
massive on
now install it on friends huge fun good
as a director that so I I got all this
data in there
I started slept at night St
really for the little script merced and
split it up into different categories
here said passwords for web sites
passwords for remote network access
mom passwords for FTP sites
people use I V using some Microsoft
Windows product on
bhajans fires just collective just
affect
women's its price
but I am
so hells day and every day a script to
parse it
and a put it all into my seat will be to
be taken have my own mini
car more inside look to the data and see
looking for thinking about
world it said this funding that the
debtor couple days
named the icon there okay
yes indeed over there grains and
add told them
yes data know what you want you want it
all the
the files and they wanted
the logs from the person signing up for
the
3 emailer it I I just got fired up some
a website including your daily slightly
down
showed Jolie Scott fired home a good
year
so it would product of where your real
email addresses
and a home
a psych
start to think about privacy is using
wow these
data and i'm looking at it term ID
decide to look at it but I don't think
coverage I
earned it they have any I decided that
giving them that that I P that was used
to treat email
the lease is something that was there
the they should have that and some logs
on just that I P and some with the
initial
email setting into love monkey brains
and
the can get an idea love what
information it had
incident the me catch that person with
the were it
FBI King easy order to do that anything
the rest the day to the other capable
key with the missing on my hardest
I had to turn off the deflection
sustained
pp much from I clicked it for a couple
weeks
maybe three meets and I got about a
third of a million
pieces in email from people around the
world
from China Russia the US
places in Europe there's no we'll
pattern is worldwide
listen like this were tartan one country
that arm there
so I I decided to 1 p.m. that day talk
to her
the criminal lawyer that as helped out
2604 friend matches turn me on twitter
she Jennifer last thinking
are but as she told me when a clinton
d-link pictures published older day
deeded asking it could make that
cool my seat will be in peace had set up
be able to the whole world
II I can make portions have it available
but not all of it
here's there are laws out there got
involved in all this law stuff that I
never really thought about
and I was kinda funny hadn't really
thought about privacy that much for
and always just see that everything to
be read by anyone
sir confirmed a mom so I
a setup Wed interface
think internet connection usual not
really you shit
the scene where a month both sides me
that that trains that monkey brains that
net se
me that live and people sergei
check that out got a lot of publicity
from brought
dot com published a story on Thomas back
you know
work together on Brady a description of
what I've been
doing that reinstated inflicting and
with C
is really fun looking to the debates and
sorry I couldn't make all the messages
available to: down
anyone's has a look at that say couple
people
high school sizzle
there where this thing a air
looked through the messages just saw
that some people
you know really looking for other jobs
other one job
people were trying to make up with
girlfriends were getting new girlfriends
some
were getting boyfriends know who were
getting 23 boyfriends
and is just Israel standard
home happens that answer to see neediest
my search for one term a lot of things
came up my father to normal
and is funded with my roommates from my
room in the search for
were one for me thought about it for a
second panties
policy Czech pornstar thima it logs
stuff from
chat windows from microsoft word
document said he never intended to send
over the Internet
you record at everything the deleted
that he's doing and
take something using this for some
things out mister fireworks
he's million on arm and there
a another guy gmail is look at work
politically minded namely what were you
wanna
lookup said thought about it involving
along with my roomie
remains anarchy the search for that
nurses
story about how some teacher it's cute
about this in our key
program has been set up in someplace
Midwest is get big brother material here
me get to see what people are thinking
about in search for other words
home on her credit card number password
you can get off and study itself
that site was up and there's one section
on
there's three there's three things you
can search and search your email address
and if you're infected
it would send you email saying yes you
are infected
if you were infected with the same want
it all arm it first I had the results
published on the sale Aki
pretty you know my friend that some
other ISP Telecom
and it's a yes or no but um it turned
out that
the FBI suggested to me that have bad
idea to publish that information is
reviewing
was indeed beats by giving a positive or
negative to change it around 10 a k-8 is
richard is
if you're in fact you get the email
denied long so
supposedly eighty putting your own email
address only Eugene receive the email
and if you put your friend's email in
while 10
you don't know infected or not says the
first for the database the second part
was the passwords
ET quitting arm any search string
wonderfully
and only Microsoft get out
anything that had to do with the
Microsoft haha safe passage
that perhaps Corey to put in on dot
dozen
to find out of Kansas cool passers
record States
you clean porn get policy porno say
batteries 1 today TFTP defined
difference a said
FTP access tees and said is became
a is came over to stir in the security
security focus
a got email from
actually he first happened is comfy pair
K as he was from earlier the company the
they provide security for a lot of the
company's
in the US like that the nasdaq online
forward
a Motorola are Adam
just to name a few the companies in some
smaller ones two years
military stuff like that Alek the couple
military
on web sites the
send email to all their client saying
old use this tool on the web preteen
girl need including
your search string in a lil
Richard overturn the all the different
resources
in it that it has passwords for that I
have passwords for any wood
it would lead to show the resource Lee
HTTP dot
don't give W dot for dot com slash
members in its a username and password
lately he'll use change passwords into
schemes
stream username/password on and my own
personal version research and find out
what
people's real pastors are kinda fun to
see that has patterns to
again TT really simple things see the
surprise team here ship down
still the company could go look for the
putting their third company name the
get back forty eight hits in the unique
resources different your article on a
safe haven unique
you going to go to website a window pops
up this is putting your password missus
this is for members only or this is for
Ford customers for this is for
you no doubt chemical product a partners
something like that and so they could
see all the passwords a
the number passes I had indeed the week
email your request immediate
made up some rules iran denies funeral
kiss from people don't have enough peace
at your domain dot com
says the only person I send the results
to be there abuse address
it for two reasons one I i wonder what
happened he said
this number two is the only way that I
can ensure that
the deal would fall into the wrong hands
leaky ideally Lister
a username and passwords say on Joe
Smith
at home yeah I dot com berkeley can
claim to be this is Adnan free after
that I'll probably get in trouble
serve added meal somewhere reliable
Senate today
use address and down that went fine
after about 30 these requests I realize
wow that's a plus he's coming in is
taking up my time as dean for free site
instituted ten dollars the which is tree
deal to a large company
but I and made them pay with Pay Pal so
they get
interested there's a there's one there's
one company
the at who EP work on the outlook from
whole dollar is
is entertaining to say the least but
this one guy Collins Aquino
work worth a fortune 500 company t know
what that means to you
number nothing you
I work for myself for him and the yeah I
think there's a Hartford
something him through that
eighty-something finances I really
don't give up on those companies um bud
you that that security guy that really
upset that we just give me information 7
you have to set up a hard count me hath
send
ten dollars to believe me monkey brains
out good it I did that for couple
reasons one just to fuck with them
and to I would like to see a system
where
the company's are more willing to give
individuals small transfer money people
talk about my coaching insects all the
time
and how he's be companies want to gather
little piece the money from all the
people what about the the company's
getting little tease the money to all
the people attended the reverse
says the humidity can be cool if %uh
more people
serve a handle called blackmail humanity
blackmailed the company's really do for
smaller see you at ten dollars and i
cant wasted time seeing you again
any legal department I think a lot of
that admits she's paid out their own
pocket
he made them think about itself that
that was
you know there's a word for me I hate
other people
thinking about something that I had
thought about said the fucking
a at and
answer that I did that views in the ATP
house
and and a couple it raises some people
only
by I have a DSL connections speakeasy
done and they're creepy
you once desire sir
their smaller companies are smaller than
pactel or a rise in the world
so there the little we try hard company
arm itself ni there at me and gave me a
free month
extension pacifism that's akin to you
and then a
playboy said meaty issues in playboy I
perot's a little that I'll
is kinda good deal say I had another
website without the employer
called the first wins that hong which
focuses on the activities and Jenna and
Barbara Bush
I and the written up but this guy mark
brown
from father writes articles for a plate
way every now and then
uses and Apple commercial by the way to
his phone
used the editor it liar but any help
you've written a story about the first
team to comedy night didn't
know that so they had to flee police
today usually don't purchase
ET partners would say about that scene
first to answer it is
see to get here protect less
the site Lee check this out in the end I
changed it from being free to ten
dollars with known as looking
in and security focus on route namely is
something blackmail
this through some stuff in II are
applied to
the thread in the I don't think they put
my message up thread Sinclair
political moderated they didn't like my
spots CNN commercial
and then something else in Jersey happen
to punch a really interesting things
happen from this
that ranch project thing playboy's screw
the company's peep outside if these
micelles
a go figure I
i think im it and that 1880s 400 bucks
is something I don't know
something pretty trivial 10 team at a
time
the end with clean margin be didn't
cover my costs that wasn't
decal the om but ppl
a froze my account because someone
decided
hey I have keystroke logging data to I
think
seles on as they get done it was be
party leaders is you in town yet getting
can laugh at it
um someone that had a bunch of passwords
for peacock house the holding on to you
the
transferred money illegally into my
peapod count instead in a ten dollar
about their
week hundred-dollar charts in fact a
whole bunch of money for a while
as as happened real fast should it take
it all out
just attended no never had this think
heat transfer to my bank account easy 24
hours forty-ones can figure it out
it took me two weeks to increase my town
so has
may back balance among peep out how and
I really want to take money out there
decided
that money's not worth going to jail for
so I didn't do it I left the money in
there
Picasa is Mike and I couldn't accept any
money from other people
I lost no tenzin ten dollars so
at least a hundred armed tense
you is that setting but and
the week a couple the pick-up people
email Katie some money came outta my Cal
and
arm when and here's why
I don't know I think there some someone
out there that has your passage
changes him and added
injury funny one person mainly in that I
realized what I keep doing this
they're gonna get my refund in whole
system he gets screwed up
in their gonna ask for refund again from
p-town they're gonna get double refund
inside the city
yet the email a house in P how's mealy
release loaded except the Eagles don't
think they said the most gifted use went
these
facing in no one will really response he
personally is always from engineer
account heat at llanview
any deals a large company known Nissan
in issue on a personal level them
yeah allocate have a lot of companies
Lee
when a problem comes in someone she that
that has to be devoted to solid namely
harm
it Tom shitty alright I want product com
I take here
one for the complaints only deals that
person it doesn't like the chainsaw
army today photo I got from South
America
if he takes off her masaje but
so Thompson di love it when the person
race back should be a little
system said every gets all a minute when
he's done it that
the next message goes to someone else
Lee weeds and then weeds deals with the
that whatever the next problems that
child swallowed by the sneaking settled
near
somewhere there's a BK major a
it
see the a annette then a
I'd hold the the FBI that I i wouldn't
give them the data on this you know that
you got a court order
or um that they somehow had the judicial
branch arm stepping in
you don't have the same as the my head
executive judicial branch checks
balances term in all the stuff in high
school
and he just said coincide and I guess I
was about two weeks ago in the New York
Times is this
charter on their homeland security front
how they want to reorganize it near
all these little three-letter acronyms
and how it all arranged in
in was he that that's legal but
it turns out the FBI's rate below the
judicial branch
and didn't think that investigation
Federal Bureau of Investigation so of
course the
coarser indium whatever they want um so
the FBI came game you're looking at is
it is for guys
instance she in a black SUV
is so predictable a
II poll in my car in people in behind me
in with I don't know if he can fall on
your way
but if they went down the block to a to
another warehouse sale is a
I work in this area with a buncha
warehouses and a
as appears in a couple different ones
they wanted a different one
like this case the within the
neighborhood but I was in a hurry
there's a server down in the
know the data centers as running to grab
my laptop to go back out and
um here 31 Mb
don't back down my stairs cell phone
dreams is my friend deeply keepers
really here I look down the stairs
by one of my roommates is just leaving
issues like blocking the door at stake
into the glass door I don't know he's
here she looks at that makes delight
well I was expecting them to come so
was a plane running at this point a I
knew and you that they're going to come
and do only had windows on the second
floor there wasn't partner on
them um so I I went and said hi
I was really scared for says shaking for
about 30 seconds
kill me global
bit that I calm down and arm and then we
had a little chat
in out for a ride in the SUV and that
not at the table
talked about then
and um
we went to the data center
I got to work on the computer that was
down the healthy
good a I shoulda
detecting it there is one guy
at um there's four guys if one big burly
guy
is like the muscle then there is a then
there's a quiet guy didn't say anything
the whole time I get back to him
then this guy did all the talking he's
the ringleader and then there is the
asian guy use the tape I Alistair take
here but that's just the way it works
out
yeah he wears black suits the techies
are Asian
on yeah they're you
and he's fun
you get to write an SUV um nearly all
say only people that to the
to the data center cuz a someone
apparently
keep their SUV you out there do I have
had a lot of neighbors that look out for
me
the stupid but I I don't know what
happened I think the
bond in the sum construction on the way
there's a lot of construction sales guys
are really bad
I don't really think it is a key good
at all for it they threaten me
and they didn't need to I was scared
gold
are that I was like unholy scared I
wasn't kissing myself skew
but I'll after 30 seconds a calm down
this is located not gonna kill me they
probably would have already done that
you just here to talk to me in is gonna
be Kong
it actually is is finally answer to
drive over the data center
which sister for miles from my house
from where the inward
we chatted about the date at Fulham I'll
think he catches hapless
in well eating shit okay you
at all my reason rationale that then
D-day is its private
Easter stuff people all around the world
from the US
in is not stuff that people intended
other people remain special ago
it's like a on and do it well you know
it might help us catch the culprit well
i DD IP addresses signed up for the
for the remainder for their emailing
for the free Elise thing and the email
faucet is gone it is gone to some yahoo
account %uh this is something else you
out to get DS hardware tech detail you
like that who
as okay
I'll mmm you them
at all no comment
yes dark
and the I'll
the said all he knew that the mailing
stuff that's in a different
my Siebel database examples get right
customers
so that you can have free email
addresses on your
on on your with the host a website with
me every 200 website
something that occurs 1850 at only check
really that it is believe the tech and
arm
text a witness the TV side I'm
his this guy its cosmos to one minute
arm
a race the record I'm gonna go today S
email
file put in it Haley is so that sucked
my pictures today
S&P mail spool file the necessary click
Hollister really cool
and suddenly it stopped showing up on a
quiet spot is we're gonna
their own team nor update don't think so
Hilton
so in fact I turned on the charm I
turned on the
collection totally alone
turned turn back on the collection data
before
HD que se to get fresh pack a good stuff
really three days I got half a game or
emails dissect look three finding
patterns to talk about
at least seven patrons that any outside
i reset
that email address and thence someone
back to the free email thing inside of
the sock my pic added
suck my prick alias again in a bit
different mailbox
City the any they got and then I went in
I
Texas so that they can do that again
change occurred a little
but I'll so I had to be a mailbox is
where the
a the worm data had been going to give
this the FBI
TI no problem with helping out as much
as I think I should help
K a if anyone here has a run with the
FBI
you know try to follow the law I mean
you want to be in jail
on a no 8 and I thought maybe the law
provision for privacy no
there's no threats none
no nothing like that really
it he said they sent me at a document in
the mail
I'm not get a what it was and i suppose
im and there's a little close in on it
say it was a sign that is a funny joke
design Big Brother then contact the
editor and
hahaha and that and as but that was
kinda funny but at the same health care
that it said
it's a as I turned off the alias I got a
got that stuff back are past this
oh that the program that does a free
email revealing watches the mail on
there's more than and in 15 minutes it
shows that user of them
it is more than X in an hour chase them
off as well so Israel
throttles this free service I don't you
will then take
binge in it for were data collection or
for
that's been in people's really heats are
at sea
it dumped into a file for me to see it's
a spam or not it's a standard practice
by is
these down that's why I am was able to
click this deal legally
on if you it is part of your standard
operations to collect things that go
awry
then you're entitled to look at it if
are if you
log on to someone else if you log on to
your router watch other peoples traffic
you can't legally
study that data but if he comes here
a its computer is a natural part of your
services
then you're allowed to do whatever you
want with it only oh the quiet time
yeah he is weird the anti theories about
the quiet
picturing that a use either this
colleges the is really watching things
to you watch my reactions and stuff
ciskei thats what's up with the disease
threat
worries the treaty and highly I leave me
about this guy
he did say he was your dream girl with
the the guy who's making the decision
when you gonna come see you next week
that cut as defined as to how that year
the fourth party along with them with
the
the end of the month the muscle guys he
he he
the All England think I didn't really
see bolger's but I wasn't looking
they had a look in football jersey guys
okay a
up on
let's see I'll here's something else
interesting I search for
bad genes in the best its database and
there's thousands a result in people
email each other I had this horrible
virus
were Trojan horse log thing in
you probably got infected but I i got
really don't worry about it
could and
I just checked the last week we're still
hoping the same thing
um people are by large siller
price he scares arm kohut workers to
teach
lots to talk about that guy bemused
fortune 500 guy
and that the FBI are not super humans a
I don't know their tech he wasn't
brilliant home he's having a hard time
getting
at that connection my server even though
sister wire from his laptop
by Sir a good I
granted I can't get a connection here
but you know the
a he is getting really sleuth you please
if you had get it brought on by
year 2012 use it. I'm using had my
laptop their tune in
publicly of são gun that his computer
is very slow
and I copied the same database arm just
to show that I could do it fast
it's the
I wonder anti-gay too much more to say
let me tell you think maybe to wrap up a
friendly questions %uh
home them okay 10 questions
he got the bike to vote or even just
yell out if he allowed
yes the OS two
on the techies laptop with some version
of Linux I was running FreeBSD
the a Aki help us out take that
or to sail out it was said always a
Chinese
FBI yeah I did a little background check
in your phone number to check that other
website at Baxter I'll
also a was a good question you know
ever dress anything anyone tells you
especially if they're taking away in a
vehicle
a yeah
oh yeah I'll take a web-enabled PC
up the little devil in the database I
keep getting this secret message that
the
they've made it really hard to do before
we actually do from home if I can get
this one are like
SS-eighteen but not at the difference on
us box other that there's something else
about it
a whole buncha people try to hack into
my boxes but the lodge
they're doing all these really cool SQL
cleary
manipulation in there in them in the
query string a
and in fact that there's one guy is as
watching the laws is starting to make
progress I did change likely
thought the whole they stop them before
you got it little bit
you so real time
auditing last seen from the terminal is
a good thing the
a
I had a good day said anyways
a and they are
end I want you to give me a lift today
yeah I would re: identify and shit what
does ATT travel card i'm following me in
my car sucks 7 all VW Bug
hey there plush leather seats that may
not be a picture be up in the front seat
is kinda cool a
with them the picture is from the big
party at a local
a weekly in San Francisco that there'd
been an article on
a me withholding the data from the FBI
the previous week a
the a copy of that article in your car
good
yesterday thanks
yet the you still see here
emails infected you can still within you
the question was is the database of
Katie Cleary
yes he can still carry fractions ovett
but I still can't make all that if a
local
because I might get sued for libel think
if anyone's a really good lawyer out
there they wanted to set me up with it
all up
whatever but I am a my understanding is
that I can't miss all the data
out there is your are you court cases
that have happened that would get me in
trouble if I couldn't publish the user
names for those URL's it had been
arm compromise a because it happened
accesskey you need a username and
password if you publish half you can go
to jail
cited published either happily published
the
publicly available arm resources at
work had been compromised in other words
the URL's
or whatever game we go in there and you
can like
see how the different sites get half to
get within
late dog can see it all the thoughts ace
had been broken into
him play in like all I wonder were kinda
people get worms is it the kind of
people that look at Bordeaux
yeah it is see mid-morning to delete the
most results
in the league but in like I don't know
something even its security focusing you
wouldn't get any results
the million about God you get more
results
so you know that no
TN these sample up there II wanna show
you back to you
media that is is that laptop working the
well just give it you know why this
evening really quickly get onto my
server
in change the IPS allowed a dusty
any for a little while it
my wireless card isn't working here so I
need a are you fix wireless
see I don't think I got external think
looted upgrade
this
this say
a
neighborhood why did these guys by
yeah funny three-legged that the secret
service guy Haiti
article apparently they look like
football players political
they don't mess around a and City
seizures guys came in I was around
over twenty it was a sad the street cool
let's was so that that the TC pictures
guys came the not
and I've known as their cities that the
car under the door this it please call
and then that they're walking out one
where there is a really I
is that month is monkey brains locating
here is accordingly for greedy in like
yeah
which is less than you think I I don't
know hah
in it's good that deliver them
neighboring were
people are just are paranoid their
know you know dot dot dot do he said yet
that trustee
much lot leaders there too
a little scrap metal mecca
mom
see any interesting to come up healthy
and do the best
I wanted to show you guys but I could
get the connection to work on the second
floor
network to sucks me hackers I
so I have a S l's L certificate rejected
its not a
one that 84 some people got really upset
like what's his certificate is not valid
don't use it then hey a
this is the version where you yet
see the good stuff at this is a talented
sheen some crazy
it's not working
like probably need to restart the
machine or something
has anyone else gotten in there can they
be started from I
I keep waiting for someone to break in
good there's the easy way the heart is
so years like that that means we're got
written about in the register
somewhere in England I don't know and
the camp where you dey
leadbelly well here's the
here's article about up know it's gone
hit
I'll people
is the prime time
getting God
%uh the secret service these want to
talk about I'll why is ready to say that
focused and Jenna barbara Bush today the
love that is interested
see let's look at that same dot this
text a this is taken it certainly is a
cultural hack yeah here and play them
love it avid stalker
p.m. call
got do
I could talk for I can talk for about
five hours on this time
training upon
figure
a whole lot I
other show the pictures I can't of it
read everything and
okay so this picture started it all or
diverging from Badrinath
learns to arm Allison adolescent
drinking
here here's a Jetta at a frat party
like this is get published in the
national choir com
that see the end of 1999
you can buy father cut this out
emailed it to her he's nailed it to me
and I saw his picture and I like get
Mississippi
what is great web sites everyone emails
around each other
check out this site that I saw and I've
always want to make love this
pockets eight sites all this heavily
this CD
by idea to take a whole sated dedicated
to watching every move the president's
daughters
a do insure know who this guy who
typically
month yeah their agenda
she's is pitcher is magnificent their
cigarettes in here
dropping off JK good time
a severe this not getting still and
these other people watching drinking
beer at a beach in jars
a I'm not from Texas I don't understand
tonight and is that enough said that
started at
and their there they are at the
know that's the republican convention
believe on 30
things families this big back in
high school you she is with her high
precision article happens
people thought those beads for sexy me
who she is dancing at they have reached
a ball
don't know if you get a better read the
news but
her dress slipped down a little bit well
she's dancing with her father
are present I'm a
here's whatever play friends he got
get trouble for be to drop the sea with
cancel on
okay Jenna Bush play friendly bridges
has three sheets to the wind it got put
in the slammer for four hours
a yep with
oh you something else fun
huh agenda bar on Hot or Not in people
are
got to rate them and a
it's funny that their photos ended up at
hot or not I don't know.
I maybe they're reading themselves I
didn't do it
that a
he I don't need two ish if you know
lets the the let me go to the hotter
hotlink that's kinda cool
and it has anyone here raise your hand
if you don't hot or not
behaviour as anyone like entered their
pitcher God
got raided I
did was messing up I got a 10
a okay so
here the file a ratings like they give
you his bar chart that shows you
how did you look to the world this
chemical cultural phenomena
and whenever something comes up like
this and try to incorporate it into the
first win say
a in some way in so and I i think these
pictures cuz
around it in the news me USA Jenna
looked ibid I didn't think the sad
someone pick these a because
general is a lot hotter in the media
in the I figured if I got d if they're
two pictures up there
and one ways you know a woman alone one
was a
was someone else at this one week at a
higher rating Barbara this was bar right
here
if you go to this bar refugees the ill
this is Jenna chiggers the University of
Texas
Austin or something and so barber got a
higher reading here although previously
all the news had said that
agenda was the hot one so I wanted it
little spin on the media
and I succeeded it's really easy to
manipulate the media
something he had this there's media
hacking is fun
I get I wrote that that they got in
trouble for drinking at a bar and I said
that their
drinking margaritas at Nasher it is a
Mexican bar and then I saw it in the
news somewhere else at their drinking
margaritas that skinny
chuckle lets the they are
was gonna here so here's a fake ID
pitcher
in then I got interest in Slashdot
could that's good for a while Halfpenny
their back into the convo
Lee which which one is Geno which one is
barbara
left with great win you can click here
okay
holly body bull holy I statutes those
eat them people on that one
show that in any good at that
outside it back in in you can see that
how people are voting and I i just want
to do this
have my kids he left for the screen I'll
on
I just wanted to you
as when he's a slacker softer as I
thought it'd be fun to try out
yeah it was fun but it's too complicated
for me and I disturbed everything out
except for the bones of Torino
means that cecile services want to say
hi
actually only talk to them on the phone
it never got to me in person has had a
bomb
but I'm sure now meet in person for
talking about public
news10 at a bar LA shit
injured internship last summer on into
an hour drink again
public to Georgetown's Desme see
here said with I am talk magazine did a
fashion
she with some models that would be
religion of our rental is being legally
George W because they're needed really
go to jail
it's got tickets the absurd reenacted
going to jail scene
and um I think someone sensor Talk
Magazine after that like born every
minute
have any news about talk be again its
crazy how our country reacts to things
political things here's a picture or
something
with the sightseeing he Jenna and
Barbara
any similarities Clinton OH
she there's a
agenda re thank you for such a short
some
cash because it because I start to make
light in days
size our corporate tempted branches out
there Lauren Bush
currently here's a Lauren Bush it at
Tommy Hilfiger bed sheet
arm there's no well as she got busted
for CNS
said a this I get shot
but it people take that activity ecstasy
because they get to press
in for girl at be Press two
my family so fun a
on way
II show one last thing and then harsh
yes finisher face looked really good
thing then on
the funny story about this too
everything surlis together we
he worked on a project anyone have fun
is try to think more ways to incorporate
things like my
my friend Karen low does some remote
control robotics stuff for
SRL on break this Facebook birthing
and I and she had a daughter say insight
I stole the
about java file that she left up there
teach a little
including the different people that I
wanted death
faces stop
jobless work on his laptop very well
look
clicking nothing happens okay athlete
adults rules but anyways
that as fun tissue she lost her short
skirt for a little while but I take
officer is that they will give it back
yeah
if he did a keep backups
it any last questions right there
yeah is what a comment about pay how it
may have been just incompetence why I
got messed up
as I have paid Callahan on and they
screwed up so badly I
rule of got my own merchant account yeah
I didn't really wanna type merchant
account
dubious activities too close to home
good
Pay Pal better for launder money good
or so I've been told here II
policy I've got some the rotten a
mask hats yeah
there's a article about the FBI once
were
call for data cool I
a
I had some rotten that car back for
in
K
handouts I also have some plucky Braves
t-shirts but I had to pay for these
at eighty-seven pockets a month it cost
me seven dollars each
in the 50 deal I'll have it and 711
you want to support me and what I do
scheme
five dollars yeah I S takers
or EC potentially
tenure security
a
up
well you