up
I wanna thank God tom is i com were
could be here for coming up with the
idea for the spam
yes top it's primarily about how to
extend our
limited senses to be able to see and
hear things in the Nam
can around us and waterways
to do that some legal some not so labels
discussions for I educational purposes
only
our a letter other voted against
themselves
and we can start the hacking the
invisible world
one
K
I
founders respective Leiser like to
explore what's actually happening around
and sometimes you're running real
interesting
there's a
there's a whole lot of stuff going on
around is it isn't immediately apparent
and that's all falls under what's called
the
electromagnetic spectrum basically
everything you see here
and radio is a is a traveling through
the air obviously
and it's a different frequencies what
you see on that on the chart here
United States frequency allocations
the Department of Commerce in this
country
a regulating dictates who can who can
use what frequencies for what purposes
and this goes all the way from very very
low frequencies which
are sometimes used by submarines for
communicating
to their home base a way up to
light frequencies and frequencies are
well above visible light so we're gonna
we're gonna cover the gamut from a from
the left to
to be online like x-rays
microwaves thats or anything I I
I'm I'll probably start are in order of
frequency
I guess it seems to make more sense
wanna start at the high end ago downer
bottom-up or already there
3 can you scan the left a letter to the
beginning a
making it the left frequencies
I don't use that sorry
barrier from your experiences monitoring
I know you're you're a fan of the higher
frequencies
but a what a what extremely low
he left for the love frequencies
applications have you
come across well not
lots inside don't like to listen 30
makers
okay I i listen to navigational beacons
Witcher airport be considered broadcast
their
there are 3 letter airport designation
like JFK
in Morse code and it's a pretty
interesting these beacons up from
from all over the country because the
long-range travel a long distance
and it's pretty challenging because it
is very low frequencies your intent is
have to be
miles very very long you have to have a
resident in a bit helps
and we're talking the wavelength
literally miles
miles long particularly helpful for
submarines to
communicate because their underwater and
just because the way the frequencies
hey it's useful for getting getting
messages
suffering director they don't want and
locate the left frequencies a little bit
higher
go up to
under one megahertz about under
1,000,000 cycles per second
and then we go to medium wave
frequencies which everybody hears you
know you're with
medium wave often he referred to as a
a.m. AM radio band
broadcast band like a 1010 wins for
instance is about one
1 maker 1000 sorry one
killer 1000 hello 1,010 killers
which is a 1.01 megahertz and
help everybody listens to that more less
about that you can have the HR
frequencies which
gently go from about 3 to 30 megahertz
and there's a CB radios in their insurer
wave radio is in there
we get a couple panel discussions
including shortwave and a
we brought along a couple examples over
abuses shortwave
a respecter to bring her I can be a okay
well we have a a are you ready player
radio 1 at ten o'clock this morning
proposal walk in I I did have several
transmitters down there
buddies library operations and I do have
one year it's called a grenade
its a.m. transmitters or 10 what's
carrier
and will swing up for you what's several
local player several players use Caesars
control
its crystal controlled
only portable jail cell battery keep
projector yup pretty a pretty unassuming
box really
yes there is made by John about you
radio animal
said left radio Bobby really a
breadboard version in nineteen forties
to
transmitter year converted everything
over to solid-state
to protect his is working file all the
all the designators on all the
chips G everything inside everything she
can even
your yourself they're fun to play with
and share with
things there shortwave I play around
with their also
Oracle's by numbers stations is there
I'll army agencies from around the world
coated spy stations which are repeated
group numbers which are Inc co like the
number yep
or later group and the make up their
best
like that wheels a play around with them
you lower your
lot of people here obviously familiar
Rekha retiree
and that's a that's prolly want all
these uses a
cryptography in in
no in this century is a is a tripped
over
over shortwave that intelligent changes
around the world continue to use
short-wave is a
as a medium forgetting 50 messages to
their operatives in various countries
you can hear these messages anywhere
between three and three megahertz on a
standard sure we're at. with the cost
anywhere from
fifty dollars on up and in the coming
year Eagles hear these
5 five-member group being rate of you
we're going to try to hook up some
audience played
I'm sure in we can do that but in any
case at
its it's done with a like a one-time pad
encryption scheme he changes every day
and know is going to be cryptic because
it's a to new key every day
there's government agencies that the BSA
chris is a a the actually try to now
analyzes messages affair with what this
other countries sending to where's
we play around with that as well we
creator all and throw them on the years
famous on a US attention 69 which is a
I think version of the Spanish attention
numbers station which is all
by letters five numbers station in
Spanish
attention 69 you play right afterwards
or
in that time slot work normally appears
at a higher power level
just really is a keep them busy is
this particular transmitters only about
10 widespread it has reached
listeners about 500 miles away in
different directions
so it's a pretty surprising how much she
accomplish is a good book you can
you can if you wanna learn more about
your way passport the world band radio
highly recommended I think we ever gave
away this book
on off the hook its premium last year
and a it's a for Ethernet for 500 pages
going detail shortwave radio stations
around the world broadcast stations
usually stations which are intended for
private people listen to their like
governments communicating
that sort of thing butter there's a lot
of books on the subject here's a book
called the underground for 20 guide
you can do a search on the web for
keyword enigma
and the Finder to a group of people who
monitor these unusual short wave signals
and try to discover the origin
purvis your in numbers gathering
mathematical a now up to the VHF
frequencies which are commonly used by
paging companies and
police other starting move up in
frequency his band
dodge which is really late you operate
your Julia you know business
I complete dispatch taxicabs my use VHF
on amateur radio operators have the to
meet her hand and which is from 140 4140
e
makers in this country you can
here's an example other the receiver
it's capable tuning VHF frequencies all
the way up to
UHF frequencies
this is a JC the R five hundred about
the size of a pack of cigarettes
and fit easily in your pocket in Italy
receiver
all the way up to thirteen hundred
megahertz there's a VHF frequency and
there's the SPCA
other New York miss you dog catcher its
near prison frequencies breakers so
forth one is thing about this radio is a
despite its low price a couple hundred
dollars
you can interfacing with the your PC and
in tears when is offering
42 I'm sorry a max offering your fortune
which is free
and you can Swofford files with people
around
around the world in if you're in the
traveling somewhere you can is down low
frequencies and have the program
restores a thousand this a
these frequencies are New York ariane
yet our item from a friend in
put them in there so was up here it was
going on around us
bear you starting getting here from your
specialities frequency range is a
UHF on up when you starts planning a
kinda stuff you are you here in Europe
UHF in about in the Netherlands
police use eighty maker which is really
low
people here even receive
because in the scanners full you can't
even receive
makers she was 30 makers and then again
and
going higher but in the Netherlands
police uses up till now
clear voice analog signaling
makers it's also because the Netherlands
is flat
makers makes perfect for
range communication between brings
but there now covering when Europe is
getting United
making digital system cool date
actually two systems and
its digitally scramble
communication network as
properties close the frequency hopping
it's not ones that general they're
really making work
people listening to police
communications getting that out of the
way
even for normal
police communications business that I
think should be open to the public
and
that's what's going on in and around the
Netherlands
this moment what are your feelings a you
just surtax on
your feelings regarding at the open is a
over to a radio communications very
I know in this country and Latta 14 said
she specialises in several events are
moving towards it
making their transmissions digital Spurs
analog and a
encrypting them as shit we as citizens
various countries pay for the systems
and pay for the salaries in
the agency's operating them you feel
their
what you feelin should be between what
should be
which would be legally heard by citizens
and
what you get private world the way used
my
radio gear after the September 11 fans
because
really freak me this thing drove me
slide oh my god you know
the world is not safe anymore and
whenever I heard a big bang or something
I just under my skin
listen to what's going on okay some car
crashed
trio that's all sold for me it is also a
tape backup
keeping close to come back what's going
on
and want it all and you can't receive it
anymore
I think will be a losing what's going on
around you
and personally I think that's really a
bad thing
of course I understand there's some
special ops that
people don't listen supposed to listen
to
because its technical information but
for
for the plainclothes police going to
rescue a cat that symmetry
I don't think that you okay
up obviously if you wanna listen to
something is on the year on the airwaves
you you know what frequencies on
and sometimes you can have an idea
generation Juve
frequencies you know the particular
mugging and tenor something you can tell
from the link to that its
rough way to Lincoln and get an idea for
what frequency band might be and if
you're looking for the exact frequency
wanna find it you can use a device
called the frequency counter
and we have one here think you go into
the studio
very the same model yeah I'd I didn't
dare to bring it with me
have problems with the pics in the
locked already so I left all my skin
years alone but I have this exact model
and have a special moment in my car I
just clip it in
and when I Drive through the city the
country
everything that surround me in a few
meters
I don't the art but anyway anything
that's that's
most people in line of sight in the
streets if something is communicating
most the time
the counter was just catch it grab it
and make a little alert
and though the frequency with the punch
it up into my scanner and listen to it
up here
here skaters says that
who make have a second later to
our skaters policy there problem
sometimes is that
exactly it says its on 170 .5
by 72 management 550 and you get a
little
spin around catching if you don't have
the cable
reaction June you get real fast in
typing even if you're driving high speed
getting some it's certainly having a
sick sense he
you can be walking around a driving
around and whenever the a
whenever the the frequency counter to
textarea frequency you can learn
we divide the poor vibrator the singer
wearing your you're sure
feel that there's some radio activity
going around you
and you can put that equity in your
scanner in here what's going on
I its particularly useful if you're
driving around
there's a no prisons a police car nearby
it will even if they're using encrypt
communications
long we'll hear them but you will detect
their presence
if they're on the radio this Sat this
counter right now is showing UHF
frequency
that was stored in earlier by I think
transmit hopefully the demonstration
that could be why a battery my
he went to show closed
captain
maybe in
okay can't
either its doing free-floating
make you push yes present is here
area this is stepping through
frequencies its log recently there's a
sailor frequency
another sailor frequency television
frequency another sailor frequency so
apparently the lotto sale if entry
operator uranium I understand that
you're not allowed to listen
I you're not allowed to in this country
but def it it's not illegal to
to know that the frequency is being used
around you so frequency counter can can
pick up the frequencies but it won't be
modulated much you hear them
up back in eighty six and
Congress passed a lot making it a crime
to listen to certain radio frequencies
kinda strange laws like now being look
at certain college
light or something on this post and free
I'm sorry the land of the free land of
the free
to those who have enough money to
persuade Congress to
get your your wishes but but a
I'm just teasing beginner you can
purchase radios that are capable uva
receiving a
frequencies and outside in
in the Forbidden range they can be
ordered like a model
version at this rate it can be a can be
ordered from
outside the US from Canada from UK from
finland
now and the Netherlands that's right I
for to some hundred dollars and it would
like you here
sale if it means however most alias now
is digital
and I got this error Sounders deal
noisier
nothing at all but according quite a few
quite a few were
phones will will fall of the digital
network because it is a member so poorly
designed
you Roman to an allotment and
than you you can listen to those cause
if you want but frankly pretty boring
and nighter not all that interesting as
interesting as a soap opera
and some of the scanner you can just
open it up
find the right jumpers or notes you can
you you can find two months on the net
he might have the case is very famous
for this
that secretary-general won an asset or
URL again
mods a emo DS dot DK
from Denmark and a half
modifications on all types of scanners
transmitters
everything also for extending range
extending power
have a debit to a lot of it's really
place where look isn't always collect
and I use it all the time
by radio most of the time there some
modification to
let it scan fast
do more channels things
your people ordering pizza ordering
card numbers the air as
Voice realize voicemail password says
everything exact this
is a transmitter as a radio address sell
for
they sell cellular radio
actually here
towered here no
the list whatever you want
there's actually a radio
3 wide
shows this
here
so there's no laws against that again as
Youkilis
okay mechanic okay well
you don't your how about listening to
these
portable telephones that people have in
the house
that was a that was cheered would change
little bit later it was
it was only listened cellular phones in
but then I think in ninety four another
law was passed making it legal to listen
to
cordless telephones can you have your
house but we're the patient with 92
to a regular ballots online it still
doesn't prevent people from
doing and it's not it's not illegal to
sell
in this country receivers like this
they're capable
receiving cordless telephones free love
them
older ones run the 46 to 49 makers range
and then there's the the newer part not
even knew them
cordless phones in the 900 megahertz
range from about 90 29 28 megahertz
and as the 2.4 gigahertz cordless phones
which are little more secure because
it's difficult to get receivers are as
expensive to get receivers it will tune
up to that high-frequency
but its quite possible on at the most
secure cordless phone you can get would
be one
is digital spread spectrum not just a
tool which
digital sprint spectrum we're signals
are spread over a wide range of
frequencies
and 2.4 gigahertz a sprint spectrum sale
the phone is a little more secure from
from casual eavesdropping then than all
the others however
you know if your adversaries someone
with means
on or legal power behind them
other not even try minor tear through
the air that's gonna
connect to the phone companies which
which is now
mandated under kaliya so on you know you
really have you're concerned private
concerns
you can't do anything about it the
government really machine uses in
in cricket phone conversations and
that's where possums to church 11 panel
came in yesterday
but a as far as cordless phone
conversations if you have an older
cordless phone
I it's not digital get rid of it
you're broadcasting conversation see the
entire neighborhood and
or if you want to take your handset
driver dryer on your car
and turn it on because by Ophelia turn
on somebody else's
receiver be there phone because there's
only 10 frequencies
used on the 47 years back in the air
yeah United States so this whole war
dialing thing going on with the EU
edited at 11 be broke all the year
earlier earlier cordless phones back and
I guess that
late 70's early 80's it was real popular
thing for kids right around the bicycles
where the cars I guess with the cordless
phone handset
and a snack downturns other people's a
cordless base units and it was very easy
to do I go around I
find a budget outlines make calls on the
phone line which
I tried the only time I tried it the the
guy picked up his
I so I had conversations that you know
that my son accidentally picked up your
dial sounds like so
turns out to I listen to the scanner
few minutes later heard in Hollister
erybody any complaints and taking this
thing
back to the store so a 11 trick I did a
on on a neighbor few years ago was a
overheard as partners phone
conversations performs a legal
had and he was talking to his mother i
think im trying to think of somewhere I
can remember
myself what it was but it's just trying
to think of some word and
he could think of it and I'm
I knew was agitated know is found in
with but I had a reverse directory
Charlotte up his phone number
and while he was on the phone I called
him a call waiting answer the fan
and all it is I said that word and he's
like I'll and he hung up
and then animals as long pause
and is like mom he just said
other or whatever the word wasn't and
then they just aren't happy conversation
like
has a possible what what was that so a
I mean I was trying to help a guy out
but a probably
probably gave him something to think
about for a while yet you're sitting in
your car
into some guys driveway and listen to
him ya going on the phone to iOS
is d whatever here's a
there's this guide into my driveway ices
drive away don't don't hang in CE
listen to him call the police on you
because just doctor
don't don't rail
course fish fish list doc steam decide
to
besides it's ever been just talking
about there's a there's other singles
out there they're
I'll higher frequency here zia
there's a device cutting have
special-purpose
here
this is an icon are three came out a
couple years ago
it's a handheld scanner but it also has
a video screen on
and to a TV station right now
but one of the things about this is this
goes up to that too
twenty-five hundred megahertz so prolly
bout
everybody who's been on the on been on
the web has had these damn pop-up ads
for extend a calmness or home
home video cameras how many how many
have seen the zapata as for x10
corporation Wow okay yeah they're quite
annoying I think they're
probably one of the biggest abusers in
this whole pop-up window advertising
methodology but anyway what their
with their products dealer would love
the product there was a transmit video
and audio over a wireless
connection radio connection it around
the 2.4 gigahertz band which is
unlicensed
as is its practicing roughly same
frequencies 802 9/ 11
the transceivers use so anyway the
intended to come to the are
are three really is not suitable for
this really high frequencies in fact
that works better with out that antenna
district it is but if you really want to
work find these things
this a isn't any here
you might have seen SM word were driving
Thai people use in this here's a and
2.4 gigahertz gain antenna
probably got nine or 10 dB gain which is
quite a bit
and highly directional so you can a
you drive around a walk down the street
in a want this thing it different houses
and see if there's any wireless video
equipment operating in their home
and you can actually see on the screen I
A twice I've been able to
to my neighbors cameras I
on in their home you can see what's
going on in their home because they have
it set up a one person has said it was
just defeat the
video from from a a VCR to another room
said
I could watches movies and the other
person had it said set up in there
at the front door actually stairwell
going up to their
Martin so I could see when someone was
coming going so it says this this
extends stuff is a
hardly secure basically what you're
buying one of these cams mixed n
you're setting up a militia TV station
broadcasting what's going on
in your home or wherever to to your
neighbors and if they have the equipment
to do that they can
they can watch what you doing in a you
you might want to be selective about
where you put one of these things
sales people realize how far some the
signals travel as well
for example the call Corliss telephones
on telephones the broadcaster half-mile
circle around your house
driving around within half a mile
hear somebody you know they're within
with it
well sir the countryside for we're
definitely getting into
berries area expertise which is the
microwave frequencies
so well in in Europe I can touch in with
with being used here in this country
better
in Europe whatcha these frequencies
above us above 700 megahertz being used
for
this 2.4 is really want the most
interesting
bans especially for while driving
with 211 in
freezes in the Netherlands prostitution
is legal so we have red light district
and
they're pretty phone securing their
places
with these wireless cameras if you are
driving around the red light district
is like having a XXX rated radio
re speak next time I go there very out
to bring my aren't really
but was almost more exciting than
the red light district is that the
police helicopters
in the Netherlands used the same
frequencies about
for for putting up on the the helicopter
images
when this right and stuff and you can
see firsthand
people throwing bricks at the cops this
and there's a guy named Schelling and
you recorded all these defense with this
yup and which
online how would I would be fine
tractors and I'd like to
I'd like to watch when there's and
nowadays I think he did it for like a
small
year was recording all these things and
putting them online
with funny picked and now they're just
trying to scramble
most things especially when SWAT teams
are involved
and kidnap situation real heavy stuff
scrambled immediately sometimes it's
still unclear
and you can see pretty interesting
things it's a it's done in this country
chile just so happens that
the icon 13 which really only hand-held
scanner dated she defines media on
it was designed to not white girl into
goes up to about 2.45 gigahertz
I to very just slightly above that not
much it on the
no no problem designed to cover the
higher I
are wireless video transmitters made by
a company called
adid audio intelligence devices which is
a division westinghouse which sells a
lot of electronic surveillance equipment
to
federal and state law enforcement
agencies Anderson surprising amount of
the
video unattended video surveillance
equipment
RAM you see cameras around but I'm done
talking about those in talking about
covert cameras that are hidden
in electrical power transformers on
utility poles
he telephone junction boxes along front
lines on telephone poles
or yeah so-called pedestal screen
reno things to seek out the ground about
three feet phone lines are in
take concealed wireless video camera net
I've noticed in philadelphia Ryland
I've got a great view from my office
other the rooftop
the Federal Building in six Market
Street and there's
there's two Mike with antennas on that
roof which are
not sadly engines they are pointed
downward
and every year every couple days their
move to a different position
and I look at things with these things
with binoculars and contacted friend on
the west coast easy sell
Angela force in agencies and he sent me
a a
catalog and describe the company that
makes makes these things and sure enough
and a catalog with these exact same
tennis team stylings
it was it was this company's product so
basically I
from looking at these antennas I could
get a general idea who were
who the Fed Philadelphia were looking at
in which direction I'm looking
with looking Northeast Philadelphia
South Philadelphia that sort of thing
and pretty intriguing I haven't yet
gotten around to getting in line of
sight between one of these intends and
worms pointed
to work to capture the stuff to I have
either committed
wouldn't do that here's a is peaceful
coming here spectrum analyzer that would
actually let you see
fortunately I haven't a camera we can
zoom in on
in two min much on was at
okay and I think we can get around for
this thing is really
anyway with what a spectrum analyzer
Liesel issues
CC bites see spikes in the electric
magnetic spectrum that would indicate a
presence in the signal
and can look at a ranger frequencies and
see a
see were bombs despite signs inspector
this equipment is also used
by people sweeping your office for
transmitters in box this equipment
being used
it raises are shown up
granite is upside down GT ET's bikes
coming from the bottom
but their representative signals on the
spectrum the range on
on the LCD display what frequency range
you looking at
we could find them
this is around 665 666 which we're
trying to find you
difficulty the the wireless microphones
were using here now
explode
if all goes well 641 until June
we operated
this
well anyway
you get the gist up you see the spikes
something sweet near officer but
somebody s your buds
wireless transmission %ah there could be
I just frankly Cesar sees itself and now
amateur bugging
yourself on
it's pretty hard to to find a buyer
these days are so many technologies that
make it and make it difficult there's
spread spectrum there's a there's a
subcarriers that sorta thing
unless you have a something like this
and a lot of patience
it's difficult to find hidden
transmitter
this hidden by professional
okay you and she now here is bytes
and I'll turn wireless mic these
chic
to as a radio signal looks like once you
do find out what it looks like you can
either listen to her play with it such
as
trans air links quickly over this
here girls are gonna touch if you're
debugging a room you want to
with the if you if the room is down
clean you would like if you had when he
sings the
in a weekly or monthly basis he would do
a sweep like this and take
alright fotografia digital storage
spectrum analyzer
store these traces and then compare them
in the future without a trace
see if anything new not done on and
decide on you
and used bike that was in there last
week and you knew you could have
important meeting this week
you would investigate what is this by
work now this is something
should be there it's also common
knowledge when you do
bucks wheaties you go like two miles
from the place where you have to sweep
you make an image what the spectrum
looks like expect you can expect and
when you're at the scene
actually have to sweep you already know
a lot of things that you can just cancel
yet it's gonna be a lot a legitimate
spikes in a local radio stations to a
radio user's
all kinda stuff like that so you gotta
be able to filter the year
just visually the old Italian
which should be there should be there so
having a record what was there before
comparing it with their noses we do it
all
wanna somebody a here at the
the conference here today let me this
this device which is a a
a cell phone jammer they're not legal in
this country edit ordered from the UK
shipped here letter I was kinda
skeptical about this I thought it was
it's so lightweight I thought this is
just a piece of paper where and
to get market looks surprisingly
sophisticated inside put it on the
spectrum analyzer have time to set up
now but I its for about a hundred
megahertz
okay stern's thing this thing
worked it actually a jammed wide noise
generator
people are on the phone now say by
yes I sware
you see that wide range that's a whole
that's a whole like 20 megahertz bread
love
RF he sings are legally just cause
interference headaches
some restaurants churches are
but these things ended preventer
people's phones ringing restaurant
disturbing other people or
if you were to now
this a transmission to the NZ 100
megahertz cell phone band and the 1900
making herself and down in the circuit
races on here were the European version
if they had different components on it
would do the
the European self and frequencies as
well 900 and 1800 right so %uh this is
an intriguing device in after taking
apart ensure their class and
and I looked at it and we rather press
for something was
hundred dollars or something it really
worked up royally gives you may be 104
range
a blocking fans but to
these things can be really dangerous
there's somebody set one up outside your
house and
emergency yourself and yeah I could be a
problem
few hundred feet
okay
yes he was he was very good Jennifer
Lopez movie which is some
someone dragged me to learn she's 12
preventer
ex-husband she planned to kill she cut
the phone lines in the making and house
in
trying to sell them she was stalking him
she had this gem you could make the call
he killed them
but skilled but analysts to the movie
but anyway
she is when he sings in the movie
on I think Craig wanted to mention a
couple of other interesting
certain packing opportunities for
summary for equities
things rigid transmitter links
Austria stations the transmitter
building practical extraordinary
radio station studios and art
interior miles away re:
area studio transfer lease operating 930
makers area
and their white band them so which is
fun to play with because you know their
frequency
and we can take your nap station is by
be
stronger receive signal their
at their studio there
the actual transmitter site said they
have 45 miles away
there serio transmitter link transmitter
which is 10 whites
you are less than a mile away from their
actual transmitter site you have a happy
water transmission transmitter on that
same frequency
you'll be able to take over that radio
station they'll settle
linebacker I don't play road lies things
so it if you do want to take over at
Station
you know the yeah I known frequency the
studio transfer Lee frequency
have a transfer operate side
recrystallized cellular telephone
bag phone player there or Beijing
transmitter once you take them over they
have no control over the transmitter
0 like it trays their control tracks
control signals girls City studio so you
know it take
have them get back control their own
transmitters
you turn it up for this and tech
interest
for my situation stationers work exit 45
miles away
at the transmitter for quite some time
so what you do actually
take it over at that point you can
forget about LP a
HPM you're in charge a control 50,000
transmitter for as long as you want
do everyone have some fun to parody
commercials
everyone as a player
satellites to not actually
giving up your own satellite also
transit on the same
exist satellite downlink frequency is
really close the receiver
this works really fun wal-mart's take
over the entire Walmart radio network
other have late special I'll 7
for adult sex toys watch everybody push
the carts
its fun stuff you along those same lines
and all these LED
LED signs you see around storefronts for
their
often easily compromised with
device like this for the biggest
manufacture these signs is a company
called
adaptive Microsystems and
this is an control that is used to to
program them remotely
through infrared like a TV remote
control but its pricing on me
mister french's put these in a window
you can but a different message on
Philadelphia few years ago there was one
in Tampa lottery
machine drugstore so i reprogram it to
say that
all them all the tickets from this
machine losing tickets
and it stayed up there for about a day
in a a lot by the next day and told the
clerk you know was that message in time
for the machine
ran over his freakin unplug the machine
you need to basically I don't like a
lighter
I don't wanna governs any anyway
so there was a lot of fun couple days
later
as the she was even there anymore she
just absolutely undertake
have on and user
there's a GPS unit probably a lot of
people are familiar with that uses
signals broadcast by US government
military satellites in
give you a position where you are you
have to worry about these things be
privacy invasion the
transmitting themselves you can be
tracked with his innocence
something like this in yourself and
which is be mandated now
but if you just have a GPS unit you can
be fun
one other need developments i've seen
with GPS easily something called geo
caching
and you cash in San something where
you can you can hide objects in
in a container tupperware when this is
military
and ammunition containers small portable
and
you hide it somewhere you put it you put
a few prizes in their new pad
and geo caching dot com Geol
CA CH ING dot com and
find out where these things are you this
thousand caches around the country's
a hobby you hunt these things down your
GPS unit
and when you when you encounter one
you open it up in New you take when I
Jackie put an object back
for the next person and right in law
book law
log book The you know when you there and
so forth you can also
with that information on the website is
to we were when you found it interesting
the street rules there the request the
not put any food items in
his animals could getting there right
rancid
no no drugs
in there you can leave any drugs for
anybody and
another stellar sea under now cambrian
explosion
these things but I have heard that that
happening for
so that if you have a GPS unit you
haven't
haven't checked at you catching comes
its kinda fun
I've I found one of these things in
there was there's just a
despicable magazines a couple other
magazines in there
when on so just in Jersey use it
the radio spectrum fun
I didn't like it the way
any questions about the radio spectrum
okay
I think work I have to hand out here for
anybody is interested
New York City area ready for you to use
by federal law enforcement agencies
cell