bottom
welcome to the condo for the masses
panel
money that I saw mom with me I have a
fav
because don's my plays but maybe
and on contrary to my position up here I
am
not going to try to be the moderator I
want this to be a fairly equal her
position amongst us on the most in the
audience as well
on I will do it so to interrupt us on
if you are looking be part of the ER
discussion at any point om
crypto for the masses prodotto wasn't
really a bid for the masses
more than about ten years ago its being
used by military is for thousands of
years but
until arm around the time with PGP
people
didn't really think about using
photography to protect their
communications
or issue arm bridge other conserve our
social schemes that we thought it take
for granted in reality into information
space
those social schemes being things like
the concept of personal identity which
is that
I love you in the face I know who you
are on the ISOC some degree of
up trust with your other attributes
concepts like being able to tell
a secret or are tell you something
privately
concerts like that and on a million on
those are all things that have leading
information space over the past 10 years
because I love
PGDM other technologies but also things
that happen to become
arm having come into the wide use that
some people expected them to be there
was
a great little safer parts for for a
long time which is love comes to an end
partially because I love not a a total
failure to you
arm make a part of the widespread among
ordinary people but it I wouldn't even
say that
may be fewer than one percent over
internet users are on
actively using photography to protect
their privacy
from Flickr shook hands with people who
who use a program like pgp at least once
in the past
as a lot of people it's all the people
in New York
here him and go to go shopping at the
holy people are
are still using it today and we kinda
regular basis 3
hero are looking at I think about
three-quarters the first time would be a
good one who decides
time net St on so let me just not the
question
why is that there are no obviously
use issues and there's the issue that
any security does not transparent
doesn't take used
but on body and you folks up to but to
say about those pipes and look for a job
with Microsoft hahaha last
with people all using fashion when
just operates and we're lives are
%um tax setting up
your mail lines choice someone's
something site had stuff like this
a lot is
work hard outlook or are of
this week
but United it is possible
all month runs would
on strong crypto after a while
hand you know that was are small
a yahan on problem
solo note that this is largely a result
does not exist
problem people's feelings a credit card
numbers over the water and
somehow there was this arm a
media hi about what are what a horrible
crisis otherwise about people stealing
credit card numbers by tapping
internet connections far as I know in a
to a first approximation has never
happened are
but up people were people perceive this
was
a a serious threat this was this was
something to really worry about
and your consumers demanded on
that they are that if they were gone
when gauging any
find 0 electronic commerce Mac any by
overall over the web %uh
baby day one encryption throne of God
protrude
was kinda silly motivation for but
are you know it didn't show that France
crypto
it was certainly feasible to do with
this demand for new responsible for
implementing resolutions of
much well he did you see a tussle
mock-up
that that's been recover files world
for for you know what are the important
questions to casket what you know what's
what's the threat were you trying to we
from
fact arm and you know it's very easy to
just way
for there was some matter pixie dust
that from
text you from no and things happen
thinking
throughput exactly this information from
there
were what's the threat like house I'll
are you know it its these looking
Wednesday
he's a handsome probably asked the wrong
question
or at least you didn't ask a large
enough actually I'm
whatever I will not lose focus on small
with his followers
it's a nice on the disciples
dropped the ball in his specifically
PG he is it's a
activism where original location balls
both parties going on exchange keys this
secure transaction well it's a it's a
manual process
do trees secure personal
your with PGP
certainly on and I this is a completely
insane
approached security it's far too much
security for what we actually need to
get a little
policy I you can see why this doesn't
have a chance in hell
working the thing about me is law
please lost value on their the group the
number of groups oh yeah
is as a is that the best definition how
much value to generate
from our communications medium on and
his laws also the best description
other number of key exchanges are going
to happen given
pgp so
can see that thought the same value from
reads law also case
in say an hour work from PGP key
exchanges are
with assault weapons over define slap to
the
some response and under under defined
the threat to be
a and the truth right as the invite
surpassing
the clearness the park and what we need
is no
24 percent better security I was not a
nice person
security on the scene know those
PGDM I technologies being an overkill
bomb
opening on this is welch's on that
could possibly can be over 200 imposible
let me give an example I've wants you
well
send a message to somebody and prove
that message
is from me my personal identity as a
Obama privately on in really well I'll
tell you something secretly I was pretty
sure you want to prove identity you
you look me in the face in you are you
know try to determine whether love
astronaut arm
on the internet when I are signs of my
public key and it's a fairly strong hold
him to give it he was fully clothed
Nura affidavit and I mean I want to
say something to you in such a way that
you can then go around & Sons has proved
to the whole world that I said such and
such a thing on such-and-such a day
and so on the the particular
cryptographic schemes that have been
chosen for for implementing
6.0 personal identity on the Internet
our own the don't match those teams with
a working we are very well
and on this carries or some other things
as well including that
if people talk about these hierarchies
trusting that trust is our
trust a Yorkie is like any kind of human
fast as we know it yet
people often confuse it and Dom Dr
one thing that I i would like to say is
that
the whole carry-over and on a mini are
the genetic information space has been
fairly successful on his honor utilizes
the whole thing that can be very
transparent
on it works very well and on
possibly argue that it's it's not a
right are have a problem with that
I with them that's the thing I'm most
excited about
right now I think most of the problems
both crypto for secrecy in go for
authentication
outsider we trust model problems are
largely
solved you know to matter point with it
on
the interesting open problems
I think our for school trust model
problems and second of all
the home how do you 100 height
information that encryption itself
doesn't rental
tactics like routed network seems like
muscles and isn't much easy
is for poverty to help you a little bit
with that arms
were but you also need other mechanisms
meant snapple's
on grounds like that and though you know
we
we know a little bit about how to
construct networks like that but we
don't know how to scale not our
practical effects on the heart is just
enormous sum
amount both I'll work to be done
arm yeah by people who are interested
eating arm pushing the bounds of things
and in the interesting thing is all
these anonymity networks require
infrastructure so from it they need
people providing relays on networks and
and services like that this is really
something that
that the hacker community is is right
to be very much involved with and
potential have a impact on on the way
our hearts to silence
one last thing I'm most excited about
these days
I think we're clearly losing the
anonymity struggle at this point in the
day
talk with saddam wonderful wonderful
stays at the same time
the I'm that this the successes that
hackers have been the
in the last mile is best for small for
example
most the posse give up his annual your
IP address this issue
with are login to web sites from a
browser
trivial things like that get the name of
your your browser manufacture
on and site for parts and
was initially successful with things
like its debts which are you know one
things
well fortunately because I problem and
nobody's really a
coalition race between individuals
receiving privacy
and of people who won compromise
the privacy a popper successes have been
targeted at a adaptations from the
opposite side
they haven't called yet soluble nobody's
looking tracing of P traffic
at a low of the talking about which is
absent is not a little people doing
extraordinary well
by tracing your IP address browser
combination
a on I know this I work for II popping
optimized
bad on according to you what we knew
about
a
the bizarre on based on what we could
have $0.00
well as your operating system all the
geographic location for IP addresses or
I can tell you when you have a lot of
people we could
increase we can but it will be windy as
we know a lot about you is these trivial
trespasses its and so the
so it's it's a coevolutionary s
Bangalore said we need to make sure
distances
are defenses for the actual threats as
opposed to you
must educate well yeah book but that's
the the
the time to enter the technology to mom
addressed for a is not while you're
under attack
so about that there isn't widespread
arm tracing and IP addresses or
little dossiers the user
me right now yeah either either
governments about private sector at the
moment
on doesn't leave the better
infrastructure is very weak against
flops a little
for up for a artisan
potentially a big problem are so I think
you know I think I think it is very
important particularly for this
community people concerned about privacy
generally think about
sales and would like to lay the
groundwork to
at the tailgate society logging on these
lifestyles
sam lebudde we had we want to take an
example of
John my babies PDP thing
wells s here right the differences
we on problem with any is
your acting monthly wanna very small
number of you of
maas on sounds
for handy to work beyond technical re
we have a lot of no was are a lucky he
is
easy these like reading long extremely
extremely gay
you know im very berlin's rooms from 101
from the website design this arm
no trouble same is actually working
months my colleague look Lori
same this group slogan privacy laws
company
and minutes networks
in really don't wanna be alone many
other people
like this wrote that story
but 1994 leaders eight years ago now
are we that I was at the first book
clockers we did provoking
arm this is this is complete a song
your we did a prepared and money
that he might from these be for reasons
I'll never quite been able to figure out
those late at night presumably
comparable or
both was in the audience a reporter from
are
a Wired Magazine I think the school in
both
Huang started on just mercilessly
helpful Spurs screaming where's the
crock rip mama
ever past proper speed aren't where's
the crime
and just screenie with even with the
microphones much lower than I was
is is this person in the room by NHS a
100 his I in think the end and never got
a chance for sanctions
season i've been waiting a year is to be
honest
the %uh and I've been thinking for the
last eight years that
does must be some levy work toward
that if I could come up with was shot in
my top and I still have thought so
this guy's not in the room at the moment
is is a big relief
in your its act
crimes
so the segue from from photography as a
threat
from needs to be addressed law
enforcement
certainly you poverty is a threat for
some fun
on the hope for vs over the last two
that was a number of years ago
though its news today
in on in many different ways one of
which is
I'm with also about a permission that he
GPS of monthly visits to this point on
the PDP
I think your two ago really did have a a
terrible vulnerability to smother
in the future following additional
efficiencies and on
it's been argued a little bit you know
inclusively
arm as to whether that was an
intentional sort of taint or whether it
really just wasn't oversight
but if you examine the structure 0
on corporations that was the party this
is what it is today
weather is no associates or whether it's
for the AG which is a
well yes no or silent for network
associates or whoever
on their side is a versatile in
family accompanies on and they all have
our
on the traces back to you are are the
NSA
and the other transit agencies that are
big questions are probably as Salaam
want to talk about is is that heating up
the polity
and down in the puzzle
for you know haha sry posse
owns college really anything else
settles arkansas are hands-on
com of continuing a big deal been too
slow
okay I think the content mom
people his Hong first
France's the anderson's problems
popped on of sunset these
is that he's a big news ours that is
tasaday of so we have
of available crypto
we have the mom
GPG which is open source mom
so that's good mom world haha
problems are
and we don't have much else right
jostling he's mom
increase haha arms I want to mention
that
related me
11 hassles
law are actions Facebook
Marjorie Charles shock haha of
me back to you if you can are read
see maas are in the end the series laws
he mentions
securely the ask is a fiasco
mop mal busy signs three drugs and other
songs
you have secure sites frames and secure
sites
in other words you listens to example
exactly what
should be impossible exactly what loans
salts of I think there's some
this is a problem and
people organizations telling us about
used in stock
are that's the highest
while employers low I'll
yeah I think a lot of this
part 03 for though include vendors
is I'll provoking specials
now as for though becomes a mass-market
them conceded were I'm hospital
microsoft office standard home you're
still depending on the security
things like your operating system you
know any other
software that has access to the betsy
one perfect but
um you know it its its K easy to focus
on things like the
is there a flaw in Pvt was has those
pieces of urban
been subverted are who the real problem
is
that proposal specialized the the wrong
is the product of their
arm you know thats the wrong with that
solves not
just figuring out whether or not arm
a particular is a software has
weaknesses but also
you note that the it is lightly widely
deployed model-driven
it okay why we love you as well I think
it's incumbent on the hackers who needs
to do more
the kind of our arm reviewer source code
and
when it's a black box for the follow
blockbuster view just dial
am relieved it doesn't expect and on
love giving us a a level of assurance on
officials in these parts that you can
actually trust
mark Harper problem months
and most polished want working has a
one-semester
wars harm forceful young
once still the people I can do
program are there of my hacks haha
nice song you propose a lot of fun
massive propose bomb arm you know so it
you know that attracts
0 a lot of lot of people has these nice
properties that the
other things are obviously impossible
but it turns out
deal things that are obviously on
their use either be really hard on so
you know they've
Matt reciprocal software export
superpower
are are also a lot of fun or interesting
the lab occasions you
surprising things want to separate out
from message security for media security
and
media is intrinsically secure are
that size the problem dot is that the
people who know how to
on bill secure applications of the most
boring
Brook Road which then runs on Windows
right
you know that the software the Purple
Heart
this offer might be completely
bulletproof but if
you know running on I love the are the
box Windows machine
what's the point okay with that
propose not the same security guards TV
to focus our attention
unevenly on
critter is on the day
could as a more interesting subject just
are
the Mexico by THQ bites
real estate on and
I think there's no engines with
progressing slowly
on this is a genuine heart so problems
so that
this this few guys
you know how much you in-laws this
problem find particularly interesting
Clausura
are owners lost before on israel's
so immersed in in the process that it's
hard to see the world
problems so the foreseeable that the
biggest successes of but you know
on hand arm it
Jol your information gay on
so for example arm its
less interested in me as singers in my
privacy keno
like 830 my bites on has to know
that's on like an obscure grass
leading to me in context you hire
on and that's a big success in terms of
of the Parthians it's a more doable I'll
on 30 I'm surely can't force anybody
think point to me that I wanna I don't
like cake that provides
way to get rid of them i cant it's very
hard to maintain the
them a lot of that it's useful
on yes same time for sure loss that
there is enough information attached to
it lately
back on so that's a that's a genuine
heart problem
Patel we handed that you can I'll 30
what's your graph cell
examples I'm getting at haha their own
today on on
gonna try push the far left at the
ballpark it's as far as I can take it
on and I don't want to attach to my was
a
for obvious reasons on I'm not
personally saying that
but was on the job you I love you buddy.
thinking about
my special streaming political history
and stuff like that so i likey
along us and so on to the simple stuff
using a pseudonym
are and process seems to say
graphing back to me following this link
back to me
it's a Google on is unlikely to her
so just saw this I'll
on yes by inserting the tolls
Journal point is that I its it's a
little too hard
do this stuff for a few d fashions I'll
on the part of Network Associates on
three leaky
on it's progressing slowly it's really
hard
in capability security just got here you
know the past couple years
its I was a huge to logistics long is
brand spanking new
so on the part of government being
are free to encryption mom
letter present one idea that I have
about 12 G
good for government and good for law
enforcement on
this additional thinking obviously has
been that if you are home
well only thing is that even further
from that and I just offer something
about the way
law enforcement or views the Internet
which is
that unlike arm the
the real world you don't have to
physically trouble to see what's going
on on the computer network
you don't have to go through a lot of
the the same hun so mom
affairs it's more like Justin
information call you can tap into in
this is obviously been very tough day
for law enforcement from as people 11
Mar the personal information
to the internet or other networks as
people alive more on these numbers for
their communications
it becomes more and more tempting me dnt
just Rd it just a dollar and this is
what things look as a lot easier for
was the problem know about that on
and this is really a natural thing
for such a
right approach to be used on are
on such a abrazarte communications and
but I'd like to say is that the more
people who
including communications arm the more it
is going to
hope law enforcement to do their job
properly about probably
I mean that choreography inclusion
a personal communications arm proposed
law enforcement from
are just sort of go to this link
communications firm
from to easily abusing their powers and
it really doesn't take away as much
power from law enforcement as they like
us to believe that led us to believe
that
something forget that fun at the end of
and really the fact is that you get so
long to somebody's house
arm and I am glad keyboards never leave
this open to cameras somebody's mother
in this happens all the time
on all information is really doing is
forcing law enforcement to go that one
additional stuff
to snooping on you a keeps them from
having just this I love
this training pop information where
everything is available to them
and on so I would live
everybody other think about this the
more important to think about it. that
arm clergy his is
a hurdle that home really makes
the information space a lot more like
the real world hun so
police power in terms of people's
privacy in terms of course you are
conduct themselves are in a private
matter and energy closer everyday
secrets
secret that you and I do all the time
but
another them think what would leave now
stated
me well even mainstream you know eight
years ago
we have a spam we have the chance well
home
that would have been you know %uh
radical but I think that
you as has finally made it into the
the mainstream you know the your first
the obvious
from thing which is that papa's these
primary purpose is to prevent crime
it it's too keep on authorized access to
information from
happen for schools and that a law
enforcement goal
and national security old you arm
for a while the hard to the government
that
I am law enforcement that are so
unfortunately threat
wholehearted disproportion Voice are
and also you know tended to what the
status quo thinking
designer thing deal but I think it's
these its
its fund around they're also confer
realize I think but
are to a large extent persian has helped
them even in solving crimes in her
injuries
using protection parisians on more
arm sensitive data to be
put on networks 16 but I networks wanted
to communicate
it's available you know through
subpoenas through witnesses through
forms and so on or just yes on mister us
also who dis though pleaded guilty are
among the evidence they
blocking on from him was is et/pt
which they did by putting out keyboards
never on
Plaza parking it in fact that I don't
want the one to his house
installed for they learned is key they
got his
his gambling records if it weren't for
the availability
berksten was gambling records would
probably not have been on this computer
in the first place
on that same note no there are also some
sleep easy but on a more attractive
platform understood his personal
information
down one of those is d the only thing
that was so
there about which is the creation of our
a trusted path inside
PC an attempt to prevent Trojan horses
you think he was the first things like
that from being able to circumvent the
first security measures which other you
install or more likely which Microsoft
installs
Tom is as close homes obviously
the bone
I think it's great
palladium is great it's so deep they
work hard
a largest I hope they go whole hog
yes strolls
with think that was a lot of it is
photography that
33 minutes away from people
it is anything anything that slows
people don't have freedom
yes not gonna work I mean what we know
about him for the Securities
right sleek any well-known
on and what palladium does wrong systems
lights on you look hot in here computers
from you
right it's worth it says will happen
computers from Microsoft
I it's so hot so there was a huge
difference between
the language fully
Council said go for it that much
confirmed by doctor both
not supposed to talk about digital world
pressure because of too much
but the earth real hello
real problem that the the thing that
makes my blood pressure go up the Los
is the subversion of the word
on up the idea trusted are they talk
about
trusted computing platforms but what
they're really saying is trusted by
people who don't own the computer to
prevent the owner of the computer from
doing what they want with
arm you know which which is is not work
are you into it we think both when I
think of something on your own
trustworthy com and
you know this this um attempt to build
machines
yeah are hostile to the interest of
their owner
are is seems to be misguided
love from also took 12 views not least
the workshop secured
I I want to understand what lying on my
computer
for security reasons box
with as right on the outside
on society's mom the demise
joplin's here that's something that
policy
yes a hong he's something and
right posit science I think really the
only effective
way that home to me
the ones is did not Jones here
mahjong parts of Lindsay's potholes
funeral is in place my yes
nothing why yet but
maybe even save us all some fun liquid
cocaine company
people here think digital rights
management is a good idea
they're really so there's no convincing
needed
climbers rushdie I think we should try
to do it
you know just let it happen and it was a
poet as a digital rights management will
donate money tonight
Billy that the science is settled behind
palladium
that nothing better than to happen just
will be so easy in life as the cell life
has engaged in this
refuelling this is not a long hot bath
homes me
the truth for the movement's told he was
never alone she
think so you know just both know there's
another problem that's been sobered
purchases tampering right below
campuses artwork and with them the
the Tampa love here is the person who
bought know this idea that I can buy
something
temple yeah it seems very strange
to Catherine models
tells hustle some members
me
for
well yeah but the only way to really the
question his
miles question the party's are
you meet people in this room of the
wrong haha splitting
ninety-some percent real users don't
then they went you know they'd call
Street use I'm you know I
McGuinty's people wrong and people can
run
so you have software anything wrong and
you have
you Dr which is preventing com
things from happening home you Nexus
samples
and of course my people on so yeah
not only one right people lot of people
are down
times program mop up the blood watching
with
and he did one other at a level that
part of the arm you know
practical claims the the Palladium offer
artist this is cataract that they say
that one person and
well break a this is Caleb rates
broken DRM scheme and about that they
will be able to propagate
change I wanna say I'll respond directly
you know that you're on the far side kid
sees
respond reckless about said on
say that you're absolutely right on and
thats
adoption positive allergies is a is
Israel is like upon the song on
we've seen in Seoul a few the areas that
people have been willing
to to adopt privacy technology on
wanna hear is highly doubt is that a lot
of people really are paranoid about
clinton's
on so there there has been
and and be a regular users to turn off
cookies so we think that at least one
example in each other
regular users you're taking over the
troubled
test themselves to was not necessarily
absolutely
essentially its rivals yet but
over there's a tendency for us to get a
little
talk about the saloon tomorrow on on up
was Mike's but I i'm
I'm a little less from optimistic that
you know just let them go ahead be there
were scattered such a stupid idea
aspect is it's tempting to say that but
you know laws and market forces are
are still powerful even he even even
when the wrong
arm you know the you know
for a while couldn't a he couldn't
export
for poverty whose no logging writing
photography as logging into your friends
but
gonna make the point that is the same as
wording but it was well as for today's
violent sport it was completely
effective
and keeping my purse of from including
bertram
the fall operating systems and horse on
or or any of the other on
on vendors you know for the most part
most love
the world particularly most the
commercial world is
some log were the offer for these
purposes so
you know even if even at the lowest you
can easily subverted Microsoft is not
likely to
teams that as the roadway with
II I still think it's important to
to to fight on those levels yep
young for fighting all although levels
unless
on I a yeah I guess I'll have to take
more seriously the Jiu Jitsu
these guys the setting insanely
placing I think it seriously I think
it's a
your James the Greater one thing
is these you would like them to be one
these
miles are workings me we want to leave
home
because we on download different things
province couldn't work anymore
DVD encryption scheme changes we lost
week at home
you new I
people heartless young you see you
stop drawn by 10 we lost
along worry on that we can win some
house see years played him you're
something else
someone cracked 12 hours split was
widely available
I'll and you hear in the future you
mobile do otherwise they didn't want to
you
so
ok we were we were asked to insist that
people use the microphone for questions
one
only a short list of both
lots of you the whole rushed to the
microphones
on both the total for people or berle's
love you
fun people in this room of
really dickey people who were on the
Internet
my mom I'm a
my mother doesn't understand why she
needs
prides she's changed and why she should
me to increase any Friday
she is asking why she antivirus software
she's changed and why she had personal
firewall on her
cable until people understand this
you not get the software manufacturers
put out eating a hefty software
long garment is out there now you have
you
who is yes
concentrate but must be used in TV and
she's on TNT
love it it's a question of the Mac Pro
the
you know there was demand for preventing
credit card numbers being Smith over the
lawyer article was not a problem there
was no widespread demand for it and so
we got
arm we got browser a security group we
offer for that particular problem
are right now computer users for for in
a web page is the true dancing frogs to
your web pages that don't a
install a virus on your computer and %uh
until all
there is that once per consumer demand
you if you don't understand the details
I'll do it arm you know we're not gonna
be words
gonna manufactures shipping insecure
products surreal of
or
blossom I'm working on getting a rogers
& and his wife
journals your car and also secure yahaan
yes this is the address
I think it's a bad mood to say lead the
way
we've run into already him do it is free
software
HDTV vissi that they are really
trying to me that they were checked and
I said today is pretty much content
providers leaving
it RIAA MPAA really want to
truncated people from the only equipment
that does what the customer wants to do
and they have gone so far as to a draft
legislation
it would be had for example I'm
receivers HDTV
the basic module here model which is a
priest three small
say they would like to and those that
didn't implement some kinda robustness
carrier their their model how he was she
is the one who said
it in the years other than the carriers
it here and they want to convince all
the consumer electronics manufacturers
to under this it which personal not so
hot out there passing laws prohibit
so end result is this would be that
folks like us are no longer able to
build
software and freely distributed me with
we went to we said okay let's say is
there any way making
right opens or so three pieces of the
comply with which one only one game
it was a yes yes USA you know this
this is obviously a min am I now live
always sure he's a dangerous path to the
game
ago time sunday it is 300 about
my my position like on
it is possible for governments
and and Chris Houston home on
when they included yet to try it sell
you the the industry the cartel
introduces a product its takes
government mandates
no other product image is between them
on
they said situation value has been
knocked out marketplace
writes it is a the value good
information technology is no longer a
harsh
on so that's that's that's the threat
that
that people are making loss out I think
that's a pretty great situation but I
don't think it's that
likely I think is more likely that a
time
somebody these these forces Allah ke
huge chunks
value our side to the good guys
that we come out stronger I would say
that file sharing isn't
wonderful example yeah everybody's
fileshare everybody about monster blog
you know
striking walk along with a dollar bill
on that's because all the value as they
handed
costs as a tool for our site for the
guys and
police %um is nothing but volume saw its
hopes about living volatile consumers
heading
cost place so I think it's a potentially
wonderful strategic tool
like begin this loss get the software
written
yeah it's the most important arts right
the
open standards talking
why of you to lotteries
Cardinals one home and this this is
great
problem wanna on home prices teens
you
of once England's team won prizes
%um are you see with the harsh
regulatory environment
a lot of the for 20 technology talent
on moving offshore armed
you see that is a trained in the future
interesting
he in bosnia thank you certainly was for
a while
arm you know when we had harsh words for
wasn't US work that
courage was it all okay non-u_s_ for
bill
this for arm its fortunately for most
products in there are some exceptions
rugby
routers one of the most notable most
mass market products ask for those
really
from last and that we've fix
on week States that problem by
March Arthur there is a risk low be
the US whatever the US regulatory
structure is
has impact all over the world by the US
is a big market
our losses and beads or so that's where
he is on
US policy against the exported to other
countries
home you know implicitly or explicitly
so it's fields do I didn't move off to
remain on
these I'll
I think believe there's a public demand
for
that there's certain age and very high
star 31 president over
a lot more money or is that the
productivity but regionally
but as for correspondence will be home
save this isn't operating a case of his
his in Haiti
he does maybe start he's in jail
be easier %uh ouija
yeah the ETag
there is there is a I believe is a
market for the holiday
he stresses the lights are low but if
he's interested so fucking
every I see is technologically she said
Italy do any good to have the Users
folder is it saying it's faster
if it's only people who is able to carry
overall male
three police security dead run the
a is a paid holiday 88 people to you
to provide dollars out for the real his
his
it yeah this is an excellent probably
have to convince people that there is an
application that
mother needs for anonymity arm
and right there hasn't then this was a
great wrestler
handle it some other with a remembrance
came up with this phrase
there hasn't been a day privacy valdez
right you know this bill personal data
that
that's been busy the whole once there is
that might be
are uncertainly inevitable are once it
happens that might be the
event that causes people to see to wake
up and say
arm on I'm worried about all the state
about worried about habits being
being monitored but though your I
the right now as a it hasn't happened
yet needs to before
before you get a hovercraft this has to
get worse before they get better
ass like any thoughts
example baby oh well really well known
cases of win
race the model cookies people here are
cooking
no big deal arm by
job %ah people do here haha see
home purely wins Johns Hopkins
kids mom newspapers moms
I'll job holders right weekends haha
first palm worry keys in my my
haha office only was on some
local theater after something it's a
hard thing to her
insights on how each year currency yes
you know
pop big thing some reporter was able to
tease
me so that the actual awesome 1
from both you know the king's name
he had seen dress: on telling
islands
my question is a only chair optimism
about a the possibility of government
and the industry
commuting and taking value of the
marketplace
but that's not so realistic are I think
a one side saying well there's a
possibility that the Sun coming up in
the morning
but that's not a realistic this is today
this is the world we live in
we're going to a couple years from now
biotechnology more more technology
that's not able to do
people you know my mother was the one
that just copy still
going to buy cameras going to be
surrounded by a secure legal technology
to a large extent it's already happening
the laws are in place that I
the technologies his I think I think
we're going to see is this actually
happening what we live in this room here
has been already characterized by by
these people as the analog hole
this is where we ate i think is a
mistake to be 18
we have a lot more going for a stimulus
for example passport
and dotnet didn't work
and they have an audience are moon party
game over the strength of
sound its
it's not that started to sing we guns
costs in with a then
taking collusion between begins to
government as as a remote possibility is
him yeah one thing that we're losing
essentially good teacher arms
well got us where we are now whole
computer internet revolution
is an outgrowth I no longer time but I
left a hundred want to keep dangerous
think the following overcoming
on