sting
as a waiting list Washington sorry when
the audience here
was actually written a computer virus
vision
okay now honey federal officers in the
audience are now looking at the person
who wrote
the computer buyers tape yes
his we will later
now a half is actually looking at the
federal officer the making and no
I just as with a guy
I do that at that time I was really
interesting desk on its kinda cool
as they had he will gather that honors
and a and haha
definitely having hot spot that which is
really funny
and I don't play it anymore
because I use a lot the night before the
car has the better all
buying alcohol in the bars so scat not
all the papers like pain is a bed
he has missed by his place of my last
night had asking us for our opinions and
showing us is that
yeah
da puzzle yes for can choose
I await mister
yes here Pittsburgh
I know this is like i've seen enough but
question that
many people other use Windows and don't
be embarrassed
vision okay me ask this question real
quick here
yeah
yeah yeah was a silent
on tape
a while okay is anyone in the audience
is
never ever use the Windows her life or a
macintosh raise your hand
right sonya is never easy issues when
the
but me and he is the Macintosh okay I
like this
one person sees the map and never use a
Windows machine now
I but how he is love it that's the
wide-ranging
a
ISAs no let's crack more fruits
vegetables
a
that and with the big problems here 'em
just can't do it be there shortly before
we get into cyber station the national
popular
well for Stallings over the bow
on known by liberia's buyers
this is Marty Mart is to be in a getting
here is her
he was I said the work with the audience
in reliance on on the slides
as a buddy my hubby out to h2k who here
was at h2k
I am you guys the media is all my top
okay we added with it so it's like to be
the exact same for grandpa
I also like to point out that this will
be the last year
that I will be giving this lecture on
the next lecture that's the front living
room right now is an advanced
computer virus course comments about an
hour long
possibly getting at the end at the
college's with actual quote examples
an explanation with was actually doing
cell
this isn't the last people any of this
he does
%uh where was i before with a
last-minute
I remember as okay a
loving the land not because of his
mostly computer virus lectures is based
on Windows
and I know the happy community and
especially in the network security
community
we all have to sit there and say help
with those blows its sauce
well is that that's what this is much
here to stay as most prominent
operating system in the world and it's
something we all have to face and his
which is why there's only britain buyers
is written part walls
you other reasons why the sign for
buyers as well for that we will get into
that can of worms I'll with things
start to become a little more prevalent
you know in the operating system rules
more viruses or can be written for them
on
couple years back have a double-digit I
said you know as people start using more
moral ethics operating systems
viruses will start coming out for them
it's on to meet your goals
or viruses other novelists heard why
came well because is becoming a more
prevalent
operating system boers more will be
using it the whole purpose the viruses
be able to replicate itself a higher
system literally useless that they
cannot replicate one system to another
I which is why you don't see a whole
lotta like mcintosh viruses that much
um you know I used to have a t-shirt
that I were a long time ago it's a
friends don't let friends buy about a
and when the window as 10 which is based
on the 3ds the OS
right now
is limited I'll buy a Mac based on the
fact that I now have
man mein so hot out command line
I we're gonna kid on here on is still
over there is next gen
NexGen purchasers as a is a consulting
group at a california
a partner the group great room they do
it. solutions network security audits of
medical stuff
so I but a that's my website there
you when I'm by a that work and
personal email is it be when I E 58 just
at work and busy knows
art that people at mention yes Haha I
can see all write that down
she I was dedicated in this hot weather
solicits code
food sectors multi-part eyes I'll atoms
now bro Trojan horse makes EDS
specialists this
also closed and computer viruses in the
future you know each year I can't
discuss what I feel is going to happen
in the future
dealing with computer viruses an its
have scary when
subject to taxes are coming true %ah
that's had disturbing I talked a lot
different people who have been
like your exit firefighters salameh
print buyers shatters
I'll I don't condole
buyers right a ride out I'll
on a firm believer that no one has a
right to actually put out some hostile
to the bank and maliciously destroying
other people's lives
people don't take in consideration that
when the virus is a company
like a startup and people are invested
the whole life savings into a company
in a completely trashed their systems in
a lil is everything
and the lender and now living on the
street and they thought it was a joke
you're ruining people's lives it's not
local I like you are right stuff and
experimentations on what systems wanna
check out
are artificial intelligence for viruses
I'll
cool la jolla game I hope he learns
there's mickey Lee doesn't make you cool
you'll
well what about the gym clothes are
strictly buddies just Apple
I that region definitional issues posed
Miller any program or script written
specifically to execute on behalf of the
user without the user's permission
or knowledge this as a whole does I mean
by lame runs into
I didn't say that a horse's all temples
on the list as per
what does doesn't it the SL okay
site healing has been exceeded class
action suit yeah
well go there later that for
that went I nodded but you know I make
my living at protecting minors
natalie that's an easy job what is a
virus
I know I'm just allele that's why
there's blood on the dance
my what is a virus her sex of rocketing
pose
that it catches up to host both can be
bloody boo records medical records
participate records
does the truckers binary files and data
files docs it sells
PT's sectors he added that he at viruses
are getting even more
province who heard about the the buyer's
atty that's taking
files on
many people know that there is actually
a virus our
four years ago that did the same thing
yeah
any any for us because it was a
replicating
it was something that actually that and
that the the JK
and it worked fine it was on your system
they had no way about getting off the
system
I spread mostly by the budget in the
file so in other words if you
.jp it does affect that retrovirus that
actually
that valujet takes a min to even see
them anymore are
and then you know as long as you switch
that day he to another person then they
can get it back to bed without
itself so it very much tied request as a
national sponsor
his work for an anti-virus company
artery years back
as a virus researcher annual pension the
name the antivirus company
%uh be I'll but
a
and he doesn't have a a cool I'll
call this work early to enjoy that they
had a special section for %uh the virus
researchers
they were actually wall of and there's a
sign that says warning in when entering
this area can actually me a you
things that are unacceptable on computer
screens a
they are and you'll be where the UN team
this year the unrest Anderson done
specifically
for the sexual harassment issues because
other viruses would actually threw up
naked pictures /a people's
ex-girlfriends was like really helps
landowners
L here's a bitch that y'all cheated on
me here's our phone number type things
the of
so you started unity putting these
viruses also there's this picture this
lady there like
okay I'll you know what's on the does
that work in the office work love
offended by that so that the site but
what if you walk in here you see
something that's offensive
because a lot of the all time buyers is
like was that the charges
your life you know you reckon so media
and yeah I'll
about you know much people have the
chance of us up
in is that we were very fit is a on the
desperate but
the screen I just dispersal that is ten
million dollars
yeah he's holding on
haha 20 a
want to learn suffocating self-contained
program ok both
that is not percent once denied that
bastard records
food sectors binary files and macros
this summer's
me much purveyed in light of the arm
sees intact there I actually read the
RTC's
done with our sister being a they know
what an RCS
okay yeah raise your hand if you know in
RFCs I don't know I'm talk blog a
yes it's funny that the one injury that
our CSA the others on what
50,000 for guitar sees other ya right
all along
I have a social life tell so that's my
girls on
and I read about those on the RC's
a
who sector virus is how they work what
to look for
ways to remove them now this is Cal when
the reasons why I'm have retiring the
spot was bouta
a visitor viruses our car going away
side there's not a lot of boot sector
virus infections out there anymore a lot
of people using like Windows 2000
at XP and other Unix operating systems
are here's a really quick a
true or false question here true or
false
it is impossible to live that NTFS
partition
drive with the boot sector virus I me
think it's true
raise your hand anything is false raise
your hand
alright need volunteers to me why it's
false
was a false and wrong
be a plus
get realistically under normal
circumstances
it is impossible to learn to that an
NTFS drive
with a bit at the virus because if you
put a floppy disk in
has been set for buyers it does not see
a drive it does not say it like that can
affect the trial
sign in or such items as yes would be a
true situation
I actually got a job because the guy
tells me on that and he was a true or
false as a
you can do it because they can't see
anything goes
the iraqi the job said okay need my
brothers
when we ended up doing with it as I dot
a I
an anti build disc
using that 32 using all the know that he
FS files that work hard actually see the
drive
well said mean that it's a that this get
I was able to infect it with the
New York who fires you a harbor Freight
and
but the disc in was able to see the
drive and the people who blew out anti
and it completely blew out in T there
was no recovery
and I got the job a
and then I had to fix his computer a
brassieres now let the pics my system as
it is your personal system is it because
he and is it
why did you let me do this to your
personal system his love the USA
if I came here to tell you all the other
day why did you let me do this because
as Adobe in your back at TC a
dear the headlights there was like 10 I
don't see that as a yes if they need it
he said
yeah I just don omar a
as I get the job
I here's why I want you to understand
how a boot sector
a virus worsens I every I mean people
here really don't understand exactly
what the food sector
how it works is cool with a hand is all
about is getting ice Irish death
highly yeah racing redheads handle a bit
higher there yeah you the lobby to head
higher
okay is cool this is all about its case
you guys %uh
the protected by David A three sections
we have the code section
which is basically the the instructions
that actually tell this is done
how the food up you know it member the
old Austin get like
syntax error Meadows Way it yet but that
the other cycles and XR
I the whole messages pop to I was all in
the code there these wealthy
the things the instructors that
partition information has all your draft
restructure their
as you know does a computer and aunt
were the pine
all all your files and where the fine is
like the mini nap if you drive
this world record structures are this
raw files or any idea
yet the market closes by five a
thats what else computer start here
yeah it up
yes the 101 either the virus first
copies
the book I'll on the drive to a
different sector on the media assault
primary book pro thats use pressure
cleaning up the system
is actually copied over to it a
difference after they copied its coat
over the cookbook
the into the virus code that points to
the new sector get that partition info
on the Indio
and the armholes the they did the
partisan above the desk
some buyers think think this if off
making it possible breach EU gated
the virus is removed incorrectly well my
asset the fires in the whole world is
the monkey
any people actually know %uh TV or play
with that
or are being hit by a day him or have
you coming up
I the DB is so freaking cool his with
much-needed
I'm a very after her psyche walking or
II
does my hair the monkey was so cool this
bright side yeah
a lot over here love it yeah a
ideal head lice that taking it right now
I would look if needed
are is it would do this to me imparted
the it's pulled over in that movie looks
like six or seven
a our second nine as 790 12 whatever
and let loose why we do multiple sectors
and let that actually discovered
up he's a coat over one sector he would
he would
me to go to the next several items were
found an open sector that we can multi
in
that this is the so if you're already
affected like New York he does after
seven
and not take it down is also the nine so
basically try to remove one
billion to go back in with the other one
they had 11 remove the other one
it made it really really interesting and
they would not eat it says
just a thought but yeah on a trip to bed
partition information
yeah I had a slight are yeah that's what
made it so call now
yeah so multiple actually loaded the
memory and the only picture partition
information overload the system boot %uh
immediately this is all seeing the
Steelers instantaneous
the marker by five AA thereby Spartans
at the yeah dung-wei had
day get yeah
well
we're going to do. I'm getting to this
report
so there the next light actually tell
you how to do
removal spit if you remove monkey
incorrectly any act together in the code
way and that having is okay great
you don't have to be so there are some
more they can no longer see
your day its
gonna is like was not actually said no
to document was looking at some
so always look for an ours is the
outlook for that
if he is a diskette are like Norton disk
error was awesome
you know is you don't just get all the
time and I just throughout the goddesses
I just go through all the different
sectors
I saw no closed for good observers by
some steamy
duplicate uploaded different sectors is
like looks
I look for strains be changes in every
usage if you start realizing that
was here that are sequences that yeah
memory
yes it was a little higher than normal
yes
some tears are stored on your local
state be here in the OS I don't know
that we don't what does so how do we
really define strange behavior
that you know you know i mean if you're
getting GPS every three seconds as if
I've you may have a problem
a harlem crash-like
by times more than I normally do okay
next
one way is to remove just basic
a he said the viruses is used at this
slash in the ER the you gotta
upbeat despite whatever now this is a
really cool way of doing it
is is that he is with at this slash he's
you that this class in the are
have been so fucking rock I here
I for those of you who doesn't know what
it is like a stock like one person
okay had with that is that in the arse
is
you know what your problem on on the
best beer ever
I don't care what codes they are just
rewriting whatever's there forget about
it
words can't put Brandon bought a coat
over it so from a book mostly sectors
but sector viruses it's great because it
just like
says its gonna you know any a popular
think it's that there's a place of it
does matter how the virus is
instantaneously gonna
on another way to do it is just the by
the old code on another sector
and just pocket his head over works the
same way yeah it does get as late as
October 7
well there's real couple well im over
thanks for playing
antivirus offer G let the hon
do you mean when the biggest balls with
antivirus expression
was the biggest follow that our fights
ni no yes
at actually the biggest public antivirus
products is you
you are the public that there are fights
I had and dozens and dozens of security
artisan with the first things I do they
look at that house well he's been
updated what two years ago
rule number seven that but network
security and Ed
outdated dat file an antivirus product
is only marginally better than no
anti-virus product at all
know the first two will not work with
some viruses that that may boob are your
whole system
a monkey was wonderful elton
if you use it just like to say that this
ice in the Arctic monkey bars
I'll as a king over thanks for playing
objectives
wanna bother McAfee actually had come
out with
a special Monkey D remover and let let
me be removed actually do is
in with their and stimulate like
listening to replicate itself
so is everything okay hey we're gonna
head a floppy disk imaging ok rate me on
a trip myself here and we recycle their
look for the cookie is it
star 90 the ink which included keep
running 15 years
phone will kill the virus and Olympic
the partition drive-in
have a nice day and it worked great
worked really great
yet the computers for that you know I
what time they were good
I does it not 10 positive sector viruses
yes tell
polymorphic then clicking in any
combination of these I'll also have
a metamorphic other ones that there's
more Fast Pass
starting to set for buyers cell buyers
is hiding up a memory
and help fight the fires gun buyers
detectors the problem is a
is why it is important to boot a system
with Phoebe just before running it a
detector will be able to use a place
that hide itself in the antivirus
products or visit their and
you actually that with foods out with
the start fires running the antivirus
product watch it how long in many cases
there's nothing here for a reality
viruses like
had Sony of Hoosier dad a
know my wife to see this video tape I'm
in so much trouble
polymorphic boot sector virus is the
final viruses are very tricky
the change the code every time they
replicate by changing their inclusion
code
in a very difficult from with a spirited
anti-virus software programs use a
similar to identify the cookie
and then use the key to remove the virus
is very very similar
it makes it very difficult for our an
antivirus products were actually
identified because it's not the same
signature each time you know i changes
in particular
see you can't use the same a digital he
is higher to remove the same virus
so once again it goes into the oil
simulator situations as he began to
replicate itself has a
okay quietly go to the encryption
process and once again against our
I had the great fortune he had using in
Turkey Day 51 destroy you
so very grateful yeah I mean it when you
see the anti virus writers
like at three o'clock in the morning
said they were like hell help put a red
typing away near 10
I got it I can go home and sleep that's
not a joke I'm dead serious I mean it
when you hear
sleep got sleep call me it you know that
so that he saw an issue
all one because they saw as we head
there was a a virus right now said
buyers to the company as other says I'll
bet he can't figure this one out
and and everybody stay there all night
and at
35 the morning the next day there's a
new debt pile out there
for thanks for the virus and it was like
everybody has like
Noah Wyle here either as a wetland the
rules on with me
who is okay or like you know on
Wednesday May you're buying the pizza
and beer
that's just house working X including
the sector viruses
in 15 months is 150 a or themselves
making it difficult more difficult to
remove the halls make it impossible to
recover data without the varsity credit
a month he was one of those solo the
following factors
on far better kinda cool I only talk
about one pound lighter here there's
actually two possible
actresses on the any other buyers could
low point to the end of the file
and the beginning at a real bar being a
this put into memory so what happens is
this perception here
is the intro at the virus in the actual
then we'll do with the lucky play itself
over here
to continue on where r la jolla run and
lonely but actually
it it for this is when you look at the
memory
go ahead and take on candy the antivirus
for the west the republic in the real by
Irish file easiest way to detect these
is
larger size files who can tell you right
now with the largest
size a comp file can be hold on let me
down
raise your hand 6.4k so we have to be
able when Meg
pump I'll alright
yeah so all other I'll backers will be
with you every 10
I was run it actually at love incised
with to the file
and their time is money at a little bit
size so you're like man that comp I'll
you know but actually for getting big
here and bigger you have attended
drivers I get this way back in nineteen
candy drug
when your day thx liking of are you
accused right now
and latinos like I'm going out to space
and install anything was going on here
you should haha I was like her home
heating up with
said that's not my type I the
something's wrong
and a multi-part a virus want that
both the food sector and files apollo
increases the spreading
that has to be the virus by this email
or any other way the
by of this is all really great way the
virus I just found taxes just really
replicating South
the diskette the files whatever so a
genuine file
try to replicate itself a time you
transfer a floppy disk
%uh you will realize that all you gotta
do is put up but just get it right
and just hit a hole in and you infected
right
infected SMS intensely do it directly
any infected s
and then they you'll who remembers Nick
Barnett
yeah all guys have gray hair
sure I dot King a lol
you think this is natural it it's all
bloody yeah
but I see my wife dies there
hits like you're looking all thank you
baby love you lol
seriously ill back in the day israel has
the Kern St net for those are you young
kids out here
where's is like again it s profile other
deaths
and
in Georgia
shit a
that was needed at what amazes me is
that that's the thing that was faster
than using Windows networking
I just watching that connects the
fucking computer
didn't a
all come on you know it's true right
yeah
natural viruses on any here we have to
get hit by an improvised vision
day in May here
he never got my vaporize the suspected
it
okay never viruses
there K cool a little bit when they
first came out
you hear a lot don't know is another way
of fires again has like hello
get over it and that the bus riders use
basic computer languages include with
the like Word and Excel to pay the virus
now I don't know what radiated hey let's
give them
cooling capabilities in our application
will make your life easier
yeah once again aspect orphans but why
wasn't done but
from you and solo homers is used in on
the dot dot file
now you get it edit this file you it
soviet suspected that you're actually
effect by now provides you get it %um
they don't know about that I'll and see
if there's
additions to it are one the a they had
rainbow virus would the one for the
rainbow virus which was a a member fires
meriwether the version that there is a
change the colors on Windows
so you know it you're serving
you be using a file like I think she's
cute green is paid back
the box over that and then all your
things were there and this was getting a
table while in until everything went
we're standing all the blue-black a
are only because light you like okay no
avail
better the easiest way to do that is
a you that they've been all that I'll
and then
you can't replace or just edited live in
Austin on the dot
issues for all the new obligations to
grow at all previous
mission of that patients O'Meara
occasionally easy
what is the Trojan War
well to use most bookies it's a condom
a use only for water balloons
%uh work with the guys
three hour time difference yonders get
rolling
second Las Vegas actually lives with a
las vegas three months ago
death has not any politician yeah
and no I'm no longer having cast his and
Sahara delivered a lobbyist the deboers
with %um
said he was like I got eighty people
went right there right
yeah that's right with like alright by
but speeds
he helped make money buddy I a bowl or
pizza Co that appears to be legitimate
actually has a hit in are often to
malicious purpose it was not the Keith
that can be personally these are
problems there
are put on your system by selling or
your trip into activity in them
yourself are a good example was
whack-a-mole ever that aidid
my bus hit one copy of you
gotta check this out as the bus for game
I've ever played just a lockable
any set their and I was like good who
who who did you give this to you
everybody's a
your and like did you read the Savoy use
policy
did you read the part was it you non
transfer
items without move on from it. 190
once again detail review you just sit
there is a unit for him to avoid
you know you on the first day of early
if you're ninety major IT director he
should have a for a clue about what
happened here damn apartment at least
know how to operate a machine
it's just me just on ok I really like a
team and his love the Department rate
hey operator I would assist I don't know
and Amy isn't helping
and a heel holders do then as insulation
Wears Prada well yeah is
dog inside I'll
most of these are back to our programs
like b.o.b educated person except a
a la the backdoor programs now like
things like IRC
and I am these are great ways that
people in spreading like
a the attrition our systems %uh I got my
RC
every so often I i easy YRC honestly
because
you know what and that's all I forget
like last thing I need is more
online it has like is in the IRC should
be drama
R Us you know bed people sit there and
get these newbies on there and it has
like Rd level to do this you'll learn
about hacking Yamaha with her
you know there's like no hey dude got
the proposal from renders you'll likely
in the haxor somebody's box
due to read the problem I can see things
happening
yeah I know %um a
good
it was wrong I don't know here try
running this program
a home and he's offline
a forget and
net and and realistically that's not
really far from the truth
now he is great I if you're a newbie in
the extremely well are the ball like he
was there were security and hacking all
as a
me know more power to you I mean
realistically you the future
I have percent you know %uh that
know who your talkin till you know iris
is like the worst
anybody dollar anybody's near a john was
gonna
a fun
yeah I do and did you get the problem is
that you no haha
here it is a any when he was he the
the little thing I don't know who's
picking up it looks really funny was a
i've a web sites
about to a a the oh is that work as a
demonstration
were the guys that there is no
screenshot from his campaigns like
look at the screen in the actual enter
the screen was like L
Hey Dude we doing laying here are
looking at this computer screen we got
this beautiful girls that like your bed
gallagher's that means it's any input
sure the heat of there's a
goes all areas
is great on by the way I'm not knocking
like no other
well it's easy here right I on the huge
supporter the CDC
great guys very very intelligent people
%uh
that the thing I believe that the
actually give his the people that more
aware of
just how much they have to protect their
systems %uh
and they make my party it's their shit
example hybrid
buyers into him into
hey like a
this him proud to have her out
other thing and it ended its bread
on like a wildfire I will it was
it was pretty impressive it's a massive
an awsome
and ice damage in as a lover on analyst
marty expand upon this because this is
Kat Bob Marley's little bit here
ago all for those you know anything
about member
despair with you but for those is gonna
be for like we don't want to get into
the details of the exposed close
husbands in Scopus
yeah he had made the bed another head of
four main propagation methods
are the first obviously if you look at
number one is
its parasitic pippen file
factor so you'll get infected files
obviously one false
rather the email was think that skill
I email was the main are made for the
propagation
along with love browsing for mobile web
servers on the Internet
and of course our there was also a
mobility in
in a explore are 55 earlier
that allow are the infection
aren't for everyone on the user's she
when they viewed
infected our web server on the internet
which
in fact that their machine internal was
that began to be can in fact
internal machines on the Internet silos
those very very
I was bert was a beautiful piece of work
first this kid
alarm while the neat things about
that I thought about member was as
Trojan capability
it the way it propagating through the
network shares compartments it did a
couple of different rows and things that
party itself as
are really don't you know so people
would see all these
really files and not know they were
course buttons
social engineering but the other thing
that was really
sled was that in a copy this all has a
Trojan
reject 20d lol now %uh a lot of our
well word on when were paid
use with a twenty the lol on world bomb
which tax anguished X-files apartment so
it lot for file-sharers to contain
Word documents and it would copy a
Trojan Richard 20 the OL
and make it a hidden file so you
couldn't see it when
the usual double click on the word file
it would look at them
at the local first at the local of worms
launched and launch
call the the Trojan which I 20 lol
infected the host system
was relieved local and
home with you this up because this is
like the
well the new bridging the gap in public
viruses
well if you ask some people
a definition that up alarm arm is
something that really
isn't personally 118 that the following
just a custom system the system
and this can bridge the gap is actually
hit the txt files
on a lot of things are really starting
to change
in the virus industry in the world I
hate to say this
that a lot I have two comes out is all
screwed Kasia
you know it's not like the old school
virus writers who said there's a
how much damage that possibly do is
little cold as possible
reusing things i would like nail you
hard
in like 4k upload official language
and now it's certainly all
twelve-year-olds know that you're going
he was told somebody else's bit loose
ads and shit and the whole anywhere so
get ready for duty at limbaugh
awesome Lee I am and have my other
twelve-year-old string bubble gum thing
you're great
you agree to stop I
the new method to buyers writings are
emerging all the time so the new bonds a
malicious code have the ability to
change themselves to
eBay detection 1981 personal buyers
was a Mac OS fires for those if you
thought that the police say on Macintosh
sorry realistically the actual
first buyers ever written was a mighty
and in
in my teens or is another story no
raise your hand if you know the story
okay basically it was used as a
competition
a domain internationally right clothes
that were decided like
take other people's court not the other
Hogan and Xcel
to use a bit much space as possible in
their effort here today it was
competition
and then one person actor cameras name
which is casting the net I he wrote a
piece a close game
it just him only when granted him start
spreading to other systems
%uh their own lives
1986 personal animus boss fires 1988
with the virus is 1997 upcoming moral
viruses 1988 polymorphic viruses 2000
and metamorphic viruses now we'd only
one slide it on the democratic process I
thought you were polymorphic virus was
which is something that actually change
the encryption key
the metamorphic bars actually changes
the code and the coat size it's also the
at the signatures different by adding
like jump won't change in the structure
a little bit
I air things progressing it's pretty bad
keeping count antivirus software vendors
siphoned a identified a thousand new
buyers at last year's bring the total to
thousand known worldwide
now identified thousand
new viruses let me clarify on this okay
one-year 1000 brand new viruses
these are viruses in the wild what you
don't understand is the antivirus
companies get on average a
400 22 to 800 new never-before-seen
virus is
each month K
moseley's don't get the lower lie these
broken close buddies
crap are or they don't replicate asset
after the concert at braums
him now they're just like there a lot of
new technology viruses
Center it think about that imagine
getting 800 brand new never before seen
Beach Club is called job security for
the antivirus
yeah the the data litres okay cool I'm
never leavin
its all of baseball's alarms
most your baseball songs come through
email love for a lotta pains
I have things like for god sakes read
this in this light
he'll as less miss miss miss miss miss
miss plans with no immediate
next line misprint
they're really good he is
send this to everyone you know I
who studies game tonight he wasn't
killed two sons a bitches and send them
to launch
a has it he said
Ltd users hi infidelity is italy did
Justin Thomas
do not send it to us in a week later you
get like it doesn't have them
do these numerous yeah okay
your walk into this and
now run into this a
okay this very thing you hear guys
is when he is based upon tables around a
fire serial of
ill make your dog right then and the
change the colour
your sisters here and delete everything
on your sins your system directory and
I'll
in all white all those texts on the bus
so and this is new and
I love it microsoft has sent out a
warning okay
microsoft does not send out by
respondents K
and the little things like McAfee is
that this is the worst thing in the
online tonight bossy shit about this and
more
so on if you concerts on the bus loads
actually look legitimate
nearly homie that's the deal is go onto
the entire sites
you know I McAfee Norton F product
whatever and
look after their face a false alarm
sections here or I'll
or hoaxes I and verify that way that
that the point I want to make here is
realistically
these themselves become viruses think
about that
here's woods by response to do is
supposed to
sure bet with right a impair with you
and replicate well when you have any
israel's
who barely know how to type in use now
says it is
any CDs and they send them to everybody
their address book you know as and Jenny
in Kentucky or everybody all the
relatives alright the whole state
kentucky
a you know it
these replicate and the surging up and
with an edge look at things in the end
up getting up let these things like
realistically these people acquire some
cell South
it's really important to educate our
end-users when you see something like
this
don't send out the 1x2 everybody know
contact me
and I'll give you even and he was up go
ahead and for me
don't bore me twenty thousand copies in
this BBS
Visual Basic spitz every damn scrutiny
in the world
no way viruses now the first lady is
lecture
I had this little 12-year-old kid at
death caused and it looked
skill vs beyond the is not damn long
said
I know the job and I'll never tell you
with the actual joke as I want you to
get it for yourself Haas
so I so you like all I get in sync cool
b1 is when the job no if you can't get
it it will be funny for you
okay the I Love You buyers
was per money example this there are a
few bars lightning was nothing more than
a script kiddie
a stuff you know the your mom
can write a virus using Visual Basic
Script okay
it doesn't have the elite status anymore
you know
these are not hard things to write
anybody can write
keys you know which Mason that much more
annoying
and how much more that you know so when
you see him BDS
their buyers is coming out the person
you say is like you know there's some
like
you know a urals never get his dollar is
likely to die im sowie
K itself as a how that was me
way he's here to see me with that as
well
a
and I he did say that didn't cry like a
little bit with the lady
you all
a the celeb up
a yes even was in the strip
hostile good now
everything we talk about is considered
ha so close so what's the deal
realistically when I talk about hard to
put up talking about things that
is like brand new undiscovered stuff you
know new and undiscovered
in the wild things that there are no
doubt ha sitting for
by love you viruses for example i love u
Myers hit
it replicated spread across the nation
like
owners is that things he was so fast %uh
so I had to get credit on that
you know mostly because you know it was
using stupid email servers
but now a good example well as
when he hit the wild the vapors
antivirus popping out there
who had at this for had a thanks to
hours after hit the US
you know is I fr you have secure and
two hours after he hit the US they
identified it
they had thanks for and they trace it
back to country watchin was pretty fast
but we're also talking about things like
Java
activists and other stuff like that you
know these can all be determined as
hostile codes
summer the mores sites you guys go to
you don't realize actually drop a Trojan
into your system
is yet another who did you know that
laser engraving and
don't be embarrassed who visit the sites
are they don't really check the system
now
you know the light-hearted adele is
appreciate you know that he is
has on stamp on pages key partner not
that I've ever done these
spanien Spagna here going to have tax
money that is something I S
and and and it's like you know we need
politeness is alleged by
am and we're gonna tell over it
you know why it's of me I was it a try
dellums be legal software like he with
the Trojan he doesn't know about it
week below and I so how do you defend
against
I in a new massacre well
killed say a proper security system
yes that means you're in a citizens as
well you really need to set up
other skinny systems up under Windows
you can actually said it so it doesn't
allow
after tax for job applications XQ
without her a with your knowledge
this is a pretty fun thing to do are on
UNIX systems
if you don't live in your system there's
a lot of Trojans backdoors I can just
walk right in
they look for in all of our police and
if you're not catching
not directly at the hizzle smalley are
your wide open help people have this
relieves
see little things I hate about you next
in this using our review here
may have another hate NXT getting
saint-saens is the same as my
Nate anti-virus products because he's at
also as a security you david has given
antivirus product you completely say
bullshit you know USA for two hours
after you installed and updated
you know my antivirus product at these
the
daily and I still low
that within 24 hours in stock in bed
with the buyers because she's coming out
all the talking ill and you are the
worst candidate yourself because you do
not bother have the
the house alright all our honest opinion
you raise your hand if he had not the
your debt pile in a week raise your hand
keep your hand at the event in a month
here and if you've never done it game
disputed
you're honest thank you yeah
it the hon Trend Micro set up for that
house just this week
and plot but is there that miles
the maggie is like once a week %uh
trail very very cool product with
anything so I but when my clothes and go
on to the website
and actually have its skin your system
from the internet and it doesn't very
very good job
yessir West while yeah
almost
all exactly
way
no no a
basically he is saying that you know
here's ActiveX
disable and on when he does like like a
la the news sites and all that stuff the
albany is after that it becomes really
annoyed because then you'll
he has problems as our way to get around
a no outline
you well access now
really because the you want there is a
way to do it
cannot tell you how the arena him
because we get right there
on so hey thanks for the Segway in
arlen doesn't stop laughing there are
pics /a
I you can now that could help out a lot
I securing a when this is done
has never ended that any level of I you
could hear me
may have topped with Microsoft Windows
in realistically
I do actually love the operating system
and because
you know I'm a gamer at heart love
playing computer games realistically the
cascades on the system's
right there's a lot you can do on when
this is done
you know i i thought i a
hackers all other nations on says an
oily use a living system I'll use the
I'll the Nexus whatever and I know
people who is that there's a
do that Italy router box with the
windows no hot when the sacrifices and
just as easy
was the deal you know it is all about
skill are
whether we should have to defend
yourself as well for the call see much
technology
peso has a multi-party work what it does
is actually a
anything that you exit execute on your
system gets put into it DMZ sandbox
and what it does is it in an isolated as
he gets here
and when excuse according to seize any
hostile activity it stopped in his
tracks
as is you know what this looks like a
financial do something that Hartnell bad
loving it do or not II stop
it's like to have it this is really
messed up what about that
qualities Pharma there are none
is not looking for signatures is looking
for hostile activity
yeah
speed yeah a pot
secure secure secure is an antivirus
nothing mmm
its I'll get it bro sandboxes
it's an awesome new hope approach
relatively new
all yet remember that a any bars
bought or react I know and as
our hearts hearts become you know more
complex
it takes farce in bars pubs longer to
right signatures for and that time
period with them spreading
near speed of light know that Times
quoted so what they're doing is
some of these are going with sandbox
Sala Rossa
integrating a personal firewall software
into their
any bars offer and is based on behavior
blocking block certain hope to behaviors
are not going to allow them
functional probe at if I am active
you know pro bout that network problem
restrict that behavior exam also wanna
be heard
it is me
and ask to be ended December fav
technologies need to be
mom by Antonov I in team but once you're
tuned
there are there's lots of the rocks all
now here's an example
are I really be at the useful engines
are concealed
no I don't take a class for the company
is by the Allied is a curious
as well because I always recommend it
doesn't use data files
and it doesn't replace antivirus product
it works in conjunction
will your antivirus products what it
does is in helping kisses from hospital
a perfect example that they actually use
on the website pages as
companies that actually we're using the
I'll engine serving shield when the I
Love You virus
here those companies but I believe that
it's thought that i love u liars
in its tracks the party back to the
system does he take it is hard to hold
is mostly used for things like after
that and jobs
so for you back there with you could
actually have is you could actually be
ready just in the background and
actually have
I after that and are running on your
system and when it he hit a web page to
be detected
hostile activity would have to stop it
last year interfering with you don't
like the new service
all the questions that okay or counting
on time here
are the website prevention is out there
that we have you got
engine dot com by and a and are a great
person to talk to cheese
at the Rec I work with all the time for
the company I'm presently working with
words all over by a car
detailed by Danielle says yes we are
great lady
I'll dollars I sent you to treat you
right that's for a test number there
thank you as our talk about to make a
special thanks to our home party here if
it had been a lot of input and help out
I'll and nothing were oil companies
%ah
on have about four minutes for questions
are you know it's very very
unique that is a much technology they
have brought servers
firewalls I'll workstations are so far
its
its it's very unique done on how it
works are
at all the difficulties they they are
doing it the only 1i fathers
in the most reliable engine and it has
it all so
there's a couple I'll a multi OS
fires is that the %uh that effect but
what is it and when it's Lexus started
the bubble a bit more
a stronger following it because others
couple things in things
well %ah the viruses are people lives
are in developing our
is they're looking for liabilities in
the next
for that people don't only pat the virus
looks for that it would ask this place
of
work
only gets going
no
yeah 0
he says he doesn't want to try to do
engine data does whatever it is that
they try to do this this and this
do you want to get that let it happen
and things I'll download files from the
internet
it has a slight little alike as a ring
over the other people's way to look at
it
I know it admitted to loving the sandbox
and it doesn't detect
likely allegedly pot probably if it
detects the selectivity
the consulate is trying to do this right
now yes or no
up