world
used
well thank everybody for coming and
after that wonderful speech ever bring
it back a little bit more towards a
the technical and professional hacker
I'm
thanks a lot on my presentation today on
discussing professional hacking
I am particularly coming home security
testing professional hacker such as
yourselves
can interface with utilizing contribute
to
the open-source testing methodology
mando also known as the Oscar normally
these presentations about two hours long
but due to time constraints
have to squeeze in about 40 minutes so
if I go too fast we need additional
information please make no they asked me
at the end
Q&A session so that we can get through
it all at the end I'm
also be available after the presentation
of drugs remain at the conference so
three Grammy ask questions so the
audience I have here at this conference
is very broadly folks are the entire
game better security professionals
now the sasser's turnout technology
visionaries
malicious hackers federal agents
security professionals as the
administrators we got the whole thing
here
I'm it makes it very difficult for me to
attempt to make these presentations that
all those levels
so they're most likely be partially me
too technical for some folks in some
parts that are impor-
some almost a view so please bear with
me if this happens
I'm and we can get together more
question there so these are the topics
that i'm gonna cover
overview of the security testing
profession and the Austin South
the session will include a brief
analysis on the security testing field
today as well as background on the idea
and organization that houses the Oscar
i dnt originated the idea for the ask
them
and I'll also give it back and ask
himself from there a real briefly touch
on privacy law
and how the awesome tries to properly
respond to as many
laws internationally as possible then
we'll get an immediate
presentation at the section title
planning lost on security task is
obvious with a certain about the whole
or in some detail the testing process
that has to be covered to be an awesome
certified
past and always knew that often results
in final Q&A
for just what the hell is an awesome
anyhow
me take a step back into
give you a little background on myself
and right after the knowledge transfer
project W
organization been involved with it since
its inception in January 2001
basically this just made us tonight I'm
getting out how to get the word out
about
our project and are open source manuals
to people like themselves
but the hamsters not a profit-making
companies or organizations that were
house for open source projects that
so all the travel lodging everything
that are all parts for these
presentations to you guys to try to
just get people signed up and and help
this thing grow I'm also a primary
contributor to the ass myself an iPod
and many other models and getting
significant feedback and very process of
me
%um and profound Republican security
Sciences Corporation
as well as a freelance security
consultant both government programs
the ID his organization
as an organization dedicated to the
development of security standards the
open the review process
the organization is an independent
third-party receive no money or benefits
for many
commercial means anyone's life becoming
criticizing tripp grady
projects or submit realized
whether or not product become the
standard is purely up to peer review an
overall acceptance turnout commercial
non-political needs
means you guys make these things really
does make these things grow and become
solid risk analyst January 2001 is
simply a small idea
we like the hamster on Fri in many
projects throughout over well as the
project is always growing in a state of
flux currently we have
the open source security testing
methodology manual the 10 min to talk
about today
the jack-of-all-trades security testing
training supplement was the technical
training supplement to the awesome
itself
the secure programming standards
methodology manual
which is a supplement to the asking for
the development of security code for
Internet applications and some hospitals
are also in development
these tools are all TDL tools in our
release the open source to support the
adoption and we ask them
all idea after project meeting a simple
things around in information security
and best practices
all documents written using open peer
review process which allows all
professionals in the field to comment
and/or review
each other's comments for inclusion in
the docking at the hamster cell
is independent non-political non-profit
simply the organization of the peer
review process the coordination in the
data
and hosting them all the information the
rest is up to you guess
so we ask them products
the open source security testing
methodology many law schools the first
the most widely accepted standard in the
development for the security testing
internet systems and networks been
downloaded by over a million individuals
worldwide since its inception
with a lot of collaborators and probably
been translated into five different
languages
the ass literally expression experts
liberation have expert knowledge
the ass move rapidly becoming a standard
for security testing industry-wide
has been adopted by a good portion of
the company's the test Internet Security
mainly because methodology is so solid
since they're over over 100 meters from
other companies agencies and was like
the Oscars truly emerging information
the single best practices document
yes the spring ninety three pages of
information checklist and templates I
have a heart heavy with me if anybody
wants to see it
the hassle of is a certification seal
for those who complete a thorough
security test according to specific
sections of the media room
there will your customers know the
difficulty the task for the best
practices in mind and they can see the
methodology used to do those tests
as legal best practice in commercial
information changes
and shared amongst the security
community it will get incorporated into
the osco
the stories of greater number of
templates and a help accelerate the
security testing process
new models are being added even today to
deal with emerging technology as well as
obscure
optional facets testing since this is a
living document the Assamese
professionals like yourselves to
contribute I'm an idea for the project
help us continue to help the security
community
all right as we all know the stats
computer security breaches are on the
rise another boring with a little
boasted about
eighty-five percent respondents detected
blah blah blah like crap
we all know what's going on we also know
that the senate companies acclaim
financial losses going on
well what can we do tell you guys a
security professionals to bring down
those debts
we formulate a standard for test that is
always updated
always current always being reviewed by
the practitioners themselves
and we take the standard mg/dl we have
many companies organizations and
agencies donating their time and some
human resources to the arts
one example would be the US Department
treasures US
Department of Treasury officer threat
there are other examples including MITRE
Corporation da Vinci consulting their
sign in for
by the early adopters in the ass these
companies recognize that offers
participants a consistent framework and
clearly quantifiable results
thereby affording a level of assurance
that the output file
accuracy and validity of the test and
uses and that seems love
testing before the US Department of
Treasury officer threat is currently
working with the awesome considering
making awesome certified test mandatory
for banking throughout the United States
this level adoptions
drawn throughout the world many
different government and private
organizations in many different
so
let's take pics that when he and other
one Sacramento by security testing
what's the definition of a security
professional security professional has
to be one of the most difficult
professions in the information
technology field a securities
professional heston out a little bit
about a few things but a lot about
everything security professionals have
to be network architect software tester
programmers a
the engineer business manager Operations
Manager Marketing Specialist HR Manager
incident response in here
among other things if you are proficient
all these fields you need to look at
their minimum
communicate clearly and effectively the
organizations are experts in the field
without constant communication
with those experts your security doesn't
seem to fail
the oscar has contributed from all these
fields and others
and we understand the need to have
expertise from across the board in the
drafting the standard
the specs next question where's the
features security profession
security professionals security testing
from the future we'll have to maintain
all specialties we just discussed along
with many more
the only be part of their support
statisticians say
yeltsin training Privacy Officer the
rose just on
18 grown spam no longer will security
professional be just a technical guru
interfacing with people and
understanding in on the skill set those
people will be pressured
crucial to your advancement as a
security professional let's talk about
security test themselves
they come in all different shapes and
sizes as you can see that its charter
some tests are on campus it s others are
defined and redefined the sunset I so
the whole
vulnerability scanning pen testing
security testing security scanning and
ethical hacking
they're all different forms are secure
it s sometimes overlapping
is test takes a different amount of time
and resources to complete
the Charter demonstrates the depth each
test in relation to a full security
assessment
vulnerability testing Boston at least in
taking the smut on the south side
security auditing penetration test which
is assessed at a happy
ethical hacking is a process that is
most exhaustive
takes the most time think last nearly
the most money money to complete
the goal of the items to cover all
aspects of almost s
no compassion thank you consider taking
the set now because
the the experts that are here
one of which I am NOT but privacy laws
play a strong role in methodology used
in security testing
depending on the laws in your local
jurisdiction nearly certain tests that
can it can be done any information that
must legally remain secure store for a
significant period of time
these privacy laws are dependent upon
your country state region cetera
both pros and cons result from his
privacy laws
privacy laws generate awareness to the
non-security community as a whole
that's a good thing however it also
causes confusion as most these laws
urging her
poorly written into specifics they
generate the need for security tests
that's a good thing but there's not
clearly and we will define standards for
these tests
that's really awesome really comes into
play there are no
their due to the public as a whole that
there's no place to reporters user
complaints
auto versus test which does the security
tester do
right now based on privacy law and the
company that is contacting us we get to
choose
the real question is which one is right
and reliable if we choose the right one
privacy laws are source of revenue for
us this of course is very good
however if we don't comply properly
with these laws will also be a source of
funds and malpractice
privacy laws will in general very
positive and well-meaning
can also be very dangerous to security
testing industry let's talk a little bit
about compliance
at this point in time there is no
security testing specific
laws within the United States within the
United States time israeli only privacy
law
currently the fact is that as the couple
of the Health Insurance Portability and
Accountability Act
banks that internationally we have few
other laws protecting privacy
basically as countries and governments
pass these laws prevailing security
testing privacy
lawyers that are contributing time to
the awesome product review laws
incorporated into the services they
together autumn into the main
I am the asking price to take into
account as many privacy and security
laws in the nation is possible that even
a
100% interest years miss the National
Institute of Standards and Technology
has risen newspaper and security testing
after release that paper they have been
in discussions with us an idea after
include have included the Oscar
in the next bernadette able to see be
released
Scentsy is gaining gain ground
nationally and internationally
as attending on standard
to summarize the security professional
the future is going to need a little bit
of everything
is going to need to be little bit of
everything everyone and the death the
security test their own on the ground
this quote signifies a mental attitude
required to do an awesome task then to
be honest with you the mental attitude
Best Actress today
okay so now we know who we're talking
about a little bit about the law's
that are unquestionably awesome things
those in your account was discussed
planning security test with the awesome
I'm
before we meet a presentation sessions
and models on the outskirts of
we should briefly define what exactly
security testers
the ass in depth national security test
incorporates all the listed factors
security test must be quantifiable
consistent and repeatable
must be melody the on the now time frame
by using Yahoo give the test in a
personal way
time in the validity of the testator for
each model is given time the room will
remain Vale
that time could be measured an
indication wanna test should be read
minister came together
security test should be based on merit
the tester an analyst not on the brand
name
as I'm sure you're all aware there are
many companies out there that have the
best and brightest testers
if they lose the bet security test to
the five companies including as your mom
show
were really needs to come down to.
visibility in marriage to the tester and
not the name-brand
all test must be thorough and compliant
individual in local laws as well as the
right to be mad about privacy
but impressing me moral and ethical code
security testers have a moral obligation
wheeler company's human rights privacy
issues just because you have told them
what you need to tell them to be legal
doesn't mean you don't have to tell
another
security testing practices more
practical look at one needs to occur
for a test to be successful to find a
usable security not just pointing out
castle problems that might be possible
to fix
must make sure to look at all the
results against the business
justification
and after all we're talking about making
rest not eliminate
most about need to build trust that
means promote good security and do not
promote
paranoia with your customers the media
does a fine job promoting her know
enough for all of us
this subclans security playing an
awesome security test
I it's not necessarily selfless here
sign a contract mohegan network
although I'm sure a lot of credit that's
awesome about security just think it is
very dangerous well as conducting a
business plans security engagement takes
time
need understand many aspects to the
customer's requirements and engagement
as a whole
from there you'll be able to charm the
time man-hours placed target
and appointed presence this information
is needed before you can ever
begin before you can even begin to get
your attention
customer Press Club very difficult to
give an average time from
ask them to us one rule of thumb has
been submitted is
for every 10 physical IP addresses and
one tester
he has made 120 man-hours included for
generations this service is available
depending on how to meet individual
tasks are free model
and reorganization over all the time can
be determined from the number targets
services and systems that need to be
tested and how big is the client's
presence and was the extent of the best
typically the first step is completed
toward Houston security test is an
assessment assessment system any such
pieces that are used in conjunction with
one another to determine the overall
cost entitled to a full so so secure it
s
assessing the client was done either by
remote unobtrusive scanning
or ask your client thought a
questionnaire both when you are
attempting to determine is the cost
man-hours in resources it's going to
take me please curious
these variables are primarily determined
from your distance hoster the client
reliability involving and I want links
between
the size of the file in the presence
that they have down speeders private
client family should also be considered
as well as a systems integrator services
to contest
all these pieces of information combined
with previous experience in ministering
awesome tests
should we disagree professional to
reasonably accurate time and resources
on
remember as with any project management
time can be shortened by adding
additional resources to the broader
in says min techniques using include
these
the steps remember the final assessment
is determined costing man-hours
during the entire project said after the
project comprising
bow to the customer the point of this
does not go for security test the
possible presence
there's a fine line between susman
anatase you need to do another
after work to get a proper adjustment it
did not do too much to be done when he
always
resources that could have been used
elsewhere symbolizing the NTC these
games have used to scan a potential
client IP ranges
this will show you how many extra facing
internet addresses may need to be tested
during the gauge min
along some services that are being
offered DNS can and should be used to
look for any information to write the
address information
write a review will help determine choke
points for Dawson the loss as well as
well ISP's and networking between you
and Tori
network network registration view web
crawling search engine is recalling
chrome can determine additional
information leads and data for your
system
the task using this
in in the techniques we just discussed
in very while to vary wildly
US security first no need to weigh the
time invested
against the reward when the contract and
accuracy all the time
resource Boolean given some other tests
are less the Onslow
for example we look at name server:
responses in the former examining domain
registry information
finding the IP block on in question
primary/secondary nice the name servers
for Hosni like the addresses if the name
servers are not properly secured might
be able to get a list of all IP
addresses
host names that are published external
determine the outnumbered layer and
routers be a TCP an ICMP ping sweep
since gains
this another more advanced techniques
can be used to determine a semi accurate
network map was no word mess created
we can focus our surging more towards
external sources
including tracks InformationWeek's
searching por las
intrusion logs newsgroup postings much
data can be going on the target
organization
million another interesting way of
determining information about targeted a
surge in job available postings from the
company
these IT I'd these IT based postings
per requirements that many times you a
significant amount of data as the
operating system type of machine
application layer
and possibly network design so the tools
used in assessments
here is a little sick Muse together the
assessment data without spending a
significant amount of time
many of these tools can be scripted an
automated to make your assessment
information
gathering session significantly less
than the test
so after you spend time pointing the
assessment information about the
potential client you might possibly be
overdrawn that somewhat similar to this
normally the maps that are generated
from a security perspective simply
include the physical network devices
any interfaces to the public from other
important note on a picture we have here
are the information-gathering results
there are many more interfaces into an
organization just through the firewall
there's information leaks from the
mobile office laptops the Internet
results the newsgroup postings
all this data will combine improperly
mind can be pieced together to
interpolate much more in
important pieces of data the end result
of which might possibly be the
compromises client information resources
obviously there's more than one way into
a network as security professional your
job is to show the customer as many of
these
possible don't let yourself in what he
displayed a client only limit yourself
only
legally do demonstrated now move on to
the trooper
got to the presentation the security
testing process Dawn Askham style
the awesome defines the problem the
processor security test is being
evaluated on his four areas
visibility access trust an alarm all of
your output will be evaluated on these
for tennis
visibility visibility is what we what
can be seen
lot or monitored in the security
presence both with and without the aid
of electronic devices
this includes but is not limited to
radio waves like the other visible
spectrum
communication devices such as telephones
GSM email
and network packets of course TCPIP
access is an entry point into the
security presence
an access point need not be a physical
barrier
this can include but is not limited to a
web page window
a network connection radio waves or
anything in which location supports the
definition
quasi-public where computer interacts
with another computer with a network
limiting access means denying all
acceptable as expressly permitted
financially and in bed and best
practices trust trust is a specialized
pathway
in regards to the security presence
trust includes the kind and amount of
authentication
non-repudiation access control
accountability
confidentiality and integrity between
two or more factors within the security
presence
and last alarm alarms the timely and
appropriate notification other
activities that violate or attempt to
violate
any of the other three tenets visibility
access and trust
in most security breaches alarm is often
simple process which in it
which initiates further consequences
again we based review on the visibility
access and trust
and alarm the data that we receive back
for example 0 visibility might be less
IP addresses shown to the external world
an example have access may be streaming
media that your customer
probably allows access to for the users
is a business justified do they actually
have a need for it
do you have a high level access just
because
do you have a high level that's just
because are kind of just $5 for business
reasons
trust does the customer happy probably
love trust with
other was only proper entities and of
course are the alarms reasonable
if there are too many false alarms the
real ones will be drowned out
yet on the other hand if there aren't
enough alarms you'll be missing
important data
so let's look at the security in their
securing it is a visual display the
security presence
within the awesome we break the security
presence in the sections
models contest the sections directly
correspond to the six sections in the
security men
these actions represent the security
presence of the company
Internet Security Information Security
physical security
communications security while security
security training
there's a close above those sections
demonstrating how they look as a whole
the sections are the are the whole
security presents a model divided into
manageable testable slots
the connectedness of the map is also
significant importance
everywhere in the sections overlap there
is no overlap and definition
for example where security training
intersects all the bottom three
communications wireless internet
Internet Security it is understood that
there has to be security training in
each of those disciplines to the
customer
for security test to be successful
another example is physical security and
information security they overlap
because if I can get into your server
room with a Buddhist on one road
sheens there is a distinct interaction a
croatian between all the sections a
former for securing that for security
testing to go by
so its glory to the sections a little
closer physical security the ass the
breaks down the physical security
section in the six different models
access control testing parameter review
monitor and review alarm response review
location review environment review each
in these models and broken down into
specific tasks the security tester came
easily repeatedly performed to allow a
thorough testing a physical security
some example tasks might be to examine
the alarm types
test access control devices for
vulnerabilities and weaknesses
mad about the location of monitoring
devices discovery of the persons
involved alarm review
and testing will set alarm for seniors
before we move on to the next two
sections are the ask them I want to
point out of there was like presentation
a new security test for quite some time
now many years in fact
first time I saw the slide it really
brought together a lot of the
information that had been in my head
that didn't have a way
a great way to being visualized it also
had a lot of pieces that ensure
necessarily thought-out in reference to
security testing
the majority security tester straight
down a path always stay on the right
hand side
floater checking the network port
scanning says medication explore
research fire all testing IDS testing
personal service very few and sometimes
only the best security
testers take the time to do something
more obscure tests such as competitive
intelligence-gathering document grinding
contain measures testing all these tests
are outlined in the ass them as models
that have undergone significant a review
to meet the highest industry standards
in other words there's a lot more
security testing just the Internet
Security
we have the whole or half a picture here
information security to worry about it's
a lot like the next two months
information security this model is
important in the verification
much to the test information pertains to
many levels
what is considered information security
this section is now is desired by the
customer however there's much
information to be cleaned using some of
these techniques
the information found can help piece
together some missing parts when it
comes to what end result the customer
really does want to see
tasks in this model includes surging
newsgroups for references to and
submissions from
people within the organization certain
documents for impose a revision data
such as tracking changes being loved on
I examine p2p networks for references to
as a mission from within the
organization
any and all this information is publicly
available can be used to penetrate
gather additional data
during the security test Internet
Security
can change where the majority played and
quite possibly have you
expertise it's the largest others as
large as the sections in the oslo
we break down the Internet Security
section many models network serving
port scanning services identification
systems identification ball early
research and verification
Internet applications containment
measures testing password cracking
and dos de dos the Oscar mistaken he
reviews from professionals in hand
worldwide and each of these models and
the tests that are involved to complete
these models
it really isn't the scope of this
presentation go into detail into these
models
I mean I can you can talk for hours
might get a little detail I however
employees should you go look at
WWW dot idea hamster doubt we're and
take a look at these models for yourself
in joining other peer review process
your comments to help to grow on
his day WWW dot idea hamster
8 a.m. STR die hoerer or senior running
a business card if anybody wants them so
communications security
this section goes over the models in
tasks involved in gaining access
privileges to the telephone exchange a
target organization
section is broken down into PDX testing
voice mail testing fax review and modem
testing
these models do yield significant
information in majority
organizations a lot of times this
section is overlooked by companies
the Zimbabwe tests include
were telling brute force can attest fax
machine detection and location
verification remote authentication
mechanisms
security training
I personally don't care for the name in
this model to me it's more
should be called social engineering
which is really what it is how do you
test security training
one effective ways to 10 social
engineering to see who's educated on it
I'm the way that suggested mister social
engineering attacks with broken down the
section 23 models
external requests forged internal
requests
and guided suggestion as an example
external request model brakes in the
test such as clearing gateway personnel
over standard communications media when
the Gateway person themselves
have the authority to grant access
privileges to others the force
internal request model involves
impersonating a trusting person
to subvert the internal the internal
person to disclose information
concerning the target organization
got a suggestion module involve
subverting trust
be a guy person at the other end a
communication medium
into downloading or gone to specific
militia locations and Alan specific on
to
wireless security
I grown significantly in the past in the
recent past
as such the oscar has increased as much
don't ask our
in the section to match while security
for only includes wireless network
scoreless communication testing
public and private privacy requirements
infrared systems
this mother's going to pass a review and
testing is new techniques come into
being
test requirements depending on the
country or perform the test from quite
possibly the country decline cell
you have to consider many important
factors prior to completing a task
just like you get out of jail free card
twice together this information early on
in the process
the company's name and legal address as
well as all contact information
this includes the lead tech resources as
well as the officers of the company that
are sponsoring the project you need to
have both
written legal contract with the target
organization
you get out of jail free card and
sometimes depending on the countries
that are involved
written legal contract for the hosting
it the right ski that's definitely
something you need to consider if you're
working
intern around europe it all does a
customer require all the %ah some
sections or just a subset of those
sections
need to define which is the security
testing styles you'll be performing in
to what degree
you also need to define what your goals
are going to be
these are the primary goals in Austin
test
by using the sections models in tasks in
the awesome
you'll be able to assess the security of
the organization as a whole
we're giving them proven best practices
completing the steps of the last contest
you'll be able to recognize and
quantified
the business risk that an organization
has as well as privacy issues both
internal and external to the
organization
from the gathering of all this data it
will be very straight forward to suggest
and how to implement practical
security solutions to customer who
having the ass the methodology behind
you during the test also allow you to
fall back on the best practices in the
industry
and the customer will know what you can
give them
but let's talk about women to the
security test you have to be sure many
things we're doing security test the
most part of which is do not cause any
unauthorized downtime in losses revenue
to the customer that's very key
doing so is very detrimental to your
credentials as a security professional
try not to leave the customer into a
false sense of security and avoid the
politics within the organization if at
all possible
be careful not to waste
any resources and organization in the
form of unintentional alarm status
if there's a goal of the test previously
stated during the goal outline stages
triggering alarm states in reviewing
responses is acceptable
in other words be careful and always
know your limits to overstep the bounds
custom reporting requirements
to achieve lasting certification on a
test the security practitioner must meet
reporting requirements this is kinda key
it's it's the deliverables to the
customer and it has to meet certain
deliverable standards for
areas within the within the testing be
careful
these environmentalists and displayed in
the awesome itself
furry for client review prior to the
engagement so they know what to expect
from the security tester
the sections in the report are listed on
the slide
most the look fairly obvious as their
need of course the security testing
still
be an awesome task enough to report
doesn't have all the sections
assuming that is restricted because
those sections are Catholic a bowler
within stop other customers requirements
as we've shown the oscar has divided the
model sections in tests
the sections directly correspond to the
main divisions
security map and also in direct relation
to the internet presence points
when doing in Austin test the security
tester flows from one model to the next
model by using the tasks listed in each
model
the input to a model when processed
using the tasks listed
will generate expected output that our
present a Canon fed into the next march
on augmented with additional input
information
this model generous the next set of
buttons on and so on
the output is simply a result of the
completed tasks
a model based on the input into it
here's a summary slide in the sections
that we went through
a long way to the models and make up
those sections if you really want to get
into further detail with a break the
slide down into additional levels in
right out the tasks that are defined
within each of the models
the flow then be blatantly obvious it's
either in protest
was required for the upper castes and
the output as it flows from model to
model
drop methodology so what happens if we
do a module has no output doesn't
necessarily mean that you get the model
wrong they could certainly indicate a
tester inability
but more than likely indicates very
tight security from the organization
it doesn't have to mean that either it
could mean that the model was not after
the ball to what the organization
requires or that the output of the test
has been properly analyzed by the tester
if for some reason it s really give you
know output or incomprehensible output
is the job of the tester and quite
possibly protesters to look for each
other's shoulders and double check the
validity of a
model results if they come back they
love they come back they out there was
no upward
saws lectures looking model here
I'll this is kinda form and the template
within
within the ask them for module on
but easy internet security sector the
asteroid as an example to get noticed
that pretty well
at the top you can see the name of the
model for our
for our example within section 1 that
might say system identification
underneath that is the description of
the model for system identification
would say
something to the effect that system
fingerprinting is the active probe into
the system for response was
they can distinguish unique systems to
the operating system inversion layer
with endless the expected results for
this particular model
Willis the expected results because if
you don't know what you're looking for a
security test you're going to end up
spinning your wheels looking for
something you never gonna find
our example unexpected results for that
further I'm for the what we're talking
about is OS Type
patch level system type system
enumeration and internal system that
worked for us
finally at the bottom is listed the
tasks to perform to complete the module
the inputs to the model would have come
from previous models while the outputs
gathered from this model feeding
future models in your test says we're
doing system identification some other
tasks listed in the Oscar for this model
including
exam system responses to determine
operating system type in caps while
examine application responses to
determine operating system type in patch
low
search job postings for server
application information from the target
Center processor security test
definition other process types of an
awesome task just like any good security
test even break up the models and gas
into categories
passive passive an intrusive attacks
passive attacks will not a factor
trespass on the party system that all
no degradation a remote services in the
least intrusive it s
will trespass on target systems or
networks and quite possibly can degrade
or you
can degrade or utilize services I
dedicated sniffer box being a test never
gonna probably checkpoint pass attack
same flight on the web server to
discover the believe the router and
server they have a high traffic loads or
settled awesome their network in Jersey
today evaluation about
on this is a very important pieces
security puzzle you need to understand
how to get away all the up a base
based upon the tests that are completed
so stick with the growing process around
long time for some slightly less on
again collected for tennis visibility
access trust an alarm
when the office returns from its the
models a good security tester a
valuation
its visibility on I know none of us in
this room is there a company
organization tell us
oh that machine yeah we don't publish
that machine's IP address
so nobody knows it's there well it's
visible in class
high visibility to anyone who is
actively searching the company's IP
address space
so knowing the course title systems the
all of your office should be looked
efforts visibility bomb
to an external source access
access as the date is returned from the
models we need to evaluate against its
accessibility
I really need access the web 13 do you
really need web access to mp3 files for
your internal users
do you really need stream media from CNN
dot com
all data must be evaluated against
access
is a business justified is basically the
question you need to ask yourself in the
past
trust
how much people trust your systems to be
a with her I was gonna trust integrity
of the data that you are sending them
so piece the puzzle hood of education
before data submitted
non-repudiation the data access control
so the data and data confidentiality
to the business partners have a higher
level of trust in the shirt or the
limited what they really need to know
and lasses
alarm
from my experience is quite often this
is the weakest link in an organization's
security measures
I'm too many false alarms the true
alarms are going to ground out too many
alarms
and you're bound to be missing some the
right one some other ones there's a fine
line to the large quantity
that meets but does not exceed
expectations
make sure the company is not crying wolf
also know what alarm systems are being
used in if they're adequate the case the
offer that is common for the models
conclusions in conclusion the Austin is
the industry's attempt to legitimize the
security testing profession
make the professional live up to the
standards are the best in the broader
security testers they contribute to the
manual on a regular basis
if you read the manual and determine
their something that were missing
submit if you read the main on the term
there something you know they shouldn't
be there
submitted and last but not least if you
like what you see
join the peer review process and check
other people submissions
please take the time to visit www.ypd
idea idea hamster died or
join the mailing lists and the peer
review process
thank you for your time %ah
I don't see a lot of emphasis on
identifying
organization's assets for asylum test
that one of the modules farm incorporate
across the board in a few models
him go down the task level on it may be
something we should expand on
I I seriously consider that is something
that's growing attention moslems are
and I also see an emphasis on the
outside this outsider
that's right Martin's desperate this the
it is put on a targeted
a outside threat is not necessarily
something in use an internal
security audit although he applied also
I'm not sure I see a lot of
was a review policies and procedures
it's there at the test load gets down to
that I don't break down so far
you know like I said this presentation
its 340
go hollowing out into itself
him talking longs G of the most
home and just went in with family more
fly in slow here dome
in the testers are located or something
it's both is absolutely both
the lost bar is is something that
actually I don't know enough about I
think a lot of testers a lot of people
tripping don't necessarily know nothing
about have a few lawyers they contribute
so is lost love try to incorporate as
best we can
on but we can use any additional
resources that people can
condoning that area
note that the last
a lot of changes does it
include any guidelines are modules
dealing with their re: rations with you
the cost
testing legs attention business partners
or
songs yes in not specifically in essence
it would say this is a model pertaining
to that
but again there something this folding
and a theme across because
the he happily all Europe based on trust
and
right so a lot of that if you have
something like that
you creations business for
as answers to your questions
is it do you I'll foreign go as far as
access spores getting into partners
areas
not per se person stepped on something
needs mint
a
you have a law firm that you don't have
response
the long as a holes category you have a
list what services are all
you know that the contingencies the
analysis at the control
those services so let's say is that is a
Korean you want the screaming
study committee the quote you want to be
able to analyze
who controls turning it on all of their
ability to turn it on or
then what are your responses when the
along those lines alarms something you
you going which outfit based upon it's
not that it's a module
say so if you look at physical let's
look at physical
security server some other tasks are to
you trigger the alarm to look at the
responses
so I think what you're talking about is
is test level stuff
then you're building which is based upon
the alarms said they sense
yes but I'm saying both
analysis is a response structure let's
say there's a fire
I would have long yeah as you analyze
stuff
you don't have I don't believe that with
the building were things need to be say
who is it that does it there your see
the whole structure
involved in at a response the long after
those of
is the analog catch me after what I have
a heart that would go through but mostly
tasks in there that address that I don't
know that s global
and I've been rising in some other these
documents show but already there's test
levels to go over there
state sovereignty
eyes his its original
mission other use simply certainly
recisions
lobbyists toward
see are cause people fibers
luck clinton's and unfortunately
I think for are security his
calls this least said wells doing
world a host policy or when workers
little me what what we and haven't
convinced
Bulls me since I
Sonata too much in essence to for
specifics on that
from again I'm not a lawyer so I I lost
over
loss and I don't know nearly to the
degree that a yes
you know problem no but in essence we
try to incorporate that the pieces of
the laws that say
whole day this month time if they're in
effect
as a law we have to do you know I'm
whether the writer on majority the time
copyright and I agree completely we have
included in the
in the methodology something we have to
do until you get 'em
take now you know once there want to
remove the group from
national I donning snow setting
three minutes
okay thank you %ah
up