all
oh my friend Tim Smith with me and Craig
I don't know you listening but in this
business a lot of people don't do their
last names
bro army army
give me a couple rar day pirate radio
I'll my radio
and I have had a lot of experience that
I guess
one of the reasons you folks here are
you're here is to
get more and perspective on
free radio pirate radio edit call
I myself have been involved in
broadcasting
one way or the other is the last thirty
years
and it started with me it back in the
nineteen sixties
when I was about 15 years old and I so
love program on ABC television affecting
one digit
and shortly holes here this
you know women look at it computer
screens plans a fancy new technology
Wireless something goals saloon old well
Wallace
I grew up with was a lot bigger than
this this is what we're talking about
today
this is a Radio Shack the X 396
a.m. SM short way receive
so the program is right here
but anyway %uh back when I was a little
yellow younger lead so this program on
NBC television about
the golden days a great documentary is a
block away
was in the sixties 1tb and
they were talking about how radio came
into the law is
is the holes people all across this
great land
and hell this
but late twenties and thirties there
wasn't any television
little bit experimentally but not on
television broadcast
as we know certainly no computers and
phone lines well a strong but it was
pretty expensive to make a long distance
call
in those so people had real brought it
to their homes
fireside chats by FDR the show
you know miss CVS mystery theater all
the different stuff
the head so office during the day news
reports
people would come home after a hard
day's work crowd around the radio and
needless said
and they use their mind to paint
pictures
sociology and I saw this
and I said she I what
one of these grades really do and I said
my head it's how I go about doing this
cellulose as a
nonetheless I told my mother about it
and she said well
why don't you write a letter to the
federal government
and ask them how you can get your own
radio station
I'll some also
that and
so I'll probably that and I got this
nice little four-letter
backs you know informing me that radio
stations especially
because I live in Yonkers New York to of
course
millions and millions of dollars to bill
and
that we suggest that you get it ham
radio
if you have any interest in raid so I
said to myself
this will not do I want brought his
I mean a lot of my friends and school
were kinda a
especially old rates were and Apple
around Camry
and stuff like that which is great fast
but i wanna protest I want every one of
these people that
access to the airwaves got on the air of
people
play music maybe had inspired
this is so I think about you is so
que estas finally I have had a
and hide other the equivalent and in the
basement at my parents house at 2:45
yielded Yonkers New York
are in October I think
I'll 1968 or 1969 I put on
a 51 a.m.
radio station with the call is w
are a the raat standing for
the first lady's radio when only a city
what's
little the game would yes people doing
now
in 1620 and we
put them we still spree actually we sell
strange pictures /a
mister natural which is on the top page
they are plastered all over the high
school
Arlington High School I was going to
saying that you know
a new radio station is gonna take to the
and sure enough I think it was October
22nd
1968 1960 went on here
and we broadcasted
on billing records music I had came out
of my father's a
record collection he had a combination
but shot shot music itself
beethoven stuff so the the first musical
selections
not the greatest thing but we were not
we operate for about three days
about it an hour each afternoon as I get
home from school at 3:30
we go on the air 4 and weed out late so
far are usually by five o'clock my
mother was hanging around the kitchen
begin to prepare suffers I think it'll
be a cool time ago of the year
because you know when you wanna higher
radio station you gotta kinda faded into
your life
its at the time so we operate for about
three or four days in all over you know
was listening to listen all up
all our friends in high school picking
it up all over the
southern part is on youngest New York
why even so the teachers and the
principal
high school was listening say they
should be arrested what they're doing
by actually what happened this
three days %uh there was a not not not
front door the house and i remember i
wont database
is basing his own hedges walked around
of the
the driveway looked with front door the
house was
just like in the movies I see to God's
with to our cats and black trench coats
standing see its
so quickly run back to the base couple
of my friends
we were doing program together I said
the SEC is here
and Avon slight it's likely that just
just like in a cartoon they were like
out the back door I ran out the back
door
and I and I went over to my friends
house I stayed here for a couple hours
and then I came back and my mother who
ran interference
actually she's pretty cool she said well
they all went downstairs need to listen
to the radio transmitters
and done the hilly you know they they
want to see this letter that what you're
doing is against the law
a local historical issued by the house
you know at all you know
certain some some some TN K and stuff
like that
they said well you know you're your son
is a very intelligent person but what
he's doing is
is definitely is slowly can't do that
anymore
and that is it so I I got a hole in my
father said well so
you know I'll looks like you really
can't do this I hate
think a lot of people like people
told so can do this yeah
so early to say remove some
to transmitter that cuts and cable
though the transmitter
I'll and I guess within an hour to I
passed everything back together
I know they took the Treasury 220 they
said although the following the 08 07 08
case it is always weird
all transferred into because it was a
military surplus transferred from World
War two
so I remember that me and my friends and
I went down to Canal Street area here in
New York City which is a great place to
get stuff
and picked up a set to five boxes
something like that
that stuff sure enough months later we
will rock and roll again so speaking all
this %uh
going through the multiple radio station
we had to be
went to FN every again II made
couple other people we set up the
station in North yonkers is
station south field office we
exclusively operated on 16:20 a.m.
and a 7.9 ed which i think some people
hire
New York City area still has a dark band
between the
or a carrier channel 6's be getting yes
yes so we did that for quite a while
all through through the years 1971
we actually had 30 to 40 people
%uh working at the station all my
friends in high school all kids in the
area
and you know it was really cool because
we were doing stuff creatively
with the pirate stations or the free
radio stations cool
we were probably 10 very the while the
very first day since 1970 1971
that began detail i phone calls
over-the-air
without delay and we would invite people
to get access to radio New York area
by calling us I'll and we were just
patched
directly using crews phone patches times
you know the phones
telephones back in the sixties and
seventies scenes
nobody could touch the falls we fade
away
taxes phone lines a little years
and I'll we of course we're playing all
latest rock and roll music which was
exploding in diversity in the late
sixties
this is still is you know this is kinda
special
and we were really really happened a lot
of helpful
and I think a contributing to the radio
are in itself you making an absolute
well hopefully a positive contribution
getting a lot of people in the area
political
programs for since the war in Vietnam
that time
no one talk page in history here but it
was this is more vietnam a lot of people
were very upset
and all my friends in high school
buddies were set you know
that who had accessed radio is no access
radios stereo much controlled by session
in New York area
by major family concerns in business
so that it goes unheard for anybody
getting Airtel
toothbrushes anything that would rock
Bowl status quo
was there was some commercial
pro-civil so
we ran the station until August 1971
we were probably busted and busted good
%uh they came in with tractor-trailers
and federal agents
and they showed are stationed down
august twelfth 1971
they arrested myself my partner
other was down to Foley Square through
the city jail cell
and only with a chance Smith
remember this in the cell
this mother rachel is father rate
all kinds of weird people in Excel
they come up to us and they say I
worrying for running a radio station
with this words but
you know any we r we got outta your way
we were charged with several counts
violated
Broadcasting Act the Telecommunications
Act 1934 which
base States I those people the house a
lot transmitted without a license
we were not fun because they think
you're doing it they do that a lot
I'll and we will release our own
recognizance
I'll we had the requisite representation
we got off with about one year probation
and they did
conversely formal
and they were there was a lot of sweet
had a lot of a
disinterested in here we we are also
experimenting with television
before the finally lower the bill
we were putting some signals on channel
six in the New York City area
definitely getting a lot of people
assert that
but and television pull back then really
expensive me
TV cameras hundreds of thousands of
dollars
up but we were playing around with old
surveillance cams
Douglas earth selfless
world war two televisions is it is
designed
the availability of equipment to do free
radio
nano is of thousands of lives fall
then what was available that sexists
so the moral of the story is on
we did we got busted and then I got into
more
which is like radio but I still hired
and my last official pirate radio
station
was shut down in nineteen he to
and I and II who had moved to me
up in northern Maine but I Bild AM a
radio station up there used 400 for
towers legal station but at night
we would take forever for telling feet
I'll a.m. into it propagate all he
scores the United States
and finally SEC kinda it really bothers
the kinda got to do with so we shut down
now is it that was the last pirate
radio I are I Detroit
cover radio in New York City area
because I always wanted to put a
high-powered
legal free station in the New York City
area
and back in 1987 I partnership
off the coast of Long Island New York
and went on the air
with the 5000 Watts 1620 and
1000 Watts 10 3.1
and that lasted a total of about four
days was the three or four days
Haji saying and
well they came out with more than the
SEC nation is there
but the I don't miss it hired station I
can see that perfectly legal as we were
outside three mile territorial limit
so now on fast-forwarding going through
other miscellaneous commercial stations
that i've been involved with
so now about about four years ago
I said I'll thank you for you
love it yeah all
so we operate yeah unfortunately to say
she didn't last very long but it
definitely made a lot of ways
fast-forwarding to what's happening now
is there's a different kinda radio
that's available
and pirate radio now
is now spending a lot of time on
something known sure
way how do you know what short-wave
radios
raise your hands up lastly to the
completely
you know and am
all necessary this is surely receive it
four years ago
after thirty years
up fighting with the Federal
Communications Commission they finally
granted a licence
to bill a fifty thousand lot sure
way station I'll on my property
in northern Maine same property that
we've hired at back in 1982
and I operate radio station along
10 on that's known as WBC
cue the plan and we went on the air
it shows
said yeah
this is a more past holeshot that that's
the entrances station or early May
is in the middle of nowhere lately with
trailer
complete with trailers and buses this
storage in all this stuff
yes it's your down-home Tobacco Road
radio station
but them we believe this station
as I said about four years ago 1998
and
a we operated as a as an
some people call WBC hugh
the country's first slices hired what we
do is
we we offer a retired anyone that wants
to get on the air like you
WDC the some other folks
off the hook right um and
we offer air time we have we have to
charge a nominal fee for it because
running a 50 kilowatt transfer is very
expensive that that's one of our
transmitters there
and we operate this station
and it has the philosophy of giving
people access to
the airwaves and giving them and an
opportunity
to get their message uncensored and
and you guys can attest to that I
uncensored
all over our are Airways no short wave
I believe is turning into this
kinda marvelous all underground medium
on as people throughout the world you're
getting more discontent with the 100 on
both
local AM and FM they're going out and
buying yeah
short-wave radios which is very
inexpensive I mean you can spend twenty
dollars alone you can spend two thousand
dollars on the go the whole
that this one was and a seventy busses
so and yet on this one oh yeah
sw1 I go sleep tonight also Affordable
Art
I would be fine with me I had one but it
all looks like dropped into the salt
water that was the end
yelling this is il-1
yeah this is this is a well the front
panel for a car radio that's only makes
which also picks up short wave
and boats so
you know there's lotsa lots of
opportunities to get short-wave radios
now that you know what's happening with
short-wave is
people throughout the country in the
world tuning into shortly
now to hear wild and wacky stuff
and WBC hugh mom
I'm proud to report definitely has a lot
of wild and wacky stuff on
takin a website WBC cue dotnet
in your spare time go to it
and you can download our complete
broadcast schedule
I can give you a tip the weekends is the
best unfortunately
commit well it's unfortunately the the
reality is to keep
on money coming into the coffers
we do sell time to which is organs old
Bible
leaders says we do we do sell time to
the bottom feeders
up but we do that because it costs a lot
of money to run the transmitters
able to operate the may L what one
transmitting to is a thousand dollars
to replace its big star but the
government requires
an international short way station have
a minimal output power 50,000 once a
week after here
to the SEC's rules even though we could
do the same
10 but it's the gold and
that's one of our transmitters they're
actually under construction as well it's
a little messy
and in their old photos
in finding new ones but anyway on
and you know so we do as I said we we
charge a nominal fee we get people on
here but it's actually a very
fascinating radio station and I believe
that even with the internet which is a
great resource in which we use now to
connect a lot of people %uh we just some
of our clients we just pick up
a couple of their website protest too
much away but the nice thing about short
wave is
and the nice thing about me is is that
its it's simple and to most people
it's so simple they can just pick up a
receipt
and I know that a lot I did you hear
love you folks here this morning
probably here because you're interested
including your old radio station here
I can say this I have this is you know
why
yes as a license protester I cannot
advocate
or encourage neru to build your own
pirate radio station buy the premade
okay I G I can't do that but I can
certainly understand
why you wouldn't want to because
unfortunately the government has not
even with the LPS and how many you know
about low-power
yeah even with all PSN they had it done
we all hoped they would do and that is
provide fans at frequencies with people
could literally put on
amateur broadcasting stations easily in
South
we just send in an application find a
frequency
which'll probably have to share with
lots of others go on here
LPFM distillers still you know is only a
certain numbers stations congress
definitely swells it back because
majorette and
protesters in his country was offering
there was actually something different
than
both done so many you're probably
thinking about this
what I have learned through the years is
people that engage in free radio
hire a radio or Rhys several things
if you put a station on the air %uh the
new tactic that the government does now
as they come in they arrest all here
with meaning if you set up a situation
like this on shortwave
using a converted him transmitter we
have any other stuff
the notice surely this high frequency
stuff on this
you know there are closes FM
transfers them by from all kinds of
companies one that comes to mind is
ramzi kits they sell their on the net
ramzi they sell Heinz's FM transmitters
people is a plug-and-play violence that
he had a building from scratch in the
back in the 60s sixties and seventies
today just said a way to get one but
you go on the air and generally will
give you a few mornings
you know they might knock on your door
they might the fine you
ten thousand dollars or something like
that but generally with new ones if you
don't stop
come in there and start trading your
equipment and Ray
things out yes a task in line for your
transmitter
your computer doctor transmitter run run
from the pic to
yeah well they'll go beyond that i mean
they are built a furniture
it depends on the st. they wanna be
they'll take furniture they'll clean
your house out because the sale of
everything he was used
in the commission of this crime oh
absolutely let's go
you know CDs goal now they don't do this
at all
I mean the SEC's like anybody knows look
you know like any
bureaucracy the always look for the easy
fast cheap way out
so generally give a couple warnings and
whatever but there have been some
you know pirate broadcasters that done
get on the air and
other they find and they lose and
and then they come in
a there a village by I can tell you this
is after all the years I've done radio
if you go to any kind of real may she
doing missions
if you wanna get only a religious play
music
basically radio mister B gonna
set up an internet radio station you
know yeah I know
I know that's that's that's a whole
different problem now which is
disgusting
that's the way it is a anytime anybody
develop something good fun
heroes people figure out how to make
money on
so if you can if you take a transmitter
and do something with it that is not you
know
the status quo however you wanna call
just be careful lectures for good reason
anytime that we would do higher radio
%uh we did because there was a reason
you know whether it was
allowing people to get access have free
expression
to here expressing political dissent
in fact the I don't think there are any
clandestine radio
you know clandestine stations you know
it was politically motivated
motivated stations currently operating
country there had been
work done those are you gonna do it
which I can't encourage you to do but if
you couldn't do it
make sure this worked on good reason he
just want to get on the airplane using
whatever
listens yourself and you know that there
are risks involved because they also
fun they also will find you and the
fines are usually have to use you try to
give you a whopping fine like they'll
start out with twenty thousand dollars
in annual
notice in all look right and maybe a
little reduces
5 deliver %uh and a lot of people I know
that have gotten day and hopefully find
love
never really paid the fine but it's
still nd still in action
got a deal so you free radio make sure
it's for a good reason because the end
and as I can advocate because my
position
but I do understand why it happens their
communities there
group of people that while access
to radio in a community or see
and adjust on the channel's left images
no way
then do it and they get frustrated and
they go on the air
I i understand that because I was one of
those people
on we do WBC hugh
has a a time and we make it available at
special rates
for people that are trying to do free
radiance
really different so if any of you out
there are
actually it was thinking really do is
radio broadcasting
wanna get on the short wave is covers
times all the world you know we've the
mars signal at a northern made using
this star
but I think there's a picture or yeah
it's one of our intent is
over are it's a it kinda looks like a
gigantic TV antenna that the elements
like sixty feet long
you know it's better we being out till
using in 10 days like this at a northern
maybe meeting that we we we being
towards mexico but obviously the united
states in the way
so we cover we cover a lot of the US
we get into Europe we get your signal
out so
if you want more information on us the
WBC cue the
we also have decided WBC to dot com
are that's we we have an audio stream
therefore our main service on 741 fights
the WBC cued up that
WBC cue that com I don't forget complex
variables
right well we have lots of photographs
complex variables
studio dot com 11 right now don't like
that the whole morning world like this
is all a work
complex variables studio dot com that
will %uh
that will get you to a site that we have
lots of photographs
and CDC she station but we help get your
signal
and your message on the air other rates
are low in charge a fee
per hour but we have to because its
electricity in obviously
we have to hire you know I have people
that help us gotta pay them
some to operate the equipment arm
and we'll get you on the above
but I do encourage everyone out there
too invests
shortwave radio and radar frequency down
my dear friend because that's where we
operate on the short way
that's our main frequency: our main
frequency at me
is 7.4 15 megahertz
and a good time to listen is on
the weekends especially tonight 82
midnight
Radio New York International those on
the year
from Brooklyn New York yeah
Smith heiress a mike capps there if you
could kindly use it
who
by any Jr I
does it all I hear you farm by censors
you meet people
it's a felony which the workers on
amateur radio I was told that
using selling over the airwaves are well
we
we had programmers Melissa right here
that
use four-letter words are the BBC's you
i mean obviously only encourage it but
we do not tell people
that they can't say is can say that we
we tell them to use good judgment
in you know whatever they do but we do
have programmers that play music
and comedy bits that had some the
you know George Carlin seven dirty words
and idaho
i'd of are
me they have yeah
well the government can come in anytime
and cleary us
on whatever we program but the actually
in all honesty in the SEC
dominate you might find this hard to
believe the SEC
has actually been very good to our
station
arm they had cut us a lot of leeway
because they know who we are from RKS
and
and they have not ever ever bother us
for any our programming content because
they don't like to get into that this is
something call
the first amendment and WBC he was a
member station
for us the first love radio transmitter
in society
when we are also the station that is
dedicated to
free speech that is what we do
yes our
since his earnings does the Constitution
at large reason point
the federal communications at quotes
its stores the his cameras
was you know this is customs correct I
believe that follow the basis for
yes numbers is the practice exchange
purposes game so advertising products
yesterday allies finances
the SEC Wednesday's
and other activities was today trade
the trade by
yes because
listen i i huge argument isn't it
actually goes beyond that because a lot
of people there
pirated have actually said well if our
signal does not go over to stay
boundaries that why does the SEC have
jurisdiction the
the federal government under access
congress claims
authority over anything transmitted from
from its shores and into
Beach Shores John guy play Missouri to
hear
guns Brightwell this is I hear what you
sayin your
your argument is arguments that we have
used in core
but the courts do not recognize it they
really look at the SEC is the ultimate
licensing authority
and if the SEC comes out and says
we are gonna start licensee be easily
like coming out of the spotlight
projectors
it can happen I don't know
how the action would be framed but there
are
at his lawyers that well word refer to
as
this in action re: 88 fishbowl will
war until the SEC should be yes
in North in a hearing to show
their authority and was nations they
by the way say they've been challenged
and unfortunately
other people that obviously radio
stations have challenged them
on similar to the issues that you bring
up
the course on C they just don't see keep
it up
the US District Courts for the readings
days
limited jurisdiction I bush
they had yes here any cases at all
involving citizen status when the data
MC gathers
they don't get this here ninety-five
percent cases they
pretending here I'll good
all before we taking your questions a my
brother in arms here Tim Smith 10 Tron
has been involved in radio
and in ham radio for years and years and
years and I'm sure
that you have to look different take
yeah I'm sure you have something to a
total I do
so please by all well take the
mobile falling polling book she owns
pirate efforts well all flamboyant lot
further ahead than mine never got well
big differences is he was busted
I have a while so certain facts I'm
going to have to withhold
but it all started back many many many
years ago I was just
a little over I love to listen to the
radio I love to listen to rock and roll
music which was back in the fifties
but it was all be getting it will fall
and follow
radio fascinated me know and after a
while
I started beginning to wonder hola
sustained work
them one day when I was about a mile and
a half years old one dad brought home a
popular radio amateurs hanbo
and I'm part through that thing and I
saw last instruction articles on
building receivers bowling transmitters
and I didn't think you know or
understand what
really was going on but I had on when I
was about 12 years old I started
building my first 22
AM radios those June well
rock and roll music on and I was
teaching music on something
so I built but after a while I was
saying
what is it to a transmitter and she had
lost the solo home wireless
follow selena is basically a little 12
transmitter where you take the offer
your pornographic jacket and
and listen to it through the radio a
very rudimentary transmitter
best but I E begin to figure out that
there's a lot more to
transmitter that just 112 lber then one
time
why won't the summer camp I attended an
electronics
kinda class or activity or whatever you
want to call the most popular thing
where these launches transmitters made
by this probably known as like shit
there was a real transmitter it had a
we'll also later
real modulator a real speech input
section if you will well they cost
twelve dollars and ninety five cents in
1962 when I
big he did with my mother for money
russians tucci
but I've got one under the Christmas
tree and I
sure the whole thing together all set up
ready to rock and roll out a hundred
feel why rock as an antenna
I hold on to what and needless to say
the range was
said I kept wondering how I'm going to
improve this thing
how are you going to make it better and
I lay in bed at night
thinking about those 22 radios like bill
how one stage was an RF amplifier that
signal from the Intel
ample quiet said to a detector and I
said
hmm maybe I can turn this thing around
ass backwards
make and ample fire for transmitter
well I had quite a star parts
back down parts were half from old TV
sets a friend of mine and I would get up
every Saturday morning and pedal our
asses down the local TomTom
stir parts of the whole TV sets
transformers
tombs capacitors resistors on on it
nauseam sites altogether an amplifier
using what was known as a
for solace sweet to output the horse all
sweet section of the TV set
ball the most amount of power in the
shower so obviously the two men fall
was largest forget about today's TV sets
the transistors that they use just are
are unsuitable
for broadcast we're side of the little
amplifier
it sure worked yeah fight it all the
rage
but things like two inserts I did not
understand that one day
dawn broke over Marblehead and I chichi
other
a transmitter that probably delivered
about 25 wats of which I'd still have
desert lush AP but I still have the
thing
and I'll all the thing which is a term
use
to impossible under the antenna and I
call a buddy of mine up
lose about eight miles away and he
started twenty right now I
Chevron station down around 800 on the
dial just a bit above WABC
and he's touring around here in the
stopper the background were all
citizens like Wow monsoons get
mammals call so after school every day
I was on the year but basically I
thought the stretch more for frontline's
a birthday present so after about three
weeks
he got his presence but in the meantime
my mother was full of questions
so she wrote a letter to the feces
better known as the FCC
and then responded back with a little
camp for title does my transmitter need
a license
well after that point I i'm kind of
operating a clandestine
matter when it came to doing pirate
radio by other transmitters I got up did
not point he
or what I hate bill given to my friend
but the Saints for amateur radio always
interested me to hobnob with other
people ever in the rolling
their own transmitters together and just
using them to communicate have a good
time with
and I started listening around only all
hella crafter shortwave radio that was
given to me as a Christmas present that
my mother follow the neighbor's trash
him
with great interest to the ham radio
people on a.m. on 75 meters
that any time I started thinking about
all
well I really want to get the ham radio
but the Morse hole was a huge stumbling
block
so I thought on as what was known as 0
like you or just simply
up boot well a few months later
I eventually saw I'll learning Morse
code which idea and I finally went
through the upgrades and all that kind
of thing but my first nation
for music and broadcasting and
entertainment
never left me well back in the ER only
shows
he is she just backing things up a bit
most my operations always been on
amplitude modulation most people operate
site
I don't care for site member to delete I
don't care for the audio quality granite
is more spectrum
vision and it gets better as far as
bang for the buck but in terms of of the
dalai its simplicity for
get don't even waste your time with it
yeah I understand a lot of today's
shortwave pirates are using it Hall
for out %ah
stars all door latch
turn off but anyway
I started listening wrong on other bands
either side amateur bands such as the
International shortwave bands in just
over 49 meter band
and the daytime was virtually vacant
except for a few Canadians
on one single on ham radio strictly
verboten to play music
yet my friends of mine and I will get on
and drop tombs occasionally to test our
translators who would get all the whole
buzzards all in
all rage in over or what not
did should be checked for play music
wrong here
start thinking about forty nine meters
consider myself
now she was a chopper spectrum is not
being used during the daytime
widely making sure that solo it's no big
thing
to move in and Richard transmitter all
the amateur bands
I had a bunch of crystals on the six
megahertz range in mostar
passion about my body's and before you
know what
we're all up on 49 meters every Saturday
morning
after partying from the night before
Sunday
and we just stay tuned back and forth
back and forth no I'm
deeds that one other gods got all air
and open up the microphone Human
Services WTK says
Florida well there's a little
publication owners
about it wasn't the H those another
publication
and they're all these %uh loggins
for these unidentified music stations on
forty nine meters
and the only clue they gave was station
calling itself
WTK seasons Florida and then after a
while I said
him this is possibilities well
the little while later i holed up in
chief engineer
of a little a.m. day-timer this whole
the slow
and I haven't harder on this console
which had a little mention border two
turntables all the time to do the
remotes
that they did quite a few about 30 times
when we weren't using it might bring
nothing in my way up
him station which was a whole building
on occupied
and I would have these parties on the
dollar sitcom of the week
really get traction I take my chill of
AM transmitter
fire it up on 1580 and put gold WX NC is
it was known as on the air from time to
time
but the whole time it was a great
all day small following air eaves
nice warm day almost drug especially
back then
saw you to master the art of feeling
good
and a friend of mine was living next
door and red pottage
we drank the board over shut up and they
want to give each
I ran back bread the tape deck gravel
pilot records grab this crap that
and then I decided it was full on sure
your typical shortwave broadcast station
now
give it to you cross you least back then
mostly political bullshit
and the Bible beaters what time is it
okay are well I'm just on going up
quickly fast for
real change from worldwide was born but
because my voice
was so recognizable I only broadcast for
the once or twice
and then I quit and then I'm signing up
with a body in mind with different radio
entity
which was more was produced and put
together but you may ask
why was I never Boston
you see most pirates to cling to a
frequency
only operate their they evolve their
phone number they give out their address
me my voice was not used on for one
thing for nothing
I always want from frequency the
frequency the frequency with him
bans designated for broadcasting do not
operate outside
obey because that's what people start
beginning to wonder why is a station
playing music
in an area where it's not supposed to be
and then
the other people are who like having
their station heard saying well
if you're in an area where all the
others are how are you going to be fun
but on a roll one of the other guys
involve the whole thing
managed to get a mail drop which was
used by a lot of pirates
it was widely publicized pokémon
animal letters started pouring here so
you're sure the circle into the air were
plans I know not where by nineteen
eighty-seven frontal eye and a lot of
the
I wouldn't say that programming by a he
was the
the basically the announcer he and I
came to a vast disagreement
is to how the thing was to be programmed
in which direction was going
at that time I was chief engineer on
am/fm home all
and why would dole is I'd make you so
the record library
a production studio was some local
broadcasts
by I was in 1987 I'm home I tons of them
law that's the way it's been love
finally
fold up with our but at that particular
point I'm I also moved the main as well
on being on stove I Alan in his
escapades
but the other thing is is I luv I lose
all country
there are no neighbors at least there
were no neighbors this tax thing
they'll really were one any server free
radio operation our neighbors
where you are a single was getting
another toaster is getting into their
hearing aid is getting into this
it's getting into his wife's vibrator
and
data dole want to hear this day so late
call off welfare Orleans saw
that's just some advice from me
arm from where things are going now
and being at the SEC's resources or more
more limited
that parents alike annoying flies that
buzz around goes around and annoy them
but then again when we come slap your
from what I've been hearing
it is bad news I always leave it at that
okay GoPro okay
I have a Canadian and I all spots are I
tractor-trailer I operate a sure way
fire station
from major as a relay station for other
stations
they'll they'll mail tapes or CDs to be
and by air them
from drug with a lot sometimes doesn't
a naval officers will use is
that one which isn't too modified it a
radio transmitter the date you must
modify it
to broadcast for want to others to
diagnose
stable of and
the Jezreel brokers with the AM
broadcast band it's a long way
want a play around with long way just
have fun to do
for home use as a whole set up here on
the
website rate which was a
other Evans radio transmitter here a no
modifications on this one
children's with just about anywhere
his you a issue 10
I other laws also there's like a model
home a single cells
is as shit hope so a that
a to a whole much speaker here I can
possible year wanna hopeful around with
a
he is a following shortwave pirate stuff
recently in a lot of talk to you what's
called a grenade
this is a great day this is a test what
a.m. transmitter personal control
little crystal they control their
suffragettes on this one as
for 6955 others for a lot harder these
days
a get an wats totally portable backpack
it
Bible at an audio source
a small about it Google the jail cell
battery
lines only sizes radio office about
diaper
it that whatever you want where we
carried Sandra
at the bush somewhere another play a
show
they bill Lee the SEC in the
directions by the fire with and within
five minutes
they can find you within a 10 mile
circle and
if you're the same spot for more than
two or three broadcast so catch up on
sleep
well as this station the same spot for
this ten mile circle
every Friday night at ten o'clock I'm
gonna go there its way
is ten mile circle illegal here the gym
clothes judge in fighting
so they get used up a
move around a lot which is great what I
D I'd rather giant Televisa
a the broadcast from
10 no here a Canadian provinces
all forty States down here several
asking one
occasional talking with seal the windows
get warning load
and down to mexico because I get a job
there across a little
into that too with my truck so broadcast
to massive problems as well
and locations for me is kinda fun to do
as well
I a broadcast the
they show the SEC's sign that is a was
day at the
Laurel Maryland their me SEC
largely location where they actually
marcher the frequencies from
that's at the other driver they were
looking at whether
day he I
to do stuff like that little on the
gravesite sometimes urs
bodies do but I guess on across
international borders while here you
know the show was
crossing down from Windsor Ontario into
Detroit Michigan
and a roll over the Ambassador Bridge St
Louis my show it headset microphone four
channel mixer I'll
do with these team players to on the day
and song and it just those roles
for the booth to clear my load a custom
size
like this one lol and I broke as he was
costly
Asian they tweeted house say my name
radio over-the-air
shouldn't really nasty but and
yet have fun stuff like that a for me
breaking the law with the transmitter a
may indeed anybody can make it a
the actual legal Park putting here
as a player so
3 questions about the
six minutes left questions questions
questions
was was all your with me
%uh those are three hundred bucks
other 10 years its transmitter's given
to me by a friend
the church's his father of my it to me
the this was the both
for poses a all
true please
the grenade was a come one hundred
dollars
p book by it the rain %um
children's its ok but later yes order
left the the higher how it's been a
furry a
fill it out for his as it doesn't look
for Susan go
close together greater second that too
doesn't look good like much but that
what transpired other examples years ago
surely
power gathering problems
North Philadelphia that the box
transmitted a
a skinny kid and it was
I'll confirms it she
by to listeners each about 500 miles
away
in different directions and it sounds
pretty amazing
10 watching range that was possible
shortwave
your you try anything Muslim brother
radio financial sense for
get local mobile station powerful was
not necessary all necessary
shorts lol Ocelot me down with a little
bit
power his team modest 10 conditions
as all other conditions as well a
there's a limit to the cider
again this table here the the web of
atrocities for broadcasting
at logging New Zealand Australia
you're all here so be it this is a
little here
you're talking to
no who is at his home
%uh you're going over some things
censorship here
mom aside from the fact that
you know anyway she broke a sweat
online are way time
same here fun as far as commercial
license
stations they are safe harbor and
feature yesterday
basically they had this post fearing
or Terry a loved one
state hitler's social radio stations
take advantage this year the committee
the SEC is actually
hammered commercial stations bonds for
really get on the excretory functions
things like that derogatory way you
someone you don't like
sure things will do one other reasons
why
we we own sense of programs
you is because hearing internationals
me is somebody the United States
listens WBC you Inc also
the SEC says well I heard a pro this
show WDC the using all homes
follow words including the F word in the
C word
everything else once what are you going
to do about
well they will reply are
its international broadcasting station
and
generally do not get ball program
world stage government
are surely is has taken a stance
we're you the domestic Lee in this
country
a lot on body
play say girl or something
other country the that his ashes
state orange BR to find
further focus on your thing are a lot
stations
this country's largest scared the
far for PST
material as a lot of questionable Angie
they just they just of blood glucose
they don't want the hassle
palm example is a yes
well 'cause bro cases like howard stern
you know
do it
the SEC is fine arm is
radio company numerous times they just
pay the fine
%uh as they've got a million so the
hundreds of thousands of dollars
do it so it really is up to the station
I think what you gonna find is in the
next five to 10 years a lot more
broadcasters stations in the United
States probably lose a little bit more
because be you know ever since the 9/11
are you seeing documentaries
programs that actual ordeals lives of
people doing stuff
and they're using all has a four letter
words
i think i think is change WBC hugh as I
said we don't sense of old
programs get on studies the four-letter
words sometimes
there are few eyebrows in a few hey I
hope you know what you doing
but generally we find people that
something meaningful to say
the you know use good judgment quickly
as I think we'll about two minutes
yet
juror news
some point I'll cannibalizing
sure way
you know him
song
s high-frequency broadcasting they can't
do that because high frequency
broadcasting
is are regulated by actually a worldwide
bottom known as the ICU
on the International Telecommunication
Union see surely free was these online
gaming and
are sharing my everyone in the world Lee
we are going on sale for 15
and I can guarantee you there are other
stations
around the plant that operate on 741 via
also
so if the government comes in and says
well we're gonna awesome awesome
followed by there's no mechanism to do
that I mean I simply could do that
someday
but I don't think that I we'll see
any way there's a mechanism to do that
because
these frequencies are on a shared
non-interference basis world one
%uh who got money one question questions
what
response all from in the red commercial
use immunity
there has been some changes in SEC
policy lately
and used to in order to complain about
holder or little retarded provided
written transcript although
program and/or is table the program to
the SEC
the last to three months maybe it change
the law so now this %uh told the SEC
about it
and you have a law and all written
evidence
and no official his all any violation
and the SEC will pursue and go after
stations moreover indecent material
also in the last year all basically
since the German changed
there's been and marketing Res in the
narrow
prosecution said the recisions that
they've gone after
content I so there are a lot of stations
out there
gets here yesterday and unfortunately
the SEC does do what we call this this
clean sweeps
this somebody gets a hero in there you
know what
and they go out on a star you know
picking our stations one by one
I guess we got close but all I can say
is if you're interested free radio
to your whole or lot summations on the
net is a lot of books available I think
this is what's available at the
pocket calculator who then on the second
floor
are just be careful use good common
sense
and she got on with us a WBC 2.9
to learn a little about international
sure way and if you access to the
airwaves and you know
we we we can help you out there is tons
a box around
I'll with the technology and and how to
do it because there's a lot of people
that want access
and hopefully someday the government
will really listen
and start licensee amateur radio
stations on the short wave on the AM on
event at cetera et cetera thank you on