I
in I'm interested in topic and a
on
a few years ago 02 March bunch of other
New York
up to Joel college football
went down to lobby Congress in protest
at the SCI
the lower today it was fun there's a lot
of work we went down there with Flyers
T-shirts woodstock people who try to
explain we're on about
he and we couldn't do it well you know
that people
the crews were honestok and and is able
okay what's your cause
waco and and we'd say oh well
10 lines later they say who's got
computers to
it just was or so when I'm working on
his
propaganda happened onus on the civil
side
on the let's play my cause my purpose
I'm usually in Cleveland I and
so I have a lot on something I i think
is right on the far far left
it'll markets I think I'm probably would
go
intentionally Hollywood girl to the last
are I'll well as people
and just say logically as well says
purely a process displaying what I'm
doing here with promises
this goes for a fire brimstone they have
a certain way
sorrow -2 given technical presentations
for them
I it's the first keeping one's the
government is to get out the music
business
were into it one or the other we talk
about the little hard
were generally months or basing talking
about Monday
understanding of what what that stuff is
in the past
here's my vision for that stuff is in
there passage
the founders wrote the Copyright Clause
it to them
us working as they did so they conjured
up in industry
there there was no electoral party
industry of and it was created from
scratch
in that moment guarantee through these
things in life a problem
which doesn't exist number two founders
created
government policy towards the Arts aside
from that the First Amendment free
speech that pretty much
is no other government policy worth arts
really
this is called to have effect that
I'll that
they created industry to administer the
Arts only half the time
now
we want where we are now because
isn't working the reason is working that
israel has the power come
find it but not the kill the bill so its
political speech format
Justin community also carries with no he
has a front pages
don't use lines I'm I have elected
government's got music business once
again well you're
the problem says not allowed with others
were the popular closet into things
the controversy industry s there and
their staffs government policy towards
the arts
this isn't working and the reason isn't
working that industry has the power
government behind it but not the
accountability the result
is that the people by which I mean you
know the people things in the
declaration
and couple hours on are subject to
regulation without having a voice
yet what the regulators still a
and as a result we have is a
anti-democratic
institutions the actual system that
sucks working it's doing its thing
prolly
this is a democratic matters so
what makes a democratic so there's
collusion between governments
they steal all in government and
industry is the same way as is a wall
between
you know any other I important parties
in the forces the Macomb and their
business coalitions
when democracy breaks down is there's
collusion
with both parties are the recourse is
for the people
to forcibly remind the government his
always say this very specifically
that force
is a real thing is a useful thing that's
the way things work
and dollar
it is the way democracy works to the
people have to
not ask the government to do the right
thing but
talent government does the people's
bidding
unwillingly as a little what's new in
your car
your government pays ambitious those
because people
Davis keepers the deadly ambitious the
pretty hardcore
no they are to yeah
where they do that Darby the world
government always strains against
democracy
always has to be forced you it doesn't
look a little
was to be elected from life the arts
only a danger
political careers politicians
strategically attack we need to keep the
arts as far away as possible
are asking you not think December as a
France
presence right supporters alike the
selflessness
none so to keep the Arts at arm's length
a politicians established this
its proxies to do with its first parties
are not democratic institutions
parties on in the government
norad when the founders established
party by Internet policy it was the arts
he created
not just in industry the super industry
this special powers
when the founders wrote the Copyright
Clause abdicate their responsibility
to make the government which is
responsible to the voters
and also paranoid no makeup conspiracy
theory
I mean to say is that on history
has for a has
me are me %um
yes stuff to see the constitution says
all this other
you thoughts yes the religious studies
and as it is
survivor die according to the rules it
means to means
a catchy sure memorable your sexy
on a lot of things that help them word
of
that stuff the Constitution on and then
there are three games
with actual real things I'll
and I'm sorry are
yes in there are other is the reality
reality is this thread institutions
to its land ownership arm buildings
investments mentorships you know
purposes really enjoy the career for
life
the whole a long time and then you teach
an apprentice and so on and so on
voiceless missile history is made up
said as long
was chill against staying with the same
overtime you have judicial precedents
or the reality really like him
really like to party it stands for the
thread
institutions that have been linked I
as a series is businesses on since
since the rite of passage sister house
its
room social problems a this thread
is a specific industries since these
institutions are specific industry
not any other industry they're not the
digital industry
they're not not a little problems not
the artisans
the exact one so
level and on where we gonna this moment
his
just by I what you expected on ones that
the industry was created by the
government protected by a
deliberately on guess you will like this
the yet the idea that
I lobster or the dot constant getting
p with them is fundamentally wrong it we
can go core
ask for special privileges you were
going to ask the have nots to survive
loses is wrong this is de facto
illegal to
I'll the music industry i think im sry
on this is part the same industries and
operates in shadows
I'll so along with the tobacco
I'll see alcohol sex industry
drugs gambling on its
its it works in citrus sale for example
Journal heard anything about
martial music industry music this is how
they're really working inside
any reason large business on 05 pretty
much nothing
with clothes go to the website universal
you're staying up by of public relations
these are not the whole
let's unlike a lot of other businesses
and
are it is secretive
its its only with sleazy lives on
chaos on it it doesn't actually sound
it says artisans and get this morning
with music it says
give us money and we won't see get this
money will hurt
that's the item price and
example this is ask with the music
lessons organizations
do with a deal because their rights law
for very long
universal various reasons scored
into to the bars chaos regardless
whether they're playing
ascap licensed music this address
service to the problem here
music industry's acting as a form of
government and sit on this
the constraints as oversight 0 votes
there's no disclosure your chimney throw
the bastards
this on purpose where does Parliament
power
nothing to Marx's for suddenly summit
when Mike
after a learns lessons which we saw and
I'll and like I think for both
the same thing when I happens there was
a huge are the
composition that a little party that was
a look at it said on
the yes to on as a Jonjo or
armed Leszek on also agree that we're
losing
going to see cockles the
morning on the kids with us
believe that this is about the best
speech from pop
is truly go to congress hospice Laura
percent
the that hackers on that's a
you are relatively mild climates it's
pretty good I think states this fall
and its totally on point
is because a quote about the same
distance particular
the signal is just a tree
the other way because it's likely the
hospital other intellectual property
my little columns should've gone
stalking
or public or risk losing it's
constitutionally mandated right to a
vibrant public to me
we believe are losing or or lease on a
place where we're gonna kill the laws
start the CBDT GaAs you know
while Balch problem battering punished
legislatures on working on traditional
tax lists in industries
where manufacturers are punishable this
for existing
as you want I'll hits and I love the
sinner I that's why we're allowed to
attack
manufacturers of our Father dole
freedoms workers within the court's
reasonable
public perception everybody agrees
piracy
harsh inspires nobody disagrees
I love this point all liking this people
who agree with
and posturing is not parse and
I do 35 percent loss and business I V
music business is to you posture from
Russell
three losses in the world but doesn't
there's no reason to my
the courts the legislature the public
said
is what matters is what they do what
they do
makes a burqa clear that they care who
the winners of
and that morality is going to go to the
wheels
the IT industry is too big to fail
russians
are is not sure you have the government
give us permission to get in there and
do we want to do
is to determine genetic
so unless it says the correct because
the Constitution is about a balance
is fooling himself the public has never
had
constitutionally mandated low to a
vibrant
public to me with the public has had his
incidental benefits
arts policy the government contract out
to a specific industry
the options there's no sick industry
there is no artisans those days baby
says
haha I live performances sale
instruments and sheet music
by living wage for getting lessons I
Bosphorus halfway decent way but that's
not the industry or think there is a
high PST
happens do pay the bills file
relationship with ours
rentals the common cause is not about
balance
the situation is always been on his way
so the situation is right now is what
you get from the combination of secrecy
& privilege: this building
popular across archer this himself
dealer
self-dealing means it membership because
the products
first our I'll is the most important
value the IPS
so with the recent decisions as far as a
yet radio this the scenes
upon %um with us
they realize when others that net radio
is not hard that industry
purpose the public because is not
tankers the Arts
workers radio sticky Nike industrial of
courts or thinks this
because they are right 6 the copyright
with the public cause as the
constitution says
industry electoral not products
this not the upward that is guaranteed
by the Constitution I think the
Holocaust in order to
blah blah blah congress has a party to
you
rights its in order to is not a mandate
not telling the truth the courts
not required to follow that in order to
promote progress in the arts
missile sites the courts holiday to
allow the congress and great
intellectual
as a very differences
and this is arbitrarily the music
industry
a key issue is no obligation Park they
can do what he wants
again music labels
to offer downloadable music because they
don't have to not responsible public
private other well
despite all this will go pretty good
leverage for so far
well agree with the gloominess a lot of
people I think we're actually
doing pretty good with internet which
does not suck
this file sharing it's really pretty
popular everybody's got their cheers
applause for people out there
I'll so we're making progress yeah I
think these are the people in powerful
we're not that we think that there is a
special or hate us
all all the way for so we need to crush
the opposition but
force so it's good contributed yes
it's good to write letters to congress
and demonstrating is a fun thing to do
but that's not I'll hackers world ac/dc
a digital politics people to raise money
for
for funds it's like pulling teeth the
contributor 150 times
amid and the truth is that everybody in
the audience is happy to go
don't stop unhappy to go on
call the congressman right cars join the
ACM
on all is really not the way we r where
we operate
is that we build stuff well we need to
keep doing
is keeping building stuff the only thing
wrong with what we're doing
is a couple small offense listings is
building stuff the more aggressively
political future said are
is an effective way to to work so here's
a few examples
mister that i'm looking for. for
Hansen's I might actually get in the end
arounds
hacks about talk about minute like
for example I so
launches okay so with his bowl physical
capital toys
that have a political on impact on that
note deliberately
political Taurus well these things they
have it with some with few friends
which is a on file-sharing Murray that
we call this Leah ribs law the pros list
and
share files what we do is water each
others houses to bring a hard drive
the funeral hour person posting money as
a as a
Bihar are Liverpool you know I
internet cables everybody has a copy the
patio people per
don't you get and then we do you direct
downloads in person to the head
yeah affects is this are its fine social
its totally believe attack I
was the cops a certain somebody in your
private home were drinking beer and
barbecue with your friends
the administrators and other than this
legally
urine a the merits
stock transfer all is discuss I haven't
we take home final kids
night a good stuff with recommendations
comments like no idea what that sucks
this is a technical political
by we we accomplish
not mass share that it's gone
terrifying to our yes attendees
does a lot of stuff you that over over
over over a hour
you know good broadband connections a
larger than its good job
you're not a bother dollars this because
of the concern
yet
well I think that the think the did a
pretty good question
sir so I think the key play
this is gonna sound a little class but
the key point is legal because I think
the law hard
this on and I think that this is it
doesn't wanna
what matters is are you gonna get lost
the hots for the community because
yet that mister doesn't want to have but
isn't there
your thoughts breaking down front door
that there will be a lot more
comfortable about
your on kisses only have a single
on if you have a I think your cool party
your loftis within a radius were called
trucks laden is its
your whole night on will be pretty green
pretty cool you know if they're
and and the consular go with it we look
good and get a licence
he answers worth
full
friends at the collection yeah
so on it's a success
so it is put these things that is a
political and tactical
by Rd and with is discussed
this as kevin said to me after
Wednesday's
email me the next day said okay well I
got on
tailgates for a ride on the subway here
back
to life through play kick ass cable
as a political hack is it really scary
position it was by the product's so look
for years
are using their inventiveness you have
to do what's
arts world leaders say ask you which is
flyer
sign petitions I'll kidney action is
factors
your actions what we do well on the only
thing that given the
is applied creativity more directly more
aggressively yeah
got I house
no about
well
County old
writer talks about it yeah
I think we all fall on
a another another similar to a political
capital hot
on years then called afraid
you got any your projects mitterrand
catching at your friend knows that
it is know it is it's this file sharing
our
so it's about down down low stock levels
list every year miles and the difference
is that only connect your friends
should never have connections somebody's
phone number
email addresses Stacy don't know you got
a little
right and so from there it's all just
fun ecology
on there's a lot of interesting moms
network month
for example yes this extremely to liaise
with going your funds are low
you cash assistance there himself
problems but a by I'm
the net result political levels it's a
cell structure I sent you one used in
true evil
with 20 treatable which would you choose
good I R pose for sure he will work
great with what's good
we had stronger the cell structure the
nearly impossible abrasion so
to enforce that way technology lucky and
not
traditionally political things are
positive political on things to do thank
you
all right
rise power all
all
yeah
and indeed they're completely justified
to do that
right so
great
way to enable you to Tracy I is not
getting any more
here the hell likely watch TV you're
seeing friends I can do that like on
ahead a little ways to go a sorry
to I'll
its or do a pretty good but we force
little
ok other when it should be there are
thoughtful I hate sauce
on reading list call this is how we have
operated
we need to keep doing what we need to do
is what's out there what we're doing
right now
to small differences the first one is on
a political
ethical hacking always on and secondly
is
with stuff I apologize and you'll I
still get
I really don't get you know I know a
buddy who feels
moral our files steel I
who've been at the center less everybody
asking
forty-five minutes mean everything could
stay home
you think it's a lonely they just think
it's the mass killings
you know knowing that if you like
mysteries
yeah I think it's really cool fun way
with
spill is it if you don't have to save a
few let's say they feel file sharing is
that
people and this makes no sense in the
world because we're shooting ourselves
in the past so that is ridiculous
it to stop good as if what we're doing
the crucial
Isshiki Colin ridiculously long URL
every cast is real property rights
mean anything at all people should
especially have a ride
he is the very body ingrained to solve
problems
create products and such for the cell on
restrained by the normally powers
which some other entities trying to
exercise real
often rises with this thing's for front
know our
are
obstructions a property rights some
hardened you a local doctor
and the police quarters that there's
opposition
between these abstract property rights
that there we call it a little problem
we'll probably likes we have
powerful real are
right she knew to you on to true
polymers
its boost electrical and there's nothing
to apologize for their
10 from to from Anderson's likud
moment basically human beings furniture
there's social beings monkeys
its for
is basically your apartment
everybody nobody culture
species shared
some deals he's
page occasions balls
it moved
you are not losing anything suree
return kids action of giving with the
the ideological missus is it's true it's
important
but is also easy on
that the job once you are absolutely
right
literacy comparison because of course of
as well
some fierce is very simple his little
bit year everyone
star break
us I will probably foster
much in the ether that the
that the moral justification for a
little problem is now I'll
versus with your opposition uses that as
gilded
sauce the the real on world
haitian horrors that on net like
apartments goods
well another I'll do them what's the
best games
another sheet music moral justification
just as saying
he's if it doesn't cost you anything
to share Moss most people that's
but not funny see
culture assertion place
less that's what file sharing is a for
sure
the point is that his virtuous to show
through friends
doesn't virgins okay with that time
here comes the barn burning conclusion
we all agree the file sharing is a
virtue pretty much hassling
that's true even if your friends should
do it other anyway
spice about so it's pretty clear that
little actual property
is evil evil
it's a good fucking apologizes
file-sharing not stealing
its freedom fighting it is decided
good nobility and the Knights the
roundtable
we are real actual people
opposition are not people only say that
sucks
me say that opposition is not the
employees at the hype he is
is the industry itself the employees to
go find new jobs in the babysitters the
collateral sprawl
what our way
the industry irate see
IIIi and
I'm sorry I love having shells I love
having chosen based on this causes
I'm absolute for look at the end
and its
we are real actual opposition
is not people is in this the employees
the industry can go elsewhere
industry there's all along all year
after year
and century after century design houses
in between us
humans in the natural environment we
have more rights
opposition us that's why we are freedom
fighters
our interests when the freedom to hustle
for ourselves
at basic right self-preservation
is a basic right it doesn't you with me
it happens written on this we don't need
anybody
offer a generous and everything taken
away from us influential party demands
that we not mind our own self
preservation that's why
we are 3 p.m. files is the white
to self-preservation is not optional
well
your needs
it's not a little
a.m. I
we got the end this is such an amazingly
haha
it's really hard house insists I can
appreciate it for a pretty sure we had
about
only agree
you know law yen we just got in some
good
on I'll so it is noble
to do what we are doing if we win
results democracy free speech more arts
apple pie love backgrounds opposition
wins
that nepotism protectionism
and power it's about cartel hasn't
permanence enshrined constitutional law
privilege with the government it's not
were not so bad steelworker
your right to it so quit fuckin
apologizing for doing good
we annihilation to not hurt the artists
where the mission Jim Crow the
recordings
cross cost crush you know to say you're
sorry that's cool
Britain because she can really take care
of urself the Backstreet Boys are doing
far
and all the other artists or moves
or over the point kill
he had a cat the artists we can be
threatened
yours because we only artists whose
from when they're third talking about
the arts
there together earlier yeah the
harpsichord
let's stop isn't there more we other
people
on the creative public domain do stuff
personal time
nights and weekends applying tell
knocking off back to raise
glory on personal satisfaction static
satisfaction
we r as far as constitution is concerned
artists
sold people say that what we're doing is
threatening
artists can't be right we were the bars
the week so I hope that the artists
it's how to protect ourselves from the
Hokies
our historic of cancer
to quit fucking hard as
it's a real struggle politics is a true
fights is not provide
as a lot around us is not the first she
is the cheese is money
stuff that matters the people's really
carer who want something she's
it's because it is serious business
worse is the way things get on other
our callers of reason for us and they
use it everyday
we're in a power struggle resort
democratic up
the reason surpassed officer democratic
on
that the ideal no actual bottom as
creative forces
which are powerful enough to threaten
democratic process
and if the court see what they're doing
archer or bizarre things
that's wrong because the courts are
doing exactly what they are expected to
do
given that intellectual property must
it intellectual property is a valid
concept
in with the court saddam what the CETP a
is when all I wanna be's want to do to
us
what palladium is is okay is
constitutionally enshrined
you can one or the other but if you
accept I P
you accept permanent industry propped up
Italy and Constitution the proper
is to give up your engines in favor
arrived
little party is not now and never has
been
a balance between might properly
public comments comments is a whole
other loggers
it's not okay some polls it's not okay
for big kids to beach of but they don't
actually break with
it's wrong all the time and everywhere
to just quit fucking apologizing
proposed are fighting and being somebody
ask you the three words or for worse is
crossing point isn't to say
I don't believe it'll happen its long
thanks
its on going back to
economics people are motivated by
self-interest
and I see full-size debate
anglicized man but I think if we can
work on the way
so arguing like rights like rights
is trying to get to the bottom home and
we can compensate
these artists for their time and test
pilot self-interest
I think we'll find a way to mutually
work and
30 the this prevail p as well as locals
on I think that on me think that's a
that's a
for that everybody agrees with that no
real or
ours okay it's really important but
getting orders
K my point here on this and guitarist
nasal
princes that anything we have been doing
that we could arrange did you get the
artist
a with on alas
on in May major nasdaq stage lines
it is said if we exist
at Lucky industry has to destroy us
has the story of this to destroy us will
that's what it's doing
we can help allies because they want
haha
well
you mention that
was all the time gotta minutes about 10
minutes more
it was worth just a clarification like
on
he said the as the Constitution
enshrines
the the street have I P it wasn't
reminders that
at least a hundred years after the
Constitution corporations
actually acquired the rights a people
a in the late 19th century that
corporations actually
were able to start whole copyrights
because they were considered important
people in very bad judge decision by the
Supreme Court
until that time the founding fathers
heading to the dismay much for
individuals to be the artist three years
and therefore the holders call right
beneficiaries
how do you think that that's where yes I
mean
the there are reports that there are
there agree with both
on the historical historia are
local property has always been under
censorship
its its store all routes around
censorship chrome I'll
and as far as without the corporations
didn't have
rightful property it away on its it's
the same thing we were so industries
star hotels on cell
a.m. even on the larger properties
passes for me these two graciously
permanent px kittens were pop
legal means
its
yeah yeah loading the seeds with their
network is lauded
to or I like the idea of fun
parties and like 7s I think that is a
great deal says it is very good to hear
people instead of just being either
practical solutions I think you know if
you see it was any
get something in the evening again
immediately if we continue
taxes like that does it actually bring
recording industry all the way down if
it doesnt mean im going im sry only down
what kinda meditations when finished
with a warning industry have the correct
those
and then I mean like you ultimately if
this does work as always for
like problem with socialism communism to
its like honey
ADRs you know like in in you know the
Grahams
on ideal analysis Angeles so
one outlet next as well as councils into
suggested
well on you
for quotations that saw
I thought about it I don't know what the
a lot following their side
I know what yes with file back in this
isn't right
the other probably would be pretty on
at home to suppress that reportedly
kill for on this list
as many artists again on let me say
that on there are many ways to pay the
artists many many ways
its on and we
there there's a lot of problems with all
one of mir's the journalists is justly
clever
means realists I or maybe a little bar
stars
as as hackers this like he does I
down and that's the problem
first is the issue miller's government
policy
your social Barcelona listen
socialize your sensationalizes
considered
gun on to some there's no better wages
for
given the parlous its lost there's
allowing
almost the whole here's the real alright
there's a there's a and your question
artists
the IP industry
doesn't care about the arts it has to
kill the artists
get to Haas thats will do and that's
what it's doing we try to always gets
people
K right now radio mod
flown at radio stations they were good
and profitable doesn't leave a lot
government Slashdot is ways that money's
close the system there's a lot of I'll
show companies in a long while
worthless trouble you still model
silly this disorder because there are
many you know
chance a spy with partner on there is
money available that can come back to
the artists for
as or in the street blood its on
so you're looking at the collar that I'm
happy to
without having to do this but I can tell
you that on
I I hope you understand
yes feels like it's going off the rails
women's
both and
someone in the unusual position green
alright
overly
rest each retake its way
bastions ish s
special things
say
pop Spanish is each tickets
see that said your tax light
rock wife its
its those fascist publish
technical thought cation software
also yet once so
units tip jar
here talking listless intellectual
says its its
arts as much what's hot taking
Weiss bus coming up
sports this its to share which a police
for entrances fair use of stuff twice
any today me
II me a point good points
Sony a each so I make
a living not planes there's
of all its
its East way I
each ha up 2600 maggots
me four ish its 26
its and a t-shirt for the
articles teams way
its books but it does require
substantial
research that so
my gas is issue
going to world outside hearts
spores for GTS throw
although the 2nd US military said you
think you gonna write for a living
with her a not only
like a the trial is really hard who
hears a writer that isn't
totally miserable called gone
you it is the worse th
take 80s and I killed you
all yeah this review just
that is babysit miss
music this there's there's a there's a
really good
of consciousness other specific or but
that's not my point
my point is that the star of the
Constitution
is not about
the Arts paying the artists it's about
guarantee need assistance specific
industry for all time
that happens also as a proxy by
the government to administer our loss by
that's a problem as a few know if you do
one thing to accomplish nothing
doesn't work go the clone look of
I stars backfired doesn't work
last less that's what I double
it is it they had to get rid of
intellectual property let you know
yet the writers were making nothing or
even last no that's terrible
absolutely on right no was
will obviously John's
me they didn't these important because
for dance I'll but when you bringin
that DMCA
much
and you JMT ships that
are just about for and music you get its
what I think
diane burns really insidious
its is providing researchers from
you know test pension schemes and door
survived
where Williams went scientific
development threes
laws that's a little on poor then which
is getting
use source somebody
is is out there triads
bad butts
ottomans other important parts these bad
laws
it really hurts us to have the people
saying
you or three I'll UGG show
I your from his lender
I have nothing but respect word work you
know
I'm not I'm reblogged
that's a great day but I think that the
people with work
are gonna keep you know or no because
nobody respects
good you know they're not scared
where they are scared and that's all
you're gonna cross me
you know in congress do they care that
Cory Doctorow
I was a really cool guy this the care
that has a lot of people sharing stuff
it's killed
us means
his research government
testing
linda has businessperson because
you know this sons speech
that awesome that yeah I'm
put forth since but let me
OC this is the real stuff the government
well
give are lobbyists on our journalists
nice
treats we me
asleep
disappoints first think the artists
it's often its how yours who try these
for free well weather systems are in
place a
love newspaper office of music is over
mail-order
the whole idea music record industry is
obsolete
you don't need it it gets between the
consumer and the musician
doesn't hurts position now in your home
40 comported album for red
equipment is available many consults
frequency
without little taking like donated
its and horsey
tease PA palladium stuff people in this
room
are he said built if you can use
your tails to feet those mechanisms
that's a normal thing to do
because on for children doing this are
sacrificing functionality
at the expense of trying to protect some
profits which is absolutely wrong thank
you
by
so I'm record
to are my arm even though I
I'll my my good friend Clark Kent a
and slashes know something is really
done same
is just like that yes I could change it
missiles by on I would like to get my
email cell
lewis's email to me I you can send to
you
wheels rims and losses carns Gonz
you can give them emailed to go into the
season
John his
his is just stays
lot artists out there very very first
three
by the his the
field is hard once keeping them from
having the feed want but online
artist that I I've spoken to will
directly are really 3
the concept I'll lose concept
key as be Hill debt
that is there out
without I key
a fielding star
I
with use will be describing
I'll without intellectual property ours
somehow
are some help people Sophie himself
budget
basic hitch
yes something very few artists
individual keep are you
had a for on lost said
are thanks a lot of Holly and I hope
anybody this year that number
the one catch phrase it was ask you
where does he have a political thing
which a point is don't have a whole lot
is said
little party as well but missiles local
mines by its