says
yes centuries on the way
probably outstanding physical security
sales
already drive by there with us we have
no I'll have no videos
we don't have any
from room my
them on their money
they wanted I Michael Glasser
on access control specialist from I
going on um my mom and factors
referenced that match officials treeline
southern New Jersey
I had a lot of new york on the
manufacturer's website electrical
installations but
if anyone has questions at the end they
can be freed on my left is
Isaac with all he's Isaac I'm
home he is Isaac I get to play vanna
white today
yeah go who dela peña the luckiest
love Lucky's up a special birthday
well we love him 5 by the wrong okay
first things access control is why you
hard
more letters control go back to the
games Yemen or
10 keep people in an hour excellence
the building of the people and now the
building he has joined or
is vicki was good but you can hold it
for anything he he goes off in the base
happy
then people starred on master key
systems which was also good because
you put the key that they need to just
talkin attendees
nauseated though anyone you know my mask
is associate head
especially other home well as good %uh
so basically for anyone who doesn't know
master key system is just one key
control a loss I we will have different
levels a supervisory
you have a user key then perhaps a
supervisor quixote
maintenance key then you have a master
key to look all the buildings cetera et
cetera basically broken down on
needs K
by what he sent out front only Marcus
and is that all the people think it
kinky is
are two locks work on the same key at
master he
that is a master key what that means is
that the key to lock
just walkin sign a bill to say a master
key system work could be that
one locking were two separate keys
completely tito little kids
that might in
move for example you might have once the
hotel
you might have a floor master for the
May
reached floor might have a grand mess a
great Grandmaster any
during the entire building you up with
another key email
a key for the job only ones all
janitor's closet sorry for causing one
possible way of doing it is or has
published essentially you have multiple
pins the neat stack can you in you can't
in three months ago 18 you walk the
downside of course is
is more where that and more kisses from
me thinking a lot because so many more
possible she like that locus
well as though he said
so any available slots that's right any
bool Oxford lopping palomar
a minimum balance every okay
well without as he said so now you've
got the door
you've got a lot of good he's eleven
allow users and
I'll just pass by each other one there
was a party dress far-right
like it then don't as although still
months so well know where I was
okay have a door leading to secure and
then some guidance I literally is cool
so the subject control systems because
it's almost sure the locket picture
keep enjoying a break in the more like
that stuff but realistically
anything get broken but it more special
is more colleges I'll tell you
therefore we have access control first
day of the show you
is basic basic basic basic basic got
substantial
at-bat why keep bed because of that
hard on that that he left the venue what
are doing
below and walk through the door
and it works for the long haul the lower
the keep it in a sense of it all
online yet the flat big we love lies the
key so drained
is the well as good as a key
battleground
the keypad wanna be shown is called I
writer a
see why we bring him debt not thinking
about that
okay II I is international something
something
problem I work for them I mentioned up
but
no was arrested up before publishing
this just so that
so I T I is international it strikes a
chord
and think and
they may keep pets and they may access
control systems and now they make a
stand alone door lock which can fit my
car
because I'm a room and mostly their
focus is access control
a harbor such as keypads and proximity
readers mag stripe readers
smart card readers arm a backlit keypad
this
control health patrol all so for those
kids to set up a time for
of was the second
about
up
I want this this is that ok well I
to 12 I'll probably
I have to say the everyone in the whole
world
does access as you this might be Louis
on something but
its previous close and I i 212 keypad II
looks like this was crossing like boxing
you are sort of a little while
on using it credit which game works
basically what this does
is it's a switch with the key Pendleton
stores up to 120 users a punch in the
code below open the door
early accessible everyone going to Home
Depot and go in advance of the crosscut
saw
you are going to see all the budget one
two three four star
and I've New York cuts good s
mindset Home Depot guys go on 2003
four-star I'm
its up to get on the ball guys I was
told that a program that
but yeah as a group of all it is
still it still hoped the authorizes the
Home Depot guy writes the code on things
president the matter what it is larger
than the Azalea
lockpicking yes or no Hana bank vault
really
as other the vault other friend of mine
so on the banks of that spills
on though it was very there was a
retired
The Daily Show shank good question yes
which bank I'm not answer that one
the bank with among other that so do
twelve-day make three different posture
oz was really got into it
the national other
we offer right now but okay %uh played
on
why does that matter is more betterer
okay
another Awlaki are realistically I don't
and there had need for I've read to the
home and will probably a hundred times
you generally when used as for long
keypad to be more like this keypad
and this will be used on it or
contracting
at was well as I was about to a get up
to this the to throw line
like this is just a switch if you once
were the two screws out
you can shorten the wires over the door
and that's the reason why it matters:
yeah has gotten I'll get there was then
answer exactly that's why the to follow
the one love guys use in 10 days
as for I had years ago
I that okay
hit by FEMA and
your ear
he had
yet I played
very never with the first
yeah you greatly Kelly
right hot with chain here
with it would relate front
bring vertical
holiday right wanted yet
what you get work where
the rain he all like
and me I can remember me
net make know she'll never leave the
south
little laundry little yes yep
but the the advantage is a system like
that is that if you're happenings be
escorts on our own building
your using these key ps2 walkthrough
doors
the person on only has the look at your
fingers as Buddhism upper left that must
be your one
who is in the lower right that must be
an online can figure it out that way
the other advantage is that in a very
high traffic situation
the numbers were aware of those keys
which I'm sure
wrong healing look at these sorts of
things so you know if the numbers to do
for seven and five
are missing what are the chances that
too
475 are somewhere in this Go so that's
not to love
means in jail me
Mitchell hopefully they'll short out
before it's a big problem
thinking I have seen on personally I'm
what this one is just the eye model
indoor basic keypad mom got was drawn
out but very much does
gonna what about wanna you now you
anomaly with me to the rest because one
really uses in that situation been
3.0 I come back from that we miss you
yeah to
on mobile a dress code is going to do is
going to inform someone who recognizes
it that something is going wrong
under the right conditions but if you're
in an unmarked
in a non-monetary facility in all you're
doing is trying to protect the door to
say data center
there's not going to be some guy sitting
all day long looking for certainly in
page someone else
but at that point it's the on girls
minutes K
that turns the Hohner of its just a
smidge well as a switch it's not a stern
it's not for anything but this which I
put these on doors inside the office
buildings
because that way the cook couldn't get
to the other costs of
it's not a scaredy it's not for anything
but just a switch there's three
different families
alone for now but we'll never get a
minute the a.m
2 12's
2 32's and secures 212 just switch
232 is eighty had a stand-alone bill has
inside brains
so tricky bit of the one cancelled out
don't do anything
basically transmit signal to the inside
brains it's a joint series just and low
key pair that has now put four
the brain somewhere on the building that
without that a while this is the %ah
inside usage exxon into a single gang
boss
those jobs are they love them seen
everywhere in the city what's up
a lot harder now any of these people can
be on any of the three families to 12 to
or security reasons so anything you see
here on the old one occasion
can tell by looking at it didn't
actually this one can't it's not really
in the back
but in as on is fine means for them
I'm hoping orange about a baller
undergo two worlds Jordan the store the
cue 15 15 in 15 looks like that
plus a barrel up enough to see anything
I'll
Trans Am Yahoo who
if you look real close it's gotta
put out the song so is due in Burmese
threatening the back the electric
buttons
here so there's no actual moving party
with a hammer last year others are
hardened up
but the last lights and super also great
plastic from somewhere
on the bottom but I'm a job it's not
hard you can read it
and inside here get a little me out blue
a
think we are and the term on certain
number
and 12 of people's things as up which
one can you put that thing there's a
down
day getting a meanie tender think
everybody probably see that somewhere
on something and once you get all four
you get it open
and guess what send the signal little
probably open
that's right same left to secure one day
and said %uh something where the number
the council rotate
that way they can tell letter-writing
fun but numbers
and hit up and down up and down the
block to know what you doing
nothing at the office if they lose
insist that other movie all the cable is
the only time to pushing it
was a really good like some on people
you're probably
responses to look the other way and to
this is for
Isaac I'll be
and I was like no other day school not
even remember that that is OK
and the like this at all these key pad
to be in any other forms
%uh somebody up there time I'm going to
like fifty-five minutes and
its own medicine I'll we're gonna go
faster now cause I figured we would give
us on our
but other than that hit by several some
festive this big thing here
is the are for rugged dust it's a break
its heaviest metal its gotta keep bad
it's a break outgrow that it will go out
it's broke it's made for outside use are
you put these on the who's next
I will drive the truck and yet it that
they had to Indo
but this there and it day and if you
know the truck doesn't break
that it is more hospital all was vandals
Asian
well only with me because this is far as
I know
one fire only factor I mean real fire
over there I'll I don't do this while
her
but if you submit a balanced
thought that a a super good bugs
that'll stop this if you paid over the
bottoms are based on those details on
the bed
aristotle's rise ago on two or three
four five six star about
I and that's the of
I think this
is the acts T extremely
haha they were smart once again no
moving parts in a hamlet last year
was it the LED it the only the only
breaks the muscle
know how hard to push that they need a
cozy turbines
wear the veil and there's no no you do
medals Asian that's really not nice
officer responded as I make my own
nigga month a
yeah but is all scratchy
18 illegally being raised by the got a
stainless steel
me if you just a joke to it that'll
David if you take a whole so to where
they were
probably some kinda massamilla much
about that now that is meant
know more about them that you have that
on the show after I personally think the
piece of crap but luckily the phasing
out of the cycle model
scrap but whatever source all that's
good 11
so that no moving parts the st. and
thats damn good though this was all over
this economic is the one class to face
Southwest member im I personally think
this is probably hope from the fight me
for saying all
on books but all I don't like it it
wears out to publish a pencil box below
to hear things you think a lot of people
do you hold it
it wears out in braids but once they're
just have seen while I was in for 10
years
they are called me up and said out which
is both a member I looked at him and
said
here about seven years overdue but I
think este
is a very good keep it for what they had
it was cheap it was good but outsiders
weber froze
because I think I was just uses anymore
now we have a new weather broke even
limbo land pollution control we got this
SE
mayhem box how hormones day
the same day super glue are like West
market
and that's that the best
a lot of noise about the show on the
test of
this is the the I'll
W illuminate back twenty years extremely
old love extremely I'll
extremely hard plastic bottles what that
means is you hit with a hammer to left
field but some guys get the letter he
was over before
the diet or stall email but don't tell
that
at bar but it's still the same
configuration modest rate
start on them and same thing
getting the inside the outside central I
L or I love you
insiders I'll outsiders I'll whether
party
24 minutes
by the forward-looking NP
made a as in plastic these are using
your all-time
the terrific EPS got a hard left buns
not available at all about the picture
I'm
oh I am so thankful from I'm blessed but
she got it. so let me know
well was seriously like people's smile
developed to monitor the vandalism his
a blast not only vandal resistant as
good as G
they use a lot on your own saliva for
Grade II
other me up not she anybody 130 putouts
a
so the DMV its cuz blasted does
to but I've useful
Park loomis all this month the same
thing as follows:
ok that involve
are
get on with ya this was the I W
difference being that the back is our
a day what that word for medically a bit
well yes by the iraqis you take it off
to a
think that but I am its hermetically
sealed would be
think that's what I'm looking for a lot
yes question
yep
there are cause for everything if you
program the man
initially a factory code is want to hold
three fourths
are if you don't take that out I'm gonna
have to make fun of you
other than that anything you don't
programming is not in there there's no
factory bypass kurds
I love if you're ripping off the wall
you not get very far storms here is your
best bet those in the back door
and power down when the power back up
there is a way to get back at the sacred
on power down and power up both the
system throughout about how that
yup
depends on which model using on like
the other 2 12's the richest and 11 it's
short of the wire with no its want to
believe our top 10
master program mode on the arm not only
and she's not guilty by
ombre but on the other hand back power
time they get to those also estimate
that might also offer
is the thing I was trying to run the bed
just thrown by an address of where
mag stripe reader and him
hello isn't here yet but we'll find out
here
da house offer that made him put that
made for only the access control
products that this works with
for their cars everybody got the form of
the standard the weekend
bill is not only a VA but I'm I can do
that the shelf I do not know the
Hey Hospital yes all the stuff comes
with the props like any
that has a maybe a half inch possible
Hamas panel named Bob Latta
I mean details now we got em
the ILWU away a Russian tried and true
but you can use Macs right after the
weekend outlook
not know I will get his type of car
but we get output is like a large 232
output its data is the data transfer our
method
over long-on try now and those are you
looking to have a weekend outlook
nowadays its are ringing hey who's this
bosnia as far as I know and i dont for
months years but some people here
probably
sit in the back and was on the docket
with a lot more than me so they opted
and using the fundraising know how a lot
of good I weekend originally were some
old guy and design the system
and they had bien carts which when used
right was like the car
with to produce a weekend output yes
what was his name
up
in month
is to take this the technology the mail
works
the problems are two things that are
concerned we had that I know of
the car type was a weekend car and the
output was we had output you can use a
Mac strive to keep it or anything
because we get out but
but they talk about the weekend cards I
honestly I've read the book on it
i've seen the car the scene cut away the
cards to me it just doesn't make it a
different way into the same thing
different input
to defrost to be mad any those stains is
different the same thing
yes
larger I should be system just by making
your own listings x-ray machines and all
kinds of things to top it
but our I yeah can you not hear me
%uh by the are basically said
dressed only say that because the way we
again
we're currently no I don't know since
you're not on his as I believe it
I've person although it still show is
the way we get workers are basically is
a picture of metal
on April operate the picture so you get
a connection she take a picture that
think he's a liar and draw a picture
some on the visa
Islam up my auntie bedfellows
in Wollongong does really tough really
good lots to do
half an hour
okay we're almost all the island that
the party thing
over the edge of them these right
thank you I'll fosse's day
that's called the many maps and access
control controller
that's made for one door begin grading
system up to 32 doors
500 uses burned or ten thousand years
maximum and
that's the max very very easy to use for
anyone who has not only with access
control the new Big Ben systems
I was just something along these lines
to but that's what I personally
doctors Abaxis develops cases the
different things want to do that ability
of
yet I wanna doesn't have bad bedding is
is I think at first haha comfortable
that first one
fed picture ID badges editor that
it a little at me an issue that bad
and you wanted to bring to this offer
the protocol to bed with all the extra
information
our system can do that us it means I
knew that is the small application small
losses we are requiring that
they also don't have was real time alarm
management she can click on the door
open the door get it on the door and
seat status it'll bring to class at
logger I love what everything is
to catch the cat on opening you have to
walk around or two cars right
I it's only really mothers US drama as
usual for
that's the minimax as this is also the
hamachi
four-door model others though this is
the one door little models all
a monthly thing for a closer he'll keep
it in there
Lestrade you that happened on all
helpful okay this can be controlled by
software but we also program beekeeper
detail as its head comes out of so does
not give customers offering no game that
will keep your chin up
they can't mess it up I
hard juror so if they get messed up
you're happy but most the time and give
them the software let them do their own
administration's they call you 10 times
a day saying
hired a new guy I wanna hear him and how
page
that's great service guide is if I have
really got hotter right there
last the IMAX arm that little deals with
the dome
that's almost died I don't sell those
it's a cheap money but somewhere along
the Grand Designs no
that request thanks to the biscotti walk
out the door to open at least a mad
is a power supply has a keypad but this
is called approx top-paid
because a prospect that the process of
have a look at the party
KK Darbhanga to plastic body
the proximity reader built on the bottom
right now the proximity is in this one
well %uh our show
a technology so he i
doesn't think the problem by these up
its own place for him and won't do it
thank you day
I'm this before battery dies because I
have used this thing
also keep head proximity readers usually
built into here
why this doesn't have one it because you
can pull out the proximity reader
install on the wall on the outside the
store this on the inside
and I have a secure setup where this you
could just as build a religious ritual
of the waters on the outside shot the
wires
you but there's a means of the process
the outside adjust your set up
is to be stand-alone or integrate into
that system in stand-alone mode of two
thousand users
and about other stuff well some topless
to I'm bulky pet them but I i good
products if you have any question you
guys can go the ER
be that Tom see all the stuff on
anyone's area
I can talk to distribute our lobby up to
that major industries lot
contact your local on da locksmith
access control specialist her
friend who knows how to get stuff in the
back
the holidays all and my
question what percentage of the market
does I yeah I have
in the US and your medium good
me in good so that will be a beating No
Mercy them in
as far as keypads go there pretty much
the biggest 130 that as far as access
control there's a lot of competitors out
there and doing better
the access control I was relatively new
keeper our site
access control ha match long is
relatively new that he had long been
around for a long time
then departed after a lot other line I
can give an exact number but a lot
hour
if you're involved in electromagnetic
pulse you have more to worry about
Georgia
i'm looking ahead to the 1000 watt
it Isaac their work %uh
but in our again but job
thank you
grants
on anyway um
I've seen guys a a while back I don't a
mother tell what safer was it was it
like trance a flock okay to wear was
probably about hotel okay but they
basically talk about 500 megahertz radio
Jack II walked over to their range right
over the Safeway
her and they were pop and opened up in
the fall to the Ryder Cup
just because the everybody just
happening making tofu
but you know what everything as
weaknesses if you can find it here
there'll be a very rich person or a very
jail prison
yeah
that's so there was anything and I'm
about a lot of sage
is great the wires to the front the
garden some
safe it's hard to be sold at home deep
bow
and not to mention of Welsh because
it's not my business but a lot of the
Home Depot that we don't let them say
yes
that are in this fire and burglar
resistant are really
to this is a very thin gmail with a
budget summit middle
or I can get them up and then six
seconds a
may be lost by Joe the last yeah and but
if you want to save go with a dollar
starts to flow from that your basic
low-level good security I I don't read
them
they make it saves I don't have a safe
I'm headed up but let them they make the
text
about that to talk about mister okay
let's get down to the summertime project
as it
I'll how much 35-year-old
not that I haven't read it was a I
up okay biometric in atlanta
psychopathic
well-wishers yeah that obliges
again at one stop portal is like to the
battery died and their ballot that sorry
charles is on a new one for the last
like five years but we've been testing
this one every day demo you the whole
time
I just bought a big plus a blessing this
is called Eliquis
I have done for full price training on
the shit I'm rather than me this job
so I won't give any false information
side yeah
anyone's lawyers law so the more the
Saunders
was on the street on Moore's Law that
the war is over they also make room
Saunders
the way this works is on the front the
lead there is in for a little be
anything he
can communicate with the key which has
information inside it
powers of the key communicates and the
key is program with a chip in it
that he had no cuts in and as stated you
do only had one from there is a visible
there in the spring hold in place
so this is an accident roses new
director for the whole apartment
building with to throw the morn Saunders
tell the whole lot the backing from that
big but a lot of the answer
um I believe it's Kennedy Airport that
uses on everyone over gays and maybe
maybe JFK LaGuardia
I all the time I think it can be done
either using among all the gates
because need something a stand-alone
where you can swap program in to walk
away
you have audit K which means you are up
to in sticky n
result the last 100 want not what the
transactions
pullout say that you back your computer
weather then
I'll give you all the transactions and
owns it it's a very very good system
it's very very cost-effective I can't I
get pricing because because we were
from like me found it but when he got
the lead loving friend three
good question its a deeply up a lot of
broken
take a temperature loss I less but
turkey and all the way
high output all that often do the right
thing
between the anybody front like a and the
lock
when he's ready to transmit via do
little things so if you can get in there
and copy it um congratulations i cant
I also never tried it I sell it
I like being a hacker out that much time
but I will do that because he could
you getting there
yeah
although the way he says but I'd like to
see but
up boys on the deficit a
last help
yeah now what he's saying is that
something else wasn't easy for far-right
what he say that you the planet
something on dorothy was racked out
as best about their yeah his
how long at the closed on the Kikuyu
brute force not on our side of Lamar
others like Austin partly by a two way
via Yahoo installed
iron I can name your price range mike in
brazil any device because
I see how the price for the same thing
every day between many factors price
list price: dealer pricing
and holes if you've ever made
you can buy for me are many factors that
you have to buy some guy sell to lose
the distributor
and then you have to call the stolen by
for distributed about me
with welcome to business
I was installer on live prey on those
lost with y'all
on the CRL also caused by New York State
has a burglar alarm installer
a the family trait the first time buyers
are invited to my dad caught me
took me in the basement soviet Assault
at election our optical
a drought school
by and then I'm going to be up over
there many sat down just a catalyst for
an hour talk about the olden days
I just remembered he is the real party
anyone I that presently also the Russian
okay
well next I wasn't talking now the
possible arson
as the office to questions at which I go
are
cuz I read the specs are ready tax stuff
but
on an engineer %uh closes clancy to take
it off but don't lock button on the
floor cuz the unknown
but we I
well we don't yet again why is this
thing
many wise okay this property re oh by
the way and only private information
seriously interested for your business
or residential application
I will be more than happy to give us
information for leave and
I would bring us that my cards right
along with me to this type environment
with volume
young hackers are you seriously people
so I the one having a life on the
on a do
that at my home phone number or my cell
phone
my social security number a
and this is a block Bay
everybody by those restaurant
I think my pockets and white
way forgotten first it
that goes into the left side of the head
looks like a whole okay
this bright indeed this process called
by a script that was the most popular
biometric readers out there
you all probably seen that jus de los
Santos from the lowest it all and then
that's cool recognition systems I I
personally don't like brought something
home size: I wanna comment on
what that is that's hand the geometry
its composer proper have that class on
Saturday the bomb against alligators
mom as hand geometry where measures the
size your fingers and let the fingers
and become a figure of it
calif.-based think that the following
days
all the wall in left more likely at the
other end so the only closely match
other
I'll and that this offer yet rated by 0
be I so love its online up
and this product to
this product is fingerprint biometric
met
let think get that that but that's it
yeah I'm waitin for the plugin for
continuous I guess
fingerprint biometrics fingerprint
biometric wanted by much biometrics
is using something you have in your
physical body
such as your finger paint your body
shape your voice you retinal scans
early-season movies
I'll a sample anything you have in your
body
is so one way it does look up analyzed
and
that would be cool I all kinds of all
kinds of things like that
well their also other things like that a
biometrics
why use it one convenience y'all have
karaoke with you
independent application now with that
activity
tumor size committed to security tapia
fingerprint everyone see nothing on the
Internet
I know Paula that okay cabinet
fingerprint or
personal favorite is very very hard now
it was about to say about the interview
have her make his arrest on the gummy
bears in Effingham revenue taking this
they did
I the guys the way at the factory tried
on all these
I they can get to work these guys are
real nerds but I got work in the press
brought an outpost products
I woman too much well but they were
never get to work for a couple reasons
is also as life in the detection for
going to view details as life in
detection
by are cutting the finger so you got
something of a lot work
once their finger dies at but a freshly
personal
duster
what you hear from me hah
anyone's balkans obviously ross take the
whole plan to mine
have backups that when I wrestled
with grab on the highest the finger will
stay fresh
for up to I'll yall cause you saw them
looks like to say when it is false %uh
my work so that's fine others are real
time while
11:44 have 15 minutes some at-bats will
be able to handle fifty
I can't thank you guys at school I just
got a hand up to your
fingerprint does sectors can you believe
prints of Bentley being all
I G me I'll all the questions a couple
thousand set but
gimme physically like with a dozens of
printer do you mean electron
well book up going to pass base readers
some allow you to call
lanes of them so using challengers or
other device if you think a dirty
and it's taken on anything it's been
leaving a friend this doesn't have a
windshield wiper
on your competitors have bombastic
residues and only I who do not have any
sticky residue in all of its
no fillers a I don't know exactly what I
know what you mean
when he asking is can you take um
a basically does the thing but he's
using a gel for my
as though he's a mutt basically say he
does the dating front of alleged people
often than you can make a copy of the
like something else
%uh I guess you're the new law school
other love when he knew that was the
goal of up
well that with that little day that's
the by a script that the past we get
details on what does what mean it
have no idea where I was when I will
that's the stuff
New York City I'm from Jersey and get
his one-time only if you think that will
you die
present for ages something as a
what something completely off the wall
detain him but
absolutely nothing but the screw but to
know the info you have no the weekend
output format
they are we in the end I can do that
which is committed 26 that number or
higher depending on which just musing
are showing us of our honey bits it is
I use is like five by J digit serial
number you guys do the math after three
tries it times out of ten minutes on my
system
so you get three tries and then you have
to wait a minute stretch i'd the matter
how long it takes before sinn after
Fabio
another actually
this is a multi connector for display
purpose on what this does is you have
I A we get up with an awesome Rs 45 a
programming I'll
that sounds like a dumb and Hawaiian are
you can cancel these bars too valuable
to the softer
but you not be able to integrate with an
access control system largely 32 as far
as I know
to beat it if you can get the out
without a doubt I'd like to see it I
personally could
I don't know enough about this thing to
go in there in Iraq and have capital
thing friends
yes sir
absolutely nothing all you have to do is
go to ceiling slice into the wires
and adjust my attitude although as you
ever seen a joke at the file
cryptographic aidid specialist who can
create the fucking thing
a yes other super duper good
but I'm gonna start so when you done for
me love by mafia
of human factors up already yessir then
a guide on how to sing
I damn i doing out there if you go I the
country of his of the stuff in Europe
mom Europe's over there are also other
them so I don't pay attention
I wish there was a time on busy yeah yes
you're going to keep fingerprints on the
singer's
exact amount of course a worry okay
larded pairs for the readers so of
course the image below three
like that the C dot dot com well
okay you mister two-and-a-half because
the British readers are DVDs TV smart
and the products and the force be easy
slacks
FTL eloy hatch lacks thanks to
kbps real quick now these all our
weekend outlook
try again for another format to be
needed all weekend offered by
factory default um and all the knots
ever are $45 for communications for
programming only so you need 45
program it and your plugin for Peter of
or he's walking to the front to talk
with the laptop it only a couple minutes
by the application watched all hardware
back to one inflation's Center
so you will have to every person on
every door around to every door
okay the best up to 100 users
only work as much as your finger call
the one too many return don't ask me why
that's my boss told me
honestly other why they call one too
many it's up to two hundred years is the
key thing I don't be
we will implement the lobby region
figure
that's it send the output it doesn't
know you that it sends a red light
if it does not mean but the green light
that's it
it simple this is great for small
offices Pakistani
happy with this and cells
yeahh put on the table for the iPhone as
a green beans
fun female okay
we can beat them dolomite guess attend
his b-day
put your finger on and updated mineral
yeah because it was a good for you think
I don't know
inmates are like president
Bud Light if you go to
compusa in RadioShack any interest on
the city I don't want to be
a hey look at that I wanna be abolished
you can buy there's nothing buy compact
that's a mouse with a fingerprint reader
every loss because a hundred boxing is
to get there now lack of security
that I can say that but he said they saw
I can say that but I happened to
possibly I can see bomb
they sample attended 15 months after
finger
am if you missed out on my butt and
that's how they work
I if you go to the finger those 10 to 15
points may very well be killed
and I don't have a computer that you can
use any more turkey that
published K so this jail sentence 150
points the finger shipping is there
anything despite what you think you're
just kind of my own work either to get
off
but I'll that's that are simple
340 points as not to point to make some
house without a bit
selector several shapes not the points
because points can change a thing again
slightly dirty
shit on change but ready for the shapes
make a novel about a bit when do you ask
her to call me for fingerprints
and now everyone will have Isaac's
fingerprint on their computer
guns i think is on the way as other yeah
when you thought it was funny thing is
awesome oh yeah I figured that kind of a
missile yellow
doesn't know what he is asking that'll
related to relate to that what that was
but the wire
about me well Hillsborough ca forget
the past two hundred users only the
figure
the procs up to four thousand users
but because the mail users and the first
time we take the four thousand years ago
proximity card proxy card is a
first-year just happened to do that also
possibly cartridge long and also what
use are you ok
that's what it's for the security
features just tryna nice is also there
you touch it it turns on anybody figure
on
and urine final I'll try anything in
front of it the truck honey ham
I got halfway through the EMA and
outside base-running you touch it
and I that's it that's the process I
don't an HID proximity
thank you budget little yellow line atop
terms of
region is good
and that's one is the the slats
which is all there in the end Ken Segall
these lights just like the fossil same
was yes yes they do have a lot of the we
get out
all these are the real now that a all
these are the real
they simply said I we get signal in
whatever that we get singled to be done
with
but yes Control Panel just send up the
signal the serial number that you can
after let's do so. the sad he just
doesn't do it this weekend out though
it's like ours too early to for the file
anything else as well talk about I just
as last summer
doesn't care what does they've really
disappointed in other users
because I'll tell us the best
the proximate seven minutes I have to go
really fast right now
an overall statistical I'll the past
the prophets these leads the flights to
level 10 HIV-related houses several
weekend invite
even use the TPS cards while only and
Kearns
I proximity card as the other method of
authentication
the other either find nothing rather
than just cross
if you go into a system where they
really have much stress really have
other things
pages that foregoing the system we want
you to keep as long have to carry cards
all
to do that these less flexible
are you so good he said it's flexible
its ok
this Martin smart card technology smart
card technology no
medium to low of now basically how we're
CBS the talk to the questions I probably
can answer them
but Isaac and that's why we're here site
the van with effect basically the smart
the smart has unlimited users the only
limitation
is the access control system for clinton
I'll or the computers make someone with
extremely high limit
I am mine as its up to $500 per door so
-0500 or that i think is
really really hot so that other reason
why is
on here the fingerprint the stored
internally in this unit on here looking
for the store in turn the machine
on here thinking for the storm in the
smart card at the five is a
right but five minutes that he said he's
waving
so in these markets more store the
information on the smart card
I V is the spice to tell you about it
I'm and
that way the database is just a little
here all this has basically in the crypt
password
we take the plunge it bring up it says
okay have my past 17 a fingerprint
said the fingerprint over and compares
I'll be smart works
this one simply put your finger print
the page was elected
this problem nelson also be i'ma show
you all
0 any volunteers
are you know something which show a
model is the product
okay these are the ones already
installed this my car
but when I put it on because I'm a mess
it up to the FDA
in your pocket grab one when the
reflecting
19 June 6 live online tonight obviously
don't leave
okay one software basic okay Alice rebut
poses to pretty perky
all the software all the tickets are
free to do whatever your neck to toe
if your mobile real snow storm looking
into that click on them by manager
control template ID number we get there
from
real so idk are you touch with any
Google Alert igniting way is that a job
at home with Julia just for the pictures
went from leading I'm still processing
now
I hate computers so much too much
thought you guys have like them on TR CE
something could use this
lives with her husband but were
collected with with other I think I'll
think lorena busting regret that's it
think
yep anything wrong place finger on Sat
good-hearted anything once again region
which ones like you read your finger on
your yeah ago image
whole removing I'm cool I can do stuff
like this
okay well this should be shown the image
but whatever the case I'll
well this is why the mafia likes it
should be shown in image but because the
future is with pizza sauce
I'm exile do that again control
from Reno touch it be a delay the wrong
pleasure nonsense hoping their
okay you wanna get three or four stars
on both knees
this is the image of his actual figure
now you can still sell
this is what the juiciest this post or
so if you take this
and to prepare for the FBI they don't
have this they call tracking by
at Walmart loves and various other
people who don't want to using the
latest or the fingerprint
because this is all you have you can
copy this you can we can copy it
but can't do anything useful in cuz you
take this you with my finger his finger
it's not the same so what you cooking
all did that night except
think the thing you're just for record
using
i thinkI real so it doesn't matter just
for
I'll be calling what do you see INZ
a AC took
temple in that story about that it's
something for the future and software
becomes better for them
me as polish yeah
%uh use already there the safety car
unit
Street threshold but that is just a
defense treaty levels over
they're not yes not enough to walk
around to make sure you can easily on a
good
of medium is the average than just sex
on the points you think it actually is
I usually leave a medium another try
anything else the real reason to know
i think is the problem is as always our
nuclear missile world
day blue pharmacy or something my life
such a venue safeguard unit
and you're done in exile now and I've
got a confidence thing on in my work but
it is upside down even have gone
straight
and it arms turn orange
who uptrend rate know honestly didn't
think that this
is on the figures set on their straight
because it was upside down before
you value most in your strength but
we're all what is going on the street
anything like
attending was the only thing right first
off I never
okay got clicking role original get for
reader
Kayla role placing on Sat
okay except that be
olney it going
yes exit
I chafing yet the controversial
where the yeah
got another from the 20 K wake up
haha not enough information official one
minute
oh my god okay only i gt are it works in
about the other night in order for
result I lived on my lunch
call I and thats access control for your
quick step for the little as any
questions anyone who wants to buy stuff
for me I love the people
%uh since I can sell directly to you I
will budget others with the right people
also giving product information
also lost a lot of other stuff including
video systems and alarm systems of
another star
lot a lot a lot thank you very much have
a great day
questions yeah it's
weird
please contact me to just go through
yeah old
house for the moment the lack of you
but let's take a look but that's able to
show you his contact me
please do not send a message not upon
the problem okay yes
the Holy Land free that low all about
you can call is not
I yeah I always climate best I've really
don't forget that insults a next
why did you log in there's no way a mop
casually get the fingerprints and
divides I enjoy most of what they are
developing get
I get that if you call I was
contractually law but a lot of time I
just got back death toll as the economy
now this but what was the question is
when it was announced
okay are so yes there is only a model
nothing damn it could be a fish for
I let full thats
thank you very much board
loved
yes
letters
guide on the internet and look for their
everywhere they can get off of my dad
pops
I take the key problem ice cream video
cameras are wild
exactly enjoy a good one talk to a
camera guy cameras not going gets tough
let's go to the strip
although i know i do not that hard
can given temperature sensor nobody
should be easy of the wiring
old
I know it this is a fingerprint device
they also have a handprint
it is almost right next to each other
three new wiring of I get a lead on a
classicism
yeah I guess didn't know that this is
the all
yes yes yes
separation databases separate because
the fingerprint databases 1 the Astros
another
work yes
group
today
reading them if you added to my data
visually and now between you can rip it
off the wall
and you can simply for any given W my
weekends are not legal for a lot longer
than the detailed
very true home but then how to clone it
might be hard if you can do that
I talking that would be cool you do it
are publicly of across
we actually not everybody form a line at
the end Baltimore
I think about it yes