we have any introduction to mac OS
kernel exploitation by jeff ball so my
name is jeff ball I'm gonna talk a
little bit of about Mac OS kernel
exploitation as he just mentioned first
off who am i I'm a researcher at grim
I'm also a member of the DEF CON group
of Orange County and my handle is Jeff
ball at 55 on Twitter if you want to
look me up later so first we're gonna
talk a little bit about why we will care
about trying to exploit the Mac OS
kernel first reason is obviously that it
controls all of the authorization checks
and prevents any type of system
modifications that you might want to do
and so if you can exploit the kernel
then you can obviously bypass these and
so that's the the most obvious reason
why you would want to the second reason
is that a lot of software is started
sandboxing itself so for instance fari
will sandbox any of the more complicated
processing and it's one way you can
break out of sandbox is because
oftentimes when you're inside the
sandbox you can still talk to the kernel
and so you can exploit the kernel you
can easily just by pious and get out of
the sandbox without having to go through
and try and exploit the other half of
the unseen box process and so it's just
oftentimes seen as the easier of the two
approaches to just exploit the kernel
and get out that way rather than trying
to go the other way and so those are
kind of the two of the more main ones
the second one being a more recent
concern next I'm just going to talk a
little bit about an introduction to the
xnu kernel which is the Mac OS kernel so
the ex-new kernel is actually a
combination of two kernels there's the
MA calf and the BSD half mock was an
early research project out of Carnegie
Mellon it is actually a microkernel and
so what that is is it tries to only have
the components that are necessary to be
running inside of ring three as compared
to a monolithic one like the other half
over the bsd half and so what that means
is it will do simple things like message
passing memory management's
scheduling but the rest is run as
applications inside of userland and so
if my application wants to send a
network packet I don't actually talk to
the kernel to send that Network packet I
pass a message to the networking
application which then sends the network
packet out as compared to within
traditional monolithic kernels like
Linux or Windows I just talked to the
kernel directly and that code that does
the network parsing and network sending
of packets is inside of the kernel and
so it can be seen to be a much more
secure approach because if you were to
exploit the networking application you
only gain access to that application and
not the entire OS so Mac OS is actually
a combination of that and the monolithic
kernel of BSD so the bsd half provides
things like the disk i/o and networking
i/o management of processes whereas the
mach half does things like memory
management inter process communication
messages and managing of tasks and
threads one other thing to note is the X
and U kernel is open source Apple puts
it up on open source Apple comm and they
also have a github that lags slightly
behind their website you can go and get
it compile it and make changes and
install it yourself on your macbook they
don't always have the latest version up
so they will put up the new versions of
the kernel open sourced slightly after
so for instance right now the latest
version that's open source is ten
thirteen six and they're on to 1014 for
Mojave so a little bit about the maca
that's important for to know for
exploitation is mock is heavily based on
passages and so if you want to talk to a
service you pass a message to it and
those are called mock messages on the
other hand and when you pass a message
you pass it to a processes or a tasks
mock port which is basically just a
endpoint for you to receive a one
directional mock message the ports
themselves have access restrictions
which are known as port rights in mock
terminology and those being send send
once and receive CIN
is obvious you can send if you have the
send right on a port you can send a mock
message to it receive is also obvious if
you have the receive right you are the
receiver for that mock port you get all
messages from that are sent to that port
and then send once means you're allowed
to send a mock message to a port once
that's often used for callback
functionality so if I have the received
port and someone sends me a message and
they want me to be able to talk back
they'll give me a send once right to one
of their own ports and so through that
mechanism I can then use that send right
or send once right to send a message
back the other thing that's important to
note is that these mock port rights can
be passed through mock messages so you
can send it to another process or
another process can send it to you and
that's actually how you get the port
rights for other services these mock
ports and mock messages are how a large
portion of the services and kernel API
is accessed from user land so for
instance if I want to draw something on
the screen I will get a port right to
the windows server which is the process
on Mac OS that does all of the drawing
and I will send a mock message
requesting that it draw something on the
screen and then it did an addition to
the processes like windows the windows
service the kernel actually has a number
of ports as well that it listens on that
you can send messages to as well see on
the next slide one other thing that's
useful to know especially when talking
about exploiting through the use of mock
ports and messages is task port task
port Tsar like other ports except as the
name implies they focus on managing a
task and so this allows if you have the
task port to a task or prop process the
one side note the processes are the BSD
term and tasks are the mock term they
are correlated in that each process has
a corresponding task but I'm going to
basically use them interchangeably but
anyway if you have the task port for a
task it lets you do things like create a
thread fork it terminate and very
usefully read and write the memory of
that task that's useful for the debugger
and so things like ll DB and gdb will
use task force
to debug other processes we'll see a
little bit later how they're useful for
exploitation the next component that I'm
going to talk about is i/o kit IO kit is
kind of another portion of the kernel
that is the device driver framework it
allows you to create device drivers
without having to code the whole thing
yourself
it's a C++ wrapper that allows you to
just extend off of base classes most
related to your driver and so there's a
number of classes that you can inherit
off of that will have most of the
functionality you'll need with you just
needing to implement the specific
components related to your device when
you code a device driver and i/o kit one
of the things that you can do is you
register that driver with the i/o
registry through that the user LAN
components that want to talk to your
driver
they will look it up via the i/o
registry and create an i/o user client
which is just the i/o frameworks class
for talking to that driver and then you
can define functions in the driver that
the user land can call with their own
values and so if you want to provide a
way for users a user land process to
talk to your driver in order to make it
work you just register it with the i/o
registry the user name process creates
an i/o user client and then it just
calls the functions in your driver that
you've defined for that purpose one of
the internally this is all based off of
mock messages the i/o kit framework and
use your land when you say please call
this driver method or please give me a
user client before this driver will talk
to the i/o kit nasty report which is a
mock port and it will say please call
this method on behalf of this user
client one thing you can do is you can
sorry screen size changed you can look
and see what what drive I awoke it
drivers are available via the i/o edge
command and so in this you can see that
I have the VirtualBox driver at the
bottom that's installed and if I want to
talk to it I would make a VirtualBox USB
user
client and then I would be able to call
the various functions that the
VirtualBox driver has oh shoot sorry let
me get out of that yeah that's good he
told me now cuz oh wow
this change size on me well alright
there's the VMware one cuz I also have
that installed but so if I wanted to I
could talk to that kernel extension by
making a VMware USB port USB client and
then calling the functions that that
driver has set up for to me to call so
that's just one of the areas of text if
this is all of these drivers here it's
very hard to see at this huge screen
size but it's actually a hierarchy with
drivers having multiple different
classes anywho anyway so moving on they
just talked a little bit about the
attack surface that's available if
you're trying to go after the X and you
colonel
obviously like most OS is it's got sis
calls there's the BSD half which has
over 500 sis calls and that Apple keeps
changing them with each kernel update
and so they will introduce new
functionality which means new bugs as
well as some of the old ones also have
the still bugs and they continue to find
bugs in the large number of sis calls
that BSD provides and then additionally
because the X new kernel is split in
half there's also the mock half which
has their traps which is just another
terminology for how they talk about sis
calls those also have had bugs in recent
years Ian beers found one and wrote a
jailbreak using it just I think last
year
additionally like Linux there's device
files and those device files have iocked
dolls and so that is another part place
where user values and user data can be
parsed which may lead to bugs networking
protocols also have taken user input and
so just a week and a half ago or so
there was the ICMP error vulnerability
which the networking code inside of the
bsd half for ice
P error messages incorrectly read
trusted a.length inside of the packet
which led to a heap overflow which can
lead to memory corrupt or which will
lead to memory corruption and can
possibly be exploited so that code while
it has been there for a while is still
having bugs as simple as not checking a
header length so that it could also be
another area and then one of the areas
that I'm gonna talk a little bit more
about today and the vulnerability we'll
focus on is inside of an i/o kit driver
device drivers are notorious for having
bugs because they aren't as widely used
or as looked at as the rest of the
kernel and they also parse user data and
so if a device driver author forgets to
check a value that might lead to a
vulnerability and we'll see how that I
actually can and how that vulnerability
can be exploited in a little bit next
I'm going to talk a little bit about
some of the methods of debugging or
testing while you're trying to write an
exploit and so what can you do to try
and help yourself out to make things a
little bit easier so the first thing i
said or i already mentioned is that xnu
is open source and you can compile and
install it and make changes to it it's a
little bit of a process there's
oftentimes slight changes to the build
system that their build mechanisms that
you'll need to make in order to get it
compiled but there are some handy guides
online you can find oftentimes you'll
have to make small Corrections to the
source code such as just commenting out
or casting a field that that a compiler
option would cause a warning that will
make the build not work so one of the
things you can do while you're debugging
things is just add print statements and
look at D message it can be a little bit
of a process to recompile it and
reinstall it every time but it is a very
simple way to try and see what's going
on in the kernel the kernel also does
have some code to not print out pointers
so you'll have to get rid of that as
well if you try and print out pointers
which bug things overall it's not the
most effective way but it's very simple
the next one is if you manage to crash
the kernel you can see an output of from
the panic log
and so if you want to know what happened
you can look at that example again which
will probably be miss formatted ah so
it's not that bad but anyway it looks a
little bit like this if you crash the
kernel you can see it will dump all of
the registers and then give you a stack
trace as well and so if you're trying to
figure out what exactly happened you can
come see and think oh this values in are
the RX register I thought it would be
this value so it's again not the most
helpful but it is somewhat useful after
that you've crashed it and you're trying
to figure out what happened what went
wrong with my exploit in the stack trace
you can see in this one
I was overriding the stack with this
nonsense value so it failed to walk its
full way back up the stack so you can
see the frame pointer is just three
three three so again another useful
useful thing you can do while debugging
but not the most useful z print z print
is a heap specific tool it prints out
the heap allocations from the zone
allocator it will tell you how many of
each zone is allocated and you can use
that while heaps praying or trying to
look at when memory allocations are made
it's very useful if you're trying to
exploit a heap based vulnerability so
this right sorry
such a small to see yes alright in this
it's just Z print printing out the
kalloch which is one of the main
allocators in the kernel it's printing
out the number of elements in each zone
so for instance if we have a
vulnerability that affects a specific
zone such as the 256 one we can take a
look at the number of allocations in
that and we can whenever we're trying to
do something like heap flood this will
tell us when new ones are being made or
when they're being released and we kind
of contract the progress of what's going
on with the Cal yeah in the calc 256
zone this is kind of a specific tool
that's really only useful if you're
trying to exploit a heap based
vulnerability the next tool which is
very useful for a lot of different
situations is 1 by Sigma it's called iOS
carney tools it's also available for mac
OS so it's useful for this as well and
what that does is it shows you the
kernel memory map and then it also
allows you to read and write kernel
memory and so if you're trying to figure
out what happened or what's at a
specific address and the kernel memory
you can use these tools one downside is
it does require you to already have
roots so obviously you can't use it in
an exploit it also requires you to have
already exported a kernel task port to
userland and I'll get into what that
means and in a little bit when we look
at our exploit the other thing that you
can do instead of already having it a
curl test board is you can recompile
your kernel and patch it to allow for
this I haven't in the repository then
I'm going to push with this talk I have
instructions on how to do that now just
let's take a quick look at it all right
good
so in this kernel I have already like I
said it requires root and so as you can
probably would have been able to see
with better formatting this is the
kernel memory map it shows you what is
that each dress and so for instance on
this one
it shows you that there is a kernel
extension with 16 K of memory read/write
permissions and so you can just
basically see where everything is in the
kernels memory and so if you're trying
to figure out what is that a specific
location or where it is in memory you
can use these tools one of the other
ones it's also useful it's called kmm
that stands for kernel memory and as you
can probably guess from the name it
allows you to read and write memory and
so what I'm asking it there is to print
out 40 bytes at that address and so
that'll just show us that that string is
at that address in the kernel memory we
can also use this tool to write to
kernel memory if we want to try out a
payload or a post exploitation mechanism
without actually having to re exploit it
the kernel each time so you can use
these tools for that purpose as well
they're very useful and I highly
recommend them and then the last tool
which is probably the most useful but
also the most the most work to set up
and is also a little buggy is just the
kernel debugging you can set up the
debugger for the kernel and then step
through it or set breakpoints and read
memory or if it crashes it'll come back
to you and you can see what happened one
thing you do have to do is run that and
if you change the env Rams to include
that command however you can't do that
while sip is on so it requires you to
reboot into system recovery or turn off
system integrity protection yourself so
one thing that to note is that Apple all
is in addition to making the source they
make the kernel debug symbols available
for the official Apple o kernels so if
you want to debug an official kernel you
can just go download the symbols with an
Apple Developer account and install them
and then use that in the debunker so
just to show that off a little bit
simply start the debugger then you just
tell it to load the kernel debugger
symbols yeah I compiled the kernel that
that VM is running and so I have the
symbols there then you can load up that
command the KDP remote command with the
IP address of the VM or the other
computer that you're debugging this does
work over the network and then you hit
the magic key combination to tell the
debugger to start up in the kernel this
for Apple is control option command
shift escape so right now that VM is
frozen and if we go back to the debugger
and try and connect to it you'll see
that it loads it up and we've now
stopped at that address inside of the
debugger and so what you can do is you
can set breakpoints or read and write
memory or registers and then continue
the I just hit enter hit can type
continue and hit enter and the the OS
will start up and until it hits a break
point where you crash the kernel you
won't be given context back to it so
this is useful that you could set
breakpoints on your op gadgets or at the
vulnerability and read the registers and
memory and see what all is happening and
where things are going wrong or how you
can adjust things accordingly this is um
just a super useful but it it also is a
little buggy often times it just crashes
or you don't your breakpoints might not
be hit so it's does have its faults but
it's very useful
next I'm going to talk a little bit
about some of the mitigations for
criminal exploits that are present in
the xnu kernel so the first one is
kernel address space layout
randomization the Mac OS kernel is
actually loaded at any one of 256
different spots in memory they randomly
pick a slide value and then that gets
added to the load address of the kernel
and so each each load address is two
mega bar and two megabytes apart and so
there's 512 there 510 different
megabytes that it could be changed so
essentially if you're trying to exploit
and you try to hard code in address that
will only work one out of 256 times and
so it's not a very useful thing you need
to find a way to leak that address and
calculate it for development purposes
there's the caste info which stands for
kernel address space info assist call
that you can call and that will actually
just give you back the kernel slide and
so it's very useful to start out with
using the caste info syscall until
you've worked up your exploit to be able
to leak that address one thing to notice
that does of course require root because
they don't want to just have a Kor
bypass and it only works with system
integrity protection disabled or a
compiled kernel to remove that and on
the left you can just see we can see
that the kernel on the first with a slot
of 0 is loaded at that base address
which is the default one and then with a
slide of dthe with six zeros it gets
loaded at D with six zeros higher than
the the zero slide it's not a very
complicated randomization and it's also
rather weak as we'll see the next
mitigation that Mac OS has is supervisor
mode execution protection so what that
does is the kernel will refuse to run in
run in user land memory and so if you
try to tell it to jump to a use to code
inside the user land the processor will
actually throw an exception and when
that happens the kernel
and your ex point won't work prior to
this you could just if you were
overriding a function pointer you could
just override the function pointer with
the hard-coded address that you put code
at a New Zealand and the kernel would
jump to it
you could run a little snippet of code
that would do whatever your desired
effect was and then you could just clean
up and it would that would be as
complicated as it got now now we can't
do that anymore and we have to find some
other way to run code that's not from
user land pages the next mitigation is
supervisor mode access protection or
SMAP it's another Intel processor
feature that is only recent so only the
late later 2016 and anon models of
MacBooks have them essentially it's very
similar to the exploit protection except
it is for reading and writing memory
from user land so the kernel will refuse
to read or write memory directly from
user then obviously this can't be on all
the time so the Mac OS kernel just
selectively turns it on and off when it
it's meant to and so if you're not in
using one of the specific functions to
copy data from you use your land the
snap will be the snap protection will be
on if you are inside one of those
specific functions that will be off and
so what this does is if the
vulnerability allows us to dereference
an arbiter arbitrary address or read
something from an arbitrary address we
can't host our that data inside of a
user Lane process we need to get it into
the kernel and memory somehow and so
this is just another one of those
protections that makes our job as an
exploit writer harder
and then the final mitigation we'll talk
about is not really an exploit
mitigation more of just a defense
against a successful exploit well some
other non kernel means and so it's
system integrity protection also known
as rootless when it was first introduced
the name is actually kind of a misnomer
which is why they changed it there's
still a root account it's just less
powerful system integrity protection
prevents you from as the root user doing
certain actions so if I want to write to
the bin directory to change some process
or debug some one of Apple's processes
system integrity protection won't let me
and so even as the root user would where
I was I'm supposed to have ultimate
authority to do whatever I want on Mac
OS I can't
whereas on something like Linux the root
user is all-powerful and can do that
this is implemented through Mac OS is
mandatory access control framework which
is based off of trusted BSD which is
essentially just a large number of
kernel hooks scattered throughout the
kernel that whenever an actions such as
creating a file or opening a socket are
happens the kernel will call one of
those hooks for the installed policies
and that function hook will decide is
this user allowed to write to this file
or open the socket and so on we can just
take a quick look at that and so this is
sorry it's gonna keep getting me yeah so
this is the struct inside the kernel
that has all of the function pointers
and so for instance we have the check
file oh it's down there the file check
function pointer when I go to create a
file the kernel will iterate over each
of the policies and check if that
function pointers define and it will
call that function if for each policy
and the system integrity protection is
just one of the policies that are in
them and we'll see how we can neuter
this by knocking out those function
pointers later on just a little demo of
system integrity protection actually
first I have to change snapshots
so that previous one was after the
exploit so that I could show the i/os
Kearney kills
all right so the CSR util is a simple
utility which lets you turn on and off
system integrity protection obviously
can only run recovery mode or if the SIP
is already turned off and you can use
the status command to just check and so
we can see that it is enabled and so if
I yeah I'm the root user right now but
if I try to write to the bin directory
I'm not allowed so it just tells me
operation not permitted because sips
Paul C function for create files was
called and it said oh you're trying to
write to the bin directory I'm not going
to allow it because that would be a
system modification and sips purpose is
to not allow that so that is a system
integrity protection we'll see how to
turn that off in a second so next we're
gonna I'm going to show off the specific
vulnerability and then we'll talk
through how you go about creating an
exploit for it the vulnerability that I
chose for this case study is that CV up
there which is a vulnerability in the AV
bridge dry i/o kit driver it was
originally found by Alex Plaskett the
URL for that is down there when you go
to pull up the slides this is a IO kit
func driver function you can call it
from kernel with a user control value
and so what it is is this user control
value is passed into the command gates
array it has an index off it and then it
calls a C++ function of one of the
objects in that array however the array
is not checked to make sure that it is
within the bounds of the array
just a little visualization of that we
have our AV bridge object up there and
there's a command gates array which has
four objects in it it's only for value
long however they don't check the index
so we can fill in any value and it will
go to whatever that addresses in memory
and try and read out a pointer to a C++
IO command gate object and then it will
read the feed table out pointer from
that command
object and then do you reference it if
you're not familiar with C++ V tables
they're essentially just arrays of
function pointers for a class and so
what this is doing is when I say zero
for that index it called it goes to the
zeroth item it reads the pointer out
goes to the V table pointer reads it out
again which goes to right here it adds
an offset to it and in this case it's
trying to call the run action function
which is 1c 8 down from the top of the V
table it will read that pointer and then
it jumps to it and so however if we give
it a much larger index it will try and
read something from memory up here which
clearly one point at one of these I'll
command gates and things will go wrong
if I can't read if that isn't a valid
pointer it'll crash if it is it will try
and use that as if it were an i/o
command gate and try and read a V table
pointer out and so we'll look at how we
can kind of fake that out and cause it
to jump to our code so now I'm just
gonna talk a couple about a couple
techniques that we'll look at and for
bypassing some the mitigations as well
as exporting the first one is one of the
important things to do is spray the
memory because we don't know where that
object is in memory specifically because
of the ksl our slide well will need to
spray the memory and so we'll have to
what that we do with that is we allocate
a large number of blocks and we fill
those blocks with our fake object
pointers and then when the kernel at we
give it an index larger than that it
will reach around past the top of the
memory back into our userland memory and
somewhere within the spray what we'll do
is we'll actually spray two gigabytes of
memory so that that 512 megabyte slide
that it could possibly have is just
miniscule in comparison and it will
always land within our two gigabytes
spread one thing to note about when
you're doing this in userland
you don't actually need to 'allah gate
allocate the two gigabytes of memory you
can just use duplicated memory mappings
to all it to set up that memory with
your spray without actually adding more
because you the memory is copy on right
it's only allocated when you change it
you can make as many of those as you
want and you can actually allocate more
in your spray than memory then you have
in your laptop so for instance this
MacBook has 16 gigabytes of memory but
using duplicated memory mappings I was
able to spray 32 gigabytes of memory or
however much I want because it's not
actually allocated and so as you can see
I'm left without the spray if we use a
hard-coded index it'll point if the
slide is 0 it might actually point to
our user memory if it's not then it
might not point to our user land
remember whereas if we just have a too
good good bite spray it will always hit
somewhere in our usual our user only in
memory how we'll use that just looks a
little bit like this what we'll do is we
will spray fake vtable pointers which
are essentially these pointers oh right
here sorry the pointers right here well
spray a bunch of fake vtable pointers as
if that was the the i/o command gate
objects then we'll use a hard-coded
index it will wrap the memory will wrap
back around back to right here and then
these will all point to our payload
pointer which would be essentially a
normal point at run action but will
instead point to our payload and so and
that's how we'll get code execution one
of the things to note is if we were to
try that it wouldn't work because of
smack
if your computer is new enough and you
have snap that when you try and point it
into usually in memory it'll actually
just crash because of the processor
exception so instead what you can do is
you can spray the kernel with that
memory and so and then point it into the
kernel instead there's a number of i/o
kit classes which you can allocate via
various api's with the kernel in kernel
memory one of the more useful ones is
called OS OS string which is just simply
just an i/o kit string object they're
very useful because you can set that all
of the content you can create them or
delete them or read them back whenever
you want and you can make them of
arbitrary size and so what you can do is
you can create many large string objects
in it and it will actually allocate that
in memory and once you've filled up the
available free slots they will all be
allocated in a row
and so that lets you all okay
use a hard-coded memory address because
it's such a large amount of memory and
so for this macbook i was actually able
to spray two gigabytes of memory and
find that the address ffff nine to five
eight with followed by six zeros is
always allocated and always set to my
content if i've sprayed to your bytes of
memory so we can use that to point
things there and when we need to bypass
man the specific laptop does not so we
don't have to bypass that this laptop
actually does have snap though so we
will have to bypass that and the way
that's done is simply through return
oriented programming or Rob like you
would in a normal user land exploitation
as well what that does essentially just
you set the stack to value that you
control and then you will set one
address you want to run any values it
uses and then the read instruction will
read that address and execute this
little code snippets that you can then
combine to do something in this example
on the right we have a gadget that's pop
RDI ret and so what that will do is it
will pop this RDI value into the RDI
register off the stack and then the ret
will load the next gadget which is a pop
RSI which will do the same with the RSI
value and through that means you can set
the registers and then if you put a
function address on there it will call
that function as x86 is fast call or
takes the arguments via that registers
that will call a function with our
arguments that we want and so through
that we can run our little bits of code
without actually having to get that code
loaded up into kernel memory in in an
executable memory region one of the
other things to note is the function
thread exception return which is very
useful function when doing Rob what that
function does is it will just stop the
kernel context and return to user land
wherever you are
and so how that's useful is such that if
you don't safely end your wrap chain the
current
we'll crash and when it crashes you
obviously the OS goes down and you can't
use anything that you just did in your
rock chain and so you need to safely
exit your rock chain or return it back
to the normal context and there's two
ways of doing that one there's the
complicated way of getting back onto the
correct stack frame with the creative
values on it in order to continue
execution the other way which is much
easier is just to call the function
thread exception return a normal user
land exploitation this doesn't really
matter as much because you can just let
your process crash and after you've
achieved whatever you were trying to in
kernel land that would cause the OS to
crash and so you just throwing that
function on there it will terminate your
Rob chain how we'll use that is simply
we'll just rather than pointing the
payload buffer into our payload will
point it up into a kernel Rob gadget the
first drop gadget is our stack pivot and
so what that does in this in this
vulnerability re X points into content
week control and so what we'll do is
we'll push the first gadget pushes our X
onto the stack and then pops it into the
stack pointer so what that does is it
just allows us to set the stack to our
content and lets us set up those gadgets
on the stack that we'll run after that
we just set up our Rob chain to call
whatever functions we want so
specifically we want that those Rob
gadgets to make us become route and so
this little snippet of code we will run
in Rob gadgets that will grab the
current process struct out of kernel
memory it will take the credentials out
of that and then the POSIX credentials
which is just an inner wrapper inside of
the credential structs and we'll assign
0 or the ID for route to the saved user
ID pointer and so that little snippet of
code essentially makes our process have
root privileges we'll just use the set
UID to take the saved you ID pointer and
make it the effective one again and then
we've become route because we've
modified the structure that holds what
user we are in kernel memory
after we've become Rupe the next thing
we're gonna want to do is get a kernel
task port exported to user land I
mentioned that was what you needed in
order to use the iOS Kern utils to read
and write kernel memory this is actually
how it's accomplished the kernel is a
task just like any other it's task is
given pit 0 it's the first task
obviously and because it's a task you
can use the normal read and write mock
API in order to read and write kernel
memory if you have the kernel task board
so the VM read and VM write functions
they can be used to just read it like
you would any other process with that
kernel task board and so what we'll do
is we'll have our rock chain grab that
kernel task port and shove it into the
real hosts array the real hosts array is
a functionality in the the mac OS kernel
which holds a number of ports that you
can query from user land and obtain and
so if you want to grab a port to a
service like the auto mount daemon tour
the audit daemon you can ask the kernel
to retrieve one of those for you and
give it to you so that you can talk to
those various statements however there
are some empty slots in there and we'll
just use our rock chain to copy the
pointer to the kernel task to one of
those empty slots and then whenever our
any user land process wants to have to
modify criminal memory or recur memory
they can ask the kernel for that
specific port out of the real hosts
array and then use that to call the VM
read in vm write functions that's
actually become one of the more standard
techniques and so a lot of tools such as
the iOS Kern utils will try and retrieve
that port to grab the kernel task board
and then they can use that to read and
write memory so then one of the the next
thing we'll want to do now that we have
the ability to read and write memory but
we don't have to use complicated Rob to
do it we can just ask for the task port
and call the normal function Alice's
will want to neuter system integrity
protection or just turn it off and so
that's actually rather trivial once you
obtained kernel memory read/write
ability and so there's a symbol called
Mac policy list which lists all of the
policies that are currently enforced for
the for Mac OS and so we'll just read
that area of memory out of the kernel
and updated so all those function
pointers we saw where are now zero we
can just take a look at what that let's
take a look at what that how that's done
the macros here K read and K right just
to read from kernel memory yeah maybe
that's better so at the top you can see
we're reading out the Mac policy list
and then we go down here to the for loop
where we iterate over each entry in that
list we'll read the list out of memory
if it's not null or that slot is an
empty will then read the specific policy
out and the function pointers that make
up that policy and then we'll just
change them all to be null
and so then next time the kernel goes to
call one of these functions that
function pointer will be null and the
kernel will think hey there that policy
doesn't define it it doesn't care about
that specific action and so it's the one
that as I showed before in the file
check create that function is called
when we create a file but if that
pointer is now null it won't actually be
called and so if we do that to the
system integrity and then down here we
write it out if we do that to the system
integrity protection policy that'll
essentially turn it off so we've written
it back to kernel memory with all those
modified function pointers and it's
essentially neutered
so now just to show off the exploit that
we've been building
so once again we can't we can't modify
it even though we're route let's go over
here to where we're not route we'll run
our exploit and we get a root shell
essentially what happened to us we
sprayed our memory set up the rock
gadgets so that the spray memory points
into the pointer to our rock gadgets
well we triggered the vulnerability with
a hard-coded index which caused it to
wrap around past the end of memory back
into our sprayed memory then it would
call it D references that D references
again to the pointer to our op gadgets
runs each of them then we call that
thread exception return function which
returns back to user land after it our
wrap chain is copied the kernel task
pointer into that real host array we use
the set UID to become root after our
wrap chain fixed our credentials to be
zero and then we called the API to get
that kernel task pointer back and we
used it to modify the system integrity
protections function hooks so that
they're all zero and then we just launch
a root shell and now you can see I'm
root and if I want to change the bin
directory I can just however I want
although those function pointers are no
longer called so I'm essentially allowed
to do whatever I want without system
integrity protection stopping me
so and that's kind of conclusion let's
hope that was helpful if you go to try
and exploit the Mac OS kernel I'll be
pushing all the materials for this talk
to that URL later today and that's my
contact info if you have any questions
afterwards there's any questions now I
can take them or we can go to lunch yes
it's real hard to because essentially
all those tools are going to run at the
kernel level and you are also running at
the kernel level after you've
successfully exploited them what one of
the more effective things that can be
done about this is sandboxing and so I
mentioned how kernel exploits are kind
of a way around the sandbox but in some
cases you're not actually allowed to
call various api's to the kernel and so
that actually can be a way to lower the
attack surface if you want to stop these
it's really more useful to stop the to
not expose that attack surface than it
is to try and catch it after they're
running their own code at kernel level
since if you're running at the same
protection levels what that Apple
actually does with iOS is they have
higher levels of it with the secure
element and so the secure element is one
level above the kernel and so it can
actually look down and try and catch
various things and so that doesn't
really exist on Mac OS which is why it's
kind of an easier target
so that specifically does not in fact if
I go back there you can actually see it
still it it actually still thinks system
integrity protections enabled because
all I did was neuter it
however the CSR utils will now actually
work to disable it or are changing the
way you disable is by changing the NVRAM
and i and i nuked the function pointers
that prevented you from changing nvram
so now I can turn it off if I wanted to
but these this specific exploit doesn't
do that because I was just trying to
show off how you can change kernel
memory but now you're outside of sip and
once you're outside of sip you can make
any changes you want to the nvram it's
essentially the way you turn it off and
without an exploit is you boot up into
recovery mode where sip isn't enabled
except now sip is just not enabled
because of my exploit
Oh