alright so for our after lunch talk I
know you guys have full bellies but
thank you for coming back here this will
be Wes talking about Container security
in containing the cloud thank you very
much guys alright now is when we need
the applause track all right thanks guys
for coming after lunch like I was saying
I'm not sure whether this was delivered
or not but I'll take it as a compliment
so container security and one of the
things that I want to put on here I've
delivered this talk a couple of times
but now I'm starting to move more
towards the engineering view of
containers a little bit of background
I'm a cloud engineer at CrowdStrike
basically a data janitor and kind of
obligated to say we're hiring so that's
who lets me come out to conferences like
this and talk to you fine people so if
you're interested if you want to do big
data in the security space as a vendor
let me know hit me up a little bit of
background to this talk earlier this
year CrowdStrike was deemed FedRAMP
ready and then even more recently we are
fully authorized to work in the federal
space and what that means for you not
just Tooting our own horn is that we
used a lot of docker ization and
containers to do that and that includes
a lot of auditing a lot of like really
like fine scrutiny of what's going on in
in a very low level and that's actually
the genesis for this talk because we
wanted to we wanted to know what would
it look like if our environment got
compromised and since we're a security
provider for federal customers they
really want to know that too so that
that's kind of what drove all this some
additional context is that we're using
kubernetes in Amazon's gov cloud region
for a security application for customers
and it's for a lot of security conscious
organizations so they want to know all
the way down to like what would an
attack profile look like all that now
the bearing that that has on most other
companies is that there's a lot of
there's polling that shows that the
primary reason that companies want to
move to containers but they're concerned
about what the security posture would
look like because containers kind of be
or kind of seem to be black boxes and
I'm coming at that can the question of
container security more from a systems
engineer perspective we do about a 200
billion events per day and that's like
16 terabytes and every six hours or
something like that an enormous amount
of data so that will come into play
later but performance and security
aren't both of those have to be
considered at the same time at a really
high volume so first I think it's
helpful to step back and ask what are
containers because not everybody has had
experience with containers how many of
you guys have worked with containers
this guy is how many of you are using
containers in production you are you
using an orchestration utility for
kubernetes okay a lot of different
orchestration flavors oh yeah yeah so
that's so right my so that reminds me of
my introduction to containers it was
working with a company where we had a
web app and I was on call and I got
tired of being paged because the app
would just fall over it was a Scala web
application and I really didn't care
what the exception was some engineer
wrote something that didn't deserialize
properly whatever didn't care wrapped it
in a container and deployed that just on
the host itself with a restart always
flag and that was the beginning of my
docker experience generally what happens
is so containers are kind of an
overloaded term here there's iOS Android
OS 10 Windows there's there's all kinds
of containers what I'm going to talk
about is containers as application
deployment
so the vhost
anybody ever seen this xkcd comic I
don't know that you can actually read it
there but their key point is most people
are introduced to containers from the
sense of I want to go play with this
application let me go look on docker hub
pull something down it's running real
fast and I could just work with it it's
almost like magic
now there's pros and cons to that the
pro is you can get working on it really
easy the con is could be anybody's code
it could be anything in there so
software development lifecycle the
simplest way to deploy an application is
just a binary just push that over so
Facebook had the famous like my two gig
binary that they pushed out that had
their entire app code I don't know if
it's still the same but generally you
want to rely on other pieces of software
other libraries and this is where it
starts getting hairy so then we need to
track down all of these deploy or all
these dependencies to make our
applications repeatable in each
environment and the problem is once I
start depending on other applications
then I'm not really sure what I have to
track their versions I have to trust
them to make sure that they're actually
using Cimber properly that they're
actually not overwriting versions with
newer versions or anything like that so
there's a peculiarities and they they're
calls for a really complex deployment
system so containerization from the
docker sense is I want to freeze-dry
everything and deploy it all together
all the dependencies system dependencies
everything so that I know exactly when I
go to deploy an image in integ and it
passes all my checks that exact same
code is going to be running in
production there's no there's no
weirdness that goes on with a library
getting swapped out or something like
that so some of our other deployment
options besides containers are virtual
machines and we could deploy a an
artifact like an entire machine as an
image and this is basically where the
cloud 1.0 took off right where we we
started baking everything into Ami's or
virtual machines
with VMware or something like that the
problem though is they're really heavy
and they're slow and their sub
containers or deployments of virtual
virtual machines in other words they
don't virtualize all the hardware it's
just from the kernel down so the
libraries in fact running a container is
just running a process with a few
caveats to it so one of the interesting
things here is that the attack surface
if you're deploying an application on
bare metal it's pretty much the most
secure because it's got its own
dedicated hardware everything VM
architecture is more secure than
container architecture you can kind of
see here why the there's no hypervisor
between the container and the host OS
this is one thing that's like really
needs to be brought out in understanding
containers you lose some security
because the hypervisor provides a lot of
security so here's another here's
another example there's been 12 VM
escapes up until 2017 when I pulled this
stuff and a lot of these are for really
silly things like floppy disk
controllers and and others like VGA
drivers things that you shouldn't have
installed in your VM anyway right by
comparison the attack surface for the
container is the kernel the kernel has a
lot more vulnerabilities to it like
almost 2000 vulnerabilities up to 2017
now that means we've got a lot wider of
an attack surface here so containers are
separated by C groups and namespaces
it's really just a convenience function
it's not for security containers kind of
have a connotation that they're going to
contain the application but they don't
unless it's some bsd jails which was a
similar concept and executed probably
with a lot more security in mind
containers on linux are really just i
want to treat this group of processes as
one unit so that i can track all of
their memory consumption CPU consumption
all of that in its own like virtual
namespace
and then I can apply things to it like
reen icing an entire group of processes
at a time rather than hunting down all
the dependencies so another issue with
containers is when you freeze dry your
entire application in all the libraries
you freeze dry all of the
vulnerabilities in those libraries as
well so if you're running a Python
application and it pulled in those
flasks
I think flask kind of vulnerability
recently then you have that
vulnerability and all every time you go
to deploy that app that that image it's
always going to have that vulnerability
baked in so you need to scan track and
scan both the base image as well as the
application libraries I would argue that
container security starts with creating
the container itself it starts so the
way that a container and I use container
and image interchangeably that's that's
my problem but technically you're
creating an image and the image that you
create is built up by layers
specifically there's a copy-on-write
system so every operation from your
docker file every operation is creating
a new layer and not entirely but it is
so your command when you're running
things when you're copying things into
your your image they're creating a bunch
of new layers and what docker will do is
at the end of the docker file it'll
squash those down if it can and here's
the layer of that image ideally as a
software engineer my application code
would just be an update to my
application would be one layer change so
what we can do is we can have a common
base layer that all of our applications
use and they have things like common
users common libraries common all that
other stuff and that'll be important
later as we get into how that fits into
the software development lifecycle so
security from the from base image and
docker allows multiples multistage build
so you can actually pull in lots of
different images and poopies parts of
pieces out of them but the very last
from is where your image is going
run so one thing we need to do is is
make sure that our from image is trusted
so there was a forget the company but
they did a analysis of all the all the
base images on docker hub and a lot of
them had a lot of images have
vulnerabilities but the trusted official
versions don't so there's been
continuous active scanning of the
official base images on docker hub and
then there's a lot of other places that
that do that so pay close attention to
who you're pulling the from image from
docker used to have this thing where
anybody could just push the binaries up
there and pull them down since then
they've gotten to where it has a star if
it's an automated build and you can go
inspect the docker file that it was
built from and and all this other stuff
best practices pull the the docker file
that the person provided builder to
build it yourself on premise that way
you know that there's nothing in there
another thing with docker containers
that the IDs for the containers used to
be used to be arbitrary now they're the
sha-256 of the contents of that image
very similar almost exactly similar to
get to the git hashes when you're making
new commits that means that you have
cryptographic certainty of what's in the
image given knowing the yeah if I I know
that if my hash matches over here then
the contents are going to be exactly
byte for byte the same over here one
thing to point out too is that in docker
containers everything that you write in
your docker file shows up in the history
of that container so one of the things
we did at CrowdStrike is we released our
the first machine learning antivirus to
virustotal
and this was one of our first docker
efforts and this was an interesting case
because we were going to take that image
and we were gonna give it to virustotal
and while we liked the guys at
virustotal we don't trust them like like
anybody shouldn't trust the other person
that you're handing stuff to so what we
would do is
we would take our image export it and
re-import it to get rid of all the
history all of the the get history even
with that one thing that we that we
really have to pay attention to is not
putting our secrets in our build scripts
because that output shows up in logs and
it also may in intentionally get
freeze-dried into the image this is
something that bit I think it was get or
get lab one of those companies recently
they they actually had their secrets
baked into the history of the images
that they were building so this this
stuff happens one thing that I like to
do is to use labels in the image and
then put like the get hash that it was
built from the user that did it like all
kinds of auditing information that I
just like to keep in there so that if
some of that something breaks then I can
look and see what that meta information
is and kind of be able to track it back
to something last thing is the Builder
pattern or multistage pattern there's a
temptation at least in the early days of
docker to take your image build whatever
you were going to build in that image
and then leave all of your build tools
in the image the idea here is if we use
different stages or different one image
to build our application another image
for the final release of it we don't we
make it a lot harder for attackers to
live off the land one of the one of the
core engineers at Red Hat has this great
talk that's basically containers don't
contain if there's nothing else that you
take from this understand that
containers aren't inherently secure so
route things like route in a container
doesn't map to route on the host but
it's still problematic they're still and
the problem there is file ownership the
UID in the container and the UID outside
the container don't match but it it's
gonna pick some arbitrary value so for
that file ownership between guest and
host is really terrible
so if you if you have to do it do it as
read-only I would say that you should
architect your applications to not use
it at all and also yeah a tight coupling
between host and the guest is a code
smell so try to make it to where your
application reaches out to some like s3
bucket or something like that for
configuration information so containers
do provide a minimal protection to the
host operating system they're not
architected to be secure but they do
drop some privileges which we'll get to
in a second so here's some quick wins
that we can get we could disable 32-bit
compatibility mode in the kernel and
that cuts our attack surface in half if
you go back and if we look at some of
the kernel vulnerabilities a lot of it
is because in 32 or a lot of the
vulnerabilities in the kernel are from
32-bit mode drivers or system calls that
are just neglected and a lot of the
exploits like the the very last session
in here one of the rhop exploits that I
found was 32-bit forcing it into 32-bit
mode because that's often neglected so
if we cut that if we turn that off in
the kernel then we cut our attack
surface in half and if we mark our
container as read-only then we make it a
lot harder for for any attacker to live
off the land not impossible but a lot
harder because then they can't like pop
a shell in the container and just start
downloading tools and using that so
another tactic that we use is recycle
containers often this makes it even
harder to live off the land because if
we're recycling containers we can also
recycle certificates that those
containers are using and we can make it
we make it a moving target at that point
it's all repeated the route think
also repeated some of the others oh the
last two points here I guess I needed to
make those a lot darker there's a
concept that's emerging in the container
world of applying micro-service
architecture to the application so
containers really fit well with a
segmented application that does lots of
different things like reading like you
break up a distributed application and
each little component is its own service
and they all work together the the
containerization or applying that to
container security is grouping those
functions not just by what they do but
by what access they need to do what
they're doing that makes sense so if an
application needs to read from and like
most of them need to read from a network
socket but like reading a file or
writing a file or doing like device
operations or something like that if we
can turn off the kernel capabilities on
this container over here then we can
like really shrink that application what
it needs its capabilities really far
down so we're applying capability based
security to the container or to the to
our application architecture what that
would look like is as you go to
architect your application not only are
you asking what what component needs to
be split out so that it can be scaled
independently but also what is that
component doing and one thing that you
can ask as an architect is how much how
many what's the diversity of the the
different system calls that this
application needs and can I cut that
down especially system calls that are
very risky like does it need lower-level
privileges to do like a ping or a
something else from the container can I
abstract that away can I do health
checks in a different container and so
that that container has its own set of
privileges you know can I cut out file
access altogether does my application
just not need to read files could I have
some other container that
in charge of reading files and it just
provides like a network connection to
another to a set of other containers so
that we don't have every container
reading off the disk stuff like that I
believe our eye view containers as a
unique opportunity so security is
usually bolted on after the fact or
traditionally it has been bolted on
after the fact for for applications but
as we get more and more into
containerization we can move security
into our software development lifecycle
was one of my favorite quotes it's on
the healthcare gov tech surge do y'all
remember healthcare.gov when it was
first launched remember what happened it
fell over so they went and they went or
they went and they asked several tech
Titans to weigh in on what they would do
and Bill Higgins has a great talk on
this his suggestion was to tell
President Obama that the team should
deploy to production every day and the
reason for that is that it smokes out a
lot of bad practices in your development
if your application is really cumbersome
and you have to do all these things
so at CrowdStrike when we went to go
wrap our cloud up and put it into
another place we learned a lot about
shortcuts that have been taken so we had
to go back and fix those those are just
good things to fix in general this is
part application security going back
making your application configurable
making sure that you don't assume things
about your environment writing your
application so that it reaches out and
asks the environment where it's at so a
great example recently is that we're we
were passing in like region information
for AWS now we just go and ask what
region this thing is in and then use
that instead of having it configurable
so there's a lot of great practices that
come from trying to shorten that
development or deployment cycle so I
would say continuous deployment that's
all
facilitating continuous security if the
way to move security forward is with the
DevOps tooling how many of you guys are
familiar with DevOps continuous
integration continuous deployment so one
of the one of the promises of
containerization is that we can wrap up
lots of different tools and put those in
different pieces of the pipeline and
I'll show you guys how to do that in a
second and all of these are their own
individual tools and if we can make our
deployment pipeline pluggable plug and
play then we can add security tooling as
we go along transparent to the developer
but also in a way that we can tell the
developer like how to do things in the
best possible way so that it's not like
after the fact where you're doing a pin
test or an audit and somebody comes
along and they're like you know the way
that you were writing your application
all along was really awful and then you
have to rip all these things out if it's
baked into the the deployment pipeline
you get immediate feedback of whether
you're doing good things or not for
example one thing that I've been really
excited about recently is using various
linting tools
so there's linting for docker docker
files themselves
there's also linting for the final
outcome of the image you can lint
through that and see what's going on in
the image like what your startup scripts
look like things like that the bash that
you would write in your docker file that
can be lint 'add everything can be lint
'add and one of my one of my friends
chris sanders has this great talk on
security and nudges as it's interesting
like psychology applied to security
practices in fact there's a book nudge
which is about setting defaults so as
security engineers or as security
professionals if we add good linting
tools to the development pipeline we can
help developers write more secure code
not by coming after the fact and being a
nuisance but helping out like we can
write our linting tools to say you
probably should go ahead and close
this file or write the closed handle
here you know as you're as you're
writing everything so what that looks
like is as codes checked in to get it
goes through the build pipeline and then
all of our linting and everything is
done there and then through deployment
that's not really useful slide so
automated security tooling in 2017 24
percent of images and public repository
had high vulnerabilities and yeah this
goes back to the freeze-drying
ok trusted registries docker has a
trusted registry google does to where
they continually scan images at check-in
time and they also scan it at rest
because an image that's in the registry
could develop a vulnerability or one of
the libraries is known to have a
vulnerability later so like I was saying
earlier your image has a hash all the
layers under it have their own hash and
so if you're continually scanning it or
scanning your images you can say this
layer has a vulnerable version of some
Python library and then you can go and
say every image that has that common
image in it is also vulnerable so I
encourage you to look at things like go
harbor I oh that's a registry system
that includes trusted registry it also
includes continuous scanning before you
promote the image to another registry
and then you can also blacklist images
pull those back out of the registry and
say this image can't be deployed because
it's no longer trusted because we know
that there's a vulnerable passionate so
all of this is before we ever run the
image this is just building the image
how we constructed how we think about it
how we pull out our kernel like syscalls
how we limit just the image that's
running to where it's just our code the
next thing that we can do is we can
protect our applications as they're
running so docker drops a number of
of permissions or capabilities by
default so and there's a great doc on
that but it drops like not file based
permissions but it drops a lot of like
other route and extended permissions so
there's two profiles that we can use app
armor or essay links and one of the
problems with this is that neither one
of them is blessed by the container
native compute foundation and also one
of them was recently public attacked
publicly attacked by the creator of
Linux himself or creator of Linux Linus
he went after the app armour guys
Google has G visor which if you remember
back to the slide on what the
applications depend on G visor basically
adds in an artificial hypervisor into
the container ecosystem I've heard rumor
that there's going to be other attempts
at a hypervisor shim that allows for you
to set policies at the hypervisor level
so givi until then G visors is an option
I think it's headed in the right
direction another thing that you can do
is trace your application and there are
tools to do this trace your application
as it's running to see what syscalls
it's actually using and then you can
create either an app R or s a Linux or
just drop capabilities that your app
doesn't need that makes it even harder
for someone to compromise your container
because even if they popped a shell in
the container which they shouldn't
because you're not baking in a shell in
your container in the first place but
even if they were to get something
running in your container they're not
able to do something outside of what
that container normally does such as
reading a network socket directly or
something like that so that kind of ties
into the drop dropping capabilities as
early as possible so one thing I
mentioned it before turning continuous
integration into continuous security so
the new hotness is to use docker to
build docker to build
her on kubernetes so docker on docker
using docker like this entire turtles
all the way down so the way that this
works is use a jenkins file how many of
you guys use jenkins anybody anybody use
bamboo how many of you are familiar with
jenkins
okay so jenkins just basically a tool
for running something like with multiple
steps like here's my recipe or whatever
so using a jenkins file what you're
doing is following the practice of
treating your configuration or your how
you build your application as another
layer of code and this is where a lot of
what you were mentioning earlier you've
got a lot of a diverse ecosystem of
containers it's probably because a lot
of companies start this way that that
you um you don't properly respect the
fact that you're creating code all the
configuration is code itself right and
so then there's there's there's usually
got to be this big push to say no let's
split this stuff out into its own
repository and treat it as code and one
of those things that needs to be treated
as code is the jenkins configuration
itself so but a big proponent now of of
moving things into jenkins files which
can be tracked as code rather than
clicking into the jenkins master and
writing culture steps there in the
script field the one thing we can do
with trigger with jenkins files is set
up a staged docker build each one of
these stages can invoke a docker image
as a build agent that means docker files
that means your build is now docker eyes
and can itself be swapped out once you
find vulnerable things or you want to
upgrade something this is where your
security tooling fits in security
tolling ends up being a stage so linting
ends up being a stage and you can have
as much linting as you want in there
well it's not exactly free but it's
mostly free and then as a security
engineer you can
come in and write your security pieces
either a pre linting or post linting
check and if it fails it fails the
entire build right and then you can also
write your tool to be really nice to
tell the to tell the developer why it
failed and that's what you should do is
a nice security person not just leaving
them hanging we've had great success
with us across the company so that
rather than telling every team know you
have to develop it our way go do it
however you want but it's going to go
through our checks and they're gonna be
mandatory checks and we'll provide you
with feedback and eventually we'll get
into this secure state it goes back into
so the whole thing about continuous
integration is as the as the plane is
flying we're swapping the engine out
right which is a scary prospect if you
haven't built for it going back to the
quote from healthcare.gov we're
continuously moving and hopefully
improving so automated security tooling
we covered all that earlier but I really
like that image basically x-ray into the
container mention that earlier to the
OCI spec doesn't include coding it does
include the file layout and the runtime
spec it doesn't specify a security model
so that app armor and SELinux profile
it's not included in the open container
initiative that's because they haven't
figured out which one they're gonna go
with or either I have a feeling it's not
going to be either and the reason for
that so the the the bodies or the
standardization bodies that you should
follow our content is a cloud native
compute foundation and then the open
container initiative open container
initiative will allows for either run
well run see I think is their official
running a container docker is the one
everybody knows because you start with
it something that you can get running on
your system really fast but the docker
found
nation is not something that a lot of
companies really like being tied to so
the OCI was put together and it has
docker as a member but it also has Red
Hat and core OS as members and Google
and and all these other places and
that's why I say there spec doesn't
specify a security model now that's
going to be changing really soon but
until then just keep in mind that
whichever one you choose it may or may
not be supported so what we've done
instead of doing a security model is
dropping capabilities and monitoring our
containers monitoring the event stream
out of our containers so I've mentioned
a container orchestration system one of
the things that that containers have
really done for us or that they've kind
of lend themselves to how many of you
have ever heard of Jevons paradox Jevons
paradox comes from the 18th 1800s and it
was a view of using coal so the the
paradox was the more coal that was
available the more people used it's kind
of similar to electricity today the more
there's available the more uses we find
for it same thing with containers the
easier it is to use containers the more
you container eyes everything so
orchestration systems are what grew up
around containers to move containers
around to start them up to figure out
scheduling so what you have now is the
concept of a meta operating system
across multiple computers the clear
winner of that right now is kubernetes
and we're not going to delve too much
into kubernetes because that's a whole
nother ball of wax might be a next talk
but the orchestration systems are very
opinionated and it's worth reading what
the opinions are of the people who've
put these systems together one of the
opinions is software-defined net
which are really interesting for example
Google treats their data centers as one
black box compute resource inside of
that data center ad hoc networks are
created using the container
orchestration systems to backup a little
bit more a container is not just a
process but it also has injected in it a
network driver and so it looks to the
developer as if you're getting an entire
VM all of your own and that's really
attractive for for software engineers
and because you're getting a network
driver injected that network driver
could be anything and so that's where
the software-defined networks have come
in so it allows us to create
software-defined data centers which are
kind of scary and also promising at the
same time because what this means is I
can shrink my application down to where
I have this group of containers that all
talk to each other but don't talk to any
other containers orchestration systems
default to just work so kubernetes does
not include any opinions on security out
of the box you have to add that yourself
and there's a lot of places where you
can going back to the nudg principle
they want it to just work so that people
will adopt it but we haven't we haven't
started nudging people to use more
secure practices another example of this
is running your own registry your own
docker registry doesn't include security
by default but there's a lot of options
there to allow like LDAP access and all
that and I neglected to mention earlier
that your registry system should be
separated allow developers to push to
their own repos to their own names but
don't allow them to push to the the
production repo gate that by Jenkins or
some other build server so one thing to
point out is that because orchestration
systems don't have security on by
default
it means that any node can talk to any
other node in the system by default and
that's something to really pay attention
to especially on on all the worker nodes
if you have a rogue container in there
and you haven't segmented access
deliberately segmented access then one
bad container could just spew or talk to
anything else one thing so I really want
to get this term out there as far as
container security bulk heading defense
and depth if we're gonna treat our
container systems with the same depth of
security then we need to think about how
we can assume that one of our containers
is compromised and then how do we keep
other containers from being also
compromised and that's part of the
kernel capabilities dropping that easy
or dropping that early and a lot of its
monitoring too so tagging is the way
forward rather than so in in times past
we had one computer one VM and we knew
what it did and we used it by name and
stuff like that going forward we're
gonna have containers and and how many
of you have heard the term pets versus
cattle when it comes to containers well
there's a third term which has come out
more recently which is insects
containers as insects doing one function
only one function and being ephemeral
and when you have that you can't really
you can't really log and monitor things
in the way that you used to do the best
way to do it and Google does this really
well is by tagging so this tag can talk
to this other tag but it can't talk to a
different tag it requires us to think of
components as discrete logical units and
it also allows us to think like in terms
of like really granular this thing can
talk this thing on this port but it
can't reach back out or something like
that yeah containers are designed to be
in motion so if you have a container
environment and you have a container
that's been up for like a hundred days
or something like that
that's bad you need to have something
that goes out there and harvest those
containers because a lot of things could
change we've run into this in our cloud
where environment variables change and
they haven't been reapplied to the new
containers because the new containers
haven't come up so that when somebody
does kick a container it gets a bad
value and it can't come all the way up
continuously refreshing catches that
early and real quick right before we end
this is another rabbit hole that we
could go down for a long time
EB pf' I would argue is the future of
not just so EBP F extended Berkley
packet filters you've used them if
you've used IP IP filter yeah
IP filter then you've used D BPF you you
don't know it but that's what's going on
behind the scenes so extended Berkeley
packet filters is an ad hoc measurement
and limited control in kernel space this
is basically byte code that gets loaded
into the kernel and the kernel executes
sit in kernel mode that then operates on
one stream of events either syscalls
or network the first target was network
so it's effectively dtrace for linux and
this has been slowly piecemealed out
into the linux kernel for the last year
so and the interesting thing is it
hasn't gotten as much notoriety as it
should this is useful so I'll skip to
the end there it's useful for evaluating
both performance and security and I
think this is really fascinating because
with containers performance and security
are wedded together down at the syscall
level down at the how you measure before
how you measure like what the containers
doing and how it's doing it that means
that you're if you're selling this up
the chain you can say paying attention
to our containers will make them both
faster and more secure like adding all
that stuff into the like taking care of
linting and all that because one of the
questions that you'll get asked is why
are we adding
so many layers of indirection have you
been asked that wreath not directly but
that is like one of the things that I
mean containers carry their own
complexity and it multiplies as you keep
on going so this is one of the promises
or one of the things that you can use to
to show how how the you get better
performance you get better security out
of it if you go down that path anyway so
summary securing the cloud comes to two
questions to ask ourselves what's
running in our containers or even what's
loaded in our containers what's
available and then how can we be sure
our containers are behaving normally and
that goes to the monitoring part so I I
glossed over a whole bunch of tools and
a whole bunch of utilities I highly
encourage you to take a look at the
awesome list that I put together I try
to keep this reasonably up-to-date
it contains references to tools like
Claire that are able to scan all the
linting tools that I was talking about
all of that gets put in here how to do a
pipeline build with Jenkins and use
docker containers as linters and all
these other things so with that there
any questions any comments
yeah so we use a lot of go and one of
our one of our systems that we use so we
use go metal enter and had oh lint had a
lint is what we use to it's the
dockerfile
and inline bash linting solution and
that's a stage and then another stage is
our go metal enter for our go code base
because we use a lot of go are you
talking about an example of the actual
Jenkins file
hmm
so yeah so for that we use see there was
the go harbour go harbour is what we use
to do analysis of the image itself and
what's in the image and then that also
scans it reefs cans it when it goes to
promote to another environment so
alright anybody else if not thank you
guys for coming and hope you have a good
rest of the day
[Applause]