well thanks everybody for coming I
really appreciate everybody for taking
the time actually
CJ security plus or an intro to cyber
security classic when the the local
colleges of the Greenville so and it's a
mandatory required class so students
have to come so I always appreciate it
when people choose to come to my
activities so I really appreciate it
via the time today if you have questions
or if you want to chat afterwards if you
want to get a hold of me feel free to
reach us for some of the work I do my
day job actually one of the information
security directors at floor and just
real quickly just kind of set the scene
so we're one of the larger engineering
and construction companies in the world
our fortune 152 right now we've been as
high as 110 since I've been there for
about seven years
my team's primarily responsible for
vulnerability management penetration
testing and also incident detection and
response so our very defensive and
offense which can be good and bad and
part of the conversation and industrial
controls as well so this is a power
plant it's actually the largest
gas-powered
power plant that we have in the Americas
right now that I was at a couple months
ago an industrial control but a lot of
this conversation is really going back
to the basics not only in vulnerability
management but how we build that and how
we actually see some vulnerabilities the
same whether it can be at floor so we
have about 80,000 IP addresses that are
live internally spread out around the
world so we have not as big a Sun but
bigger than most may have a pretty
fairly significant large testbed of
course to see a lot of different issues
across so lots of stories that we can
talk about as we go along I won't throw
a plug in for besides Greenville so will
be March 30th so we'd love to have you
guys in the Upstate if
to make it but anyways so we're going to
this presentation I initially started
writing I was actually sitting at Panera
with my girlfriend one day it's our work
date place right we're sitting at Panera
and I was actually trying to explain to
her the main focus of my job which is
finding vulnerabilities and working with
different people in IT to get them fixed
so we no longer have the issue where it
can be attacked or taken advantage of
and while we're sitting there having
this conversation one of the local
newscasters came in with a friend and
they sat down right next to us and he
started having this conversation with
her about with the friend he was waste
about Brown anybody know who brené Brown
is I hadn't until I heard was
eavesdropping on this conversation
because they were sitting right next to
us so she actually has one of the top
think it's still top 5 TED talks at all
times and she she's a psychologist and
she talks about these idea of being
vulnerable being vulnerable and you're
personalizing your relationships
you know I'm sitting there with my
girlfriend and try to explain to her I'm
like yes it's great for your
relationship and with your significant
other that's not what we're talking
about when it comes to my job right I'm
the type of person that I will go a
couple minutes out of my way to make
sure I don't have to turn left because
the chances of a car accident right
occurring are gonna be a lot more if I'm
just making right-hand turn so now I'm
also very practical I'd like to think or
utilitarian I would swear that you till
sex comes from the place but the idea is
so if it's just an extra minute or two
I'll go that direction if it's more than
that I'll just I'll take my chances with
the left-hand turn right I like the
thing I'm very practical and very
utilitarian and in the work that I do
and whether it's at floor which is my
full-time job or a couple of the other
side projects that I have as well and so
we start talking about the
vulnerabilities that we see a lot of
them and we'll talk a lot about will
touch on finding
patience in the environment it's not
necessarily a web application security
talk so then sometimes it scares people
away so don't worry but I do actually
like to go back to Panera cos AI do a
lot of work at a Panera just like I was
mentioning and back in April they
actually had a big considered a breach
right and that a researcher security
researcher was able to go to their
website and with a simple URL I dumped
out the entire database of all the users
including myself that had signed up for
the Panera users rewards program right
so they didn't have social security
numbers or credit card numbers except
for the last four digits email addresses
they could see the point balance of the
theory was Oh somebody could take all
those reward points I've earned and they
could steal them and get a free bagel
okay more power to you if you could pull
that off right I couldn't pay back to
this one also that got lost with Equifax
because a month later the Equifax breach
came out and so everybody heard about
Equifax I mean most businesses impact
all of us also had a personal level as
far as allowing all of our personal
information to be out there so Equifax
at the end of the day though was really
just somebody not patching the server
right then so there's a very easy attack
to pull off right it didn't take any
nuance or technical knowledge work I
definitely give the gentleman that was
doing the research for the Panera Bread
site he actually put some work in sound
like it was still very easy to find but
he went through it and actually found
where he could get to where he dumped
all that customer information on the
database right and he did the right
thing he tried to do responsible
disclosure the worst part about the
breach was the Panera IT folks that he
was trying to work with were working
we really will talk about there a few
more times as and as we go through but
as we start to shift and we've seen over
the last five or really even almost 10
years now and some of the environments
that we've been in is that we have a
growing number of devices that were
connecting to the network and whether we
talk about regular PCs and laptops and
servers or if we do get into talking
about IOT and so we have our thermostats
on on the network along with our HVAC
systems I have a friend that does a lot
of building automation systems so we
actually knocked over the building
automation system in our corporate
headquarters oops
accidentally with a basic neccessity
scan believe it or not and so all the
door controls shut so you could get out
of the facility
right for safety purposes right make
sense well thankfully they do feel open
so in the vent especially if you think
there's a fire
people are still able to exit the
building but nobody was able to get into
you know doors a basis our corporate
headquarters and floor is about a
thousand employees they make 700 of them
are executives so there were a few
people that weren't very happy that they
couldn't get into any doors
yeah especially if you're talking
wireless yeah and I've been doing a lot
more Wireless work these days so if you
ever sound like Ocean's eleven that was
that wasn't the movie - yes we don't get
too far into the back so everything
we're talking about in this presentation
has done over the water so and we've
seen some attackers we've we've
definitely experienced advanced
persistent threats we've had the
nation-states the Chinese the Russian
probably things that actually targets a
company in some way shape or form I'm
not but yeah it's a big part of this
presentation is is understanding that if
it has an IP address if it communicates
right if I can touch it right if it
sends especially a packet out to the
Internet right it is vulnerable period
the end and so we have to start looking
at where those vulnerabilities exist
well they're everywhere we still think
of and probably pointed out a little bit
more on this
this slide is with Pender's probably is
still today one of the most over look we
talked about I could be IOT I saw almost
thinking was industrial controls right
because industrial controls we talked
about you have a system that sits like
at a power plant right and it has an IP
address and an operating system and it's
supposed to right make physical changes
in the real world what a printer does
right it spins gears and it spits out
paper and and so when we start looking
at you know where are these issues
always I do a lot of detection in
response as well and of course that
stereotypical situation we've talked
about for 20 years now still exists if
you have the sock analyst sitting there
see sees a potential intrusion that's
alerted on and then they go back and
they realize oh that's just the printer
never mind
right and going ignore it and at the
same time more than likely an attacker
could sit there on that printer and have
full control over that device using it
to
the rest of the network yeah their
printer is just another computer right
it looks like it's an HP right it's a
Xerox maybe it's one of those tall
multi-function device right it's like
this all and at the end of the day it
runs Windows it runs Linux at you grunts
Linux how often are we getting those
patched how often are we getting well
and that's why you see a lot of
industrial controls also switching -
yeah exactly yeah when you think you I
can connect to that system I don't care
if it's a printer a server a workstation
a laptop a phone as long as I can get
access and run commands on it as an
attacker so one of the things I like to
talk about a lot and a lot of people
still haven't really got to the critical
security controls too much I'm gonna do
by show of hands are familiar with the
critical security controls usually
there's a few people in the room okay I
got one so the idea is critical security
controls act they just had a more recent
update in March I came out of a project
that the SANS Institute had originally
started and then they shifted over to
the center for Internet Security which
was a group that was
kind of formed by the NSA the FBI back
in the day when everybody had their
suggestions on how to secure systems and
they decided we need to put one group
together to manage all this and so the
SANS Institute handed over the critical
security controls and the idea is here's
20 areas in your information security
program that you need to focus on and
that if you apply these and then
depending on who you talk to it will
protect you against Bank 80% of the
cyber threats that are out there now the
idea being is that the nation-states are
the other 2% and there's nothing that
you're going to be able to do so when
you look at the critical security
controls though and you look at them
from top to bottom the nice thing is and
this is where I love using this when
working especially with different
executives or other folks MIT is that
it's a prioritized list so the idea is
we should start and have the most impact
by implementing the controls at the top
of the list versus the controls that are
at the very end so they're very first
and they really talk about the first two
items right really make up asset
management I don't know about you guys
but there aren't a lot of organizations
that do a really good job at asset
management right there's a few right but
so thankfully this year they bumped up
vulnerability management to continuously
assess the remediation up to three from
four and then we can look at the other
end of the extreme right where so number
20 you see penetration tests and red
teaming right so that's both my ends of
of my world response and management a
lot of the questions they usually come
as you put incident response event at
the very end it's extremely important it
is and they're not saying don't have an
incident response plan
don't be prepared to respond in the
event of
incidents right just the idea is do
everything else first because this is
supposed to happen after the fact right
after somebody gets onto the network
after something bad is occurring versus
right everything else that comes before
it is supposed to protect or prevent the
bad thing from occurring in the first
place make sense and so I always go by
the 80/20 rule I'm familiar with the
Pareto principle that idea is probably
more than likely 80% of our overall risk
comes from 20% of our vulnerabilities or
we can have maybe the 80 most 80 percent
impact on our cybersecurity maturity
level by implementing even just the
first 20 percent of those controls I
still argue that out of all of these
controls the most important is
vulnerability management because it
actually touches on all of these I'm
gonna go do a pen test I want to pull my
vulnerability scan data I know a lot of
pen testers say right that we don't do
vulnerability scans and it's not the end
of the world and we're gonna talk a lot
about that in the rest of the
conversation right we're not gonna lean
on and we're not going to just sole to
use vulnerability scan but it's still a
data set that we want to consult all
right so like for example you leave me
accidentally leaving your admin
yes hopefully not right so the idea is
these are all controls to protect the
environment when something that like
that happens right or what if what
happens when somebody clicks on that
link in an email or opens up an
attachment right because we know someone
is always going to click on a link or
they're always going to open up the
attachment right there's always going to
be an infection in the network there's
potentially always going to be an
attacker in the network at some point do
we have any pin testers so hopefully
this conversation will kind of set you
on that way so yeah so I spin again the
goal so depending on if you're on
offense or defense depends on the gutter
and the goal of that gasps yeah those
are the two worlds I live and and we
primarily still always focused on the
vulnerability management we didn't
really necessarily always have the
ability to add pen test we would go out
and we would engage outside parties to
do there's been an attrition test for us
but we didn't do the internal testing
until our internal audit team came to us
and asked us to help them with their
penetration test so it's like so I'm
responsible for finding the
vulnerabilities and fixing them and then
you want me to actually see if I can
break into the systems that I'm
protecting so either if I can't break
into the systems I'm a really bad
penetration tester or if I can't break
into the systems then I suck at my
normal job so I
right so like ice mentioning though the
idea is I still see as the main focus
for organizations to really focus on
vulnerability management right and that
we are continually scanning the
environment and that's an automated part
that's still in that way yes yeah
exactly and so and we'll talk a little
bit about some of the automated
vulnerability scanners that are out
there the big one is is still Nessus and
those people will use there's open baths
out there which is open source but then
we will the conversation does turn into
not just solely relying on those
automated scanners and building in these
pen test light activities right into
your program that you should be doing
this is true maybe not all of us we know
I don't know about myself some days so
yeah the idea was vulnerability
management though is and that's kind of
the whole title at the top right we want
to be able to find the issues before an
attacker dies or especially an auditor
because I always even will have some
examples of and and I do pen tests for
other clients as well and I hate write
whenever somebody comes in and says oh
wow we found this issue and we were able
to get domain admin credentials and you
know half hour or less right so it it
has taught me hopefully to be a lot
nicer and more empathetic when working
with other clients as well when we go in
to deliver those results but we do want
to be able to find those vulnerabilities
and remediate them as quickly as
possible the other thing I like and this
is kind of where I have like one one
foot on each side of the fence is that
from an intrusion detection and response
perspective if an attacker gets on the
network right by an employee clicking on
a link or opening up an attachment which
we know will happen right they're going
to then have to start looking for other
vulnerabilities and gaining access to
other systems and services so they're
looking for other vulnerabilities if
we're finding them before the attackers
that just means the attackers are going
to have to spend a lot more time on the
network trying to find ways to gain
access to their systems and resources
which gives our intrusion detection
teams a lot more time to be able to find
them right and then kick them off the
network find out how they got on the
network in the first place and hopefully
plug that hole like you mentioned though
most of our holes come from our users
right and it just goes back to that
entire cycle if someone's gonna click on
the link or open up an attachment so to
go back over the basic so when we talk
about vulnerability scanning in general
right there's the the four phases we'll
just go through these real quickly but
right we can use an automated tool to
scan across the entire environment
or we use five neces Pro boxes currently
to scan the entire network takes about
ten days because we are spread out
globally we do business in just about
every country on the planet except for
the big three like Iran North Korea we
actually just pulled out a Libya poly
six or seven years ago when the strife
really started we're gonna scan right
we're gonna take those results and I've
gone to clients before and say here
literally as a hundred gigabyte Excel
spreadsheet that'll take you an hour to
open up in Excel right of all your
vulnerabilities that you need to fix
what right so we do go ahead and we
prioritize those vulnerabilities right
on a scale of zero to ten or we say
right critical the worst being the worst
and maybe a low risk which we'll never
get to want to get those issues fixed
again before whether it's an attacker
well there's not a door some come
somebody coming in to do a pen test
who's actually able to find this right
the whole idea is raising the level of
cybersecurity across the organization
and will verify that the work was
actually done just because somebody
thinks they fix this doesn't necessarily
mean it's I've done it to say trust me
so what I like to do is actually like to
do vulnerability scans with out
credentials because that'll is what will
actually show you what a non credential
attacker will see at first and then go
back and do it with administrative
credentials so then you can see
additional information where the scanner
can do things like log in to a Linux or
Windows box and see you are there
missing patches right and then we could
see there's additional X points that are
available especially local privilege
escalation so we can do it with or
without credentials I like to do both
yeah it takes time but we get a lot of
really worthwhile information out of
doing both we on a prioritize game we'll
look at an example from dass's where it
goes from critical to low but the idea
is the critical are the worst of the
worst right this is where somebody with
no technical knowledge can exploit this
vulnerability with
the free tool that they downloaded from
the internet and they can have complete
control over the machine
I think Apache strut equifax my
grandmother can pull it out or I say my
grandson who's seven he could pull it
off well part of the joke right yeah if
my grandmother can do it yeah not being
that that's a V right that tells you
it's it's bad right so yeah we want to
get things fixed and this is really
where we're gonna take the rest of the
conversation is yeah we understand okay
there are the critical vulnerabilities
out there and those typically are
usually fairly easy to spot especially
by an automated scanner and we can get
those fixed the business these days
understands alright let's get those
holes plug and move on with our lives
but a lot of what we're going to talk
about is the low-hanging fruit that a
lot of people overlook and that you
aren't necessarily going to get a flag
but for something like an open share a
shared folder on a Windows system right
that could present risk in a Windows
environment or anonymous FTP that's kind
of OSC P rule number one all right to
see if I can log into an FTP server
anonymously an access dated that didn't
and then again we mentioned verification
and then we also want to and this is
very important from a vulnerability
management perspective we're always
monitoring for new vulnerabilities and
especially we've seen this shift over
the last couple of years I think for a
lot of folks in business because if you
don't well guess what your bosses or
your bosses bosses because now we get
those emails that says hey I was just
looking in Forbes right or our CEO was
just reading in Wall Street Journal's
about like not Pecha right which we'll
talk about at the end of last year and
they want to know are we protected
against this right not Pecha caused more
than three hundred million dollars to
merit write down the largest shipping
company in the world right and so our
our leader for our company wants to know
and we need to be able to go back and
say yeah we already knew about this
we're already monitoring we've already
skinned we know where our
vulnerabilities are and we know where
we're patched and we can tell you that
we're good right and that's usually what
executives want are we good or are we
not so when you start looking at and
this goes back to also a part of the the
presentation really is finding the
vulnerabilities well define the
vulnerabilities we have to take a step
back right we have to know where our
systems are and so then we look at those
from the outside perspective and then as
well as the inside perspective so we
talk about most organizations Mo's that
when I have systems that are connected
directly to the internet that's usually
a very small number right compared to
what I have in the rest of the
organization right for flora again we're
probably on the higher end of the scale
but we have about a hundred and fifty
internet-facing systems that are open
right and then we have 50,000 just
end-user workstations spread out around
the world big difference so usually when
we talk about internet facing we see a
much smaller number of networks smaller
number of computers and services right
and then usually everything can be
fairly well documented because you had
to go back and open up a firewall hole
to allow that connectivity but I will
also tell you we go to new organization
as a go to work with the client and we
always find something that's connected
to the Internet that the client didn't
know about right and so we want to know
about especially if it's vulnerable so
if it's supposed to be exposed to
Internet great but let's get it secured
if it's not supposed to be there in the
first place let's go ahead and talk
about from the internal perspective
that's where especially automated
vulnerability scans come into place
right because we have a much larger
number of networks a much larger number
of
host we see pretty much all of the
services all the applications that are
running on the systems it most
everything could potentially be
documented that goes back to critical
security controls one and two for asset
management all right which organization
has a list of all their systems and all
the software that's installed on those
systems so I'm get close and so what are
the attackers analogy is looking for I
said for me what I've always seen is
they're either focused on really the
easy attack right which takes advantages
of those critical vulnerabilities that
most vulnerability scanners
automatically look for so that's why if
we're looking at a tool like necess and
I see it critical yes I want to get that
fixed really quickly but again there's a
lot of these low-hanging fruit items
that a lot of people in their enterprise
vulnerability management programs are
not looking for in any way shape or form
this is what we're for the rest of the
conversation so I do talk about right
there are vulnerabilities scanners out
there like open vazh so when necess
right went closed source and so you
actually had to pay for messes that open
files was an open source version of that
you could use for free and you still can
it's not as fast and it has less than
half the plugins or the vulnerability
checks that neces does but it's free and
there's a lot of awesome resources that
built up around it so it truly awesome
right great work most organizations will
at least have an automated scanner
though that they're paying for like
neces professional which is about two
thousand dollars a year now I tell if in
anybody if your entire IT security
budget is only two thousand dollars go
by necess and run the scans it doesn't
do everything and I'm not saying it's a
silver bullet but for most organizations
it's a really great start right and
we'll see why that's not
but that here you can see not only do we
find vulnerabilities but we've gone
ahead and categorized them by a risk
right so we see those criticals patch
here first and that's 17 Oh 10 that's
the vulnerability that was leaked right
by shadow brokers that they borrowed
from the NSA and that was responsible
eventually for one a crying not text you
know and it's one of those wonderful
very very very easy to use
vulnerabilities because it works almost
every single time so we see there's high
those are still pretty bad and we want
to get to those we just want to do them
after the criticals and then most
organizations the mediums and lows the
informational you'll never ever get to
because you're still spending time on
the criticals bless you and the highs
that's just the sad truth I did doctor
some of the slides so this is actually a
combination of your Windows and UNIX
rumor I was gonna fix it then I just
kind of left it alone if you don't
typically see X server running on
Windows boxes but I knew the low and
used to make it pick up I think I've got
all the IP addresses and MAC addresses a
filter out of all the slides which would
be good thing so when you start talking
about looking for other things on the
network outside of the servers and the
workstations right our laptops other
types of services that fall outside of
our normal baseline ideally we try to
have zero default SNMP community strains
on the network period the end when we
see one pop up we know to investigate
and look something is here not only did
they use default community string which
from a security perspective is normally
not the end of the world though I have
used them to take over a network
infrastructure before which was fine not
only SNMP default commute strings but
they're running Talent and so we could
device you can actually see it's running
in setup mode right so nobody even
touched it so it's essentially default
potentials right or default factory says
it just turned out to be one of the
humidity and temperature centers and one
of them so at the end of the day this
was fairly limited right and at the same
time we've seen issues you love the
story about the thermostat at the casino
in Vegas right the thieves I've used to
funnel data and money out the door
potentially right there's still an issue
right one of the other things in this we
start looking at is you have to remember
web applications are everywhere just
about every IOT device and just about
every industrial control system that
you'll see has a web interface that's
all I always preach now if you're not
learning web app security now start even
I'm definitely behind the curve on that
but the idea is just about everything
these days comes with a web application
front-end so we can start looking for
web apps across the environment and when
something new pops up like this this is
somebody in one of the Asia offices that
went and bought one of these little
wireless access points so you can
actually buy them here for 20 bucks off
at Amazon
all right and they wire it to the
physical floor network and then they
actually had 12 different people
accessing it wirelessly of course the
kicker is they didn't change the default
administrator name or credentials
so we could log in we could see the name
of all the devices that were connected
we could see their MAC addresses and
then oh well we just kicked them all off
change the password shut the device down
that that will do gate it right like you
can see if somebody starts screaming to
figure out you know whose it actually
was they actually did have somebody
complain and they got a corporate
security policy violation for it these
devices are out there though right this
was another interesting case I thought
because it was where we're skinny
found a web application on a workstation
so usually we start thinking shadow IT
right somebody's doing something that
they shouldn't but yeah I've been shadow
IT before I understand people are just
trying to do their job so it's like hey
let's work with you to make sure this is
done securely in this case we found this
web application if you hit the web
server that was running on their
workstation it actually redirected you
out to the internet your browser out to
this Chinese search engine and so what
happened was their workstation actually
became infected with a browser hijack
tool and not only would it take their
browser to this page but it actually ran
a web server on the workstation so if
anybody hit the web service it would
take them to thought that was
interesting right they got a corporate
security policy violation - they were
they were doing maybe some not
necessarily business yes yes exactly and
so we started looking at talking about
finding you know our presences out on
the Internet
how many of you are familiar with
Showdown okay so usually there's a
discrepancy a lot of folks know about
about census and in in show Dan and
since this and show Dan talk but the
idea is like if I want to do a pen test
or if I work for let's say Panera and I
want to find where my presence out on
the Internet is I can go to census type
in Panera and like show down both of
those services scan the entire internet
right the index the information that
they find now they're not scanning all
65,535 TCP ports but they're scanning a
couple dozen and they'll get most of the
web server so if you have a web page out
there that mentions Panera right or if
you have a digital certificate that
mentions Panera you can actually pull
those up through census showed in does
it as well but I think if you're just do
pure name searches census will actually
have a lot more usable results versus
showdown which is more hey give us an IP
address or a network range and we'll
tell you what's on it so usually I'll
start with census to find the networks
and the IP addresses and then switch the
showed an to do so but really the rest
of the presentation I know we're kind of
winding down but this is an example of
where I actually was trying to
demonstrate to a client the dangers of
WordPress and if your WordPress sites
are updated and secure bad people can do
bad things with them
and it's very easy so in this case this
is just an example I found off of the
Internet but I found this site your
living body through Google which has
where they have the WordPress like API
right exposed unit where somebody can go
and upload content to the site does that
sound like a good thing to allow just to
be wide open to the Internet no right no
this is osep trick number two so one of
the tools out there and then this kind
of build on anybody heard of Spyder foot
I got the graphical interface that
follows recon ng so recon ng which was
written by tempt Holmes is supposed to
automate the open source intelligence
gathering process for you for a lot of
people though it's difficult to use
because it follows the Metasploit
interface is Vic man mind driven so it's
not easy or accessible to everyone
spider foot is right so you have a web
interface you literally can go in and
say Panera comm right it's actually
Panera Bread comm which I found out
through my useless spider foot right but
put in Panera Bread comm right and let
it go off to the races
well what he started to find out was
when I was looking at these different
WordPress sites so somebody was going
ahead and hacking all these WordPress
sites
some of them are actually on the same
hosting provider some of them were
scattered across other servers all
around the world and they would hack the
site so that way if a visitor went to
the page they would get redirected to
the site called best meds dot biz which
is probably what you can imagine right
is is for online buying pills so we did
some additional research so I can go
yeah I can use google dorks or
specialized Google searches exploit
database the offensive security guys
doing awesome job hosting the Google
hacking database to give you some ideas
and you don't even have to go to this
extent but right we can use Google
search searches to find all of these
pages on the Internet and so we started
to look at all the connections and then
we see the Stanley Spencer gallery it's
like it's an art museum essentially and
buying Xanax online from Canada probably
not their actual business model right
and so when you start looking at yeah
here's best men's biz and if you go to
some of those picture one of them I
think was the soos group and I sent him
an email and say let them know hey
you've been hacked by the way and the
idea is if you went to the page their
high-end realtor's for you know
Manhattan and then like Central Park
apartment and and then also like
high-end real estate out in LA right and
that if you go to part of their page you
can oh here's where you get redirected
to not part of their business model as
well I would I would imagine I did find
it funny so then of course oh here's the
little chat right that pops out so I
went back the next day and I thought
maybe it would be a good idea to
actually talk to them and see so in this
case I actually went back I thought it
was being super smart and setting
turning on my private VPN so that way oh
I saw the servers hosted in Germany so I
said I'll make it look like I'm coming
to Germany so actually it's hard to read
but they actually say oh they tell you
like right away oh hey not to waste your
time we don't ship to Germany
looks like oh well okay
obviously you're already looking at all
of my information that you can pull
these from my public IP address and I'm
coming from thought that was interesting
yeah okay well well thanks for letting
me know
so go back a couple hours ago made it
look like I was coming from New York
right and then have the same
conversation and there's other
conversation it doesn't take long to
realize it's just somebody might be a
woman might be a man they could be in a
call center in Bangalore they could be
in a call center in Denver Colorado
you never know right and the ideas
they're just another person sitting
there doing a job all right because you
probably don't have a clue right when I
say oh yeah our site was hacked and that
helped redirect me to your web site but
technically build by pills I wasn't
going there right and have them sent to
you here in the United States without
going to a doctor even though I think in
this case EF diazepam and Valium you
have to have a prescription for and then
they even ask you to rate their service
afterwards so gave them at some time so
again there's low-hanging fruit out
there though and just to mention a
couple to wrap up right looking for
things like open shares when your
systems get infected ransomware crypto
mining infections right that want to
spread one of the ways they'll spread is
by open shared folders on the network
when attackers gain access they're going
to start scanning for open shared
folders on the network you need to be
scanning for them and I do have a lot of
slides and that's partly not to throw
everything in the kitchen saying it's
just so you'll have the references for
later on right so you can see nASA says
hey you have a instance of Windows
shares could be good could be bad they
could be all restricted well if we start
looking well mostly has a scanner to
look for open chairs and in this case
we've found some default chairs as well
as a chair for accounting HR and sales
one of those is wide open to the entire
war
and hard to tell from there right so I
loved esses and all the necessary
engine scripts we have right this one a
little rough that doesn't give us a lot
of information the one tool believe it
or not we use the most I'm looking for
open church because it's so easy and has
this wonderful graphical interface is
perfect my network scanner or network
scanner by soft perfect how about that
so the idea is I can run a scan on the
system write all the information
redacted of course but you can see on
this 10.10 10.10 I have an accounting
folder that's open to the world
anybody can open that folder as long as
they're connected to the network they
don't even have to have a user account
that's a red exclamation point
there's a lock on the sales folder says
I'm not getting into it and then there's
HR folder open that means it's read
access only so depending on what
information is there right the attacker
can take that and use it to do other
things on the network right which goes
to the next one for a non MSF TP all
right in this case
Nessus doesn't even say hey it's
anonymous X it just says you have an FTP
server running so then you can go back
and I can run a scan for anonymous FTP
servers so can i log into the ftp server
with a username of anonymous and a
password of any email address I choose
all right Joe odd Joe calm and there's a
Nessa there's an nmap script to do that
as well and then and the story is we
actually got a client where we had gone
in right found anonymous FTP server
login the one their web developers had
stored their project file there and even
one of those project files they had a
text file with the default credentials
for their web service and then that web
service had local administrative access
to a system so even though Nessa Stein
I'm a today at owner ability scanner
doesn't find an issue it doesn't mean
that there's not
issue their language is really the
Poynting definitely do the automated
vulnerability scans but also you want to
be taking the time to even build in
those penetration light techniques to be
able to look for those things that the
scanners just aren't going to find
automatically one of the tools and I
don't put in here but it's built into
Kali
it's called sparta which will actually
automate a lot of those I guess low-end
if we call them that pin test techniques
for you and so if it finds a webserver
it'll take a screenshot for you so you
don't even have to open it up in a
browser if it finds an FTP service it'll
try to log in and nonnamous daily I'll
let you know if it finds a sequel server
service running and it'll try to log in
with default or maybe some easy to guess
credentials so check out sparta but and
there's a lot of other slides
like I said I put a lot in there but it
really brings us to kind of the in just
a couple quick reminders again there's
just some recommendations remember from
my perspective is owner Bill
vulnerability management still has to be
a key aspect of anybody's security
programs right it needs to be it touches
on all those different areas right that
we saw laid out with the critical
security controls all right work with
the folks in IT the system owners to fix
those issues based on priority right you
don't want to give anybody a hundred
gigabyte Excel spreadsheets right change
those risks that make sense to you right
just because NASA said oh this is a
medium risk vulnerability that might be
high or critical to you depending on
your organization maybe you're in
finance and that could be a compliance
finding we started to look at build open
source intelligence into your
vulnerability management practices put
your domain name into spider fuzz
fighter foots free it's very easy to
download and run and see what the
results come back right see if you have
any you know hacked WordPress sites on
organization's servers right okay don't
rely on just the scanners go build in
those pen tests like that at a bare
minimum and then always be looking for
those will have applications because
they're out there
IOT industrial controls servers
workstations shadow IT right they're out
there just waiting to be found
so find them and take a look at it and
make sure that they're supposed to be
there and if they are supposed to be
there
secure them if they're not supposed to
be there get them off from there so
thank you everybody again I really
appreciate you guys taking the time and
hopefully some of you might make it up
to Greenville it's about three hours
from Charleston we have a great show I
think lined up Doug Burch is Doug Burks
from security onions doing our keynote a
lot of local guys like Tim towns got
Chris Sanders coming up from Gainesville
a lot of we have a lot of great local
talent gonna be at the Clinton
automotive research facility which is a
really exciting place so we're expecting
about 225 to 250 this year for a second
year really awesome exciting show and
the clemson automotive research campus
is very very techy and very cool so and
feel free to reach out in time if you
want to shatter catch up so thanks again
I really do shame