so I'm doing a talk on CTF R if you guys
don't know what that is it's a abusing
certificate transparency locks I heard
about this in another talk and but I
took it a little bit further so
basically you put a like what I would if
you want to do this manually you can say
you could find there's usually api's out
there that I'll show you a bunch of
stuff and you Paul if you look at
subdomains there right and then you
could say copy and paste one of these
things then get an IP address out of it
and then put it through a showdown query
and you know type in you know and
actually find certain you know
vulnerability sometimes or nothing well
yeah but what I did I actually made a
script that does all this so let's say
we want to do
check that out
so I run the script so basically it's
pulling it all subdomains from the API
and then it's resolving each sub domain
to an IP address and then it's putting
it through a show to end query right and
the shooting query will actually list
all the vulnerabilities and stuff like
that open ports and every sort of sort
of boasts and stuff that you want to
look at right so oops check this out
listen CD bees puts the right up there
and then I could stew I haven't made a
parser for this yet but I will put a L
make one eventually and then sometimes
they don't actually lead to exploit dB
so that'll be my next step in this thing
and then you know then have it actually
linked to medicine like through the
Metasploit API and have code ready I
guess for your engagements so it is
passive reconnaissance yep but you guys
want to try it out I mean I could
actually just type in any domain yeah so
here I'm swearing it again I'll delete
everything in here real quick
that's open summer oh that's right oops
you guys have your own personal demands
you wanna put in here yeah
what's the website MUSC health holy Sh
but it actually creates as it goes you
know so ok no no see bees there I mean
okay be you'll still give you all the
other information you would want so yeah
I'm not touching the Nanyan touching
their website essentially so yeah but it
won't touch it
let's see let's see how much we got here
I got to make something that Flags it
saying Oh CBE listed here and then yeah
yeah yeah good imagine do this by an
well yeah I showed this off to a friend
he's like yeah put my stuff in there but
might put my blog on there and it just
like just had a huge list of ships TVs
every was like I was like whoa dude well
yeah you could I showed her this I
showed this off to some pen testers and
I think I rotated and we just played
with this all day
say what yeah yeah I do this whole in
Python so like yeah I just use Adam
because of the colors like don't make
fun of me please
yeah so I just do yeah I just so what I
do is I I just do a get request on to
that API to grab all the dns name the
DNS names right and then I just parse
all that out put that into a big list
and then I just loop through it and then
resolve each to sub domain to an IP
address and then and then I just you
know put put that all into the each IP
address into the showdown query and then
profit right yeah I haven't put it up on
get up there's if you google CTF are
github you can actually get the the
original one but I just added to it but
I could put my stuff on get up in a
little bit I literally was writing it
sitting next to you so are we doing the
FBI thing yeah well yeah this this will
go on forever sometimes and you'll be
surprised at what you can find the other
thing I do with it I used Google Dorking
techniques with it so you can pull those
subdomains with it so you can say
subdomains site github right and then
you could find people's code that ties
to it and sometimes it's like if it says
Devon it is it's really
something you want to look at because
sometimes it has credentials so really
really cool Osen scripted Osen
essentially so but yeah I've been doing
this for like I'm actually pretty new to
cybersecurity I just my friend told me
about something and I was like oh this
is kind of cool so I've been I guess
doing cybersecurity professionally since
April so but I'm not super expert in
Python so if you look at my code you
know don't make fun of me you know yeah
yeah yeah yeah yeah okay I saw this
picture is like he's like I'm so gonna
you know I'm so I'm such a good
programmer and you see a book next to
him in its Python like is actually
really easy
oh yeah you get so actually this might
be kind of cool yet yeah whenever I see
Devin it it's just like it could be
something you know so so what I would do
I have another so I have another script
that I kind of used with it and see if
it'll actually work so I'll do my other
one real quick to show you the Google
Dorking part it has to be a really good
company to do it to search with because
like if you do like something with so
few subdomains right get to have a huge
list of subdomains because I mean
sometimes get Google won't find it but
the more soapy wins you get the more
information you get to the Google
Dorking method so I yeah it's it's just
a really really I think it's a really
good strategy
but yeah you want to try another one out
clear I'll just clear it out if you want
to tell you another website do one more
which one gap yeah okay okay hold on one
sec wait delete what I got in there real
quick so we won't have to like filter it
out why is this not working
okay cool
oh it's the end of the CCF or thing
alright yeah give me a give me a domain
let's get I'm gonna do one more
you want a retailer Capcom I'm afraid
what's gonna show up honestly
oh Jesus no gifts okay yeah dip tickets
then okay cool let's see what's popping
up over here
yeah I need a I need a flag to just like
to tell me when there's a CVE oh yeah
it's just gonna populate through all
these things but you guys I missed it
I made a parser to for Oh sent a put up
on github um you guys play with it at
home so well yeah
yeah it's gonna keep going
well yeah my next my next step is gonna
be putting it like automating it through
Metasploit and then I mean I'm not gonna
execute it because that would be kind of
illegal unless I had permission of
course so but definitely just just to
line me up right so I take its courses
here yeah but to finish it up horsey so
basically I take a list of subdomains
form from a CTF our query basically and
resolve those IPs and then then loop
through them into a showdown API and
then that list that lists like all the
ports and stuff and and in CBE's is what
I'm looking for because there's another
API that shows that shows the actual
actual vulnerability so if I do this one
because I know this one has one real
quick let me just delete everything real
quick oh actually nevermind start that
over
almost done of course
all right here we go
awkward silence right I think it's this
one here we go sweet so it's actually
looping the see bees listed and showed
an to to parse them out so ya know it's
it's it's based on the IP yeah so they
can lead you to the next steps thank you
guys I'll put the I put the thing on
github just catch me off line