yep indicators of compromise maybe
compromising your Android analysis Who
am I I work for the National
white-collar crime Center and I'm from
the lovely say to West Virginia my
professional job right now is hacking
into analyzing breaking analyzing some
more all the fund mobile devices and
those things those things that are the
buzzword that I'm going to refute to say
so surprising surprised I'm from
Charleston West Virginia so we're not
hooked online and I says hey I want to
go and talk at Charleston 'besides it's
a little bit farther away than just
going around town there's about eight
and a half hours wrong Charleston it's a
great trust mr. Austin is so much more
pretty alright so what this talk is
going to be in my tenure I've had I've
had a lot of interesting cases and I've
worn a lot of different hats I've been
part of a prosecution team and I've put
people in prison for the analysis of
what's in their mobile device whether
it's contraband on the device we're
using his intelligence I've assisted
state local and federal agencies and
their intelligence gathering efforts on
mobile devices and I've even done civil
litigation within now and my job there's
a lot more research and a lot more of
that subject matter expert consulting
and with that one of the big things that
I see is it is a full ecosystem on a
mobile phone much like with the computer
and if you do any type of incident
response or forensics work one of the
big things that we're always doing is
taking steps to validate our evidence
taking steps to verify our evidence and
it's not just the safe evidence handling
procedures or you know if I'm going to
do I are yeah we're gonna stomp on that
box a little bit in the IR process but
we're going to be taking the steps and
getting the information we need to
provide authenticity to our artifacts so
one of the big things that we don't see
with mobile devices and that's why I
want to share this with y'all is when we
look at a mobile device and the
commercial solutions out there when it
comes to acquisition and analysis or
even the bespoke solutions or the custom
scripted solutions there's a lot to be
desired you know if we have a Windows
box throw the dart at the board and
you're gonna find a more than capable
product some are better than others
um you know jump out in looking for a
professional consulting team again some
are better than others but the
availability the transparency and the
knowledge is way out there but with
mobile it's an emerging landscape and it
gives a lot of different vectors in is
if I am a computer user and I'm not
elected to turn on Skype and I am just
utilizing my Windows walks to grab a
email to do other corporate functions my
attack surface is relatively small I'm
most likely going to be on that network
there's part of my business if I get to
work from home take it to a coffee
coffee shop there's risks there but with
mobile it's a completely different Radio
one of the big things when it comes to
verifying that evidence if we find
something is a mobile device is one of
those things where I can put photographs
on your device you know in my tenure as
a law enforcement officer I've had tons
and tons of people tell me that the
thousands of evil images on their
computers just got there and doing
computer forensics we know that that's
not the case with a mobile device the
lines are getting more blurred just by
knowing your number I'm able to send you
a thousand images and yes you could
block me but I'm gonna get a different
number and you're probably not gonna
change yours so I'm gonna still continue
to do that not only can I send those
images I can essentially engineer you
and it's in a more digestible way folks
are getting better and better when
they're in that corporate environment
and we know it's work mail and we're
having our work email give us a banner
that says do not click on links this is
an external email it shows up flag
there's a lot of rules going into place
but you're getting your text messages
just free in the tiny graph that you
can't see as part of there is a trending
graph of the development of new malware
samples for the Android platform so
that's not just the total samples about
that's the total samples the average
being brought so for 2017 4.4 million
and for 2018 2.7 million those yep
arbitrary numbers that I'm saying in a
talk but it's a huge attack surface tons
of new samples in the trend did go down
but it is still much higher than it's
been in the big thing is yes there are
constant attacks and one of the reasons
that Android becomes such a huge target
is it's got a 3/4 market share globally
more users use Android that's in more
devices
it's the kernel is open it's the Android
Open Source Project is much more
inspectable and while that lends itself
to increasing its security because we
have vendors that are responsible for
pushing out our patches and our update
cycles we start to get behind the ball
so much on iOS we make that trade of
telemetry versus security from a
security standpoint in an our standpoint
there's very limited telemetry in iOS
it's hard to inspect things it's hard to
acquire the data and then analyze it
because Android we can but we're also
behind that ball in a different security
model and it's not just like when you
talked earlier about potential key
loggers or potential spyware there is
actual in the wild observe samples that
we're pulling off of Android devices
that are capable of reading your text
messages capable of reading your
thoughts capable of fabricating entries
into your text messages performing
malicious redirects on your web browsers
harvesting your location data harvesting
audio files and there are even a few
unique samples that go to that ability
of remote interaction it's where they're
actually able to in real time grab data
and act things take pictures so that
brings us to what can we actually do to
start combating it so one of the big
things that any type of Incident
Response case is gonna be indicators of
compromise so if there's some type of
security incident or potential security
incident that has alerted us to
something and when you're trying to do
our root cause analysis or dig in so we
can one contain it and then work to
eradicate and remediate I always see
you're great because they're going to be
signatures they're gonna be hash values
of files executables payloads so there's
gonna be unique signatures that we can
look for locations of certain artifacts
certain iOS these are written that hey
if this path is created that's a
potential indicator
compromise there's no benign windows
processes where there's no legitimate
third-party applications that are
creating these pathways with these
naming conventions we see a lot of non
and or-else logic which is is it named
this and not this and it also contains
this file path different characteristics
and just anomalous characteristics of it
so it's a huge io C's allow us to
inspect a device a lot of different ways
but there's a problem whenever it comes
to getting to do that so if I am an
Android user or an enterprise that has
androids as part of my work product
Google and the Android Open Source
Project gives us a couple things get
Play protect we can use different
enterprise mobility management for
mobile device management solutions we're
able to go in and make sure people have
passcodes on we can go in and limit the
wi-fi's that they can grab but a lot of
other types of security we're leaving up
to that device to handle we can go and
deploy a Windows computer and just leave
it up to the native Windows applications
for security there's always going to be
an enhancement or generally there's
gonna be an enhancement but we do that
with mobile and we end up seeing
quite a few failures the Play protect
store is riddled with errors there is
long been the statement hey as long as I
download this application from the
Google Play Store that I'm good any
given day when we go and we do a scrape
it's a quarter million to 300,000
samples that are active in the Google
u.s. Play Store now this has been
trending down but it's still pretty big
if you're an Android user what's one of
the big reasons that people always say
we use Android we want more customized
we want to be able to customize it more
we want to be able to change our
operating system we want to be able to
watch movies before they're released and
we're doing that in a cost of our
security in our privacy any time we go
outside of the Google Play Store we're
to going to an even bigger risk risk and
in modern versions of Android built on
the NSA kernel you know it's a very
hardened operating system there is a lot
of constraints that are going in
Communications inter-process
communication is being handled through
various API to keep it secure but
there's still vulnerabilities so one of
the big things that we see happen is I'm
an enterprise I have mobile devices we
use enterprise mobility management which
doesn't do much in terms of security
it's our common security but then things
happen where I'm a device owner or I'm
an investigator I work for a consulting
firm we've got a mobile device Incident
Response do you work for an organization
and somebody is subject of an internal
investigation one of the first things
Ren do is go and seize or attempt to
seize either the corporate asset mobile
device we're gonna see if we can seek
legal process and get there personally
own mobile device criminal cases civil
litigation tons of things are involving
mobile devices so where's the big
problem with it all right first off
Security's compromised Incident Response
if we're gonna make the statement and
we're trying to scope out an incident
for containment in remediation we've got
to be sure of what we're doing it's one
thing to think of it narrow scope with I
have one mobile phone and I have one
computer but when we think of today's
organizations we're talking millions of
endpoints even we're trying to correlate
how this attack or how this data has
been lost and we've got to look at that
full scope we can't just say yeah it
looks like it came from this mobile
device we have to be able to say that
with certainty route calls analysis one
of the big things that we see a push for
in today's media and in today's
government operation is that attribution
characteristic you're gonna say hey
there was this that occurred and we want
to say that this certain group did it
we're in my case I've acquired data and
I've analyzed it and I may be attempting
to take some of these freedom away for
the rest of their life based on what I
found on their device and that's
something that I don't take very lightly
he could be somebody could end up losing
their job because of it if it's an
internal investigation so the big thing
comes if we are looking at that mobile
device and we're saying okay I'm gonna
pull these texts mess
is off there I'm gonna pull these call
logs off there but with just that little
note that millions of active actively
developed Android malware samples the
attack surface is huge it's phone calls
to make a call you and say to go to this
website email emails being pushed to our
phone users are more apt to click things
on their phone because we trust
everything on our phone we get SMS
messages we have facebook on there we
have other social media platforms there
are all avenues for social engineering
or phishing campaigns clickbait being
sent somewhere you don't want to go so
that's where we get the wolf in sheep's
clothing so when it comes to true
evidence integrity are you sure that you
can attest to how these things done on
that device just by acquiring data and
looking at it really sure there's money
on the line there's jobs on the line and
in a lot of cases I've work there's
people's freedom on the line so when we
look at those common acquisition methods
we have things like adb talkin android
Narus code we've got some commercial
tools up their oxygen forensics and
cellebrite magnet forensics and these
are just different companies that make a
product to speed up and enhance the
analysis and acquisition of these mobile
devices a lot of mobile device
management and EMM solutions also will
allow some data acquisition or some
remote cloud pull or some remote backup
tools with ADB and ADB is the Android
debugging bridge it's a Native Client
that's part of the Android operating
system that allows some low-level
communication it's really cool and then
of course some of my favorite types of
acquisitions are when I get a rip phones
apart and remove the chip chip off
acquisitions in systems programming
acquisitions different ways to get the
data so we get the data what do we do
with it 99% of the examiner's that I get
a teach and help and work with they grab
the data and they pop it in a tool they
hit the magic find evidence button and
we move on to the next thing
it is I'm telling you Mobile forensics
has changed so much in the last few
years but it's become the Nintendo
forensics world there are there is a
tool that literally has a find evidence
button and you hit it in the blue wheels
start turning and you just sit back and
wait and
presentation of your evidence is
categorized by what they want to tell
you it is and one of the things that we
don't see in the one of these being the
most popular and robust mobile forensics
tool in the world when you hit that Go
button it's not assessing anything about
that device of security it's not taking
any steps like it's doing to parse many
arbitrary applications and present you
with data there's nothing going on to
say yeah this is given the context of a
human using this there's nothing going
on one of those tools you're able to
click on a malware scanning button and
it's one of the few tools that lets you
do it and it does a signature based
search with BitDefender so pretty robust
hashed set sometimes there's gonna be
some static names depending on where the
database is but I've seen hits before
with getting some static names but what
do we know about malware when we see it
is it always gonna be the same name is
it going to be downloaded as one thing
is it gonna stay that one of my favorite
examples an oldie but goodie is Zeus
what happens when you run Zeus it
disappears the process is given some
arbitrary character value so if we're
using that methodology and looking at
the device statically we're not gonna
find any indicator for compromise even
though it could be riddled with it
riddled with evidence with it in that in
that compromise could affect the
integrity of what we're doing nothing's
going on so I wanted to find something
because one of the big components of my
current job is to actually guaranteed to
stay local and tribal law enforcement
and I wanted to be able to give the
folks who are working these cases
something that isn't barbarically
difficult because whenever I think of it
I get excited I'm like we're gonna get
his fan line and you use clamavi we're
gonna use low key and we're gonna do it
like this and we're gonna be great
people just typing on that blue and
black screen that's not the way the
world operates so we've got to add a
little bit integration there so Brian
carriers tool autopsy an autopsy 4.9 has
a really great open-source module that
lets you grab an API key from virustotal
so community API key from virustotal is
free autopsy is free so we
of them both in they can handle EXT for
EXT acts in the fat32 file systems all
the file systems we're going to find on
android and it does a lot of analysis on
there so one of the things virustotal
will do is it will go through and it's
gonna look and say hey this is gnome to
me this is not known to me but again
it's only looking based on what that
module is telling it to submit there's
gonna be some limitations on that public
api but of course it's nothing it's not
the fuel the full yara rule it's not a
full contextual analysis of the evidence
it's gonna be based also on that hash
it's gonna be based on name it's gonna
be based on depending on the way you
have the ingest module configured are we
gonna do any searching for urls are we
in try and put urls up to virustotal to
be searched but it's a good it's a good
time so when i got there i realize is
ice making this when i when i make these
powerpoints i try to roll through an
investigative process and i kind of
skipped a couple things which is why
just signatures wouldn't be that great
very high level and if we look at
something just based on signature base
static that's where we would have a hash
we're taking a half of the entire
executable in this case an APK for the
android device a subcomponent of that
APK because apks are archives it can be
an archive and you can see their core
files is it the way that something
creates a signature whether it be a
process ID the process name dynamically
is it a combination there uh and that's
where we see that these current methods
is discussed in the previous slide we're
not able to look at that because the
data set is static so we've got to
really work that limited data set that
we have so the biggest thing was I knew
I couldn't read when reinvent the wheel
on it
so the best thing to do was to find a
method to intelligently search for
indicators compromised on that evidence
set with its unique characteristics so I
knew that Yara yet another ridiculous
acronym which is the Swiss what do they
call it the pattern matching Swiss Army
knife from malware euro rules are really
cool it's a very plain easy to follow
descriptive like text language that will
just give conditions to an artifact or
to an object's where I can say does it
contain a certain ASCII string at this
offset does it contain this hash at this
location there's a huge culmination of
different things that yarra can do
honestly you can do pretty much anything
you want so when we're looking at the
mobile ecosystem and we know that okay
we're gonna have apks our apps there's
apps are gonna have databases containing
data we know that we can download it
from the Google Play Store but what
happens every few weeks when we've
downloaded an app what comes through
update are those updates managed
directly through the Google Play Store
those arbitrary many are arbitrary so
what we have is yes the initial
application passed the Google Play Store
a week goes by we update it we now have
malware one of the biggest ones that we
saw was Pokemon go Pokemon go was was
one of the huge things that we saw that
people were figuring out and saying hey
people are downloading this is there a
way that we can take over some of this
control when we do the update there's
there a way that we can push people out
of the application store into a Trojan
horse that they download freely off the
internet so that's where yar came in
because we're able to get down a much
more granular level determine different
things we wanted to classify with it and
even use it to look for no blacklisted
phone numbers so who here if you use an
Android of you something like true
caller so true caller is an app that
will come through and it'll say hey this
is a potential spam call I use it and
it's pretty successful true caller is
pretty cool you can get an API key from
them they've got a full software
development kit and I'm currently
working on a project to where that's
gonna be incorporated so whenever we
analyze these Android devices we're not
only doing yarra for known malware we're
known indicators are compromised we're
also looking for do we have Texas text
messages and phone calls from
blacklisted numbers because that's the
full context of the threat environment
for Android so the big ones that I came
up with working the best was first was
clam antivirus part of get to it from
Talos the talus research groups website
cross-platform very extensible malware
scanning engine it can do amazing stuff
with email gateways but it does really
good at pointing it at the acquisition
set of data from Android and letting it
roll I'm a very robust signature set you
can write your own clam rolls if you
want to extend its capability for known
samples fast free we love it the other
one was using Loki Loki is a very
Spartan iOS II scanner that
extraordinarily flexible in it will take
in hashes that will take in rulesets and
it will take ignarro rules and you can
point it in anything you want so in my
case of an Android backup whether it's
an arbitrarily mounted volume on a Linux
system or whether it's a bundle of files
on a Windows system I can point loci at
it and have amazing results so
everything's working great so my
framework that I would do I our cases
mobile forensics cases I'm gonna grab
the data in whatever manner I want to
most often ADB and over a variety of the
different ADB implementations Android we
can do what's called a custom recovery
where we would do it boot it to an
alternate operating system or install a
completely different operating system is
the device something that we can route
and we can get a root shell on and we
can use DD and pull data back out
listening on that cat or does it require
some physical intervention like JTAG
joint test action groups soldering on to
those PCB pins in systems programming
where we're actually gonna sidestep in
on the actual demand of memory package
or chip off everybody's favorite be
physically sever the chip from the
mobile phone and we pop it in a reader
or pop it in an adapter and we do our
analysis that way we can either mail
notice if we do chip off or a lot of
these we're gonna have the X the entire
physical extent of that memory on the
device and you see some really crazy
stuff you see most Android devices are
twenty and thirty partitions the
Motorola HTC mm1 9 was like 99
partitions from the factory so you find
a lot of different unique new unique
environments that Android is operating
in so we grab the data we pull it down
tonight so we don't we fire it up with
Loki and Loki in that it's a very small
screen shot but from the factory they're
already helping you out with false
positive hashes file name locations file
names that are suspicious hashes some
yarra rules for hack tools web shells
just general yarra rules so there are
tons of things that from the factory
it's ready to look at you can go and
simply Google search I need your rules
for the specific thing on github and
help pull it down so Loki performed
valiantly playing a V worked flawlessly
I did not I was missing the mark and one
of the big things was I've got a brand
new in this case I was using beta
version of Android Pi I never stopped to
actually look at the rule sets that is
being shipped in these tools I said to
stop and I had to look it turns out
Android 9 real sets whether it being a
commercial antivirus product it's for
Windows or Mac OS or in the case the
rule set for some of these for Loki
isn't really cognizant of these Android
malware sets so yes they're performing
their job and we're not gonna find
anything because we're looking for
Windows executables or Windows iOS C's
on Android we're not gonna get anything
now there are some and trust me I
googled it a lot because I really didn't
want to have to do what I was decided to
do next so I googled a lot and I
compiled a lot of stuff way too much
stuff on
question yes even in the regards to file
system do you every different yes to
almost build specific almost yes and one
of the big things that select with
Android so we'll have Android seven so
then I might have a Samsung Galaxy s7
I'll say Android 7.0 point one security
update part 32 what version of Android
seven point nine point one is an API 22
API 23 hey be out 24 so then there's a
whole other set of conditions that
Google has in and you're exactly right
so if I write a yarra rule and it wants
to look for a WiMAX partition that's one
vendor that has that partition so
exactly right - if it's Kinnaman I can
either spin my wheels doing that or have
I not written that real set in that
specific and it's huge and one of the
crazy things that I was that I found was
of all the github repos I was searching
through to find people that have already
written some euro rules concerning it
the average time was three years old and
we know that the landscape of anything
malicious that's we still have to do the
due diligence and make sure that the old
stuffs not there because how often do we
see that folks are popular old
vulnerabilities or an antiquated set of
I an antiquated iOS II scheme would
actually be able to find something if
free but in the newest one I found was
nine months old yes
yeah and I did notice that it's kind of
like whenever we see the kids like when
rig was really popular yeah you're gonna
see the the clustering where we see the
clustering techniques and that's one of
the cool things about Yara's where it
can be so extensible is where we can
open source or yarrow rules and people
can come in and say hey can I ride in
that line I have an htc can I ride in
language into your open your group so
that's what I decided to do I'm very
fortunate that where I work and the
manner in which I get to work is I
curtain you have probably 400 Android
test devices a variety of operating
systems builds my my office looks
ridiculous at any given moment I mean
it's it's a sight to behold none of them
are really great no some of them are
decent fun but I've decided to go on a
hunt so luckily fireEye makes a lot of
tools so that folks who aren't that
great at it like me can have a chance
with IOC rider an IRC editor and I've
literally went out and have pulled every
Android malware sample that I can find
off github every Android malware sample
I can find on fire a share virus Bay
hybrid analysis all the ones who let me
download it and that brings me some of
the project that I'm working on with it
so I work follow a choir hito his clan
Navy hit it with Loki look for the
indicators to compromise but know that
we have to embolden that so surprisingly
this really short domain was still open
like I can't believe I let that with
that Android piracy org it'll return
nothing or that spams like we're trying
to sell it to you right justly bought
for $12 left running project of Android
malware samples mission campaigns claim
rules Garba rules in the spirit of happy
in the spirit of Billy Madison
O'Doyle rules so that's where I'm
standing with the IOC's because you will
find them Android is riddled one of the
things I did notice was using one of the
commercial tools that had integrated
with BitDefender if you get a device
with some road miles on it like a year
on it that's got true use it's gonna
flag signatures and every time that I
did that I'm like if it's flagging
signatures I can't only imagine what
else I'm gonna find when I dig down and
actually do
more in-depth analysis so I've talked
about finding the malware but one of the
big things that's what we missing in a
lot of mobile forensics training I think
only one really big national provider
the certain Institute really hammers it
in with their mobile forensics training
is what do we do what how if I'm going
to be presenting a statement or summary
of these artifacts and they need to hold
weight whether it be in court
arbitration executive committee or just
as part of an investigation
what about done and a lot of times when
we find this I know I've consulted with
a lot of examiner's in whenever I
encourage them to go and look for it
Chris I found that what do we do this is
where we start we've got to figure out
what it is capable of so we need to
analyze it find out what his permissions
are find out what that actual core
executable is can we do a sandbox
detonation that's usually where we go so
for the crash course part of this we've
defined our security we're going
scanning if you go hunting you're gonna
find a prey eventually so if we don't
hunting for malware we're gonna find it
or if we go hunting for other indicators
of compromised you do it enough you are
going to find it now what do you do of
course the winnow ones isolation
cautious precaution this is not your
phrasing machines should be on the wide
web for most traditional forensics
especially mobile but we have to have an
appropriate analysis platform so for
doing this project pretty much I did
everything with Microsoft Windows and
I'll let the fire off layer team do a
lot of the heavy lifting for me with
their virtual machine build a flare
virtual machine and then there's a
really great open source project called
Android tamer the next distribution
that's already set up with all of the
the hundreds of packages that really
allow you to dive deep into an Android
file system because the Android files
the Android executable in the Android
file system is a little more than just
that apk that apk is it sits on your
device or what you download from the
Google Play Store is actually a little
more it's gonna be an archive so if you
are on a Knicks base machine or Mac
you're gonna be able to onion archive it
and go jumping in - usually I give folks
two sets of device when I've gotten that
data of course I'm gonna make a static
copy that we keep for purposes of
archival we're gonna have two or three
copies of it that we've made for our
analysis depending on the environment in
the case we can use tools like
virustotal hybrid analysis Anubis a Joe
sandbox the list goes on of online sand
boxes that will do automated automatic
detonation and work on generating that
automated report but much as I was able
to go to hybrid analysis and download
samples so can you so if you're doing
anything that may have pH I personally
personally identifiable health
information or PII personally
identifiable information or something
that is you just don't want the world to
know if you also have like a virus total
account virus total intelligence account
I can have I can define certain things
that I will be alerted to so there is
course always that thought that somebody
malicious will be watching to see when
their maliciousness is alerted to it's
always take that into consideration
before we file everything up so once we
open the that's really great handwritten
a puts in your android apk your Android
manifest assets libraries classes so
that's gonna be your Java bytecode
that's actually gonna run that sucker so
what would the big things that I look
for immediately so in static analysis
I'm a big fan of dumping that over with
strings or again using fire I makes a
great tool called floss that looks for
strings with different parameters and
through some obfuscation I'm gonna look
for the basic things because I still
find the basic things from malware in
the wild I can I routinely still grab
Android malware from the wild and I find
hard-coded URLs from the strings
function you feel amazing when you do
that like this so easy you find very
verbose lis declared permissions right
in it in the manifest that says hey I
want to have the permission to read SMS
I want to have the permission receipt
Ms Reid the usual dictionary read
contacts acid accessible location and so
on now if you are an Android user what
do we know happened a couple versions
ago when I'd download an application
I am warned immediately this application
wants to read my SMS this application
wants to do all this people agree to it
that's that's still the crazy thing
folks agree hand over fist the desire
and that drive for that to just they
want that map and they want it to work
now you'll agree to anything but that's
always great whenever I can find ok I've
read these permissions but then I've
observed its analysis in a sandbox and
it's requesting elevated permissions or
its request or its received permissions
greater so that's where we know there
may be something around so again we can
jump in there with tools like Jade you
know Java detox from a code Mac OS and
Windows JD GUI Dexter jar there's a lot
of different things that we can do to
help break it down to get that readable
JavaScript has it been off you skated
there's tons of ways we can be obfuscate
it one of my favorite of cyber chef can
run pretty much any function you want
over something so that way I'm able to
look at the functions I can look at the
code signatures I can look at the
declared permissions and see what I've
got going on knowing that I'm gonna be
able to probably pivot into something
like a sandbox report this is a
screenshot from a Jose Jose Pro Android
sandbox and they hit it on the mark they
start out with huge graphics just come
in and say hey this malware is doing all
of these things it has things in place
for spam it has things in place to
affect the networking and when you go
and you drill down because this is the
high level what to do when I find it
you're gonna be able to from a high
level say this malware was potentially
based on this analysis in what we have
was not capable of affecting this
article of evidence that is pinned to
mount to our investigation or conversely
because of things like in the criminal
system
Brady we've got to be able to say
incriminating criminais ting evidence
and exculpatory evidence
due diligence have we actually looked
for all the articles of evidence and if
we given an explanation to them so
that's one of the big things that we run
into with that night and this talk went
way too quick and when I flew through it
with with E for folks in here all right
so he's in but yes hit me all right so
the way that chain of custody so I'll
walk through a sample one and this one
has actually went to court been
adjudicated so we arrived on scene of me
executing a search warrant I take the
evidence into my possession at that
point I make notes of the state it's in
you know is it on is it off if it's on
I'm gonna take steps to isolate it from
Radio connectivity so pop the SIM card
airplane mode put it in a Faraday bag
I'm gonna control the state well so
that's where we that's where we keep
falling through so the big thing that
I've learned is transparency with it so
when I show up on scene and I'm gonna
snag that phone there's gonna be a
picture of it before I've touched it in
my notes are gonna be verbose and I
always would I call them big pads a
little like shirt shirt pocket size
notebooks they would have my verbose
notes those go ahead and get copied over
and sent with the discovery one of the
big things I found is there's a lot of
folks that tried it with hold things or
they want to make people work for it I
was just an open book it's like here's
everything you want so yes I would state
in my in my executive summary I touched
the device I've used an Android device
for nine years I put it in airplane mode
if you want to know what airplane mode
is we can go and look at the open-source
developers guide or we can go and look
at Jonathan Levin's Android
confectioner's cookbook and be able to
definitively say what went on there so
then it keeps going because you said the
physically manipulation oh yeah this is
where it gets dicey
there's that's gonna say been proven
through like statutes or policy or case
law to be ineffective arguments but that
gives you some leeway of in regards to
like certain things that the state of
what that action does yeah and so
essentially like it's about defending
evidence at that point like there's a
lot of case law I know that like
essentially like a prosecutor removing
the bullets yes yes yes right and when
the big thing is a search warrant is
meant to be a static artifact of time if
I wanted to get something real and
ongoing that's gonna be a title three
you know pin trace it that's an
intercept like if I wanted to listen to
a live phone call that is a whole other
ballgame
then simply going before a you know
judicial officer in my state with an app
sworn affidavit requesting on these
merits permission to take something in
upon the time that I take it it can't
change its if it changes I'm responsible
for it and I have to explain why so
where that gets tough is a lot of these
devices we get are locked a lot of these
devices they will not give us the
passcode and there's still a lot of
debate on whether people can be
compelled in the United States to give a
passcode so we are left with breaking it
and this is one of those keywords it
depends you know some devices for a long
run of Android devices USB OTG I've got
a USB rubber ducky that I had tons of
ducky scripts I'd pop it in brute force
it unlock device other ones you know now
there's a really big exploit set called
emergency download mode where we're
causing a short in a Qualcomm processor
it exposes it in different ways is a is
a different process to windows box
different versions of the team win
recovery project different versions of
the
Odin project yeah you are substantially
changing it so the way that I've always
accomplished this especially if it's
gonna be evidence that is going to be
going to potentially a criminal trial
yeah yeah so for a criminal trial say if
I have a device for one if I'm reading
it I know I have access to it so the
reason I would route is to enhance the
level of access so a lot of Android
devices like you've got an s7 if you
take that s7 and you fire up an ADB
shell you're not gonna be able to go in
if that level of permission most often
and get your text messages
the EMM SMS MMS database it's too high
of a permission for a DB we can route it
and we can give it we can route it and
we can use DD and get the full extent of
that Android file system get the full
extent of the databases the actual
applications installed all of these
great paths and we can see not only the
pass but the way their context relates
with other paths so we can really verify
that evidence so yeah we're cute I mean
we're we're hacking the device I mean
we're grabbing root shell on it before
that is done we've acquired data and
tested methods to the highest extent we
can so you're never gonna jump in and
say I'm gonna root before I've even seen
what I can get and you're documenting
along the way and then for me I'm not
gonna do it
if I've never done it before so I can
tell you that the employers that I've
done this for and the agencies that I've
done it for have all been really good we
usually drum up a test device to say
okay well you're gonna be our platform
is a Samsung Galaxy s7 930 V from
Verizon this is what we want to do we're
gonna take that seat it with known data
perform the action and then go after and
look for the modifications so that way
we can go and say you know we did it as
controlled as we could utilizing these
methods a lot of times these exploit
methods are open-source so we're able to
say these this is the actual methodology
behind it you know where it gets goofy
is in iOS right now there are some
things that are not to be talked about
capable of doing some things and the
same goes with Android you know that
physical exploitation is
is a huge thing and there are certain
commercial tools that are very robust
support the pass code of thousands of
devices and you're not really told how
it's doing it and I've been in the
position where I'm taking that to court
and your narrative is I had this device
these are the steps I've taken here's my
initial evidence I've been performing
this action here's the evidence
what if it's locked we never had
evidence that's a good question because
yeah
how would you feel cuz you do you've
done offensive work before in the or do
offensive work how would that go if I
said okay the only way I was able to get
this data off these ten computers was
offensively jumping in grabbing a shell
and pulling it out yeah yeah yeah
no missing persons right protective yes
you go throughout this whole sake it's
cool it who said that you care
yeah it's something you don't know how
these friends of tools doing this what's
going on with the stingrays right right
where if you use the the cell site
interceptor you use the stately nervous
hey you can't talk about it
judges are swirling that out yep you
know so these companies are making a
product yes so I guess through like in
many cases by disclosing that for
purposes of meeting or trying to satisfy
some requirement they essentially become
you're able to directly circumvent at
that point or like essentially caused
the company to be unable to
be financially viable they create their
own self sign interceptors and it's even
easier with software because when we
think you know hardware there's gonna
have to we've got to engineer something
but these software exploits and we look
at things like zero diem where we can
say okay I want remote code execution is
gonna say I'm gonna cut you this huge
check what would stop somebody if these
companies would have to disclose that
from saying through the concepts of
rhodium pay me my Bitcoin and it's I
mean think of it because you're probably
more in it than I am to know that that
markets use the exploit market the
volume discovery and exploit development
markets huge and one of the big things
that cuz I spent a couple weeks you're
going around on teaching mobile
forensics and that's always one of the
things that I have to hit and I hit hard
like this isn't the way that we see it
through the marketing material is not
what it is you know by the time we see
it
it's just bypass this this is supported
but in reality this is a highly
competitive market that is you know
specifically offensive security and it's
completely glossed over as being a
couple clicks of a button and then we
have these things that are pivotal
pieces of evidence like you said when
we've got you're innocent until proven
guilty in this country and we've got to
protect everybody's rights period in the
way to that should be taken in the state
of West Virginia where I'm from you know
one of the things on the prosecution is
we must know every facet of evidence so
good bad ugly and different and that is
a very high standard when you get 20
terabytes in a case and you're expected
to know what is incriminating one sec
sculptor Tory what's the validity of it
and you have to go through and explain
it in until you it's changed my thoughts
and opinions and a lot of the actions of
myself and the folks that I get a
counsel with on the way that we handle
the offensive nature of passcode bypass
or privilege escalation and mobile
devices because I'm tell you if you go
to any
agency and say didn't you guys hack
mobile phones no okay how many pass
codes you might pass this year okay 300
all right yeah other folks might
disagree with what you do but I mean it
is what it is so yeah definitely looking
forward to furthering the conversation
on how we how it moves from that hmm I
think that's all I got for this thank
you