so hey everyone so we're going to go
into our final keynote of the day there
is a funny story here we thought we were
gonna be clever and do like a surprise
keynote and then I check on Twitter and
then it's like the not so surprise
keynote so I don't know if we were just
not bad security conference like we're
not good at security or you guys are too
good I'm gonna try to go for the ladder
so that we can save ourselves a little
bit but as you guys already know yeah
I'm gonna present Wolfgang Gorelick and
he'll be talking about following the
rules everyone should do that thanks so
much
alright guys I'll hear me okay I love
the Michael of the podium but I paced so
I might go off I apologize I'll speak
nice lob yeah this talk is is following
the rules right that's where we're all
hackers right we like to foul rules be
told what to do no not at all not at all
my name's wolf and a little bit about me
I love b-sides I was involved with
b-sides Detroit up until this year is
one of the organizers huge fans of the
b-sides movement so really excited to be
out here in Charleston I also do an
apprenticeship program I'm responsible
for an apprenticeship program in CBI
which is my employer we put around 60 70
people through it now it's a two-year
program where people come in and you
train and get mentored get coached and
at point in time where I was like we
can't find people we got an average 55
people for every one person we let in
that program so it's a real cool group
of folks that get into that and then my
day job is I'm on the defense so I've
got a peer who's in the pen test so
we're going to a meeting and people are
like he's a red teamer he's the Yoda of
information security he once broke into
the Pentagon ladies and gentlemen there
was a king and then I come in next night
okay and there's wolf and he has
spreadsheets
he tries to stop there yeah so a lot of
this is from the defensive perspective
today that I'm going to be covering but
race stems back from this fact that an
information security we're moving
towards professionalizing what we do
right it's become a profession a lot of
us gray beards like myself we started
when it was a hobby I remember getting
on BBS's going I want to get in what do
I do and they're like you need to get
sis admin and roots and I'm like yes
what is that and they're like I don't
know but you need to get it I will get
this this admin what do you do you're
one much too trash okay I don't want to
do that but you know ya got in in the
ground floor and none of us knew what
we're doing in there were no rules and
today a lot of folks are coming out of
the university and going into my
apprenticeship program a lot of folks
are coming out of the school system and
they're coming in to the the very
organizations consulting with them
advising with and we've sort of like
cemented this this layer of rules that
people are supposed to follow and that's
what I want to poke some fun at today
because I think that's really dangerous
because you better believe that the bad
guys don't follow the rules right so the
way this talk is up is like this I'm
gonna say here's a rule they tell us
when you talk about technology not risk
and then I'm gonna talk a little bit
about how are we doing this here's where
constrains us here's where causes of
problems here's the issues
alright cool from the defensive side red
teamers can mock me all they want
because we all know red teamers well and
they'll flip over the table and oh god
damn you red teamers I'll lock the table
down next time so let's start with that
start with this constant that we're
supposed to talk risk this is like
embedded in so many different university
programs today it's like Cecil one on
one don't talk about the technology talk
about risk and I do love risk I love the
game they're here here be monsters we
will protect the eastern seaboard but
part of the concept of risk management
always comes back to this idea of risk
appetite have you guys heard this we got
it we got it
no one organizations risk appetite so we
can define their security and I love
that question because you go and you ask
like the CEO hey what's what's your risk
captain like hi we're in business to
take risk oh my god okay that's not
really helpful but alright you ask the
CFO and it's always like to the penny
nine million eight hundred seventy five
thousand sixty-seven cents to the last
quarter
that's our risk appetite that kind of
tells me how much I should spend on my
security budget I guess the CIO is I
keep the lights on no rest don't do
anything scary keep the lights on please
don't pen test my mainframe or touch any
of my systems and by the way who are you
again and should you even be in here
right sale yes bourbon are a CIC so
right yes cuz see so what the risk
appetite is it's my risk appetite and
that's the one problem that starts with
this whole issue is that we we have this
idea we need to talk risk but no one
really has a clue what risk means and if
you're a young person you like that's a
risk because you can run responder in
the dark you shouldn't talk technology
that's a risk because you can give
passwords well we don't really care cuz
everything's no professor and you
creates this weird cycle where we
actually don't solve any issues moreover
there's there's a bigger problem when
you start figuring out what the real
risks are for example rhinos seems like
a weird Segway but they're with me in in
in France a couple years ago maybe you
guys heard the story in France a couple
years ago there's this beautiful rhino
and they got the Rhino and they had him
over here in a cage fence about this
tall and people said over here well no
that's effective
that's a beautiful Rhino and that was a
day in a pair of sue that was the case
for about a month about a month the zoo
had this Rhino after a month the Rhino
got killed sadly by poachers but when I
saw this I bother my mind I got
something that's supposed to happen like
a third-world country you were in Paris
man get some wine and some good food why
are you messing around with a rhino and
I saw it digging into this and trying to
figure out what
going on because you know they had a
most that offense should be fine why are
you when you actually did the math on
this Rhino it was a little bit over a
million dollars that horn million
dollars now if you think about a zoo and
you say I'm gonna give you a million
dollars of gold coin right here no no
they're absolutely not because they're
gonna treat that as a completely
different risk number two problem with
risks is we think about it as the nice
animal that we're all here to see not
what's enough for the criminals right
and what's in it for the criminals is
oftentimes abstracted from what the
business is seeing which is why this
he's so says bourbon and the CIO says
you know they'll keep the lights on the
CEO everyone's got their own perspective
it's oftentimes not oh I've got a
million dollars rhino horn right there
it's not the way we think so back to the
game of Risk this has some really strong
implications we set up all our pieces to
protect Europe right I'm gonna save that
rhino horn haha and we've got all our
pieces around everything's good and see
our bra parameters and we see our
perimeters and we see our borders we're
like yes this is fantastic and this is
the defense of you however the attackers
see a completely different game same
pieces but completely different
parameters completely different edges if
you guys sat in the red team talks today
you heard that here's how we see the
network here's how we see Active
Directory here's how we see bloodhound
to map it through bloodhound is not what
our Active Directory admins are seeing
right they're like oh I'm damn it and we
put everything to me that because that
works
no no it's two completely different
games and that is the next problem we
are fundamentally at any given point in
time putting the same pieces on two
different boards because one of them is
the way the business works the other one
is the way the criminals work and the
difference between whether or not we
protect that rhino horn is whether or
not we have the piece the right place
the right time and hopefully we do until
they change the board problem number two
no one knows the real likelihood or
probability of an event when we talk
about risk management we all get excited
about it very difficult to do
I do a ton of risk management or risk
assessments to my organization we just
in like 50 a year and before then I was
a CSO of financial services firm so
company's gonna do risk assessments on
me and we'd always come up with these
great reports and I'd be like your risk
is somewhere between high and whining
I'm like okay good and down here's blank
stare which is my favorite category of
risk but you get these weird charts
you're like what the hell does it even
mean and yet we're supposed to act on
that and build security around it risk
management sounds really exciting and
really fun until you actually to go
ahead and do it that's a problem another
thing we're taught from a very young age
101 class what are the criminals want
intellectual property they're out here
to steer our data right this is what
they want and yet oftentimes I'll go in
organizations I'll have a very similar
conversation I'm like hey what's what's
your intellectual property I was working
with a cabinetry company cabinetry
company that built cabinets I'm like
what intellectual property you have and
they're like where can the company what
do you mean if people want to stare
camera so go to the places you buy the
cabinets and they'll like measure them
and there goes our intellectual property
we have no intellectual property so
oftentimes I'm like what's your sense of
data we need to protect look we don't
have any yes I see something like yeah
this is why we drink
it's stuck in this trap right but we
know there is rhino horns out there we
know that cybercrime is a thing cyber
crime is reported to be three trillion
dollars annually three trillion dollars
every single year made by criminals
defrauding us doing terrible things with
our data and and so if you start piecing
that out that gives us some better
visibility into how high we need
offenses to be and how why we need the
months to be intellectual property first
number one half trillion dollars every
single year stone blueprints stone
plants you name it right stone Pat's
next one of course as you might imagine
is credit cards intellect or in your
health information 160 billion this is
actually dropped and this is one of the
things that's kind of interesting about
cybercrime this used to be like the
number one way right I would steal
someone's credit cards and then I would
make all the money do you guys know what
killed that why dropped no before then
dare to head it right target happened
home see people happen how many times
have your credit cards been stolen I
mean big credit card value would from
like you could be $300 I'm a stolen
credit card to like 10 I need 10 me
before that because maybe I can like
charge 15 bucks Network right same thing
with health information amid an anthem
went and would crash so you do that math
3 trillion - those things
criminals might still be doing some
other stuff and usually when I put this
sign up there it was like I know what it
is I know what it is I have the answer
ransomware because we hear about
ransomware all the time right
this is like one of the top things
customers asked me before like hey can
you get the pen tester in here cuz he's
the cool guy I'm like okay second that
top thing can you can you help me
protect against ransomware why
ransomware because I heard in the news
we had this thing called security by
volume right now I don't mean like water
volume that would be kind of cool maybe
I guess just flood everything and then
we don't have to worry about it no I
mean security by how loud the media is
yelling that's really how tuned we are
to risk when you hear about all the time
ransom so must be ransomware check out
the stat the ransomware last year 1
billion dollars 3 trillion total only 1
billion when transport when I was
researching this talk I pulled out a
whole bunch of reports and everything
Casper's get some good numbers and
really surprised me because ransomware
actually fell by 1/3 fell by 1/3 at the
same time I was still freaking out about
ransomware fell by 1/3 one of the
reasons is of course it became harder to
get people to pay and people are said to
have backups and god forbid they
actually protect their data that's
happening somewhere I hear and still
criminals like wait a minute this is
hard and we're doing all this work to
get cryptocurrency how can we get the
cryptocurrency quicker so of course you
might imagine crypto mining is what's on
the uptick I've got a good friend who
does web hosting and he found Manero up
you guys are for millionaire it's like
that the prime way to do crypto mining
now Bitcoin is is too hard for for the
criminals Maneri can put the browsers
great he found one narrow people had
used apache flaws sprayed manera all
over his web firms and something like
1.6 million dollars was in stolen
wallets running off web front-ends in
this data center it's cool you should
keep that no no I can't turn it off good
your ethical that's great so what was
the wallets and you
but anyways so crypto mining right that
is going up 44% kind of interesting so
ransomware and crypto mining are gonna
do some like this and maybe you'll hit
about a billion maybe two million
we'll see what shakes out us still a lot
of money left one of the primary ways
that I'm seeing attacked or I see my
clients attack today is actually invoice
fraud you guys are probably well
familiar with wire fraud hi I'm the CEO
please transfer your money and someone's
like oh there's a CEO here's our money
that has been going on forever wire
fraud is a thing but invoice fraud is on
the uptick here's the way it works I
steal your cribs okay somehow I've
gotten into your office 365 email I fist
you or whatever and I'm gonna set up
rules and those rules are gonna be
whenever I email you
you're gonna forward it on whenever
they're you ply back you're gonna send
it to me and then you're gonna delete it
so you don't see it
alright so now I'm gonna email you and
you're gonna send it to you and you'd be
like oh that's my my email from Jim hi
Jim how's it going you see it for back
to me deleted I'm like hi I'm Jim how's
it going right and we started a
conversation that way they've been
targeting Accounts Payable folks I've
seen this all over in my manufacturing
customers and then when they says oh by
the way you may be interested to know
that I've got this brand new Acme
billing site that has all your invoices
you're like oh that's great cuz I think
all I need to know is what are you owe
me so I'm right so I can reconcile oh
here's what I show great now here's the
thing if you pay now I'll give you 10%
off this here how many times are gonna
fall for that if your accounts payable
person you want to be the person at the
end of the month I said I saved the
company million dollars I am a hero so
people do and they pay all this money
and then company gets to fraud as
several millions of dollars very
interesting attack this is the point on
the slide where I love to give you a
great statistic of how many billions of
dollars that's happening but I don't
have
I can't find one and that is really
interesting two trillion dollars
remember is unaccounted for so why is
there no stats in this we get called in
all the time to investigate these things
one of the reasons is if you're
compromised for this you couldn't tell
anybody
oh by the way I totally lost you know
your payments do as a matter of fact New
York Times did a survey they found that
only about 1 in 10 crimes is actually
reported one in ten crimes so we're all
panicking about ransomware cuz that's
what everyone's yelling about we're all
worried about intellectual property if
we have any and we're all told to like
worry about crime but yet most crime we
have no idea what it is about two-thirds
of it no clue what we're even defending
against most what goes unreported
unknown scary thought
scary thought and really big hole and
how we go about doing security wenonah
guys are thinking don't worry about it
wolf don't worry about it
all we need to do is secure it like a
castle we just build walls or run
organization tow walls thick pair or
thick walls parapet another mode we're
good right secure like a castle it's
like the quintessential way we're taught
to do cybersecurity just need a castle
we're gonna build a firewall what I'm
gonna do I'm gonna use a castle I'm
gonna build my website what am I gonna
do I'm gonna do a castle I'm gonna do
how to do it's okay we're gonna build a
castle
I don't get that one but at the same
time we've been talking about building
castles forever we've been talking about
building datacenters forever right and
we all know the other centers are like
on the way out
but I think there's some really good
like crossover there because you take a
long time to build a data center you
take a lot of money to build it is so
similar with the castle this castles
harlech castle this castles in Wales
it's considered by many to be like the
prime example of medieval castle really
great defenses has stood the test of
time some interesting things about this
castles when they're building it it took
10 percent of the revenue the entire
kingdom to build that castle those of
you in defense please raise your hand if
you have ten percent of the company's
revenue and I got the band I I am
looking for a job so no no generally a
gardener says we get 0.2% of IT security
spam usually when I put that up
someone's like I wish I had 0.2% right
we don't have the money for cast oh we
love our castles but there's no way we
have the money for it problem number one
back to France for a minute
back to our Rhinos this site in France
is really freaking cool
what they're doing is inserted in 1997
and I hate giving out years because now
that my my apprenticeship model is grown
and people are like there's always that
person Gold I was born in 1997 of a
goose top pocket so for those of you
maybe born in 1997 congratulations thank
you for being in cybersecurity we need
you but for a minute don't make me feel
they they're building an entire castle
by hand by scratch
they're like dragging the stone up
they're crushing the stone they've got
like hatchets to make the wood they're
doing this as a archaeological project
to figure out how castles were built
really freaking cool they got 50 expert
craftsmen working on this and they
figure it's gonna take about 25 years to
build about 10 million
- to construct they're learning at time
time and you can go you can visit their
it is your google it when you're in
France go see it don't see the zero
there's nothing in the zoom exactly but
this also gives me hope for all the rest
of our spray beards this are my
retirement plan I'm looking for 50x for
craftsmen to help me build data centers
send me an email we have tours will show
the kids this is a hot aisle this is a
cold aisle of a great but think about
the way we build data centers and think
about the way we build castles and think
about the way we build infrastructure
it's all this waterfall model right here
is my 3-year plan that I'm going to
construct something and here's my
revenue associated with it and my
full-time employees at the same time we
cleaned to this waterfall model in
cybersecurity in the 90s application
development of courses went way to agile
smarter loops feature functionality
implement feature function element when
I was doing DevOps back at a financial
company I thought it was really really
cool and I got to a month and we were
like calling the press and we had a
white paper on it and my smiling picture
was and that sounds cool and so then I'm
sitting down with my friends they're
like we do DevOps Mike it's great
what's your velocity they're like once
every four hours what did you guys do at
the same time once every four hours
they're changing the environment we're
being asked to build a castle around
that not knowing where it's gonna be in
a week let alone a month let alone a
year that's the next problem with castle
building it just takes too long
specifically given the pace of modern IT
infrastructure I would before it the
following definition of security
security is not castle building anymore
it's not high walls it's not strong
doors security is bells on strings
strings rolled from one side to the
other and bells that ring when attackers
are moving across your network following
given path that is a great way of doing
security and I say that people are like
that's great once we have the strings we
can put weights on and we can do defense
because that's the only thing we're all
taught about right I got I love I love
it when folks come in and they're
working with me and they're fresh out of
college and they look at this
environment they're like we can solve
them we just need to do defense and
death look that's great how are you
gonna afford it they're like I don't
know do you worry about that here's what
we need and the flipside to is what's
always exciting is when you talk to a
CSO or a CIO see so they know better a
CIO and you're like what's your defense
in death
right I do a lot of these risk
assessments that's what we start with us
re-interview sit down okay
how good is your defensive death when
they go home we spend a lot it takes a
lot of time our defense and depth is
deep that I can it's littered with the
bones of our enemies oh my god this has
got dark but okay
building bones of our enemies but then
we bring in our pen testers and anyone
was on the red team knows what we're
gonna find the defense in depth is more
like this right you're like what
happened what why you guys you guys were
awesome what I heard such great things
in the interviews so if we jump back to
risk for a minute
for those of you guys who have played
rest probably recognize like you can
attack these places that you're touching
and it's a numbers game if you've got
three guys defending and you've got six
people attack you like with the wind
this is defense I got my defenses evenly
distributed across my entire environment
and if you're designing a network you
but like this is good because we don't
want but but if you were to take those
same defenses and put them on the
perimeter otherwise design it right
where the attack is gonna go you're
gonna be much more successful if you
focus on where the attacker really is
you can build a good defense it's not
defense in depth then when you go to do
that someone's got all we got all this
weakness over here look did you hear
about the caravan no forget about the
caravan the United States is fine we can
focus our defenses right but no one
wants to focus defenses at the senior
level and at the junior level you're
like but I was
defense-in-depth I want to spend
everything and it's not like you know
the people who may have a magic quadrant
don't encourage this you talk to the
Magic Quadrant folks they're like here
is our security here's we're gonna do
it's really simple I just need you to
buy one of everything and then we've got
expense and death I have three Sims I'm
clearly protecting my environment it is
oh good I like to think about security
more like balloon tower defense and if
anyone wants to spend like the next week
playing balloon tower defense their
bosses like what are you doing I was a
security conference and they told me
this is security I'm playing I promise
you can get away with that but if you
imagine this the red is the attackers
okay and they're following the attack
path through the network someone is
always gonna mess there's always gonna
be a mess oftentimes multiple misses but
if you actually layer on the defenses
along that attack path you can have
multiple chances to get them right you
can have my a-v be only 60% effective I
can have my guys who cook fishing only
be 25% effective and 75% they click
things you can have this if you have
defenses along those that path and this
is the beauty I think of threat Mellon
you can take any take a kill chain take
an attack path take whatever framework
you want but layer on the entire path
that that balloons gonna take and say
there be monkeys I'm gonna stop them
here I'm gonna stop them they're
everywhere but where could I put those
monkeys a few times during this
conference I've heard the words might
attack framework a few times I'm
assuming you guys have as well miter
attack framework today is the way that I
think about these things I look at that
path that they are taking and I lay
across my to attack framework and say
what are the real tactics are using what
are those tactics that are being
performed and once I know those tactics
I get people in the room from that
organization and I say okay how can we
add some prevention how can we have some
detection how can we increase the time
this book is time based security win for
two great great book very fundamental I
think in how you do so
security and this whole thought was this
security is defined as follows
it is secure at the time it takes to
breach the de prevención is longer than
time to detect and respond time takes
use breaking the house takes you longer
than the alarm system go off and the
police to arrive you're secure I've got
a fireproof safe and it burns for eight
hours but it's rated at ten your
contents are safe right that's security
right there if you can figure out ways
to drive up the prevention how long it
takes detected to thwart that and drive
down the detection how quickly you can
get to them you're in a secure state and
if you look at that path you start doing
that you can lay out monkeys I think you
have a five plus two strategy if I can
stop five tactics twice detect and
prevent I'm probably in a pretty good
state and it's a hell of a lot cheaper
than buying one of everything so that's
the next problem defense-in-depth sounds
great but without a clear use case is
expensive it's expensive expensive and
it always has gaps and when we think
about how oftentimes pen testers break
in
it's those gaps that they're following
the next one we hear all the time is
don't do check box security right don't
just check the box we've got to really
be compliant everyone's afraid to check
the box or somebody's I don't know why
but it's not like you usually compliant
with one thing there's like a bazillion
things that people have to be compliant
with these days right and then they just
keep adding GDP are now CCPA next who
knows what's coming after it and the
answer is you just no problem we'll
build a road map which again you might
remembers if we just have three years we
can be completely secure and just throw
a bunch of money in it I thought you
there's only so much money and fortunes
are you so many monkeys and so how do we
spend that money and how do we position
those monkeys really determines over
there secure back to software
development for a moment you guys have
probably heard MVP Minimum Viable
Product and I love that concept for
security if you think about Minimum
Viable architecture
what's the minimum that we can put in
place to satisfy the requirements and
check those boxes and then and then
here's a crazy thought if we used a tack
framework or other detective methods
what if we were to get feedback when
those controls were touched or triggered
we use right what if we can lay out the
compliance and every time someone trips
over something we go ahead that's pretty
weird I checked that PCI box but three
times in a row
Frank bypassed mfa and then go hot I can
invest in my fake or I checked that
checkbox and you know what damn fa is
Roy crappy so no one has ever tried to
steal passwords from that never not
gonna happen
but you know I'm saying kind of an
interesting way to flip it on his head
so from there is blind compliance just
as bad as defense and death and we
always say don't just check the box but
make it to 11 each one we end up
spending a lot more than we can actually
afford probably the the quintessential
like bumper sticker for rules like a
people in trouble though as I think is
the one do not do security through
obscurity the actual rule for this makes
a lot of sense if I've got a path to
where the bad guys are going don't just
hide stuff because that's gonna be easy
to circumvent but people take that to
the nth degree I had a very long
argument one time with someone who is
bound to determine to put SSH on the
Internet
I'm like all right we can do SSH in the
internet but why don't we change the
ports you and two guys going to no can't
change the port why not that would be
security through obscurity and I know
that's bad like I'm not trying to trick
you bro scanners are looking for SSH but
if we move it isn't that giving up no
it's putting in a good control so the
scanners don't get to you oh and I've
had similar arguments did you guys see
Tom's talk at was it nine o'clock we
mentioned how the Qualis users are
always like Qualis user and like admin
abilities scanning the full networking
and Qualis if it's across user and so
red team loves to look for the koalas
user I was talking to our companies do
like why don't we need that something
else like Voldemort well that would be
security through obscurity I'm like yes
and then when they pull down our user
accounts they're not going to go there's
the Qualis account I'll steal that cred
probably won't even say the name out
loud so this is this is one of the
fundamental problems of this idea of
security through obscurity good
obscurity adds time to circumvent the
prevention it makes it more difficult
for the determinate attacker
good obscurity increases the likelihood
of detection especially via Baltimore as
the account and Qualis is just an
account that no one uses until someone
tries using no one to use that you use
it you are the bad guy done right drop
the net it's a way of slowing down that
determined attacker by confusing them if
you hear like red team horror stories
it's usually the obscurity oh man you
have no idea they have your computers
all named with numbers and I'm like what
the hell and they're these service
accounts and they were named after
artists and I'm like I can't even I
can't even right now and I'm trying to
map this out and the maps won't form
that is good obscurity because it really
pisses them off and slows them way down
now the thing about determine attackers
though in most organizations and most
organizations it's not what we face most
the time about 90% of the seven percent
of the time across the organization's I
work with it's not the determined
attackers not the hoody guy with the
superpowers it is some malware right now
that's not always the case I recently
hired a guy from the energy sector and I
was talking through this neat that way
back you know what what he goes no
Russia really is out to get us
yeah but your energy I mean like for the
cabinetmakers guys it's usually just
some malware that's spraying around so
quick story of mine back in the day back
in the day used to install Citrix citrix
metaframe now is that a frame or
whatever and you install it to a funky
level right you installed to like an for
me to frame it was clever and then when
people logged in they would map their C
Drive to the actual C Drive so they
could browse
and I never thought about this as a
security control ten years ago but we
got hit with some malware from one of
our partners because they're in a
network and it jumped the network so we
get hit with us malware and it's scanner
on our network and I had no idea what I
did know was suddenly we're getting
pop-ups that an executable failed that's
weird
Wow an executable failing and come to
find out the malware was hard-coded to
the right to the C Drive and it wasn't
I'm the secret windows 9 C to have it
crashed it got past our IPs it got past
our IDs the cap passer endpoint AV
change the drive large done killed it
completely prevented our us from being
affected whereas my partner who was
connected to us whoa they're done for
days kind of interesting kind of
interesting and I've heard other similar
people go hey shoeless when malware is
like in the sandbox can't run like yeah
so you know what I did I go what you do
it he was like I found the registry keys
is looking for and I push those to all
my windows endpoints that is brilliant
malware infects the box looks cool I'm
gonna stand back shut down be quiet
and it sound like the secretary machine
life is good right
obscurity a little bit of obscurity is
really a lot of fun because you feed a
bot bad malware and a bot does what
suffer always does with bad input it
does and then we're protected then we're
safe so problem find that clever
bumper-sticker like I don't do obscurity
has actually caused much more problems
it prevents us from finding some really
cool clever hacks that we can deploy all
right next one is and this one drives me
nuts we have a town sure did you guys
hear this we need somewhere between one
and a billion people to solve the
InfoSec problem numbers may vary but I
think it's up Mundo billion look before
I tackle that one more thing about
castles castles and knights right back
in the good old days there was a
percentage generally around the time of
Harlech Castle that works something like
this for every 200 people you had about
one night and for every one night you
had like five archers supporting them
that was the number that was about the
number the English have and
in the French give or take you know
percentage here there similarly we can
slice and dice with IT folks this
numbers comes from Gartner wonderful
ASEC professional for every a thousand
employees wonderful SEC professional for
every 20 IT pros kind of scary when you
think about it kind of scary because
that means 20 people are doing
who-knows-what who knows where who knows
why probably with admin rights at any
given point in time to get one inputs
that guy like wait guys you saw that
what you do those numbers kind of paint
a bleak picture but you know this
castles is nights and we all know good
metaphors are hard to find when you go
and look at Cecil says I say hey we got
0% unemployment when you go to look at
like yeah we can't find anybody at the
beginning of this talk I mentioned that
my program has 55 qualified applicants
for every one person I hire and I bet
you a bunch of guys here are looking to
get into information security and a
bunch of people are in and are looking
to move up how can that be how can we
turn away 54 people but have 0%
unemployment doesn't quite make sense
something is not adding up part of the
problem is this concept of and you I'm
sure you guys have heard this if I only
kind of clone myself you know if only I
had one more of me risky risky thinking
hey I would never want to clone myself
because I would not want to work with
that guy
no it breeds this mentality that talent
must look like me right and a lot of us
who are in information security just
sort of like ended up here it just
seemed fun at the time and now people
come up to goes you've been doing this
for two decades I have but we didn't
start out that way so why are we looking
for people like us it doesn't make sense
the other thing is is that human mind is
inherently flawed right the the the
flaws in the animal brain are fantastic
and phenomenal we have things like the
choice support bias whatever I chose was
the right choice
it's what my brain tells me it must be
true you have things like the like me
bias if their people are like me and
studies have shown this again and again
if someone looks like you or you
your boss your boss rates you higher you
get raises faster you get promoted
quicker weird weird I don't even look
like my boss which is why I need a raise
performance by the same thing right if
we think people are like us we rate them
higher so think about what this is doing
at the moment I talked about this the
cementing of what it means to be a
nympho sack as we turn into a profession
we're getting this point where like
hackers I know how to hire hackers this
is a quote someone told me I have no
problem hiring hackers because hackers
look like hackers what the hell dude we
got into this thinking hackers are weird
right it's it's a it's a meritocracy the
smartest idea wins hackers are strange
we're people with the Mohawks and the
flamethrowers we're where the people go
to like the Wall of China and realize we
don't have any money and con our way
down onto the back of a you know there's
some weird stories with hackers but this
idea the hackers look like hackers
concerns me because we've solidified in
our mind what that means and at the same
time we're embracing all this weirdness
whenever someone is not weird like the
way we think a hacker is suddenly they
don't belong right something they don't
shouldn't be in the room something we
should've listened to them slowly why
are they at our conference I think it's
so scary and so terrifying right hacker
diversity diversity inclusion hacker
style should mean finding weird finding
the new weird finding the weird weird
not the guy with the Mohawk we can hire
him that seems cool but I mean what
about the person without a mark but the
person who looks normal likes to wear a
suit well if it's a woman loves its you
name it finding new and exciting folks
right that can change the status quo so
paramount right now in a day a nature
would say we can't find anybody because
I can tell you there's tons of people
want in we're just not talking to
because they don't look like Acker
so that's problem number one we don't
have a counselor get a hiring problem we
have a hard time hiring people who are
different than unique problem number two
I'm mentoring some people right now from
local university and one of my mentees
it's not the mentees men-tel's I always
want to say Mentos like what am i Mentos
it's down
I'm the dico no but he sits down with me
he tells me about this interview he
wants me to help him interview like why
do you need help interview I'm a
terrible person I don't interview anyone
great I'm sit down like hey you look
cool you want to go intervention they're
like yes I'm like you're hired
terrible interview what do you mean he
goes well here's what happened he went
into an interview he sat down all
excited he has hi I'm Sukkos all good
and he weighed in the camps room for
like 20 minutes and the hiring manager
comes in this early looking like IT guy
and comes and sits down with him he's
like we're gonna start with the
technical questions first cuz this is a
hard job all right sure he's like tell
me what's the difference Eugene telnet
nice to Sage and the guy didn't know it
was an information assurance degree he
was taught compliance he had no idea
it's like I H s SS what no clue and you
know what happened the hiring managers I
got thank you very much packs up of
stuff because you can see the door the
HR people will contact you yeah ask one
question shown the door she's and I had
me thinking about skills right the
skills that we used to value and I was
joking a little bit about the data
center back in the day but I used to
love building data centers and I'm gonna
brag cuz I can show the slide only for
probably like another year before no one
cares ever but this was my data rack
they're pretty wiring really thank you
thank you I thank you
I am really pretty wearing we did our
entire cabinet this way it was beautiful
I could find everything and at the time
I could tell you like there was a queue
all 2340 fibre channel card I knew the
name of the firmware and everything I
love this data center loved it and and
yet it kind of makes me want to be like
well if you can't do that should you
even be an info SEC bro should you even
be an info SEC had me thinking about
when I was a young man and my my father
and my uncle's my grandfather gave me a
lot of grief because I'm terrible at
working in the car can't change a spark
plug can really change my oil I probably
could figure it out but why I'm like why
why are you guys giving all this grief I
can take it to someone and they will do
this for me that's the way there's
people who do this now I'm like no you
need to know this and it wasn't until I
was a little bit older that occurred to
me why that was when they were my age
all the good jobs in Michigan I'm from
Detroit so all the good jobs in Michigan
were manufacturing and if you can work
on your car you were not going to get a
good job and they were so concerned I
didn't know the mechanics and a light
want bulb went on because I'm like
that's exactly what I'm thinking about
because I'm like oh you don't know what
SSH is you don't know what a fiber card
is right I think the real talk is to us
Greybeards is is this skills that we
needed to get here are not the skills of
the young people in this room are gonna
need to get there but we got to remember
that when we're bringing people in so
vitally important and when we hire them
this is great we bring out the young
people are like how do you do your job
like just do it and if you haven't seen
ass now skit for that you guys like move
you guys should google it you'll enjoy
it this is our attitude right oh you
can't do it move out of my way kid
what's going on there's very little
apprenticeship programs there very
little mentoring is very little coaching
we just expect folks to know it and then
we have a real hard time today bridging
that gap of college to professionals so
that problem number two is we don't have
a talent shortage we've got plenty of
talent talent a lower-class town in here
telling everywhere we've got skill
shortage we got training problem we got
a mentoring coach
problem alright it's okay it's not like
we have an ego or anything which reminds
me my next point we can't patch stupid
there's someone back there going amen
thank you and then you got the great
bumper sticker like don't click it right
you know in in a in a building in a
building that my wife used to live in
there is this problem right the elevator
wasn't stopping on the right floor and
people were getting hurt we're getting
hurt and at one point time it stopped
like too low and you walked in he like
fell right and cut yourself into this
blood and everywhere and she's sending
me photos and what now and she reports
this to the property manager and people
would report this is a property manager
again and again and again and they fixed
it they finally fixed it after her
report after blood and photos and
everything finally fixed it
here's how they fixed it please look
down what'd he give him the elevator
they didn't actually fix the problem god
forbid and I snapped a photo so like
that's InfoSec gardener gardener my
favorite four-quadrant folks had a quote
that said 95% of cloud security failures
will be the customers fault in 2020
it's their fault that's three buckets
open their fault bunch of credit card
lovers leaked their fault right and and
I read this I'm like ah this is this
reminds me of something because I had
read this book of design theory so I'm
looking looking and spending a lot of
time looking at design these days and
they had this comment that industrial
accidents industrial accidents are
caused by humans right estimates range
from 75 to 95 percent ok that makes
sense up to 95 percent how is it so many
people are incompetent the book asked
and I was ills at the bar on the page of
a guess why are this own competent why
can't we patch stupid I click to the
next page click to the next page that's
terrible
alright I click to the next page and the
types of answer they're not it's a
design problem like why are we doing
right we build these security systems
people trip over them we block access we
block usability we allow people to click
on stuff and they're like huh they're
stupid it's their fault we've got to
figure out better ways to get folks in
because for every one of us is a
thousand of them how do we engage some
of those folks to build a better
security to tighten things down maybe we
can scare them a little bit that's one
way right and the quintessential way you
scare me as we all know is is pen test
we just did that pen test will show them
that there's a risk and we'll get budget
so I was spending some time looking at
pen tests and I found like the first pen
test was at besides Detroit earlier this
year I was asking people was the first
pen test and I got some great answers
all the young people are like like 2010
yeah I was around then some folks like
2001 yeah you getting closer 1995 when
hackers came out that was it right cuz
they almost the boat almost flipped and
it was terrible there would have been
oil everywhere and was cool about
hackers by the way is the guys
skateboarding through a data center I
can tell you a ID not very good
skateboarding but B I had a data center
and see you better damn well believe I
tried that don't try that you get
nothing else don't skateboard as 1988
when the Morris worm hit and took down
the internet that's the other thing I
heard one thing does fastly about
cybersecurity cuz we're so focused on
this being a new discipline new domain
we oftentimes forget our history and
forget where we came from we need some
historians but I want to take you back
to a time it's 1967 that's not the first
pen test but 1967 all you need is love
was the song and the top of the charts I
pulled that record out the other day and
listen to this phenomenal summer love
was happening cars look like this
computers look like that and ran
corporation got a bunch of people
together they threw the very first
conference they like Colonel that grew
into besets Charleston in 1967 I got
15,000 people together and said hey
we're building on the stuff computers
and networks were built on stuff you
think it could be broken into we know
the answer today right we know the
answer but they launched the first pen
test those by a guy named James P
Anderson I love it because he sounds
like neo James P Anderson 1972 he
published his results JP Anderson today
looks like this job making me feel old
but the first pen test was phenomenal
read because you read it and for a while
you forget you're reading history it's
like here's our attack scenario here's a
were thinking could happen here's what
the threat actors would do and then you
get to the point where they're talking
about and they could shuffle punch cards
you're like holy hell it's 1972 but
we've been doing this pen test in the
exact same way
right can it be breached yeah can we get
funding okay we've been doing this again
and again and again since I'm sure we
made improvements there's nest there's
pitas but we're so focused on the pen
test on the weakness side we forget the
strengths we forget to say okay break in
this room and they're like we can break
through that door that door that door we
forget to say okay where's the walls and
can you get through the walls we forget
to figure out how to build on those
strengths and core tenants if you're
testing that way you test something like
this does that control even exist seems
silly but I can tell you from experience
CIOs think I exist until you get to
someone who goes that's funny no we
haven't done an act in five years is it
effective does it actually like to stop
the bad guys we're talking about Equifax
earlier in the speaker lounge
Equifax had a fire eye box it was
incredibly effective except it wasn't
looking at thing in their web firm so
they have briefs didn't see a damn thing
all right can't be circumvented
operationalize when you're doing these
tests is someone actually respond think
back to that prevention detection it
looks something like this this is
testing your prevention and the
detection response is all about the
operationalize a different way of
testing a better way of testing for 45
years we've been doing the same thing
right this goes back to a time where you
couldn't trust politicians so much has
changed not going to touch that much
further than that but mash was on right
the Waltons were on and at that point
I'm the og James B Anderson did the
first pen test we've been doing this
again and again and again not
necessarily focusing on strengths but
always focusing in the weakness is the
quickest path in is what pen tests show
so that's the problem
but in what you guys are gonna say right
well we got to do that because and this
is the last one and I'm gonna wrap it up
we have to be right every time but the
bad guys only need to be right once you
hear that again and again every single
scary slide ever right every single time
we need to be right but do we do we if
you've got a good attack path right and
you've got controls along that and you
put a hell of a lot of monkeys on that
you're gonna get past that guy
and not be detected and not ring any
bells and at that point time I'd argue
they have to be read a whole lot of time
so they have to be right every single
time along that path to really get in
and still the rhino horn or whatever
their target is so how do we do that we
do that by playing both games by
protecting the resources of the
organization and preventing the
criminals and mapping those up and
realizing that we don't have a hell of a
lot of visibility either one we're
dealing with a lot of unknowns the fog
of war is the world of InfoSec today we
can say the criminal mind we can get a
better idea of their motivations their
tactics by pulling in reports by looking
at the analysis folks do by looking at
our own environments we can skip
building castles and instead focus I'm
very flexible very fast defenses that we
put in place and one of those bells ring
we rip them back out taking a lesson
from the agile community where security
is a feature that's rolled and really
quick and rolled out just as quick if
it's not used we can check the check box
where we need to saving time in some
other areas and spending time in where
it counts to be bear compliant but to
raise it up where we actually need it we
can build weird things which is what is
exciting about InfoSec embracing the
obscurity when designing so we trip up
the attacker so we trip up the software
so we can come up some really clever
hacks like embedding the registry keys
for hypervisor and all your machines so
malware shuts itself off we can hire
weird people which is also what makes
InfoSec exciting different people right
strange people to us more diverse people
who bring in different ideas in
different ways of doing things
we can pen test strengths right we can
build those defenses and hire those
people and put them in the right place
and then test to make sure those
defenses are working test to make sure
people are responding test to make sure
that the right things in the right place
that our assumptions are holding up when
they don't we can improve those instead
of just finding the quickest way in
because we all know there's a million in
one ways in or network because we don't
have enough money we don't have enough
monkeys these are some things we can do
or don't right and this fundamentally
I'm talking a lot for the young people
right here is my call to action to you
guys don't break the rules right think
for yourselves find new ways to do these
things argue with us all Greybeards hack
at yourself don't sit there when someone
handed you a bumper sticker that says
don't flex should think that they're the
rule right don't be in school when
someone says build your defenses I could
casually go yeah so but maybe not maybe
argue about that maybe challenge that
set of school and come up with new and
exciting ways to do things because for
45 years we kind of doing it the same
way and it's about time to flip some
tables so I'll leave you with this
thought me that dumpster fires daylight
and I'm talking about those guys who
follow the rules right the dumpster
fires that are lit by people every day
you try an over engineer and overdo and
push people away and not embrace true
security and finding new clever ways I
mean the dumpster fires they light light
your way thank you very much
[Applause]