more specifically about election acting
a little bit about what happened and a
little bit you know of or hopefully the
bulk of them beat you know how to
actually affect influence over our
election process right so brief
introduction I managed an intelligence
seat for vanilla cyber security that it
was involved in investigating the DNC
and a bunch of cybersecurity events
involving both parties in 2016
I teach computer science and information
science at the University of Illinois
generally I focus on criminal threats
top brought in to do this stuff even
though it's more nation-states has one
of the exception professionally but me
being involved in more nation-state
geopolitical related work so go through
this quickly because we all kind of know
what happened and John also touched on
part of it right in 2016 in June of 2016
trout strike was called in to
investigate it reached the DNC found
malware mapping to posting their fancy
fare which is no now we're used
exclusively by the Russian FSB and GRU
respectively so they used to say now
where they've been using for years and
then it's already been attributed to
them
[Applause]
I turn this on
this is full battery also
we are not empowered by technology so I
will just project and hopefully if
anybody can't hear me just let me know
and I'll start yelling even louder
so I'm characteristically four firms are
brought in to confirm the findings to
the states if you've ever worked in
digital forensics you know we work a
case we don't share with our competitors
and this case poor competitors got
together to confirm the conclusions
right this is on top of what our
intelligence community also did during
their own assessment right fancy there
began a 2015 cozy Bear April of 2016
based on fishing domains of just
transliteration of a couple letters
based on the IP contract for the DNS are
the DNC users right Mis Department if
you looked at mis department comm at the
time anyway it's a we're probably you
know you know what a customer's proudly
is the DNC right so somebody did
research to do very specific
impersonation of minute so as far as
social engineering is concerned right
somebody took some thought to me right
starting infield somebody using the
moniker up to the server
lucifer 2.0 started releasing some
measure of documents those documents had
medicated in them and the previous
speaker show how metadata can be useful
in bleeding some more information based
on what the person is doing i mention
this because of the high-profile nature
of this many security researchers
started looking at it
commenting on the metadata and we're
giving real-time tradecraft critiques to
the russian government of how to hide
their involvement so as we would point
out mistakes they made they stopped
making those mistakes i mentioned that
just because I found it was particularly
amusing in terms of how things
progressed over time right
DC leaks is a smaller site that also
began releasing information most of
their stuff there was some overlap with
Dean's Democrats but they also released
some day on Republicans and a couple of
military officials so they set up sites
explicitly to lead things you know using
an essence low-rent kind of people who
are not necessarily overly sophisticated
and we'll talk about that in a second
the Democratic Congressional Campaign
Committee was also breached that is the
campaign arm of the Democrats in the US
House of Representatives
so there's actually national parties who
have three different major campaign
committees one for the Senate one for
the house one for the president
[Music]
[Applause]
alright similar characteristics of the
DNC briefs are able to establish
forensically a pattern of behavior right
it is very as as the previous speaker
mentioned it tends to be very difficult
to really strongly attribute somebody
back but when you have now learned all
these unique characteristics that you
can map based on three to three years of
observed behavior you can start making a
lot of stronger conclusions versus hi
this Facebook account was created with
this IP in this email address and that's
probably all forensically you're going
to have but when you breach an
organization you create lots of forensic
evidence that you can map to previous
patterns of behavior right so we did a
lot of that work to prove it those
emails are also leaked by WikiLeaks
included some donor information but
clearly nobody concerned about
monetizing it because they just
published it online versus taking it to
alpha Bay at the time anyway to sell it
so no real financial motivation another
strong indication right as an
intelligence agency Jon does this email
got reach this one that's a little
harder to attribute but we're pretty
sure based on how the information made
it into the public domain you know here
is John Podesta is fifty thousand some
on email addresses released in wolf and
max right and I mentioned that
specifically for anybody who's ever
dealt with the press if you want to get
them to do something you have to make it
stupid simple for them you can't say
here is five thousand emails go fish the
only reason the media went fishing is
because of the high profile nature of
this but by large there was no attempt
you know
with this to drive a specific message
right you know it was let's just create
mayhem and rockets which that they did
it right there's no look at this email
that says this right nut earlier on
right there was leaking of things saying
can you hear me now okay you know
earlier on in terms of the primary
questions were shared with Hillary
Clinton for a debate with her and Bernie
Sanders things of that sort but towards
the end of the the general elections
like there's no attempt to really drive
any specific narrative based on these
messages according to the DNI report the
Director of National Intelligence we did
this big not read the US intelligence
community did a big report in the
aftermath the election what happened
made some reference to attack some
Republican officials - only one of those
I had the opportunity to look at that
look like commodity fishing I'm
unconvinced that that was Russian
government or Russian directed proper
but if you know anything about how the
Russian cyber criminal ecosystem
operates the boundary between Russian
cybercrime and Russian intelligence is
Flores and complicated where they will
share information with the FSB in
exchange for not being loved about their
criminality for some measure of time
right so things might not necessarily be
state directed but still find their way
into Russian government
as a way to perpetuate their behavior
I mentioned election authority hacks
also there's a lot of talk about voting
machine hacking I'll come to that
towards the end of this you know the the
highest-profile incident is that the
state of Illinois recently passed online
voter registration so you can register
to vote online it is now being
deprecated because we have now just
passed automatic voter registration so
voter registration is meaningless in the
state of Illinois starting sometime the
new year a few months I have from the
effective date of that law but this was
a sequel injection attack that
interestingly enough was discovered by
the State Board of Election because
their database was falling over because
there are so many queries being
hand-pounded added they were basically
brute-forcing tables no real attempt to
say hey you know what I want this
information I know this is a voter
registration database you know doing
sequel commands to go for the
information they were just pounding the
database and then the attack that
discovered of why is our database under
huge load look at all these sequel
commands coming from internet right so
no meal sophistication there to be
honest looking at that I think it was
just one of these machines that sequel
of sequel scan the entire internet 24/7
365 doesn't mean the Russian government
didn't get some information but I don't
know if they necessarily directed the
operation out front so some of the
motivator are some of the motivations to
help defeat Hillary Clinton to help
Donald Trump
- so distrust in institutions which is a
very typical thing for them to do when
they do any kind of influence operation
right they want to so just try
in the existing power structure
diminished the confidence people have in
their government and their leadership
right and there are obvious geopolitical
motivations which it's kind of a mixed
bag of weather Russia actually got what
they want it's clear that President
Trump has not necessarily been the front
to NATO that NATO would like but on the
flip side of that equation when Syria
launched and we saw slide critiquing the
u.s. about this when Syria launched a
chemical weapons attack against a
civilian population President Trump in
essence called up the Russians and
saying you have about one hour to get
out of the base that we're going to
level in response to this attack look
you can't do that you have one hour to
get out and then we level that base all
while President Trump was having dinner
with the Chinese president right where
you know as they were kind of counting
on a weaker America and like I said it's
a mixed bag obviously our relationship
with NATO is complicated but a
relationship with Russia has in some
aspects done worse than it has been
under Obama for a variety reasons and
that's another conversation but once
their influence operation successful
right how many people think the Russians
were successful in accomplishing what
they set out to do and just raise their
hands how many people think they were
not successful just a question why do
you think they were successful
[Music]
yeah that was her objective a then they
did create chaos anybody else want to
chime in now
[Music]
sure sure and to recap just so the
microphone catches it right you know the
releasing of truth may have caused chaos
but probably potentially in a beneficial
way for society right you know there
wasn't a lot of at least for the leaks
of emails and I'll talk about this not a
lot of fake information there as far as
we know all the emails were true
perhaps that meant me to help the public
make a better decision you know other
people can decide I'm not taking the
stand but I want to get to my other
point right you know if you think about
an influence op right you know first
word there's influence was it
influential ultimately to change
people's mind we have we never really
studied that question by a March it's a
hard question and I'm not going to say
it's easy one a good at math but we've
never really think about how many people
change their looks
how many minds were worshipped I posit
not many I'll show some in a couple of
slides you know but did it undermine
faith in institutions I think so but not
directly not not for the reasons they
intended or at least
when they started out right and that
goes to my Keith one on the slide right
Russians or sue there are these two
Russian government's students of history
understand that empires don't die they
commit suicide right is that if Russia
wants to beat the u.s. they're not going
to beat us they're going to inspire us
into a self-destructive spiral which is
a good probably description of what our
past 12 months have been as a society at
least in terms of politics it's been a
very self-destructive cycle that they
may have pushed us into but a lot of the
pieces were already there
you know we were a pretty bitter and
divided country before the tear you got
into the DNC so that's example right you
know if this is kind of the polling data
you know from June 1st 2015 so before
the campaign even really started between
Hillary Clinton and Donald Trump and
about March 20 actually starting
September 1st statistically speaking
those are flat lines not much changed
and if you really come the big dips of
Donald Trump is usually when Trump went
full Trump not that Russia released
anything you know and you've got the the
movement at the end that's because of
the length of graph you don't really see
it the biggest drop for Hillary Clinton
was then FBI director Comey's Melman
right we generated a lot of headlines we
generated a lot of news we focused on
fake news but as you saw him last slide
of Melvin and the last name escapes me
right these are a council with no
influence or not influence their
accounts it creates a lot of noise maybe
you can get a trending topic but that's
kind of hard one of the problems that
they have right and using the sequence
of cutouts Lucifer was a con artist that
they weren't particularly sophisticated
people good surfer froze one of their
main mechanisms to communicating to the
public and in my conversations with him
which since I'm talking about this
publicly want to emphasize I gave to the
FBI so my purpose is fully disambiguated
here you know is he was complaining
right that you know a reporter spirit
involvement right didn't think he was
going to quote us work so there's lots
of browsing about that point one let's
just assume that's authentic grousing
because you don't know how to work with
the media why would you disclose that to
me with the simple Google search we know
that by the way I'm investigating you
because it was not private at all that
my firm was involved and me specifically
right was disclosing this because he was
just kind of a dumb guy he's not
somebody you know in a basement in
Moscow who's been doing this for a while
there's my ability of using on
sophisticated people because they make
mistakes he had no idea distinctions of
swing districts or geography but weirdly
even how our elections worked Julian
Assange has some degree of media savvy
but really didn't care so much about our
elections at self-aggrandizement right
when you use cutouts you can't really
control them right they're either dumb
or they have their own agendas
the useful idiots and Julian is a useful
idiot right you know but he proceeds
with his own agenda right they could
really understand what swing districts
were right they're releasing documents
about congressional races in districts
that are completely uncompetitive he
gave me documents about congressman
Bobby Rush I don't know if anybody hears
from Chicago I'm guessing not right the
only way Bobby Rush is not going to be a
congressman anymore as it dies retires
or gets indicted right there is no way
he is ever going to lose an election
ever right and they're releasing
documents about it because they don't
know that because it's very hard to
understand the nuances of what people in
a district or a country or a state are
actually doing on the ground from large
distances away Russia has a lot of
physical presence in Eastern Europe it
dissipates somewhat the more West Lego
but they have institutional people on
the ground who understand the lay of the
land they don't have as much of that
here right so that's a real liability
for them right the thing about releasing
some of the information about Hillary
Clinton that they did right you know and
some of it was scandalous to a degree
but by and large the public perceives
the Clinton family is kind of sleazy
already you give you specifics to an
already kind of ingrained notion right
and I don't say that as a partisan you
know the fact that
if Hillary Clinton won the election
she'd have been the most unpopular US
president in history two more popular
than Donald Trump but by and large you
know there's baggage there right but
they never really tried in this surprise
and I expected them to try to make up
things right because the Russians have
been known to do that if they can't find
a compromise of material on you they
will try to make it up they did in the
French election all right which
reference briefly our reference again
one of the emails they released was some
elderly MP in Parliament who bought
drugs with Bitcoin off the dark web and
shifted department I absurd on its face
seven-year-old guys gonna get out to
work really you know figures out Bitcoin
and anybody who does drugs is never
gonna have it shipped to the most secure
building in their country with x-ray
scanners looking for things like
suspicious powders you know it's an
obviously doctored document it's very
hard to use fake documents because it's
got to be believed long enough right to
have an impression you know the French
unlike us just kind of dumped cold water
on the whole thing and then moved on
right because in the end if the goal of
your hat the series to undermine your
institutions one way to ensure that
happens is line up all of the heads of
your intelligence agencies and all of
your congressional leaders and say the
Russians have undermined our democracy
now the numbers don't even matter of
what they did our own country said they
did it we're moving on because we have
undermined our own institutions I do not
believe Russia
that initially I think we did that to
ourselves so there are limitations I
reference this they don't have a lot of
resources on the ground here to work
with we just cut the amount of
diplomatic presence that can happen to
this country I think only 455 people now
which means they've got to use cutouts
are actually covert sources of which
they're also not many and probably many
are test on more important things and
doing the real work with espionage right
there's lots of suspicion right you know
we're we're looking for reasons to
suspect Russians of something right we
are trying to give the American
corporate death penalty to Kaspersky for
no other reason than the company is
based in Moscow as far as I know that's
the only reason best buy to stop
spelling Kaspersky software yesterday
today or whenever it was right no real
evidence aside that right how can you
succeed being overtly Russian you can't
you got abuse on the nuts right you can
exactly vote by mail and Russia we track
at misses you know an election of
authority the Illinois or Iowa State
Board of Elections is going to be why am
i mailing the hundred thousand ballots
to st. Petersburg probably should check
that out and we're going to check that
out before the election actually happens
because you've got to apply for that
over a month ahead of time right the
same thing for voter registration I mean
you can be an expat vote overseas people
do it all all the time right
but it's very difficult to sit there and
game that system at scale right you know
their attacks generally have to be
remote and that complicates things right
if you've got voting machines that are
offline you know it's really hard to be
on the other half other side of the
planet
voting machines at least on election day
you know you're relying on doing fishing
- maybe I'll click update firmware right
but we'll talk about voting machines in
a little bit right you know you know and
I said all of you I'm sure have done
political littered literature stuff in
your dorm right it is one of the
cheapest forms of political
communication there is but they can't
really do that right they can't do a
normal neighborhood influence stuff pay
some nine fifty bucks a day to leaflet
an entire neighborhood that's just not
something that that's available to them
but they do have something so far and
that's what we're gonna talk about so
we're going to start with this kind of
premise right because there's a lot of
conversation about think news the New
York Times did some reporting Thursday
and Friday about Facebook and Twitter
bots and the like right you know as far
as influence operations go right in a
highly polarized and politicized society
in which we find ourselves right now
right is a lot of people look at things
from the prism of their own confirmation
bias I'm not going to ask you to raise
hands but I bet there are people in this
room that watch MSNBC and do not watch
Fox News and there are some people who
watch fox news are not MSNBC right and
there are probably good reasons for it
but in you know the point right it's
confirmation bias so when you start
spreading going stories like you saw
from world politics you know Russia or
US intelligence officials discover no
links between Russia and Donald Trump
right
odds are depending on your political
persuasion and the less educated you are
the more true this tends to be you're
going to believe something based on what
you already believe right it is very
difficult to get people to change their
minds in a polarized society which is
both a positive
in the sense of it's really hard to
influence the American public because we
already have our minds made up when it
comes to politics anyway
but it's a calm because well you know we
kind of are on a self-destructive cycle
right now so Russian sources spent
$100,000 on Facebook ads on some of
those things for fake names and you saw
you know an example of that right they
attribute that to the Russian government
I really be fascinated how Facebook
could make that determination that they
did you know and you know there are
things you know on Bernie Sanders pages
saying you know basically never Hillary
messages post primary that is also being
attributed by Russia but did it really
change anybody's minds I don't think so
but they're really good and then figured
out how to start exploiting this problem
with us kiss lyac until recently was the
Russian ambassador to the United States
if you know anything about embassies
that is where official cover espionage
takes place every embassy in the world
no matter what country you're in or what
country that embassy belongs to is the
most surveilled piece of real estate
ever
so when kiss later makes a call to
Moscow on an open unencrypted line he is
not talking to Moscow he is talking to
us right and said hey look you know
Trump wants a back-channel to Moscow
properly leads by our intelligence
community put into the media and based
on confirmation bias people are saying
see we have proof now that may be an
entirely possible the Trump
administration wanted back-channel the
rush I don't know I wasn't in the room
but kiss me act reporting that over an
open channel
that was him directly in
directly communicating with our media
and the people to rustle our jimmies and
it worked
you know Jimmy's were full-on ruffled
and he's done that more than once
explicitly to communicate to the
American people from his office in the
Russian embassy right how to get people
to change their votes right I want to do
an influencer operation where you know
what I can make sure Hillary Clinton
wins or Donald Trump wins or whatever
preferred congressman wins right next
level stuff because I'll get to this
point at the end
Russia is learning our system they are
learning what we do they're learning as
they go to try to manipulate us to get
better outcomes for their national
interest right and I don't say that with
moral judgment of course they would do
that they're our nation nations act in
their own self-interest and a lot of the
time Russian interests and American
interests don't line up right so they're
going to try to get a better deal for
themselves to an extent we do that to
other countries in the world to I it is
easy to get somebody to hate somebody
else this is a facet of human nature why
are most political ads negative we don't
like politicians wearing this like they
hate them it's very easy to make
you hate no politician I cannot create
an ad campaign that will make you love
and admire a congressman there are a lot
of reasons for that up to and including
many are just not admirable people right
you know but our political biases even
if there were we would be disinclined to
believe it right but overtly negative
campaigning has a backlash so instead of
campaigning against right your target
right I'm not going to give I want
Hillary funded ludus I'm not going to
campaign against Hillary Clinton
I'm going to campaign in inflammatory
ways right and we'll talk about a couple
examples but the first targeting you
know you need to communicate a message
right to the most easily persuade scible
people you have some raw tools for
Facebook to do that I don't think the
Russians used it at this time but
they're learning right I could try to
play a little persuasion interest
geography there's a whole platform based
I can micro target you know I'm going to
display this act to this kind of person
right President Obama when he was
elected in 2008 did a lot of the same
thing that is called revolutionize in
politics where I am giving messages to
specific people based on my ability are
based on a message most likely to
influence this class of people right all
of our political consultants and
campaigns are engaged in influence
operations of their own right they just
happen to be Americans and they accept
that right so focus on data that allows
the ones most likely to change their
votes there hasn't been a lot of
discussion that voter records have been
breached what most people don't realize
is I can buy the voting records of every
American in this country it is so on the
open market there are companies like the
one reference than the headline below
that not only sell who votes republic
who votes Democrat who's a swing voter
who votes and primaries and generals
right they included 48 different
ideological preferences so I could say
this person's pro-life this person for
instance has traditional family values
so that if I decide to run in propagate
a propaganda campaign saying a next
candidate is gay those might be the
people have when I directed to all of
this stuff is public they can buy there
is no law to stop them from buying them
because people buy all the time it's
sold on the open market when to act most
of Russia's intervention in our election
was in the general I cross up this first
line because most people think of
elections I can vote for whoever I want
well I mean I guess strictly that's true
right you can write in anybody if
there's a right of mine but when you get
to the general all the important
decisions are made Donald Trump was a
Republican candidate Hillary Clinton was
a Democratic candidate if you didn't
like those choices tough nummies right
we have already whittled down the number
of candidates there's a 136 million
voters in the general between the two
parties 54 million right less than half
the smaller the number the more
influence all right what if I would have
influenced the primary so that Bernie
Sanders would have won instead of
Hillary Clinton but the election have
been much different because I
they are nice and errs would have
followed Hillary Clinton's hawkish line
in Russia and not being an expert on his
foreign policy but that is how they
played in France a little bit because
they have this jungle primary system
where if nobody gets to 50% then it's a
runoff between the last two which is how
marine lepen
was one of their candidates you only had
to get somebody to 20% to determine the
outcome I'm so easier influenced more
elections do it do it earlier so
examples of what how do you can change
somebody's mind right how many people
have enjoyed a robocall they've ever
received and I am seeing not a single
hand having run for office once whenever
my staff let a robocall go to a
household after 8 p.m.
I got deference detail specific death
threats not like you called me I'm gonna
kill you right the kind of deference is
like do I need to get state the State
Police to protect my family kind of pets
people get out of their mind map