if I were running robocalls
for DeWitt Clinton after 8:00 p.m. on
any weekday and all weekend long people
would be out of their mind mad and that
would cost $40 a line analytics server
running asterisk which by the way comes
caller ID so I can make it look like
it's coming from a million American
Hillary for America's campaign office
because we believe caller ID is accurate
it is a trivially spoofed thing there is
not a person in this room whose caller
ID I cannot smooth right now right and
it's trivial to do it with an aspect
server right now I've engendering part
negative feelings another example right
many kneeling shops and print shops take
orders from the internet all I have to
do is have a Visa card and saying here's
a PDF of my mail piece here are the
addresses I want to mail it to do a
harshly negative one that causes
backlash I will give you an example in
the state of Illinois south of
Springfield there is a young woman
running for State Representative we
don't really know who sent out this mail
piece but it included a photo shop of a
somewhat less than clothed version of
her that campaign ended with that mail
piece because people were so mad I don't
think it was her or anybody involved
with her but somebody did it because
they're a jerk right but people blame
the other guy for it it didn't matter
what the facts were that race ended
right there seven weeks before the
election even happened I am that guy her
opponent right thar for life right so
easy way to change people's mind because
they hate this stuff
right for good reason right that was a
very obnoxious male beast but I hear the
Russian government and
don't care what happens to the
candidates afterwards this is something
accessible to you and we can do nothing
to prevent it right even if a print shop
whose job is to run Xerox machines knew
that it was a Russian buyer what could
we do to say you should not do that yes
the steel dossier
[Music]
does this feel dull so you never really
got out there before the election and a
big enough way for that I think there
are other reasons for why that was
created and I think the I I don't think
that was the Russians or maybe maybe it
was them having fun yeah yeah so there's
a lot of questions I have about that one
so I don't have any conclusions for that
one but it was so transparently an
easily provable false right hi
you know Trump's lawyer went to Prague
on this date to meet with Russian
officials okay I'm gonna have a pen up
and have a press release I press give my
passport I'm a lawyer working for a real
estate mogul don't have access to a lot
of legitimate thank passports cuz I work
for the CIA
who makes those right what are we
talking about here which is why it's
very dangerous to use fake information
because it very quickly can be disproven
in a hoax right which is how it was in
that case what that was about I don't
know for sure precisely
based on this week's event right as a
humorous example Equifax got hacked the
repository of every American's financial
data right in the country now we they
say credit reports weren't hat and of
course I've been trying to believe a big
business who got caught with their pants
down saying no I'm sure they're telling
the truth now and that's sarcasm right
but if I were the Russian government I'd
be buying congressman's crap credit
reports and comparing that to their
financial disclosures in capitalism
lists all of their debts and assets
I find big discrepancies and congressmen
start getting thrown out of office
that's an influence operation hi there
voting machines and I'll say this really
brief because I'm kind of getting close
to time here right we focus a lot about
voting machines but I've been doing
security for a long time and in no case
except for voting machines have I ever
seen the response to security saying you
know what let's pull back and not put
more technology into this stuff voting
machine vendors are explicitly creating
paper trails and selling based on that I
forget the precise worthies but electric
electronic voting machines they will not
use that term anymore because it makes
it less likely for them to sell it right
so Virginia just yesterday or late late
this week as these certified touchscreen
voting machines we have lots of paper
trails involved and I speak a lot of an
Illinois answer system I know the best
but we have electronic not voting
machines but tabulators you feed in your
ballot accounts out the numbers you know
on Election Day when the polls close
that count we issued 500 ballots there
500 ballots in the box done we go home
but after the election before the
results are certified they pick randomly
3% of all the voting machines this
machine
these results were going to come by hand
could I physically access a machine to
manipulate the counting Mecca down
methodology and not get caught but that
would be impressive doing it remotely
right but I do it in such a way to trip
and get passed as 3% audit and not find
discrepancies you know I'm not going to
say never but we're getting to pretty
pretty rare there are non technical
controls on this process right but you
know go to an example right teacher-man
give a man a zero day on voting machine
yeah maybe it influence an election for
one day but social engineering is by and
large the biggest part of security
because it works right one of our
biggest defenses for election hacking is
there's thousands of independent
election authorities all that do there's
different things they have their own
process they haven't they picked their
own vendors within a subset of what
they're allowed to do how do you
compromise that systematically that is
very hard
prior to 2016 weakly figure out a way to
systematically protect them it was to
organizationally complex so but like I
said we are we are never and I
encountered what we we pull back from
using technology like we are from voting
machines creating paper trails that even
if you compromised all the technology
and somehow you know get past it on
election
we're going to find it we can count it
all by hand and figure out the sauce
what we did wrong I referenced it we
said they were successful Russia wanted
to say our to undermine our institutions
we undermine them France pull thorwald
of cold water on this thing
the French citizens are like and have
them whatever moved on right very
different response in different outcomes
so some takeaways Russians and learning
other nations are getting in the game
the techniques the Russians used are not
outside the scope of much more beyond
what anonymous to do right Iran could do
this North Korea could do this China can
do this and they all took notice because
it inspired a self-destructive cycle
than us right other nations can get on
that getting on that game too any
questions behind you first okay yeah
well one thing I think of its polls you
know we had that period of time when you
know the third party got to 15% in the
organizations that do polls you know
these are just you know it gotta be
pretty easy to have there Joseph call
centers so is anybody looking at those
of looking at whether there may have
been any attempts so the question is was
there any manipulation of the poll the
pollsters directly for like debate
inclusion and things of that sort and
the short answer is I don't think
anybody's looking at it in part because
most of the stuff took place after the
primary when there's our minds you know
like with the 17 Republican candidates
well loan in that and that's fair right
what pollsters are looking at is go back
that was not the outcome the pollsters
know they got something profoundly wrong
and I argue the point was consistently
wrong throughout the whole cycle but
that's an assumption
do they know there are flaws that they
need to fix because if you can't trust
the polls why are people paying them
money so they're looking for
systemically buy everything's wrong I
would imagine they would find that a
biggest governor I don't think they're
looking for that specifically but
they're trying to figure out why that
was not the US China on defined
institutions our intelligence centers
like that that guy from the Russian
embassy knows that he could talk
directly to the American people because
our intelligence we talk about our
polling organizations and yet we have
the media
we get fitted stuff don't you
we talk about a politician no need for
leaders we talk about our voting
I mean how a budding records being for
sale do I mean those are all things new
slides how have to what could this
happen they have to be well and that's
the point right
and basically the question is most of
our institutions are any compromise
already how hard do they really have to
work and the answer is not very right if
I really respect somebody or an
institution right I less than Klein to
believe that information unless I
believe that that information is true
and even then compromise confirmation
bias being strong as it is I may not
even believe that it's true right but
yes our politicians are scandal plagued
our pollsters were wrong our
intelligence community is leaking
top-secret classified stuff to the media
and the media reports on it yes if era
go right we are our own worst enemy I
[Music]
just don't know how to tell Congress in
a way that they would cactus you guys
really should adopt some ethical
standard I I don't much care what it is
as long as it's not the Church of Satan
right anything other than that pick
something and stop stealing money and
baby right but we see congressmen
indicted every couple years right
Aaron shots on file and not far from
here you know and there's plenty of
legal corruption right yeah I we
undermine ourselves but I mean yeah the
Roman Empire didn't die because the
barbarians rated it I mean it was
corrupt as well yes ma'am
[Music]
Wasserman Schultz in that there is more
to come on that story of which I can
only speculate that we very dangerous
for me to speculate but except to say at
a certain point if I had an employee
that was accused of what he was accused
of and active had an arrest warrant
I doubt he would remain mindfully
anything more than say as long as it
took me to call HR why that situation
persistent as long as it does I have no
idea I am just I'm interested to figure
that out right but yeah right I don't
know the next few yeah any other
questions
all right thank you you've got time too
[Applause]