foreign
and welcome to to this presentation uh
now we are going to to speak about uh
bypassing antiviruses using bad dsb
uh this presentation will be mostly
Technical and we will tackle the the
Windows Defender
um and basically I know that this was a
very very very long day for everyone so
I'll try to not bore you some
um some very technical topics so two
words about myself I'm a penetration
tester founder of a cyber security
company part of the S certified ethical
hacker committee and I'm also a speaker
and trainer for multiple organizations
all over the world and in time I also
speak to some conferences like those and
write some articles on me
and the agenda for today would be how we
can buy the MCI which is the the
protocol used for one second which is
the protocol used for Windows Defender
um to to check this to check the
malicious files that we try to run uh
next we'll check how can we bypass this
policy in order to to run those scripts
uh to to build the payload runner in
which through which we will insert our
payload directly into the memory and how
can we put everything together on a
little bit USB and demo also included
running on a Windows Defender up-to-date
version
and the scenario is the following
uh Bob uh went in the parking lot he
found on USB next to uh to his car
took that USB to his computer introduced
it he was just curious
and now an attacker is connected to top
computer
uh how would that be possible because
Bob had and is having antivirus running
more specifically Windows Defender
um and Bob is a privilege user within
the the organization so how that
happened uh and before moving forward I
want to to ask you how many of you I
still rely on Windows Defender
hands up
okay okay how many of you do you think
it's it's a good choice
okay
that's fine uh expected as expected so
uh also we have a policy in place for
our organization that disallows USBS to
be into into
um computers more specifically removable
media storage
what happened we'll see during this this
presentation
uh the the sequence of attacks that has
been performed on the on the Bob
computer are the following firstly
attacker evaded armsy in order to run
the the script uh then execution policy
bypass
payload Runner is being inserted
directly into the memory so we have a
files uh payload there and post
exploitation he migrated to to another
legit process in order to not be caught
firstly we will go into details
regarding MC bypass methods
uh this this technology works as a man
in the middle uh interface between our
antivirus and the Powershell script or
other scripts that we are running on our
computers and if we find a way to
disable it of course with low privileged
accounts if we find a way to disable it
we can run any malicious scripts that we
we want on the on the computers uh and
it is usually used with third-party
antiviruses in order to provide a
scanning interface between the scripts
and the engine and technically speaking
uh it uses the armscan buffer function
from the library amc.dll so if we find a
way to manipulate the returning results
of this function we may find a way to to
totally disable or to tamper with it in
order to return a result that every time
it scans for a file it will return that
file is legit that file is valid and is
not flagged as malicious how can we do
that
firstly we will do a Powershell script
and we will Define multiple API
functions within the the Powershell
script uh why we need this sequence here
is that because uh Powershell does not
know uh c-sharp and what we are doing
here is basically uh c-sharp so we are
defining those functions in C sharp and
then translating them to to Powershell
using the add type method
and then we we load the amc.dll library
in memory in order to to manipulate with
the functions within it as you can see
we Define get proc address loader
library and virtual protect
those functions will use to manipulate
the MC scan buffer function and the
first one that we are using here to load
the library uh is actually the download
Library functions uh Windows API
function
next we have the amc.dll we need to
extract the function from dmc.dll we
will uh use the get proc art or get proc
address a function in order to to
retrieve the ampsy scan buffer method
and then we need to make it writable we
need to make it writable in order to
tamper with the return address of the of
the function for that case we'll use
Virtual protect in order to to change
the permissions to uh to allow us to
tamper with the with the function
and after that we need to create the
value that will be replaced every time
the function is being called against a
file or against the script this value
here uh is 0 x 8 0 0 7 0 0 5 7 it
doesn't make any sense for now but we'll
see why it's uh it's a very important
return value
during the next slide next
using Marshall copy we are doing a
replacement of the of the result
and why this value should be should be
replaced for the ampscan buffer result
Let's Take a Look Over the official
documentation for amsyscan buffer
function and we can see that it takes uh
an ampsi result as the output if this
output uh succeeds if the function
itself succeeds scanning the file it
will return as underscore okay if the
function does not succeed it will return
on age result error code
why is the why is this a problem in
Windows
the problem is that
by default if we think securely if the
arms is gone buffer function would crash
would return an error
the file should not permit it to run
but by default in Windows the file is
being run when the armscan buffer
function return an error code
so we'll make the the function to return
an error code our error code is this one
eight zero zero seven zero zero five
seven we'll see also the documentation
for this code
so that's that's also flow within
windows by itself
and
the value of the of the error code it
says that one or more arguments are
invalid we can take any error code that
we we want but this one is pretty pretty
effective so there is the uh the age
result documentation on on Microsoft
official page we can take any value uh
this one seemed to to work without any
uh additional manual interventions so
if we make the function sorry if we made
the function return this this error code
uh we may have the file running we may
have bypassed the the antivirus
and this is our final uh arms bypass
payload
let me ask you something what do you
think it is missing here
this one is being being caught by most
of the antiviral Solutions
so we need to do an extra step
for it oh
okay
we'll apply authentication we can apply
this obfuscation using
um using the invoke obfuscation built
from from Powershell it can be found
also on on GitHub it's a it's a function
that applies layers of obfuscation over
our Powershell scripts and this is the
first part of our exploit the arms
bypass we successfully bypassed the
um the main in the middle between our
antiviral and the scripts that we are
running
next execution policy bypass what is
this execution policy bypass by default
Windows does not permit users low
privileged users to run Powershell
scripts that are unsigned by an official
provider such as Microsoft
but unfortunately
windows allow us as low privileged user
to disable the execution policy for our
user
so attackers may just disable the
execution policy using this one line
command
for the user that they are targeting we
cannot disable it for the for the
machine itself but we can disable it for
the user that we are running the the
script within that context of which in
our case is Bob so the attacker uh
disabled the execution policy or for Bob
and the third step within our uh within
a payload development would be the
runner what is this Runner uh the runner
allows us to insert the uh
shellcode.payload directly into the
memory without having any additional
files
is firstly we will Define a lookup func
in order to search for assembly
references later within our payload uh
we don't have enough time but this this
function as a summary these functions uh
check the the system check the system
for any assembly references that will
take later into into our payload and use
them
get delegate type this function should
be should be defined within Powershell
because Powershell does not know some
argument types that are used commonly in
C sharp for example pointer partial does
not know about the C sharp pointer so we
need the function that defines all those
types
then we have the actual payload Runner
which injects our final shell code to
the into the memory
we take a unwritable memory we allocate
it within within the machine
using uh using virtual lock that we just
defined previously
then we generate the payload for example
using msv Venom a simple metal printer
payload that is that is caught by by any
antivirus
today like it's very very basic
and then inject that using Marshall copy
into our previously allocated memory
space
and we can we can invoke it later and
here we are using the get delegate type
to
um
to provide Arguments for the invoke
function argument types that are not
known Powershell but they are they are
defined in C sharp like uh pointers and
integers so we we take that and we
provide them as Arguments for our invoke
function
and now uh we should put everything on
on a small device and let me bring the
the small device real quick
foreign
so we have this small device right here
which looks like the normal USB like
real normal USB and we can put
everything that we've seen previously on
this device
so
firstly you remember that the the
payload was successfully run but the
organization had policies to restrict
removable media storage so why why did
it
actually this is not a removable media
storage
it's a simulation of a mouse and a
keyboard here we have an Arduino
Arduino board within the USB that takes
the keyboard.hash and mouse.hash
functions to libraries sorry those
libraries and takes the functions from
those to simulate
choice of insert some keystrokes or to
move the mouse of the compromised of the
compromised user
how can we how can you we develop
Scripts
actually we have two options we can use
the digi spark scripts which are Arduino
uh screen and they are they are scripted
in C plus plus or we can docky script
those documents are mainly used for
rubber ducky payloads which are similar
to to those bad USBS but they are more
expensive than a bad USB because a bad
USB can be bought for like one dollar or
maximum two dollars while rubber duckies
can be bought for 20 30 depending on
where you are located in the world so
those are much uh much cheaper but they
came from China so you need to
investigate a little bit for before with
them for example mine had the command
and control reverse callback to
the addresses so I had to test it within
a local sandbox
and uh going back to our discussion
we'll use the the docky script we'll
code our final payload in docky script
and we'll transform it to digispark
and using this uh dakuino which is an
open source project can be found uh
through GitHub and you just insert the
docky script and then it will compile
into Arduino code
bed USB uh and darkest
what is the the Syntax for developing
payloads using uh docky Scripts
if the the string variable which what we
type after the string will be typed by
our USB we have also delays we have the
the repeat Loop which allows us to uh to
run the last command multiple times we
we must insert our special keys that we
see on the keyboard like enter tab shift
control as they are typed on our
keyboard we insert them into into our
payload without the string without the
string variable and the Windows key will
be
um
must be inserted as a guy
command and in order to
to temper with the with the mouse
locations will use Mouse underscore move
uh and the coordinates of the of the
mouse and L mouse or air mouse and M
Mouse are corresponding to the mouse
buttons
and some tips regarding post
exploitation that we can do after this
attack succeeds
we can migrate our reverse shell to to
process such explorer.x or explorer.tex
because it's a very very common uh
process and it is usually
left running uh non-stop on the on the
target computer
and Metasploit can help us using the the
migrate command
and let's let's move forward with the
demo just one second to prepare
everything
okay so uh to explain you a bit we have
here a command and control endpoint that
will be that we'll use for uh our as our
listener and we have the the compromise
machine which is uh local Windows 10
machine with a real-time protection on
from Windows Defender
and firstly we'll use the uh Metasploit
framework to
to start a listener in the upcoming
seconds and we'll insert the debate USB
to see how how it works with the Windows
Defender up and running
foreign
USB
and we wait for it to to load but it has
been inserted I'm not doing anything
this is a proof of concept that's uh it
is slow just to show you the the payload
and we are waiting a bit
and there we got a shot a metal platter
report shell Windows Defender fully
fully running
and that's that's basically the the
purpose of this exploitation
uh what we can do next we can migrate to
another process in order to not be
caught or just uh insert another another
payload
so and as you can see it's it's also a
metal printer so it should be it should
be caught by by most of the antivirus
Solutions but the the
payload was successfully running we
disabled uh the OMSI and here here we
are and you can drop those uh bad USPS
like in the parking lots or at the mall
at a very crowded uh station and things
of the nature
and you know what's the the dangerous
part about it that uh I have researched
and it's working
it is working with office macros also
and like when I say working it's
actually working with most of the
antivirus Solutions
and one second to switch to the
presentation
okay so what is the prevention for those
attacks firstly Microsoft should update
their solution or the antivirus products
should update their Solutions uh but for
us as administrators or security
Engineers we should disable Powershell
for end users we should have access
control lists on Mac based specific uh
White listing for the for the USB ports
and we should move our we should shift
our perspective from from running
antiviruses for our endpoints to a more
advanced solution like an endpoint
protection or ADR xdr and things of the
nature and security awareness training
for for the end users
some research and statistics about this
exploitation because we cannot name it
really a vulnerability
we can call it an exploitation thing
was reported to Microsoft they said that
it's basically not a not an issue
because it requires a lot of user
interaction
like what user interaction do do you
expect like
there was a USB on the uh on the floor
and the user picked it up and then there
was a reverse shell like two user
interactions pick the USB or insert the
USB you don't want to pick up the USB
good just deliver it directly to the
user then you have one user interaction
needed uh the the payload was tested on
20 antivirus vendors uh seven on of them
allowed us to to spawn a reversal matter
Predator reversion then to load mimikets
directly into the into the memory uh
nine
sorry nine of them allowed Us only for a
normal reversal but that's good also so
that's good uh
and four of them blocked the entire
attempt of exploitation the the attempt
was caught during the MC bypass through
Behavior Analysis
and thank you very much