foreign
good evening everyone I'll be speaking
and doing this presentation in English
and the topic for today I believe it's
one of the
most interesting ones in the uh
kind of new trends
we're going to speak about secure
destroys oci images we're going to
Define first of all what is an oci image
what is this true list and what makes
this combination secure by all means uh
we also going to explore our approach to
a new way of building what we have used
to call Docker images via Docker files
and we're going to perform this action
via ammo files so we're going to focus
on what the first presenter uh Bojo has
talked about about the containers and
how nothing is secure in the container
world and at the same time we're going
to leverage this we're going to look
through some exploits and a lot of
interesting stuff
um first of all I kind of reminded
myself to introduce myself and so I'm
Victor bonif and I'm part of VMware
carbon black team uh carbon black is the
team that manages cyber security inside
VMware and we kind of develop a lot of
those Solutions which are the xdr MDR
EDR uh words that you have heard about
the previous presentations as well
I'm a senior developer and I'm very
happy to be here and discuss gather
opinion from each one of you and
hopefully you can learn something that's
good and uh kind of the companies look
for a lot
let's go through the the table of
contents so first of all we're going to
focus on what is oci we're going to
Define it we're going to have a little
bit of a brainstorm with our view then
we're going to speak about the oci
isolation so we're going to do a crash
course which is 101 crash course which
you used to have at the University
understand what is c groups what is file
system and the container aspect talk
about the change route or sea root and
namespaces
then on the third chapter we're going to
show some exploits and we're going to
take a brief overview of the key moments
that have happened in the past year of
course many things have happened I'm not
going to show all of the exploits but
this I'm going to focus on the more
interesting ones
and based on the previous presentation
we had a bit of chat about Alpine Linux
so we're going to talk about Alpine
Linux loved by many hated by even more
so we're going to understand why is that
the case
uh then we're going to talk about this
release what makes this release image
and it's yeah it is a lot of uh
interesting topic and we're going to
focus on the on the last chapter we're
going to talk about project Micron or
michaelian also it is a project that we
try to develop internally inside VMware
carbon black and it is our approach to
solving some of the issues which we will
outline during this presentation with LV
together
so let's talk about oci what is oci it
is the open container initiative what
you have all referred to Containers
Dockers images
that is basically oci and that's the
right way to refer to the container
world it is an oci image it's not a
Docker image it's not a podman image
it is the open container initiative
that's the standard wire of
you know how those things that we're
going to talk about are based upon
so we're going to have a little bit of
introduction what is this all about
you're most familiar I personally I
believe that you're familiar with Docker
you have heard it during this
presentation you know what is it about
and uh Docker is very popular
historically it has been here for
maybe a little bit less than 10 years
yeah cool
well kind of I guess that right all
right so the next platform for oci
images and I'm not going to refer as
containers is kubernetes of course and I
want to pay attention to all of you that
those are totally two separate things no
matter that they handle containers in
the same way
they're totally isolated we're going to
look why is that the case
first of all if you follow you know all
those containers by behind the word
container there are a lot of services
and software behind and sub-components
so we have to break down what this is
all about what is behind that structure
that makes
isolated environments unique and why is
it so popular
so behind Docker there is a container G
which is the
container demon basically behind that's
the
um
basically you can refer to it as an
engine but it's actually a demon that
does the work for you to spawn and
basically handle behind the curtains uh
and in preparation for the next step
on the other hand for kubernetes
kubernetes does not run on containerdy
by default it used to have Docker shim
which was removed it's no longer the
case and kubernetes uses a different
runtime
uh demon it's called cryo or you can
also see it as as CRI as well that's
container runtime interface
uh and cryo was supposed to be a very
lightweight
uh very performance oriented
container runtime interface so there are
more than this one uh but we're not
going to observe the rest we're going to
focus on those two
so uh what comes after those demons uh
of course that is the open container
initiatives so uh dopen container
initiative sets a standard of what a
container is you can think of it as a
protocol even though it is not but the
same way of how for example
TCP is defined in a big protocol in a
RFC yeah it's very different but you can
think of it of an analogy what makes a
container you have to have a a checksum
you have to have a file system you know
a lot of stuff that needs to be there in
order so we can call a container
understandable by container D and by
order container runtime interfaces
it's a set of standards that we have our
agreed upon and it's being
a continuously developed updated so keep
in mind the containers of today's might
be totally different from the containers
of tomorrow
since all of those run times and
container runtime interfaces keeps
developing new features come in and
that's why we need to certify
pretty much every three years this holds
for kubernetes as well so in order to
get a certificate and say a certified
kubernetes administrator I have to
certify every every three years due to
the fact that everything changes pretty
much everything a lot of those things
changes maybe not the core ones but a
lot of those stuff change so what what
is after oci and what comes after oci is
basically run C
run C if I'm not mistaken was first
introduced in 2015
it was version 0.1
and this is the executable
or maybe is curable is not the right
word but it's the runtime of how your
containers are being run in the Linux
world
and run C takes always a Json
configuration if you have worked with
containers you have probably seen that
you have to
provide a Docker file in order to build
stuff and you have a lot of from run uh
a lot of commands which are integrated
and those commands basically bundle
different Json files it could be a Json
file for the networks it could be a Json
file for your volume mounts so all those
configurations and pretty much in the
dockerwood uh everything is in in Json
uh there's b-zone as well everything
fits to run C it basically runs C
executes
all of those things all together as a
big chain
so that you can have what you have
called container so far
that's how it works behind the box in a
short summary without
the details but this would do just fine
for our demonstrations later on the
showcases which I have prepared for you
what I want to take from our view
together and if you
have to remember something is always
question the whatever you come across
that doesn't apply only to containers
and kubernetes Docker whatever you use
always question
how this works and by no means those are
magical services or software which are
unique something is happening and if you
don't know the answer to it there is a
very high chance that you'll be
exploited
why you can be exploited due to the fact
that you don't know the stuff behind it
simply as that
this was stated by some presenter I
don't know who
so how it works understanding those
pieces of software that do Leverage The
Linux kernel system and its components
alongside with it attributes is the key
and as famously as the engineering from
the Mandalorian have said it this is the
way and this holds for everything does
not apply only to oci containers to
kubernetes you have to understand the
concepts
so we're going to talk about the oeci
isolation what I'm going to do without
you with our view is a crash course 101
what makes sort of you probably have
heard again uh why use containers in a
company or if you ask someone in person
well they provide an isolated
environment and my question will be oh
how so so in order to understand how
that happens
you might have heard you might have gone
to the next level and probably heard
well containers are a bunch of c groups
and namespaces but
what I have witnessed is that the
questions about c groups and namespaces
also are unanswered for most part so I
wanted to show you and I I know that it
might not be very visible which I'm
I did my best but uh the kernel future
basically c groups or control groups
those are native kind of features and
they provide resources isolation for
example imagine you want to run a
process and you want to allocate only
256 megabytes of memory to that process
you can do this via control group
uh all of them resides under CIS slash
FS C group what is unique is that you
you can create your own c groups on most
Linux distributions uh they're already
predefined c groups those are mostly
your memory management CPU uh something
that's related with network something
that's related with volume mounts and
you already probably map the features
that Docker provide are not so unique
we've got some Docker or or kubernetes
basically what is exposed through a lot
of its Flags is actually goes to the
native kernel feature which is C group
of course container D and cryo which is
a container runtime interface leverage
this via flag and I'm going just to
spell uh say out loud what is written
below so I can do a Portman run or
equivalent podman is different flavor of
it's a different software similar to
Docker I can do podman run with detached
mode with uh hypnd and allocate uh minus
m flag which will limit my memory usage
to 256 megabytes and I'm going to spawn
on nginx
and latest nginx container what it's
going to do is create a
a separate C group under my
parent process ID which is podman
because podman course container D and
it's it has it already knows the
namespace isolation which we're going to
talk in the next Slide the namespace
isolation will be your container
checksum and you have spawn containers
you have observed that every container
has a unique checksum a unique shot
so basically what you use to reflex is
controlling c groups and basically
you're controlling kernel features
there's no magic behind it
and in that case if I simply Echo the
value I will see that I have allocated
uh
like a 2 million 68
000 bytes yeah the equivalent in bytes
for 256 megabytes
and it's present in my file system
so we're going to
take to the next level and talk about
namespaces
as you recall
containers basically namespace in c
groups so namespaces what are those
those are even more important those are
kernel features for resource partition
partitioning into set of processes
um
if you compare this to c groups the c
groups limits the resource usage while
on the other hand the namespaces limits
the resource a process can see
what do you mean by that imagine you go
to a shell into some server
and you know just simply through that I
can execute again I will run a container
I'll do podman run with an interactive
mode again with the same nginx latest
image I'm going to execute a shell this
will basically uh I'm going to use the
no term don't use it SSH into the
Container basically involve a bone sound
bone shell session and I can list
namespaces so the command to do that is
lsns
and I can see there are different
namespaces each comes with an unique ID
you can see it on the left column
and there is a type of namespaces so we
have now understand that there are
namespaces and the different types of
namespaces what is listed here we have
time we have user we have net we have
Mount we have UTC which is related to
the universal time we have IPC which is
inter-process communication we have pit
which we you have heard in the previous
presentation you know what Piet is for
sure and you have C group out of those
uh namespaces
have Associated bit Associated user and
what command has access to what
namespace
so now we're going to the more a bit in
depth
namespaces
two
and we're going to talk about what those
kind of namespaces are and it's very
important to understand the namespaces
so we can provide security for our
containers if we don't know that we can
say that our container is secure so we
have Mount we have process ID we have
Network again interpros communication
IPC Unix time sharing system
UTC user ID and a control group
so
what is odat means
well it all follows that those are
simply attack vectors
those are the primary targets of how you
can
exploit a container and we're going to
observe some of those exploits that do
leverage this some of those namespaces
not all but at least some
and you can see that there are a lot of
attack vectors nothing again if you
refer to the the first presentation for
today maybe nothing is secure let's see
containers do use namespaces to
partition different resources imagine I
want to run a podman with a BusyBox
image I'm just going to give you uh an
idea what busy box is BusyBox is one of
the most lightweight
images it's not a distribution by any
means it's a type of a Linux image where
all of your essential commands that the
previous presenter have shown AOS cat
Echo uh
then netstat whatever you can think of
ipss those are how bundled into one uh
executable which is kind of a a greater
uh set of those commands so they are not
built each one by one they're bundled
into one there is busy box and there is
another flavor you might have heard it's
called Toy Box same principle
you out of your Linux command that you
have used during your terminal sessions
are basically bundled into one
executable and once you refer it
there is something that's happening
that's closely to soft links and the
soft links basically refer to different
parts of the binary so you can command
can run safely so what we do here that's
what BusyBox is
and we execute a shell
what this does is it's going to create a
separate namespace that will allocate my
hostname and you know that if you spawn
a container you see some checksum or
maybe you don't see checks I mean
depends on how this is configured and
executed through runc and containerdy
but usually behind you there is a
hostname that's being created Network
different types of c groups and a
process apparent process ID
so
I can list you know I've now I'm into
the Container interactively so I can
interact from within
so I can type yes and see what my
processes are and currently there is not
much not much of it going on I have
shell and I have PS those are both
root owned by root but what happens if I
execute another shell so this
if I execute another shell this will
basically do shell within shell and if I
do PS I will see that I have two shells
so what is strange about this
that I'm in my child shell process but
I'm able to see the parent one
observe here that my process idea is
number one
and if I invoke shell again I have a
different process ID and this is the
active one which is three
but then I also am able to see the
parent process ID which is in that case
one that's the parent from which I have
originated from
and even if I spawn a PS3 which is same
as three for file system but for
processes I'm able to see that shell is
my parent with Pros id1 I'm currently
running on on the child process with bit
number three and I've executed PS3 and
that have allocated me uh process ID 11.
so it is strange we're going to see why
and before we go into the detail I want
to do with our views on brainstorm and
there is a simple process inheritance uh
on the left we have a cluster it could
be a Docker machine
it could be a kubernetes cluster
it's some sort of a cluster where many
nodes or containers can run either
through container D or through cryo for
kubernetes and I have basically spawned
a very traditional showcase I have my
backend I have my nginx it doesn't
matter where they run on containerd or
they run on cryo I have four containers
and I have my back end I have my nginx I
have front end I have some metrics for
logging uh which that's how it I love to
do things there was a separate container
that's responsible for logging it
doesn't interfere when I update
so imagine here that I have exposed for
my nginx port 443
and through kubernetes this is quite uh
easy to do you have either cluster IP or
you have node IP for your exposure there
is another type of exposure but we're
mostly focusing on this ones so for that
case that is a note Port basically your
Port is exposed and can be uh you know
you can interact with it
so my question to all of you is what is
the worst scenario that can happen based
on that picture yeah you don't have to
use the mic if you have ideas please
raise your hand
yes so communicating with the
inter-process communication that's why
it is uh bad but it's not the worst but
it's a great observation
can we think about something else
any ideas
right
precisely
exactly so
this is the root of the problem and the
worst thing that can happen and there
were cases like that in Amazon in Google
in the major vendors for for clouds
and what has happened is that you can
escape outside of your container towards
the cluster and now not only you have
exploited like how I can do that imagine
I have a vulnerability which I can
exploit in nginx
it's rare it doesn't happen I know but
let's say it's not nginx it's software
that I have written so I can exploit
that it's either it could be buffer
overflow it could be used after free
those are two of the most commonly used
vulnerabilities that are being exploited
I load my shell and then I have access
but I have access only towards that
container so I'm isolated I can't see
what is the back end doing what is the
front end doing I have access to that
particular service and
you know miraculously
their issues and exploits that can allow
me not only to control that container
but I can take control over the whole
cluster and this is drawn exactly
through exploits that are targeted on c
groups and namespaces and uh mostly you
can Target container D you can Target
cryo
and you can get leverage of the cluster
and now you do not control only your own
data the cluster can have thousands of
notes and I don't know how many
containers uh maybe about 10 000 if it's
a big one and owned by the Enterprise
Corporation and I can I can control
pretty much everything
doesn't matter I have hole control
so I'm going to show you two of those
exploits which do leverage Linux type of
vulnerabilities the first actually the
both of them were discovered last year
uh the first one is CV 2022
0847 the second one is CV 2022
1085 and what is the CV just so we are
on Common Ground that's the common
vulnerability exploit so
notice the word common those are
vulnerabilities that we know that do
exist there are many that we don't know
that do exist
so what are those exploits the first one
main cause it is initialized by buffer
flag variable
and this is a future that's
uh in the uh in the kernel it's back in
the kernel that can be exploited
basically page cache is always credible
to the kernel imagine I have to write a
specific file but I do it in such way
and I can write a c program which I can
write a cache but while writing the cash
in a specific way of course I'll show
you how this looks like I can write a
cache without the kernel checking for my
permissions so this came actually from a
ticket the exploit is called uh dirty
pipe
you you have seen it probably in the
previous presentation one of those
presentations it was called dirty cow so
basically that's the successor
of that exploit
and what it does I can write for example
Etc uh password file and write it as a
cache replace it with my own password
elevate my privileges become root and
then restore it from a backup so you
know you wouldn't notice that those this
file has been written down and then
restored there's no way you can guess
that of course if you don't have some
kind of a audit monitoring of the
actions that have been performed the
second exploit is actually related to
the Heap based buffer overflow in Legacy
parse pyram function again it's a it's a
bug in the links kernel and what it does
is there are certain namespaces and the
certain namespaces have different
aspects that they can interact with
certain kind of futures or or kernel
classes
an unprivileged local user say I'm uh
non-root stating this clear I'm not root
and I want to enable my capsys admin
such that it opens its capsys admin is a
is a Linux kind of definition of
uh or something Legacy but it's we
trigger it so it can execute that Legacy
uh code and what it does it's open a
file system that does not support the
file system context API and then it
falls back to Legacy handling where we
hit that exact exploit so it's something
that's very similar what bonjour have
shown in the previous uh in the first
presentation with the printer there was
a printer that was printing something
that's uh for legacy you know how you
can send uh a gif on your phone and that
gif becomes PDF and your phone gets
exploited that's the same thing we're
triggering a legacy function that's I
don't know how many years old nobody
knew it existed
so a fast recap there is Docker there is
kubernetes those are two different
ecosystems and they run on different
demons one is containerd one is cryo and
what I want you to emphasize on is that
kubernetes and Docker do behave
differently
in the aspect of the runtime
so uh
what I'm going to show
I hope it's not very visible but I can
share the slides with our view after the
um the presentation I execute a busy box
image and I do a PS so I can see that my
uh process I have two bits both are
owned by root and I have 5 15 49 for my
Linux kernel version then I do an unsure
and that's on the docker provisioned
container when I do an unshare that's
basically detaching myself from another
namespace from the namespace and trying
to create a new one it says oh unshare
operation is not permitted that's on the
docker if I execute the same thing on
the kubernetes with the k run K is just
an alias for cube CTL k run interactive
same image busy box
shell it's the bone shell it's the same
shell and I try the same command unsure
it will run so what I wanted to
emphasize with this very
simple example is that they behave
differently if you test your application
in a Docker local environment and say
hey boss it's done we can deploy it to
the cluster I've checked everything
there is no way this can get exploited
kubernetes
do things differently
of course this has been a
much improved with the latest version of
kubernetes they are now
filters that you can leverage but you
can state that explicitly so you have to
know what you're doing
uh
so the lesson to take home is that they
behave differently kubernetes and docker
the next uh exploit that I wanted to
show you is dirty pipe dirty pipe is an
exploit which is the successor of the
recall it's where I can write a cache to
the Linux kernel without the Linux
kernel checking for my right permission
so I can write pretty much anything and
I can override the ETC password d file
so what I'm going to do here I have
created a scenario where I use pound cat
pound cat is a remote shell it's very
similar to uh probably some of you have
played with Metasploit and meterpreter
it's again a sort of a remote shell and
you can spawn sessions uh basically it's
very interesting you can check it online
it's called pound cats open source
um what I do here is I trigger and
compile that specific exploit it's
written in C and that uh it triggers the
vulnerability
it's compiling it says compiling
verified exploit attempting to run
completed successfully and uh what I do
I check my ID and I have become root
initially I was not rude but then I once
I do that exploit I have be I have
elevated my privileges and you don't
know
how widely spread that exploit is
that was fixed in the later versions of
Linux kernel 5.15 by 29 so it's it was
fixed in the last seven months
or eight months
um imagine how much it will take for the
industry to catch up and update not
everyone updates their kernels regularly
so everyone makes makes them vulnerable
and if we don't know again uh simply by
attacking the kernel we can Elevate
privileges become root now imagine what
will happen if we find problems and
combine different exploits so we can
escape outside of this container and
reach the cluster with root privileges
it doesn't matter whether container
whether our container is running with
non-root we can Elevate our privileges
the next exploit uh it's pretty much
a key buffer overflow
and for this I have prepared an image I
have uploaded to the public Docker Hub
under VP bonus besides hyphen Attack One
and I create a pot which is called
besides attack one then I SSH or
spawn a bone cell session interactively
and check what my uh
my processor
so I list my namespaces
and the idea about this hacks that I can
change my name space so uh if I do a
captch print which is capture
um
uh basically capture the current the
bounding and the current iib namespaces
the I can do unshare
urm and basically uh unshare urm tries
to detach from the current namespace and
spawn a new namespace and now I have
elevated the capsys admin privileges for
which I I was supposed not to you know I
was outside of that namespace they
didn't have access to it but simply by
invoking unshare I'm able to change my
content of visible namespaces and
namespaces which I can reach to
so
that is one way of container escaping
that was fixed in uh
I believe quite recently
but it's one attack that you can work
and some vendors which I will not name
have suffered from it
so
the tools that I have used I always want
to uh
State my software which I've used for
that presentation the first one is
asking Nemo for which I uh recorded my
terminal sessions it's very useful I
recommended it it's uh you can
you'll remember the name because it's an
an acronym for ASCII Cinema
so it's asking Emma and the second one
is a bind reverse shell it's called Palm
cat you can check it out and you can
also watch the uh the introduction from
the guys that did invade it did invent
that remote show uh they're great I mean
I've learned by watching that session
alone more than I have learned in five
years and the session was 50 minutes
about remote shells so
another important point that I want to
make during this presentation is that
security moves with time and what is
secure today will not be secure tomorrow
what do you have observed so far are
Kano exploits those two exploits that I
have shown you
and I want to again emphasize that the
kernel kano.org
is one of the most icing software ever
developed you know this is watched by so
many developers so many eyes are
developing on this including our company
sponsor building
but
it's so big that a certain developer
takes a certain class there is a subset
in that class for that future and there
is just one little fragment that he's
focusing on and that's reviewed by many
this is one of the most secure software
ever written and it does have exploits
yeah despite it is at the root of
everything it runs everywhere you'll not
find something that does not run
uh Linux kernel even now the new
versions of Windows are shipped with
Linux Kano and they support
that it's very safe piece of software
it's present everywhere
now for a moment
imagine how many common vulnerabilities
uh other softwares could possess
think of a moment about this
because if one of the most observed
piece of software
have such vulnerabilities and those are
criticals
and of course
the industry tries to catch a patch
regularly Etc but the order software is
not
on such string monitoring usually you
can have a developer pushed code and
there could be buffer overflow that
could be used after free and it's yeah
it's a lot more dangerous in at least in
my opinion
um
no not only that but this software can
be added on top of public
uh images Docker images or container
images or all CI images they all refer
to the same thing
so
the next time someone asks you oh I
wanted to
run that service very quickly you
probably will just go to download the
first Public Image that's available on
Docker Hub not saying that you do it
many many
developers do that and those images are
full of vulnerabilities even there is
snuck now running on Docker Hub which is
their scanner and you have approved and
certified verified images and
repositories it's still like tons of
vulnerabilities everywhere inside those
public images don't trust them
so
the next topic I want to to bring is
bring on this table is Alpine Linux
and my question towards you is Who
currently uses Alpine
okay
you know this would be bad because this
presentation is not about Alpine right
okay so uh
yeah Alpine is loved by many and hated
by even more people
why is that the case
um usually the process towards coming to
Alpine Linux
goes through a size comparison and I
have shown just an example showcase I
want to build uh and provide basically
an image that can be that can run go and
build go whatever that the case is if
you build go then it could be a larger
image in size but I wanted to just
provide a comparison
um about how the choice to pick Alpine
is usually done in in companies not only
Enterprise companies
one manager and that brings us to our
previous talk one manager checks all
that image about dividends one gigabyte
that's a lot what's how can we bring
this down into into a smaller image and
developer checks say oh you know I saw
this Alpine Linux they pretend to be
pretty much small in size let's give
them a kick see what happens
usually the people don't know what the
four
other words mean below that graph
meaning
distrance busy box and scratch
so I will explain those to you this
stress we're going to talk about in the
later slide uh scratch is basically you
can refer to it as a no so it's a no
image it's empty
busy box I have explained that our recap
that's an image that's pretty much
scratch with the essential Linux command
so you can still uh Echo Cat OS sort of
those stuff that commands that you use
day to day
uh and you also have scratch Advance
which is
Advanced scratch but I still know
so Alpine why why do people pick Alpine
yeah you have package manager there you
have APK and APK can install very easily
additional software on top of your image
I can do APK add and install I don't
know Vim GCC music compiler
whatever I want quite easily
so understanding
yeah again understanding how those
pieces of software leverage links kernel
system components and its attributes is
the key and this is the way
as the man who have said it
so I will speak about why I personally
never use Alpine
uh the main reason for that is that
Alpine uses muscle which is an
implementation of the C standard Library
so it doesn't use the traditional glitzy
or the new C library it uses muscle
what muscle does is it's more
lightweight it's performance optimized
so so with DOT it's faster and simpler
than glitzy but it's used uh you know
it's used by other Linux distribution in
glip C is used by other lens
distribution muscle is kind of specific
to Alpine
so
what is the you know the backfire of
using muscle in Alpine because Alpine
size reduction strategy is based around
muscle so they're compiling the whole
stuff
into a different lightweight C library
which is obfuscated it doesn't present
with the same features
so
the first thing that happens is native
call hell software compiled against
muscle runs only on muscle
what is meant by that if I use Alpine
during my cicd pipelines I do compound
native code
I have to run that code again muscle
Lipsy will be immediately segmentation
fault uh so I'm limited if I'm stuck
with alpine I'm stuck for life I I can't
run that on on other C library that's
only for native code we're excluding
Java we're excluding uh yeah other types
of non-native interpretation or uh Tech
Stacks talking about native code C go
rust Etc
next thing node.js and that's JavaScript
node.js goes to the muscle compiled
native code by node Gib so node.js can
call native code by node gear basically
you can access your
um your C classes from JavaScript and
that's done through a library which an
awesome person wrote uh through an npm
it's called not Gip
false big time uh outside of muscle
again we have the same problem and we're
referring to the native called hell so
if I compile node.js native code on
muscle I have to run it on muscle
otherwise I'll get memory uh hell I'll
get segmentation fault immediately I'm
not able to run my software uh on my or
my service outside of muscle
the next thing is very uh I believe it's
it's one of the most interesting at
least for which I have come across and
it's DNS hell so it's funny so uh bear
with me muscle by Design so we're
talking about the muscle C library
does not support DNS over TCP
which means that uh usually you won't
give up a damn about this right uh you
just would notice and the chances to
read that
randomly anywhere is
pretty much zero
uh it will just explode at some point
and
the way DNS are being resolved the
responses and so forth for muscle is
done through UDP it's not through TCP
it's done through UDP
UDP is limited to 520 512 bytes and
that's
you know by by their standards they said
ah that's enough you wouldn't need more
than
512 bytes which kind of refers to the
Bill Gates famous saying who would use
4K of memory or something like that and
of course there are cases where you need
more and I want to tell you a story
about uh a case which we had running
kubernetes and again a manager came says
oh well you know I talked with other
managers they use Alpine and we should
use Alpine as well they're great they
stated that everything runs lightweight
slight ways it's fast awesome let's do
it let's onboard Alpine
though uh
the cluster starts throwing unknown host
exceptions and basically it seems every
it was seemed like liver breached we
were exploited big time we got unknown
host
and we had our Network so we verified
this but nothing worked everything
stopped working at some point and this
was the fact due to that kubernetes and
the internal DNS name resolutions they
used tremendously long DNS names so you
have something that's I don't know how
many you can get tremendously long and
five uh you know 512 bytes is not enough
and you just not get your DNS resolved
in kubernetes if you use Alpine and who
will have thought about this right what
are the chances uh and it was just a big
No-No for us once we have to get this
and gladly we hit this in an isolated
environment but at first it was like oh
God we got hacked
um we didn't know what what was causing
this
and we understood there was this DNS but
we thought it was DNS hijacking and
someone took control of our DNS that's
what we thought
so we're going to talk about what could
be a successor to Alpine and it's this
for Less so what this release is and I
want to again ask who I've heard or use
this through us right okay so two people
excellent
um
so this race is not a buzzword
I know that this bezel attack has you
know come across a lot of us but it's
not a buzzword it's the the the right
approach towards working with containers
especially uh in the kubernetes
ecosystem
so the initial concept is developed by
Google
and uh you know they started with some
of the rules what this release is they
started you know basically the same
approach where your manager can say oh
it let's use something that's smaller in
size but they were a poll you know they
were opposing this and said okay we're
going to develop our own stuff uh maybe
for usually it fails you know the
chances to succeed developing your own
ideas
have a great chance to fail but they
succeeded and their concept was right
so what this relates is it the name
refers that it is a Linux image without
the distribution
but it's not it's not the case right the
distress image means that you don't have
any command or anything that's present
you only have the things that are needed
so you can run your application no
matter if that's Java if it's native
code is go uh whatever you only have the
capabilities of the software you truly
need
and of course you can think of that
brings the size tremendously the base
displays images like three megabytes or
even less
so there are no package managers
that's why it's probably not understood
by many because you want to work with
package managers so so we thought there
are no shells or any programs there's no
less there's no more there's no Vim
there's no CAD there's no nothing
you cannot shout just you can run your
executable that's it in most cases
and it's perfect for kubernetes clusters
why is that the case because we are
limiting the attack surface
on our clusters so when we're packaging
our services in a distress image and
we're bundling this we can ensure that
we are only shipping the essential stuff
we don't have overhead on our traffic
cost
and we we are not you know
striking down our ECR repository if
we're on AWS by pulling tremendously
huge images
yeah maybe if you're doing that's
something that's very specific you might
you know this might not be the right fit
for you but this is currently something
that's
lost by many that approach it's perfect
for KR clusters and what Google did is
it provided different set of distress
images so you you have static Debian
bass based noise cell python Java Java
11 Java 17 node.js etc etc they come in
four flavors you have Nom root debug
debug Norm root in latest
um
and of course this release image does
differ in size the static file system is
around two megabytes if you add some
additional stuffs like certificates open
S cell handling Etc and of course Java
if you are Java Java is a giant it will
get the size will increase but relative
to the the things you need it's still
very small
so size is relative
and uh I wanted to demonstrate this with
something that we
we basically monitor our images and how
they behave
internally through plot and I've picked
some of the
images which are publicly available for
go reading top to bottom go node.js
nginx and we have developed our own kind
of a distressed version of those images
which I will call VMware slash go VMware
slash node.js vmos nginx those are not
public images so if you search them they
only own our private registry
If You observe the total CV count on the
public images like for go there 461
present on March 6. in comparison we
only had eight
that's how we have limited and addressed
the attack surface and it's the same
version of go
same goes for node.js and goes for nginx
and if You observe at the end of the
graph we basically we address them with
time and we work very close to zero
and those include high medium and low as
well so not only critical
so so some of the VMware inside and I'm
going to wrap it down we wanted to
create a symbiosis between package
managers because usually when you're
creating a Docker file you usually do a
run commands and those run commands
install different stuff so it's usually
how a Docker file looks it's one from
statement something that your image is
based upon which someone else developed
then you have a big chunks of a run
statement usually in one block to be in
one layer even so it can be a little bit
lightweight
and it's
there so many limitations with Docker
files that if we wanted to kind of do
then maybe add something that's better
than Docker files and again leverage the
package managers
so we ditch Docker files and we switch
to yaml syntaxis
and it was our plan to save big bucks
uh as we wanted to reduce our cost of
goods sold and basically our Cloud bill
on our Cloud vendor and overall
technical debt we wanted this to be very
easily maintainable because if you
developed uh images
container images you would observe that
if you want to bump the parent image
with and fix address vulnerabilities Etc
you have to build uh you know
synchronously the rest of the images so
it could be I don't know how many uh
built operations and constant bumps so
it's one parent another parent child the
child of a parent so it gets like I have
to build 10 images if I want to have a
proper inheritance
um
we wanted to have a far more security
and approach flexible built and dynamic
images so we something that we refer to
project Michael and it is a Insight name
something that we plan to
develop it's a new way to build distrust
images if you search on the internet
about this nothing will pop up something
that's internal so there's no
advertisement in this one so we
something that we understood is Docker
files are in the past
and there is one Docker file that's um
we used to have and we still maintained
you to several reasons but uh we wanted
to switch from Docker files to yaml
syntax I know that it's not very visible
but we wanted to build an oci image
against
ayamo and what is the good what what
this does to us is that we are no longer
relying on storage for our images in a
container registry we can do this
runtime and if you have watched or seen
kubernetes in action you can do a port
specification and you can specify an
image and there you can specify uh like
an a repository which is an oci
repository path towards your image with
the appropriate tag and so on you can
just include an yaml file which is local
and you don't have to pull I don't know
how many megabytes of image each time
and you do this runtime it's very
quickly it's like that and basically it
calls your package managers
uh it supports uh dignified uh DNA
um yum aptitude get uh APK even though
we don't use it we don't recommend using
it because it was breached
and
yeah usually you you just handle the
package managers accordingly so we
wanted to live even you know that was
the first iteration then the next
reiteration we wanted to use a cloud
native Foundation emerging project which
is build pack
uh and build packs IO so what build
packs IO does is it can look into your
repositories and
create a Docker file specification
it's it's an it's a tar at the end your
image is just an archive but it can
create the right capabilities in order
to build or run that specific image
imagine I I have a C plus plus
repository with some C code in it I
throw a bunch of stuff in it and I can
just uh
execute build pack against it and that
will create the the necessary recipe so
I can create my image without me
observing what's in there without adding
additional libraries and so on it does
it for JavaScript for rust for golang
for Java C plus plus C whatever you name
it so we combine this
and uh
we don't create a
atar archive but we create a yaml
specification which can be broken down
and you can inherit this leverage this
separate it into different pieces and
you can
of course develop on top of it without
bundling inch time separate image upload
and so forth so the process is uh it's
very unique in an aspect at least
I haven't seen anything so far and the
flow usually uses Co which is the code
build so if you go to GitHub and says uh
Co it it's something that's used in go
to produce a minimalistic tire archive
basically your file system for your
image and that's consumed by the
container runtime interface there are
two separate Sims that you can pick
either you do a build or you do a
runtime because the images that I do
requiring build are totally different
they're usually bigger they're not for
production runtime images on the other
hand means to be you know only the
things you need so you can run this in
production
so we have build we have run and we have
build packs that does feed what needs to
be added in terms of packages and we
have a process where those packages are
managed by different uh
package managers and you don't have to
use run or anything like that what's
used to be in the docker files Docker
file is pretty much outdated by now
um so each package is broken down into
capabilities and that's that's again a
feature which we uh it's not something
that we have invented but we have
improved upon so if You observe upon
nginx nginx if you do yum install nginx
or up to you get install nginx
um there are different capabilities
inside that image so nginx is a bundle
of its sub components sub-components or
capabilities yeah and we just uh it's
we're making a compatibility match
Matrix where we're matching only
capabilities that we do need for our
specific package the what is the end
result okay so what's all this doing
we're creating an image that's minimum
in size easily built and easily
maintainable and in comparison
you don't need to contain a registry
this is artifactory Nexus Hub ECR and
Amazon
you do just do things on the runtime
the cacd flows usually repository
cross-referenced by centralized
repository it executes a child job prior
to the build a reproducible Yaman spec
is created for that required image for
that specific repository in which is
using build packs uh it then it consists
of two yaml file specification one for
build and one for runtime pick your own
thing you know we just do both of them
at the same time our images are assigned
with cosine and with the appropriate
time stamp stamp and built on the Fly no
artifact storage no HDR
and last but not least uh just for a
comparison uh size wise image size is
drastically lower like the Public nginx
Image is 56 megabytes and by using all
this novel approach
we managed to bring it down to 3.8
megabytes that's fully functional nginx
as you can include in your uh a
kubernetes cluster for audio load
balancing works
um and you can fed it to your uh K9
kubernetes definition and you can
cross-reference it with a timestamp and
so forth
so
that's how I had guys and thank you very
much for your attention and do you have
any questions