oh no they just my IT guys said to tell
like a two-minute what it's just it's a
security thing it's unbelievable yeah
okay good afternoon everybody welcome
back to another fun-filled session Edgar
con 2019 hopefully you're enjoying your
Friday today I have the pleasure of
introducing Milan Patel he's going to
talk about an SOC I love these acronyms
today it's been great so about life in
your SOC so one thanks thanks guys so
this usually takes about 45 minutes but
I got 25 so I'm gonna speak New York
fast because that's thrown from so a
little background myself spent the
number years at the FBI is a field agent
and then finally the CTO of the cyber
division where I spent a lot of time on
instant response and cybercrime you know
investigations like anonymous and Silk
Road when I was a street agent New York
and and then transitioned out of
government a few years ago to help found
the company I'm at today which is blue
voyant gonna talk a little bit about and
I'm sure you guys know this from the
audience I left this slide in I could
have taken it out even though you guys
know some of the stuff but I thought
it'd be fun to to show you guys some
pictures I took along the way in my
career on the right-hand side you know I
often tell the story of of the the
picture in the middle there with the guy
with the money on him he was a part of a
criminal organized crime ring out of
Eastern Europe russian-backed organized
crime that had siphoned about two
million credit cards and debit cards out
of a well-known multinational bank and
that organized crime gang had a deep
website set up that was operating in
real time with customer service the
whole nine yards and basically signing
up Russian j1 students kids who came
from Russia to come here to go to school
they would overstay their visas not want
to go back to Russia for obvious reasons
and they would turn into skimmers they
would get MSR 206s hotel key cards and
then go hit ATMs this guy in the middle
there hit 200 ATMs in New York City in
the span of about four weeks and
siphoned out like three million dollars
in $20 bills he stuffed that money after
paying
sending money we via veteran Western
Union in walls at his house and then
spackled over it
we had actually dig through walls to
find the money on the on the on the the
bottom right hand picture you know I
illustrate this point because you know
things haven't really changed since
those those investigations I was a part
of but what we are seeing is sort of
that organized crime element become very
technically sophisticated and so when we
think about Russian organized crime we
think about other Eastern European
organized crime it was you know more
organization five or six years ago
trying to get young kids to do credit
card fraud ATM fraud and what we found
is those same criminal gangs are not
running full-blown operations to build
pretty substantial pieces of code
designed to be as a service and today
we're tracking a lot of these guys in
the deep and dark web and we're finding
some amazing ways they're they're
maintaining their persistence evading
next gen Navy like some of the guys on
the other side of the expo hall and and
we see it every day in our sock and it's
a it's an interesting place because I
think it's really impacting how socks
are supposed to run socks for many years
were designed to be very reactive they
processed alerts they triaged they then
sent the alert to the customer or if it
was an internal sock sent it to the
business unit responsible for those
group of servers your machines and then
some somebody would manually come by
take a look at it and everybody figure
out they don't know really what's wrong
they're scared and they rebuild a
machine and and as you guys know now
you've seen before you know rebuilding
machines on end is very tiresome very
uncomfortable and makes a lot of people
unhappy and so how do you do that more
transparently how do you do more
proactively and and sort of happy to say
that the industry is evolving but but
really we're still sort of in this place
where most organizations whether you've
outsourced your sock or you've you've
got an internal sock depending on the
size of the organization what we finds
the same problem if you guys have grown
up in friends experience and response
like I have there wasn't a day that went
by that you weren't copying pasting in
virustotal you weren't doing you know
basic rudimentary pivot tables and Excel
spreadsheets looking for IP addresses
and user agent strings and
and doing things manually and so what we
found in the space especially in the
mid-market space is these organizations
have realized that you know they're
gonna be attacked there's going to be a
threat to their brand new reputation and
how do how to actually impact that
what's happened is a sort of spur to go
buy a bunch of tools so they're buying
CrowdStrike carbon black Splunk and all
these great tools and the tools are
great they work well we use all those in
our sock at bluevoyage but what we found
is there's no material change except for
more detection some are false positives
and so how do you deal with that how do
you figure out a creative way to bridge
the bridge these tools together in a way
that you can actually track a threat
from from a coming in your environment
it doing its nasty thing and then
leaving and can you show that that
threat that came in to the environment
was just an incident rather than a
breach and and and the distinction there
is something was stolen corrupted or
damaged where you've got to call outside
counsel you've got to call an instant
response team and then you talk about
the tail end of an IR and IR engagement
where you doing cleanup forensics
there's law firms involved there's
notifications to customers accounts and
partners that you've lost their data and
every state across the country has a
unique way of identifying what
notification is and with respect to what
happens side of a network some states
the mirror the mirror compromise of a
server that had client date on it
requires and triggers notification and
so if you've got a database of a million
customers you're making a notification
to million customers you can ask Equifax
and Target and no Depot what that's
really like I can tell you that that the
cost of that far outweighed anybody
being on site fixing any machines and
getting things up and running I had the
fortunate or unfortunate pleasure of
being a part of some of those breaches
and I can tell you most of it was around
not the fact that they didn't have
technology they all did they all had the
next-gen buzzword of every device you
could possibly think of what they had
was product fatigue an alert fatigue
they had too many products too many
tools to monitor and all these tools are
different and approach alerting
differently based on thresholds that
those platforms are designed to trigger
on and what we end up finding is there's
more there's more tools and more data
than one person can handle let alone a
sock that's built internally or
externally and so we don't see a drastic
change in any of this information in the
last few years which is we're
seeing in an amount of time being wasted
on alerts that don't matter
and then alerts that matter not enough
time and I can tell you we see this on a
regular basis when we go do IR for
companies I've been briefed where we
don't provide any sort of services for
them we see the same thing they'll give
us a list of all the alerts that were
generated out of their Splunk
environment and Excel spreadsheet and
they'll say we think we may have looked
at these but we're not entirely sure and
so you'll find inevitably in those
alerts you will find the telltale sign
of a breach or compromise or some sort
of credential theft and so we don't see
a lot of change in these problems around
meantime to detect meantime respond and
really that response is more not just
response it's really remediation in the
industry we sort of confuse these two
together when you think about MDR just
the terminology you know Gartner sees it
and the industry sees as a response
which is somebody picking up the phone
making a call saying I responded I've
told you something is wrong and really
that's ten percent of the problem right
that you got the ten percent right
you've notified your customer or your
team that there's a problem but the rest
of it is what exactly happened what took
place and and how to actually rectify
that problem not from just the point of
the detection of ransomware
and your next you Navy was able to
identify the encryption and kill it
before it encrypt the entire machine the
challenge really is how do you defeat
the persistence mechanisms and the
propagation techniques that these new
pieces of malware are using and and
really a good example of that this was a
live case from one of our customers you
know we had in this particular instance
next-gen maybe Ronnie we were managing
it for them running their policies and
deployed actually the next-gen ad
solution for them rather large company
got hit with trick bought and run and
Ryu right at the same time and what we
found was the AV solution kicked in and
stopped the execution of code but what
we end up finding was every machine that
that payload had touched was trying to
execute this code and so you can imagine
you can imagine the number of alerts
being generated out of the same
environment and out of the next Jaime
solution where you've seen hundreds of
alerts per hour across thousands of
machines over and over again and what we
figured out was it was more than
the race we're trying to encrypt and and
actually be doing his job is the tool
had left behind a ton of ways to be
persistent on the network writing over
SMB doing discovery lateral movement
stopping updates the virus to antivirus
making all these things available
because the bad guys realized look we
really can stop but let's keep the
persistence mechanism in place given
that hopefully one day our malware does
land and we'll have we'll have at least
our payload in there and we can send
down new stuff so this pickle of one is
really really interesting because not
just it was a you know credential escape
can crunch already over SMB using sort
of living off the land techniques it
went pretty deep into looking at what
you know as you I'm sure you guys know
what scribbly do is but really just a
binary cyma Microsoft that allows for
deregistration and and a nun
registration of controls within within
the registry and what we found was
squiggly-doo was not only just a part of
this problem we couldn't get it off the
machines so we couldn't use next-gen AV
to reverse shell into the machines and
remove remove this activity we had to
start writing custom policies to
actually impact this what we did was we
wrote a couple of different policies num
number one was if anything wrote over
SMB or tried to make a lot of movement
after SMB and it try to make an external
network connection sever that connection
don't allow that SMB to happen but if it
doesn't actually rise to the level of
creating an external connection go ahead
and let that happen
because if we don't let it happen then
you've got you know disruption to the
network and this was during a day right
so the company's up and running there's
people running around doing their jobs
and if you start sort of you know
cutting off basic Windows functions
you're gonna start impacting the user
base the last thing that cisco wants to
do is have you know a lot of employees
upset that they can't get their job done
you know they could care less about the
attack themselves but they want to get
their job done and so what we found was
not only that it was doing this and and
and also doing the registry key changes
at the same time and so we ended up
having to do is write these custom
policies to go in and basically
stop SMB from making Internet
connections and go in and actually
forcefully fix the registry keys to
remove remove the the the the the
ability for the payload to actually do
this and so you know when you think
about sort of what a sock operation is
and what innocent responses this was all
done remotely there was no there was no
body there was no team I didn't send
anybody on site to do this work this was
all done through the console of the
next-gen AV solution and this is goes
back to my point which is these tools
are great they work really well but you
got to know how to use them most
different customers who buy the next-gen
tools will come to us and say hey we
just bought you know XYZ company tool we
realized we actually don't know how to
use it it looked cool when we bought it
and it looked like it was doing his job
because we all these lights go off and
all these all these all these things pop
up and we're like a that's doing his job
you know you go back and everybody
because it's thumbs up the reality is is
that they are good tools the challenge
is their detection mechanisms are
somewhat aggressive and so they detected
a lot that things that shouldn't be
detected on that requires whitelisting
and custom policy development but more
importantly it is capturing this data
but it needs to be forced to go do
something about it so this particular
instance you know the out-of-the-box
policy for this next gen IV solution is
to go let this binary run to not stop it
because if you stop this binding from
running it's gonna affect it's gonna
disrupt the operating system and thereby
disrupting disrupting work on the
network and so when you buy these
solutions yeah they're great detecting
they've got great policy enforcement but
you gotta know how to use the policy
enforcement to go in and do this and so
when we see things like this this is
like by the way a customer had bought
this tool had it for six months and then
realized this was this was too much for
them and they were thinking about
removing it and going back to a
traditional AV platform we came in and
told them absolutely not don't go back
to traditional AV because you're not
gonna have the ability to investigate
and and determine the root cause of
those those issues after the fact and so
when we talk about sort of you know
really fighting back what are we really
talking about we're really talking about
is shifting to sort of a different
philosophy right asking more questions
up front of your sock operation is it
really bad how bad is it what makes it
bad could this be legitimate these are
all really important
as we start seeing malware and and the
various payloads getting into
environments designed to live off the
land right so it's basically good stuff
behaving badly and how do you actually
make sense of that and what we found is
you know over the last few years of
building this capability out we saw that
the questions we're asking are great
questions but they're really hard
questions to ask and and to do that at
scale is really difficult and so we we
added in orchestration into the platform
that allowed us asked all those
questions quickly so I know you can't
see the screen in detail but on the
right hand side is an entire automated
playbook designed to look for gang crap
and that's it it's designed to look for
the persistence mechanism its
propagation and the payload itself and
so what you're seeing is a fork when we
determine it's high confidence and vapi
from the platform it's going back into
that next-gen AV solution killing the
process deleting the the payload and
then quarantine that machine from the
network so it can't go spread itself
just in case deletion didn't work and
this is all being done with those same
basic questions that were asking before
which is you know is it really bad you
know how is it bad why is it bad all
these really really tough questions to
ask especially when you're talking about
things that are legitimate in an
enterprise that are designed to run like
PowerShell and others but being used in
a malicious way or masquerading behind
something else and so really what we're
talking about is the ability to do this
at scale do it efficiently and we're
starting to see sauk operations whether
you've outsourced it or you're building
your own sock some of the largest banks
in the world are finally starting to get
to a place where they're automating a
lot of these tickets particularly on the
benign and false positive side which is
now cutting down the amount of time it
takes for sock analyst to actually do
reviews of more important stuff today at
our sock we roughly automate 50% of
tickets so all the false positives and
benign indicators are that are that are
created from the network we're actually
running through various playbooks in
reaching them with threat intelligence
and making the determination is are they
really bad or are they not in that key
distinction between is this an incident
or is this a breach we don't tell you
our customers we can stop you from
incidents because that's not possible no
tools should be able to do that no human
should be able to do that but can we
give our give our customers a sense of
comfort to know
we are looking for that Delta between
what's an incident what's a breach and
that is where the rubber meets the road
particularly if you've suffered a breach
and you realize what it takes to
actually resolve a breach it's not just
forensics as I said it's law firms its
IR teams its auditors its examiner's
from federal regulators who come in and
ask the questions what did you exactly
do here when this breach happened oh
sure it's a response plan and most
people's into response plans are
non-existent they don't have one and so
what we end up finding if you think
about the merchant mercantile exchange
that was breached in Chicago the the
federal regulator went to them it
basically said certiorari our plan shows
what you did when you figure this out
and the simple question they asked was
when did you find this was bad when was
it really bad and what's the Delta
between when you realize it was bad you
did something about it
and that Delta was massive because
people are running around trying to
figure out what to do there's IT guys
saying I own this you on this I don't
want to be stuck with it's not my
database I didn't configure it I don't I
don't know who did what I don't have the
logs that doesn't feed into that doesn't
feed into our our smoke environment so
if you asked me to look at it I have no
idea because you never sent me those
logs and so we saw a lot of that
infighting get generated from not being
able to respond appropriately to these
problems and really the the the name of
the game is trying to find really really
creative ways to reduce the amount of
false positives in an environment so you
can then go go concentrate on the more
significant stuff that potentially could
be a breach where there's a corruption
of data in exfiltration of data of some
kind and you really can't do that if
you're buried in alerts that look really
important but they're really not right
so commodity malware that was stopped by
a next-gen AV is that a problem should
anybody be reviewing that or should you
just get it out of the network versus
something like this that I showed where
it requires some actual additional root
cause analysis behind the scenes to make
sure it was really out of the network
and what we tell people as a sort of you
know I guess funny and crude way it's
you can hire ADT right to to monitor
your house with cameras and they can
come in and tell you where all the
cameras should go but if you're not home
and you're looking at your camera
through your app and somebody Rob's your
house you know there's not much going on
there gonna be robbing your house while
you're well you're not home and so what
we like to tell folks is it's not enough
to have ADT it's not enough to have just
cameras you've got
to think about where the right place is
to put in blocks and put in humans to go
affect some of these things that are
very manual in nature you know we talk
about AI we talked about machine
learning and those are all great things
and they will impact cyber security in
the coming years but really what we're
talking about is this ability to use
humans to empower technologies to do a
better job at identifying these issues
which typically is what drowns out a
sock if you look at any sock the number
of alerts to come in the number of them
are handled under the SLA ticker you
would be shocked on what the SLA says
and what the actual what the actual
timer says on the real-time response and
so lastly I'll just say in general what
we're talking about is you know these
great tools that we see in the
marketplace today you have to have them
they do a really good job of detection
they do a better job behavioral
detection and some of the some of the
older legacy tools but what we find is
that they're scaled back the policies
that are written or scaled back which is
which is good and bad because you don't
want to disrupt the network but the
reality is some humans got to come in
and interact with that next-gen tool and
determine what processes we're gonna
write what policies we're gonna write
we're going to enforce on the network
whether it be black listing white
listing or some combination of both
depending on what you want to do on the
network and so this particular customer
that's actually there that's actually
part of their no policy development and
we actually went in manually and created
a lot of different things for them and
and we actually learn after that instant
response there were a bunch of other
stuff things on the network that that
you know if they were hit a different
way it would have probably impacted them
so we went in and cleaned some of those
things up as well which was like you
know batch process is the middle of the
night for their financial applications
we actually saw that those batch
processes did make any network
connection so we wrote a custom policy
to say if this batch process runs let it
run but if it makes an external network
connection don't let it run things
things of that nature we did for this
customer and we think we've got this
network pretty locked down but again
it's never perfect
these policies need to be reviewed from
time to time and you need an expert to
do it so I can give five minutes back
I'm actually all done did New York fast
how's that all right
thank you guys
[Applause]