all right are we ready okay well welcome
to the last talk before the last talk so
today I just want to talk a little bit
about aviation security in particular
wanted to talk about how some of the
different attacks that people have
talked about as it comes to aircraft
affect you know the big planes airliners
heads etc differently from how they
might affect little airplanes little
Cessna and such so I'm dr. Phil Palestra
from Bloomsburg University of
Pennsylvania anyone else from Bloomsburg
so you know why this talk in the last
few years has been a lot of bold claims
people have made about you know all I
can have you know I'm gonna hack your
triple 7 with my smartphone or maybe my
Arduino or something you know it's
something crazy so of course all those
bold claims get lots of press and you
know that's that's one reason another
reason if you look at general aviation
aircraft you know your little Cessna
sandpipers and such things are very
different from the world of airliners
and a lot of people don't really talk
about you know the difference is between
these two sets of aircraft so some of
you might know me you might know me as
kind of a hardware hacking guy maybe
author forensics guy also a little bit
of an aviator
I have 17 aviation ratings all of them
are current you know I'm a commercial
pilot flight instructor airplane
mechanic I have an inspection
authorization for aircraft I'm an
avionics tech I'm a licensed skydiver
got em in coach I have a few thousand
hours of flight time I've built aircraft
before and I've actually worked on the
development of some of the avionics that
are sort of pertinent to the airliner
discussions as well so what are we going
to talk about today gonna talk a little
bit about some of the common aircraft
systems and how do they work you might
have heard people talk about ATSB they
don't talk about it so much
but something that's also relevant it's
called a TS a I hear people talk about
things like a cars and transponders and
collision avoidance and course GPS you
probably know about GPS because you got
on your phone now auto pilots and things
like that you know how does all this
stuff connected together alright so what
are some commonly discussed attacks out
there of course you know the one that's
fit for your average movie is I'm gonna
get through the you know in-flight
entertainment system and I'm gonna
completely take over this aircraft and
things like that other people talked
about things like hacking a dsb you know
sending out false signals in that system
or maybe even hacking engine systems and
eight cars alright so we're gonna talk a
little bit about some of these also I
recently discovered attack myself last
month
and I've dubbed this the spear smashing
attack so last month I actually went to
a conference in Iowa and you know I got
to the baggage claim and this was my bag
I'm like wow but I feel like it was
targeted by the airlines and yeah they
just matched the living crap out of my
bag and it was lots of fun dealing with
that okay so I said I want to talk a
little bit about different kind
of aircraft so here is a old general
aviation aircraft this I want to say is
like a 1956 era cessna here
now how do you think you could hack this
airplane good luck all right I am in a
flying club and we have a couple of
airplanes and our trainer airplane is
actually 1960 1960s us that's very
similar to the sky and it's all analog
electronics there there's no digital
electronics there's no GPS
there's no autopilot all the radios are
kind of like the radios in this picture
they're mechanically tuned so the
ability to hack that airplane is
significantly reduced you might see
something like this can anyone identify
this aircraft let's see well this is a
Cirrus sr22 yeah yes you just didn't
want to speak up but you knew you knew
what it was
so this is a serious aircraft I just
picked this one there are other aircraft
have very similar avionics systems what
we call glass cockpit airplane this is
the g1000 system from Garmin right
really nice stuff what do you think is
the attack surface a little bit larger
on this aircraft yeah yeah there's a
little bit more electronics a little bit
more software going on here okay and
what about this anyone identify this
cockpit you didn't know this is gonna be
cockpit trivia you're closer this is an
Embraer 145 regional jet but
some of the regional jets I mean this is
stopped not as true as it used to be but
you know sometimes you look like say 10
years ago at a regional jet cockpit and
they look nicer than the big jet cockpit
right because they were still sort of
transitioning from that analog phase
into the glass phase all right so just a
couple of things you can't override
pilots they're kind of the last line of
defense
you can social engineering but you know
that's another story
also even the glass cockpit aircraft
they do have unhackable mechanical
backup instruments now you know I was
talking to some folks earlier this week
here and we were talking about different
kinds of airplanes and one of the things
we were talking about with the Cirrus
the Cirrus pilots get a bad rap and it's
probably justified honestly but there's
so much automate automation in some of
the planes like the Cirrus that if the
automation goes wrong people are like I
don't know what to do all right I don't
know how to fly this plane and it's kind
of bad so you can't make people look at
those mechanical instruments but they're
pretty hard to hack right in some cases
you can affect the autopilot operation
however if a pilot notices they will
disconnect the autopilot also all auto
pilots have to be able to be overridden
physically all right so if you're having
an airliner and you have a 90 pound
supermodel and you know her night job is
flying a big Boeing she has to be able
to override the control forces on that
aircraft and that's that's the rule
otherwise you can't get it certified
okay so talking a little bit about some
of the bigger airplane some of the big
airplanes they have really
ticketed systems for the avionics to
talk to each other and the older planes
the big ones use something called ARINC
429 and that's just a standard for
talking between different components now
newer aircraft tend to use a modified
version of Ethernet that is called ARINC
664 or AF DX right so ARINC is just a
set of standards you know kinda like you
have ISO standards and I Triple E
standards well this is for avionics
people and you know why did they do that
basically they wanted to use cots common
off-the-shelf components they're like
hey this is really hurting us it's hard
to get all this proprietary stuff
together and to try to test these things
so let's let's use Ethernet people
understand Ethernet now one thing you
have to understand about this erring 64
or FDX
is it's not the same Ethernet that you
use right it's like saying I have a
video cassette tape and I know some of
you are like what's that you know okay
it's this thing we used to have before
everyone had DVDs which is you know what
we had before we everybody had blu-ray
which is what we had before everyone had
4k blu-ray but anyway you know if you go
back a long ways some people actually
use this thing called Betamax so it was
a video tape but it wasn't a VHS tape so
it wasn't exactly the same thing other
things to know about this protocol it's
never Wireless there are reasons why
they will run miles and miles of wire
and a big airplane it's because it's
reliable and there is some security in
place it's not directly connected to
things like entertainment systems an
in-flight Wi-Fi so this was originally
developed
in the triple7 and as i said let you use
common off-the-shelf stuff not the same
as your father's Ethernet it uses
redundant channels and it assigns tie
slices to make things deterministic now
if you learn anything in aviation you'll
learn that aviation is all about
redundancy and safety you know people
are like hey why are you using 1930s
technology in the engine in your Cessna
even your cirrus same thing and the
answer is because it works right that's
that's why we use it we prioritize that
over efficiency any day it's like yeah
this would be more efficient and all
this but this works reliably
so we're gonna go with what works and
works all the time and so we have
redundant channels the other thing that
we have to do is Ethernet it's not
deterministic I can't set out of the
pocket and then know when I'll get a
response so instead what we do with this
protocol is we time slice things so you
get your time slice you know that your
packet gets out there won't be a
collision and you know that you'll get a
response within a certain amount of time
so it's a deterministic system and the
way that it works is that it uses
virtual ways so a virtual link is just a
virtual pipe that connects two processes
and there's one and only one sender and
there can be one or more receivers in
the system and we use something called a
bag a bandwidth allocation gap and that
determines the time slice size and then
we have jitter right and it's related
you know what's the maximum latency that
you can have when we look at it
physically again there's two lengths
there's an A Channel and a B Channel and
the way that it works they both send out
packets whoever packet
arrived first they win right so one
thing if you were trying to hack into
the system and you're like oh well I'll
just you know connect a garden-variety
Ethernet adapter to this system somehow
and send out packets if you're only
connected to one channel it might work
for a little while but it's gonna alert
right it's gonna alert in the cockpit
because they're gonna be like hey
there's a wire broken you need to send
this sucker to maintenance right and
you're gonna know that something's going
on this is just a little part of a
schematic showing you how some of these
things are connected if you see the FMS
box that's the big box over on the right
that's the flight management system or
autopilot if you will and here's
different things that it's connected to
you know like the joystick to guide the
aircraft and various other things when
you look at these schematics in more
detail you'll see you know there's
there's some paths they're a little bit
more important than others now one thing
I should say is this is a schematic
right as a schematic it's not going to
show you certain components and one of
those components is a networking switch
right so if you look at Amy onyx
switches avionics which is every single
connection in there has to be programmed
right so I have a connection from port
one that maybe has some sort of a sensor
on it and port two that let's say it's
connected to my flight computer right
that connection is program so that port
2 can only receive from a certain number
of ports and port 2 can only transmit to
another set of ports all right so you
have a lot of restrictions so every
single connection in that switch has to
be explicitly programmed right it's not
like oh I can just start sending
fake packets around this avionics
Network and things will happen well it's
it's a lot more complicated than that
okay okay real quick entertainment
systems so you got an entertainment
system and what's that's common
component in these entertainment systems
you want the little screens like here's
the map of your flight here's where
you're at here's long that's gonna take
here's how fast you're going all that
other stuff right so we're you're gonna
get that well there's a couple places
you can get that information one of them
is directly from the GPS or the FMS and
if you're getting that information that
way it's connected through something
called a net a network extension device
important to realize this stuff is never
like connected into that ARINC bus or
anything like that right also never
wireless not your father's tcp/ip all
right so you know here's just one
diagram for a system I won't tell you
which aircraft this is but just showing
some of the interconnections weave
between the in-flight entertainment and
some other systems all right we were
briefly there was some confusion a lot
of people out there were confused with
triple7 because of something that the
FAA said Boeing asked them for special
condition to allow the passenger
information network to be connected to
other networks and they granted them
this condition as long as they used a
net right so you know one of the things
they said is that there had to be
isolation from or airplane electronics
systems security protections against bad
things all right I'm not gonna read the
whole slide but so what is this Ned
alright they're like I've never knew a
guy named that alright well now you did
okay it's basically a gateway now
remember a gateway
is often a translator right it goes from
this protocol to another protocol in the
case of a ned on your airliner it's
going to go between the airing protocol
whatever it is your garden-variety
tcp/ip that the in-flight entertainment
system is going to use so they're not
talking the same language it's a
translator and like most gateways every
pas has to be programmed right I can't
just say hey there's a connection right
in you know in security we have this
kind of general rule if a wire connects
two things there's always the potential
for the hacking right would you guys
remember that if you're connected to
something there's a potential that you
could hack it
I'm not going to say it's impossible
here I'm just saying that in this case
you're talking different languages so
it's a much higher barrier in order to
try to do some sort of attack and here's
the other issue all right so the Gateway
has to be programmed so the Gateway is
not normally gonna receive any inputs at
all from the cabin right it just outputs
to the cabin and the switches those
avionics switches I was talking about
they're not programmed to receive inputs
either for those ports that connect out
to the NED so there's multiple barriers
that you're gonna have to overcome if
you're somehow gonna try to go from
there into the cockpit here's a picture
of one net I just stole it off of the
manufacturer site you know manufacturers
are great right they'll tell you all
about their products because they want
you to buy them earlier there was a talk
and they were talking about you know
these different venues and how do you
get all the information of the venue's
you go to their their website and
they're like hey here's all of our
security and all of our wonderful things
that we do we're trying to make your
life easy by yourself
all right another thing I wanted to talk
about briefly few years back it's about
five years ago now there was this
Malaysian flight 370 who remembers this
right so this plane disappears alright
and what did a couple people come out
and say immediately it was cyber
hijacked must have been that really
that's kind of a leap it's not the is it
the first aircraft that ever disappeared
no right but a lot of people went right
to that and then of course there's the
big conspiracy theories you guys always
have conspiracy theories right what
would the world be without them you know
but and one of the things that a lot of
the conspiracy theory types actually
talked about they said hey you know
there was these signals that came you
know after it went off radar I'll talk
about that and a little bit okay but so
again if if you're thinking that
somebody in the aircraft may be hacked
in through the in-flight wireless and
did all these other things and somehow
it disappeared hmm I'm not saying
impossible I'm just saying pretty hard
hello and welcome to how to hack into
and take control of a commercial
airplane step one when trying to get
access to the planes navigation system
we try to utilize the planes in flight
entertainment system
this is near to impossible both with
enough typing and hacker buzz words such
as and three routed the network
interface also I've got into the router
girder yeah you can make it seem like
the in-flight entertainment and
navigation systems are connected and
thus frightened and air marshal enough
to incapacitate you with enough hacking
one could be able to sign on to the
planes y5 every alright anyway that was
just a fun little video a friend of mine
made we've got some more fun videos but
you know talking about in-flight
wireless again this in-flight wireless
entertainment to be typically not gonna
be connected to anything really
important I will say this though there
are some GA planes out there typically
business jets they do offer in-flight
Wi-Fi now those may not be so separated
right so you know if you're looking at a
little pissed yet then yeah there's a
lot more possibility that you could
actually attach to something it kind of
important
of course my question is this you have
to be in that airplane right how can the
airplane they are in doesn't sound
terribly smart and you know you're it's
a little busy yet it doesn't have a
fortified door blocking you from the
cockpit or anything it might not even
have a little curtain you know depending
on what it is there are easier ways to
attack that aircraft okay a little bit
about ATSB how many of you have ever
heard of this ABS beep alright so it was
created initially in Alaska right so
ATSB you
is this idea it's something where
complains talk to each other right they
send out signals it's meant to
supplement radar in value coverage areas
like Alaska a lot of you might not
realize this Alaska is huge right and
they have more planes than cars in
Alaska what's one of the biggest
problems in Alaska plane crashes well
it's related to that drinking and flying
all right they got more planes than cars
kind of make sense you know a lot of
people get drunk and they they fly
anyway but anyway it's this is part of
this system called free flight that you
know maybe someday we'll actually get it
the whole idea is planes talk to each
other and they kind of work out their
differences they're like hey you were
kind of collect let's let's not do that
right now
PSB can also if you receive these
signals you can get traffic and weather
and things like that right now that's a
lot of people have heard of a DSB this
is not what airliners use idiot
airliners actually use something called
ABS a which is addressable right it's
related to something called a cars a
cars is a messaging system and it's like
this a DSP is your cable ready TV ABS a
is your cable box right so you can get
pay-per-view and things like that but
ATS a if you will because it can know
who you are where as a DSP it's just
like this is me this is me right and
there's like good things there's this
rule out there that says by January 1st
if you find in certain airspace you have
to have a transmitter for a DSB right
and we'll talk more about that here a
little bit related to a DSP in we have
this system called tis B traffic
information service B that's based on a
DSP and this is provided by air traffic
and
and if you have an equipped aircraft
I can look possibly at my GPS or other
screen and I'll see other airplanes
around me and sort of a poor man's
collision avoidance I don't get every
airplane I only get the planes that are
under radar coverage that air traffic
control knows about and their ground
station relays back to me and they don't
have to relate every craft back to me
either
right other collision avoidance systems
that you might see little airplanes have
something sometimes called tea CAD it's
called tea CAD because it sounds a lot
like tea casts but it's nothing like
that it's you know something you buy for
cheap and basically it it's not
authoritative it just kind of says I
think there's an airplane over there
right and then we have tea casts tea
casts is what the big guys use this
Jetson up now on a tea cast system
sometimes they'll say the fishfinder
you know if you look at this I just
realized that my slide is somewhat
truncated I apologize for that but it
looks great on my screen by the way but
so it looks kind of like a fish finder
that's what they call it that and when I
was in Iowa we had a professor in our
aviation program there he'd always say
things like they call traffic I have
them on the fishfinder like you don't
have a fish finder you got one of those
you know cheap little GA things but
anyway so what are the t caste systems
do here's the most important part about
this t caste systems don't use a DSP
signals very you're not gonna get an
alert and your big airliner or your busy
ette because I spoofed a DSP signals how
hard is it to spoof a DSP
software-defined radio ever heard of it
I mean it's super super easy like I can
make fake a DSP signals all day long
it's probably not very ethical
but you know I could do it okay the
technology is very simple but these guys
don't use it instead what they use is a
transponder signal
so transponder if you don't know what
that is it's basically a little box in
your airplane when radar hits it it goes
hey someone's looking at me I'm over
here alright and I have a little number
so you look at the bottom screen you see
1200 is on the display that's the I
don't have a code code right and it also
sends things to your altitude all right
by the way this is like the only real
world current application of octal
this is called a 4096 transponder
because it has four octal digits you
know some of the other professors at my
university are really big on making
people learn octal and I'm like if this
is the only place like I've ever seen
people using octal as transponders right
now the airliners have at least two of
these guys and here's what the T caste
system does it uses a directional
antenna so that is it as it flies
through the air it just sends out
signals and it says hey if you're out
there with the transponder please
respond
and then it uses the directional antenna
and the delay and it says oh I see
you're over there and here's your
distance right so it's pretty hard to
spoof that you know I can't be signal
sending signals over here and thinking
that that is somehow going to be
interpreted as signals from the other
side of my aircraft it's a pretty hard
thing to spoof force the plane to
reroute one another location or at least
harass the flight previous simply have
your pilot friends by multiple planes in
front behind and around the plane you
would like have said planes send
transponder signals to the hijacked
plane and force it to react to
resolution advisories the crew may
possibly reroute to another location
this is real fight
seems like a lot of work why don't we
just borrow that one
in actuality here's what would happen
okay so again you know when it comes to
like the little planes
maybe things a little bit different all
right sue if you have a smaller airplane
like even my 1960s Cessna in my flying
club okay thing has got no GPS or
anything like that
so sometimes I bring my own right I'll
bring a tablet and I might hook it up to
unit kind of like this guy little guy in
the corner a slow down in the corners
called a strap tucks not to be confused
with the Stratis what's the difference
between a struck talks and a Stratis
several hundred dollars that's the
difference and strat talks
it sounds very what Linux see
open-source eat cheap you can buy these
units or you can build your own a less
than two hundred bucks
so what does it got inside it's got a
Raspberry Pi and it's got a dual channel
receiver so there's actually two
channels that a dsb is transmitted on
and it has something called an a whore's
unit which tells you which way is up so
it's essentially electronic gyros less
than two hundred bucks and it integrates
with my tablet I you know it's got
synthetic vision it's really cool you
know I can feel like I spend a half
million dollars on a Cirrus and I spent
like five hundred bucks tall very I got
the exact same effect so these guys yeah
if you start sending out all false
signals to this kind of a system I'm
gonna pick it up and I'm not gonna know
that that's a fake system right now it's
not connected into my avionics it's not
like it's
going to reroute me because it's not
connecting my autopilot or anything back
but you can certainly mess with me
alright and that's kind of true in
general you can really mess with the GA
pilots it's a little bit harder to mess
with the big guys right but they
certainly can do this in fact the other
day I was flying into a Lancaster
Airport and air traffic control is like
yeah I see some traffic in front of you
do you have him in sight and I looked
and like yeah yeah I think I see him
he's my two o'clock and said could you
estimate his altitude and I looked at my
tablet and I said I would say his
altitude is about 2,500 feet and his
tail number is n33
because it actually had it on my display
because I was receiving a signal from
him and you might say well then how come
the tower didn't know who he was he was
not within range of a ground station
where they can receive his a dsb signal
and they only they didn't give his
transponder for some reason right so
things like that happen right alright so
here's some new attacks I mentioned that
we have this new mandate and this
mandate says come January 1st if you
find in certain kinds of airspace you
need to have a DSP out so my flying Club
you know we have this older sis now we
bought earlier this year we're using it
as a trainer it's great I love it my
kids love it because the windows are
bigger than the new Cessna and you set
up a lot higher you know it's just pure
flying it's not adulterated byte
electronics and screens to look at you
actually look outside you know even the
gyro is in it the gyros normally their
vacuum driven and you have a pump on the
engine that you create suction what
spins these things nope no we don't need
anything like that we have these venturi
tubes on the side so it works great but
only after you've been flying for like
ten minutes it's not only you know if
then if the weather is kind of low it's
like you better go taxi up and down the
runway a little bit get those things
spin in before you get up at the clouds
and be like I'm not sure which ways up
but anyway
so our club decided all right initially
we were gonna say forget you and we
weren't going to comply with this ATS be
out thing we just wouldn't fly down to
Philadelphia and things like that and
they change their mind
they're like okay we're gonna comply
with us so there's this company you
avionics and they make a lot of products
and they have made their company based
on this product pictured and something
else that's very similar that works on a
wing light and here's what their company
does they make these little things where
you take off one of your navigation or
position lights off of normally your
wing tip and you put their special light
in its place right that special light
has a GPS receiver a high precision GPS
so that it can send out your position
over ATSB
an ATS B transmitter a altitude sensor
and some other smarts it actually uses
the power wires they can go into this
unit as an antenna to receive the
transponder transmissions to go oh your
transponder just fired and here's the
code that it just sent so let me take
that information and put it together and
I'm gonna transmit the appropriate ATSB
signal that goes with that transponder
reply right which is kind of cool now
why do people buy these things because
they're only $2,000 right you're like
all that's like seems
like a lot well when the effe first came
out with this rule I think they gave us
like ten years of notice and everyone's
like FAA never does anything on time
they'll push it back they'll push it
back and initially it was at least five
to six thousand dollars to comply with
this rule and again if you do a DSP out
you get absolutely nothing as a pilot
it's no benefit to you at all right you
have to do the receiving in order to get
a benefit to get the weather and traffic
and stuff like that so a lot of people
were like no I don't know
and then you avionics comes out with
this thing you're like just replace your
wingtip and it's gonna be super easy
right I actually installed this guy this
guy goes in the tail light it's slightly
easier I think than the wingtip lights
and I installed it a couple hours
configured it and it was super easy
right so these things are really popular
how do they work well you have a
smartphone app again they may be easy
for people you know you just pull out
the old light pop in this new thing and
get out your smartphone you turn the
thing on and for the first five minutes
or until you leave the ground it says
hey let me set up a Wi-Fi hotspot and if
you connect to it using your little
smartphone app you can configure this
thing guess what the security is you
know the network password that's it if
you can guess the network password
you're good you can you can reconfigure
this I mean I can take my little 1960
Cessna and turn it into a Boeing 787 for
a United Airlines IHOP I mean it's super
easy to just change it all right or you
know maybe there's something called
anonymous mode I can set this unit to be
an anonymous mode so I'm not telling the
whole world my tail number as I fly
around this guy okay you can
at that I mean there's all these things
you could do so what do you guys think
security fail to configure it
that's part of them yeah you just in
fact you can go to their website and
I'll show you a video tutorial I think
my total time to install this unit
configure it and do all the paperwork
was about three hours and to be fair the
biggest part of that well first of all
it started raining so I was working on
the ramp and the rain which kind of
sucked
but this particular airplane someone
upgraded it so that these little lights
flash so I had to find this stupid
flasher unit and then disable it which
you know I ended up like removing seeds
crawling up under the dash and you know
that was like the biggest pain in the
butt of this thing so you know if I
hadn't had to do that you're looking at
probably hour and a half or so
so it's like super easy to do you save
on job time and you know people like
like that but you know I'd say it's kind
of problematic all right okay question
well otherwise how would you configure
it well it's gonna it's gonna transmit
that you have an aircraft and actually
the anonymous mode still sends your
identification
it just doesn't send it in the same way
so that the average person can see it
air traffic control can see it but not
everybody else but I don't have time to
get into that and how that works but
okay real quick a couple other things as
some people have talked about things
like attacking engine systems a lot of
engine systems have monitors and some of
the information can be set out on
something called a cars I'll talk a
little bit more about that right now
so a cars is a system that is used to
send messages to and from the ground
this is used all the time it's used for
things like weather flight delays flight
plan updates maintenance stuff the lab
is broken sometimes it's used for
passenger manifests a lot of different
reasons that it might be is many of the
components on a big airliner will
actually send out these messages okay
the engines send information and you're
like why would they do that for
maintenance
you know Royals Royce tracks the engines
the airlines track the engines what are
the parameters what's going on I want to
know that alright I want to know hey is
there something that's not right and I
need to address that next time the plane
goes in is there something that the
manufacturer of that engine wants to
know right so they send these messages
all the time right so could you attack a
cars yep it's not encrypted or anything
you could send up bogus messages
probably not a practical way to take
over to their from the ground one maybe
you could take control of the flight
state cars message where a crew receives
flight plan modifications
okay so again by the way thanks to a
friend of mine Polly
Adolphe over in Dubuque she made those
funny videos but so yeah it's use that
you're gonna run into with that there's
protocols right there's protocols and
procedures in place so and for example
if you say hey you're gonna reroute the
immediate action from the pilots will be
to contact the airline and ask they're
gonna verify that and they're gonna say
no we didn't tell you to do that now
again is there possibility like can you
send bogus ACARS messages oh yeah yeah
you definitely can you could like hack
into a ground a car's unit and send out
messages all day long there's no
encryption or validation or anything
like that so there certainly is
potential there and what is gonna
prevent attacks it's gonna be people who
actually follow procedures and verify
things you know you might have better
luck with something a little bit less
tragic state then hey you're going to
Cuba that Fargo but anyway so just a
couple closing thoughts
nearly every protocol using aviation is
not secured it's not encrypted you know
even the radio I remember one day I was
flying around Atlanta and
some kids were on the radio going maybe
maybe maybe you know they like making
Mayday calls and then the controllers
are like just having to verify that
did anyone declare an emergency and
everyone's like no it's some idiot kids
right now increasing automation without
securing those protocols could be
problematic I mean it doesn't sound like
a great idea
you know and I would say that airliner
is pretty safe you know I wouldn't be
worrying about people hacking in these
systems there's there's so many other
easier ways that people could be
attacking those systems in general but
you know if you really just don't like
general aviation pilots you can just
annoy the crap out of them honestly
especially if they got the cheaper stuff
so that's pretty much it and maybe have
time for one question it looks like but
don't feel any pressure to ask yeah
[Music]
it makes a good movie doesn't it yeah
and again if you're talking about an
airliner so an airliner is gonna have
some sophisticated stuff where you know
if you're close to the ground they
usually have we called radar altimeters
which literally reflect radar signals
off the ground
so when you're low you would know that
and that's gonna be tied into that tt
cast system and you're gonna get alerts
and they're gonna tell you you know pull
up you know you're you're low so you
know hopefully you would notice it there
have been crashes not related to that or
any kind of hacking but there was
actually an airplane that crashed many
years ago because a light bulb was
burned out and the crew were so
distracted by that they even sent
somebody down into the bowels of this
airplane to like verify that things were
working correctly and they disengaged
the autopilot and they didn't notice in
this plane crashed but yeah okay let's
see quick question
[Applause]
okay that's a good question and the
answer is no for a couple reasons number
one if I send in a new flight plan using
a car's it has to be reviewed and
manually accepted by the pilot so the
pilot has to approve the change it's not
like oh here's your new flight plan and
then you know off it goes and and again
if you somehow could not disengage an
autopilot you can't always override it
not that you're gonna enjoy that you
know that you're gonna enjoy you know
muscley you're playing around this guy
for a little bit but you're always gonna
have that so all right well I'm out of
time so thanks for listening and enjoy
your next talk