Sting's gonna fall
give I don't lie
how do you use this thing actually I'm
right there good morning everybody I
said good morning everybody
hey there the other knew I'd wake him up
cool multipath interference is always
fun some oh yeah
my name is Ricardo hello everyone Oh
talk about this is gonna be Lou okay
we're talking with Cloudy with a Chance
of suck-ups before legal did yell at me
so everything we're saying here is on
our own recognizance
this has nothing to do of our company so
we would be talking about see now I
can say and horrible horrible stuff
without legal yelling at me
boom official alright I'm the chief
information security officer for
Morningstar financial I've been in info
SEC for about 16 years I'd like to do my
fun facts I have five crazy children
five dogs two cats thirty fish and two
roaming Turtles I always step on
creepily at night my name is Matt
speakman I've been InfoSec for about
five is five
I have one cat that's it and also I want
all of you to be extra nice and
exuberant
this is mr. Matt's first time ever
public speaking outside of work yeah
so I'm also make him do most of heavy
lifting all right real crate by
Morningstar we're a global company about
5,800 employees in 27 countries about a
billion revenue just kind of give
perspective that I'm not working a crazy
little vacuum with 20 employees that's
pretty much why I put that there
why are we here why do we care
this I've been to a lot cloud talks as
many of you have been as well allow more
bland repetitive cloud talks and watch
you guys call us bland repetitive as
well which might and that's fine we have
a lot of boots on ground experience we
did a giant cloud transformation about
two years ago to re-platform most of our
applications by most I mean 30 percent
of our applications to be cloud first so
we have a lot of horrible war stories
behind that security education is isn't
everything you can bitch and moan until
people take the training cloud this
cloud that but unless you have
actionable controls it's really hard to
grab that adoption and in actionable
takeaways I know no wrong button sorry
all right
why do you care sec UPS is live in
dumpster fires any given time no matter
what you have this beautiful project
plan nope you and the whole cloud will
eventually be your problem even if it
isn't currently I came from DHS where
everything's mainframe yes the cloud was
there in small small instances so we're
getting there
you came from the Lord yes I do have
them alert with me because some of you
may have come from the Lord it's in my
bookbag and I also took one of those
weird little cups from the hotel where
you put the waffle mix in so I have
waffle mix cups that you can put milord
in so I got you how many waffles worth
of weren't you drinking it's pretty
awesome
alright and we're here help I want this
to be very open if
we're talking about some stuff and you
don't want to wait ten just ready raise
your hand I'll come run down there and
you can ask your question so I want this
to be as interaction as possible all
right traditional setups motto I'm not
gonna spend too much time here all of
you know the flow you get your alerts go
monitoring you do your investigation
bla bla bla bla bla this pivots
significantly when you start moving your
processes to the cloud and I'm also a
big fan of Soundwave cuz he's awesome
but anyways we had to retool a lot of
our setups processes to be very cloud
first I don't know why did the on-prem
and cloudy icons Rumble should have
actually been there I got called out Rea
this morning about that but nonetheless
loss of visibility in control this is a
cultural change and also a way that you
need to retool a lot of your processes
using cloud trail is very similar to
using review and syslog files but you
need to learn how to do it differently
serverless
is a very big different change for a lot
of people when they're moving from print
to the cloud your traditional AV agents
are not there or we have DLP it's not
there it's quasi ephemeral so being able
to retool for service environments
eventually my first year here I was like
what am I going to have a lambda
function
I can't secure a lambda function and
then starting to learn how to put
controls and governance around lambda
functions it's really a key there and
dynamic by design the old-school ACLs
where its IP address IP address when you
change that from on-prem to account
instead of IP address is also a big
learning change specifically on the
networking team whether traditional
cider - cider or a host a host is a big
fundamental change that infrastructure
had to go through as well and
environmental controls are key outside
of your overall environment you need to
understand that working in the cloud has
a lot of miss configuration issues that
had caused significant interruptions to
your environment we know all the s3 open
buckets blah blah blah but that's now
part of your responsibility as well and
talking about response
bili working in the cloud is a shared
environment where you work with your
developers your own team and also
whatever your cloud provider and were
primarily AWS AWS has their own stack
that they take care of and you need to
learn how work interact Lee with them
specifically doing during IR engagements
all right a little bit about our
environment we have a crap-ton accounts
for no good reason
except AWS told us to do it this way in
actuality it helps reduce our blast
radius in case one of the accounts does
get popped there are all small enclaves
but that also is a pain yes from a
licensing perspective which my good
friend here Matt will talk about handful
of EPCs
eight regions crap ton of buckets blah
blah blah more importantly or AWS
organization we have a master account
and then there's a multiple accounts
right below that that's how we govern a
lot of our controls and monitoring
across organization and for those that
are not familiar with the shared
responsibility model the customer or
what we're responsible is in blue and
then Amazon takes care of the rest and
being able to understand where those
roles and responsibilities are clearly
defined specifically with your
infrastructure folks and also your
security operations folks is really key
we've been on many investigations where
oh I don't know what's going on
with the knackles
and it's a downstream issue on a VP C
and I don't know who will call an Amazon
that should never happen you should have
those rules of engagement ironed out and
talking about rules of engagement I'm
done talking everyone elaborating
further on that shared responsibility
model we kind of made our own little bit
of a shared responsibility model so in
the red here is kind of what we as a sec
ops as an infrastructure team kind of
take care of for our customers which are
now our developers so a lot of the
things that we control are like cloud
trail we make sure that's turned on we
make sure that it's running we have we
control all the VPC and networking the
firewall knackles we actually control
our ami there's very very very few a.m.
eyes
that are not some better not ours out
there we control a guard duty we control
access to the Amazon account through
federated access through a DFS and we we
give our developers two specific roles
that they can login as trying to kind of
model off of like lease privilege right
so we have an operator account and then
we have an admin or I'm sorry an
operator role in an admin level role
they kind of controlled the rests they
control all the blue they control they
can build up as many servers as they
want I can use as many lambdas as they
want there for now in charge of
encryption we are working on taking that
away from them hopefully and so I just
wanted to kind of show these are kind of
the things that we give all of our
Amazon accounts all 120 of our Amazon
accounts get these out the door so we
have our Morningstar base image which is
actually built monthly we use chef
packer and terraform to do that it's
shared to all accounts and all regions
on completion of that build developers
could actually subscribe to an SMS
notification which would actually tell
them hey the latest build is available
and if they're mature enough they could
actually hook into that process and have
a scheduled time where they could
actually build their application with
the new ami without really ever having
to do anything that image is has our
configuration tools built built in it
has its CIS hardened its patched and
it's not dependent on AWS generated keys
for authentication which means we don't
have to play where's the key anymore we
don't have to play which developer lost
the key for the networking we kind of
control the VP see the subnets and all
on Prem connectivity by default the
security features that we all enable is
we have cloud trail that goes in from
all of our team accounts that goes into
a central bucket inside of one of our
central accounts so every single
accounts cloud trail blogs going to ask
three bucket that we suck up and then we
do things with we have their VP C flow
logs we have guard duty logs we have
their base knackles
and we have again that federated login
on top of that we have some reactive
infrastructure monitoring and alerts so
kind of that classic sock that Ricardo
was talking about so Oliver like I said
all of our team counts they have our
cloud trail goes into their centrally
managed s3 those s3 vlogs or that s3
bucket pumps into Splunk and then those
that Splunk instance generates alerts
that then go to our traditional sock to
you know manage so someone makes an ami
public we don't want that to happen
because like I said we have all these
things that are proprietary to us we
don't want that ami to be out in the
public so if we see that get made open
to the public
someone needs to get on the phone and
start calling some people make that
getaway if people turn off our cloud
trail obviously we're then blind to the
account we don't know what's happening
so we need to make sure that that's
happening blocked as well root logins we
actually take away our root account and
throw away the key so if that happens we
definitely want to know about it and
that's just I think like a number of the
reactive and kind of old-style alerts
that we do but you know we don't really
care about that anymore like this this
is the cloud now we need to be prepared
and we need to stop kind of reacting
right we need to be proactive that's old
sock so this is our proactive
monitoring workflow now this particular
workflow is for our AMI scanning and
monitoring tool so what we have here is
we have a team account and then we have
our cloud services account someone in
our team account will you know say spin
up some random AMI
it'll cloud so we'll track that it'll
send and fire off a cloud watch event
which then goes to an SNS alert which
triggers a lambda that lambda will then
analyze that and say hey do I care
do I care this happened and if it does
care in this case it definitely does it
will then run some stuff functions on
the AMI it'll ask that ami hey who are
you who is your daddy what does he do
what's your parent ami if it's one if
it's built off of our parent IMI it
leaves it alone it's cool if it's not
then it's going to auto terminate we do
have exceptions that we get that
sometimes there's black boxes that you
have to deploy and you can't always
control that but largely that's it we do
have code look it works sometimes this
is this is am i scanning still basically
we go through our V pcs for every single
V PC in an account we get all the
instances and then in those instances we
say is this one of the a my images that
we expect to see or a parent of I think
that right now we let the last four
months of am eyes be valid so you
basically have four months to get off of
an old am I
those am eyes are obviously still
patched the old way while they exist but
we do not allow an ami to be long livid
in the cloud environment that's not the
cloudy way another thing that I'm really
excited about because this is one of my
biggest qualms about cloud talks is I
feel like a lot of cloud talks I've gone
to end it in you know the the main point
is don't make an s3 bucket public and I
hate that because you can tell every
single person that all you want till
you're blue in the face they're still
going to make that public if security
education was all that was necessary
half of us would not be employed so same
kind of thing as the ami scanning we go
through and say here are all the buckets
is it public is there an exception if
there is an exception then we use our
API to basically find the owner of that
account and then we cut a ticket for
that person say hey we found this public
bucket we turned it off do you need this
if they do need it then they say yes and
it goes through exception process if
it's approved then we never bother it
again so how does that actually look
so if I'm you know Davey developer and I
just need to build instance I don't care
what it is I don't care what it's setup
I just need this server and I need it
now I don't care I'm not gonna tag it
security groups sure let's open it to
the Internet why not cool
oh this key I probably don't have this
key but let's let's do it let's do it
let's just go with it
so now we look let's look at this this
is how it looks to our developers
basically we're building this spinning
up still spinning up these things take a
little while sometimes still up shutting
down what is happening my server uh-oh
nasty Graham terminated that's a minute
minute after it comes up it's can't even
actually barely make a connection before
it's gone there's they're nasty Graham
hey why are you doing something stupid
we know it was you we know this is what
you did we know that's what you built
and we terminated it successfully here's
this documentation that I know you're
not going to read don't do it again
please but if you do same thing so we
have some other ideas that we want to
keep elaborating we're gonna keep
building on this and that's something I
really want to point out it's very weave
the way we've made this is it can be
very modular so like I said a lot of our
right now manual processes we want to
make those automated when an ami is made
public that's obviously very kind of a
sensitive thing for us we want to get
that on non-public as fast as possible
so that's a huge one for us if someone
turns off our cloud trail again we're
blind to that account if that cloud
trail gets modified and we can't really
take away their permissions to touch
cloud trail because they might have
legitimate reasons to use their own
cloud trail so it's a bit of a
double-edged sword there and that kind
of comes back to that shared
responsibility model
creation of roles and permissions I am
is obviously a huge part of Amazon if
you've ever been in it we can't take
that away we can't take that away from
people and what that means is that they
can also create their own roles and
permissions to stop or to circumvent our
controls and we've seen it happen a lot
oh I tried to put this firewall in it
won't let me well I'll give myself
firewall access and then they'll do it
so if we can stop that from happening we
can stop yelling at people and I don't
know drink more oh my lord now I
wouldn't normally talk about costs but
when your cost looks like this I think
it's worth talking about so we've looked
there a couple vendors who actually do
this kind of stuff and vendors can be
useful if you're utilizing multiple
clouds however when we were looking we
found that a lot of their costs were to
the tune of $100,000 a year plus a
percent of your Amazon monthly spend per
account we have a hundred and twenty
accounts that's a lot of cash
our solution that's our scanning
solution this runs out of one account
and it scans all 120 plus of our
accounts for that much a month so
there's about 152 dollars worth of
shared costs that's like you're now a
weighted Kinesis already yes a lot of
that some of that is kind of just cost
of doing business cost of having an
Amazon account some of that is actually
to tribute to the scanner as well that's
why we put as shared then there's direct
sienar costs so lambda two dollars and
22 cents a month cloud watch dollar 31
month DynamoDB two dollars 83 cents all
these things we can move process 20
million 20 million a cloud trail events
a day 120 counts 20 million cloud cloud
trail events a day get processed through
this so it runs and it runs a lot
but you know 186 a month 100k a year I
don't know what 6% of 186 is but doesn't
really matter if the flat is 100k a year
so you know shared cost 150 to direct
cost 30 for final cost 186 getting
emails from your developers when you
immediately kill their instances
priceless
thank you Matt really appreciate thanks
for the overview um just want to provide
a high-level summary why we did this is
really to identify how as long as you
learn what cloud environment and do the
investment up front you can build these
controls yourself it's not overly
complex it's having the time and effort
to understand your environment and what
your actual scope is those third-party
tools are fantastic I'm not going to
knock them they are expensive they
provide pretty graphs but you can do
that too and I really want you guys to
understand the environment you're
walking into and know that you can do
this yourself and at a reasonable cost
and being T so I have to pay the bill so
I absolutely love this and I want Matt
to talk a little bit about the education
and then we even close out I've said it
before I'll say again you've heard it
before
you'll hear it again security education
it's obviously important it's number one
you know fishing all that good stuff you
need to educate your users but as you
know they're not going to listen to you
and like I said if they did listen we
would not be here we would not be this
industry that we are so prepare yourself
for that you need to be able to actually
respond to these things when they don't
listen to you preferably in an automated
way we want you to be part of the same
environment that your developer is going
to be in that's why we that's why I
prefer building this ourselves we
actually learned so much by doing this
whereas if we just deploy some tool
which and a number of those tools
actually pretty much deploy the same
kinds of things that we build then like
what are you actually learning learning
new tools actually
Ricardo told me this yesterday getting
put in front of the new tools isn't
growth you don't learn anything by that
there's a reason that these things can
be kind of handed off and offshored so
easily new tools that's nice but getting
in there and actually building it
yourself that's what's important you
know that they're gonna do stupid
you need to know how to prepare yourself
for that stupid so we're here to
help if you have any questions we'd be
happy to answer thank you
[Applause]