all right so I got a feeling people are
gonna keep swell yeah I know I'm I'm a
bigmouth I don't even need the Celestia
talks I haven't even used it but this
way it's recorded all right so good
afternoon now gurke on it is afternoon
holy you've made it this far everybody
in this room I'm guessing already ate
lunch because everybody else who is in
here is out there eating lunch that's
our story we're sticking to it all right
a couple housekeeping things don't block
the fire exits I think we're okay right
now cell phones turn them off silence
you know the drill I wore boots today
specifically for this purpose don't make
me come out there and use them on you
all right they're almost awake we're
getting there all right so we are
talking blinky badges all the cool stuff
anybody's ever wanted to make one of
their own or you're just curious what
the heck goes into making these awesome
little toys we get at cons and
everywhere else Hey the Ishwar Spurs
here he's gonna talk to you all about it
so with that Dave I'm turning it over to
you thank you so if you haven't eaten
yet thank you for going through the the
hunger pains I feel yet I haven't eaten
yet either it's good for you though too
fast a little bit and then we can party
after this so here before you today to
talk about some stuff that I've been
working on over the past few years I've
helped participate in making about five
different badges whether or I'm
designing or I'm kind of just sitting
there and watching people and learning
and in any combination thereof so who in
the room actually is sat down and said
I'm gonna make a badge and made the
badge and finished it one person you did
I I know you did Phil so you did and was
it like the easiest thing you've ever
done
oh hell no right so that's really kind
of part of this talk so there's
so many different components so many
different facets of things that are
going on into this process that when I'm
having these conversations with other
fellow makers you know they're you know
other people want to do this too but
they kind of really don't know where to
begin or they have these great ideas and
they're not capable to write code or
whatever their personal hurdles might be
and I it just seemed like a main sense
to kind of talk about this so this way
if you are one of those people hopefully
after this talk except for that
gentleman who is leaving is inspired to
continue with the process or maybe get
started with one or you know reach out
to other people that might have the
skills that you're you need help with
thank you for joining so first off my
name is up there it is not pronounced
heel lands you know the name comes from
my childhood playing Dungeons & Dragons
and to the extent of my creativity this
is the concatenated version of the name
to accommodate AOL never one or night
but this is the name that I originally
gave myself again limited creativity at
the age of 14 I played a cleric but for
shorthand reasons I just go by heel at
these events my real name is Dave
Schwartz Berg it's no secret I work for
Cisco Systems as a technical solutions
architect and yes that is just about
more fun than it sounds getting to play
with all of cisco security tools
including duo wolf what's up buddy so
it's a great job lot of fun and I have
Cisco on the slides because they support
my speaking at events to folks like
yourselves let's talk a little history
first so when this whole badge life kind
of crazy that's been going on for the
past few years where did it come from
so on the very very far left you see the
badge that drew Joe grant put together
for Def Con 14 2006 anybody you want to
call me out on that
I think it's 2005 ok my facts are wrong
or you are but one of those two are
correct
so 2006 2005 Joe grant comes out with
this badge with this kind of idea of
wanting people to get excited about
doing some kind of hardware hacking
alright so they put some blinky lights
on the badge some other components so
you can do some other fun stuff very
simple but also very effective because
over time this kind of little spark that
got flem flame or flyff and turns into
this big you know burning sort of
dumpster fire but not dumpster fire
depending on your perspective which is
again why I have the controversial stuff
on this talk at the end then I don't
know if you guys are familiar with DC
darknet and Smitty halibut so the badges
to the right starting with the yellow
ones Smitty read these books called
demon or daemon however you want to
pronounce it and in there is a dark net
and he came up with this fun idea of
making these little yellow badges and
kind of left him around the hardware
hacking village and it was your way into
the dark net he made about a hundred of
them didn't realize what he did but he
got a lot of people really excited about
the kind of custom hardware and getting
involved with hardware hacking and that
kind of again springboarded into the
next version you know so on and so forth
they created more this is a picture he
took for me because I couldn't find the
older versions I found the newer ones
but I was like you got any old photos
and he like went on and told me the
whole story
which then turned into some brief
memoirs that he put in like a twitch
stream so or tweet stream or on Twitter
so if you look for you could see like
the history of what he was creating and
what he was trying to do but is a fun
kind of thing but really turned into
also again with Joe grande
into what we call today is badge life so
these are the close up of the one of
these badges
I pretty much have just about all the
darknet badges except the first one
they're really cool if you can get your
hands on some of the older ones put them
together yourself they're really meant
to like get people excited what about
wanting to do hardware hacking and and
it did for me so the one on the left on
the middle in this picture was the one
the first one that I was able to get
and back like when I was like 18 at high
school I'm like I want to become an
electrical engineer so I can fix DVD
players that is my future yeah wasn't
funny back then sir it was quite serious
so after a couple years of that and then
really like designs probably a better
place to go and then said heck with that
I'm gonna become an accountant and
eventually got into IT and now
information security so that's kind of
like the past 30 years of my life or so
in a very brief like one sentence but
the point is that badge kind of like
rekindle that my passion for tech and
hardware so doing that one thing and
kind of like taking me back to when I
was a teenager and I think that was
maybe five years ago six years ago I
think was like six years ago it's kind
of funny how these little things can
then take you somewhere else that you
had no idea where you were gonna go and
that's where I'm going with this and
there's some links so quick kind of like
the the cool wall so this is uh so
anyone see this tweet anyone who's wall
this is yes sciatic nerd
perfect and how do you know that sir I
actually tested this presentation out on
him so thank you for that Steve
so yeah so Jason collects these badges
he's like you know mr. Def Con so he
wants to collect these badges support
the community here's some of our
creations you can see the arrows we've
created one badge that was like a cypher
disc there over at our table there in
the exhibitor hall one one bad job we
created was a card game so going analog
so two different kinds of analog badges
do your badges need to be digital no you
could still make a really cool badge
that's not digital that's analog and and
people will still love it you know you
can't you don't have to be you know
within like the herd think differently
be different and I got some other like
wisdom pieces of wisdom for you later
but there's in the the red box is the
current badge that's the kids badge and
here's the organizers badge in front I
don't know if you guys if you're not too
familiar with badge life culture one of
the things that we do every year is we
do have like a meet-up we get together
kind of swap badges sell badges talk
about like how we designed it and stuff
and then somebody takes a picture and
you might see it in like hack a day or
something like that so so if you go to
hack a day you'll see I think this photo
or like kind of like a bird's eye view
almost like a fisheye lens on it and we
are right here in the corner we I just
kind of put it down walked away but yeah
it was kind of cool that we're like
right there with all those other
fantastic and amazing and fun designs
it's not rocket science people this is
something that I again depending on your
level of education and your tenacity and
you know your real hacker mentality is
is this something for everybody I think
it's possible I didn't think I'd be
standing here today talking about some
badges that we created for the events
this year and some other things but it
was it's just like anything else if you
really put your mind to it you're gonna
be able to do it you've got to have the
passion that helps you with the drive
but also when you have limitations like
I could kind of write code I don't think
of myself as a developer but I wrote the
code on the badge twice so according to
my friend I guess I'm now a developer
but I don't I necessarily agree with
that but I kind of had some skills from
earlier in my education which I then use
like almost 30 years later because I had
the foundational knowledge it's just
kind of learning and pushing yourself
and and then doing what you need to do
to get it done basically don't quit
right there is a way to get there so
personal like kind of message to you on
this is even if you like oh you know I
have this creative juices and I really
don't know what to do with them talk to
somebody talk to somebody who's done it
they can help you get started and that's
kind of also with this talk is for kind
of whoever can't be here today or is
having lunch kind of help you guys get a
little bit more motivated and inspired
to move forward now part of the like
what Joe gran was doing
if you went to Def Con this year and you
went to his opening badge talk and how
it was really important to get more and
more people into hardware hacking you
know these are some of the reasons right
so here's a one type of a hardware
hacking attack it doesn't say there does
anybody know which one this is you might
get this all right it's row hammer so
it's a little older but it's kind of
like some of the things that came out
we're like yeah now hardware is being
attacked pretty much more frequently I
think you'll know this one because of
the iconography like meltdown but those
are the links to the papers if you want
to read them they're actually pretty
interesting no I did not read them them
an entirety but I kind of skimmed
through and was like how these people
are really smart and I wish I was but
that's the point you teach yourself you
keep going forward you never stop so
let's look at this badge really quick
kind of how we kind of covered some
history and some other problems so the
tyro badge that was created so it hack
for kids we've got the kids they're
known as Tyros they're learning that's
what that word means the chaperones we
call pones a little fun thing for us the
volunteers we call admins and the
organizers called the badges just called
leet set of uber or somebody did that I
didn't name these things so I don't
think of myself as leet that's why I'm
saying that
so the tyro badge for the kids and for
the adults is the white one the admin is
red and the organizer badge which is
what I like to call it is as the black
one so that's the one you see here and
here's the tyro badge or the board now
there's not any real difference on them
so the event that we did in Chicago this
year I did make them a little different
to put different puzzles and it's kind
of easier when you have like a couple of
badges and that kind of makes it fun so
if you're designing something where
people are interacting with people with
badges the colorization of the badge
does help tremendously because then
people kind of know who to go to or who
not to go to if they've already done
something versus having badges that
scroll something and you're like that I
get that
get that and it just makes things a
little bit more clunky and awkward
awkward for people if you're going to
turn it into a puzzle or challenge so
but the new version of the badge or I
call like the DEFCON version of the
badge is really for just about anyone in
anything and it has a virtual escape
room on it which is really pretty cool
so we had an actual physical escape room
at hack for kids this year which had
them have to apply the different things
that they learn usually at an event so
like if you've done lock-picking here
they do lock-picking at a hack for kids
or they will do that tomorrow if they're
also you do anything with maybe
electrical engineering right snap
circuits they had to assemble a radio so
kind of like hidden or locked away in
one part of the room was a schematic and
then another part were pieces and then
they eventually had to figure out oh I
need to build this and when they build
this they're listening to a broadcast
coming from a Raspberry Pi which had
instructions for another part of the
puzzle so lots of layers applying the
skills lot of fun stuff and they had 25
minutes there were some crypto puzzles
too there was a suitcase that was locked
that they had to kind of get through and
only one team finished it which some of
them got close but maybe we made it a
little too hard or maybe we need to
focus more on teaching them the skills
but they all had fun and that's the big
part of it is having fun so that's the
badges so badges have some other fun
features if you want to see one or play
with one we still have some over there
in the exhibitor hall you can kind of
check it out it's got pong running I
don't know if it's still running now but
I have found a demo of pong which old
video game on new hardware that's really
kind of fun the hardware is also I don't
know guys familiar like an ESP 32 I
don't I wasn't planning on getting too
deep into the hardware but we have so
many different LED like IO ports so that
we have our pins we we had to put like
an LED driver so we go from the ESP to
the LED driver to the lights so that
that tends to be a little complicated if
you're new to this thing but we also
have just regular plain old like
monochrome like red and white lights so
that's a lot easier to get to but it's a
fun thing built in Wi-Fi built in
Bluetooth a lot of fun stuff to do just
if you want to kind of get started so
for the kid
it's kind of like they can leave it as
is or they can go to github and look at
the code and learn and then completely
wipe it and make it their own that was
really the intent so when they leave
they had some kind of hacking platform
for them in addition to the fun game so
kind of explained this part already part
of the next generation it's really
important for us to get youths and even
adults exposed to these things so kind
of get their passion going and their
fires fanned just like I was talking
about a little bit earlier um
if somebody is doing this for and here's
the Pikachu so twinkle twinkle I feel
he's really big as the artistic part of
creating the add-ons or there sa OS
special add-ons as a kid president I'm
not going to use the other official word
but it's a special add-on our essay oh
and he's really does some amazing things
with the different substrates and
avoiding things like light diffusion or
controlling light like this particular
and on this it's kind of robably hard to
see this gift add on when it's
illuminated you know the earlier
versions there was light bleed in two
different areas and he didn't want that
so I think he went with three a three
layer board with some copper in between
to control the light bleed and if I
apologize if it's a four layer somebody
will correct me put it in the the
comments or the notes to say you know
fool it's four layers not three or vice
versa
I forgot I had a couple drinks last
night but those brain cells are now dead
but this is really cool this kind of
shows you his passion about making the
electronics do what he wants them to do
from a visual standpoint right so it
doesn't have to be a badge that you
could cereal in and have a whole virtual
world that you can kind of go and hack
into it could be something that's just
visually appealing like my next design
I'm thinking something that's much more
visual and maybe using like an
accelerometer which would be kind of fun
so that's that's that the other things
see if I can get this to work so we got
Captain Kirk so that's there on the
badge this is the phaser so this was the
prototype of the phaser it used red LED
but I wanted it to be a blue LED to
match the actual phaser from the series
of the if you watch Star Trek back and
like you know in the 70s it was blue but
you couldn't get blue LEDs back there
bless you but your boards were that
color green right so I went with the
nostalgic green but with the new blue
board the new blue LEDs which you could
see down here and then you know the fun
one with pong and what you have before
you so this is more for the benefit of
the people in the video kind of see the
video of what you guys see physically in
front of you it's a lot of fun I mean
it's that feeling of just doing the
Captain Kirk face and finding a picture
of him and putting it into GIMP and I'll
talk more about the tools and cleaning
it up and then making it black and white
and then putting it into ink screen and
then trying to get it vectorized right
from raster graphics to vector graphics
and then putting it to Kai CAD and doing
all of that it's a lot of steps and yeah
it could be frustrating and there's a
lot of tools to learn but when you
complete your project that feeling of
self accomplishment and how proud and
the how proud you feel of just kind of
getting over those knowledge hurdles of
you know where before like I never used
Kai CAD like that was the first thing
I've ever created in kai CAD was the
Kirk face I was using other tools and
like Fritzing but the Kirk had simple
blinky eyes but at the same time it's
kind of like that coming of age and then
now I could do more because I've
overcome that first obstacle so no keep
it blinking moving on so where do we go
from here okay so now that we've kind of
laid the foundation of what you could do
and where you are mentally with the
entire process how do you go forward and
actually do this now you know hats off
to anyone who started it even if you
haven't finished it you started it and
and that's really an important thing too
because just getting something started
you could find people that would help
you finish you know this this badge I
had somebody help me do the electrical
engineering design great guy the one the
guy he created the goon badge the
boombox badge I'm actually wearing
coppy kid Mike thank you I was actually
thinking of his company in an MK factor
which is on it but yes thank you copy
kid Mike great work great person to work
with and he helped us with the
electrical engineering and I kind of
worked on the other stuff and I'll get
to that a little bit more but you need
to figure out like what level of quality
do you want you need to know not just
okay we're gonna start but when do we
need to start you got a look at your
project and kind of go backwards I'm
gonna get into these in a bit more depth
I'll get to that later you know why are
you doing this what is your purpose what
is your end goal if you're just saying
well I don't know I just want to make
something you got to think about it a
little bit more again I mentioned some
tools but you've got to find tools that
you're comfortable with but sometimes
like when I was gonna go and learn
Fritzing in the badge life slack channel
they're like no no go and learn cai cad
you'll you'll realize yeah those look
steeper learning curve but later on
you'll really appreciate it and I listen
to them and I see that now
and also how's this gonna be funded so
it's not that inexpensive like little
little things smaller things you could
print up where I'll just speak
specifically the the phaser I think when
it was all said and done probably cost
us around three or four hundred dollars
to produce about 50 which doesn't really
sound that expensive I mean but you
could still kind of buy a laptop
nowadays for about that much money so
from electronic standpoint it sounds
pretty expensive you got to decide you
know what you're willing to spend so
when you pick your team who do you want
on your team the guy with the right hook
of the one receiving the right hook
sometimes you might be the one receiving
the right hook but don't let that get
you down I got a better laugh at this in
Canada with these Toronto teams I wonder
why I guess I got to know my audience a
little better you should've had some
Michigan teams up there so who do you
want to have on your team you know you
want to get the heavy hitters but if
you're thinking like I want that and not
X or team I know they're gonna help me
that's a team of five and they're all
super busy and cups some of them I think
own a business it's gonna be hard but
then you also don't want somebody who's
like apologize if this offends anyone
well I've never really done this before
and I want to get started and I want to
do it because then they're gonna be slow
to start and
you're gonna be relying on them but they
really aren't too sure what to do find
someone in the middle I'm kind of like
that guy I'm kinda in the middle I'm
like past the well I wasn't really sure
had to do this to our first electronic
badge somebody did it I kind of gave him
the yard told him what we wanted and he
did a lot of the work and I learned from
him but the other badge is a lot of that
was me except for this one you got to
keep the time to you got to take the
time to do this so find your team
communicate set up a way that you could
talk on a regular cadence it's
incredibly important to keep the
communication going I'll move on from
there you're also level of quality scope
creep is a huge problem when it comes to
these things and you probably heard this
before yes my puns are koala t when you
say like here's the ten features we want
but here's the three features we must
have you know you've got to focus on the
must-haves first because as I'm like
yeah we're gonna do Wi-Fi we can do auto
updating on the badge and we can do all
these other really fun and cool things
but if we don't get what the core
purpose of the badge is done first then
you have nothing right and and I look at
it as what motivates me which pushes me
is I feel responsible to the recipients
of the badge so the person that has the
badge I feel like I'm obligated to give
them a good experience is it the best
experience you'll ever have I can try
for that but I know I'm not that good I
realize that but I want them to learn I
want them to have fun and I want them to
have like a takeaway and that's my
responsibility my obligation so I said
we got to do that first all the other
cool things all the other fun things
that's gonna have to come later and you
got to have that same mindset of you
could build it for you but you might be
the only one who appreciates it I'm
building these for you guys and that's
my mentality when it comes to this so I
recommend that as well now getting
started like you kind of sit down you
define you know your features and
everything and you kind of like where to
begin and it could be like a really long
winding road
this is like in some mountain range I
think in Germany or somewhere that part
of the world and and you might just feel
like you're going back and forth but
you've got to have time milestones some
of this might sound like basic project
management cuz it kind of really is but
you don't want to just talk about
features and get yourself excited and
get other people excited and then never
start and sometimes you need to look at
when you're going to start something
when do you need to have it ready by and
if you don't know what the road at the
very end looks like getting started in
that road it's just gonna be kind of
like it doesn't really exist at least in
my opinion so when you say like this
badge had to be done it was by like May
1st I said because our event was May 18
and we needed time to flash them when
you're flashing about two or three
hundred badges it takes time it could
take four or five minutes or more you
can run into problems you might run into
a hardware she'd do I want to sit there
and troubleshoot the heart issue or
throw it to the side put a little
marking on it on a piece of paper and
say I'll get to that issue later you
know led else display whatever it might
be and just keep going forward and going
forward and going forward so you need to
have that date when you absolutely need
to have stuff done by add two weeks and
then every other point where you have
features or it's kind of like a
milestone step figure out how much time
you think you're going to need and then
once you've added all that together just
add on an extra month and if anything
slips because it will then you have a
window you've baked in a window but if
you're like well we think this will take
three months so we're gonna get started
three months before when we actually
have it you will not be ready on time
one person in badge life and that was
their first badge that created it was a
young man I'm not gonna name him but
he's a great guy and everything and not
want to name him just because there's
none necessary he worked on a project
and he did it pretty much all himself
but he got the badges stuck in in
customs of China they never showed up on
time for Def Con
I was one of the people that backed his
Kickstarter so I was like really excited
to have it at Def Con and then they
showed up at my doorstep two months
later after Def Con now I say you know
stuff happens I think and you know if
he's watching this not being judgey but
you maybe put a little too much on
himself you know but I also hats off to
that because it's a big project you know
a lot of things happen and you need to
be flexible you need to have the time
and you know it's a lesson learned for
him but he produced it he finished it
there are some people unfortunately they
could not finish the badges and
sometimes people made comments publicly
the badge life people are not trying to
have you you know support them and then
not deliver things happen so when you
you know decide to get it funded through
a Kickstarter or at Indy or something
think about how the recipient feels if
they don't have it and you really want
to make sure that you deliver which is
kind of a slide I'm getting a little
head of myself
delivery is incredibly important but you
got a bacon the time that's kind of the
message here bacon enough time we had
issues with this board and another
personal story with this one trying to
set up the prototype it would take me I
had three prototype boards would take me
four hours just to get one soldered up
and then I had bridging which is when
your solder kind of connects and some
other issues and with the ESP 32 it was
like bridging under the chip so I
couldn't like see under there and trying
to remove it you destroy the substrate
so I kind of had one left I sent it to
comp you kid Mike he looked at and he
goes oh look you're not like connecting
I'm like how do you see that he goes
well I'm using a microscope I was a
magnifying glass I got 50 year-old eye
so I couldn't see that stuff guess what
I did I bought a microscope $135
investment and I use it all the time I
feel like I have Superman vision now
because I just said it to my focus not
like with the glasses on and I see
everything so little things like that
can make a huge difference but we lost
time he found errors on the board I
already gave the approval to start
producing the board's in China never do
that you want to make sure your
prototypes working because we were
running out of time and
I was able to stop what they were doing
in China in time too like they save like
the materials and then they were able to
fix one of the two physical errors that
we had like yeah I mean that's a lesson
learned for me but again I was trying to
stick to my timelines you got to figure
out you know you want to take that risk
it could have been a very expensive risk
but I wanted to make sure we had things
moving along again going back to why are
you doing this what are your objectives
try not to over engineer I think I'm
spending way too much time on some of
these slides I'm gonna go a little
faster
try not to wait oh I mean I love Rube
Goldberg machines I think they're
hilarious I've built a few but your bad
should not be one simplicity is
definitely key and usability if it's
just in your mind you're like yeah I'm
gonna have all these buttons and I want
to do all this other stuff for you it
might be easy to use but for other
people they're gonna look at it and
they'll sigh inside and say I have no
idea what to do with this thing yeah it
looks cool but I can't because you
you've kind of put it to a position
where now you set the bar too high but
if that's your objective then that's
fine if that is your objective just try
not to over engineer it tools that you
could use some people use paint because
you can create a nice vectorized bitmap
with paint go for it if that's what you
want to use some people use Adobe I tend
to go with things like GIMP and Inkscape
[Music]
fruit website if you see like the
graphics with the lines and the
different colors that are wires that's
like Fritzing which is great for
somebody to learn but if you actually
want to produce something that you want
to have like the different colored
solder mask and the silk and have a
different colored substrate and maybe
even have exposed copper it's harder to
do that with Fritzing then then it would
be with Chi CAD but again Chi CAD has a
steeper learning curve because it has so
many capabilities and then you just
produce your Gerber's send them Gerber
files of the files that you give the
people that make the board so they they
understand where things go and
um where to cut it and drill it and
other other really important things
there's also Eagle Eagle has been around
a long time it's also now than another
popular one that people use I just
wanted to put that up there how you
gonna get a paid for what fine sponsor
is gherkin right here right here
cipher con also right on the side it's
there's no um I'm gonna say there's no
shame but I don't even think it's shame
if you don't have the money to do this
and you know you're having an event or
something it's okay to ask other people
because they might really want to
support your mission your cause and they
might want to be a part of your creation
I know for example like CG Silver's he
loves the fact that we have his logo on
the badge and we were able to do that
because we have a big display but if you
don't have a display or you know may not
work out for you because of the
real-estate reasons find a way to get
sponsors to help one person
Johnny Christmas gave me something like
really good advice was we were at cypher
con he's like your display is so big in
your Kickstarter you should put
something so that sponsors can like sign
up right there at the Kickstarter or a
Kickstarter we had three thousand
dollars in sponsor money alone yeah so
it pays and it's absolutely it was a
great suggestion thank you again Johnny
and it works out how you want to sell
them kind of to you right you can go to
Shopify we use that online you could
sell them on tindy a lot of the makers
also love to go to tindy cuz that's
where the buyers are right there also on
Kickstarter but how do they know when
you're on Kickstarter you gotta use
social media you got to get out there so
I'm gonna move on I have more to talk
about this but I'm gonna jump ahead now
that you kind of you know you're you're
thinking about what you want to do and
get started now you've got to work on
your circuit board design how are you
gonna do assembly and then who's gonna
do the coding if it's not you let's get
into that a little deeper so this is the
schematic for this board and again it's
up on github
again thank you Compu kid Mike so you
need somebody that understands how all
these things connect together so you
want to figure out like what tool you're
gonna use for the circuit board design
right so if you said okay we're gonna
use kike a great so now you go forward
and what's it gonna do like
when you had your specs before and said
we needed to do these three things is it
going to be a chip like in ESP 32 or is
it going to be separate chips like
separate Wi-Fi controller separate like
Bluetooth or ZigBee or xB or something
you've got to figure out what those
components are and that's kind of the
stage right here is before you could
connect the things what parts are you
going to use and on the right here is
also the like kind of the layout of the
board so it's a zoom in of the forearm
where I call it the arm pad where we had
some LEDs behind that as well and you
can kind of see where the traces go
where the silkscreen is gonna be you
guys know what the silkscreen is right
and the solder mask all that stuff so
getting your board design and setup
again how much time do you think you
need to do the board design if someone's
like if it's really super complicated
and it's gonna take I'll get it done in
two weeks like is that realistic maybe
say take three take four but maybe no
more than four you really got to kind of
set up the boundaries on this also in
assembly and production I wanted to go
local now
I wanted to start to build a
relationship with somebody I live in the
Chicago suburbs these guys accelerate
assemblies are in Elk Grove Village I
like the idea of when I have the parts I
could drive them over why it saves me
time
wait but you're doing it right but if I
go to ship it I could ship it overnight
and it costs a lot of money but if I
ship it regular and maybe today that's
two days of time lost well then just
plan ahead sometimes things don't always
work that way so when we heard about the
tariffs going up with the components I
bought a lot of parts before the
beginning of the new year to save about
25 percent of the cost because of the
tariffs so I had I don't know I think
was like $4,000 with the parts like
sitting in my house until we were ready
to get to assembly and my wife's like
when are we gonna do with this stuff and
I'm like well we'll get there you'll see
but when we got there and she's like oh
I get it now because she's not very
technical but she kind of like you know
she's very good support
all these crazy things that I like to do
but accelerated assembly I also got to
check out their facility so if you're
going like one of the other companies at
a remote you don't get to see like
solder waves like they had this in there
this giant machine with molten solder so
the board's kind of go over it and it
gets like bathed in solder and then it
comes no one else thinks that's cool
it's like molten solder not just like a
drop like an ocean of it I mean it was
really cool and you get to see the
pick-and-place machine which is like up
there like it's just these robotic arms
moving super fast grabbing and putting
everything accurately and then after
having spent over four hours trying to
do this by hand you appreciate the
assembly another thing to think about
how are you going to do the assembly if
it's a small quantity maybe you could do
it by hand but if it's a high quantity
you're gonna have to say well we might
have to just pay the extra a little bit
of money to save the time and this was
another time-saving thing you know cost
benefit analysis
you gotta weigh it in but I like I said
I want to build a relationship that
pictures it's a picture to show you like
you could be sitting there and soldering
yourself so when you're right in the
code what platform do you want to use if
you're you're you know you like Eclipse
and you're comfortable with that IDE go
for it
you could write all your code in like
C++ or you can write it and maybe Python
there's like micro Python and other
other tools and platforms you could use
I went with what I knew Arduino IDE and
it worked well with this chip all right
so it kind of made sense for me and it
was easy because if I made a change I
could just flash it again flash it again
flash it again at war you could just use
a text editor and then there's they
typically whoever makes the chip
typically has some kind of tools or
there might be some open-source tool
where you can then after you've compiled
your bytecode then write it to the chip
sometimes it requires assembly language
it's kind of a dying art who here here
still writes code in assembly language
right yo I'm not surprised at you Phil
who could read assembly language sort of
but who wants to sit out in like JMP and
then I don't know where we're gonna go
from there it's just wherever wherever
we need to go
now once you've got your your badge and
you've got your timelines you got to
start working on also think about how
you're gonna promote it and you could
use social media there's different
options there of course we'll get into
that keeping track of your expenses so
my original so I started when I was 18
in electrical engineering then I went to
school for accounting so I'm really kind
of an accountant
that's a techie nerd that then said
accounting for the birds I'm now gonna
go and into technology full-time so
fortunately I have that training there
are some people who are brilliant in
technology but they don't get like you
know debit is left credit is right and
when if something goes in something
comes out it has to always balance and
if you don't know where it goes it goes
somewhere you just got to figure out
where it goes
maybe retained earnings or owner equity
so having somebody like you know you
don't need an accountant with just the
bookkeeping tremendously important
because if it's a hobby that starts to
turn into something where you become
profitable you need to figure out like
am I gonna have to pay taxes on this I
may so I really need good accounting
because I don't want to pay more taxes
than I need and then delivery another
one I gave you one delivery example I
can go on with more but I did hear a
story of a friend who had I think three
badges
you know the friend is I had to had
three badges or so and they that this
got lost like they were delivered they
weren't there when he showed up and some
of the makers were really cool because
they had extras and they were able to
replace it but others like I'm sorry
they're all gone there's nothing I can
do all right so there is a risk from the
buy side as well as from somebody who's
building a badge kind of covered a lot
of this stuff right social media you
guys know to use it Kickstarter is good
selling on tindy also helps but
promoting that badge incredibly
important because once you have
something what you want to do is if
you're planning to sell them to raise
money to support your cause or you just
want to have them because you're gonna
you know give them to people like kids
or something but you want people to know
about it you want people to be excited
about it and one person that I think did
a really fantastic job with promoting it
is if you guys saw the the multipass
badge
the Fifth Element he was building his
prototype and taking like really kind of
close up shots and putting them out on
Twitter and social media and saying hey
here's something that I'm working on and
people like ooh that looks cool what are
you doing and then when he released it
I think his Kickstarter was done in like
what 12 hours 12 hours hit his goal and
was like I'm done that is pretty awesome
so hats off to him Romulan bee is his
handle so hats off to him like he did a
really good job with that
accounting use the tools that work for
you you can use QuickBooks which I have
if you really want to get into it kind
of gets a little expensive
Zoho books a little less expensive but
it's online its cloud-based I mean
QuickBooks is also an online version as
well kind of go with what works for you
if you're looking for something that's
simple
Zoho books is pretty good if you're like
you know I don't have any money for any
of this you can go to some you know
office supply store and buy some
columnar pads and just kind of like
write it down purchases for X and then
the you know cash is deducted and assets
or whatever you're gonna put it to is
now increased you do manually but keep
good records when you come to the
delivery you know this was a Canadian
post one but yeah so again know your
audience I forgot to change the mailbox
you could just send it off regular mail
which is one thing that we did you want
to deliver you want to be able to
whether you're delivering in person or
you're shipping it through you know
Amazon Prime air or how are you getting
it to them I gave you a couple stories
already if you're not going to deliver
what's gonna even unfortunately happen
is you're gonna have people that are not
gonna trust you and the more anymore so
people might love your work but if you
can't get it to them they're never ever
gonna come back to you so very very
important or they might even trash talk
you on the internet you know on some
social media site or something and you
don't want that either because now you
got to go through that mess and
sometimes it's just easy to refund the
money to people bless you sometimes just
like hair here's your money back I'm not
trying to rob you just trying to
pay for this fun thing I'm trying to do
no harm no foul let's make it right okay
take the high road
post-production I got a few minutes left
I'm gonna come a little faster but I
think we've covered most of this which
is really good so well when you reflect
bring your team together maybe if you
want do a survey like a survey monkey or
something with your your people who
supported your Kickstarter or however
they may have bought it just say what
did you think what worked for you what
didn't work what would you have liked to
have seen one of the weird things that I
get is with the badge because it had
like a little film on it and so many
times people like my badge is broke and
there's a line here I'm like well no
that's a line to let you know that
there's a tab you can remove so maybe a
little like better usability and how am
I kind of delivering it to people and
just let them know by the way there's a
tab here you need to remove your display
is not broken or just little things like
that can also when they're when you're
asking them for feedback it certainly
shows that you care and that you are
trying to make things better and and the
experiences for them right like we said
before you're gonna have some damaged
goods
things are just sometimes they mean it's
electronic sometimes they don't just
solder up right I've seen some things
while I was flashing and testing some
what LEDs they just did not go on am I
gonna take the time to sit there with a
microscope and try and figure it out and
reflow and and reposition if you got a
short time frame like a deadline this is
looming and coming up on you quickly
that's not the best use of your time
so when everything's done like when
after gherkins done and I kind of get
all the accounting and everything
cleaned up I'm gonna be sitting down and
looking at the 20 some-odd badges that
had some issue somewhere couldn't flash
it to the usb whatever it is take them
apart a little bit and then try again
and see if they could be usable because
at the end of the day like I don't want
to keep all I want to keep a couple but
I really don't want to have like you
know 50 badges sitting in my garage for
the next ten years it doesn't serve a
purpose I want it in the hands of
somebody who's gonna learn from using it
and then when you're done like part of
the reflection think about like next
project are we gonna have an X project
was this painful was it painful did you
do another project afterwards
trying to look it's great right so you
decided okay it's kind of like type 2
fun you guys familiar with type 1 type 2
fun type 1 fun is fun in the moment like
right now that you're having listening
to my talk type 2 fun is when you leave
and you think about the talk you like
man that was really good talk or
building a badge when you're done you
like you know it kind of kind of hurt
some way along the process but you know
at the end I really feel good about
right and I really want to do it again
that was actually kind of fun so some
people like you know boxing you know in
the ring it's not type 1 fun but when
you win it's type 2 fun so things like
that so think about that next project
again in your feedback survey from your
your customers or your people are using
the badge ask them what would you have
liked to have seen like what could have
been something that would have maybe
taken this badge to the next level or
would you want like less visual more
visual more challenges less challenges
more visual whatever it is because again
you're making it for them so think about
that next project and then in a
realistic time frame how much more time
do we have 5 minutes ok I'm nearly done
when you're thinking about that next
project also think about like when is it
a good time to start
I've already started thinking about my
next projects and one I want to make
more visual I think I mentioned it
before with like an accelerometer and
some graphics and we could see if we can
do that I also want to make some others
that can do other different things you
know I'm not going to talk about it just
yet but you want to keep keep doing this
um one of the things I just kind of
forgot to mention when you are doing
these projects and you are thinking
about your next one who are you
competing with yourself if you're like
you know and not X or they make
beautiful educational wonderful badges
but it's a team of 5 and if it's you and
maybe one other person you can't really
compete with them so don't spend your
time and your energy doing something
like that because you're just going to
kind of feel discouraged compete with
yourself so look at what you've done and
what can you do that you've never done
before so like I've never used an
accelerometer so I think that would
actually be kind of fun and then have it
change like a graphic or something when
when the
moves to give it like a 3d effect we'll
see if I can get that pull that off but
I've never done that and if I can do
that I'll feel really proud of myself
I know sciatic nerve will feel pretty
proud of me too and I think it might
just stop there but just you want to
have fun and and just challenge yourself
compete with yourself now you're gonna
get some negativity especially if you're
gonna make it very public and very
visual or visible to people being calm
remaining positive is incredibly
important one if if you get to start to
get discouraged people gonna pick up on
it and then they may or may not have
again faith in you for your next project
but people like positive people right
like who wants to be around like Eeyore
all day maybe not it's kind of cute once
in a while but for the most part no so
keep positive you know make think of
this thing is like your Zen project
something that is is kind of lifting you
up into enlightenment as best as you can
remember to communicate if you have to
communicate here like leonidas I mean
you know he's like here is his team is
dead they're on the ground he's got a
few arrows in his chest it looks like
the end is near especially if you're
doing a Kickstarter your backers want to
know they want to know what's going on I
think I sent out maybe seven or eight
communications just about things because
they feel like they're a part of the
process they feel like they're
supporting your project that they should
know what's going on positive or
negative again I said keep it positive
but if like hey we're having delays
because of something with China customs
or we found like a part is not really
working and we're kind of re-engineering
it they want to know because they're
expecting a deliverable again delivery
and if they see there's a delay they'll
be like okay
most people are pretty reasonable you
just need to communicate it's gonna wrap
up two minutes
I might not really talk about this too
much but somebody brought up like again
like environmental concerns you know
what I don't know how this is gonna
affect the environment to be honest but
when you think about how many badges we
created and all the other electronics
that are being created it's a fairly
small footprint compared to a global
scale now is there some impact
but um I recycle everything if it's not
gonna be like used I take it to our
local cycling hump company it's just
basically the Town Hall but you wanna
and there are some company but you know
beep be mindful of that you don't want
this stuff sitting in the ground for a
couple billion years so some people
bring that up as an issue it really is
not an issue there's more other like
other stuff that's in the ground that's
worse I think I'll stop here so I'm on
folks if you guys have any questions you
could reach me here heal with hands at
hack for kids calm or hack for kids
Twitter account or my other Twitter
account or on Facebook I want to thank
Cisco again for giving the opportunity
to be here today to speak to you folks I
had fun I think I had a couple you nod
off that's okay the yawning it's hard to
fight that but I understand it's kind of
like around lunchtime but thank you for
being here anyway and if you guys have
questions you want to check out the
badge I'll go out this door and we can
kind of coalesce over there is that
sound good oh I got to give this away
mmm
so who's never who wants to work with
electronics and has never really had
like an opportunity to do something with
electronics let me see your hands
none of you why are you in this room sir
with a hand up this is yours all right
well thank you guys okay