I got 12 o'clock we good night Navy good
cool we're gonna get started so
everybody that's coming in still if you
haven't heard please come up front I
have a big pet peeve and I am very very
shy I cannot talk to strangers at all
I'm the dude that goes to the parties
sits in the corner and hopes that
there's a dog there to pet right so
everybody come up be my friend okay come
on
seriously this is a management talk
everybody come on up
yes but it's gonna make it much more fun
and not boring okay okay said this is a
management talk this is a lot different
than the talks I'm usually given I'm not
releasing any new tools today I'm not
dropping any O'Day's here we're going to
talk about something a lot more
important though we're gonna talk about
how to get our work done because if you
see my bonus talk we kind of covered it
a little bit but how many here have
trouble getting budget for security it's
gonna be all of us right as an industry
we're terrible at it and we're going to
talk about kind of why that is right now
and we're gonna talk about how do we
solve this so during my technical talks
I usually have hands-on workshops since
it's a management job we're gonna have a
hands-on management workshop so how many
here is their first security conference
ever wonderful good good good
first gurken whole my goodness all right
there's something really cool about this
industry and this community that we've
built over the years everybody here is
really here to help each other so why
I'm up here speaking how to make sure
that you learn from my mistakes and then
we can have the conversation and kind of
just further the industry so we're gonna
take two minutes I'm gonna put down my
phone and we're gonna turn around
introduce ourselves I don't care if you
use your real name your hacker handle I
don't care
but what we're gonna do is talk about
the one thing that is pissing us off
about the industry and you're gonna find
out that we have a lot of commonalities
so two minutes on the clock
turn around find somebody new go
ah
I don't know what's pissing you off but
good
[Music]
terrorism
don't they understand inside it's a
weird place that we're in right oh we
need marketing the CEO is not the
marketer right we've hired people for
that but for some reason people think
thank you one minute warning if you have
not switched make sure you switch it's
pretty
[Music]
10-second warning wrap it up wrap it up
wrap it up
[Music]
five four three two one
I always wanted to do that that's really
cool all right so again this is hacking
a barter on how to talk to executives
and secure your budget because we're
also so engineers here we are all texts
we all know how to hack stuff why can't
we do this to our boardroom to get our
budget so today we're going to talk
about Oh everybody
protip Pete the parrot is a PT PT P for
shorter than I think these will be
coming up in our presentations that's
offering a little bit of advice as
presentation styles and everything
always have an agenda people forget the
agenda side all the time so why isn't it
important anybody remember giving
directions before Google Maps GPS
MapQuest right it was all right you're
gonna go to this intersection you're
gonna take about five minutes you're to
see a big rock on the corner you're and
take a right there there's gonna be a
Whitechapel you're gonna take a left
there right so this back in the day we
used to have this mental map on how to
get from point A to point B you never
missed the Whitechapel it's right on
your left just past it and then 30
minutes later you're calling them right
so what we want to make sure is our
audience doesn't get lost so we're gonna
build a mental map on where we're going
I am putting my head because I know what
this presentation is some of you much
she didn't download it off and github
everything is up here public available
Twitter github slide deck it's all over
place if you can't find it come talk to
me I'll get to the deck feel free to
take pictures but we're building this
mental map on we're at point a we're
going to get to point B this is how
we're gonna do it so the objective of
this talk is to talk basically we're
gonna talk about how do we talk better
though we need budget we need to do this
stuff to get the job done
we're talking about four things we're
talking about framing the problem we
talked about how to make that problem
real now we're gonna talk about
explaining the solution and then doing
it right so for this presentation I will
be reading the PowerPoint no no no no no
I see this all the time we're gay
technical talks the slides have 800
words on there the font size is 8 you
see thank know there's this great
feature on your computer called
text-to-speech now if I wanted to hear
you read your slides I could just
highlight it and say talk to me computer
they are not here to read your slides
they're not here to listen your slides
they're here to watch you speak they're
here to listen to you they want to hear
your story your slides should be visual
representations of what you're talking
about to help you tell that story no
more no less
so again I said we're gonna talk about
frame the problem
so let's frame the problem this is
something we do terribly as an industry
so from our exercise before shout out
one of the problems that we have over
words alright give me some more budget
success is not appreciated alright these
are a lot of human problems do we have
technical problems too many tools not
enough management cool so let's say
let's pick one of these problems and
focus in on why do I care so here does
anybody do vulnerability management here
ok is it a struggle or are we just
producing reports people patch it it's
wonderful we're in the green we're at
95% patch right now it's terrible so we
know that we need to do vulnerability
management you don't need to convince me
that but you do need to convince your
boss
so let's frame the problem right so why
is the owner ability management a
problem why do we need it that's Tuesday
ok why do I care we're gonna lose data
why do I care my data is public equifax
have you seen their stock since they got
breach it's up right why do I care if I
get breached
we're gonna lose money okay cool so
reputation cool how do we quantify that
because if I look at recent breaches huh
has anybody here stopped sharpness is
shopping at Target since they got
breached we got one two three whoo-hoo
Home Depot t.j.maxx you stop thinking it
was far galore Bank of America or not
everybody's breached who cares why am i
spending money this is where framing the
problem comes in so I'll give you a
story it's not like telling stories so
anybody here have to sell a sin project
I'm not talking about selling Splunk but
like we need detections and correlations
all that's okay so I'll give my
presentation
you know we'd give everything like oh my
goodness look at all these problems I
would have and then I'm gonna need to
put this in so Splunk oh my god I'm
gonna need 32 distributed systems to
handle the indexing we're gonna have hot
cold storage bla bla bla bla bla but at
the end we're gonna have all these
problems that we can fix them boss look
something goes Ryan you must think I'm
an absolute idiot what oops sorry it's
winking to miss on that one what do you
mean sir so right now we have no
problems and you're asking for money to
go create problems and then you're gonna
ask me for more money to go fix those
problems why the hell would I do that
hmm hmm that's an important lesson
learned didn't explain why it matters to
him so maybe maybe there's something
going on here so stats we all know we
need budget the more budget that we have
the more good things we can do so on the
Left we see spend it's left right yeah
on the Left we see spend come and up up
up up up up from 2010 2018 we're
spending more and more so we should see
incidents go down so on the right is the
incident graph and it's not going down
it's going to rather way so it's
somebody outside the industry you go
home so you're telling me the more money
I invest the more incidents we have all
right maybe I'm playing games of stats
right let's take a real world example
Facebook 2017 says they're gonna bolster
security they're going to double their
spend from 7 billion to 14 billion
dollars and then West in a year their
breach done 50 million accounts oops
maybe they spent that extra
hundred thousand they couldn't stop that
one so there's something something going
on here so let's talk about how these
things are framed right everybody know
it's a capital one breach by now right
so this was a headline from the
Washington Post I believe that source is
done here yeah it's Washington Post so
if I'm reading this I look and Capital
One was breached because they embraced
cloud services
does anybody know what's special about
the relationship between Washington Post
and Amazon AWS same owner so you
literally have the only media outlet
that is incentivized to spin this in a
positive way for AWS and they still say
and in the end the embrace the cloud
services couldn't save them it's like if
I read this this is what this is telling
me it's cloud bad knows anybody know how
they actually got breached unsecured s3
buzzes they're breached by somebody that
helped them set up yes that is one story
anybody else know the other stories this
configured firewalls anybody else know
the other stories ma a.m. and anybody
else know the other stories metadata
servers right what else we hear unpatch
since 2015 right we are the security
industry and we still can't get a good
cohesive story on what happened so
here's my challenge everybody here is if
your executives are getting their
security news from the news media you
already lost your game they need to be
coming to you to understand hey what
happened to account for the one do we
need to care about it can you explain to
me how they could have mitigated this
start briefing your executives and your
management and all these things happen
in news because news is gonna get wrong
every time so if we want them to
understand our problems we should
understand their problems does anybody
know how to answer this make money it's
a good start if I make $1 and I invested
100 billion is that a good business it's
probably not
so something more to it so we want to
make money well smile did profits cool
we're getting there
so if I'm Pepsi and I make a hundred
million and I'm coke and I make 1
billion is Pepsi successful depends on
what your costs are cool so protip
people he's gonna help us out
the objective of business is to provide
an abnormal long-term return withholding
nonprofits charities mom and pops that
have different things to kind of take
care of the company right majority of us
are working in public sector the
objective of a business is to provide
normal long term returns haven't all
most important because if I can provide
3% but my competitor who provides 10%
the money should be invested there as a
as a member of the board my job is to
make sure that the investment from my
owners is being spent in the best way
possible
so if I'm making 3% my competitors
making 10% it should be my
recommendation to go invest in the
competitor that never happens but that
should happen right so long-term returns
because if we make a million dollars
today but we lose 10 billion next year
that's not a good business right so
abnormal long-term returns hotel again
how does this relate right so let's
frame the problem so shout out one of
the programs that you guys are working
on nobody's working on anything we're at
a conference we're drinking network
visibility cool so I need a project for
network visibility how does this support
they have a normal long-term return of a
company anyway ok let's break it down so
if we work in security oftentimes if
we're not in a cybersecurity firm
selling our services as security
professionals we rapidly adding value to
the business
all right chances are we're costing the
business a lot of money we're expensive
it's nice well we're expensive right so
why do we care about add value reduce
cost because this is one of the basic
principles
that everybody knows in management we
need to make the profit goal one so that
leaves us two things we can raise the
revenue or you can decrease the cost
right
that's easy math so network visibility
are we gonna add revenue to the company
if we got more visibility into our
network cost are we making costs go up
or down
why would I approve your project alright
so here's the fundamental issue
does anybody know a different industry
that is not security that operates like
security from a business model
perspective because what do we really do
as security professionals if we're not
adding value or reducing costs what do
we do manage risk the risk of the
situation right we're protecting this
formula right we're protecting the
profits because we can protect the
revenue stream right we know that if we
don't have security revenue isn't going
to be coming in because you don't have a
business you got breached you're gone
the revenue drops let's take our network
visibility we can actually reduce costs
with network visibility because right
now we need a staff Asaka thirty five
people because we got all these
different logs coming in we're trying to
correlate different things and it's just
taking way too much manpower if we had
better visibility we could actually
reallocate some of those resources
elsewhere and kind of reduce our spend
over all right so we can actually reduce
cost right vulnerability management when
you go hard on that one because it's a
terrible topic vulnerability management
done right it's gonna reduce your
patching costings gonna reduce your IT
maintenance cost because let's say we
don't patch everything we can offer them
an 8020 rule
idea this is the patch that you care
about you need to get this patch in all
right we're gonna reduce the cost on i.t
minutes this is how we have to be
talking okay now again this might be too
hard there's one last trick I can show
you so your boss has a button don't not
that button don't press that button
that's the button that makes you work
nights and weekends don't press the
right button press the green button I'll
get to boss excited
when you're talking about something what
does your ears perk up chances are it's
tied to his objectives and its goals if
you don't know your bosses goals ask ask
them because that's gonna be tied to the
company's success and the other thing is
it's gonna be tied to his or her bonus
and that makes anybody excited right I
come to you I'm going to say I'm gonna
do this working it's gonna make you
money I'm excited right if you're not
reporting straight to the C so how's
your Cecil's bonus structure work you
make this E so happy chances are you
gonna get some budget right find this
button press it as often as possible
that's gonna start the conversations on
yes I understand the problem right I'd
frame the problem effectively this is
why it matters to the business so
conclusion we need to educate our
management we can't be letting them get
in there security news from the news
we're gonna relate to the solution to
the business and the problem and why
this matters and how it affects the
bottom line and we're gonna press that
bosses button all the time right so
that's step one step two is making the
problem real everybody knows Deming
right process genius of the 80s 70s 80s
somewhere on there stickler for metrics
right so if anybody here has never
managed KPIs or metrics or anything go
pick up this book it's on Amazon eBook
read it on the way home it gives you a
very good fundamental understanding of
what measurements and metrics are how
many of you get asked this I should see
more hands this is our one job so how do
we answer this one not some of those
Russians right we are maintaining an
appropriate level of insecurity okay
how do we know if you can answer these
questions chances are you can skip this
part of the talk a problem is when we
get asked if we're secure we throw out a
whole bunch of words and this is what
they see sometimes where I've been using
words oh I'm gonna need a new sim to
write I OCS and I'm just spitting
letters now this is really hard to
understand if I'm not in the industry
this is easy I don't have to know about
your firewalls or anything - no
something happened between April and May
and since the graph is green it's
probably good to progress this is simple
so thank you for coming to talk to cell
you need to do know so how do we get you
all right so if you're in the American
education system you probably learn the
scientific method back in third or
fourth grade all right we're gonna ask
questions we make observations we're
gonna form a hypothesis we're gonna
figure out how to test that we're gonna
gather some data we're gonna make
recommendations up what we find
excellent maybe I'll learn this one
maybe they're teaching you this an agile
101 no see you dilute credit so I
believe it was the Air Force I got
credited with this who knows if they
actually came up with it but the theory
is I'm in a dogfight I'm a fighter pilot
I need to observe orient decide and act
as fast as possible to make sure that I
live whoever has the tighter you de loop
wins a dogfight same thing in security
same thing project management same thing
in business strategy whoever can react
faster to the changing environment is
going to win there's another one out
here that we cover in class I don't like
it it's really ugly but it kind of makes
sense so this is the critical decision
map and what they do is you tell a story
so I'm going to do this because of this
and then I'm going to do this because
this and the person you're telling the
story to throws in Jack say yeah and you
handle the index oh if this were to
happen I would do this and you make sure
you get out to your fundamental
objective and if you didn't you figure
out why and then that's your process
break down this is a lot of crap to
remember I'll make it easy so those four
steps well question are we try and
answer cool we already did they form the
problem what day's going to show us the
answer
if I want to know which is heavier a
pound of rocks or pound of feathers I'm
probably gonna weigh them I'm gonna get
their masses and I'm gonna compare them
right how we gather data points of scale
so if we want to relate this to security
I have a theory that it takes 8 hours
from initial compromise the laptop to a
full-blown compromise the domain how do
we gather that data red teamers yeah oh
cool so we're gonna hire the red team
we're gonna come in and go hold crap
seven minutes is a lot less than eight
hours okay I'll represent the findings
this is who's our stake holders and
everything so again when we're gonna ask
are we secure we now have things oh well
we run a phishing campaign and last year
is a 33% click rate we introduced new
education systems now it's down to a 12
right metrics don't answer to questions
they reduce uncertainty so now we can
answer this in a fundamental way how are
we secure well I'm gonna throw a bunch
of numbers at you and those are gonna
make sense so now I'm not talking
security I'm talking metrics and they
can understand that I can know that
numbers too big I want to drop that
number how do I do that
now we're talking about explain to the
solution right so now we have them
engaged in our problem we need to talk
about the solution so we're gonna throw
together all these different task lists
and plans we're gonna build some models
about how we're gonna go about it we're
gonna list the project benefits and this
is what you end up with right yeah I
already watched half with you this is
boring make your content to enjoyable
and easy to understand anybody know what
this is it's an eye chart this is the
main page for one of the simplest
commands and commuting this is ping okay
I don't want to read this if you are not
following this Twitter account go do it
now b0r Kim Julia releases comics on
different commands and techniques and
everything in really nice ways I want to
read how Bing works now it's a comic
this is wonderful this is like Sunday
newspaper all right so how do we do that
here
I refer to this in the last talk mist
anybody reading this documents and
staying awake nope all this is just for
inventory you need inventory break it
down all this all this stuff right here
can be set in four sentences just say
the four sentences this is easy to
understand I can grasp it and look I got
numbers on there too good going back to
this is a terrible screenshot anybody
know what I'm trying to convey here nope
make your screenshots easy to follow huh
I'm in a security conference
what is this trying to show Metasploit
cool what am I trying to tell in my
story
we have no idea oh yeah I'm trying to
show you that it's vulnerable Oh 8 67
honey this one's a little better welcome
and am i running and what am i doing
exponent users cool which user do I care
in the solution so this is how we solve
stuff right we create project charters
we create project plans for poles as all
this stuff and again who cares now let's
try something different so what we're
going to do is I got this problem it is
taking it takes about an hour from
initial compromise to fold the main
compromise and given our response times
and everything we get about 30 minutes
two hands on keyboard so we have less
than 30 minutes to react to this and
actually clean it up that's kind of crap
because there's no way we're gonna do
that so what I want to do is along at
that time and the way I'm gonna elongate
that is with an idea called active
defense and cyber deception that was
cool it worked
as I click the button everybody's eyes
straight to the screens you started
reading it you're engrossed in it you're
going to read what I want you to read
now and you're gonna like it right so
this is wonderful because management's
gonna read this and it's gonna govern
some questions and we're gonna start a
conversation about this here's a problem
that is absolutely useless to us as
technical people what the hell am I
gonna implement here no idea that's why
you do all this work still because this
work is gonna be what enables your
success to deliver on this one
we can enable frictionless work six and
seven go together generate the short
term wins make it easy to win and start
gaining that confidence in your board
because when you can do that and you
sustain the question isn't why do you
need a budget is how much do you need
and that's a really good place to be
these guys last step is Institute change
I don't like that one so many legacy hey
this is what we're here for it so in
conclusion well maybe one more tip
always have a conclusion side because if
you did this right this is a nice little
bow on your presentation all right third
trick is the conclusion is just the
agenda slide renamed because if you said
I'm gonna talk about this and you talk
about it this is what I talked about
alright I had one more them it's may a
legacy always in the collection so what
I want everybody to do here I talked a
little bit about all these different
problems that we have and why we have
the problems and how we're going to
solve them I want you to think about
personally who do you want to be in the
workplace I want you to think about how
you're going to do that what support do
you need who's gonna help you enable
your success how do you build these
relationships to make sure that you
become the trusted advisor the security
professional how do you become elite
right we are here to be the absolute
best that we can be getting budget is
going to enable you to do this and grow
and grow and grow
and with that I'm out of time thank you
everyone I got questions in the hallway
[Applause]
[Music]