good morning come and find a seat if you
didn't know thank you so I'm only about
25 minutes so about 15 slides I really
want to talk to you a little bit about
how surfing relates to security and my
experiences over the last thirty years
from security and probably the last four
years from surfing and there's a lot of
analogies that go along with this track
so really we are in security to help our
organizations protect their data their
people the brand and I'm going to talk a
little bit about what you could do for
your organization to then follow those
those creases that as security people
are basically following for
organizations that's why we get paid so
the agenda plan the work work the plan
tools why the matter actions
practice makes perfect or at least
better have fun find other people that
share your passion because I think the
most successful people in security are
the passionate ones I interview people
every single week whether they're for my
team the company or for other
organizations that we work with and if I
can't see passion and that person that
I'm talking to they automatically get
put in the other pile
because I don't think you could do this
job if you're not passionate about it
it's not a nine-to-five job and then
reflect on the past learn and find some
new challenges which I call the waves so
here's my labels I've been a leader of
my entire life whether it's the captain
of the football team president of
eternity
coach blah blah blah I like the
leadership positions I like teamwork I
like to learn I've gotten my MBA my
cissp those are things I needed to do to
make it into the corporate world and get
the get the Cecil position so I've been
a CSO for twelve years until I joined
CBI we're a cybersecurity consulting
company what I do really is go help
organizations look at their strategy if
they have one if they don't build one I
look at their team's look at their
technologies look at their tools along
with the entire portfolio vote CBI
offers and we put them on the right path
so basically I've been doing cyber since
1993 started off as a UNIX admin doing
that then doing broke into my first
computer probably before then but in the
corporate world broke into my first one
but within the first week of my job and
trying to secure those kind of or those
machines I got the bug they didn't
really have a security title but I was a
UNIX admin for quite some time moved to
the networking team did some development
then I was in Oracle DBA for 14 years
and then in 2006 switched over to a
Cecil role and had been doing that up
until last year so I think I'm qualified
to talk a little bit about the
technology side and then also about
making organizational change because you
could have the greatest technology the
greatest code the greatest ideas but if
you can't communicate that well you're
gonna sit in your cube and you're gonna
have great ideas and you know to talk
about at the bar and say you can do all
these great things but if you're not
helping your company you're not doing
your job you're creating cool technology
and doing things for fun but ideally as
passionate people we want to bring the
value to our organizations and grow
ourselves and help protect the company
so I think before you can help the
company you have to understand what the
strategy is of the business every
culture is a bit different every
business
functions in a different way some are
more risky some are less risky so
understanding what the drivers are for
the company helps you frame your
messaging and until you understand what
the what the business goals are you
really can't put an effective strategy
in place whether you're the CSO or the
admin or the network director you also
have to understand what your superiors
are doing and you have to communicate
that down to what your direct reports
are doing it all goes together whether
you're an endpoint guy a network person
a developer they all have to be seamless
because all it takes is one crack in the
in the portfolio and the strategy and
then your name or your organization is
in bad light in the paper and when I
joined Oakland County as their Cecil in
2013 my whole premise was keep Oakland
County off the front page of the paper I
knew I was the fall guy I was a security
consultant brought on to assess and
build a program for Oakland County there
was nothing there before I showed up how
was the fall guy
it was my brand and but most importantly
it was all Brooks Patterson who was the
county executive and his entire
portfolio that he built it was all
dependent on a security breach he
preached we are one of the best in the
country I didn't want my name to tarnish
Oakland County's image so I thought I
took that to heart very passionate about
it I looked at what they had to do I
went and talked to all 23 directors of
the what I called the kingdom's inside
Oakland County and found out what their
business drivers were the prosecutor the
sheriff the medical examiner all these
people and find out what they are trying
to achieve from their business then I
could properly build the strategy around
it I came from a manufacturing
background I also worked in utility and
Finance different type of cultures
different type of mandates in the
manufacturing world it was whatever the
CEO said at the time followed suit in
Oakland County it was whatever these
twenty three kingdoms decided to do
within their kingdoms that's how they
ran their business totally different
environment
I would not be effective if I used the
same strategy at the manufacturing
company that I would if I had at the at
the government cuz in manufacturing the
CEO says yes everybody follows suit at
the county one person has
argument and then I have to go have
three to twenty three different
conversations with 23 different people
and potentially 23 different solutions
the different type of strategy at the
rollout so understanding that will help
you build what's most valuable for your
culture
I suggest selecting a framework just
pick a framework that works best in your
industry whether it's a NIST framework a
CIS 20
ISO finding out what's works best in
your sector because you're gonna want to
compare at least your leaders are gonna
want to compare what you're doing to
what the county is doing the next or if
it's a manufacturing company what are
they doing how are they comparing to you
everybody wants to be a little bit above
average or or better than most but they
don't want to overspend it's your job to
make sure you put them in the position
where they want to be nobody wants to be
the under spender and nobody wants to
over spin and be laughed at basically by
their peers and say why are you
investing all this information and
resources it's not needed so you have to
you have to balance it that's well how
kind of equates to surfing I had been
doing lots of team sports until I was in
my low early 40s playing basketball and
football as I said I really like team
sports but then I started tearing my
calves and my Achilles tendon store so I
had to kind of give up playing sports I
had to switch to something new
so I switched to wakeboarding well I'm
switching to wakeboarding when you're 42
it's hard on your body so these epic
wipeouts said I was taking as I'm going
35 miles an hour seven feet in the air
may come in a Monday Monday morning work
pretty hard so about four years ago I
switched to surfing if you haven't seen
wake surfing you go about 11 miles an
hour you can actually drink a beer while
you're surfing you can hang out you can
talk to somebody on the boat you play
the music it's a lot of fun it may be
going to work on Monday mornings a lot
easier but I had to learn how to balance
because when I first stepped on a
surfboard is way different than a
wakeboard I would just fall over and
until I started practicing I would have
these epic wipeouts that my friends
enjoy but I didn't enjoy so much so
there's a balance there
so here understanding the top management
support understanding what your
landscape looks like to figure figure
out what the right type of balance you
can play and you're in
you have to also understand your
expectations so what's the wave that you
want to ride it all depends on your
culture and you'll see later in the deck
when I talk about what works best it's
about people
a little picture of Jerry Maguire one of
my favorite movies relationships
relationships matter your career your
organization could depend on one person
and it's that one person that you have a
relationship with that can make or break
the brand of your company or yourself so
I found building relationships is the
most important thing to do when you're
talking about information security I
never found myself to be a sales person
until I got in the sales side of things
but I figured as a Cecil I'm actually
the one of the ultimate salespeople
because I have to impact change in an
organization that does not want to
change and it makes it sometimes harder
but for good reasons so you have to be
able to communicate that to make people
change the way they've been doing
business for thirty years it's a
difficult job and sometimes it's an
extra task but there's the benefits once
you understand that you can use those
relationships to position your message
another great movie in the 90s so this
is a the whole movies fun for me but
it's about positioning your message so
Billy Hoyle is basically a hustler in
basketball if you haven't seen white men
can't jump
great movie he goes out and he just
hustles the street and wins a lot of
money doing this but it's a balance
about how he's positioning himself he
has these gray socks long shirt baggy
shorts a hat backwards not what you
typically see on a basketball court I
grew up playing basketball on the east
side of Detroit I never saw a guy like
that playing basketball if it was
anybody was probably me that looked like
that guy playing basketball
so it was positioning myself or
positioning your message to be able to
get in and win win your objectives so
tools
I see people processes and technologies
as tools they're all components to a
business outcome and I always always
focus on people I think with the right
people you can make the biggest impact
just like with the right wave you can
have your ride the longest or could be
the shortest so this is kind of some
transitions between surfing and security
if you don't have the right people or
the right wave you're not going to surf
long and you're not gonna last long so
what you can do is find the right people
make the right wave that you can ride
long how do you do that understand what
your processes are so the speed of the
wave matters the height of the wave
matters and the weight of the boat that
you're behind makes a huge difference in
the way that it creates so understanding
what components make up the processes is
the next most important step
technology is the tools that you
actually use to create that business
outcome so for me it's the boat it's the
surfboard I've got boards that have a
1-inch fin and only one of them
I've got boards I have four inch fins
with with five inch depth they were used
for different things if I want to spin I
use this the board with a small little
thing if I want to go super fast and
jump out of the wave I use the five or
the four fin board different things for
different outcomes just like you at your
job
if you want to communicate something
with finance talk to them about what
matters in finance getting records
cleaner of having faster access it to
anywhere understanding what makes it
easier for them to do their job makes
the difference but always focus on the
people decisions one of my favorite
things so how do these things kind of
relate together so when you're going to
the store and you're going to look for
an Apple how much time do you take to
make that decision whether gonna get
this Apple or that Apple probably not
much decision right you look for any bad
spots I'm gonna buy it you know why
because it costs you less than a buck
and the impact of getting this Apple
over that Apple impact is the key word
is not much right no not much of a
difference okay think about you're gonna
redo your kitchen how much does it cost
injury to a kitchen between 20 and 50
grand maybe you're gonna think a little
bit harder you're gonna interview some
consult you're gonna interview some
contracting companies take some
recommendations I'm gonna put more time
into the decision because there's a
bigger impact to you just like in your
organization some decisions you can make
really quick and you shouldn't spend
much time thinking about those others
there's a long play think about those
long played to say
and get feedback from other people
there's a bigger impact here when you're
thinking about things and the last is a
scalpel I've had I don't know eight or
nine surgeries throughout my my life and
I had interviewed people I got
recommendations from doctors I looked at
recovery time whether to have it have a
surgery or not have a surgery and
sometimes I elected not to have a
surgery and do physical therapy because
the impact of my life was too big to
have that one surgery but you put a lot
more time and thought into the impact of
a surgery than you would over buying an
apple just like in your job think about
the impact that these decisions that
you're making every single day can
impact you and your organization what I
find when I talk to a lot of people is
they fail to take an action and I say
change is okay if so I would rather have
someone make it a decision take a step
and realize it's the wrong step and then
take a sidestep you've actually made
some progress it may not be the most
effective progress but in life you think
you have this pick this very straight
line you don't you have this jagged line
and why do you have this jagged line
because you're making decisions but
you're progressing typically you don't
start here and go down you're making
decisions that are impactful and that
you are trying to achieve something so
making a decision is okay being the
chief no officer is not okay locking
everything down don't do this you can't
do this being the fear monger doesn't
work it's you're gonna be booted out and
not listened to and people are smart
that's why we've survived because we're
smart and we are innovative we find ways
around processes we find ways around
guards we found ways around systems that
are put in place to control us humans
exist because we were innovative and if
someone wants to do a job that you put
all these protections in they're gonna
do it probably in a more insecure way
than the originally planned because you
put all these controls in so don't do it
have the conversation be a negotiator I
have an example I try to get the sheriff
to do something and he said I'm in a
locked building I've got two deputies in
front of my office with guns I have to
run or two guns no one's gonna mess with
me kind of mentality well are you here
at six
o'clock at night no people have acts at
the cleaning crew has access to your
data has access to your files has access
to your computer
let's wrap a couple controls around
there and then once I started
negotiating about locking your files in
having a tighter screensaver window
certain things that I thought were
important to it to me he said that
sounds reasonable
no problem and then I had him forever
every other decision I wanted to take
he's felt that I understood took the
time as a technologist as what he looked
at me as an IT guy - time to go over
there understand his point of view I
communicated my point of view and we had
a happy outcome it was great
but having that solution negotiation
mentality will go way too far also
understanding what your peers are doing
I talked to CISOs every week and as soon
as I say you know your competitors are
doing X Y & Z they start to lean in a
little bit more they want to know what
their competitors are doing from a
security standpoint are they keeping par
are they doing more are they doing less
because ultimately their bosses are
gonna be talking oh you're not doing X
you're not looking at thread Intel we
found some great things we found this we
did this and we did that always look at
your peers for great ideas you don't
need to come off the ideas yourselves
use the people that you have in your
network the people down the street I
found that I spent the first seven in my
year seven years of my life and security
focusing I was in an international
company so I talked with my peers within
my own company and I only got as good as
those peers in my own company once I
left and started talking to Tier one
suppliers healthcare CISOs all these
other type utility sees those we had
great ideas that I don't even thought of
because it wasn't in my vertical but
there were probably good ideas that
transitioned to my new group to my new
role so I leveraged those ideas I took
power points and said I'm just gonna
change the name wrapped a couple new
boxes in there and say I'm gonna use
your stuff and they were they were happy
to give it to me and likewise I shared
with them I would go to their their team
meetings and and talk to their team
about how they can better improve their
security so these lessons learned across
even verticals are helpful
but also keep in mind that you have to
not blindly follow everything that one
organization tells you use your own
brain you know best what will work in
your organization and if you don't ask
questions you can't just say take the
the direction of your your superiors and
say this is what you must do what you
could but I suggest that you don't I say
how always have a counter-argument and
say well what if we did it this way or
this makes sense but have you considered
this just blindly following this
protocol in my opinion you're not you're
doing your you yourself and your
organization a disservice practice makes
perfect
or at least better haven't that I think
we get the perfect but at least better
and I always say start small so you
can't change the entire organization and
there's for all security controls and
come in and say they're here we did an
assessment there are 700 bad things that
we're doing starting tomorrow we're
gonna change everything that just
doesn't work but start at something
small that you can have a positive
change for a low cost and a quick
turnaround time with a big impact I
always use time cost and impact as my
decision points when I'm doing security
is it cheap is it easy and is there a
big impact if I can find those things
those are great quick wins I'll do those
all day long then you start to build
your case it's a good strategy to take
that's made it effective for me in my
career again learn from others and teach
I think preparing for things like this
talking to people you'll have a friend
for life I've mentored people inside my
company I've mentioned people outside my
company when you are put on the pedestal
to teach someone you actually have to
research a little bit more and figure
out you do you really know this topic
you may think you know this topic but it
may change in the last 10 years and
you're like I used to know Dean that's
pretty well well man I haven't really
kept up with I know Dean s everybody's
internal CMS but really attacks have
changed things have changed methods have
changed technology has come out
there's tool changes things have
definitely evolved so if you're in a
position where you actually have to be
you're the expert you have to go out and
teach somebody I actually had to go out
and do my own upkeep you know refreshes
of certain things but you'll definitely
have a friend for life I've got friends
that I've mentored and we're good
buddies now so that I'm learning from
them which I taught them things 12 years
ago my direct reports probably every
single job I still keep in touch with
when we share family stories and we and
we share professional stories and I'm
learning from them and they're learning
from us from me so it's fantastic and
then write down your goals I've this
picture is I had a wrist surgery back in
2011 and the sarai two surgeries on my
wrist the first one failed the second
one either have a full reconstruction of
my wrist and the doctor said you
shouldn't lift anything more than 225
pounds and I still work out today I've
worked out since I was 19 I go four to
five days a week and I've done that for
thirty years consistently because that's
what I like to do there's a couple
things that I'm passionate about one is
information security two is working out
and then I picked up surfing in the last
four four years but working out as much
as mine is my jam I love doing it I feel
great about it you'll see in a slide
deck but I've got goals I've written
down my goals how much I weighed how
much I lifted since 1993 it was in paper
format up until 2003 and now it's
digital so I can go back and tell you on
October 5th of 2007 what I was doing how
much I was deadlifting how much I was
bench pressing how much I weighed
yada-yada-yada because that's what I'm
passionate about I like to teach people
I've had one workout partner that stuck
with me the last five years I probably
had 50 workout partners since nineteen
but this is the guy that we would ride
to the gym together every day and we
hang out we're great friends we're
passionate about we push each other and
I found that he's probably my best
friend now because we're passionate
about something and we love to do the
same thing we from the workout
perspective it's great but without
writing it down I would never achieved
this which was my Pete my personal best
dead lifted this which is 510 pounds a
month ago prior to this summer I had
only done 470 the most and I hurt my
back when I tried to do more and I would
revolve and try it again and try it
again and then finally I said you know
I'm not it's not worth it one day I felt
great
the gym and I put on some what I put on
some crazy rock music white zombie and
went in there and I felt great and I
pulled up five ten so if to me that was
cool I'm proud of it I'm passionate
about it this is something else
so while surfing it's light out longer
I'm drinking more beer and I'm eating
more bad food because we're staying out
later on the weekends so I put on 10
pounds over the summer time even though
I continued working I was putting more
calories in the more calories burned so
I said okay fatty time to burn some
calories to get at it so I said I want
to get down to 185 I was up to 196 I
said I'm gonna give myself 50 days well
today is day 35 so I stepped on the
scale yesterday I got down to my goal in
34 days and primarily it's because I
exercise 40 minutes a day every single
day for 34 days and I ate eggs with
broccoli and hot sauce for breakfast
every day two cups of coffee and a
protein shake and it sounds kind of
gross maybe to you but I feel phenomenal
I've got so much energy that I'm not
putting potato chips in I'm not eating
ice cream I'd grab a cookie for my kids
I would do all these things that I'm
working out five days a week I can have
that well what happens if you keep doing
that you put on ten pounds and you're
not happy about it but writing down the
right goal got me to my objective two
minutes left
all right so two more objectives I think
keep it simple I'm a huge fan of the
power of three if you can whittle down
your message to three things you want to
do you'll achieve those three things if
you have more than three most likely
you're not going to accomplish those as
quickly as you probably could so focus
on the power of three so it's a great
marketing message people can remember
three things you should do it what's in
it for them when you're speaking with
people especially about cyber always
include what's in it for them you'll get
their attention and you'll probably a
lot be a lot more successful focus on
the strengths of the people in your
organization there's a lot of people
that have great strengths that we never
leverage do it passion is contagious
hang out with people that are passionate
about the topics whether they're in your
company or outside your company that's
why you're here probably hang out with
more passionate people
execute I call it GSD get done find
others that are passionate we have less
than a three a six degree of Kevin Bacon
and IT security it's a one degree of
Kevin Bacon an information security you
know everybody or at least know somebody
that knows everybody walk around here
you can't walk around without just doing
this handshaking people especially the
people have been in for a long time so
find people that give you energy hang
out with them you grow and you keep
feeding your passion some days you feel
like this Security's not easy some days
you want to take a break and just chill
that's ok take that day re-energize get
back at it reflecting on the past so
I'll review yourself quarterly look at
yourself look at your or have you made
progress
are you trending up are you trending
down do yourself some positive marketing
people don't do that enough celebrate
with your team they need the support
they need your help they need to
understand that their passion may is
making a difference
I'm telling you that they'll do run
through brick walls for you strong teams
can overcome obstacles if you can tell
it like it movies in the 80s this is
breaking the rules culture rules
everything people can make it or break
it
scope doing this sauce small simple
things the three things that matter
focus on them continue a networking
commit and do community work look for
new challenges we grow when we're
stretched and keep learning so sorry I'm
out of time but I'll be around the CBI
booth in the vendor Expo if you want to
chat with me I'm very passionate about
what we do and what I do I'd love to
talk to you guys more if you have some
questions on your goals and your
organization's thank you
[Applause]