did they get the beer machine fixed well
I see beer so it must be yes
somebody told me last when there's no
the beer wasn't working correctly so I
just wanted to double-check before I
walk all the way over there so well
thanks for being in our afternoon
session we're going to talk about
symbolically executing a fuzzy tyrant
with our friend logical all right
thank you very much everyone uh I will
be talking about symbolic execution
fuzzing that sort of stuff today I have
a flair for whimsy so you'll notice that
this is mostly using Nabucco verdes
Nabucco as a theme has no tie-in
whatsoever but you'll see it throughout
the talk my name though is stefan
Edwards I am the assurance practice lead
at trail of bits if you're not familiar
with Trello bits we are a low-level like
cyber security research firm we do lots
of like blockchain sorts of stuff in
tech reverse engineering those sorts of
things you may be familiar with our
tools I myself work in defense
blockchain IOT compilers that sort of
stuff a lot of our VCO Services
procedural services go through me and I
also do like our threat modeling things
if you read the kubernetes threat model
or if you saw the the kubernetes
technical assessment for the CN CF that
was myself and my team at Trello bits
you also may have heard me on absolute
apps a core risky business which just
came out I think yesterday so just two
warnings
I'm extremely hard of hearing I'm also
extremely sick at the moment so my
hearing is completely gone so if you
have questions and I ask you to repeat
like 37,000 times it's just from that
and then I'm also from New York
I slept enough so my accent shouldn't
come out but if I do speak too fast or
if my accents too thick or anything like
that just let me know so what are we
actually talking about today today we'll
be going over some of the basic tools
that we use to understand code right and
then we'll move a little bit deeper into
the stack of things and I'll explain
what I mean by that as we go through but
I wanted to talk about first the the two
major ways that we attempt to understand
code currently and then try to try to
suss out what
sort of coverage we get from those
things and then move into fuzzing
understanding what maybe we think of as
fuzzing versus what someone from trail
of bits or from some of the other
speakers I think Jared DeMott is
speaking on on symbolic execution and
fuzzing later but what others may mean
about fuzzing and that sort of thing and
then move into symbolic execution what
it is and what I'm using it for in my
personal time I'm releasing a framework
today and I apologize I'm presenting out
of marpe normally I don't but for some
reason mark is generating a bad PDF
today but this talk mainly covers three
things I really want you to understand
that we can do better than traditional
tooling right the sorts of things that
we run to understand code we can do much
better than that
for malware for pen testers for whoever
you are and then I want to explain what
the hell does this actually look like
right very frequently you'll see things
that reference formal tooling formal
verification symbolic execution it's not
really nearly as scary as it might
necessarily sound the framework that I'm
releasing today it's up on github it was
written in about a month it does some
Pathak's pleurae ssin and things like
that it's very simple very
straightforward to follow but these
these sorts of things are not used by
the vast majority of folks because it's
like this hidden area of academic
InfoSec that we don't normally touch
upon and then the last is how to make
these things much more accessible right
there's a lots of papers on these sorts
of things Fabrice good gutta freud will
publish on these sorts of things we've
published on these sorts of things but
they're not really accessible for for
normal folks people don't think of these
sorts of tools when they're thinking of
how do I understand my code how do I
understand what I'm doing so I want to
try to break down that barrier and make
it a little bit more accessible but if
there's three things that you really
take away from this talk is that there's
nothing wrong with the way that we do
traditional tooling for code for for pen
tests for those sorts of things there's
absolutely nothing wrong with it it does
have its place I'll talk later
but as much
I love symbolic execution and think it's
super interesting lots of findings can
come out of it I still find most of my
findings either with fuzzing or with my
own two fists very little of what I find
is necessarily from symbolic execution
symbolic execution can colic execution
those sorts of things they help a lot
they helped me understand the
constraints under which things execute
and whatnot but traditional tooling
still shouldn't be thrown out just based
on anything that I'm presenting here
today or Jared or anyone else presents
and that formal verification techniques
themselves are not actually that scary
they're very accessible once you
understand what they're doing once you
understand what they're actually how to
use them they're not very difficult to
get into themselves even though they
might necessarily be a little bit more
academic than what you're normally doing
and then lastly I wanted to just give a
really quick really brief introduction
to the sorts of program analysis things
that we do so what is actually program
analysis right programs actually have a
space over which they execute now I'll
demo what I'm talking about in a minute
but there's a large space that we intend
so if you think about your program as a
graph and all the things your program
can do you probably intended for it to
do a very small slice of that entire
graph of potential actions and yet
attackers people like myself reverse
engineers whomever will discover the
entire set the entire domain of of
operations that your program can
undertake so that's what we're
attempting to uncover we're attempting
to find the ways in which your program
can operate in unintended consequences
and there's there's multiple techniques
for you doing this I'll talk about
fuzzing the various techniques of
fuzzing I'll talk about symbolic and can
colic execution but there's a large
world of both academic and practical
methods for actually uncovering these
sorts of things themselves but
effectively whenever you hear me say
program analysis you can just think of
it as very fancy potentially automated
and very formalized debugging itself so
has has anyone heard of weird machines
before perfect one person - maybe so
weird machines is is this actual area
I'm talking about these are the sorts of
things that your program is normally
meant to do you may have codified it to
accept some user input and do something
on it and then there's an entire
universe of think of other things that
your program can do from unintended
consequences and these are called weird
machines there's several names for them
but that's that's the most common name
that you hear and there's many different
techniques for actually exploiting
discovering and actually using weird
machines for all sorts of fun things so
I think the most interesting one are the
three that I've I've picked here
everyone knows Rob gadgets right yes
at least I've heard about them right so
Rob gadgets are certainly a type of
weird machine but I think the more
interesting ones are that the move
instruction on x86 is actually Turing
complete so you can use move no other
instructions whatsoever with in x86 to
completely encode effectively any
program that can be encoded in a Turing
machine so that's a neat one and then
pythons pickle is also another one
pythons pickle is a serialization format
similar to like JSON or something like
this but it's actually implemented as a
virtual machine so most folks use it to
store class or maybe some structured
data in a dictionary or something like
that but pickles can actually execute
all sorts of functionality external to
that so discovering those sorts of
things is a lot of fun if you ever see
things that use pickles or consume
pickles from untrusted sources you
basically have remote code execution and
it's fun because I've actually created a
ripple that compiles a small subset of
Python into pickles and then executes
sit on the target machine so when I'm
thinking about programs the techniques
that I'm talking about will fit into one
of these areas right in the in the top
left over here we have the potential
domain of your entire program and
ideally we have this little box that we
expect our program to actually execute
that's what we want our program to
execute but the ways in which we
actually discover if our program does
that very to the way to how much they
actually map to our ideal so
traditionally we may have spot checks we
may think of something check it and then
we'll put a little dot and hopefully
those forms
for a little box we may create tests but
these tests can test anything that we
want them to they don't necessarily have
to test anything that's related to the
program itself correct functionality we
have no idea what they actually end up
testing we can fuzz the bejesus out of
something right we can have this giant
Oort cloud of things we have no idea how
this relates to things necessarily and
then we can use these higher-level
techniques that I'll be talking about
today abstract interpretation and
symbolic execution but those don't
necessarily get you to an ideal either
they may map out a domain of what your
program is doing but it doesn't
necessarily mean that it maps to your
intended domain I know this is crazy and
there's probably a lot of people who are
thinking what the that I just walk
into
but I'll hopefully explain most of this
but more than anything I want you to
walk away with this talk or from this
talk that you can understand code using
automated techniques discovering
constraints discovering these sorts of
weird machines that are in programs that
are in software that you'll be using and
apply them to the domains that we work
in
I at trail of bits obviously run the
assurance practice I do quite a bit of
like you know the normal code reviews
and those sorts of things right we do
hire surance we're Cottrell vets but
still we look at a lot of code so for us
understanding code is is bread and
butter to what we do but there's nothing
stopping folks who work in malware
analysis who work in reverse engineering
from applying many of these same
techniques and indeed there are
mechanisms for applying what we'll be
talking about today - like reverse
engineered code so before I dive into
those higher-level technique techniques
and before I dive into the sorts of
things that I think are better that we
can be using let's let's talk about some
of the traditional tools that are out
there so traditionally we have two basic
divisions right and this is probably
semi controversial to say this but
there's two basic divisions of what
we're talking about we either have
dynamic testing in which were we're
actually exercising the system under
test an application code whatever it is
and we have static testing
and that's the the usual dichotomy that
we see so these are the sorts of things
that might scan code look for
misconfigured credentials look for
default credentials that sort of thing
or they would go through you'd see your
fortifies your your rats your splints
those sorts of things and just look
through for dependencies this is the
traditional stack as much as as much as
we want to move beyond this this is
really the dichotomy that we focus on
even though we can move beyond these
sorts of things so in a static world
we've all seen linters we've all seen
those sorts of like code check tools
we'll look at some today unsafe function
checkers basically things that either
look through for Strings grep for things
whatever they are and then we have the
the dynamic runners themselves if you
work in MySpace they may be something
that you know goes through a web
application goes through blockchain
exercises ER c20 functionality something
like that or it may just be malware that
you run in a sandbox but those fall into
basically the dynamic domain themselves
and these are the simplest possible
tests that you can run these are the
sort of like you must be this tall to be
audited sorts of tests that you have and
whilst they do provide usable usable
findings and usable bugs they're usually
lower quality or lower issue lower
severity sorts of bugs for several
reasons right and we'll get into that
but partially because you just don't
know much more than the actual location
that something has occurred so let's
take a let's take a quick look at this
some C code right not everyone's going
to know C but just some simple code here
right this is actually something that I
use for interviews when folks come in
right now hopefully several people have
spotted a few different bugs here but
there's actually a subtle bug in here as
well that not everyone catches so we
have some simple C so the simplest
possible type of scanner that you can do
is something that just checks for
Strings right we've all done this we've
grep through some code we've used act
through some code we use rats for things
to look for for Strings within code
bases and
indeed rats does actually find some
things in here there are some problems
with this source code that rat rats
actually captures so we do get two hits
that they call two gets is is incorrect
and the call to stir copies is
problematic the F gets recommendation
itself is fine there's nothing wrong
with what rats suggests for it F gets
instead of gets the stir copy one is
everyone familiar with stir or is anyone
familiar with stir copy itself few folks
so stir copy one is is not so useful but
it's about as simple as we get we have
no set-up time there's no understanding
literally anyone can run this code and
look for things that are problematic air
so we may want to upgrade ourselves we
may want to see okay look
rats doesn't give us very much
information will run splint splint does
some higher-level checks it reports six
things some of them are our
initialization related some of them are
our type related some of them are
function related perfectly fine the
problem with splint is that of those two
of them are false positives the get
there's the get s finding and there's a
potential memory leak with it with our
use of foo however despite the fact that
stir copy is extremely problematic
splint doesn't actually recommend
anything to do with it right because
splint can't determine intention for
what we're actually intending to do here
but it's still pretty simple we do
something a little bit better we get
some better findings out of it but
there's lots of false positives and even
these things are completely fooled
easily has anyone ever seen PMD run PMD
and gotten clean results from it and
then looked at the source code and
noticed that someone put no PMD at the
top of source code which means don't run
PMD on this so I've had I've had
developers who when things were failing
in see ICD pipelines or things like that
instead of fixing it they just add no
PMD so that it stops failing but that
also means it's not being checked the
other interesting thing is that the stir
copy is completely wrong so stir copies
arguments are actually backwards this is
a UNIX historical
tradition or convention and neither one
of these tools noted that we were
actually using foo which is the source
for the destination now so it at this
level when we have these sorts of
lower-level traditional tools things are
very easily confused there's lots of
false positives but we basically have a
lot of things that we can triage for a
minimal effort
and indeed these all go back to the way
that these tools work they don't model
things necessarily too strongly for
example rats is literally doing this
it's literally highlighting boxes in
your code and says hey this is probably
problematic there's nothing that you can
do that's safe about these sorts of
things so at a simple model right and we
all form mental models doesn't matter if
you're developing code doesn't matter if
you're analyzing something you develop
these sort of mental models yourself as
well so this is the sorts of model that
rats is actually using a splint is a
little bit more formal it actually
builds up a tree of things to walk all
right and that's how it does this sort
of coloring on objects right so it knows
that foo if you remember back to the the
actual code that we have it remembers
that foo is nullable that foo itself
actually could be null and could be
passed into these sorts of problematic
functions so it does some sort of
checking it actually understands the
model of the code that it's executing
right and so it can actually capture
more things whether or not those are
false positives that's left to behold
but it actually does build up a greater
understanding of things and greater
understanding of programs themselves and
the model of things impact what we
actually can test that it impacts what
we understand about our code itself
right so we have two strings here we
stir copy one and to the other and then
we attempt to printf right and splint
based on its model realizes that the
start copy the initializations
and the use of all of this functionality
is completely acceptable but rats still
warns you and now you have to go back
and triage
what's actually happening in the code
itself to actually understand what is
what is being impacted here which at the
end of the day is nothing so you get
these findings very quickly you get
these issues very quickly and then you
end up having to triage them much more
because of the sorts of things that you
have here so yes so what we're trying to
do is actually form models of our code
this is this is from a ideation that I
was having when I was talking through
some of these sorts of things and on the
static side we have the like the simple
string searches regex is linters paint
and then symbolic execution and dynamic
side we go down in power but as we're
attempting to understand code we're
attempting to go down this list on
either side until you get to something
like abstract interpretation which
straddles both sides we're trying to go
down and gain understanding of our code
and gain understanding of the exploits
issues and surface area of our code
itself using these techniques does make
sense to everyone probably yes No yeah
cool so let's talk about fuzzing I think
people have a notion of fuzzing they
think of it as just random testing it's
not necessarily what we always mean but
fuzzing itself is an extremely useful
technique probably everyone has seen it
or used it in some fashion but I want to
talk about what we mean by fuzzing
versus what is often used as fuzzing
itself so traditionally people think of
fuzzing is just throwing random garbage
on an application right you can think of
you know I don't know reading out of
like dev you ran or something of this
nature to throw out an application
itself that's not what I mean when I say
fuzzing I'm talking about mutation
testing and I'm talking about property
testing so we can do something like
we're given a valid input from an
application we're given something from
an application and we bit flip that to
see and watch what an application does
right that's the sort of mutation
testing
so we start from a valid input we
mutated as many times as possible see
what the application does see if it
crashes right and this also can be
highly structured right so I've had
applications that required some some
form of JSON in we want we don't want to
fuzz the JSON parser that's probably not
useful to to the end-user right we want
to actually fuzz the application itself
so there are techniques and there are
ways of doing these sorts of things via
property testing and via other other
related tools and these are remote in
most folks tool sets right they people
use the fuzz DB they use SEC lists they
use intruder if they're using burp right
they have these sorts of things it's
completely normal right but we're not
actually mutating program State with
many of these right think about SEC
lists not to pick on Daniel but to think
about SEC lists right if you're looking
for XSS or you're looking for something
in an application if you just run SEC
lists it's a literal huge list of XSS
payloads super useful you may discover
something there but it's not actually
mutating program State there may be
things that the program is doing that
are contextually interesting for what
the program is that will never be found
by just throwing a random list of words
at it so we're trying to uncover the
light yellow portion of our applications
by throwing random data at it and
mutation is is one of the most useful
ways that we can do those sorts of
things so this is the this is the
easiest example here we're looking for
something that's a strength right we we
may just throw random bytes on it they
may be valid ASCII they may not be they
may be utf-8 we have no idea we don't
care we're just throwing random data at
our application if we're doing mutation
testing we actually take valid data and
then output invariance of it has anyone
used read and saw before for fuzzing now
so Radames a naive fuzzer it it does
mutation testing has many different
techniques and algorithms that you can
use for these sorts of things and I
found a large number of vulnerabilities
just by running
Radames that things we can also have
grammar based fuzzing so basically we
describe the data we describe how things
work so for example I've done grammar
based fuzzing by describing the
instructions of a virtual machine
describing the opcodes and the operands
and then having something randomly walk
through and generate grammars of these
sorts of things and then we can have
property testing so property testing is
like unit testing on steroids it's
probably the easiest way to describe it
we describe some set of invariants we
describe some set of properties within
our within our code base and then we run
random generation on these sorts of
things and see what we can actually
cause to break and perhaps perhaps not
with things like AFL we can actually
implement or instrument our program to
see what the actual state is itself so
the goal is to get greater depth right
beyond what humans can see and and we do
see these sorts of results I myself have
had 50 I think 57 bugs just from radon
so in the last two years doing nothing
else not being smart about it not being
you know not modeling anything not
actually attempting to go into any depth
of these sorts of things I've had 57 or
so bugs say 50 right and AFL actually
has to maintain a repository of all of
the bugs that it's found so we're
clearly finding some some random we're
clearly finding some issues with random
testing right bless you
but can we actually tell what we're
covering here right
if you throw random data at an
application do you know what you're
getting out of it do you have any idea
if that state was intended if it wasn't
and like what are we actually getting
out we can watch for crashes but what if
the application doesn't crash right what
if it just gets into some weird state
and continues to hang we've seen these
sorts of things before kubernetes itself
fuzzing it you there are ways to make
kubernetes like cubelet hang or ways to
cause things like block chains to hang
that don't produce any any actual valid
results but that doesn't mean that we
can watch for a crash they never panic
right so we have to have some
understanding of what we're actually
looking for in order to get this sort of
coverage then we can write we can use
some things like a FL FL American fuzzy
lop it is a tool for for actually
instrumenting binaries or code it hooks
in watches which paths things work down
fuzz's those and we can also spend time
specifying property tests so if you've
written unit tests before imagine
writing these sorts of tests and saying
hey no matter what happens this this
function should never fail right based
on this property you can do this and
have a have a tool actually randomly
generate that but the amount of time
that you actually spend doing that is
very high compared to what we maybe
would want to do we want those that's
sort of like quick fix that we have with
with the sort of rats and splint and
things like that and we can use newer
techniques to gray box fuzzing is a new
technique that's that's out super
interesting if you're fascinated by
these sorts of things gray box fuzzing
is interesting but no matter what we're
trying to do the whole purpose of this
is to discover the that light yellow
area in our weird machines picture we're
trying to find and exercise new
functionality within an application
itself
so we need to uncover these paths right
because programs themselves are just
fancy graphs has anyone seen graphs of
programs before like a control flow
graph or a data flow graph sure if
you've done any reverse engineering if
you've done any like code analysis with
compilers those sorts of things programs
themselves are just graphs there's some
constraint there's some like basically
boolean check or whatever there that
specifies some condition under which we
execute this piece of code this portion
of code and then we also are constrained
by input right it doesn't matter if it's
user input or if it's system input we're
constrained by these sorts of things but
really the question that we're trying to
ask is can we discover and graph all
paths within an application itself so
let's talk about symbolic execution so
program space itself is usually quite
wide right there's lots of things that
go on in an application there's lots of
things that that happened within an
application that we want to discover
them without having to do much ourselves
we want the cheapest fastest way to
discover these sorts of things and
symbolic execution can certainly work
that and one of the things that I'll be
introducing is what I've been working on
for like the last a month it's not a
month's worth of actual time it's bits
and pieces here and there as I need
things but programs themselves are just
grass they're textual graphs that we
write things together and string them
together write nodes represent some sort
of action within the system and then we
have edges that represent constraints so
think about this code this is some
simplified code that I've seen many
times I'm sure everyone has seen things
like this so we have an if and we have
an else we undertake two different
actions depending on if J is actually
less than K so there's actually no
difference between those two programs
right the textual representation before
can be just as easily represented as a
graph here right we don't know what J
and K are so we set them to some lambda
we don't know there's some some
you to say symbolically we know that
these are two different values or we
suspect they're two different values and
then we have this graph on one slide we
know that J's J is less than K and on
some other side we know that J is
greater than or equal to K those are the
that's the dichotomy of this program
itself so what we're actually attempting
to do is is provide these graphs or find
these graphs generate the constraints
and then solve them has anyone seen
constraint solving before yes
so constraint solving is basically a
system that takes a you know like a SMT
formula and then attempts to apply a
bunch of binary techniques to generate
these sorts of things there's bit
bashing in a lot in here
my focus is mostly on combining fuzzing
with symbolic execution but nonetheless
there's various means by which you can
actually generate these graphs generate
these constraints and then solve them
and it's extremely useful Klee is it
helps if I don't lock myself out Klee is
a common one that works atop LLVM we at
Trello bits have a symbolic executor in
a Manticore consensus diligence has one
named mithril mythix now and these two
Manticore and mithril are both used in
the blockchain space quite heavily right
so if you have aetherium code you can
symbolically execute them and understand
your programs much more deeply just with
with using Manticore mithril so the
problem with many of these tools though
is that they they generally tend to work
on binary code itself and you know if
we're doing malware analysis my interest
my side interest is in malware analysis
especially with with languages right I'm
kind of curious how we get safe
execution of of office macros of
JavaScript of jscript those sorts of
things and we want to uncover
second-stage things in a safe
environment and I'm kind of tired of
setting up a VM to do these sorts of
things when we have better techniques
and better tools to handle these sorts
of things and the other thing too is
that very frequently they require full
code bases I don't want to walk through
your entire code base I want to see
something that
looks extremely interesting in the
middle of your code I want to pull that
out execute it and find the constraints
itself so I I've been working on this
unnamed cindex project number nine
there's been several all the ones that
I've written either for clients or
written for myself but it's live right
now you can go look at it
it's basically a high-level language
symbolic execution and constraint
environment I'm not focusing on the
these sorts of like you know XIII and
those sorts of constraint algorithms
themselves but it's it's certainly a
possible area then there's a whole list
of references up there as well if you're
interested in these sorts of things but
what I'm actually looking for is a few
different things I want it to be able to
work on partial code like I mentioned I
don't really care to execute your entire
program if you're familiar with symbolic
execution search spaces will explode if
I have to execute your entire program
and I also want to be safe by default
especially because I want to run malware
in this thing so I want something that I
can run arbitrary malware not on the
sandbox and not have to worry about
what's happening in the background so
that's where I'm working here it's it's
roughly a month old currently but the
way it works is it translates languages
like JavaScript into an ugly scheme
dialect does everyone remember scheme
from school like if you went to in
colleges it's very the last time most
people have seen it I actually was a
professional scheme programmer for a
while but it's basically a scheme
dialect and a Python library for
interacting with it and it handles two
different edge cases this can colic
execution concrete execution this is
what we normally think of as execution
when we execute code we concretely go
through we get a set of values we
execute those values return them to the
user display them run them however it is
and then we have symbolic execution now
symbolic execution will go through in a
second but it's basically working on
unknown data itself we don't know what
it is we don't know where the
constraints are we want the application
to tell us that
so we want to map program space itself
so in this code itself I generate two
concrete integers themselves here F and
G and I just add them now that's not in
and of itself interesting where this
becomes interesting is that we have the
trace that's here so in this system
every single value is tagged so you can
actually look through and find even
where constants are used so for example
if the number 10 exists multiple times
within this application you'll actually
see the unique location that that 10 is
actually instantiated each and every
time within within it within an
execution and then we have the trace so
we have the execution path by which we
actually got to this value so it's not
useful to know that H is equal to 21 we
don't care about that we want to know
where and how we got to 21 and these
sorts of value constraints and these
sorts of value traces allow us to do
that but more interestingly is when we
can work on unknown or symbolic data
here so here's a relatively simple st.
almost the same program but now G is
symbolic means we don't know what value
G actually represents right so here when
we add two values we just say we have 10
plus something else now we know for the
lifetime of the program that H is always
10 plus whatever the value of G is we
have no idea what G is we may solve it
we may not solve it we may fuzz it we
may generate it we may constrain it
ourselves we may say hey later on in the
rest of this program G is actually equal
to 20 but from now on the program
actually can trace and follow that H
itself is always 10 greater than
whatever the value of G is and then we
have these unique tags themselves no
matter what so wherever we see that you
UID and I'm using you IDs because that's
the easiest way of getting fresh stems
but no matter what we do we can see
where those values came from themselves
so who actually cares about this right
like why why do we care right why why do
I care about these sorts of things well
there it becomes interesting when you
actually start to look at constraints
themselves so this is what the scheme
dialect itself looks like if you haven't
seen scheme I apologize or Lisp itself
but basically we have some variable foo
and we have no information about it it's
purely symbolic to us and under certain
conditions we return twelve and under
certain conditions we return thirteen
but we know nothing else about about foo
we only know these these sorts of path
constraints so we can start to ask this
questions I know this is a little
difficult to see but we can actually
start to ask questions here so the first
one we have two virtual machines here we
have test VM one and test VM zero so
test VM zero it has some value for foo
itself it has this this information so
when we execute when we execute foo when
we execute this if it actually knows and
can provide a value it says oh hey under
these constraints we actually get a path
execution that returns the value of 12
and it does it under this condition so
you SPE VAR f ast says when foo is true
so foo itself under this path execution
is true now we may have another path
execution so in VM one we have no
information about what food is so VM one
actually says hey there's two different
paths that we have to walk there's one
path that's false
right foo is is false itself it
definitely has to be a boolean and we
have no idea what that returns but under
that path if the application was false
we would get we actually get it twelve
and then if it's if it's true we
actually get 13 we get these two
different paths and they walk they walk
the same constraints so the program is
actually telling us under these
conditions we either have a concrete
execution we execute some path return it
or we have a fork the program doesn't
know which direction we go and you have
to figure that out you have to start to
walk this can be extremely useful if you
have a giant nested if if you have
something that rely trip relies on
environmental data so for example
certain malware we're actually check how
many files you've opened recently on the
system and if you're in a virtual
machine you've probably opened not
enough right because you're not actually
interacting with this system as a normal
as a normal system you're not actually
opening things you're not running things
you're not running programs there
well symbolic execution allows us to say
hey under this condition under this
constraint the program will do X and
split and fork there so we can then
start to trace down and say okay that's
interesting let's continue execution
from there so we want to find the
constraints under which things execute
and symbolic execution allows us to do
this it has many problems but it's
extremely easy currently to at least get
path constraints here and one of the
things that I am very interested in is
is the new techniques that actually
combine symbolic execution and fuzzing
the sorts of gray box fuzzing the sorts
of like learning inputs for for
applications so that's that's my next
step is to actually go through and say
hey if we see something that looks
reasonably like it traces through to a
sink that is XSS let's try X ssing this
let's try something that's contextually
relevant based on the constraints that
we have and let's actually attempt to to
execute that there and then also we have
both concrete and symbolic executions so
we can go through with unknown data we
can go through without data so if you
have valid data you can execute this as
well and I support both micro execution
and standard execution throughout now
has anyone heard of micro execution
before no new technique so micro
execution is actually an extremely
fascinating technique you literally run
one form or one instruction a form is is
a syntactic form like an if block or a
function call or something of that
nature and you provide it with a stack
and E and V all sorts of things that you
need to set up maybe some user input
maybe not but you literally run this one
instruction in the stack in the
environment in whatever you have set up
now why is this interesting
because you can continuously manipulate
the other factors to this instruction
and see what it does to the
environmental variables so for example
if you wanted to discover that move was
turing-complete
you could provide a stack you could
provide certain like certain register
values and see what move actually does
based on the on the execution path that
you see for each single time that you
call move so you change nothing else
about the program other than the stack
and you micro execute it trailer bits we
have a we have a certain section of the
company called lifting bits it deals
with binary representations to higher
level representations but we do have a
micro executor called micro X and then
Patrice could go to Freud has actually
worked on this quite a bit Microsoft has
quite a bit of work into micro execution
but it's a super fascinating technique
and one of the things that I wanted to
explore was how does this actually
interact with high-level languages and
USP number 9 is actually part of that
but there's a lot to do if if any of
this is actually interesting to you I'd
love to talk afterwards but there's a
quite a few things that I want to do
here I want to flesh out the JavaScript
parser that I have currently it's quite
manual there's there's quite a bit
that's going on in there I want to do a
normal form and Static single static
assignment a and F and and SSA are super
useful and lambda lifting so lambda
lifting basically takes anonymous
functions from an in situ representation
and moves them to a higher level and
then passes in anything that's captured
from that lambda and I want to add a ton
more tests and strategies so if you're
interested in fuzzing and you want to
understand code more I'd love to see PRS
and poles to help with some of the
generation strategy but my use case is I
want to understand gnarly code that I
get from either clients from malware
from those sorts of things and I want to
exercise them as much as possible see
under which constraints these programs
work see how things are going and then
actually execute them without having to
know the entire code base without having
to understand much here and that's what
I'm using this for so I'm a bit early
but that's it thank you very much
everyone for coming
does anyone have questions since I can
now play like I can be tortured by
questions here now everyone everyone
will wake yeah sure
sure so the question is like if you want
to execute gnarly code are you just
doing sections the entire application
that sort of thing my my use case is
very frequently when we have say go code
or JavaScript typescript that sort of
thing I want to know what this section
is doing I may be able to understand how
to get there but I want to know what
this is doing and I don't want to
include the rest of the execution path I
don't want to walk through so yes I want
to just rip this out see what this thing
does and then walk back to those
constraints myself and then you can
obviously do control flow graphs to get
there you can do other walks to get back
to it but mine is to really pull out in
situ sections of high-level code and do
those sorts of things so for example and
go in JavaScript you manipulate the
stack quite frequently right you may
have defers and go you may have
continuations those sorts of things that
manipulate the stack
I want to mechanize those to CPS or ANF
and then actually walk through those
constraints there themselves just for
that one function instead of the entire
search space of an application that can
break does that answer your question ok
quite fully anyone have any other
questions well perfect thank you very
much everyone for coming it was a
pleasure
[Applause]