anybody have a free beer by the way yet
yes free beer the beers broken down you
just drink out of the keg I think that's
just a gherkin thing but yeah it's not
wrong not but these kind of people so
welcome everybody it's afternoon session
at gherkin 2019 I'm Ron introducing
Chris Russell he's going to talk about
the past present and future of cyber
threats for about next 25 minutes or so
Chris thank you good afternoon everyone
can everyone hear me OK in the back
perfect all right so we're gonna start
off with the past cyber threats little
history lesson so the threat landscape
has evolved over the years starting in
the 80s and 90s we we saw the first
types of computer viruses infecting what
was at the time was a pretty small
platform of systems in the world that
quickly evolved into worm outbreaks in
the in the 2000s where they were much
more able to quickly spread you know
their attack platforms via the the
warming capabilities or mass mailing
capabilities or techniques used to
spread over the network things of that
nature in 2003 we saw that evolved into
spam and mass mailers 2004 spyware
started at the scene 2005 we saw
intelligent botnets 2007 we saw web
threats coming down so things like
malvert iseman malicious urls malicious
web site content etc in 2010 we started
to see target attacks and with advanced
persistent threats in 2012 with the
advent of mobile phones and mobile
devices we saw mobile attacks start hit
landscape in 2015 ransomware so for most
of us when we hear ransomware we think
okay this is a pretty big issue now it's
hard to think that you know even four
years ago ransomware just hit the scene
that's how damaging and prevalent it is
even today 2016 BC our business email
compromised at the scene 2017 we started
to see attacks on IOT and I I
and then 2018 we saw cryptocurrency
mining in 2019 even though the years not
over yet
we've seen a massive resurgent of
ransomware more sophisticated ransomware
attacks tied in with social engineering
harvesting to make those attacks more
effective and prevalent so in 1988 we
saw the Morris worm wreak havoc with its
denial of service attack and propagation
mechanisms reportedly crashing 10% of
computers on the Internet at the time it
was one of the first to significantly
affect the then nascent backbone of the
Internet in 1989 we saw the AIDS trojan
it was arguably the first piece of
ransomware its creators distribute
20,000 floppy disk copies of the Trojan
to attendees of the World Health
Organization AIDS Conference in 1990
polymorphic viruses first emerged in the
form of chameleon created by its author
by building on the earlier Vienna and
cascade viruses capabilities in 1992 the
Michelangelo virus creates cybersecurity
panic since it was expected to cause
significant damage in reality it didn't
in 1999 the infamous Melissa macro virus
was released eventually causing over 80
million dollars in damage worldwide
Melissa placed heavy burden on email
servers incessantly emailing itself to
unwitting recipients in 2000 the I love
you or love bug or love letter worm
demonstrates the adverse impact of
social engineering enticing victims with
a seemingly heartwarming missive so this
was kind of our first social engineering
slash malware attack and today still
very prevalent in 2003 we started to see
backdoors and worms become more endemic
as more security flaws were reported do
s attacks become large-scale so much so
that one worm SQL slammer hits more than
75,000 computers in just 10 minutes the
blaster worm makes headlines when it
disrupts some of the government services
in the US state of Maryland
two thousand five mobile malware starts
gaining traction against Symbian devices
most are offshoots of the
proof-of-concept cavern that was
released the year before Komori becomes
the first mobile phone virus that
spreads through multimedia messaging
services in 2007 storm worm emerges
combining the tactics of a worm a Trojan
and a botnet at its peak that accounts
for 80% of all malware infections
becoming one of the most prolific
threats of 2007 and 2008 in November of
2008 configure a ko-dan add worms its
way into as many as nine million
vulnerable computers spawning several
variants and picking up new tricks in
the process most of you probably are
well aware this is still very prevalent
on many machines worldwide 2008 is when
that first hit the scene it's so it's
amazing that it's still out there
2010 stock net comes into view it's the
first worm to target supervisory control
and data acquisition SCADA systems
prompting discussions on securing
industrial infrastructure in 2012
targeted attacks and data breaches
become more common the Middle East
targeting flame data stealer and wiper
comes to light taking cues from stuck
Nets motifs distract effects the
workstations of an oil firm 2013 a rash
of spam emails start delivering the
cryptolocker ransomware one of the first
to scramble the infected systems file
and take them hostage crypto lockers
operators reportedly earned millions
today it's more like billions 2015 data
breaches become more potent affecting
the healthcare industry the most with
the exposure of more than 90 million
patient records a bevy of zero day
vulnerabilities are dumped and then
weaponized in cyber espionage campaigns
2016 by this time business email
compromised schemes have caused over
three billion dollars in global losses
more zero-day vulnerabilities are
uncovered and closed 2017 cryptocurrency
mining becomes the most prevalent
Network event in devices connected to
home routers
right now so the good more than 48
billion threats have been blocked access
to epic exploit kits have dropped by 63%
ransomware related threat components
dropped by 91% distributors excuse me
distribute distribution of critical
rated vulnerabilities dropped to 18%
from 25 the bat cryptocurrency mining
detections increased 237 % business
email compromised attempts increased 20%
fireless threats rose 474 percent in
industrial control system
vulnerabilities rose 224 % so right now
cyber criminals are casting a wider
fishing net so we all know the first
phase of any attack is going to be
typically an email attack where they're
trying to get credentials from a user or
get them to go to a malicious site or
execute a malicious file and that's
continuing to become more prevalent
fishing has been traditionally
associated with email but recent attacks
have also been used other modes of
communication such as chat SMS voice
calls fishing methods have also
diversified the use of encrypted sites
to go after Apple IDs for example the
use of deceptive Unicode technique for
SMS enabled phishing and the use of
hijacked email accounts to respond to an
existing email thread ransomware related
detections drop a profits to be gained
relative to the effort to be spent and
launching an attack remained compelling
so we continue to see interesting if not
new ransomware tactics such as fake
software sharing sites and pop-up ads
ransomware bundled with legitimate
software ransomware program to send a
copy of itself to an infected users
email contacts and want to cry numbers
persisted because of the effective the
effectivity of its underlying exploit
eternal blue and because users might
have not patched or when able to patch
despite the fix had been available for
over a year we still see that today many
other new variances of ransomware
emerged in this year alone Rio for
example was a big one
causing many many millions and sometimes
billions of dollars of damage to inter
cryptocurrency mining detections and
file as threats have increased even in
the underground cryptocurrency centric
tools and services were being advertised
cryptocurrency mining malware and
cryptocurrency stealing our which
targets wallets and intercepts tyv
intercepts the transactions we aren't
seeing this as a consistent threat this
kind of goes in line with a value of
Bitcoin for example that when there's
money to be made we see increasing
cryptocurrency mining when the value
drops obviously this drops 2009 has seen
more of an increase or re-emergence of
ransomware attacks exploitation of patch
vulnerabilities so this is still a big
one today and I think everyone in the
room can understand that it's very hard
for an enterprise to keep their
environments patched a lot of
organizations do a good job patching
some organizations can't patch some
organizations are very slow to patch so
even in the underground cryptocurrency
centric tools and services were being
advertised cryptocurrency mining malware
and cryptocurrency stealing malware
which targets these exploits to spread
their infections to to breach the
systems and get on there etc so
exploitation of plat patch
vulnerabilities is still huge even in
2019 and has been for many years skate
of honour abilities soar so the
vulnerabilities of SCADA systems Stuxnet
was one of the first examples of that
and it has continued to soar to to this
day it is one of the highest growth
attack platforms that we see today most
of these we can speculate are from
nation-state type actors I'm trying to
attack other nation-states it's becoming
more a a government type attack platform
than even a for-profit or cyber criminal
attack platform so revamp threats new
abuses so the moriah based malware
started infecting routers I think it was
in 2018 and taking over millions of
routers around the world the
used for to create botnets - to do
denial of service attacks that continues
today they also can be used for you know
cryptocurrency mining other types of
farming etc we saw you know outbound
router events from the eternal blue
vulnerability that still is the number
one outbound router event we see today
even though that's been patched now for
well over a year so what is the future
so we see an increase even more so in
social engineering via phishing as state
of Monaco culture declines exploit kit
attacks decline cyber criminals will use
social engineering even more most of you
are probably familiar with the attack
type where a user in your organization
typically a high profile user will get a
phishing email or a spear phishing email
they're hoping to get the credentials of
that user within your organization then
they'll elevate that attack with that
company credential company email address
to potentially send that over to another
user in the organization that has power
and authority perhaps to transfer a
large sums of money it's coming from the
perhaps CEO it looks and feels real it
may say I need a transfer of fifty
thousand dollars immediately for an
emergency capital request they go ahead
and send that attack done the only thing
that needed to happen was a spear
phishing attack succeeded they gain that
users credentials then they were able to
send an email to that other user and
they gain fifty thousand dollars and it
can be met in much more cases it's much
higher we've seen examples of one
organization transfer to half a million
dollars via an attack just like that so
that doesn't only apply to email it can
also apply to you know SMS chats sim
jacking a lot of customers that I see
are moving to office 365 using the
built-in chat capabilities of office 365
the built-in file sharing capabilities
of office 365
same attack where users credentials are
harvested can then apply to that entire
office 365 workflow causing even more
harm sporting events upcoming elections
socio-political developments will be
used as premise for social engineering
attacks so open source intelligence
gathering this this kind of ties into it
the example I just talked about
so everyone today is on social media
usually or maybe on five or six
different social medias these thread
actors are basically harvesting the
information that you're putting out in
the public to better attack you or your
organization so that that example I use
where they're going to craft a message
from that hijack credential they can
find out a lot about that individual
from their social media and then craft
an attack that really matches what they
would really do so it makes it much more
effective so we see even more of that
happening now and moving forward and of
course artificial intelligence engines
are gathering this so it's not just
human intelligence there are AI engines
out there gathering this tracking users
tracking their their destination their
travel etc all that's being used to
better attack organizations automation
will be a new wrinkle in business
process compromise more aspects of
monitoring and function are conducted to
software or online applications this
will also be used in supply chain
attacks we're seeing a big increase in
supply chain attacks I think the first
one most of you will recall was the
target breach way back that was a supply
chain attack where they compromised the
HVAC vendor and used that to get into
the larger target network and then from
there finish their attack more
techniques to blend in so we're going to
see more living off the land of tackers
this will obviously increase use of
unconventional file extensions less
reliance on actual executables as in the
use of fireless components such as
powershell scripts and macros PS exec
you know no file needed basically just
running something that executes and
takes advantage you know digital sign
malware new activation methods abusive
email accounts our online storage
services and apps minimally modifying or
infecting legitimate system files so
this is a big one 99.99% of exploit
based attacks are using known
vulnerabilities that's very true today
and and we see that in the future as
well
successful exploit based attacks
one-ball vulnerabilities for which
patches have been available for weeks or
even months but have not been applied
yet so that's a big number so most of
the attacks we see in 99.99% aren't
using zero days aren't using some
homebred attack of an exploit that no
one knows about these are all known and
patchable other techniques remember most
threat actors are lazy worms will be
used to infect more our systems
including IOT botnet wars destructive
attacks and mobile attacks so some
advice on how to prevent you need a
multi-layered approach because of all
those different types of attacks we
talked about you need a solution or
solution set within your organization
that can cover all those different bases
so at the entry point upon arrival good
firewall good micro segmentation example
of I've got a database server that is
connected to an app server the only
thing the database server is used for is
a database for that app server do I do I
need to open that database server up to
the entire data center no I can micro
segment that where okay that that
database server can only talk to that
application server therefore closing the
loop on potential infiltration points
host based IPs so the the section we
talked about where 99.99% of attacks or
exploits are from known threats so if
there's a known
threat or a known exploit or a known
vulnerability you can't patch it let's
say or you don't have time to patch it
use a host-based IPS where the intrusion
prevention system is going to identify
the network packets associated with that
attack drop the packets the exploit
fails to the attacker the system appears
to be patched browser exploit prevention
device control so Stuxnet for example
that was using human intelligence took a
USB to the air gapped systems plugged it
in loaded the malware using something
like device control if they would have
said okay all of our USBs are locked
down or the old school method fill them
with epoxy whatever whatever it's
necessary the Stuxnet attack would have
failed web reputation so phishing
attacks where the leveraging malicious
URLs etcetera web reputation can detect
and prevent that next phase of the
attack so they get through the the entry
point they move on to downloading a
payload to the disk so typical
anti-malware protection you want to have
multiple layers of detection with your
anti-malware solutions so because
attacks can come from any variety of
ways we recommend a solution that has
pre execution machine learning
predictive machine learning application
control so if you've got some more
sensitive work while I was in your
environment where you want to lock them
down so known applications can even run
we recommend application control for
that variant protection file ever file
level signatures so what a lot of people
will call traditional detection file
level signatures are still very
important important back to 99.99% of
all attacks today are already known and
the next phase of your attack would be
ok it got through it got on disk it was
able to install execute so we want
execution based scanning so runtime
protection so runtime machine learning
indicator of attack behavioral analysis
exploit prevention and then let's say it
got through all of those layers of
protection and still is able to run and
execute you need to be able to say ok
I'm identifying that this system has
been breached how do we do that so we
have techniques like web reputation
so if something is reaching out to a
command-and-control server host IPS so
if something is laterally moving
internally within your infrastructure
post IPS can detect and prevent that
data loss prevention maybe there
exfiltrating sensitive data in your
organization data loss print prevention
will detect and prevent that as well and
then because you've got all these
different techniques in a solution we
recommend that you you go with something
that has false positive check so don't
don't go with a solution that just uses
an artificial intelligence engine for
example and doesn't cross-reference that
too ok I know this is a good file I know
this is a good site I don't need to run
this through any of these engines so
false positive check isn't very
important use of that equation to keep
your enterprise moving forward so this
kind of identifies what we just talked
about the different layers of protection
the first line of defense web and file
reputation exploit prevention
application control variant protection
filter out the known good filter out the
known bad move those on to the next
generation engines such as pre execution
machine learning less overhead less
false positive look for a solution that
has this kind of a structure what's left
take it through the runtime engines
behavior analysis runtime machine
learning is there anything left we need
to scan let's go ahead and send it to a
custom sandbox detonate it determine if
it's doing anything malicious create a
pattern on the fly submit that out to
the rest of the organization protecting
them and patient zero as well and then
of course you need a solution at the end
of the day nobody's going to be perfect
no solutions going to be perfect if
something does breach your organization
you still want to know what's happening
have a good investigation in response
platform where you can identify that
you've been breached on day one instead
of maybe six months later or a year
later
stay educated so if you're a responsible
for the security of your organization or
maintaining your data centers or
whatever it may be you need to stay up
on the latest trends latest attacks etc
is there a patch for this vulnerability
whatever it may be using podcasts blogs
research reports threat reports webinars
videos news articles etc if you're an
administrator of your organization and
you're responsible for employee training
put in a good training program with
videos classes phishing simulations
Phish your users right you you go ahead
and and and get get them caught with a
spear phishing attack that's safe ahead
of time so that they don't end up
getting caught from a malicious actor at
the end of the day you can deploy all
the layers of protection from a
technology perspective and that scenario
that I talked about where if a user
gives up their credentials and that
threat actor has the keys to the kingdom
unless you can detect the data
exfiltration you know it's game over so
training is an important piece where to
invest so gateways we talked about how
messaging and internet browsing are kind
of the first line of defense against
most threats that's where most threats
will start so invest in a messaging and
web security solution things to look for
in a messaging solution make sure it has
a good platform or engine for socially
socially engineered attack protection AI
and machine learning for detecting okay
it's a known threat but they changed it
a little bit so if knots a new threat
with AI and machine learning it can
actually see a brand new threat that no
one's ever seen in the wild before and
say this is close enough to that threat
I know about I'm going to flag this as
malicious that's a very high level
overview of what and what machine
learning does embedded URL detection
sandbox attachment support for web
security look for web reputation command
and control detection exploit detection
malicious script it section sandboxing
off URLs where to vest on the network
side we
talked about what if everything gets
through what if we're breached breach
detection systems so something that can
identify targeted attack behavior such
as infiltration lateral movement command
and control communications be able to
sandbox
you know files that aren't prevalent on
the internet that we want to make sure
are safe before we let them through and
then of course exfiltration so these are
all things that okay something has
gotten through or maybe someone brought
in a BYOD device and it's infected we
want to be able to know that's there
before it actually causes a bigger
problem or if we are breach we want to
make sure we minimize the damage before
it turns into a bigger situation so
breach detection can certainly help
there network-based intrusion prevention
system RFPs this can provide network
based vulnerability shielding so that
whole scenario we talked about where we
can't patch our datacenter we've got you
know maybe Windows Server 2003 is still
running without patches etc network
based IPs can certainly help there
machine learning context and visibility
where to vest on servers obviously you
want a multi-layered approach and
endpoints same basic thing we've covered
a lot of these spaces earlier and then
that's it thank you very much
[Applause]