good morning that's worse than yesterday
Wow it's a new mic we brought in a
second one so awesome so I can tell from
your response you're all feeling about
like me right now
waking up an hour earlier than I was
supposed to with a hangover sucks and
I'm sure you guys are right there with
me some of you anyway I see some faces
out there I probably aren't even old
enough to drink no judge I don't I don't
judge anybody uh so a couple
housekeeping things first of all please
whatever you do do not block the fire
exit
I've got folks stationed back there they
will tackle you out of that doorway if
you try to stand in it so no standing in
the fire exits please with that in mind
you guys are in ballrooms see this is
the anything track if that's not where
you want it to be run now I'm locking
the doors in ten seconds get out okay
some of you heard this yesterday I know
same spiel with that in mind the second
thing cell phones
turn them off silence um something we
got almost the entire day yesterday one
person at 350 in the afternoon had their
phone go off that that's not his blood
and roll four over there I promise no I
wore boots I will crush you if I hear
that phone I swear other than that we're
ready to rock you guys ready I love it
you guys actually have energy this
is cool all right
so kicking things off we are talking
about info security versus digital
security
we are gonna dive in and look at how we
can help give people context for what it
is that we do in this crazy world and
the take it away
it's John Drake
[Applause]
I like to walk around a little bit so
obviously thank you for all coming I was
not expecting a full room or at least
pretty close to it so I appreciate I
guess I used the right title and so my
reference is actually to the movie war
game not jigsaw so though a viewer
wanted to expect the other one I'm sorry
so thank you all for showing up I will
say the first thing is probably some of
you know me I am a sales guy I work for
Optive I've been around for 15 years 16
years of the area I am a sales guy I
started out on the networking side and
realized that I was not the guy that's
gonna go home and pummel away but I
loved security I loved those sort of
things so I did what I did best is
actually connecting people with other
people helping people out go from there
why why am I here and why did I talk
about wanna play game so a little my coo
mi
I actually am bachelor of fine arts in
PE in sculpture so that is where I
started out so and also I love IT
security and security because they're
all about puzzles it's like a blank
canvas it's always something changing
there's always something new you all are
problem solvers because it's always
changing it's always very complex it's
one of those things I also love love to
play games I love to play D&D I love to
paint figures I like to be the geek of
geeks and go from there so that is I'm
letting all I also love to go vault of
midnight on Wednesday at 10 o'clock when
they all send they get their comic books
in for the day so just to give you a
back so I am NOT a normal sales guy I
love this place I've worked with yeah I
know I know so I work just Chris and
Jamie Payne I run the strategic summer
for them to develop that to keep this
going so if you have any ideas let us
know to be honest we had the tattoo
couple years ago I think next year's
your number 10 so it's going to be even
bigger I am talking about bringing them
try Boucher's to see what we can do to
have fun with that or something like
that so let us know go from there that
is my job I am also involved in the
community and go from there so
oh why the title wanna play games comes
back to everybody loves to play games
everybody likes to have a time I mean
even non IT people I mean how many
people have had Angry Birds on their
phone right or every every kid likes to
pick up a game play game figure it out
to be honest our job is a game we try to
figure out puzzles things go we it's
always being sort of like a game of
chess for security it's always moving
forward going things like this and
trying to figure everything else in all
pieces and it's always the rules are
always changing always always always
changing new things come in why they
need so as a salesperson I always go
into this whole thing of awesome they
say I only have so much budget and as a
security guy we need to get out of the
ideas of budget is the magic number
it is about aligning it to business it's
about business risk sort of like IT
infrastructure servers networks they all
have projects they have complete control
of everything they do every day there is
no like okay and we they can get four
nines by putting redundancy in all of
those systems they can get four nines
their life is pretty simple and they
have complete control over what they do
we do not we are only going to get maybe
to 80% we are planning on failing there
is no four nines in our ways at all and
they don't seem to understand that I've
got customers of all sudden like said
you know what I went in to see I needed
more headcount and an infrastructure
manager and the server manager says why
do you need somebody I have I'm not
getting anymore why does security need
to have more people it's like because my
job is not a project my project my job
is always changing always moving always
expanding the new stuff that they buy
affects me 10 times more than the
stuff you guys on the soy there so how
how do we do that
we have to find a way to talk to people
who are not in security who have never
sat in your shoes to experience the
change the flow everything that you guys
do every day and how many variables that
you have no control over
in your life that also and change and go
from there and screw up your day pull
you off your project and go to the next
phase we had to figure that out well too
early so the question is is how do we do
this and how did I come up with so I
created a dice game I started out this
about a year ago for gherkin and explain
cuz I was trying to figure out how can I
explain this to people not IT or how can
you all explain to what you really do
without getting technical in last year I
had some I went on Kickstarter which I
love Kickstarter my wife hates it
because I have I think 20 in the last
year that I've sponsored and they just
keep coming in it's like where'd you buy
this Oh a year ago don't worry about
honey it's already the checkbook it's a
long time ago so last year I got a
Kickstarter which was just three dice
you know and I brought like I 20 or 30
of them here and everybody loved them
right it's like oh this is fun this is
just a you know and then I took it in
front of Phil Keebler Meier he says I
love this sort of thing because it's
just a conversation starter it's
something that we can roll this dice and
we can say what happens and people can
see and mostly it was I use your
problems like ID 210 you know issues
between keyboard and chair
those sort of things roll into the
issues or even application security
concerns and it started me thinking like
okay if I can roll this into some sort
of dice game just to start a
conversation started just so that
someone can have a conversation
understand all the variables that you
guys work with then that's at least a
starting point and that's what I started
with in it's already gone through three
permutations so basically Ike went
through and created these three dice
variables broke them out to programs
variables and businesses so programs are
things like incident response identity
access vulnerability management you know
threat cloud those things are all
changing these are all different
verticals in the areas that you guys
have to deal with no matter what part of
IT your security you're in they all
affect you one way or another this is
also what all CEOs have to deal with you
have all these different programs or I
don't know if they're all programs but
they're you know they should be programs
or at least instances that go build and
go from there
the variables of course this changes
around is users because users always
screw up or they do some good jobs IT
admins someone makes a mistake not
necessarily security but someone in the
networking team leave something open
marketing goes and buys an AWS puts a
credit card down and opens things up and
data goes back through or even you know
threatened tell if you get bad threat
intelligence from there so in the last
one of course is the green one is what
sort of a C cell would be able to
control like your partners who you trust
are they really good or they just
probably buy a new products are they
gonna be there to help you out when
hits the fan because as we know
hits the fan somewhere somewhere down
our path sooner or later our job is
gonna be pain and the most important
thing is to have someone you can rely on
or not rely on at least you'll know that
also budget budget goes up and down in
IT security and that's the thing we have
to fight is that security should not be
fluctuated by the budget unless you're
going to increase it because of an
increase which you know we're all in the
same rooms were all in the same page of
that day you'll disagree with us
staffing I'm sure you all have open
spots in your groups that you work with
or even training or training gets cut
people leave new people come in new
things come into the picture so that
always is one more variable that a CSO
has to deal with there's also the
business risk because that's what we're
lining to so in other words if your
company is very risk tolerant they say
oh we just make widgets okay that's that
they don't have they don't think of that
as a risk issue for their customer it
goes from there they're gonna keep
moving forward but some companies are
very risk you know they need to make
sure it's everything's locked down and
go from there it's sort of like I don't
know if you all heard Matt Carpenter
speak I mean it's a crazy crazy world
and that's a risk that I don't think
anybody else understands and then let's
see that I think that's also you see two
other symbols on these dice one is the
Gherkin skull and then one is the binary
so binary code so when I was creating
these dice I had to come up these two
wild card solutions and I asked Chris
Payne all right here's your opportunity
to decide which way you want to go he
said I said do you want the Gherkin
skull to be bad or good he says good
okay
that's where we'll go for this and then
the binaries of course is the bad
wildcard so here is assistance so also
here's the first permutation of the dice
game
so in other words the first set of dice
was just to roll it skin you know go
from there this came up is that each
category you have one detailed 12 dice
to roll you roll the dice and each one
at the start of the game to figure
things out of how many points you have
and there's the hole so the plus and
minus what's that's a great what's this
deal all as you roll these dice it also
changes your aspects of everything that
goes on in your day every day so in
other words also and you roll the dice
you get them magically you get identity
access management also and you get a
negative it means somebody screwed up an
ID X mismanagement or someone forgot to
delete somebody or you roll a plus or
minus is in the in users so there were
some user clicked on mail where it opens
the door it changes your variables it
goes from there so the first step of
course is to roll the d12 right and that
will give you obviously 3d 12 equals 36
potential the goal of the game is to get
to 30
so that also throws it you don't have to
be perfect and everything you just have
to get to a certain level to reduce your
risk that's what we always do we know
that we're never going to be perfect
it's that whole perspective and then
also the links of how many rolls so in
other words you can make this four
rounds so in other words you can go four
quarters per year you can extend it out
to six times a month so you know half or
you can do 12 times or three years so
just it's a variable time so that gives
you that perspective of a C so either
going through every quarter of the year
every month of the year and that way
you're starting to get this pattern of
these checkpoints you go from one point
the next and as you go through the next
step of course as you roll the dice two
sets of green two sets of black two sets
of white so one is a category of what
terror category it is the next is the
outcome from going from there and these
start to change your variables on the
side of the twelve sided dice you also
can either go play with yourself on this
on your own story of having the seaso
dice and try to get better so you can
have conversations or you can have
everybody has a set of dice and you can
go against here see who's the best t so
in the group to go from there there you
go it's always a competition right one
way or another so you roll those dice
and then you match up the colors and
then we go to this matrix that we've
created just to add plus and minus like
I said this is still rudimentary idea
game to get this so this is really not
for you to experience being an IT
security person but to have a
conversation with somebody to help them
understand what you do by playing a game
so these are just the matrix that we
created to sort of factor out so in
other words if also and you rolled I am
in category and you rolled you know the
lead score there's the binary code you
would have a minus three on that
category so if you had an eight you
would also go down to a five on that one
and the other ones would match up
through the whole system
this conversation probably will not be
an hour just to let you know you do this
all the time and the you know so you
lured you set up how many times you're
gonna roll and then the first person to
thirty wins or at least the closest
person to 30 wins that game so as we've
been doing this through the tests it's
been very interesting also and someone
gets a twenty eight one round and then
they're down to fourteen the next round
so it's very interesting how it all
fluctuates and goes through certain
lower just because you're getting the
big number this eat today you're not
gonna be a winner tomorrow right the
next round you may go to the bottom of
the park someone may go up to the top
and go from there so it's definitely a
simulation of what IT security does
every day
in comparison to what other groups do
it's always that variable I think that's
giving that and everybody I've shown
this to we've done the demos has like
that this is exactly what we deal with
at a day to day basis of what the
craziness in our life is that we're
always winning or always losing it's
always it's never gonna be a keepo
continual ramp it's always a Jake Jack
going from there
so so there we go so here's the next
permutation us as throw this out there
all sudden as I was talking some people
like okay well what happens about
hackers because it's not we don't live
in our own bubble we start throwing that
together this does it basically starts
to show you the influence of outside
influence that's going to attack us not
just your own little bubble this is that
next phase of that infrastructure
servers and application people don't
have to worry about as they're building
their stuff so black and red so in other
words they have the same thing as
programs because they're trying to get
into your I am they're trying to ruin
your
vulnerability management programs
they're trying to do this so they have
the same things in the programs the
variables they also have the same attack
surface or your guys the protection of
admins users staffing those are things
but they also also when we go run it
like a business they have things like
vulnerabilities they find a
vulnerability they don't have
vulnerability they have blocks they've
been blocked and here and there so it's
that whole another hacker dice it's
throwing that corruption side they also
start out as a business each of them and
their goal is to get to 30 and then you
they also have the plus and minus dices
with also those and they have their own
category dice but as you'll notice
they're binary is the positive the
Gherkin skull is the negative so in
other words it's that they also now
they're flipping on their side they're
running their own business versus the
anti right there the anti C cell the
corruption so and you repeat this over
this whole time
the winner posts 30 wins after so many
times so if the hacker Coulson so now
you're competing not versus other C
cells but now you're competing against
someone who's trying to break in and
ruin your job
second permutation here we go so in
order playing this game all sudden you
come into the second role whoever is
below 10 also and switches out the C so
dice is the corruption dice at that
point you roll it two more times through
the system then all sudden if you or the
corruption dice is beating the other
people so words also in the corruption
dice goes to 15 and someone is at 12
they also enroll over sort of that whole
thing of going through the things that
one bad environment creates another bad
environment and you keep rolling to go
through those permutations it's just to
give you that perspective that is the
story of the game it's very short and
sweet but it's always growing always
always good
we already starting to talk about next
three turns to build this game up the
next idea is more advanced reputation so
the first part would be you'd roll the
dice to get budget every year so in
other words like we said we do the three
year window at the beginning of the day
you roll dice you get a budget to put in
certain categories to protect yourself
so many point the unit so in other words
if you roll the three you could put it
at I am some words if all sudden the
negative comes at I am you're protecting
yourself from there and it goes through
there every so often every four quarters
or whatever you
to roll the budget dice throw it back in
so now you're starting to play that next
permutation of what you guys really do
at that next level to get that
experience of this is now you're having
control and not just a random variable
experience that is what we're doing
there's also the body of putting cards
to it so that you can buy and acquire
things and go from that and build that
game up more and more and this is an
actually testing feedback input this is
what we're gonna do so to be honest at
Optive booth that's cuz I work where
that's where we have a booth I have dice
so we can run through these if you want
to try it out I would appreciate it so I
can get your guys's feedback everything
the test groups that I've done already
we're getting a lot of feedback a lot of
permutations the idea at least is
initial phase is just to have
conversations the idea to expand this
game up even more and more so it's a
real game that you guys experience every
day in your life to explain to somebody
who does not have your experience does
not work in the system to understand all
the variables and also how to possibly
train somebody to do these things so it
could be incident response sort of a
module off to the side y gir content
that's next year I think the dates are
current at the end of October and Y is
gear content we're gonna do a
Kickstarter for this in 2020 so we
should hopefully have a Kickstarter
kicking up we're gonna build this game
up it will be on Kickstarter to spin it
up to celebrate Gore content 2020 that's
the idea like I said we need to spin
this up
I've getting vendors already sponsoring
we're not it is not going to be a vendor
sponsored game because they all get
bought all the time and move around so
we don't want to brand the game that way
but it is an opportunity for you guys in
us to explain what we do for a living
have it go forward and move forward so
that's it so if we can have your trust
in that so I am NOT imagine that a
Facebook or any so this is the only
social media I use is LinkedIn because
that's what I do
and it's really just to keep context so
I can reach out to people I we created
Optimus Prime is actually the sort of
pseudo company we made to generate this
game for us if you want to please follow
that that is where we will post things
about alchemist prime will get this
information out hopefully you get some
feedback from you and how it's going
and also this is where we will post up
the Kickstarter information if you want
to if you want to be involved please let
me know I am local I am out of Grand
Rapids we are also part of West Michigan
cybersecurity consortium just go through
us and find us
I mean orga reach out to Jamie they will
also go from there like I said I don't
have an hour presentation so you have a
little more free time so any questions
any thoughts please let me know short
sweet go from there and this is for
Gurkha so this is one of things thank
you
[Applause]