we were walking through the contest area
and we came across
one of the weirdest sights i've seen at
def con which is saying something
we have a the floor is just littered
with paper airplanes
all the way to the wall some with some
pretty impressive distances
and people are just pouring in to give
it a try
and i am here with the man who uh who's
the problem here who had made it all
happen yeah the troublemaker so like can
you tell me like what in the world is
going on right here uh well i'm gurney
i'm with the aerospace village
and we're just like wow we need to have
some crazy
funky outrageous activity for people to
do
and we're like let's have paper
airplanes so
we got a paper here to do it we got
crayons to color
we got uh little flinging rockets and
little flingy chickens
and uh set up some targets in the back
we got a nice little runway up there
and people have just been going crazy i
thought it was gonna be just a goof
and uh we ran out of paper yesterday i
had to buy
two more packs today and as soon as i
put the paper out
people just like wolves on a carcass
came in
i mean it's absolutely hilarious because
like
you see the floor is just littered with
them all right
so you've now been doing this for almost
two days what has been
the most impressive one that you've seen
one guy made like a spear
and uh like almost a javelin type thing
and was flinging it all the way down to
the end and
actually got into one of the holes so it
was almost dangerous
as to how big and heavy it was we were
asked by defcon to set up a netting here
just so that things didn't escape too
much
we didn't want to you know attack the
packet hacking village or the
well we did want to attack them i mean
that is incredible
especially the javelin you have to
always be careful man thank you so much
for doing this what a cool creative idea
fun it's been absolute tons of fun oh my
gosh
we're gonna we're gonna expand it next
year to add
uh lights and uh buzzers that go off
when you hit the targets and
time lapse camera and add in some
contests too
oh my gosh yeah another reason to look
forward to defcon 30 but
in the meantime we can make a paper
airplane
thanks for watching and hack on