in vegas
in the biggest and largest hacker
conference in the world also hosts the
most paranoid security people in the
world
so
it's natural to defend yourself against
all the snooping all the wireless and
all the government microchips which we
all know are injected into our hands all
the time in our sleep
for the most part so the best way to
protect yourself is with a tinfoil half
an defcon
we have some of the best tinfoil hats
that you can absolutely create and as a
challenge at defcon the best one wins so
this is tinfoil hat we are
currently making
defcon attendees construct tinfoil huts
to protect themselves from evil mind
control rings
so we have a
[Music]
couple receivers set up and a
transmitter somewhere in this room
we do a delta between uh the two
receivers to see how much we affect the
signal
wait hold on hold on i'm getting in
front of the camera right now
did you just say that it's not just like
a conspiracy theory where like you're
brilliant for a hat you actually measure
the efficiency of the tin foil yeah you
can actually see it going on behind us
so okay that is freaking incredible it's
not just building one for the best looks
but which one actually has the best
signal interruption in it right that's
freaking science here yeah
serious operation absolutely
amazing quick question would this stop
the voices inside my head
it could stop the working amplifier
depending how good you are and uh
creating a tinfoil hat some of the
people
made really good antennas today
oh incredible thank you crux uh and we
will talk to you later this is the
tinfoil hat contest
at def gun you come you build a tin foil
hat you wear it around conference and
you get the enjoyment of knowing you're
protected against every government chip
in your hand and any wireless signal
which is going through your body all
within your own protection
hack on