we are back in the ham radio village and
something we talked about in our last
video was the ability not just to
broadcast your voice but actually data
across would it be this
is the radio spectrum all right it's not
the spectrum tubes no not the spectrum
of
of uh of ethereal tubes
magic ham radio magic magic
so right now we have an image down on
the phone
which we are going to be sending over
what frequency is this
one four four
one four five point seven one point four
five four products
and i hear it going over which is
absolutely ridiculous
and it's going oh my gosh look we can do
we can see it live it's coming into this
one right here
and you see it loading on the fly how
cool is that and it's a straight up
audio cable to like the world's cheapest
uh
uh audio adapter audio is coming out of
the ham radio through the wire into the
computer through the mic adapter and we
have it up on screen
right here you can see it
loading piece by piece
that is absolutely incredible it's not
something i would expect ham radio to be
able to do yeah i know with just a phone
app and a little handheld radio you can
send photos or memes or anything you
want to all your friends on ham radio i
mean no one on ham radio would ever send
a meme it's always very serious things
right yeah typically it's always very
serious matters nothing very fishy going
on but yeah i know you can send whatever
you want on images as long as you use
your call sign on it how how often have
you been rick rolled over ham radio rick
rolled i haven't been rick roll too much
but i've sent out for my fair uh
fair share of rick astley photos
oh man thank you so much thanks for
giving us a quick demo thanks for
watching and hack on