[Music]
um
we are standing at scav hunt the best
competition at def con earth in my
opinion it is an absolutely incredible
competition and i love it because anyone
can compete it doesn't have to be
someone who's highly technical it can be
anyone even if it's your first time at
defcon this year it's both virtual and
remote and they give an incredible
amount of work in it and it's not just
like incredible amount we're creating
the list but the set around me like look
at this
you have an old original monitor
cutting in for a minute this is a
terminal not a monitor i'll blame the
coffee for that one back to it this is
ridiculous
you look around they have like the
original old printers
but just i love this competition because
it's so approachable the people who run
it are fantastic and what ends up
happening is hackers come around the
contest
and they pick up a list read through it
and that in and of itself is so much
entertainment but then they go around
and create new ways of answering the
list like just looking at it fish and
chips that's p-h-i-s-t
hack the planet with an axe
a moby duck
a buffalo overflow
a polp pulp fiction
in sweet potato baby there is just a
ridiculous list it goes on and on and
seeing people come around
in and just submit their entries has
been a huge entertainment
one more reason i love this contest is
the people the people who come to this
booth are absolutely some of the most
friendly and most passionate individuals
who love
this culture love our hacker culture and
it just exemplifies what we're looking
for
at def con ridiculousness and embrace
your weird which is accepted
let's take a look at one other thing
right here which is probably the most
important thing on the table
thanks for watching and hack on