hard-working team looking at all
disrespected
security perspective
overall a
cyano on the world and also for your
inside
op today we got bottle which is not
present
and then in addition arielle fresh
talking and the senate
appears to be
uses your are insecure he
uh... he has won the war for the longest
rather missionaries in frankfurt germany
anti
are and reading the information security
industry aloft
uh... the result of a lot of
technical information so he has an
interviewed this bar
interest is planning
yes possible provocations excuse me just
twisted
uh... i wanted to do spot again because
of the orange
uh... against joe schorr
he is the best manager our priorities
here you go out industry or c_i_a_
a great britain is a a consulting firm
of trait
uh... and release the statue yours as a
managing consultant
forty rich
ethical hacking
team that
grace dot ok thank you
saute with all of them do what we're
going to be here is uh... i'll start to
talk about quality of our company
about parents who
of the business side of the clot and why
it's got all talk
uh... and not your jordan will next
are almost you need
uh... issues uh...
detected in the u_s_ from the you're
starting it
and joel are card from the u_s_
from this year's he said
and i hope all the questions and then
uh... ah what rosiglitazone question he
left hardball
uh... yeah
and ask questions soul
uh... permanently
so i'd like to say that uh...
the obviously is ready for a pesticide
since offer us first about ten fifteen
years ago rightward
if you have
people and you know they've been is
perceived as the stallion and there is
this is about
uh... people rushing to the clout
uh... i don't necessarily understand
may not get their and detracting secure
february's business value perspective
implementing assira
uh... haitian earlier here peacekeeper
large corporation you're talking
a couple of yours and yours is not one
hundred problems on ninety eight years
in prison nation cost
and when you hear it and so what does it
take me and said to me and said
uh... what does it cost me eighty eight
yahoo upgrade so you can uh... you'd
want to see below robes now normalcy
translation
for collaboration spots work by ten
million just to get to the next breath
uh... software
right network
or going to be distracted when something
like six first dot com who is eight
hundred-pound gorilla powder and they
don't
antiserum at last updates
uh... says they're not as as a
consequence
uh... and uh...
and also i'd like to
but it's so i can get the people in
salesforce dot com
uh... literally have falls the rim
solution
beyond whatever might be pretty damn
close that you have a business decision
part can be some
basket cheater litigation costs
dependability infrastructure
uh...
unit and that is the environmental
concerns please datacenter austerity and
there's a lot corporation i probably
have
some sort of a number of religion going
survived by reducing the number of
servers are happy luck cost might might
maternal footprint
and really wines from business
perspective question then becomes
it and i think about it wouldn't cost
peak
salah dudes at europeans have it
uh... about how you're all you're
you use the sea
president college students to vote
accomplishes he's got a job agencies
false systems dot com
the are
all u
noah's using them
at almost one sorry
why is this the case
precipitator
isn't that high and
and it's uh... comhey elected
insists that the processing off personal
data that peaceful op
except for specific reason
and if you do so
you have to have you been transparent
you'd have to look at it
process the
watching
axle orbital
the require
and and you have to do with that
service did you have to make this that
if he did
sold the scenes uh...
personal data and personal days
everything that can be used identifying
is set
so a lot of all
also includes it also put in place
with the president of the install
strategy sold as an example destefani in
germany
helpings abated expertise may want to
see
has to be physically england
so if you use
canals and modesty
where is your name
you're going
can prove it
you're spots policies that
soul
how talking to address this this
decision and that's what's boom reviewed
twenty eight-year-old european union
hostile all reasoning
sought out
i listened to speeches this afternoon
about this rush
ticket three classes
ida costa rica elaine
champions of the people here
or have borough undergoing her daughter
dopamine physical evidence which it
before
to get your guidance on how many of
those additions have to do something
like
sales parking sales automation
however your sales people regarding
birds that information security
redirect
yet so
so the russians as well i i wonder
sometimes with the militias arrested and
if i understand it but i don't want to
subside somewhat invested with people of
the most vicious regarded as a
salesman's felons
of the other part of wonders how
database for doing it because the sea
and first of all of us who has aids
activists really well what's great is
the file abuse product then so it's
probably better when you're doing your
job
but as usual and also give not just
because the sea front we do things
this probably norms asked mister secured
abandoned the designated salsa dancers
just yet
extremal yourselves people running out
and also
images of course i i don't know what
what the heck team
one of the original
this you know
montserrat british people without or are
running around accused your man
absurdities alternatives that suits on
and what was the biggest
business as it happens here
rich investors stocks at prayer
outside settled a lawsuit was this the
salt intake it's really cool
falls through these were treated
differently on a personal countries
there was a big
nations written up
and it will be in a similar steps
probably really grew into a trust
periphery subcommittees village in iran
were recovered or something for disputes
unemployment
gave his speech he walked engendered the
same insistence of mister silvio tests
the census
so reports the wholesale n withers
you know that they had wings part of
that personal
personal information
network that's been fed up there
uh... so i think the devils you this is
not and if you're gonna run
eruption you'd better have a plan in
place priorities
so you've got to be she's like alex
eligible riches report places you know
whose number one three months or so
it was said
what's the business impact sony
red wine wondered playstation
uh...
network is down
even the number of people in a
playstation they're probably going to be
sure xbox divergence
an honorable licensors one can never
really got some problems
the higher color
has already reviewed shocked that the
big bang problema business perspective
is
it was caused by wasp road
you know how many playstations reason
i'm not so
three ending response honest or
cyrus with john
okay so obviously there is the
businesses need to go there and and
you've always got this national title or
it will be treated as the same
saying well call
because eating itself cracker xoxox dot
com
and policy had movement there
so bothers me is a software support
so ten of them at all of you talk a bit
of an intro about what her cost actors
are businesses see according to the
following
different aspects of that
so send him back to you if you could
cost three hundred million dollars
diplomacy are hungrier the application
uh... purses
studied multibillion hundred basis
sears tower
i mean district an axe murder makati
but uh... that's a good possibility
application
costed to get additional rather
so universities you're literally talking
to her days scenes if not more
and that's pretty significant financial
organization particularly with
organizations
affable profit margins
says taking care of you know wal-mart
cardinal health
that aspirate ben
i could see myself three million dollars
from providing
i probably have three or four
applications that profile
uh... that's pretty substantial
cost savings to the bottom line
troops are reconstruct anywhere else
answered questions for you can
so experience that this is the
here's what
happy michael
about sidetracked watchmen
abstract way do you think
heart transplant
jorts listing
people resources participation
and organizations kal
are west point
recipes personal information
appears requirements aren't your dot
blots
in europe
voices right law
system here
here in the u_s_
response
security person scott
to do a reviewer valuation
this happening
you sister
your need
states
uh... levine sugar hain
your
venus
charming
xxxxxxx
well um...
i blew it
sola autopsying slow probe from the
experience of having
european losses but worries about for
reforms this year
soul
when you're in you're next cars
he says
what most of the most you're saying
absolutely including at least bulls
business back but i think he's
how improving
you have to tell dad
usable
everybody
totally would use the word about
greg is there is no remittance and
usually engine separate countries
incurable endurance
about how they did it can be transmitted
by this law
you want basis
so uh...
which and shit
reviewer of your account
assault
what you can do institute
insists that the president of the
individual reviewers sitting here
business needs to insists
but nevertheless uh...
usually usually checked
small all day
frank is also work to do i don't know
how many sauce lautenberg three months
ago
the chairman of the hw
oh
in several articles and island new york
and atlanta scheme
tearing up my first off
because they're giddy about somewhere
somebody microsoft in the clock
and been holding with my suffix policy
well
nahi excess
uh... needle here
well that is in stark contrast to
uh... uh... the yugoslavs you're talking
about
sol
talk a little bit about the the question
here about cap backwards with this
question but i think about that
pitched battle scars clark option
al u
but also standpoint multinational here
u_s_ acknowledge
so my question is polluted
cardwell
uh... value
undersecretaries
rooms
principles reporters songs
just pop
sold is right
ke about that
garments
holdings
constitutions
users really ball are smart
sarantis generally speaking about the
proselytize providers in my mind is not
active for uh...
csc rationale
basic principles holds true uh... as
well so
it would be sick controls
actress protecting information
it was my contract law
as unregulated
company with natalie
provision after while maverick
wants
separate contractual perspective needs
language
says table to comply with my policies
and standards
uh... and here's what i need to bring
peace businessperson
to information prosecuted alliance has
uncontrolled matrix
it's plastic ones
attitude control me speakers is a good
uh...
silence has worked on it
one's uh... as i said
uh... trustpass
so will still be accurate identification
in terms of
how unusual scientist
and it is the religion on
the information that paul extras
restoring clear
we're saying is that issues pretty
strong that these sovereignty infantile
regulatory issues
so reminds us that
uh... his shirt top pretty much out of
the picture indeed
is what will the sixties
plus
of the school stuff that would control
student success center
this policy they need a government
purple
uh... security awareness of place the on
tree
evidence of new york
human health
certainty
sitting on that
once in the priority of innocent
weekends
flat spots here again
eleven players
against the same thing i think
one of the things i was honest
obviously didn't at all you need
fast
christiansen
propeller cost
so it would be is picked up
mature trolls model
uh... working with the one senate-passed
by dr interpreter but
if you've got this crown jewels in her
company has big house offering
people plan place
descended
images policy-wise
questioner
fifty questions rooms
security
she's really
this industry pop stands
such groups out
housing option
vendors
prices
actually talking
this peaceful
that
started asking her to don t and
control of the clubhouse matrix honestly
want
accidental are large resistant using now
made a lot more efficient use select
uh... he contacts you
uh...
if you can't you really trust
or it could be great
and and and i'm stressed out there
you've got to be able to go ahead and
argumentation
excise actually counter cultural
it got bought which kind of surprising
that dick nixon
united technologies secret sauce
energy last sunday institution
uh... and i didn't have intelligence
that
covers that might be considered
can you know how
terrifying
products op
clubhouse he's
issues
but the quote the product of finance
darrow
iptables conway got hurt
right about the cluster
nigger
optus
they say they believe personalized
environment so i may have the employer
facility
so that's that's relatively safe
so i have no or what
servers act
interested
stations out
teton servers or happy and
outlines next year
that's the basic up
sponsors
i'll try going back to mister overgrown
so
job growth
so let's go back to you privacy laws
and here is the issue
it is a good carl
is at home these
those issues with that
like came out with his are at
of expecting up discipline network sites
if it isn't there
but at the end of the houses that
it's said
whose explosive it's selangor
notice you have to the
lebed
stated processing status from sixteen
excess of it
pistols once processes is the
purposefully so away
explaining it
you would
macau loot for processing the sava
qualities principles to security
you have to secure
processing
personally dot
and encryption is one way
go to protect the state's civil if you
were talking about substance
googlejob if u it could be statement
unit that you all
if you prefer to state that it did
accused of breaking the casting
expansion using this
still standing
and say idaho sets the stage
eight states only the
the cost of those naked makeup i'd had
read actually it's there
the city
used mentioned
like himself
no sign that said i think
upbeat and cheery is somebody
rapists
prescription side about
gospel
generally i think uh...
europeans approaches
more since
at the school issue because of
experiences
substantially
still starting
i think that you were doing these
associated
to be very careful with reportedly be
available
case is going to cost got an invitation
to it
most of the facts that person that i
thought that
that's when i heard the top of the
message
what's up brother
and i think god there's a lot of people
that
that is that it was time
uh... but he didn't see uh... ms dot gov
obvious presentations response
together back here
it's really really good in terms of
getting basic definition
midwest pract dot helped
communities
i think that's a really good lots of
pictures
it's also
contribu
used to be the federal c_i_o_ white
house put together
arafat strategy like asap dot
bus transit passes more update
admissions and also has a good strategy
silverdarkcure nine
this process
of high
and he process all
maynard's ira acouple riding on saturday
insanity hello calling organize
except saying exhibiting
you should probably built by people over
sixty
me pablo do you do something
okay once you do integrated here it is
database or or whatever legal process
raised according to our
data processing at policies standards
are in sports figure cost would be happy
to say
non-smokers
it's the economy
so let's talk about what the rockets to
begin your abuse
s we need
free of charge
to keep all the information is useful
about being team
reserves are on our website
yet artwork manner
europe
who are looking at the lawyers around
them
a big plus
i find it arrives
tennessee
all ever i talk here so of one last talk
to you
copyrights
copies are being into you
all of the world
acknowledges hikari issues also
interest rates
so to speak to you
terrific about that
hot
because i've seen it out
anything else lol secretly or export
subscript question some time uh...
determining accurately business flow
what is the ability to care about in
terms of uh...
or to restore the provisions of the
questions you guessed
yasir solar executives accuracy where
burglars were again
one hundred racial
in that country
yet did you make of the retrospective
the report is from
border her mind
attributes required
spasms kickbacks c
a lot of has got to do it
extracted
deployment utility cloud computing where
is my information
sites are half
primary designers exited salesforce
handicappers replication squirrels
surface fogleman's rehearsal
because it's a symbolic insults
i thought well that's probably his
wrists new york
i think the opportunity
with international stuff has to be some
sort of
federated
precision instruments somehow
saturday
what's what's left
his request
accelerating advanced search clear
housebreakin
cancers have one last time it sells for
citizen dole
communist governments as it were
so they set up a center
indicate that he speaks his mind
sense of the question becomes you know i
was wondering what's up
partitioning installed
it's possible
okay thank you guys uh...
and i think it's a lesser but there are
ranjan
are you
uh... run welfare
uh... honey hyderabad
jewelry morris
authority or you can sometimes
what i want to talk behind bars hours
three years ago
he realized that
with barb
vp uncanny
carbine
hahaha here anyway
on
actually actions
here
uh...
he reckoned combined walkway
make those tough cost
here here
i've had a few etc
traditional is record
trip here
risk-takers
location information asking for
and innovative extracts
occupancy
conquer
one
week his welcome react okay
beginning on
one happy review
humorous overall actress
the resort
equity
important huh
paul's yucaipa pakrac off
diac
i will get better
all right
out here
work for me
lowered
haha
i mean carry i'm
exploded on that
yet
what was fought you've got to know
paragraph
or company
effort itself you know relations yahoo
co are
all ear
denouncing
his death
enacted
consignee i don't think i'd be happy
anywhere
before he was born
and your job
detectable archives
nahi convention poorly
if
taking that information
before eleven ninety
we've got a place of the evening
inquisition and user data
would you then
so a person who guarded by rebel
identifiers you could be largesse
his vast number
but you know this advertising his big
time
without any uh... correlation yukon high
i think the abusers
if you have on without agribusiness
how important do you remember
if that happened
i don't believe all such crime here
wendy dad
correlated with you could tell
substantive content provoking
perspective
just leave it for me
terry hilliard again system
you know it
who arrived
people will go to the house
when we land
and do you want
very quickly believes he's on escalated
privileges
anyway getting broken world
but all of your comment that you have to
come here to see review
the sale of a new orleans asthmatics
first
after that
fountains and you use cases
reportedly found not guilty
we have an aluminum did anybody knows
he's got mobile
animal lover bruising
or whose accounts
you protest was loud and then i would
like me
that individual user
is better than what we saw one block
room
ridiculousness
when he lost and did you see it
with whom you isn't do you have all
recruitment
that's right there
sahoo
p_g_e_
you lobby and bilingual really bad
words a session still
not only to the best season rockbox
reviewing the body
we know where he came in from so we're
still waiting room
everything you see these
contacted you
he's asking for an report
evanescence forwarded
so if you know endurance
brian correlation system
you need to have a place to do business
what we call that it was a personal
problems
but there's always been eating dynamic
immediately obviated rerouted
by rule or condition
without having to do that
delegate his
therapy session
sessions of the closing argument work
p_v_c_ memory for processing ac
so officer candidates for the load in
memory for our problem
uh...
the next ten years been waterboarding
did you see
ballooning
but all of our own people off and you
animals you on
if everything works and big mine
that representative revocable
but noticeably deteriorates farmers well
but you can understand them
if you're a defense the internet you can
do that
but if you really have at least of all
that
where subcontractor roles
behavior
or if i could for example
an operative hahaha
so you can talk a lot
which i think that he's or across the uk
bob
correlating accessions distinctly
black person who has i think that you
know
they went through the process
this fall and that's fantastic
station are working or or preprocessor
genuine work hard
petey system
associate user enterprising
exactly what the parking lot
what do you think that you see
jurgen wattenberg what department will
do
i'm typing information packet for you
the difficulty is that a lot of movement
and information
well let me tell you how box basically
transports
weekly standard
alfresco responding via
who change their current account deficit
person contractor
any running disgruntled lane
uh... with
anyone's websites that people are
block
expressed for uh... right
you can get a border because somebody
might have been
people's arms
is very proud of our country
about expressed or can be
changes that you need
there's another you don't have any
longer
voting and warning
century all activity
our national marked difference this time
and what he did not
this is voting for john doe is that
one two three
for a variety
into the uh...
ourselves they didn't go back to you
despicable report up to you
role admissions if you can have a lot of
people don't have roles with great you
got
delayed world people are still trying to
roll out idea system here
role information in there
but it
elective revived at
say someone from sales
contains
and a certain basically say how many
times i've done it
eppadi financial systems
don you're buying one-time unemployed
order
how you want
financial systems of the juicy bother to
reply
effect on you
so i was
you'll see here
it'll be good news
tell me
s brothers
send email to a predator message was
sent
a bilateral basis
correlational
what value do they should be acting
i didn't need to see
eugene human resources consistently do
it
what's his role to get more information
on
advice generate members based on a roll
back user group membership
mohanty human resources inventory
the extent of the matter is that at the
new security
but maybe something he doesn't want to
be traveling to resign greedy or here
right now
for example
it's nice to know to be a role
when it was really wrong manager
this is market development yet as part
of your security systems and windows
block
but if all in one place here rip-off
grounds
i don't do this
eating will be gone
initially loan guarantees
needed what's called active list
and then we go with different systems
yes i do you need i think so
specifics is out there basically for the
same person
already that he ast interests of our
all fire one single person
now whatever pc user
with bob we can suck it up
entertaining
you sir i did
wonderful adventure you notice the
numbers at
pennies
resulting additives
anybody
sonali from forty five million well
who spends a lot of active
were born in general
role that doesn't work where most people
do not have the rating systems
lawyer
information below
if paintball turkeys unpopulated
and even in the world
the roles in through that much of your
support
unless you have an activity
advances toward important for managing
vendor
so now we know that it is
administrators and knowledge
frequent repetition but
the holocaust needing information here
okay
wrote for an extended
judaism
there's been a lot darker and more
pgp plus detractors
if they're coming into town
speaking deputy editor and my dad
so we can seriously affect
alas lots of where they want you to
there's a lot of the windows system
and you can use your account for web
services
one of the people at work i want to know
mr donahue wants to cut what you think
we have ninety
are interested would be prepared to use
that money
olesco across the border or not
where is that there is no way
wasn't certain
easygoing networks i have to do anything
if you go into that war is that we do
know i work on it
and by i think the basics of these laws
even higher tax on contracting
so it should be fall basic attributes
right out of our city
are very peaceful and my block
and the next decade
you have to have the ability to listen
to him
titanic and judi
andrew agnew's environmentalists
you don't have many things that you
wanted to have that based on your policy
ability to try and use that as i went
through resulted from the union
the aaa apparently there are
d_c_ police keep track
you know i can meet you
we don't want pizza where do you know
when you get shut down determination
inquiry into the next
iraqi facilities
method where you are going to happen
alcohol has to get involved in germany
me medicaid much easier
black finally did
it doesn't work all our congressmen who
borrow
information they have no idea at all
over here
now we have also seen the session back
in florida is a
up into the department hotmail
one hundred onto
and they'd be able to get information
robbersons which is
better meet your or our community what i
you're going through there
is reliever
got how do you have any question
or how it works for her
regional office
people here and let's see it
uh... runtime deeper
but uh... there's no question thing
so basically law
so for example if the spirit of the city
uh... you know off-the-shelf
implementation
so that it is optional but we've got to
have a mackerel online lautenberg
and then he grabbed access to the stock
market
firepower
now to talk about what they should be
published dot apartment four a
but here are a lot
if you believe in and out of our
argue
they've already written off comp park
sitcom
products are in part we don't need
there are not part of the indian creek
further
yes a lot of our hearts by over all andy
and i hope all the financial loss
are all happy right
are ruben sierra club
so it's published its own source right
now
to use our site
other tables for example such as former
apartment building
be magnet for parents out
except for pat buchanan borrowers
it off
i'll write up dekho and uh... that up
donated and annette organized crime
and will appear
not just us is the price is workable
nasty out
you know and you've talked to you
alice analysis lorena
those all supported the authorized off
uh... or
that
yes uh... there we have our repertoire
granddaughter
uh... engines and
under
dinner time
are review
united and mandarin
pretty well
fantasy