I thought it was a really good idea to
start by insulting the audience just to
sort of wake us all up and I was asked
to do this talk a few months ago and I
spent like anybody's asked to do a talk
the last few months figuring out what to
talk about and then sort of wrote it
last week and what I what I want to do
really is sort of talk about things I've
learnt over the last two years but first
I think like anything these are really
the two questions I asked myself pretty
much every morning when I when I wake up
Who am I so it's so what I want to talk
about as I said it's kind of the things
I've learned for those last two years
prior to that I was a pen tester I sort
of ran pentose businesses that sort of
thing why am I here I'm here to tell you
about that I've been doing security for
25 years and I thought with this talk I
could do something technical and pretend
I'm still technical but I'm not so that
wouldn't work in front of this audience
so I'm trying to give you the benefit of
what I've learnt in the last two years
and it kind of turned out that most of
what I knew in terms of doing security
on the inside if that makes sense
was fairly wrong so this is what we're
trying to explain the things that I've
been I've been up see I'm a see so in in
a retailer and I think it's fair to say
that that two years ago security wasn't
really a thing so the first thing I had
to figure out how to do was how to
actually make it be excuse me be a thing
the second kind of key lesson that I've
learned over the last two years is
actually getting stuff done is really
quite hard in fact I'm a lot grayer now
than I was two years ago it is it is
staggeringly hard sometimes to get
things done and perception is fact I
mean you can sort of debate this in the
world we live in at the moment
what digital I think has done and this
is much broader than just my job is is
actually turn perception really truly
into fact you hear stories of fake news
and so on and I think what's happened is
people's sorry people are confusing
opinion with fact and if something said
enough times online it sort of becomes
true and this is creating I think a
really really interesting atmosphere in
which we try and do our work so lesson
number one that I've learned maybe 70%
of it is how to make security be a thing
doing the security stuff I think was in
inverted commas easy because I like to
think after sort of 20 years I have at
least some knowledge about what what
security means but sort of making it be
a thing in a large corporate is quite
difficult because for something to be a
thing and this is going to sound
slightly bizarre it sort of has to exist
and there has to be a difference between
what is security and what isn't security
so you sort of have to carve out a space
for it to exist in and in order to do
that there's a few key things and these
look like blindingly obvious statements
and in fact they are blindingly obvious
statements but quite often the
blindingly obvious is completely
overlooked and certainly when I was on
the pen testing and consulting side of
the fence
they were overlooked certainly by me you
need a budget that's fairly self-evident
if you're going to do anything in any
organization you need the money to do it
with so the first thing you got to
figure out is how much money does one
need in order to do what one wants to do
which means you got to figure out what
you want to do and then you've got to
figure out how much it costs and then
you gotta persuade the business to give
you the money to do what you want to do
but the problem is you've got to explain
to the business what it is you're trying
to do and when it comes to security
that's quite hard so what you do you sit
in front of the board and say give me
all this money and we won't have a
breach that'd be a really bad thing to
say because I suspect the vast majority
of these audience could probably breach
most companies if you sat down for long
enough so that's the state
that's not really gonna get you the
money or certainly might get you the
money in the short term but you'll fail
eventually so you have to try and figure
out a way of explaining to the business
why it costs approximately ten times
more than they thought it would to get
anywhere near to what they want you to
do and even that's not the end of it so
that's kind of problem number one and
specifically when I when I started where
I am now a large part of that what is
now the security budget that sits under
me sat in I T so as effectively having
to rob IT of money in order to secure
their systems so that creates shall we
say the wrong kind of friction between
the security team and IT because they
don't want their budget to be robbed
because it's being compressed anyway so
that's tricky some of the other budget
was managed through a project management
office so they would manage my capital
budget for me
they provide project managers for me
they'd give me far too many project
managers and not enough security geeks
to get the job done so that was another
problem so I spent the last six months
trying to get all this budget
consolidating into one place so I can
actually manage it and we've sort of
achieved that and that's a good thing
the second thing having got a budget and
again this is a blindingly obvious
statement and this is going to be 40
minutes of blindingly obvious statements
you need to buy stuff with that budget
this is this is particularly difficult
and again do you think this must be
really easy because I guess a lot of you
guys are in doing pen tests and things
like that all the time and you don't see
what's going on behind the scenes
procurement departments in companies
there KP ID on reducing cost
now surely as security people we know
that reducing cost increases risk so
this is almost entirely counter to what
we're trying to achieve as a security
team so we go to procurement and that
they're good people they do a good job
this is this is not a criticism of them
of any of my colleagues but they want to
run a tender process because it's what
they do and they want to get competition
because it's what they do and they want
to find the right price because that's
what they do
fair play how
if I want to buy a certain specific
piece of technology from a small startup
company that doesn't have any
competitors in the market having
procurement spend three months looking
for a competitor is a bit of a waste of
time but they have to follow the process
anyway a lot of this stuff I think it's
fair to say was not entirely visible to
me initially and I'd wonder why things
weren't getting bought quick enough so
I'd say to my guys what's happening and
they're sort of chasing the procurement
process around the business frankly like
it's sort of wrapped wrapped in a maze
trying to figure out why it's being
blocked I describe it as kind of
wrestling matches between procurement
people who are tasked with reducing cost
and security people who I'm tasking with
get this stuff in as quick as we
possibly can so that was interesting so
what we've what we've done is we've had
to build or are in the process of
building a security specific procurement
process so that we can not necessarily
bypass the controls because they need to
be there but so that we can get stuff in
without having to go through competitive
tender processes and looking for the
best price and all that sort of stuff so
this took months in the meantime we've
got a budget we're not spending any
money or anything we're not necessarily
doing security yet what we're trying to
do effectively is sort of build the
interface between what security will be
and the rest of the business it's a
strange one and it struck me actually I
was reading something in a magazine I
think when Harvard or something on the
plane on the way up yesterday and it was
talking about doing agile at scale now
I'm not a developer I was one a long
time ago 27 years ago I started in
security in 25 years ago because I
realized I was a really crap developer
probably crap developer not half-bad
Penta so I don't know and but in this
article it was talking about doing agile
at scale and the fact that if you build
part of the business that's using an
agile methodology that's going to get
bottlenecks by all the other parts of
the business that are still doing things
in a kind of hierarchical command and
control manner and it struck me that
actually what we do in security
particularly pen testing and security
testing is sort of agile
we find a load of things that are wrong
and we try and fix them as fast as we
possibly can which is why stuff gets
bottleneck so that just kind of made me
think and it's something to think about
over the weekend astir as to how I can
learn from what the developers do and
how they interface with the rest of the
business I think we've got somewhere
through this in order to buy stuff but
then what I've noticed now here now I'm
on sort of if you like this side of the
fence I you know I could throw stones
and I've got a real job and I used to be
a consultant but that's all just rubbish
anyway because it's all they're all real
jobs just the hilarity of emails that
come in trying to sell me things it's
they're brilliant this one I get an
email from this chap and you know Fair
Play he's trying to sell I assume what
is quite a good solution the emails very
good
how many privileged accounts are active
in your network right now world loads
privileged accounts are essential for
day-to-day operations in all areas of IT
attackers are aware of how important how
far-reaching privileged accounts can be
they are a golden ticket to compromise
allowing total control of all resources
and a network well no Sherlock you
know we know this the problem is the
subject line when I look at my email on
a Monday morning and I see that it's
bloody terrifying does it work as a
sales technique no that's the first time
I've read his email I might go back to
him a and say look actually you know
what I took the piss out of your
conference maybe we should meet if
you're in the room talk to me afterwards
you need people this is this is really
really really obvious and businesses are
populated by people not processes again
obvious statement that the trick here is
that you need to get the people doing
what you want them to do and that's very
difficult and I found that one of the
hardest things in the mood from
consulting into client side and I think
one of the reasons is in consulting work
there is a team of people who are tasked
with a specific goal for a client the
deadlines are known the team forms and
everybody broadly speaking is driven
towards doing that that one thing so
getting people to do what I want them to
do or what the task leader wants them to
do
is a relatively easy thing because when
it comes to review time in consulting
firms it's all about did you keep the
client happy did you hit the deadlines
did the projects come in on budget and
so on so there's a set of drivers sort
of hanging over every project team in a
consulting firm that are pushing them
all in the same direction and drivers
are really important but in client-side
if you like in industry there isn't a
common set of drivers because you know I
work for a retailer that means there's a
blind adobe statement coming up that
means we're not a security firm so the
drivers for the business are not
necessarily about security and the
drivers for the board are not about
security yes they need to manage risk
but security to the board is a nother
risk that they manage in what we do the
key drivers are making profit selling
things in the stores selling things
online
keeping the shareholders happy keeping
the investors happy that sort of thing
that's the drivers that are coming in to
the top of the company and they spread
out and various teams as I said are
driven by various different things so
I've talked about procurement and how
their job is to keep the cost down
finances job is to add up the numbers
and make sure we're hitting budget and
so on but you also find in any
organization that the real network is
not what it says on paper because when
you sort of dropped into a company as I
was two years and I love my job please
please don't get me wrong I think I
really really really really enjoy it's
excellent because it's hard there are
some people that have been in the job
for 10 years 20 years 30 years these are
really good people don't get me wrong
these are very very good people they're
sort of you know family man family women
they they want to do they want to do a
good job they want to provide for their
children they want to come to work they
want to do well what they
don't want is disruption because it's
terrifying and I can understand this
because I've been disrupted in the past
and it's not funny
they don't want this they don't like
change not because they are they don't
understand it just because it's not what
drives them so you end up with a very
very very tight what's the word I'm
looking for effective informal all chart
where Bob or no Jim who knows Mary who
knows Lisa who knows Colleen who knows
George that can get something done so
something came up this morning actually
funnily enough I've got a contractor
working for me on my team I've extended
his contract because I've brought him in
using my security procurement route not
the standard way we bring contractors in
we had a little glitch this morning I've
extended his contract which means his
his user account needs to also be
extended otherwise on Monday he can't
log in which means he can't do the stuff
that I want him to do HR can we extend
his contract yes just go on - I'm not
gonna say the name just go on to the
company that we use to bring all
contractors in and they will trigger the
process in order to get his user account
extended he didn't come in through that
company what do we do and this is the
problem so what I did is I use the
informal org chart to get it done so I'm
now supporting the very thing that was
working against you when I started and
this is this is tricky this is really
really tricky to figure out how to deal
with and you have to sort of work with
it and you have to sort of work against
it and hopefully the end of the day
something will something will happen I
like John Kotter quite a lot he's
written a lot of books on unchanged and
and I would sort of urge anyone here
really to read coarser I'm assuming a
large number of you will be aware of
what he what he wrote I think his his
kind of seminal work if you'd like is a
book called leading change and it talks
about the seven stages of change in any
in any book written by an American there
has to be a number of stages that you go
through but to be fair it's quite a good
way break
problem down and I can't remember off
the top of my head what all that what
all the stages are but the key thing
that always sticks in my mind is you
have to articulate a vision of where you
want to get to and keep reiterating
where you're trying to get to otherwise
people forget why you're trying to drive
the change they get bored and they go
back to doing what they're always doing
he also talks about the fact that you
have to get some early wins in otherwise
people don't see the change happening
and again they get bored and going back
to doing what they what they always do
trying to sort of make security be a
thing in any organization is actually a
massive change so continually
articulating what you're trying to
attempt to do is pretty critical so I
kind of refer back to mr. Kotter quite a
lot as a decent sword IDing point just
to remind me that because we're not a
security company 99% of people in the
company forget about security within
about 24 hours so I have to keep
reiterating it which is why awareness
and culture is absolutely critical I
just really can't emphasize this enough
I'm a huge believer in the fact that
human beings I think frankly cause every
security problem which which might sound
slightly bizarre but code is written by
humans so if the codes
failing there's a human at the root of
it humans attack us so it's humans so so
changing the way that people think and
the way that people behave around
security is absolutely fundamental I
don't I don't think as a and without
sounding pompous or anything I don't
think as a society we've got anywhere
near understanding what digital actually
means most people's mindset is nowhere
near figuring out what what we're
actually doing with all this digital
technology things that I'm not here to
talk about but it might be fun is why do
we have to connect everything together I
don't get it why does why does
everything have to be connected it's
bizarre surely the best way of
protecting massive pieces of data is to
not connect them to the Internet
if they don't need to be if it's an
internal system why you know is is the
benefit really worth the risk I do
wonder if there's going to be a big push
now to you know the digital
disconnectors let's call them people who
don't want their data kicking about in
Cambridge analytical or other companies
people that don't want massive online
databases that can be hacked that
contains their personal data I think
there is you know maybe on there you
know this the Gartner hype curve we're
kind of at the the peak of inflated
expectations and we're sliding rapidly
down into the trough of everything's
being hacked and all our data is out on
the internet for free anyway so why not
just put it there let's just put my
personal date on there and say there you
go make my job a lot easier
politics kills anything particularly the
large business I mean it's its political
by nature again this isn't the criticism
I'm not going to go through any
particular specific examples but there
are always senior level politics in in
any in any in any company and one of the
things I've learned over the last couple
of years is sometimes you have to fight
this again is all pretty obvious I mean
really fight sometimes you have to give
things away you absolutely have to
choose your battles you can't push on
all fronts in one go and this is
something I'm constantly sort of telling
my team to do look don't worry about
that
someone will say I don't know there's a
load of paper lying about in people's
desks and we've got clear desk policy
okay that's bad obviously but how much
paper whereas about that much how many
records on that few hundred okay are you
really going to pick a fight with that
guy in procurement who's leaving that
stuff on his desk well actually really
what you want him to do is buy database
access management products so we can
protect a million records in the
databases so let's just choose the
debate we're going to have with him are
we going to give him a kicking for
something at which point he's probably
going to make our lives difficult now
I'm not having a pop up procurement I
like the guy but I have to sort of
advise my team just just be a bit
careful what you're doing because the
person you're kicking today is going to
be the person you really want
to help you tomorrow this was something
III sort of didn't expect at Odin it's
linked to the budgetary problem it's
just moral hazard all over the place so
so so moral hazard basically is sort of
defined as making decisions that won't
really affect you in the long term so so
for example moral hazard some of the
banks look out for its effectively
gambling with other people's money in in
my in my environment it's a part of the
business that is doing something and I
have this conversation quite regularly
and I'm saying that we've got to look at
what what we're doing from a security
perspective if we're going to I don't
know put this new system in open these
stores whatever it is we need to make
sure that we do this in a secure way oh
but that's your job pool I thought I
thought that we do it and then you come
along and sort it out afterwards no no
that's that's not how it works
oh but we've them we've already signed
the contract
ah so I didn't see that contract so I
really don't know what you're doing and
it all looks you know reasonable but I
think there's going to be some holes in
it so we've got to come and sort it out
well that's that's your problem well
we're gonna hit our revenue targets and
our budgetary targets so no problem so
I'm trying to figure out a way and I
haven't got the answer yet of putting
some security targets or some security
drivers in place to try and catch the
things the business does that it just
assumed that we're going to come along
and sort out again this is this is not a
criticism this is about sort of whole
scale change in people's thinking so
that stuff is sort of baked in from the
top if we do this we have to understand
the risks inherent in doing it and we
have to pay as necessary to mitigate the
risk that the most common conversation
actually there's two really common
conversations that I have the first one
is what we're doing this and I'll be
sort of at a meeting talking about what
what the business is going to do and
I'll say well actually broadly speaking
it's going to cost X million quid or
whatever to build security in well
that's what your budgets for isn't it
Paul no my budget is there to do sort of
operational security and effectively
transformation across the piece my
budget isn't the pot to be robbed
whenever the business wants to do
anything
in year because I can't predict what
it's going to do so I couldn't possibly
assemble a budget to do that at start my
general response is if the business
wasn't going to do this would we have to
pay to security to secure it if the
answer's no then it's not my budget it's
got to come from the budget the asset
budget if you like that the second most
common email I get is Dipple we really
support what InfoSec are trying to do
and obviously we know that we've got to
mitigate the risk and we've got to
protect the business however my
particular project is going to generate
10% incremental revenue in year and why
percent 5% dragwon say incremental
profit in year and it really has to go
live on Monday your team have identified
some problems with it and they're saying
it can't go live can I have a security
exception no you can't you just can't I
get I used to that they've calmed down a
bit now because I think I've got across
a lot of the business but I used to get
those sort of emails on about a
bi-weekly basis and if you start giving
security exceptions to everything you
sort of end up with a colander and
that's not a very good place to be so
the second thing I learned I've probably
covered some of this in what I've been
talking about already is is that getting
stuff done is actually just really hard
there's there's no other way of putting
it it's just hard because as I said
probably cover some of these slides the
business does do dumb things and this is
exactly what I was talking about with
the theme and I keep guessing the main
one we get is well we have to keep the
business running so we can't shut this
thing down to upgrade it or patch it
well we've got over that hurdle and now
we can do that the 15 million quid
incremental revenue as I said I get
those emails about not as often as I
used to but I used to get them a couple
of times a month excuse me
the CEO is asked for this person that's
a good one as well I get that a lot
the CEOs asked for this personally I'm
sure in some sense he or she has but
actually what they haven't specifically
asked for is to take liberties and take
risks so in another very real sense they
she hasn't asked for this personally
quite often it's very easy to get caught
in a sort of escalation game so I'll
have my security analysts working with
project managers or doing whatever they
do and the project manager will write my
own list of email saying well you know
we're going to have to try harder to get
this live on next Wednesday
because insert name with very senior
director here needs to see this live and
is going to be very annoyed at you if it
doesn't happen I've told my guys just to
escalate that straight up the chain if
it happens we have a process where we
sort of risk assess things this is this
is nothing particularly rocket science
see we have a process where there's
there's a risk assessment the start of a
project and if we get those kind of
emails and people saying well we're
going to have to have a security
exception we write back and say that's
that's fine let's just have a half-hour
chat about it and we put the the risk
assessment in front of them so well this
these are the risks that we've we've
identified and these are the controls
that were that we need to put in place
and one of the sort of first things I
did was was put in place a a whole sort
of you know risk governance piece with
what grade of person can sign off which
which type of risk so we put the risk
assessment in front the project manager
and say that's fine you know it's it's
our job to advise and guide on security
and in this instance we recommend
strongly that you put these controls in
place otherwise you're taking a risk
it's not my job to decide between you
know decide what risks the business
should take that's the job of directors
and the board and so on so we say to the
project manager well here's the here's
the risk assessment as you can see these
are the risks we're recommending you
mitigate them if you don't want to
that's absolutely fine but as per the
the guidance here you're going to have
to get sign-off from the exco or from
the PLC board so you know I'm happy to
come in front the board with you and
support you and say this is my opinion
and this is what you're asking to do and
we'll see if the board makes the
decision ok Paul and just I'll tell you
what let's put half an hour in tomorrow
and have another chat about this okay
magic tomorrow comes hey Paul yeah I
found some more budget and we can deploy
these controls yeah we recommend get
them in by Wednesday easy it's about
getting the decision-making in the right
place and making if you know I think of
it as a sort of the common point of
ancestry in the org chart who is the
right person to make the security risk
versus gain for the business decision
and we've tried to identify those people
and push the process so that when the
project matters is trying to take
liberties they know they're gonna go and
have to ask someone and explain why they
want to take a risk and possibly expose
the business the last one on this is
that we've done it that way before is
it's just that you know we'll know this
when it's really really hackneyed one of
the things we're trying to do and as a
strategic goal if you like for security
is is to not do anything that would
downgrade our security okay so you kind
of incrementally improve so if we
replace something with something else we
make sure that something else is going
to be more secure which does cause a few
ructions and quite often we just get the
thing well you know Bob's doing like
that over there well that's fine but if
he was slapping himself in the face
every morning for half an hour would you
just do the same well crack on or well
that's the way we've always done it but
surely that's that's the absolute reason
not to do it that way because that's the
problem and that's kind of why I'm here
and that's why I've spent the last year
trying to fight and get a budget and do
something to sort this out so if you
like they're that they're the kind of
four key reasons the people come to me
with as to why they don't want to do
security we are we are slowly winning
I'm not I'm not suggesting that we're
not
this was the one that has an ex
pentester and is this net this next sort
of little section it is quite pen testy
because I love pentose and it's great
actually it's really it's it's it's just
brilliant but vulnerability is how do
they actually get fixed when I was a pen
tester you do a pen - so my pen test
vintage is is you know if we kind of
wind the clock back about 17 years year
2000 2001 2002 and give me the Unicode
standard I could probably hack an iOS 4
box but you know and I did buy the
Unicode standard back in the day it was
a riveting read but I'm actually does
does go a long way if anyone here and
there's a lot of young people I'm now
old and gray I almost you to read the
stuff about what Microsoft did when they
were solving the Unicode vulnerabilities
because it was a very very good tale of
not fixing the root cause when you into
the kind of double decode
vulnerabilities and things like that
anyway
probabilities get fixed by IT people
okay at that that's fairly self-evident
I used to put a Penta support in you
know here's here's a bunch of things
that need to be fixed go back six months
later do another pen test ah hang on a
minute this kind of looks pretty similar
to where the six months ago I'm sure the
situation is a lot better now but I know
it's not completely solved IT people
have to fix vulnerabilities you have to
put it in the queue the IT demand queue
to get something fixed which is not
necessarily the right way because the
problem with IT people is they're
generally quite busy wondering why
something's gone offline so you think
okay
let's just look at fixing the really
critical stuff because that's the bit
that we have to deal with absolutely the
mediums and the lows fine we'll put them
on the pile and we'll we'll get round to
those but I'm really worried about the
super critical stuff but IT people are
really busy
they're always but the thing that I've
learnt as well actually is that the
digital economy it's not really that
digital to be honest it's it's held
together by a bunch of people sat in
rooms looking at massive screens waiting
for a red light to come on somewhere and
then frantically fixing it that's how
digital works
it doesn't work by being digital it
works by people who are drinking a lot
of coffee so a better question to start
asking is how fast are we fixing the
critical vulnerabilities and if this is
something where we've we've simply had
to inject more pace into what we're
doing and I think this is something that
when I speak to other other sort of
people in my position this is something
we all wrestle with is how to get the
stuff done really really fast because if
we're not careful we get caught in
queues of change requests and IT demand
and all that sort of thing so coming
back to the point I made about about
agile I'm trying to start adopting a
more agile approach to fixing critical
vulnerabilities with sort of squads of
people who are going to fix stuff and
people are going to find the problems
and so on and trying to sort of learn
from what the what the software
development community have done in order
to just inject pace into things but this
means we sort of have to go around
change request queues which does make
life a little bit difficult because
there are certain things that we need to
inform IT that we're doing we simply
can't go in and mess with the stuff
because it'll probably break something
so this is an this is quite a difficult
one to crack I'd like to get the quick
the critical fixed time down to about 24
hours on the basis that was
internet-facing an apprentice has hacked
it then probably someone else has and
that's really quite terrifying the other
piece I I sort of had to learn a lot
about was how penetration tests actually
happened when you on this side of the
fence once you've gone through
procurement we refreshed our pen test
suppliers we've got a sort of mechanism
where we have four suppliers and we
allocate work and so on and so forth but
then I had to deal with the absurdity
and it is an absurdity of raising a
change request when I wanted to do a pen
test of our internet-facing systems
which honestly I banged my head on the
desk or now and that was just bonkers
you know and this is basically what I
say and this is actually what I'm going
to start distributing around the
business now I think because why do I
have to race a change request to do what
many people are doing to our systems
anyway I just don't get it
there's so many arguments if I do a pen
test and the pen tester knocks it over
at least we knocked it over and we can
hopefully
get it back off having said that I have
a good degree of sympathy for the IT
people buried as they are under racks of
spaghetti and why they want to know what
I'm doing and when I'm testing the
systems and this is sort of my plea if
you like to the pen testers amongst you
and how you can help people like me and
how you can help people in my team and a
key one sort of with regards to change
requests and the raising thereof before
I do a pen test is number seven and I
can't stress this enough you've got to
make us really comfortable that you're
not going to cause a p1 outage okay
because in IT world yeah there's
security high priority obviously there's
also system outage high priority there's
there's a problem with the
re-platforming over the weekend in
another company I'm sure you saw it on
the news they are having a devil's job
with their new platform and and they
absolutely have my sympathy they are
there it's a horrendous position they're
in system outages these days are are
huge and in fact as I'm sure you're
aware the GDP are now is shining a real
spotlight on availability of data and
there's going to be some fairly meaty
fines for companies whose kit falls over
which you know arguably on my side of
the fence is going to make IT even more
itchy about getting pen testers in
because there's going to be have to be a
balancing decision about is it worse to
knock something over for two hours or
lose a little bit of data I don't know I
think this is going to be thrashed out
in the courts for quite a long time to
come a nice second career as a lawyer in
this field would be quite lucrative
so pen testers please engage with our
incident response processes engage with
our service management processes
understand how they work and understand
you know that if you're testing
something and you're I don't know
fuzzing the fussn't ahead out of
something and the site suddenly becomes
a bit laggy and your thing
you know crap what have I done don't
just kind of hit escape and control see
and stop what you're doing and then say
nothing tell us right please because at
that point we've got guys in an ops war
room oh god what's happened trying to
find the problem and then what happens
is they find the problem and they track
the IP that is coming from and they come
to my team thundering literally saying
your pen test is just knocked over the
site but this process could take three
hours of fault-finding but if you just
phone us up and say look oh boy might
have a might give me a bit of a problem
we can fix it really fast and it makes
my case for doing pen testing that much
easier you know things are going to go
wrong and and particularly on internet
facing systems as I said with system
outages arguably being as bad as as data
losses potentially going forward we need
to know what's going to make the site
laggy I'm not going to go through all of
the rest of these I'll just pick out a
couple of really key ones consistency
with titles of findings I would like to
see consistency across the whole of the
pen testing industry I know you do CBE
references and things like that that's
all fine but even just the way that the
things are worded so we can get the same
company testing the same system finding
the same vulnerability about calling it
two fairly different things now on my
team we understand that they're the same
because we're in that we're in the
subject domain when we take them to IT
we then have to explain that these
things they're seeing that look
different are actually the same and that
just takes time which kind of goes
counter to my my concept of reducing
fixed time four critical vulnerabilities
so anything that requires a level of
discussion waste Simon and one thing I
think that sort of I've observed after a
length of time in security is that
sometimes we can be a bit rubbish
explaining what we do to other people we
get too technical we use too much jargon
most people don't care they just want to
fix so I think there's there's got to be
a sort of industry-wide effort to bring
a lot more consistency and make us
easier to engage with
number six I want to just comment on
quickly when we get a pentas report the
executive summary yes interesting but
straight to the table here's the red
ones here's the yellow ones IT fix them
that that's it we don't necessarily read
all of the reams of descriptions of
vulnerabilities because in the main
we're finding the same types of
vulnerabilities many times there has to
be a better way of distributing findings
you know I know some companies the
pendous findings go straight into a
demand queue and sprays a ticket
straight away to get it fixed
not all companies or as sophisticated as
that but there is opportunities and
money to be made Pro pentas incumbents
to come in to the client and help us
build a process end-to-end that deals
with this the last one I think is really
critical no pun intended
need to be really clear about what
constitutes a critical finding we we I
have a guy on my side who upgrades quite
a lot of findings in Penta supports when
he receives them and downgrades a load
of others I'm we're trying to get our
suppliers to come and work with us to
put together a consistent way of rating
findings and I would like to get them in
and brief them on the business and for
us what actually constitutes something
that's really going to hurt us because
it doesn't always or rather there's and
there's not always a direct match from
what's in the pentose report to what we
consider to be a significant risk and
the worry here is not necessarily things
being overrated although that obviously
takes time when we fix stuff that
possibly we don't need to if that's a
reasonably true statement the worst one
is actually when there's findings that
are underrated and as a result are not
necessarily going to get fixed as fast
as we need them to get fixed I guess
what I'm saying here is also try not to
cry wolf too much because I too don't
like that they have enough to do keeping
everything up and running so I have to
be really careful as to what I raise as
a critical finding and how if you like
how loud ice down the klaxon and there
is a real balancing act here in terms of
sort of keeping the business should we
say alert enough to the problems or keep
raising the alarm and get into the trap
of crime wall from them when something
really does happen
one's actually listening so on the
communication point and this is sort of
particularly when talking to senior folk
in the business something that had mrs.
John Kotter again something that
addresses people's anxieties so a
pentose report is a list of anxieties
and it talks in big technical jargon
about how to address those but they're
not necessarily understandable to a lot
of people and what makes if you like
this this sort of lay people people who
are not in security but who are very
clever people and very senior and
businesses anyway what makes them more
anxious than anything is knowing there's
something they should be anxious about
but not understanding it enough to
understand how anxious they should be
that makes them more anxious and leads
to me and my team trying to explain what
this actually means so we we just simply
have to get a lot better I think as an
industry at explaining exactly what we
do findings have also got to be credible
a lot of a lot of sort of you know
business management is there is a lot of
gut involved in it because a lot of it
is making decisions based on risk and
uncertainty which by definition is not a
deterministic process you have to
effectively place your bet and hope that
things go the way that you predicted
they would which is gut and sometimes I
think as you know as we are we're very
technical people I'm a lot less I used
to be but I still have technical
personality traits which means things
that don't fit into nice compartments
compartments scare me but I'm having to
talk to people whose things don't fit in
those compartments and figure out a way
to sort of make that interface work I
was consulting for 20 years I'm sure I
had some really good ideas but things
are just very difficult to implement I'm
not going to say a lot more than what's
on that because I've kind of talked
about it for the last 20 minutes but
this this is really critical I think
there needs to be a lot more support
sometimes in actually getting things
done rather than just raising a list of
things that need to be fixed you know
quite often you can get to a point where
the last thing I need is a little issed
of things to be fixed and if I don't
need another list of things to be fixed
you can show us how about the IT need
even less this is obvious right but I
work in retail that's the biggest threat
I have that is the biggest threat I have
is Christmas okay Black Friday who
invented Black Friday I mean really we
have to run you know with an order of
magnitude more capacity through Black
Friday and Christmas than we do for the
rest of the year I can't you know if any
of you seen spinal taps surely some
people are old enough to have seen
spinal tap with the guitar and don't
look at it don't even breathe on it you
know that's what I tea is like over
Christmas because so here's that here's
how the math works right we have to have
enough capacity to sell as much stuff as
we're going to sell online as we go
through Christmas Christmas from Black
Friday through to sort of the broadly
speaking the back end of the January
sales is our busiest time it is in every
and every retailer Black Friday
incidentally is called Black Friday
because traditionally in the u.s. it was
the day when retail accounts went into
the black okay so it's massive Christmas
is massive the whole of the year is
about preparing for Christmas so we have
to trade through with enough capacity to
get things working to their peak so if
Trump predicts how many people going to
buy stuff and yada yada yada and then
buy just enough capacity to serve that
if we're ten percent spare capacity
that's ten percent wasted money that's
CPU we don't need this memory we don't
need its network bandwidth we don't need
its stuff we don't need so IT do a lot
of work trying to predict exactly how
much capacity we're going to need and
then and this this is a bit that sort of
them immediately was quite new to me
there's a lot of load testing before
they would literally thrash the hell out
of the websites with load tests see
which part of the whole chain falls over
is at the load balancers of the
firewalls is at the front end is it or
whatever right that's that's a 100% CPU
here the rest of its running at 50%
that's unbalanced that's wrong so
literally everything in the whole econ
pipe is thrashing away at night your
percent through Christmas so I can't get
any changes done and when I have let's
say an urgent need for a pen test in
October then I really do have an urgent
need for a pentose and it can't wait
until December
I can't do it then and that means we're
trading through Christmas with with an
uncertainty which is not a good thing
this is Christmas it's great actually in
retail it's genuinely really exciting
because of all the work you have to do
to make all this stuff actually hold
together but I will implore you to kind
of know your client and understand what
their business cycles look like other
sectors in retail Easter DIY sector
that's their biggest piece not Christmas
it's over Easter everyone's got a guy
out and you know mow the lawn and like I
did buy some barbecue cleaner and buy
some steak and ham barbecue um isn't it
obligatory in any in any talk or a
conference like this you gotta have
anonymous you gotta have a county gotta
have mr. robot who thought serious one
was great but serious to lost the plot
I've not I got two episode yes I've got
2 episode 3 on series 2 and thought gave
up if anyone comes and says actually it
gets better after that like Breaking Bad
didn't serious to then let me know and
war games which you know how about a
nice game of chess this is a really good
book actually no you must be aware of
this I'm sure you are
I'm sure it's it's shown every every
every year here but please read this
it's still really good it's it's still
relevant it's all really old eunuch
stuff and rattling keys on bare wires to
to disrupt the attack which is a which
is an interesting thing because if
anyone reads as read Lockheed Martin's
intelligence-led Network defense
disrupting attacks is a good thing and
is a strategic decision
I wouldn't rattle keys on the racks
anymore that would annoy IT but so it's
definitely worth having a read of that
book I think and then you can read his
second book called silicon snake on and
laugh at how wrong his predictions were
but then think all hang on a minute
we're about to fall into the trough of
disillusionment a digital a maybe cliff
was right all along
we're starting to circle in on our
upcoming London dinner this was another
sales email I just really like that
starting to circle in on our upcoming
London
I also learnt the perception this fact
the board are absolutely listening
please consultants don't come and say to
me how I can get your board interested
in cybers they are they they really are
and they are genuinely worried about it
absolutely and the reason they're so
worried as I said it because they don't
know how worried to be I probably
covered a lot of this in my rambling
just now but then we've got to be able
to articulate it properly we have to
have a consistent way of talking to the
board this is this is critical for one
reason
I wouldn't say one simple reason alone
one reason is a lot of boards of large
companies the directors and the non
accept directors you know have
chairmanships and and roles in other
companies so they'll go to company a and
the seaso or whoever will kind of
present what they think the risks are
around cybersecurity in a format that to
them makes sense
and to be fair in a format that that
over time they've you know that they've
discussed with the board the best way to
present it and the way that the board
can consume and then you know the
chairman of the board of that company
will go and take up his non exec
director on the Audit Committee of
another company and have some papers
talking about cybersecurity risks in a
completely different way so he he or she
just simply don't know what they're
supposed to be reading what they're
supposed to be taking away from it one
of the things I sort of talked to people
in my position about is how we get to a
point where we can actually report in a
consistent way if you're an accountant
you have to write the accounts and order
the accounts according to GAAP which is
the generally accepted accounting
principles I think any auditors shouting
if that's wrong we sort of need the
generally accepted principles for
explaining information security risk
it's not really as matías GAAP is it but
um we need something where there is a
standardized way of reporting this and
also accountability so that there is a
sort of equivalent to an audit partner
for example in a big four that signs the
accounts off and says these are a true
and accurate representation of the
what the wording is the state of the
company at the point in time of which I
signed these accounts off there needs to
be an equivalent I think for the way
that we deal with in Passaic I think as
an industry we've done a really really
good job figuring this stuff out as
we've gone along and now is the time
when we've we've if we're going to be
absolutely taken seriously in the
boardroom we have to professionalize
ourselves and we have to be consistent
and we have to hold ourselves to account
in the same way the accounting
profession does and actually the account
profession the legal profession the
architects engineers nurses doctors
pilots anyone in a position of
responsibility in any other industry has
professional credentials that they can
be stripped of if they misrepresent
something it doesn't mean that the FD
gets stripped of his credentials if the
company goes under that's not what it
means what it means is is that if it
goes under and he's misrepresented the
facts he's probably got a problem I
don't think we hold ourselves to account
in anywhere near the same way and I
think we need to we write things like
this and apologists to the companies
here I'm sure these are all pretty good
pieces of research share prices drop an
average of 5% when a data breach is
disclosed share prices fall by an
average of 1.8% on a permanent basis
following a severe breach stocks on
average suffer an immediate decrease in
share price following a breach of 0.43%
in the long time share prices continue
to rise on average but at a much slower
pace now can anyone tell me by how much
the share price drops on average six
months after notifications the
Information Commissioner can't find out
from that so what can I say to the board
well there's some research that says
probably somewhere between 0.4 3 and 5%
over an indeterminate length of time
your shares might drop but actually
they'll continue to rise anyway but at a
slower pace compared to something I
don't know about remember John Kotter
how does this address the board's
anxieties at least credible they might
be in and of themselves but there's a
mess of reports are is that credible as
an industry is that credible the last
thing we'll talk about is this is that
the media and their brief stories
brilliant right it's cyber it's digital
it's exciting it's hackers it's North
Korea's Russia it's brilliant the FT
love it and the BBC love it
but it's a really really febrile
atmosphere and in in the scale of sort
of breaches sometimes a company hasn't
done what they should have done
absolutely the control environment is
not in place sometimes they have done
all of that and they get hacked anywhere
and there's a massive breach and there's
one simple reason why this is is that
the and you know this you know this
better than anybody the adversaries have
a mission objective and they won't stop
until they achieve it so by definition
they are going to get there in the end
and this is something I think that it's
going to take a while to sink in to the
sort of public consciousness and for the
media to kind of understand the nuance
in this but at the moment the atmosphere
is so febrile that sort of miss this
really relates back to my crying wolf
point that it's very very easy to cause
emotion right at the very point when
emotion is the absolute last thing you
need you to think about the airline
industry clearly there's a motion when
the aircraft goes down obviously it's a
tragic event but what happens then is
there is a the air-traffic investigation
board or I can't recall what they're
called they come in as an independent
entity and they figure out what happened
and they don't stop until they get to
the absolute root cause of what happened
in that accident it's not investigated
by the aircraft manufacturer or the
airline rather it's investigated by an
independent entity that has the what's
the word I'm looking for teeth is the
wrong word but has the right powers to
demand things are provided to it and to
work through it and and as much time as
it needs to actually get to the root
cause of the problem and then they have
the powers to order the you know airline
manufacturers or sorry aircraft
manufacturers or Airlines or whoever put
in place the remedial actions and they
actually try and figure out genuinely
what went wrong they don't just sort of
guess at it a bit and say well there's a
few things that I've said 27001 that
were amber and not green and therefore
that must be the problem it's probably
not the problem and I think we've just
got to get a lot more collect
a lot more science around the way that
we deal with breaches and the way that
we sort of allocate if you'd like to
blame and cause this slides broken which
is slightly irritating that's supposed
to be a slide showing the number of data
breaches from 2005 to 2017 just
increasing like this and this is the
sort of thing that this was somewhat an
industry put it on LinkedIn number of
data breaches since 2005 to 2017 has
increased markedly well you know the
slide doesn't work so well cuz it's
broken but I wanted to show comparison
so the picture on the Left should look
very similar and if not identical to the
picture on the right the number of
Internet users has gone up to Z since
2005 and 2017 so simply saying the
number of breaches has gone up since
2005 to 2017 doesn't really tell us
anything
what if you control the size of breaches
or the cost of breaches or whatever for
the number of people on the internet or
the number of devices connected to the
Internet and then have a look and see
what breaches are doing I I don't know
but we need to have some clever people
doing things with data and actually
trying to figure stuff out so I think
there needs to be much better education
into the public and in a way that they
can consume so that they can understand
sort of what digital security is all
about
and this is a big problem I think people
are starting to understand what fake
news is I remember talking to people a
year or so ago about sort of Russian
troll farms and this sort of thing in
that way really and now it's it's in
that it's in the media and people sort
of guess it it's difficult to know how
to conclude this part from Donald Trump
obviously you know this is move on
this was the best sales approach I had
and I will sort of finish here didn't
work but it's the best one hey Paul
how's you Co give a quick call and if so
when what numbers best for you yes
brilliant so I think to sum up what I've
learned over the past couple of years in
many ways is is that sort of the role of
the seaso is to represent security to
the business and represent the business
to security so one thing I've sort of
figured out is that I'm pretty much
always devil's advocate in any room I
sit in if I'm sitting with the business
I'm arguing as to why we need to do more
security and why we need to manage the
risk if I'm sitting with my security
guys I'm sort of arguing why the
business can't just turn off the website
on the 24th of December and that we're
going to have to trade through that was
me thank you questions
[Applause]