then everyone thank you for coming to
see me talk to you about replicator now
mmm this is a burp extension I've
developed to solve an issue that's that
I've hid when I was working as a pen
tester I now work at port surrogate and
as well as helping out Burt users one of
the things I do is look after the map
store and now the story of this
particular extension is um when I was
working as a pen tester I often found
there was difficulty getting developers
to be able to understand some of the
more complex issues so you worked really
hard you'd be three steps into this
multi-stage process you bypassing
JavaScript valid as you bypass some
server-side filter and you get this
really great vulnerability but promise
you you'd write this all up and the
recipient they would struggle to know
what to do with it you get follow-up
questions by email they'd want to have a
conference call to discuss it it was a
challenge and what I found from working
with developers is what they want more
than anything is to be able to reproduce
an issue on their workstation you can
give them a strap test you can give them
a cord of you could tell them the exact
line in the file that has got a book you
could even give them the link to stack
overflow with three different highly
recommended solutions and still what
they want to do is replicate it on their
workstation from maze with some of these
difficult security vulnerabilities these
issues can be hard to replicate now well
I'm always doing an earlier draft of
this talk I made a minor Freudian slip
on that second bullet coin and I wrote
reproduction can be challenging and what
I was trying to get at is there can be
technical things like for instance there
can be all sorts of technical problems
that come okay
but that can occur why are you trying to
do this and a good example would be if
this JavaScript validation on the site
so you go to the forum you put in your
payload in a text field and the
JavaScript on the site kicks it out now
for a pen tester that's easy to get
around but you have to use some kind of
security tool right Bert proxy or one of
the other lesser tools now one of the
ways that my previous employer tried to
deal with this was to keep a full copy
of the request in the report so you
report real Oh we'd have the title have
a description of the vulnerability to
say hey you want to reproduce it here's
the request so the idea is the developer
they'd copy that they'd paste it into
some kind of raw HTTP tool and they'd
say this issue we produce the problem
however is that there are normally
session tokens in that request so what
you're testing you can paste that in and
the issue reproduces now by the time
you've sent this report to your internal
QA let's come to the account manager and
it's been passed to the security manager
who's gone to a project manager and
eventually it'll lands on some
developers desk is going to fix this by
this time the token has expired
so they fire this will request it in
their app and they don't get any
meaningful response so given all these
issues there is a need to do something
better and what we thought is what if we
can make replication as easy as saying
tea Earl Grey hot and I'm going to show
you the solution that we came up with
apologies if you can't read this at the
battle is it that there's a bit of a
trade-off here between the font size and
actually being able to fit everything on
the screen now just put your shoes
yourself in the shoes of this developer
so they've had the Panthers commissioned
they've received the report and it's got
these findings on it now because the pen
test company that did this particular
job is super advanced than they're using
replicated files as well as receiving
the PDF report you also receive a
replicator fire so you fire it your
trusty copy of burp suite and you can in
fact do this in the communtiy Edition
and we load the file that we've received
from the pen test company now we've just
got a little security warning here
because it's gonna update our
configuration but this is cool oh yeah
I very much trust this pen test company
so I'm gonna say yes here now what we've
got we've got a list of all the issues
that have been found in this pen test so
this there's three in this particular
pen set now and the very first thing
that I'm gonna do is I'm gonna see if I
can reproduce the issues that have been
sent and that's all it gives us a single
button to do this this is a slight
moment of truth about whether my demo
labs actually work or not so we're gonna
hit test all and all of them has come
back as vulnerable which at this stage
is exactly what we want
so the pen test company have identified
we're vulnerable and now we can
reproduce that locally now in this
example we have the pen test firm work
on the staging version of the site and
but I'm not actually going to be
deploying fixes there and initially I've
got a private dev copy of the site and
so what we can do
we can redirect the target now when we
say yes to this do we want to change all
the targets and the request macros it's
going to do some magic under the hood
this magic and hood was significantly
more complex than I thought it was going
to be initially but hopefully it's going
to work now
just as another test we're just gonna
check that all these issues still
replicate because there's always the the
concern that you've got a slightly
different configure your dad versus your
staging so the next step just test them
all and thankfully they're all still
horrible okay now we can start working
away at each issue so the first one SQL
injection the pen test report this is
going to have a description of why SQL
injections are problem is what the
business impact is and what strategies
you can use to fix it and they hope that
these reports are going to be lovingly
handwritten and not in fact copy and
pasted from the burp output originally
so having read and understood this I'm
gonna go to my source code and I'm just
I'm just running a local VM here that's
got the vulnerable app on there
now form a thermos file a little bit and
so there's two two lines here they both
decide week one of those vulnerable to
SQL injection and one of them aids
bizarrely in Python the two lines look
so similar it's ridiculous but this one
this secure version that's currently
commented out I'm going to make that
active and I'm going to comment out the
vulnerable version okay so we think
we've done effects the next thing we
want to do is prove that this fix
actually works now we can go back to the
replicator tool here and we can try
testing it again right and it's resolved
which is good now there is a little
caveat in bracket so it says resolved
brackets sensitive now this has been a
necessary inclusion based on some of my
experiences dealing with developers
because of course what we want is for
them to address the root cause of the
issue so if there's SQL injection we
want them to move to having a
parameterised query unfortunately time
and time again I've run into fixes where
they've literally blocked the attack
vector that we've reported so there's
always the worry that some different
attack vector is going to you know mean
the vulnerability is still present now
one thing we can do to help deal with
this you can do an active scan at that
oh that's fine okay there's some really
minor issues there that we don't greatly
care about but the crucial thing is this
SQL injection issue seems to be fixed so
that's great we can move on so the next
one on the list was cross-site scripting
now similarly we can we can look through
the code and we can find in this
function here the developer is following
very poor practice in that they are
taking a variable from a form parameter
and they are dumping it straight in HTML
without any escaping which is the
classic cross-site scripting attack now
if I uncomment this line here it means
we are going to escape less than
characters so I can quit out here I can
rerun labs I can go back to replicator
and I can try testing this issue okay so
it appears to be resolved and that's if
we look at lower down on the screen you
see this bit here where previously there
was a script tag echoed the less than
sign has now been escaped so this isn't
this is no longer gonna fire up
JavaScript now just like before it might
be a very good idea to do an active scan
to see if the issue
genuinely is resolved right now this is
more concerning because something has
popped up on the target tab and this
time it's red it's a high-risk issue and
it appears that we still have cross-site
scripting and in fact if we look at this
more closely we're better looking at the
response to see this what the active
scanner has done there is its founder
sir native payload that's got through
our very simple escaping
so the escaping was only removing a less
than sign in this example the injection
was into a value tag so it's possible to
have a across that scripts before
without using the less than character I
don't know if you've used this
particular trick before this is one of
my favorites for going into an input tag
and that you can use the on focus
handler to put some JavaScript when the
when that object gets focus and you can
also give it the auto focus now so as
soon as the page loads up you don't need
any user interaction your JavaScript
payload is going to execute and soon
from there you can continue working
through these things to fix all the
issues and then that would be a very
good point to send your application back
to the professional pen test company and
have them do a retest and hopefully
you're gonna get the best benefit out of
your retest because I I can think of a
number of times when I've been asked to
work do a retest for a client and when
it comes look at it nothing has changed
in the behavior of the area that was
vulnerable and even if this can't prove
things are fix it at least should stop
that
okay so the the key points that made
this good for a developer everything was
embedded into a single file so it can be
passed from the pan tester to the
developer it can be passed around
between development teams it'd be chosen
as share points replication can be done
in one click so this is this is quite in
line with agile and test-driven
development it's the sort of behavior
that you want it's adaptable to the
environment so the fact that the Pens
have worked on bla bla bla
staging comm doesn't prevent the
developer then working on dad calm or or
whatever whatever other environment but
the big thing to remember is that this
is not a silver bullet in itself and
that a manual retest is the way to prove
that the issue is properly resolved ok
so that was the flow for developers um
but I think a lot of people in the
audience here at Penn testers and you'll
be asking what Hamilton we make this
replicated fan we need some kind of like
workshop to help us craft this and I'm
going to show you exactly how we go
about doing that now ok so first thing
I'm going to do is just to clear out
what's in replicates and now you may not
know this if you hold down control when
you click this tick and extend the tab
it does a quick reload I only learned
that quite recently I wish I've known
that ages ago and and what we can do is
we can put replicate into tests of you
so it's going to we get a few more
buttons and options now now
so I've been asked to do a pan test of
this my demo staging comm and in fact it
turns out we've been given a a test
account to use as well now I'm going to
focus on the kind of burp heavy workflow
of doing the pan test and we're not
interested in my demo dev at this point
just that's my demo staging and and I'm
just gonna okay so I can start by
spidering the house just to find all the
all the different pages within the site
and we can do an active scan
okay now some of these I'm just I'm just
gonna delete because either they're
low-risk issues or because of the
environment we're in we don't actually
care that the password is is playing so
we found this issue cross-site scripting
reflective so this is something that we
want to communicate to the developer and
we can right-click it and we get a
context menu option here which notes to
send it to the replicator now we've been
replicated because this was found by
active scanner is able to automatically
pick up most of the details so we've got
a title for the issue we've also got the
path and parameter which are normally
key bits of information that developers
want to see and here on the left there's
a probe request so this is a request
that will trigger the vulnerability and
the other thing we've got is detection
logic in this example the intersection
logic is a graph expression so with this
regular expression matches the response
we're going to treat it as vulnerable
there is also a collaborator detection
master that you might want to play with
if you if you look at this later on so
if we can try this now and if we test it
it shows that the the website is
vulnerable
I've just realized that I'm that I need
to undo to demonstrate sort of it I need
to undo the face okay now you this scam
didn't find the SQL injection
vulnerability now I don't like to rely
fully on automated testing so let's do a
bit of manual testing as well now the
the go-to starting point for any manual
testing is a single quote so if I've got
a single quote this field instantly I
get an SQL error message so this is
ringing all sorts of alarm bells about
this has got a floor and I'm thinking
why has an active scanner found this now
one of the first things I can do to
investigate this is to dig the request
out of proxy history you can see in the
history we can see we've submitted the
single quote if we just hover for a
second we get handy inline URL decode
and we can see the response with the
suspicious-looking string now if we send
this to repeater what we would expect is
that we can send this off again same
payload and we would expect to get these
same result but we don't
this is forbidden this is a bit strange
so if I go back to here I will refresh
the page if I put in my payload I put in
my payload again and get an error
message so what is going on and we can
dig a couple of these requests out of
the proxy history and send these to the
comparer so this is going to show us the
exact differences and what we can see is
that this token has changed between
requests we've got this dynamic anti
cross-site request forgery token so what
happens is we refresh the page and we
get a valid token we submit one payload
and that gets through to the app and
triggers the error but by that point
that token is burning it's been used and
we can only use it for any further probe
now it turns out that Bert's got a
useful feature to help us deal with this
and what we can do I just remove these
because these are these were set up so
the first thing we can do is define a
macro so we have this request which
would get the search form and the
response contains this token so if I
create a macro like this I can call it
fetch CSRF token now the next thing I
want to do is I want to configure this
post request so that every time the post
request runs it's going to fetch a fresh
token now the first thing I need to do
is capture the URL of that request and
then I can create a session handling
rule and I'm gonna I'm gonna call this
update CSRF token in the rule action I
want to run a macro I'll select that
macro that I've just defined and
crucially I'm going to leave this option
here enabled which says update the
current request with parameters from the
macro response now we also want to
define a scope so I'm going to paste the
URL they I just copied and because we're
going to use this with replicated down
the line I'm going to enable the
extender scope okay so now if we go back
to repeater what's gonna happen when
press goes under the hood it's going to
issue the macro is going to fetch that
fresh fetch that fresh token it's going
to update the request we can see here
and then we are going to get a different
response and you can see you can see
each time we do it tokens updating but
it's not just good for repeater this we
can now send this back to active scanner
we just give this a minute oh yeah try
that one more time right and we've now
found the SQL injection floor now this
time if we send this to work replicator
now just as before it picks up the
vulnerability description it picks up
the path the parameter it gives us a
probe request it gives us detection
logic but crucially as well it's
identified this session rule which
applies to that request so now when we
save this replicated file embedded in
that file is that such a rule and that
macro and then when the developer
receives this when they load it they get
that configuration preloaded into burp
which which helps them with this sort of
you know just clicking go experience now
you cannot rely on active scanner to
find everything so something else that I
tend to do during a test is to use the
content discovery function now I know
loads of people use deer Buster and
Durbin things not everyone seems to know
that there is a similar functionality
built right into Burke which lets you
leverage a whole load of other stuff
like their set and handling rules so we
can kick that off for inning and
actually already after a little while
we've already found something new on the
sitemap this admin page oh I wasn't
expecting there we send this
[Music]
it's need to turn on the cookie jar for
a pizza there we go
so if we request this admin page even
though we were just logged on as the
test use them with no special privileges
we have gotten authorize access to the
admin panel now again we can send this
to replicator and but because this isn't
an active scanner generated issue we
have to do a bit more work so for
instance we need to write in the issue
description ourselves so now we've got
the probe request but we also need to
manually define the taxon logic now
seems to me a pretty fair thing to
search on would be the admin panel so if
I I select that string I can then
instruct it to use that selection and
now any term that probe requests gives
you the admin panel it will trigger a
vulnerability and we can test that now
now all these requests have got session
IDs in them remember I said earlier one
of the problems is while you're testing
that session ID is valid but down the
line the session ID may no longer be
valid now we've got some tools here
which can help us and deal with this so
the first thing I'm going to do is I'm
going to scrub cookies from all these
requests so now I've removed the session
ID so there's no chance that we're
corrupting ourselves with sort of having
a session ID that won't be valid in the
future now that alone won't solve
everything because it burps internal
cookie jar will affect things so I need
to also empty that cookie jar so now
we've simulated the situation that all
our cookies have expired and those
vulnerabilities are unable to replicate
now what we need to do to fix this
is define the login macro so I can go
back here if I look down history this is
the original post request where we
logged in is use men's hat so define
this macro and call it log in and as
test now back in replicator we can
select a loggia macro we now try it they
all replicate as vulnerable and now we
can have a lot of confidence that if we
send this off to a developer that they
will be able to replicate them just the
same and there's one other feature
that's come in handy in some some
situations and so you might have some
particular bird config setup that you
need to access it could be an thailand
platform or authentication it could be
hostname resolution it could be all
sorts of things now we've got the
capability here to import some config
from the currently running burp instance
so I'm actually going to from the
project options within connections I'm
going to import the hostname resolution
and it so this Maps the my demo stage
intern IP address so if the developer
tried to run this and they didn't have
this confit it wouldn't work so we can
save that so now everything it all get
packaged up and we can say that as a
file now obviously there is a fair
amount of confidential stuff in this
file and but you've already got some
secure communication mechanism to get
your report from your company see your
client so you can just leverage that
exact same communication mechanism to
send the replicates file as well and
then they've got the ability to
reproduce all the issues
so that that's the that's the workflow
for a tester the key points I thought
first of all is that there is a list of
all the vulnerabilities that every
vulnerability has got a probe it's got a
crafted request which you can prove used
to prove presence or absence of of the
vulnerability and it's got detection
logic so it can look at the response and
it can say okay this is vulnerable or
this has been resolved and then to
support that it's got a login macro it's
got all the session handling rules and
it's got the relevant sections of your
bit configuration now is it so so you
can serve up a wonderful post battle
banquet now sometimes even with the best
starship technology things can go wrong
and one of the scenarios that we
envisaged happening was that you would
you have a developer one and they say it
just doesn't replicate on my machine and
you've got the pen tester and then say
well it works for me you think how how
would we resolve this impasse so we've
included a trace feature so if you're
having difficulty replicating an issue
you can turn on the trace feature so now
once this is turned on every HTTP
request which goes through Birds Network
stack and the response that comes back
gets recorded in an in-memory log so you
can then repeat all the tests and then
when you're done you can stop tracing
and you can save everything to a trace
file and you can then send that back so
the person who gave you the replicator
file and hopefully between you you can
debug it it will still take some degree
of skills to debug that
yeah
so that was all about the extension um I
just wanted to add to this about some
things I learned about developing
extensions because this this is the
first like major extension I've written
that's ended up being in the bat store
I've written one-shot extensions before
that were to deal with particular
technologies but they never they'd never
been released publicly they were always
kind of written to a standards like well
it works for me now but if it breaks
stuff so things I've learned that work
really well and you really do want to
use an IDE to do development and um I've
certainly found that IntelliJ is very
pleasant to use so compared to Eclipse
and NetBeans it just does a bit more
code suggestion immediate static
analysis or smade refactoring and just
all those little bits they actually add
ups making it look there's a lot more
flow as you're developing Gradle works
really well as a build system and and
just like maven it lets you reference
external artifacts from your build files
and this is actually a really handy way
to integrate the burp API quite a lot of
the extensions have exported all the
interface files and kept them in their
source code and this this works fine
there's no problem with it just put as
your source code up and that's a
referencing the artifacts is a really
clean way to do it and if you're
building forms while there isn't
IntelliJ form builder we found that the
NetBeans form builder is is preferable
and actually they work together fine
it's absolutely no problem to be adding
a form in NetBeans editing the code and
in salad if you change one they ought to
reload and it's is it's actually really
hard to mess things up
and now something I'd not done much of
at all when I was kind of like a pen
tester who did a bit of coding was using
a debugger now if you've got your
captain breathing down your neck and you
to get your Wharton those cells going at
what dr9 fast a debugger can greatly
help you with that if you used to
debugging by putting print statements in
your code and a debugger can really make
things a lot easier for you and I'm
going to show you how you can use
IntelliJ to debug a burpee extension
this isn't specific to IntelliJ but it
is well I'll show you how to do at this
Java has this facility to do remote
debugging so if we go into our debug
configuration we can create a remote
debug session now IntelliJ here it gives
us the command line we need to use to
start Java so when you start you ever
with that command line it will open up a
listening port and it will allow a
remote debugger to connect to the
process so if I quit out of this
instance a bit now I can run Java from
the command line I can paste in those
command line flags for debugging and I
can start bits wait so I'm just going to
like let it start up a little bit it
slows down a little bit when the debug
is running but not not tons and when it
started up a bit I can go back here and
attach the debugger
it's a running process now if you're not
used to debug your before one of the
main entry points is a break point so we
can satellite in the code and in fact
here I'm going to just set a line which
is run when you press the scrub cookies
button so
okay so we've got this breakpoint set so
when I click scrub cookies it's going to
bounce us back into IntelliJ so it's
frozen the application and at this point
we can analyze all the currently running
data structures so down the side there
we've got the stack trace I've got all
the local variables on this side now if
he did do debugging by printing what I
found happened all the time is he print
something out when you saw the value of
that wow I wish had printed out this as
well but the DES Buca really helps you
there because you can just explore all
the objects in your current context and
you can just expand as deep as you want
and there's also capabilities to run
like inline javis going to up your game
and become more of a more like a
professional developer I would say that
Linux user debugger is really up there
with good things to do now something
else a few people asked me about is
highlighting tabs now you know you know
we need to send a repeater
you know how the repeater tab flashes up
for a little bit people have asked well
hey I've got an extension I want to do
the same but there isn't an API to do it
well replicator can do this because
although there isn't a burp API you can
still access all the Swing components
now I'm going to let you into a secret
since Bert won seven to eight that is
the exact color you want if you want
your highlights being exact color match
the internal tools that's the color and
if you want if you want to get the five
details right 3,000 milliseconds is how
long they highlight for now it turns out
actually making them highlight is is a
mild pain in the ass because what you
have to do you've got your tap and you
have to walk up the swing hierarchy so
you find like the container of all the
tab then you
the one with your caption the problem is
when your components created it is an
orphan it doesn't have a parent so what
you have to do is register a hierarchy
change listener which is then triggered
once your component gets connected to
the swing tree you can then walk up the
hierarchy find the correct tab highlight
it and when when activated you can set
at the timer now you may not want to do
all this hard work so I have created a
gist to do this in fact if you're into
doing extensions there's quite a few
gist's on the github there and sometimes
when people ask for things if I'm
feeling in a good mood I'll write them
adjust to do it and and there's now a
reasonable collection of them now
another little pet peeve that I see
extensions getting wrong is whenever any
sense and creates a pop-up dialog it
should be given a parent now swing will
let you provide null as a parent now I
have this idea that all the extensions
that do this the developers only have
one monitor because we've all got dual
monitors at ports wicket and when you've
got dirt running on your right-hand
monitor it really grinds when an
extension pops something up on the other
monitor now the way around this is to
give all these pop-ups the parent the
parent should be the burp frame now
again there's one there isn't a burp API
to practice you can use the standard
swing api's to find a bit frame and
again there is a gist to do that for you
now this problem may be familiar to a
lot of you because there are so many
wonderful burp extensions that you want
to add them all and that navigating your
tabs becomes like a skill a skill all
all of its own and now what a few
extensions are starting to do people
have realized is this
this area of the street this is getting
pretty closer but there's still a good
bit of space up here now well again
there's no official API to access the
menu bar you can still directly use the
swing API and some extensions notably
active scan plus plus and backslash
powered scanner which recently gained
graphical configuration screens but you
access them from menus rather than from
tabs to reduce the clutter issue and
another thing a few people have wondered
is how an extension like replicator is
able to access the session handling
rules and macros and other parts of the
config now that's down to these two
calls that are on the I burp extended
callbacks interface so save config as
Jason Takes and the running Bert project
configuration serializes as Jason and
returns it as a string it's your
extension so you can read any aspects of
the configuration and then load config
from Jason works the other way around so
you give it JSON as a string and it
takes that and it updates the running
configuration and it can be a little bit
icky to do it because because actually
they there was a lot of configuration
options so this is there's quite a lot
of like nested data but very powerful
the one limitation note is there is no
change listener so if you remember
earlier where we needed to create that
login macro to make our replicator file
reproducible now when we switch back to
the replicator tab the drop down had the
name of the macro there immediately well
the only way the extension manages to do
that is every time the tab activate see
we does save configures Jason just on
the off-chance you changed something now
there was one final thing which was
quite subtle and you might not have
noticed but
I'm just going to turn off this break
point well no yeah while I do this now
um when we click text the token update
says f3b
click it again c19 now I thought it was
it was a really helpful feature of the
you worry that that screen updates based
on all the session handling rules
because it gives you confidence that you
has session handling rules are working
however again there isn't there isn't a
direct API to do this but you can cobble
together some other pieces of the API to
get the effect so if you register an eye
HTTP listener you get a callback you get
process HTTP message and that gets the
message just as it's ready to be sent on
to the destination web service so a a
tool with Imbert says he wants to send a
request then any session handling rules
platform authentication a and other
things get the opportunity to modify the
request before it goes on just as it's
ready to go process HTTP message gets
the final request so we've got the
original request which is in the text
box in the URI we've got this final
request it's going to the web server the
last piece of the puzzle is how do we
connect the two messages there isn't
unfortunately on process HTTP message
you do not get like a request ID this is
an often requested feature but currently
it's not there so instead what the
extension does is just before you send
it it adds a header
it's like X replicator ID and it puts in
a random value and then within the
process HTTP message if it sees this
header it first of all it strips that
out so it doesn't go to the target web
server but it uses that to update the UI
and this
gives you the effect where you can see
immediately the effect that all your
session handling rules are having so
there you go
few tricks you've got all the tools now
to run your sdlc at warp speed you may
have some questions about this
which are welcome and I'd just like to
leave you with these final thoughts
[Applause]
Jordan yeah
Evan the past few months so at first
I first had the idea in the final months
when I was working at pence s and I
thought are they thought this will be
great you know I'll have the opportunity
to do this like in a in an even more
conducive environment and in in in the
first couple of weeks so I said that hey
let's Ruth this would be a really cool
feature and um it's quite often happens
when we discuss these things that stuff
will come back and say well this would
be good if it can do this and this and
this you would have to do this to be
good and so I thought about this and I
realized it didn't need to be a core
feature and it could be done as an
extension and then yeah it's sort of as
a backbone of projects it came together
any questions would be good yeah right
so yeah so this current version doesn't
support unattended running so you
couldn't you couldn't put this like in a
Jenkins pipeline a few people have
requested that um although personally I
think for doing my odd job security
you're better using scanners I know
there's some merit in checking that
you've not broken the same things you've
broken before but I think there's a lot
more merit in in using scanners and
setting up I mean whether you want to
use Bert with the carbonator plugin or
you know or whatever tooling but having
having ongoing scanning as part of your
pipeline
oh so it's soweth so if this could be
integrated in the pipeline this would
automatically give you the take the
failing test that you need as the so
that so you were doing like full TBD
there all right well that's that's a
that's a good suggestion thank you would
that do the trick for you then right
hello
sure um I mean would it just be enough
if if you could do it like on the
command line and you just got some like
XML output on the command line would
that be enough to script it yeah I don't
know do you do you segregate your
pipelines do you have like you sort of a
fast in a long pipeline us and thin
yeah I mean I've always thought one of
the issues with doing agile security is
as scanner does want to run quite a lot
of payloads against your arm and
especially as you sometimes worried
about kind of spooky action at a
distance you know that you might want to
do a security scan of the entire product
just in case a change here had a
far-reaching change yeah sure yeah
unfortunately this thing will always
would always require burp to start it
because it's using all the logic in the
session handling rules I mean there is
some I don't know if you've used the
there's a feature to copy as a kill
command so if you've got something that
it's relatively simple to replicate that
you know that doesn't require a login
session so if you could copy that as a
kill command that would be a one-liner
for you okay that's all the time for
question I think it's lunchtime now so
enjoy can we find me later on if you're
on a memo
[Applause]