country
on on the quality of public institutions
especially in the spa in this part of
europe i'm talking about the new member
states
we are lagging with the quality of
public institutions
i'm not ready to talk about the
distinguished old europe but that's
always the problem the pierre maybe can
mention his experience
and the second one is my second caveat
is that while politically
really politically extremely unpopular
uh physical capacity
as uh as something which is uh
indispensable for for euro european uh
for years on the area
to
to function better
making it
larger and permanent permanent
i would say
this is not a magic
formula or penis here
and and just lasting why because i think
that
just to solve fiscal and structural
weaknesses and failures
by adding new and new that somewhere
else
this is not visible no this is not real
absolutely well you mentioned that the
kind of new reality that we're living in
and i wanted to hand that over
to governor westlake
and to get a feel really for the kind of
playbook that you've had to
basically write while you were acting it
out what have been your main sort of
learnings that you've taken away from
the events of the past year and a half
now
having in mind that what we faced uh 18
months ago was really a unique uh unique
situation unique crisis uh most probably
or hopefully uh once in a lifetime so
what was
most
impressive for me uh was how quick it
was possible to find an intellectual
consensus on how to react to this crisis
so to have this disagreement this
consensus that we need a breach over the
the troubling months and uh then the
response of of both policies
of course maybe not so much on on our
side on monetary policy but what was
really a new element in whole story is
how the fiscal policy reacted it reacted
fast but
also
in a way that we were
trying to to to construct construct
during the previous year so the unique
response of the fiscal policy was really
a novelty in this crisis and i think
this will be something which will stay
with us for the next year as well
very much so
you're all here representing eurozone
central banks and obviously the
peculiarity of that is that we have a
single monetary policy across 19
jurisdictions and this
obviously stands in contrast to the fed
in the us the bank of england and so on
um governor bunch would you say that you
know fault lines potentially have opened
um given that reality and do you think
it may be time that we had some sort of
reforms in that respect
maybe i would like to you know take a
step back and and come back to a bit
what what's the conceptual framework or
what it was and what it is now the
conceptual framework was after the the
the old sharks and the inflation period
in the in 70s and 80s was
monetary policy is going to do the heavy
lifting in terms of
controlling the cycle
and fiscal policy is going to be
relatively passive
automatic stabilizers are going to play
their role but it's stopped there
and then this idea was but what do we do
uh well the problem was what do we do if
we are constrained by the lower bound
and then was this idea that
instead of being substituted
fiscal and monetary become complementary
and that when we are faced with a big
shock you need a fiscal and monetary
response together because monetary
policy being constrained cannot do place
there its role basically
what i would like to point out is there
was a big consensus on that and we did
it but beyond that we we were successful
despite the fact that we were at the
lower bound and i think this is for me
the biggest takeaway it's not that we
did it i'm i'm not so much surprised you
know when you have people dying in italy
uh and everybody is being told you can
spend money and you need to do something
we we do it
um politically it was an easy crisis but
despite being at the lower bound
monetary policy could play a very
important role and i think the the key
uh metrics there is that we could push
interest rates below g so r was smaller
than g which allowed for a fiscal
response
uh without having sort of a bad debt
dynamic and so i believe that you know
this reference of being close to our
star is not enough the big question is
whether you have some room between
between r and g and we were able to push
uh r much below g i mean potential g of
course not g during the crisis
um
so that's i think quite consensual i
guess going forward the question is
whether this complementarity close to
the lower bound should lead to some kind
of formal
coordination between fiscal and monetary
my take on that would be to be short no
i don't think we need that i think if
the shock is big
we've shown we can do it
and you know try to
set rules about how this coordination
should take place is leading us to have
a discussion
that is dangerous for independence of
central banks but that probably also
will find a solution for one type of
crisis but not for another one
and the case in point is what what if
inflation is low but you are back to you
you know a positive output gap
a lot of monetary
policy people dream that there will be
fiscal support to go back to two percent
honestly i think if we are you know with
a closed output gap or even a positive
output gap just doing fiscal just to get
to two percent given the uncertainty
about whether we get there is is a
dangerous way and looking a little bit
to japan i don't want to go the japanese
way but i mean
i think i'd like to pass the same
question to government governor kashmir
just because you mentioned your former
job and um i recall four years ago when
you were here as finance minister you
called then for more reforms
greater integration so what's your
stance today and um you know what are
the risks that we're facing
do you see that where we are now you
know so of course for that just i'm i'm
very pleased with
with the
courage of of head of states to to agree
on on
a new generation eu and of course this
recovery resilience facility is a major
part of that
that's it's it's truly uh for me who is
a was a veteran in that time
um and was observing and also observing
the this resistance uh against that even
the just that was a taboo
word you know if you remember this
process about the instrumentary that
that's budgetary instrument you know
because
in certain countries i'm not going to
mention them uh the physical capacity is
is a double word so now we have
as a central capacity is is not the way
that was not the way just two years ago
now we just decided to do it in that way
that we have this new seed of capacity
but this is really this is not
not
the whole story of it anymore i think
it's uh and we'll come to that this is a
fiscal rules this is enforcement of of
the of these rules and uh
and why because uh we are
just we are dealing with a lack of trust
in the europe because once we have the
the problem with for example monetary
physical interaction we would like to
also have a such
agile
uh and
and um
prosperous uh uh partner on the fiscal
side if like fed has in in in us but it
is a different concept because
in my view we have fundamental uh gaps
uh in in our architecture i'm we're
talking about the
physical uh interaction which is on the
european level it's very very
complicated issue and once
what we do need it's it's a real new
fiscal framework together with
fair enforcement of less
complicated rules at the european level
and proper true
fiscal uh central capacity as a dreamed
of endgame in the in the future yeah
just and all these would allow us to
consider concentrate more on our job and
maybe
uh worry less about
about
how others
might try to play the game
absolutely i think that's an interesting
point about having everyone stay in
their lanes and with that i'd like to go
over again to governor vazque because
we've talked quite a lot about the
positives right of monetary fiscal
interactions but one of the negatives do
we risk a potential loss of central bank
independence or an abdication of
monetary dominance um
how do we ensure that these interactions
as they are remain consistent with your
goals as central banks rather than the
goals of the fiscal authority
again i can start with the very same
thought as before so it was a unique
situation and yes
because of this uniqueness we were both
on the same side of the equation so both
policies were prepared and urged to to
act swiftly and boldly and and very fast
of course the situation will change when
the the the cycle will change when we
will be on the other side of the
equation where our action will be
needed to to go into the opposite
direction so i i think that then the
understanding and the coordination of
policies will become much more much more
difficult and of course one more thing
now at the the main stage there is uh
there are always these two policies
monetary policy fiscal policy but when
we return to more normal period then the
structural reforms will again become
very important and here i i also see a
potential for for further tensions
between central bankers and and
governments and fiscal policies
absolutely what we talk about when the
situation becomes more normal and i
think a question that many of us ask
ourselves is how long must monetary
policy remain accommodative so crystal
ball time
what's what's your take and sort of
what's the right action to take
well it's going to be data driven i mean
um
i think inflation is going to be higher
than uh in our last forecast i mean
there are a number of indications just
numbers that came in
in between that that go that way
but
the argument that part of it is
temporary uh in nature is correct
now sometimes i have the impression that
we focus too much on that and that it
would be you know we argue it's only
temporary well i think we should convey
the message that hopefully our policy is
going to work
and uh bring inflation at some point
back to two percent i think it's going
to take place faster than we thought six
months ago
but i'm in favor of being patient uh i'm
not in favor of doubling the bets each
time if it doesn't work but i'm i'm in
favor of being patient
um but the exit is going to be bumpy uh
this was the easy part of the crisis in
terms of policy i mean getting to a
consensus is not always easy but again
the context does matter when you have
previous crisis some countries cheating
on their uh
numbers and and really big structural
issues is a very different context from
seeing people dying in a hospital in
italy
so i'm not sure uh you should you know
draw two strong conclusions from the way
we dealt with this crisis
some others will be more difficult
politically but now the name of the game
is exit
half fast but at some point it's going
to be accessed on on on fiscal front
monetary front
prudential front and exit is going to be
difficult because it's going to be about
less instead of more
and so there i fully agree with what
boston is saying uh it's politically is
going to be much more difficult
uh so the question about
when to miss may be less important
because it's going to be driven
then the question whether
the shift
that will be required from governments
to realize you know uh end of the part
end of party time
uh now it's going to be going back to
tough choices
and there i'm not
that comfortable i mean i hear a lot of
politicians in my country in other
countries saying
rates are so low we shouldn't do
anything
all that
come with numbers like my deficit is so
much like that
after not taking this and that and that
and that and that into account
because that's the new uh
name of the game is that uh
you know we changed the
instrument to measure the deficits
instead of uh so
all that points to the fact that it's
it's it's not going to be that easy
i fully agree with fitpeer on that you
know at the moment uh
we are the finance ministers the best
friends you know but definitely this is
not going to last forever
and uh that's a new reality which will
come
hopefully back to normality you know
it's probably new normality with certain
kind of flexibility which is needed in
transitory
uh period
uh but definitely it will come and and
specifically okay the domestic issue as
a country which is surrounded with the
country with the countries without the
euro you know we are the specific uh
pressure once the inflation is here
there are the heights after the
this height will will come next year
with the with the the energy prices
which are regulated
uh but
of course the
the central bankers
in surrounding countries i must be very
uh distinguished and diplomatic
they little bit maybe hurry up with uh
with rates you know but they they have
their own
reasons to do it uh but what we have to
do now to to do it in the right time and
and to be patient and like others say
don't panic and in the moment
don't panic
indeed um governor wesley do you have
anything else to add there or are you
also in full agreement
i genuinely agree with uh
with what was just said so
fantastic i think um you know speaking
as we are we're sort of a couple of
weeks away from cop26 so i think we'd be
remiss
not to mention climate change or the
environment at least a little bit
um i wanted to discuss sort of those
dynamic links right between the
financial system environmental
sustainability i mean effectively like
the pandemic climate change is or has
the potential to be an exogenous shock
and we've seen on the eu level
various measures for example the
recovery and resilience facility which
provides that kind of scope for
environmental taxes
i wanted to get a feel from you on your
take on this and what role monetary
policy operations should play in
supporting this if any
pierre i'll start with you
yeah
yeah i'm a little bit skeptical on that
one i'm going to explain but first i
don't like uh the climate issue to be
associated with the idea of a shock okay
which is like suddenly something is
going to happen and we we have not
planned for it it's going to take 30
years
and sometimes i've got the feeling like
suddenly we want to do it all in one day
or we want to
know make sure that the banks know
everything that's going to take place
within 20 years it's it's we you know
it's going to take time for us to
integrate what and and in a way if you
look at energy prices today it might
well be the case that the
the hike in gas prices for instance
represent already three-quarter
of
what's moving to green gas implies over
a 30-year period actually i would like
to go to know exactly what the number is
but in bill gates book he says green gas
is three times more expensive than brown
gas well gas price is just what double
tripled so maybe we are already close to
a shock
but but this is on energy markets that
that for climate will be spread over 30
years now we have a lot of work to do
instead in terms of understanding the
interaction between monetary policy the
economy and the green uh stuff uh we
have to invest a lot i fully agree in
terms of transparency capturing the
risks
where i'm not comfortable is when some
people say that monetary policy should
play a role in terms of allocative
efficiency
you know on relative prices this is not
in any textbook and my concern is
twofold
if you start with that then it it it
opens an extremely broad avenue why not
uh you know try to stimulate innovation
uh diversity whatever
and and then we have a
very broad mandate
and we are independent central bankers
and what i'm a bit concerned is that i
hear a lot of people saying
the governments are not going to do it
so talking about a policy failure
so you should do it
right well you know we live in a
democracy if governments don't do it
first i would not be that uh negative i
think what the commission is coming with
in terms of the green package is
actually i think a very good package
i i think the broadening and extension
of ets is is the name of the game if we
can get that it's 80 of the story
and and i only see a relatively marginal
role for monetary policy as such
but we need to much better understand
indeed what is going to be an impact of
green on inflation on any coming growth
on you know that we need to understand
and of course risks but
on risk it's not enough to say oh there
are market inefficiencies so do
something we need the metrics if there
are inefficiencies if there are biases
we need to measure them
if we can measure them then we need to
act upon it but on the basis of
something which is more than just oh
i've read a paper
right basically i think
all we have to admit that there are also
other policies i mean fiscal or
regulatory
and
which are they are much better in them
much better position to deal with
climate change
goals
especially on on day-to-day uh
basis
uh and here i fully agree that um that
we should refrain from randomly
experimenting
with our monetary policy toolkit uh
and and and and the same i think counts
for for communication on on that but
it's what's uh what's
what's quite clear that we are obliged
to deal with the climate change in line
with the mandates so there is a
evidence you know there is a clear
impact on on inflation relative prices
and it's true that that it will be
costly you know for companies
to be environmentally responsible or to
be environmentally friendly
it means that they will be forced to
price in
the part of this additional cause to
customers
and of course they will have to also to
change their business models to the new
reality
so that's that's must be on our radar uh
how to to so which channels uh this
these pressures will will come to uh
will affect
inflation but not only inflation level
but also the seasonality uh volatility
and and that's that's our part of job
to do it
okay yeah i would also like to stay
realistic in this very broad debate
which is going on about the
environmental changes and the impact on
our policies and our response as well
first of all as
pierre mentioned at the beginning it's
not a shock we are aware of these
developments for a long time now more
and more evidence is coming and it will
be a long term process so there is
literally enough time for us to respond
and so that's why i would like to be
very cautious on our side it's
it's definitely there are there are many
policies which which are much better
entitled to to react to these changes of
course this does not mean that we are
not one of them but one has to be
realistic what our main date is and what
our powers to react actually are so i
think it's quite appropriate that we are
well aware of this problem that we
discuss a lot about it uh during our
stretch strategy review process and we
defined the the next steps but
let's let's be let's stay realistic we
are at a very
early stage of of the process in terms
of reaction from from up from our side
from monetary policy side okay what
shape could responses take
no maybe because i don't want to be you
know completely uh close to the
discussion i think one difficult one
which is uh to some extent related to
the carbon adjustment tax
is what do you do about financing of
emissions outside of the union because
again
if the
the most important instrument it's not
going to be only one instrument but it's
ets in europe and and the extension of
ets
i don't see why we should discriminate
between two companies that are compliant
with an efficient first best solution
uh unless you believe that the price is
too low but then it would be for the
central bank to say
there is a policy failure and i'm going
to say clearly that the price is too low
and act upon it which is institutionally
a big issue
so i think i have to make the assumption
as a central banker that politicians
have taken a commitment and that on the
basis of that a company that is
compliant with the eu regulation
i should not discriminate against or for
it but what if the same company would
make investments in other jurisdictions
that
clearly are not compliant with
net zero in 2050 i would be open to the
discussion and say for that part of the
emission we are going to tilt our
portfolio
we are not going to buy for the part for
the volumes or for the part of your
activities of financing and then the
question is whether you want to
discriminate financing for
activities in europe or outside europe
but indeed i have some sympathy for
people say it's not your role to help a
company finance the uh investment in
coal power plants in countries where
it's still possible without any form of
regulation
so and and there i make the parallel
with the carbon adjustment tax it's
again it's a worldwide issue
and as was previously said we also need
to think about not only what's taking
place in europe but how we relate to
activities outside of europe and i would
be willing to have that debate as much
as i'm
you know not comfortable discriminating
with companies that comply with the
european rules
in a jurisdiction where we have taken a
commitment and i have to assume we are
going to take the measures to get there
you know if you if you get cheap
financing uh in europe to to do dirty
stuff outside of europe yes indeed
that's a problem
i can hear a few either sounds of
agreement or disagreement from the
audience so i'm going to open this out
for questions from the audience if i may
um
yes
thank you
mata storage brd poland
and also the european physical board
one argument
um for fiscal policy coordination that
you that you mentioned um and common
physical capacity which is the maybe
ultimate form of fiscal policy
coordination
is
is effective lower bound i mean an
argument from from your point of view
uh and the lack of monetary capacity uh
that that the central european central
bank was faced so we heard please from
from the governors please spend a bit
more
because we we just won't help you
anymore because the rates are at zero
and is regaining this policy space on
your side
have you heard that something oh yeah
from from
christine
i was translating a bit to more lively
languages
but
is trans i mean is regaining policy
space uh uh in in monash sphere an
argument a variable uh that you take or
you would take into account when
deciding on the timing of of rate hikes
for example is this because we hear a
lot about
uh building
uh fiscal policy space for the next
crisis but is building monetary policy
space for the next crisis a is something
that you you you think about and you'll
take into account thank you and just one
little question on digital currency
let's answer this question because we
have very little time and a lot of
questions so we'll just take that first
question
i can see governor kashmir sort of
nodding a little would you like to
address the question no matter she's my
former
colleague
from the council so so that just was my
my my question if we we have heard about
that appeal of governor is pleased to do
it
so it's uh
definitely we cannot be only game in the
town so and
it's okay
just to be very honest
in the beginning of pandemic we were you
know i think we were quite active
and effective to do
some substantial steps in favor of
to just to to pump the liquidity
to the system and we did
our best and in the situation which was
quite critical
if you compare with the system or
decision making process among the
finance ministers there is a full
understanding that it's it's it's much
easier with us you know to do it
but this is our part of of this this is
division of labor you know and it's it's
really
uh this is not been a share from outside
you know the the monetary policy cannot
be the
the remedy for all for the
problems in the europe and it it's not
you know
so and of course just to be realistic
okay i can dream as a
federalist about the physical capacity
but at the same time i know that is
politically unfeasible now
and again we are in a situation and we i
think
we agreed in the ecb that we are going
to preach about that you know that this
is a
this is optimum you know so that that
must be end game that must be vision
somewhere and once in the future
hopefully we can
we can uh just come on on the
on the proper uh
also
assistant or hand in hand together with
uh uh with fiscal
uh
uh with uh the fiscal part of
of uh policy uh to act together but now
just to be very realistic we have own
tools we just went through the big uh
inspection
i mean
i mean our strategic review which was
quite substantial revision of our
monetary theory and and we we have
certain consensus which is quite strong
and we would like to go further you know
just to do new reality which is which we
are going to face
in the coming future
so just very quickly to to uh complete
what you're saying i mean the result of
the strategy review is clear and there
is unanimity we want to rebuild buffers
you know we want to go to two percent so
the question is what if inflation picks
up more rapidly than we thought
should we
be
extremely patient at the risk of you
know taking some risk of pickup
inflation we don't control anymore so
that we don't rock the markets and so on
uh that's one case in point another one
is what if the economy is doing much
better than we thought but inflation
does not pick up or goes back to 1.5
and then we've got difficult discussions
but but i think it has to be extremely
clear we have unanimity in our strategy
we want to reveal buffers it's when you
are faced with difficult trade-offs
outside of the base case that it becomes
a bit more difficult
thank you i hope that answers your
question gentlemen here
let's get a microphone to you bear with
us what's the take of central bankers in
uplifting the role of esm european
stability mechanism so it's a european
instrument
that really plays a role specifically in
the in the field of fiscal policy on a
european level
because the potential of esm is to my
extent or to my opinion underestimated
is it really a vision to go into a
european monetary fund
or what is the future of esm
thank you for the question
i'll leave that open to the floor to
choose governor maybe we can ask klaus
raglin
definitely he has his vision with the
vdsm in the future
short but sweet
um gentlemen over here i believe you had
a question let's get a microphone over
to you
thank you very much mario holtz-naviena
institute for national economic studies
um if some of the current members of the
euro system
several decades ago have been
providing a different type of interest
rates for different sectors
now are there any discussions about
emulating
such a policy maybe
in europe i'm just thinking about so
different sectors as a
housing market which is
gone crazy and which might be the source
of the next uh crisis
on the other hand they already discussed
a green
sector which might need long run very
cheap
credit
an interesting question again thank you
um i'm going to give governor valliere a
chance to to answer this please
no actually we are not going into this
direction at the moment
you know in the past years there were
other policies which were developed
exactly for these purposes to mitigate
some effects which our monetary policy
might have on different sectors and
these are the ones we are we are using
on a national level at the moment
thank you very much um do we have any
other questions from the audience please
do make yourself known
not for the moment um i did have another
question i think it's something that
we've we've kind of touched on and we've
discussed um ongoing you know whether or
not these monetary and fiscal policy
interactions are simply an emergency
response um a short-term thing or
whether they are the shape of things to
come and i've heard different
messages from all of you so i wanted to
find out you know which side do you land
do we go back to normal after all of
this is over um or have certain things
changed for good
i'll start i think with governor kasimet
certainly it would be
very nice we're very helpful to have
very
cooperative and committed partner on the
physical side but let's
let's face it we cannot see this
happening anytime soon
as a as a principle
on i think i'm afraid on the contrary
uh on the physical side we can expect
a very similar experience as after great
financial crisis
this is my my personal view about the
fiscal
action on the action on the physical
side
after the
pandemic
because i think that exceptional
cooperation and robust
country cyclicality which we have seen
in 2020
was in my view an
exception
that was not something which was the
rule and and
i'm afraid that normalization
will bring uh
all pains all problems and all biases
back
that's in other words all we know that
what would be
the best practice should look like
but
we we are lacking
proper
uh framework and and
it's politically and feasible to deliver
it deliver it now what are the old pains
and the old vices that we should be most
cautious of returning to
ah this is a certain way of
fragmentation this is about the the
problem with that you know
sustainability of that this will be will
come the fragmentation and on on this
issue
uh
this the country from country to country
will they will differ what can they
afford in the future
you know so and
and then we will see how the new uh new
deal i mean the new generation you will
will act
in this situation so
so at least that problem with
sustainability of that is is back
as an issue
do you have anything further to add well
i mean what was special in this crisis
was the common shock so everybody was
faced with the same shock worldwide uh
and that allows for
a coordinated answer which is much
easier to coordinate
the likelihood that the next shock is
going to be that beautiful common shock
where we all agree on what we need to do
is indeed not that big
at the same time you know
the rule of the game when there is a
crisis is at some point you forget
uh
the rules of the game that apply in
normal situation you have to make the
switch like financial crisis
uh you know you want some discipline in
financial markets so if someone
go the stupid thing it goes bankrupt
well when it's a big financial crisis
you have to forget about that and you
have to be ready to go for bailout for
instance what we did
by the way you have to forget about just
you know
uh public tendering and whatever i mean
you call people and hire them and you're
not you know in accordance with the law
because it's a crisis
so
you know
knowing what the next crisis is going to
be and how we are going to to react upon
and that's a bit of disease in europe is
that
after a crisis we want rules
to deal with the crisis we just had the
likelihood that the next one is just
going to be the crisis we just had it's
so small
that um
you know when the next crisis is going
to arrive it's going to be depending on
the circumstances uh
a specific answer to that crisis easy or
not easy
absolutely i think to sort of wrap up
i'd like to hear from you
like you've just mentioned sort of
coming out of this crisis are we doing
enough um in europe you know if you look
at other global regions are we spending
enough um do we have a clear path out of
this and what more could we be doing um
if i start with governor wesley yeah of
course there is always a space to do
more to do more
more more in terms of quality especially
and
yes i i see some signs of which will
change the dynamic of interaction
between different policies especially
what we mentioned several times in the
field of fiscal policy so yeah well what
we learned from this episode might help
us in in the future ones
i agree that the quality of spending
will be decisive
again we are back to these billions
which could be i think uh
good flow
into the uh into the projects which will
strengthen the productivity and
competitiveness of the european
economy
and so i would like to dream together
what like really ask about the esm uh i
feel agree that this uh institution with
best practices is ready to play much
more important role in the future but we
are back to the issue
very provocative as a physical capacity
or safe asset which used to be
the quite taboo in the past but will
will come back you know once hopefully
excellent well um i'd like to draw this
panel to a close thank you very much for
your insights thank you as well for the
provocative and interesting questions
um we'll go now to a coffee break um
following which sona muzikarova will
lead a panel on the strategic
transformation of the cee economy so
thank you very much
you