so things are going to take even longer
than
otherwise would have taken so
i think we are not seeing the onshoring
i think it's just the beginning but
i think things are going to get worse
supply issues are going to
dominate
the next decade because uh you know
we've got a bit schizophrenic we want to
be local but we don't want to quite give
up being global i think the gentleman
from bmw andrea so i don't know if he's
here he said the sentence of the day for
me he said catl is chinese but they're
willing to put a factory in germany to
make batteries for bmw and bmw makes its
cars in china so you know you can't
say better than that it's very difficult
to europeanize
so quickly it's going to take time that
it will take time but do you see it
happening eventually eventually
eventually it will happen because the
rules of origin will dictate how people
are going to live
how we're going to live in the future
what is the future of
mankind because
you know we haven't done anything really
for climate change temperatures are
rising carbon levels you know emission
levels are rising so we have to do
something and we will i think we will
things will change we'll sort of
change the way we move mobility will
change more towards public
transportation
and you know cars and scooters and last
mile and jobs we know we need jobs and i
think the supply chain will create jobs
and industry and technology will create
jobs and the next generation will
dictate how we live
and and it's interesting that you say
with this new supply chain we're going
to see perhaps in your drop creation but
a lot of this new supply chain will be
based on uh potentially robotics and
machines that are going to be doing the
jobs that usually people do so i wonder
actually do you see that happening you
know a supply chain that is profitable
that sees growth but actually also sees
employment because i guess that's where
the tension is too
that's for me yeah yeah of course we see
we saw it even even before but what is
now reality is that this process was
just speeded up but uh speaking about
about supply chain and and shortage
economy now the the fresh uh issue of
the economist the cover page is the
shortage economy
elder from us who lived here in this
region we
we know what does it mean uh strategic
economy
now i don't see i don't think it is the
same of course
i i think that this is temporary i mean
this today's situation of course if we
are speaking about what does it mean
temporary if it is
months or or years but i think in
principle it is temporary
but if you are speaking about the
main topic of this this panel
which is competitiveness competitiveness
of europe competitiveness of
uh central european uh central central
eastern european region in particular
i think very very important is speaking
about these global trends which are
everywhere which are as as you said it
is now very difficult to say which
companies chinese american and so on so
on but there are some some some global
challenges which are clear and which
will influence very significantly future
of competence of the different parts of
the world i think there are there are
few which will be the most important
first one will be ecology of course we
need to restructure our economic models
and it will have significant economic
consequences for different parts of the
world second one is geopolitical rivalry
it is it is another important point
because it will be not only economic
conditions or economic factors which
will influence the competitiveness but
also politics in this regard especially
between rivalry between uh western world
usa especially and china on the other
side then it is demographic because we
have very different development in
demography in different parts of of
europe and then finally it is also the
model of economy which we have all over
the world it is which is that
debt-driven growth which means you have
very very quickly growing around that
and what we see now don't want to speak
uh
to to too much but what we see now
is that europe has problem just just
speaking about economic
economic factors during the last 10
years
if you are speaking about usa
europe and china
we see that usa it has the biggest the
the best economic performance
uh just just look at the at the share of
global global gdp which is still 25
share of global gdp of of europe is
going down china has very serious
problems now which means what i i
think is one of the biggest problems is
and of course u.s usa has its own
problems especially political but
speaking about
about economic competitiveness i think
the biggest problem of europe
is the lack of creative destruction
legal flexible economic economic
conditions which are stimulating the
qualitative changes which are
stimulating these new very demanding
conditions which are creating really new
environment and europe in this regard is
is lagging behind
and specifically central institute or
maybe we will speak later about about
this situation yeah and you know on that
point before how do you uh you know you
you made a good point that i always find
uh interesting you know the dynamics in
the united states are of course
different to europe because well it's a
very self-sufficient country and that's
where the administration is working out
to be but it also is about the
innovation you know if you look at the
big listed companies in the united
states through the future of industries
companies you know it's your airbnb it's
your social media and it's everything
around it if you look at the list of
companies in europe it really is a 20th
century companies you know it's the
pharmaceuticals it's the car makers and
and so on you know it still looks very
old is that because in europe there is
still a risk aversion that you don't get
in the in the united states or perhaps
in the more anglo countries or does it
have to be with the kind of leveling up
and scaling up that you need a lot of
the companies that i speak to say the
problem that we have is that in europe
when you do the investor round it's very
very hard to get access to the cash in
the united states you do two rounds and
you've raised the cash yeah so really
where well many companies will tell you
in the united states you do your invest
around with a good uh
pitch and you get your money i mean look
at the companies over the past 10 years
namely one innovation in europe look at
the once the united states the ratio is
probably one to ten
so what's so why is that happening not
here it's very complex phenomena of
course it has his historical reasons
different
and we don't have in reality single
market in europe still yeah which means
flexibility of the market is different
but also historically it is it is it is
very different and yes i agree and then
if you look at the europe inside we see
then very big difference in the north
and and and so but even nordic countries
which are considered as without problems
have problems if you look at the germany
today after 16 years of very successful
very stable government of mrs merkel we
see that they've been missing necessary
reforms and answer is in flexibility and
reforms because
outside development is changing every
day and now after pandemic this it is
changing even quicker than it was before
and if your system is rigid it is not
flexible enough to react on this
to for me the the best explanation is
the schumpeter's create creative
distraction you need you need to have
very flexible system which is very
flexibly reacting on the new demand on
the on the new possibilities on the new
threats which are connected with this
and this is the problem of of europe
and just to the final round of questions
of course let's talk about the
geopolitics when you look at the supply
story
this is of course very much a political
story in many ways too how much of an
impact does the current geopolitics that
we're seeing you know there's still huge
trade tensions happening in the world
feed into this conversation yeah i react
to what tara said right i mean we are
global
company i mean we in robotics for
instance we have three factories one in
europe one in china one u.s
and uh of course i mean uh what what is
happening now is impacting all three of
them right
and
what you said it will impact next year's
use a decade
i think we will learn quickly what to do
with that because with this
microchip shortage not only microchip
but the microchip has started probably
uh atleast
we now have see the solution
i mean if the one microchip which was
priced two thousand dollars per hundred
pieces is now sixty thousand dollars
what shall you do
so immediately in order to to complete
certain like big lines for 20 million
euros then you have to talk to the
customer said are you willing to buy
pay spot price
and this is this is the learning and it
will come and it will be new standard
because we will be able we will be able
to to cope with that because then you
prioritize right
um
what you said about the competitiveness
so for me this is a relatively easy fix
of course there will be shortage it will
have impact i mean there will be
projects delayed but what you said about
the shortage of labor as well i mean we
as a robotics company we always
accuse that we are taking work from from
people and still the unemployment is on
record high level right with increased
automation but what we should start
talking about is risk killing of though
of the people and this is actually where
we at least in central europe have
really big
gap to do
because
the the
the labor is extremely mobile today
especially with pandemic that is fast
and
the process much
much quicker than expected i mean if you
are an i.t guy
it doesn't matter if you are working in
bratislava or sri lanka no one really
cares
i mean discussion about innovate i mean
what is the ratio of people employing
slovakia and other three continents
right i mean you are very flexible and
this is actually in future manufacturing
company
right
the capital the the human capital is
extremely mobile today
and and we should actually make sure
that uh we get the best for european
interest because if i see the
people dealing with
artificial intelligence and cyber
security there is a
great community of people in slovakia
that is working for asian companies
they are living here they are spending
money and they they are taxing them but
the know-how and the added value is used
in taiwan china japan it's pretty sad
do you want to i feel like you wanted to
uh yeah i mean i've worked all over the
world
mostly in emerging markets right
and
people are immensely resilient i mean we
say the british we the british love
queuing up shortage economy we love
cueing so we're all queuing for petrol
and then you know something else becomes
short everyone's queuing it's a form of
distraction for mankind you know you say
you're too busy sourcing what is short
to worry about real problems because you
said it there are very few leaders at
the moment mrs merkel was stability for
germany who do you look up to as
government and another gentleman said
something very good today when
politicians start choosing technology we
really need to worry so
i think
you mentioned in about it's only a year
that i've started working in this region
wonderful region immensely capable but i
have to say
that i find it amazing at how little
support innovation gets here
yes you know if you're innovative here
you're actually penalized i'm very
surprised
you know it's like what
you know you should be really really
nurturing this innovation this all the
ideas you know ai robotics
battery value chains all the great
things that are happening here but i see
them fighting for basics yeah you know
getting attention you said in the us you
do a couple of rounds and you get your
funding right i have never seen people
work so hard to get funding that should
come to them naturally in the central
and eastern european countries and this
morning they were talking about
uh it's too expensive
because
you go and buy second-hand german diesel
and gasoline cars and bring them here
therefore you have the worst co2 level
you're number two in terms of that so
i'm worrying about that you know you
have to maybe bring some change here
because
otherwise
climate change will take the decisions
for us you know for 25 years we've heard
650 million people have no access to
electricity 25 years we've been talking
about it and now it's 700 million people
so we're not solving the problems that
well are we
but tara would you say just just to rub
on this uh point that you make uh about
perhaps a lack of innovation in eastern
central europe i know it's it's very
hard
there's plenty of innovation lack of
support to okay of support
is that because you feel like it's still
very much ingrained and again i don't
want to be rude but this is something
that you know behind the scenes many
governments in eastern europe still
continue to tell you in central europe
that would they see their big advantages
on the price is competing on this
exactly is that because you are
absolutely right the decider of all of
them
is cheapness yeah we want things to be
cheap
and if things to be cheap requires
subsidy then we need
institutionalization as you said
disruption positive disruption
and free freedom of choice should be
given to the consumer and the consumer
should elect to spend that money i was
saying this morning that
mobile phones are a very good example of
how it evolved right because if you look
at haiti the poorest nation on earth per
capita there are more mobile phones in
haiti than there are in the united
states because people choose not to eat
to buy that phone right
so
somehow we have to translate that desire
of the consumer to have the best
into the support from the eu and nations
to make it happen you use the example of
innovate i didn't but i see them
struggle
you know they struggle and
some of the big ideas that came from
this region you know cradle to cradle
recycling making sure that you know
energy neutral processes and businesses
all of those things are innovations but
they're not getting airtime
and this is a very good point you know
because it does show that there's a lag
and a mismatch perhaps between where
government action is going and to some
extent where your consumer also wants to
wants to see so how can you narrow that
gap yeah i think specific problem of
this region i mean ce region is that
in first stage of reforms we have been
we have been creating the basis for
market economy it was kind of will to do
to change this because communism
collapsed and everything everybody
wanted to be very to do it very very
strong kind of kind of support for this
was eu integration because it was for us
as motivation as as banker also
now you know these countries entered to
european you know some of them also to
eurozone
they
increased mass industrial
competitiveness and is the key we are
very calm still competitive in mass
industrial production
problem is that it was based on the
skills also but also in the low salaries
but they are losing this competitiveness
of course because we are growing
economies growing growth ages are
growing and we are not doing enough uh
for restructuring from mass industrial
production
to
innovation-driven economy but the
problem is
that first it is kind of lack of
incentives for for politicians to do
this because
you know every reform is is politically
difficult it's political challenge and
now it is not kind of necessity and i
mean visible necessity it is necessity
of course but people don't consider even
politicians don't consider this and then
if you don't have this kind of consensus
among significant part of population and
politicians that it is that reforms have
to be permanent process not campaign we
are doing two three years reforms and
then nothing other than we are great and
i see few countries which which are
relatively successful in this estonia is
good example every small tiny country
which which has this kind of consensus
among politicians that okay
despite if this central right center
left governments they agreed that they
want and they need to
modernize the country permanently and
this is something which is missing
especially if i'm speaking about my
country slovakia maybe we are at least
in in visage for the worst example or
one of the worst examples because we
have kind of periods of very very very
speed reforms and then doing nothing and
then so and then then as is more you are
you are delaying necessary forms as more
difficult politically it is to do
because then price and and so on which
means but this is general problem not
only in central eastern europe i mean in
all europe
because because this process of
necessary modernization saying in other
words doing reforms are very very
important and politically risky and
politically difficult and you know just
a follow-up on that you know perhaps a
controversial question maybe i get a lot
of uh hate for asking this
and knowing that of course eastern
central europe is is very the politics
it's very hard to kind of reduce them to
a stereotype but i have to ask you this
question given that you mentioned eu
integration you also mentioned uh the
politics how they feed into the economy
what about rule of law and in the past
year we've seen a lot of money that kind
of goes
you know what i like eastern europe is
cheap is good for my business but i'm
not sure if i like the liberal term that
some people are taking
how big of a risk is that this is my
favorite question first
this is very difficult because uh
friction and legacy you mean not only
formal rules but informal rules are
changing very very slowly through the
ink change of generation gordon brown
said i very agree with him that
regarding rule of law first 400 years is
the most difficult
and this is of course a legacy i mean
historical legacy not only from
communist 40 years in this region of 70
in ukraine and russia is is really
really very difficult and this friction
and this this reproduction of the
informal rules and deformations in the
informal rules are huge which means it
is fight it is it is it is it it will be
improved and it is improving i have to
say
but but unfortunately very slowly very
costly it is one of the reason why
reforms are even more difficult maybe in
in this region i spent five years in
ukraine it is even more difficult it is
it is you know it's extraordinary on one
side they have really i.t sector very
developed very competitive on other side
they didn't do this industrial
competitiveness reform restructuring of
the old industry was not done which
means you have some kind of contrast in
this that it is it is objectively
difficult and it is simply impossible to
change in few in a few years but it is
necessary fight and push
and do you see to that extent of course
this week it's been very much in the
news in particular in one country but
i'm not going to
name and shame anyone but but do you see
this tension at times between
kind of the national dynamics that
happen in some countries and and then
the rules also emanating from brussels
and and it's very important to ask this
question because a lot of the industrial
policy is going to be guided by brussels
going forward do you see that tension
removing momentum in the economy
uh you mean tensions between uh brussels
and nationals so the industrial policy
perhaps that comes
and also the money perhaps also coming
from brussels with strings attached on
rule of law there is there is of course
some some tension but i am strong
deeply convinced that the the european
union membership for countries like
slovakia and czech republic is the
biggest fortune what they had without
this it could be much much much worse of
course eu has its own some problems and
but in but in principle
you you rules and you not only
regulation but also fight for uh level
playing uh for instance for for anti
anti uh monopoly policy and so on for
for responsible public finance for
instance is is very very important which
means i think it is grateful it is it is
very positive that that there is this
tension because it is finally speeding
up this necessary development uh
to to normally functioning uh i mean
country with the rule of law and
everything this and is that being passed
through to the citizens i wonder if you
want to add she comes from the uk
i wonder if how much because i i fully
agree but it's not enough at least from
my industrial perspective is this not
not enough and what you mention here
also is
i mean
we are lacking uh certain
things like basic things like education
here in slovakia right i mean how many
universities we have forty six
for five black people
and uh basically say something about the
quality as well
and if i if i look at the
needs of the industry right
i mean from this cheap labor we are
coming even slovakia to higher debt
value
but
we don't have the skills yeah and this
is not really something you can fix in
five years yeah
and
i mean if you look at the government
current government we are just in the
middle of the of the time right
so what he did uh regarding this the uh
the educational reform so final thing
hopefully there is actually something in
pipeline kindergartens let's say
we have to start that anyway right
but uh
i mean we really have a long way to go
and the the industry the population in
slovakia is three million five five
point four five point four million yeah
but
i mean the industry is actually very
flexible in terms of mobility
right unfortunately there is
so far no better option
but what we see in for instance in in
serbia serbia is actually attracting a
lot of industries by subsidizing
providing land and so on i mean we see
bulgaria is having
exactly the same problems in slovakia
lack of educated educated people in
order to provide higher value
so we still have time because there is
no one better at the moment
but the time is the clock is ticking and
i think we should we should really stop
wasting time and do something yeah and
can i ask you to follow up on that point
because
i see it for myself you know i'm based
in brussels a lot of france colleagues
that are eastern european very clever
very smart you ask them do you want to
go back to your home countries and they
say no so
is that
i mean how can you fix this binary
because again these are super capable
people that add a lot of value to the
economy and then you ask them do you
want to go back and they say no that's
another thing i mean this is my favorite
question i mean may i
because i mean we in slovakia
we lost two generations in 90s
uh university educated people move out
to do the west czech republic and others
but today i mean if i look at my old
alma mater in bernard which is a
technical university 7 000
slovak student
at least one third will never return
back to slovakia one half
you know if i may because this is a very
very important topic
it is not like that that if we will be
when we will be in the future reach then
they will return no no if they will feel
that it has perspective to return
because if you have dynamic economy
which is growing six seven percent is
very dynamic then it is creating better
opportunities for young educated people
than rich country which is growing two
percent for instance which means what is
very important is that people have to
feel that they have perspective there
and then they will return which means it
is good that a lot of slovakians are
studying abroad but bad is that they are
not returning homes and also bad is that
what czech republic is is doing
regarding slovak republic they are
taking the best students there they're
free of charge studying in slovak
language they do it because it is active
immigration policy and we are not doing
the same
in connection with for instance
ukrainians and others because it is
competition it is fight for the best
brains which means and we had period in
2002 2006 when slovakia was considered
the most reformed country in the world
and i met those students in prague in
czech slovak students in prague in brno
many of them told me at that time yes we
won't return because slovakia was
considered economic danger very dynamic
very eight percent growth which means it
is also about image and perception of
the perspectiveness but can i also ask
you and again you know i'm going to get
so much hate for for presenting these
ideas like this but i think it's good to
have the frank discussion there's uh you
know i hear this a lot also in brussels
particularly eastern europeans will say
you know you see this catch-up so you
see explosive growth of course that's
going to happen when you have a lot of
catch-up to do but perhaps two percent
growth in germany that's going to pay me
more good school for my kids good health
care i'd rather stay there is are we
talking not just about the salary but a
whole ecosystem that needs to be made
more attractive is that and not only it
is also about roots a majority of people
feel the roots from the place where they
are they they have been born and so on
which means ireland is the best example
ireland in 60s 70s it was huge
immigration to the us then reforms very
high economy growth prosperity many of
them returned also with experience with
money and then after after enlargement
of eu they they absorbed a lot of people
from vietnamese they turned this and it
is it is possible to do because yeah it
is very complex it has many of
dimensions this but in in principle
people if they they feel perspective
majority of them i'm not saying all of
them
in principle wants to to return but i
guess when in the example of ireland in
particular you know what they did was
cut taxes major time attract apple and
the tech sector people started getting
paid well and then returned is is that
basically what essentially we were
saying perhaps that you need big names
transferring here
you know now it is it is they have big
names because it's like a land rover
yeah and
but you see what i mean you know
with the irish store it's very
particular on on the taxation you know
that's that's how they were able to flip
it and and and some countries will tell
you in a way that
it perhaps was very competitive for them
but wasn't good for the european union
overall so you know this is more
difficult question it is another my
topic my favorite topic because we did
uh tax reform one of the reform which we
did was tax reform and we have been
accused at that time that it is tax
dumping and unfair tax competition but
that's simply not true i didn't want to
use a word but you didn't
than before we just restructured the the
taxes we can't throw some taxes we
reduce some direct taxes but we increase
some undirect taxes and finally finally
the tax we didn't have a lack of money
which we covered from the structure of
european funds no on the contrary we had
more money from taxes because economy
was growing and we collected more money
and finally if you are growing quicker
you are shorter time in position of net
receiver of the european money it is
more complex fundament is not just look
at the rates in the
another example we had 19 of of
corporate tax rate at that time germany
had 38
average uh profit tax rate but we
collected much more from this tax than
germany collected because nominal rate
is only part of the story another part
of story is tax base and exceptions
deductions and so on which means finally
our 19
corporate tax rate was bigger
than germany's 38 which means this
sometimes sometimes it's a very
simplified thing the the discussion on
this and can i ask you just to also wrap
up on this conversation of you know
brain drain or attacking attracting
talent of course you work here in this
region but you're also based in the
united kingdom it does seem that the
debate in terms of what's talent what's
high added value worker to the economies
is very different and changing very fast
how do you see it what's to you a high
added value uh worker so brain drain is
nothing new it's been there forever and
it's part of the supply chain human
capital is part of the you know supply
chain uh and
i think
that
we've you you quoted gordon brown but uh
you know
it's actually
the problem with mankind is we have
amnesia we don't look at history we
forget about past lessons and we repeat
our mistakes over and over again that's
the problem so uh you know tax
incentives and tax reforms don't build
economies because you give them a
10-year tax break they come for 10 years
then they up roots and go somewhere else
where do you get a bigger tax incentive
package it's about the ecosystem
creating the right ecosystem for people
to put down roots this is this is the
words that you use and that's exactly
right how do you entice people to put
down roots somewhere and if you notice
countries that are subjected to
sanctions typically do well
because people come together people come
together they become united and they get
of common purpose and countries that are
thrown money at eu funding sometimes
don't even know how to spend that money
they can't spend that money because they
don't know what to do with it because
they are clogged with bureaucracy
the issue of serbia doing better is
because they tackled bureaucracy they
set up a notion of one-stop shop to
attract investment
and here i find in this region
especially in what i've experienced the
bureaucracy and the gentleman's club
i mean the women are very subservient
here i don't know why
i mean very very very capable women very
you know
on top of the world but very subservient
they i don't i find that very strange
because i think if there were more women
in positions of power they know how to
fix things because you do that
yeah and and there's what i i hope that
the woman here do you have something to
say about this i mean yeah where are the
women
yeah like
but how can you hear you know like women
in eastern europe are very
kind of submissive and i mean i'm sure
you have a a reaction to that
we have moldova now which has uh
president and prime minister and you
have a president uh but that sometimes
is different because you know what you
see is that women who make it to the top
may not be reflective of what you see in
the in the average you know neighborhood
with respect with respect i find a lot
of those things symbolic because the
women who have made it into politics and
outside finland and other places as well
they stay neutral when it comes to
choice of technology or choice of
industry or whatever they don't support
one faction against the other i think we
need a bit more free enterprise and less
bureaucracy from government
if we allow the commerce and industry
and will of the people and the consumer
to dictate a little bit more then
pricing wouldn't become such a big issue
cheap cars for everybody isn't the way
to go
it's good to have mass transport
mobility and leisure cars maybe it's
that's a different way of lifestyle i
mean
climate change will dictate our
lifestyle whether we want it or not
because you should see the floods in
africa you should see the temperature
rises it is real and we're ignoring
people were arguing today about
extending the gasoline ban to 2050 like
it's a choice we have like we can
dictate at what date we turn the trap
off nobody's taking it really seriously
cop 26 is round the corner did anybody
talk about it
they can't even attract the right
attention to the right numbers
so i think we need a few more women in
positions of actual decision making when
it comes to spending money and when it
comes to creating jobs you said the
right thing tell the consumer that this
chip is going to cost 10 times more than
it did two years ago do you watch it or
not right
yeah and what tara says about you know
the female workforce is just so
important come on these guys are now
much smarter you know they don't know
much more than women do like how do you
get cold things i mean i'm old enough
not to care what i'm called pushy
uh ball breaker battle axe what was the
other one god she's gonna kill you
before she lets you out of this room you
have to get used to that you know but i
think the results will speak for itself
and this this region has the most
opportunity in europe look at the
demographics look at the age you know
the young we have to look at the young
the proportion of the young and i think
that's where your opportunity is to
support your new industries and your new
technologies
and and it brings i mean look at japan
you know when they finally started
taking women seriously and someone had a
yeah well
thank you very much anthony tony blair
institute i live in london i'm one of
those slovaks who left when i was 18 to
study in the united kingdom i did my
whole university education my
undergraduate master's phd in the uk
i've been away for
more than 10 years now
the problem is serious about drain
brain
brain debt
and i think there is
i think what matters in the end is the
quality of opportunities for people to
come back to i think that is the single
most important thing
the one positive thing is that it has
been changing in the last couple of
years and i have seen a whole
number of people who spent their 20s
abroad actually gaining a lot of
extremely valuable experience they would
not be able to gain in this region and
then bringing that experience to
the region
slovakia and then being able to set up
their own companies and try to change
things so i think it is not necessarily
a negative things in the grand scheme of
things
it is about being able to incentivize
people to come back and give them the
quality of opportunities that they are
looking for but the serious point i
wanted to make about the innovation
economy and the transition and the
attempt to overcome the middle income
trap which is a real real economic
threat
is
that this region has been chronicling
under investing in r d for a long long
time
the average eu 20 spend on r d is around
two percent in slovakia it's no point
eight percent
and that includes public and private r d
and that's just one indication of the
scale of the problem here
so
i think the biggest problem in this
context really is the lack of
long-term vision and long-term
commitment that
leader political leaders really need to
make in order to overcome these
challenges
um
because to overcome things like middle
income trap you really need to have
long-term vision and the institutions
that are able to safeguard that vision
and at the moment
all we can see really uh and it's the
feature of politics in 2020s i suppose
is is politics driven by very short-term
interests
and and a lag of that vision so i think
i think there is a really serious
question about how we can institute
institutionalize that long-termism and
policy making
and and how can political leaders
build strategies that are really
designed to tackle those long-term
issues maybe just one addition what you
said from my side
what you also need is not only vision
and implemented it but you have to have
consistency
i mean for instance education i mean you
cannot do anything in one one term it's
just four years right
i mean if we look uh
we are extremely good in eastern europe
uh if we have new government they take
everything out from the predecessor they
start to build something
on the
on the new premises and if i look at the
asia for instance singapore japan they
always build on
and there are certain things where the
opposition and the governmenting parties
actually agree we need education
and it doesn't really matter whether
elections are won by this or that party
because they made certain agreements
that they will continue regardless i
mean they will modify it slightly but
not break it down into pieces and start
again right
but i fully agree what you said and it's
great that people are returning but it's
not massive it's not massive
i don't see it
i think this is what i mentioned what i
had in mind if i mentioned this
kind of consensus on permanent
modernization of the country and i think
this is the most important part of the
vision because you can create you can
paint the visions for for there would be
20 30 years but you don't know but
problem of this is that yes we have
really under invested in in and very bad
quality of high education it's like a
particularly in in research and but it
will be not enough this is the problem
that if even if you will give more money
even if you will improve
university quality which is difficult
and long term it will not be enough
because
the the problem is very complex you have
to have
sound and sustainable public finance you
have to have improving effective and
improving
public administration public services
you have to have
permanently improving business
environment and you have to have
development of knowledge economy
everything but is connected with this
only if you are doing progress in all
these areas you are creating conditions
for this restructuring permanent from
mass industrial production to innovative
economy even for instance if you will
fulfill this free but you will not have
high quality of education who will work
in this innovative economy every
everybody will leave especially those
the best which means and problem is the
short-termism in politics is not only
problem with this region it is problem
of parliamentary democracy of course
everywhere now it is even more difficult
also because social media and everything
connected with this
which means yeah it is a really real
real challenge and
now we need even more than before strong
political
leadership because this short terrorism
if politicians are doing everything just
to be the most important priority is to
be re-elected and then of course we have
populism we have been that nice we have
lack of reforms and so on
and uh actually before i will move to
perhaps the european uh recovery fund of
the money is coming in because that's
that's green and digital terror i want
to ask you a question uh that i think is
very fitting for this panel you know
you're both in the uk but also here uh
there is no question and you know and i
lived in the uk and this was a real
debate that kind of eastern european
migration or eastern european labor
force was seen as not the best quality
for the uk now flash forward 10 years
you have companies begging the
government to extend visas and change
that regulation so first of all isn't
that right around heck and then secondly
uh you know are we wrong in terms of
measuring how you how you how you add
value and what high value means i think
people
deserve the government they get because
we the voters
bring it on ourselves okay and
in the past the problems were maybe the
same but the respect for government was
different there were leaders
social media has naked made everybody
naked everybody knows everything about
everybody if winston churchill lived
today he would be one of the most hated
leaders on the planet because everything
about him and his personal life and
everything else will be known and people
would never vote him the greatest oh
he'd be getting on earth for sure
the statue will fall and everybody will
jump on his head and all of that stuff
so we deserve the government we get
that's point number one point number two
is that information has turned into
misinformation so my neighbor
voted brexit
my neighbor in my holiday home in the
middle of england voted brexit because
she firmly believed we
were a victim of immigration and syria
was part of europe that's what she
thought because all the syrian
immigrants that were coming to live in
her area she believed that turkey was
joining immediately exactly so and then
my other
friend was telling me that
her workers were voted for brexit
because they believed that eu was
dictating the shape of vegetables and
all of these things so misinformation
leads to a lot of calamities so we need
accurate proper information secondly i
do not believe that it's all the role of
government increasingly we have to
consider what you said it is
personal responsibility japanese and
singaporeans feel personally responsible
for their uh you know nation and their
growth and they have you know hundreds
of years worth of uh
sort of uh back
experience to rely on here we keep
ditching everything we keep ditching
everything something new and expats with
respect they all come home to build
something but they expect a different
treatment to local people and that
creates this two-tier society and i
noticed this at work that there is a
friction between diaspora having come
home
and local people who feel they're being
treated differently and in africa it's
so
glaring this issue of expat versus local
i've always loved that in the uk there
are no uk migrants they're just british
expats exactly exactly i've always loved
that and now i mean my husband is a
professor at imperial college
i have had this issue of lack of
investment in r d since i was 20 years
old it seems we never invested in r d
you know this is an old issue so
i think
we as individuals and private sector and
entrepreneurs have to take life into our
own hands
it's up to us to basically gather
together and create a society that is
just just transition just
you know fairness men women diversity
all of that we are it's in our hands you
know
and the eu to me is an interesting
concept i mean i am i am a very much
a remainer and i you know applaud the eu
and all of that but sometimes you know
individual nationalities have to play a
role yeah it's very difficult if you
don't see the differences and celebrate
the differences instead of trying to
iron away the differences
and you know going back to to perhaps
the the comments that we had from the
audience but of course this question
about perhaps the uk i remember the
economist had a front page that said uh
brexit will trigger now a a kind of
return
of uh eastern european minds that have
been in the united kingdom and go back
to eastern europe i guess perhaps they
were referring to more like countries
like perhaps romania or poland so on but
to me if i look at that front page and
what you said and the audience has said
it seems that that really did not
materialize this big return and we're
going to see brexit is going to bring
the best back home that hap that hasn't
happened it didn't and what it in fact
has done if i look at university level
you know phds and research for what has
happened is that more common wealth
people are coming we're getting a lot
more singaporean chinese indians into
positions of research but interestingly
it's not the government or even the
electorate who made the changes it's
actually big industry yeah rolls-royce
choice chose to move to germany yeah
right and that took a great deal of
research uh from the uk
and if you look at what's happening
within the car industry you know who
owns who you get confused isn't it i
mean uh mini is owned by it's a bmw mini
is owned by bmw somebody else bought a
tata motorsport jlr so when you look at
the ownership of the asset
and then you map that on where the
actual commodity is built which is
slovakia then you come to understand
like i've done over the past year that
zero decision making takes place here
where the cars are made you know that is
the issue the issue is decision making
and direction of use of funds batteries
have to be made where the cars are made
i mean
it's like fact of life
55 of the cost of a vehicle is its
battery right
so batteries should be made where the
car is made if it makes it more
expensive that's where the incentive
should go so what are we getting it's
the chinese who make the batteries and
it's
you know talk to the car maker the car
maker says i need to be competitive on
cost
i can't take a risk that my cost will go
up so what is this circular argument of
catch-22 so that's where legislation
should come in legislation should come
in to say if you make your cars in
slovakia please make your batteries in
slovakia
i mean that's what i think anyway
and there was uh some go ahead if we
could get him the
and there's also you okay
you too nice
hi jeff leiffer from center for
international private enterprise and
thanks for a good discussion maybe a
short comment as an expat immigrating
here and then a question for the panel
but you talked about attracting talent
the czech republic almost pulling away
slovak students is an american married
to a slovak who left 11 years ago and
she's coming back for my new job here
i'm navigating the foreign police and
the bureaucracy here is just
you can see what a deterrent it is to
bring to anybody wanting to actually
come and live here from outside
a couple months ago so oh you still have
like 12 15. i know and you said if one
more document has to be notarized
apostilled right and certified
translated it's just
it's like it just makes you say why
would for universities would you ever
get anybody who would want to come
outside of the eu to move into this
system because it's
it really takes a huge amount of
commitment if it wasn't for the fact
that i was married to a slovak it just
wouldn't work so i think that's
something to think about in terms of
moving up the value chain anecdotally
i'm just sort of stunned by this
accidentally the u.s is even worse i
have to tell you getting anything done
in the u.s forget it it's it's not yeah
it's not easy in you i know i i know
because my wife just went through that
in the u.s too but my family live in
america so i i know because it's
impossible to do anything it takes a lot
of determination for sure but i did have
a question then for the panel about the
whole idea of onshore or sort of
restoring of supply chains we i've heard
people in romania see this as an
opportunity post covet and you hear of
some desire in the western balkans to
maybe they could be part of this
reshoring is any of that realistic and
based on this conversation we're hearing
where might be the the places in central
southeast europe that could potentially
take advantage of that what would be the
most promising markets you might see i
think it was answered
and from from my perspective it was
answered worry by tara
very simple who will be the
most flexible at the moment
and actually i i have uh
i would like to react to what you said i
mean it's about the whole environment
that you create for the for the people
coming into the country right i'm not
slovak welcome check
and i can tell you that for my kids that
were that time very very young i mean
the experience it uh with the foreign
police was really drastical yeah
and of course i'm
i'm doing a little bit better but i mean
if if you have this kind of conditions
how you want to attract talent
i mean
basically you skew it they force you to
queue in 24 hours
up front in order to get in
for i mean then we talk about european
union yeah
i mean schengen
what are you talking about huh
so
good point yeah but your question
regarding near shoring everybody is
speaking about this and of course it
depends because for instance i will give
you a very concrete example ukraine and
what is happening in this geopolitical
rivalry between the west west and and
china china is the biggest exporter of
these rare materials
and uh
this is necessary to change this also
from geopolitical reasons and safety
reasons and ukraine on the other side
has a lot of
resources in titanium for instance which
means in these areas i think it will be
surely because not only economic reasons
but also other political and
geopolitical
well there is the lithium the biggest
lithium deposit outside of china is in
this region right yeah czech republic
and serbia
but the bureaucracy surrounding it has
made it almost impossible for the past
20 years to get past this um
schizophrenia of wanting to have
mobility and cars and batteries and not
wanting to harm the environment so you
know so that's why everything is so slow
and that's the debate
to involve the electorate in
understanding a little bit more what it
means but looking at the uk we have a
project within about in the uk
you know it's a hundred times worse
because
people have lost the will to make
anything manufacturing is a dying sector
in the uk margaret thatcher started
selling everything right and now we're
trying to save the car sector by
incentivizing
you know packages and all of that so
what did the government do gave money to
stalantis and gave money to nissan
right to make
electric vehicles but didn't consider
the battery didn't consider where the
battery comes from and how it needs to
be recycled because that's the other
thing we keep talking about the
final product it's actually the entire
value chain it's from taking the
material out of the ground turning it
into
active material for battery then making
it into a battery then making a car that
make and then you have to recycle all of
that so returning it from the beginning
back to the beginning and the recycling
is the biggest challenge people were
talking about charging being the biggest
challenge i don't agree with that so
much because i think charging the
technology will change soon we will do
it wirelessly you know we'll have little
pads and we'll put our cars or scooters
on top of those little pads and like
like scotty with star wars and all of
that maybe soon we won't even need cars
they beam us up what do you think about
that
and i think there were two more
questions uh from the there's two more
so given that we have eight minutes left
i think i'm gonna
leave the floor to you yeah zaltenberger
from hungary i have one comment on one
question the question is uh how do you
see the impact of the global minimum tax
on eu and on the v4 countries
and the comment on luring back young
people to to the region
i think it needs political stability not
only growth or gdp growth but it's
political stability if the people don't
feel that they they can express their
view and there is no free
media they will not come back thank you
yeah i agree
regarding global minimum tax i don't see
problem in this if it is uh this concept
as it was agreed i mean that it will be
for the for the
uh i mean global international companies
fifteen percent of course it will be
ireland will be it will be affected but
only are
in hungary i think yeah only two
european countries but it has logic i
had nothing again against this
what what we have been afraid uh when we
when it was discussion about
harmonization of the corporate income
tax in europe it was much broader con
growth broader
project and it's still under discussion
and the problem is
when we did tax reform what we did we
cancelled some taxes we reduced direct
taxes and we
we
cancelled almost all exceptions
deductions and special rates which means
we broader the tax base
and now you have problem because if you
will if you if you want to have the same
rate the same tax not only rate but tax
corporate tax you have to have not only
the same rate but also the same base
and if you're speaking about the same
tax base then the question is
theoretically and also practically the
best is to have broadest possible base
and lowest possible
rate
but to to cancel to remove from the your
tax system
exceptions deductions and special rates
is politically such difficult is almost
impossible because you know
the
groups are are profiting from these
they're very influential and so on so on
which means it is impossible because i
told at that time at the ecofin
ministers i told my colleagues okay we
will agree if we will take as common
tax-based slovakian tax base but you
will have to remove all these exceptions
deductions special rates and is
politically simply impossible but if not
if it will take some kind of compromise
of in the middle average tax base then
we will have to impose to our system
again
deductions exceptions and so on which
means it is practically impossible to
have really
one tax
corporate tax which means not only rate
but also base and on that note i mean
especially when you get eastern europe
there's a number of countries of course
that don't have the euro some would
argue you know if you try to harmonize
the taxes but you don't share the same
currency to some extent does that even
work i don't think it is connected
directly with the common currency
uh regarding it was your previous
question which we didn't answer is what
happened with with eu after
uk
uh came mouth
and it was interesting because i was
finance minister two times once before
euro
and and second time after europe was
implemented this was working and it was
it no no but it was interesting from
this point of view that at that time
when it when it was without euro
the the influence of of uk and others
was was much much bigger but after euro
was implemented the most decisions and
and discussions have been done in the
eurogroup discussion which means then in
you in in
european union ecofin finance ministers
meeting was mostly irrelevant it's
pointless because especially it's all
about the european central bank right
now exactly
this was this was i think
also important that
because euro real influence of uk was
really decreased in the in the european
union but then how does this apply to
perhaps eastern europe you know again
countries that say we want to stick with
our national currency because it gives
us a competitive edge but as you said
the big decisions in the year
architecture are done now by the big
holders of the euro so doesn't that take
away some of the leverage that you could
have and not only not only for small and
open economy to be in eurozone is in my
opinion much much has much more
positives than the negatives okay if
you're speaking about about the uk it is
different story but look at estonia
estonia entered eurozone in the peak of
of crisis in 2010 i think yeah
or 11 which means which means because
they they know that for them
a small and open country doesn't have
independent monetary policy it is simply
impossible from the definition which
means then if you are so interconnected
with the eurozone countries economically
slovakia is there's no no doubt that it
is better to be despite of the of the
problems and costs and maybe potential
future costs which we still don't know
what they'll be exactly and you know
that's that's also i find it very
interesting uh you know there's a number
of again not to name and change anyone
but you know against some of the eastern
european countries that have their own
currencies you know behind the scenes
the finance ministry will tell you we
want to keep it because we devalue
quickly we jump out of crisis very
quickly and we play that that game you
know the way that perhaps you know
countries like italy and spain used to
do before they became big members of the
euro area is that logic ultimately in
their long run flawed it's doing more
damage than good
in the long run we don't know of course
you know prognosis is difficult
especially future habits
it is difficult to say but look at today
what is development about this inflation
development in poland czech republic
hungary and what is in slovakia
yeah which we can see also now the the i
mean positive uh consequences of the
being in the interior would you agree
with that do you see any you would agree
with that i mean look at the czech
republic i mean being czech i mean the
influence from germany is what sixty
percent right so what do you wanna do
and the other eurozone countries are
remaining 25.
what are we talking here about
and i think there was a final question
from the audience was that you the one
yeah let's take that one
hi my name is andre shimon i'm also from
hungary my question is first i fully
agree with mr miklos about the
importance of
creative destruction and continuous
modernization to speed up the
development of europe
however
this takes means taking risks
and moving people out of their comfort
zone
which europeans have never been good at
compared to americans for various
historic reasons
but the challenges for politicians the
following if you look at the last 15
years we had two major crises we had the
financial and economic crisis and now we
had the pandemic
the consequence of this is that people
i presume want more security
rather than less security
and then you have a politician who wants
to get reelected
and he chooses between
giving people more security and slower
growth potentially
or taking the risk
of not being reelected so what is the
motivation for politicians
in your view
to actually go and take the risk
and moving trying to
to move people out of their comfort zone
in such an environment
if you're able to answer that then
you're in for for a noble
politics what is what is it exactly you
are right it is you you you i i mean
describe the the situation very very
correctly and precisely
the
motivation has to be to change the the
this vicious cycle and to not to be
leader and and and statement and not the
ordinary politician i know that
even i i have to say that i am not not
optimist regarding the
future development not only in this
region but finally in long-term
perspective i think finally if we will
see that it doesn't work
it is necessary to change this that
hopefully hopefully it will be changed
because you know finally
i very i like this kind of uh
words that politicians are are doing
what is necessary and useful after
trying and everything else
do you wanna
how about how about a game to change
politicians
space with private sectors so company
chairman could go and become politicians
and politicians could come and run the
private sector for a bit because i think
this uh
public private partnership is where it's
at this is in singapore i mean yeah
you have to have 20 years of experience
in the private sector in
i'm pretty sure you speak to a lot of
companies and but also a lot of
politicians you speak to a lot of you
speak to a lot of people all the time to
try to make this happen when you speak
in particular to politicians what is it
that you tell them i'm sure you always
tell them
the one line i mean there's got to be
something that you repeat we need to get
this right
well
it's a brilliant question but what is
coming
as a most of the times in current
times i would say last couple of years
is the fragility of the government okay
yeah so you don't have the the kind of
interesting
yes
but you cannot be really strong leader
if you don't have the ultimate support
yeah and then
we can have a look at slovakia we can
have a look at czech republic
i mean not only i mean if you have
actually five uh five parties in the in
the government how stable the government
is and how much
political power you have to do something
right
yeah and can i just ask you since we're
out of time but i'm still curious you
know there's all this recovery fund you
know money they say it's green it's
digital it's going to take europe to the
next kind of big industrial revolution
are you excited about that do you think
it's going to turn into another junker
plan that he looks very excited look
what was minister what was minister
dhulejah saying uh one hour ago here so
excited he said for me the priority is
to build the roads
the priority number one is maybe two
elections pulled him off
yeah pulled him off but but i fully
agree with him i mean we really have to
set one priority number one
i mean you cannot have five priorities
number one
because then you do nothing huh
i mean of course you can do it
together right you build the build the
roads and you build the charging
stations around it
but you have to really focus
and i think that from his perspective i
really like what he said i mean let's
focus on on rail i mean
rail is actually the low-hanging fruit
here if we get it funded
exactly
well time's up it went by very quickly
so i hope you know it was it means that
it was good i certainly enjoyed the the
session so thank you so much thank you
for taking the time and also thank you
to everyone that put the questions that
were actually very good uh the gentleman
that asked about the oecd tax uh you
know deal that was agreed yesterday you
put me to shame as a journalist because
that was actually the big news item of
the day and i forgot to ask about that
so well done and uh thank you yeah we
hope to see you next year thank you so
much
thanks so much
you