[Music]
anybody who speaks about banking or for
that matter and especially economists in
economics should put up a warm warning
like this um
i'm going to be talking you know
quite a bit about economics and economic
theory but
mostly disparity i'm afraid because a
lot of economic theory is well pretty
bad
and
i'm going to also advocate that one of
the reasons for it being bad is actually
that you know economics has been
avoiding the banking system
and so we're going to talk quite a lot
about the banking system where it comes
from and
hopefully at the end of this talk you
will have a better understanding of it
why it causes problems and at some level
how to at least anticipate them in your
personal life
but what ultimately you're seeing here
is what happens if you know a computer
network tech engineer gets really
interested in what is essentially a
medieval
network the banking system decides you
know because it actually was a rainy
weekend to sort of try to build a simple
simulation of the economic textbook so i
could understand it better this is
usually how i get myself into trouble
and discovered that actually the
economic textbook the standard example
can't actually work as shown
which is kind of interesting to find in
a textbook so you know then i got a bit
more interested in it and discovered how
it really worked and talked to quite a
lot of bankers who were surprisingly
helpful
and
built what is as far as i am aware
the first
banking simulation and economic
simulation that actually faithfully
implements the double-entry bookkeeping
protocol that the banking system uses so
believe me or don't believe me you know
but i do think i have a fair claim to
understanding how the system works just
because i built a working copy and you
are welcome to uh go to the public
version of it we do have a developmental
version that's quite a bit further
forward um get it working with the
latest version of java um download it
and play with it and i warn you now it's
research code so
you may need to email me if you need
some help doing any of that but several
long suffering classes at reykjavik
university have downloaded it run it and
found out just how easy it is to crash
the banking
system and it's at this point when i'm
talking at economics conferences i get
start getting very strange looks from
economists
um so we'll start talking a little bit
uh about how the banking system actually
works and
you know how we
reproduced it and why it keeps crashing
um and just to sort of you know
prequel it i guess
what we did with the system i called
fred needle once we got it up and
working and had implemented double entry
bookkeeping and you know could basically
have
multiple banks and look at the
transactions between them
was we isolated it so
the problem with any form of economic
simulation
is you need to create some kind of flow
of money around the system you know
banks create loans they create money in
the process we'll get to that in a
moment
but somebody then has to repay that loan
usually ask but you know companies take
out loans all the time as well so do
governments
um governments quite often don't repay
them that can be a problem
and
that money that you're using has to come
from somebody well it probably comes
from a company and that company has to
hopefully be selling something for a
profit to give you that money and so you
have to create these complicated loops
of monetary flows
and that's quite difficult to do and
still just figure out what is just the
banking systems behavior and what is the
economy's behavior
so
we isolated the banking system
very simply actually by just creating a
borrower who was paid a salary by the
bank
that matched the amount of money that
they needed to pay their debt in any
given simulation state and we just
looked at that for for a couple of years
what we did was just look at how banks
behave if it's a completely closed
system not how it is in real life
and
you know borrowers are repaying their
debt and we played with different uh
regulatory frameworks and so on and saw
what happened
so
let's go back to where we began
the textbook
uh description of the banking system
still in the textbook still in wikipedia
and honestly wikipedia gets worse every
time i look at it
um originates with the british economist
john maynard keynes who is writing a
report to the british parliament in 1931
on the big banking crash that europe and
the united states is just experiencing
and he gives this rather convoluted
example and he makes a couple of
assumptions and one of the assumptions
he makes which turns out to be very
important
is that there is only one bank
so
that actually gets rid of a problem
which we'll talk about in a moment which
is you know how do you transfer money
between banks that's actually quite
tricky that's as soon as you have to
transfer money between banks you run
straight into consensus problems
and anybody who's done distributed
computing maybe you've heard of the
fisher consensus problem it is
impossible
in that situation to guarantee that any
two
asynchronously connected nodes can agree
on even a single bit value and the
single bit value in in question here is
your bank account and people generally
get very upset if that does not match
what they want it to
um so you know
that problem has to be solved so keynes
basically said don't worry about that
we'll just look at this you know money
creation thing that they do and you know
i'm trying to explain it to politicians
trust me i'm an expert
so 60 or 70 years later
um the textbook model of fractional
reserve banking is sort of appearing
like this
uh sometime in the 60s somebody in the
federal reserve thought it would be
better to take keynes's single bank
example and sort of split it out over a
whole bunch of banks
and basically hopefully to make it
clearer
and so what he's showing with this
example is the problem that everybody
sort of screams about with the banking
system the money out of thin air problem
you know banks create money which they
do they also destroy it this might
actually be a larger problem
and banks create money every time they
make a loan
so
somebody took the keynesian example
broke it out so that bank a made a loan
ended up in bank b bank b makes a loan
where the deposited money lends up in
bank c and so on and actually 20 years
later and on wikipedia not in the
textbooks a computer scientist came
along said oh yeah that's a recursive
equation
and it should stabilize to this and so
economic theory being misled essentially
fundamentally by the federal reserve and
john maynard keynes
is predominantly based on the assumption
that the money supply is stable
it might go through an initial expansion
series theory um phase but you know this
is back sometime in the 1700s 1800s
but now it's stable and so we can ignore
it you know we have a stable money
supply
we know that you know supply and demand
and market trading which we've based all
of our sort of systems on is a function
of the money supply i mean prices depend
on the amount of money you can pay for
something demand is expressed as money
and the supply but we're just going to
assume the money supply stable and that
will be fine and maybe if the money
supply was stable it would be
i don't know
we've actually run we can run
simulated economies with very stable
money supplies i'll talk about that in a
moment and we still have problems
so there's more going on with this than
just the banking system for sure but
let's start with the thing that we can
easily focus on
how do we know the banking system isn't
stable well um keynes didn't or he kind
of did actually if you look at the
numbers in the back of the report he's
got about 10 years of economic data and
you can sort of see that it's changing
but they didn't really have statistics
in the way we have them now whereas now
you can go to pretty much every central
bank in the world and you will find
either an m2 or an m3 a money supply
series and for every single country it
will look something like that
continuously expanding but this is the
fun part expanding at different rates
this is a problem for the euro
um each banking system in each country
and sometimes in different parts of the
same country which also causes problems
it tends to expand its local money
supply its local lending supply at a
different rate
now
this is a very very slow system by human
standards it's glacial
all the interesting behavior in it is
actually linked to lending
and loans can be quite long you know a
typical loan period if you're buying a
house is you know 20 25 30 years go and
look at the annual reports of all the
companies these days they've all got you
know 30 40-year loans on their books
so
the behavior evolves over time with the
lending and that takes decades
so
a common theme in economics over the
years and something that cryptocurrency
latched onto
is that we would like to have you know
fixed
currencies that have the same value with
respect to each other
because this solves a lot of problems
you know if i'm running a restaurant and
i'm trying to import spices every month
and i'm trying to price my meals
accordingly well it'd be nice if those
prices stayed the same and of course
they don't because foreign exchange
happens and banking systems are
expanding the money supply at different
rates so you know there's always these
you know changes going on in foreign
currency
so you know every so often basically
economists try they've tried with the
euro and they used to they used to be
trying with something called the bretton
woods accord to fix
currency uh relationships to each other
across the different currencies and this
is okay for about 10 15 20 years
depending on the expansion rates
but ultimately it's destined to break
and because you know they're all
expanding at different rates think of a
carpet think of a carpet where the
threads of different parts of the carpet
are expanding at a different rate that's
essentially what's happening when you're
looking at different banking systems
and this is the uk
the uk was a three times a decade
country you know and i tend to measure
it by how many times in a decade the
money supply uh increases the us up to
recently was a two times a decayed
country
um
stability is sort of like the two to
three value the germans are very stable
so the japanese they're down at like
1.25
the russians well uh they've had to
re-value the year the ruble i think
about six times last time i checked um
everybody else is somewhere in the
middle
um
it's quite interesting that from 2009
onwards uh the uk sort of stabilized and
then is increasing again
um i don't know what it means i don't
know if it was deliberate or not
but it's
changing something very fundamental in
the entire economy
all right so how does this actually
happen
well
these guys discovered statistical
multiplexing
they discovered it
essentially in the 14th century or so
banking is based on a very old
technology i would say protocol
basically called double entry
bookkeeping
and in computer science words double
entry bookkeeping is essentially a
single error correction detection
protocol
so
from the perspective of people who have
to run companies and want to sort of add
up all the numbers and make sure that
you know nobody's committed any fraud
and that they've bought about the right
number of things it's a nice simple way
to do that and correct any errors and
essentially the way it works is you take
two people you give each of them a book
and each transaction the company makes
whether if it sells something to
somebody if it buys something
both people write an entry in their
books at the end of the day they add up
the totals and hopefully they are the
same if they're not at least the problem
is localized
so the books are classified as assets or
liabilities and equity and the operation
is called a debit and a credit except
that the meaning of debit and the
meaning of credit mathematically changes
depending on which side you're on
the way to remember this if you care is
the right hand side is what you think it
is credit adds
and the left hand side isn't on the
left-hand side a debit ads and the
credits of tracks
and because that is done that way it
works it's actually quite a nice system
so
back in medieval times
the goldsmiths basically sort of started
setting up and providing places to store
gold for the rich people let's face it
it wasn't a large number of people who
had gold in those days
and they were using double entry
bookkeeping to do this and so you would
turn up you would deposit your gold
and you would get
a single
basically a depositor account in there
and they would give you a chit
looked like this back in sweden in the
1700s
and that would basically say i have
a deposit of gold with this goalkeeper
now here's the thing with gold it's not
like a pawn shop
you're not going in there saying here's
my shirt i want my shirt back
you're just going in and saying i want a
certain quantity of gold back and i
don't really care you know whose gold it
was originally just as long as i get
that back right it's perfectly
reasonable
it's also the 1700s
it's 200 years before anyone is going to
invent police services so basically the
rich people realize quite quickly i
imagine that they are now going to a
well-known location taking out a heavy
uh valuable metal and trying to get a
way of anyone noticing
so very quickly uh people stop going to
the goldsmith and start just signing
these chits over to each other
so basically you know you would give it
to your friend it's yours and this very
rapidly evolves into being cash money
obviously that makes sense
and
meanwhile
the goldsmiths are kind of like okay
well we've got all this gold here and
nobody seems to be coming in for it
right
um
okay i mean you know let's be honest
about this they were probably the
hackers of their time
um you know what can we do well we can
make short-term loans right why not
nobody wants it
we'll just use our nice double-entry
bookkeeping technology we'll write 30 in
the loan ledger um and we'll charge some
interest on that so we get something for
ourselves we'll make a liability deposit
for them and we'll give them a cheat for
you know 30 more gold and as long as not
too many people come in on any given day
and want their gold back that's going to
work just fine and it does
actually um
the problem although it's not the
popular view of the problem the problem
that you know
a lot of people turn up and want their
gold is just actually not usually the
real problem that's going on
um i'll talk about in a moment but let
me just draw your attention to something
as soon as you've got this set up and it
emerges you know over about 30 or 40
years
you've basically got two forms of money
the sort of the physical kind that
everybody can relate to but in today's
terms on this side of the books
you've created virtual money
i mean it's actually a huge argument
with quite a few of the more obtuse
economists um you know is this money
even money well let's just say let's
just regard money as a token of exchange
nothing else store value forget it
as a token of exchange
absolutely this is money because what
happens very shortly after the chits get
invented is that the goldsmiths start
taking checks and basically you can just
write an instruction to the goldsmith
and say transfer my money to my friend
and you know it all happens on that side
of the book
um so you know it is being used as money
there's no question about that it
doesn't leave the goldsmith
and so you've now got two forms of money
in the economy one is virtual and one is
physical and about 300 years of complete
confusion for the economist
it's statistically multiplexing so it's
going to kind of work most of the time
but if too many people want their gold
at the same time it's a problem
now
the one final problem they have to solve
from a networking perspective for
basically what is if you just regard the
money transmission side of this a very
elegant
uh form of networking i would say
is they need to be able to transfer
deposits from one bank or goldsmith but
at this point of time they are now
becoming banks
to another
and of course when you do that you run
straight into consensus problems okay so
what the banks actually do is they
transfer cash
so they take the physical form of the
money and
they deduct that from your deposit they
deduct the cash and at least for a while
they physically send the cash over to
the other bank
this is why if you sort of see 1960s
1950s american criminal films they're
always robbing bank fans that's what the
bank fans are doing
over in the british empire
essentially you had a clearing
meeting the bank clerks would run around
to all the other banks with the checks
and things that they needed to balance
out bank clerks are energetic young men
they weren't stupid either
they quickly realized that what they
should do is all meet at a central
location
so the lombard street tavern the second
floor of which they would all meet up
there and they would basically all
balance out the clearing between each
other
and it took 50 years
for anybody apparently in management to
notice that all the clearing operations
were being done down the pub
and when they did they got their own
premises
so you've got checks you've got physical
cash being used as a transfer you've got
mechanisms to balance up you've got a
network and you've got something that's
actually very important for a modern
economy which is ways to transfer money
between people that you know are
relatively robust um and allow
commercial enterprise to occur
so what about all this lending
the the the thing that you know when
you're watching the youtube video the
vaguely anti-semitic tone usually starts
to come in on
um
it's it's an emergent you can see why
they did this i don't think there was
any conspiracy involved i mean it makes
it actually makes sense they sort of
stumbled over a way to create a network
but the problem was in some sense it's
embedded in the bookkeeping and you
really need to understand the
bookkeeping to appreciate what happens
when they create the money they
basically create a loan and they put the
sort of money in the deposit account
and when you repay the loan this is what
tends to get left out in a lot of cases
is you know what happens when you repay
it
hopefully you do
um well the capital the amount you
borrowed that is debited uh sorry
credited because it's on the left-hand
side and
that shrinks the amount you owe
and then your deposit account is also
debit uh debited
um and that shrinks the amount of money
that you have it also shrinks the total
amount of money in the whole system
so banks create money sure but they're
also destroying it all the time and
that's where the system can get a little
bit quantum
and then when you pay interest well that
just basically is a transfer from your
account to either the bank's account or
somebody else's account if it wasn't a
bank that lent you money in the first
place
so what goes wrong with this system
well what happens if you don't repay the
loan
that's this last one
the bookkeeping is straightforward you
credit the loan you write the loan off
hopefully there was some collateral with
that which you can take and sell and
recover your money as a bank but that
might not work so well
you
strictly then have to debit your profits
you basically write off that amount that
you owed that was owed to you you're not
going to get it back unless you can sell
the collateral so you deduct that from
your profits
okay
what happens if there aren't enough
profits
and also by the way you've just
destroyed some money because profits are
also money it's just the money that the
bank earned and what you're doing
well this is fundamentally what causes a
credit crisis
it's the economic consequence of an
interruption in the credit supply from
banks i mean it could be there are other
people in the economy lending
but it's only the banks who interact
directly with the money supply and so if
the banks stop lending and they stop
creating money
and the money supply starts shrinking
that has global and very unpleasant
economic consequences
so the expanded accounting equation
basically says that loan defaults are
treated as an expense
so you deduct it from income
and
you know if you've got a really big loss
then you're not going to be paying any
dividends and if that comes out negative
then you're going to start deducting
from equity well equity includes things
like
loss provisions and so on so maybe
that's not so bad
but fundamentally as soon as this
happens as soon as you can't cover your
losses with income
you start interacting with all the
controls that over time people have put
on this mechanism to stop it expanding
the money supply too fast
because we know what happens to about to
a country where the money supply
expands without any regulation it's
called the weimar republic the viola
hyper inflation the zimbabwean
hyperinflation the icelandic
hyperinflation of uh 1970's 1982.
um
it basically that's actually the
quickest and fastest way to destroy the
entire financial system that anyone's
comes up with and the social
consequences usually afterwards are
disastrous
okay so how bad can it be how much loan
defaults can the banking system absorb
in a year
well and that's the problem and the math
is very is surprisingly easy to do
so i don't know why this isn't pointed
out more often but it doesn't seem to be
banks profits are essentially take the
total amount of interest they can get on
their loans
take the total amount of interest they
have to pay on their savings accounts
so you know banks don't really make
profits in the way that a lot of
companies do they live on the spread
between lending and
savings so this can vary a little bit
but you know four percent is not an
unreasonable figure for how much on
average
a bank is making in terms of interest
generally banks you know they might
charge one person 10 percent uh because
they think it's a really risky loan they
might charge a company that's really
stable only three percent it also
depends on what the central banks are
doing the interest rate but they care
about the spread and the spread will be
about four percent
so
back of the envelope calculations assume
that three percent was going to cover
you know salaries dividends big bonuses
at the end of the year nice parties and
so on well you've got one percent
to cover your losses
uh the industry figure is 0.75
okay so we have a critical system
system that our entire economy depends
on
a system that if it uh breaks in any
particular way will destroy an entire
society and has done on several
locations
and its fault tolerance is about 0.75
percent every year
great
would not pass design class
it wouldn't but you know it never got
designed it got emerged
um you know humans being humans doing
what we do best try it and see
so uh you can depending on the country
look at sort of some of the evidence
behind this
now
i'll talk about this again at the end of
the talk but
a continuing problem which you see with
a lot of economic figures is they don't
factor in any of this money supply
expansion stuff right so this is the
chart for how much net write-offs u.s
banks have done over the last 30 years
and when you're looking at it you have
to kind of squint and go okay
30 years ago the total money supply was
about a sixth what it is now
right
that's the money supply uh back you know
in sort of 1986 it's just past the two
trillion value
and so as a proportion a
two billion dollar write-off level is
actually a much higher percentage of the
total money supply back in the 1980s uh
than it will be the following uh decade
and especially uh now
but you can see that you know these uh
basically the the driving mechanism of a
recession
is these losses you know being very low
and then suddenly increasing above the
point that the banks can absorb them now
it depends a little bit on how bad the
situation is what your central bank will
do
in the 1980s what i've
saw somebody say at an economics
conference one time was basically
everybody knew everybody being the
central banks around the world that the
entire u.s system was insolvent i mean
it's a bit of an exaggeration but it was
kind of what was going on they'd made a
lot of loans to south america and the
south american government
defaulted on it and actually
government's defaulting on back loans is
historically been one of the big issues
with this system um because you know you
can't do anything about that when you're
banking you can you can beat up the
little guy but you know there's not a
lot you can do with charles ii
um
so uh basically everybody sort of
ignored that made whatever tolerances
they could and eventually the system got
to the point where it could drain out
the losses from the system and it was
pretty stable for the 1990s and then the
internet bubble happens
um and something else happens which is
called loan securitization i'll talk
about that in a moment and that causes a
huge wave of defaults in sort of the
2000s now
loan defaults are what we would call a
lagging indicator well that's what the
economist would call it i would call it
a latency problem
somebody defaults on the loan they stop
paying
their interest they probably stop paying
the capital as well the bank doesn't
just then and they write it off
in fact if the bank can't afford to
write it off without hitting its bank
capital it's going to keep that loan on
its books this is the so-called zombie
bank phenomena where a bank has a lot of
bad debt it's making a little bit of
money on the interest perhaps and it
can't make any new loans because the
rules won't let it
common in japan in the 1990s and also in
italy now
um so the banks will sort of bleed off
these excess periods and that's why you
see this sort of net write-off thing
actually lagging the main event of the
recession as well so in 2008 the credit
markets froze in 2008 but the write-offs
didn't really peak until a couple of
years later
so one of the problems in the entire
system is latency and various um
accompanies for that so
to understand what the central banks are
going to do in any given situation
um basically
they will act to protect the banking
system
and rule zero is money must not shrink
rule one is that debts must be repaid
because if they are not repaid the money
supply will shrink and rule two which is
what the politicians have told them is
inflation should be less than two
percent a year
only they don't really have any way to
do that but you know we'll we'll ignore
that problem for a moment
why must the money supply not shrink
well because the last time it shrunk in
a big way it destroyed the entire world
not exaggerating there you can draw a
straight line between the u.s banking
system essentially collapsing and the
money supply in the u.s shrinks by a
third in the great depression now you'll
still see economists saying no no it
didn't really it was the fed's fault
actually no it wasn't um when economists
say the money supply didn't shrink in
the great depression what they're
talking about is that asset money the
semaphore money the cash money that
actually does stay the same
it's the liability money that shrinks as
bank after bank in the great depression
went bankrupt and was just wiped out the
money supply progressively shrunk
well in a market-based economy prices
can adjust in that situation prices will
go down salaries will go down that is
painful but it is an adjustment
what doesn't adjust is the critical
thing what doesn't adjust is debt we
have no good way
to adjust
debt repayments especially from the
banking perspective because the banks
are stuck there right if they change the
value of the loan outstanding they've
also shrunk the money supply so they're
stuck with this and
so
as the 1930s progressed more and more
banks failed
more and more companies were unable to
repay their debts more and more banks
failed because of that and the entire
system basically reaches bottom in 1933
when roosevelt intervenes revalues the
value of gold and kind of kicks the
banking system off again it was probably
about to be
do it by itself anyway i mean the system
is somewhat resilient but the social
consequences are enormous
one of the social consequences was that
during the 1920s the new york banks had
made a lot of loans to germany to help
the germans recover the weimar
government then
and in 1929 they called them all back
because you can do that sometimes in the
system you just say repay me now all
right
of course they couldn't so the german
banks failed then there's a cascade
problem in germany hitler's performance
this uh the voting for hitler is
actually going down a little bit in 28
but by 1932 33
with the german economy collapsing again
the second time in 10 years essentially
um
right-wing progressivism seems like a
good choice
and the rest as they say is history
okay so
it's not a very stable system it's got
terrible fault tolerance just for the
record
is it possible to have a stable banking
system well
yes we can run a simulated stable
banking system under very peculiar
conditions which would never exist in
the real world
um
all account transfers have to occur
within the same bank that's an
interesting one
if there are unbalanced flows between
the banks
that creates what we call liquidity
problems you know one bank has doesn't
have enough asset cash to
pay their depositors and another bank
has too much
and actually loans will do this all by
themselves
i'll show you in a moment
loan defaults have to stay below the
magic profits and expenses uh thing or
that might be possible if bank was very
very conservative about its lending and
this tends to be how banks do behave
well run at once anyway
and it's also why banks have
progressively become far keener on
lending on property
which you know has a value as a
collateral that tends to retain itself
than for the original reason they were
set up which was lending to people to
create businesses which is also a
problem
and if you want to control the money
supply if you want to have a completely
stable money supply that is actually
possible you just have to have a strict
asset cash reserve requirement
uh and you have to apply it to all the
deposit liability accounts and not just
some of them and if you look at you know
the american banking system for example
it has a 10 reserve account requirement
but only on certain kinds of deposit
account so you know there's that
but it is possible and it can be done so
that raises another interesting question
should the money supply actually be
constant
it's a good question
um
economists and i actually kind of sort
of agree with them think not they think
that there's some value in having a low
rate of inflation not a high one that's
problematic we're about to find out how
problematic but
um a low one
kind of eases the invisible constraints
on people repaying their loans
collateral being perhaps a little worth
a little bit more every year so if
there's a loan default to the bank it's
not quite as serious
um
and it also means funnily enough that
there's actually more new lending
so if you look at the amount of new
lending you can have you know new loans
assuming you've got you've regulated the
system to not expand too fast can i ever
come from somebody repaying a loan so
the bank's got a little bit more lending
they can do to somebody else
or it can come from the expansion of the
monetary money supply and if you look at
the numbers actually
you know for especially short loans and
a reasonable monetary expansion rate the
us is about seven percent a year or at
least it was um you know
more new lending is going to come from
monetary expansion than it is from
people repaying their loans and if you
need new lending well that's something
to consider
why might you need new lending
well as i said there are a lot of
problems with banking some of them are
economic some of them are systemic one
of the economic problems is this
you know very small rates of default can
break the whole system
who's a big borrower from amongst other
people the banking system well in the
u.s power companies
power companies are building big power
plants and
these have to be financed over 30 or 40
years so there's a lot of lending to the
power industry
the coal power industry and some of the
nuclear power industry as well now
it would be very sensible to switch all
that lending and more over to uh natural
forms of power generation silicon
especially but also wave and so on and
to do that now
and i think people would except that you
know it would crash the banking system
it really would you know there's more
than enough debt in those power
companies to take out the finance the
banking system um in a big way
and
the interesting part is that might just
happen anyway i mean the improvements in
uh solar cells
are accelerating at such a rate that
this might just happen you know without
anybody
you know trying to get involved or try
to stop it i hope they don't try to stop
it but you know
so there is this element too to banking
that sometimes the banking system goes
wrong the regulations fail or something
bad happens and sometimes the economy
goes wrong you know something happens in
the economy like you know
solar cells or in the 1920s it was
basically the invention of the combine
harvester
speeds up that part of the economy it
doesn't necessarily need lending anymore
and the whole system gets out of whack
again so you know we don't know really
enough about that side of things but
it's definitely a factor there in
history
and we see this a bit in the great
recession in 2008
um what caused the
previous crash because we're now into
another one
so
another element of the history of the
system the long one i could give a whole
lecture on this is how do we control it
and
first people try to control the
expansion rate to stop you know the
money supply expanding too much this was
done naturally by depending on the price
of gold um which it works up to a point
but actually every time somebody writes
a check and uses that virtual money on
the right-hand side uh they influence
the price of gold without the sort of
gold itself being involved and so if you
look at the figures for the gold
standards they've sort of been two
periods when we use gold that way you
actually see a slow steady expansion in
the money supply even in this period
where a lot of people would have you
believe that it's stable it wasn't but
it wasn't expanding that fast so it kind
of worked for a while
um
after the collapse of the second gold
standard which was the bretton woods
fixed currency exchange scheme
and fundamentally it collapses because
everybody's buying oil from arabia huge
amounts of money are piling up there
there isn't a good way for it to come
back
all the banking systems are sort of
expanding at different rates
and eventually it became possible to
arbitrage the price of gold between
london and the us and that lasted for
about three days before nixon was told
to pull the us out of the bretton woods
scheme
for the next 10 years the system kind of
freewheels which causes a lot of
countries immense problems and iceland
in particular has a hyper inflation
because of that
and then the basel capital controls
emerge in the 1980s and basil capital
effectively shifts regulation from the
reserve requirement on the left to the
uh capital
uh on the right and capital is a few
things
unfortunately one of the things capital
can be is some forms of debt but mostly
it's things like loss provisions and the
initial injection of cash that allows
the bank to be a bank in the first place
so okay that's fine it actually works
quite well as a regulatory framework
problem was
way back in the 1930s and said it's a
very slow system so sometimes the causes
of problems are really removed from the
sort of final denominator as it were um
the us is a great depression measure
brought in something called loan
securitization
loan securitization is basically allows
a bank to take a loan that is made
create some money with and just sell it
to somebody else i mean it's a decent
investment alone you know a treasury is
alone so
fannie and freddie mae did this for
decades at a very slow level it didn't
do anything particularly bad it probably
helped the economy it slightly increased
the total amount of debt available
and then computerization comes in in the
1980s and 1990s and it suddenly becomes
possible to do it on large scale
and salmon brothers is actually the sort
of company that kicks this off
and suddenly there is a lot more debt in
the system because up till that point
with traditional fractional reserve
banking
without it really being explicit there
was always this one-to-one relationship
between the amount of debt and the
amount of money
and loan securitization broke that
completely and suddenly you had a lot
more lending and you know a certain
amount of money
think of it as a water system okay
you've got pipes the pipes are loans
money's flowing around them you increase
the total number of pipes but you leave
the amount of water alone that's what
loan securitization is and suddenly the
pressure starts going down and at some
point in the system there isn't any
water flowing at all
and that's where the loan defaults start
and basically that was the 2008 crash it
takes a while to build up
because fundamentally debt is an
asymmetric network flow
by asymmetric we mean that more is going
in one way than another and this is
where you know i came in as a network
engineer and goes okay that's
interesting because you know in computer
networks when we have that going on it
usually causes quite a lot of problems
and it does in banking networks as well
um
the loan securitization broke some sort
of things that the banks were doing
without even really you know telling
anyone
one of the things banks do is try to
keep all these money flows on their
books they would rather there wasn't any
interbank you know flows you know they
want their lenders to basically
um be basically perhaps working for a
company that's also borrowing from them
and so all of this money just stays on
the right hand side
no cash involved everybody's happy all
right
and they will make decisions accordingly
so quite often you'll be told you know
if you want to borrow from a bank you
need to have your account you need to
have your salary paid into us and that's
that's why
okay
loan securitization just let them sell
these loans willy-nilly across the
system so set up all these cross-bank
flows and
after a while you know what happens
basically if you know you've got your
borrower here and they take their loan
over to some other bank well they're
paying back more than you originally
gave them
and
bank three starts losing its cash
you know without bank free of any
control over this
bank three is seeing a continuous flow
of money bank back to bank two basically
the interest rate
uh this is one of the ways that interest
rates affect the banking system which is
not acknowledged um
the higher the banking s the the higher
the interest rate the faster that
process will naturally be
um so it could be about to get
interesting
and what you also saw in this period and
this may not be that visible i apologize
um banks started taking loans from other
people so they would also borrow and
re-lend
and that doesn't make the banking system
any stabler
so uh cut a long story short
the united states printed a whole bunch
of money
used it to buy the bad debt on the
banking books put it aside kept it away
and actually did manage to more or less
recover the system uh
so and this is we're showing we're
showing here is m0 and m0 is the asset
the physical cache that we keep talking
about m2 is the deposit account and you
know you can see this jumping up and
down like a yoyo
but the m2 up until reload do recently
was pretty stable expanding but stable
so what happens in 2020 why do we
currently have inflation what aren't the
central banks
really wanting to admit in public
although if you read the right articles
in the financial times they do admit it
[Music]
in 2020 with the entire world basically
going let's shut down the economy which
is not something that's ever been
designed to do um
essentially it was obvious to everybody
that within a month or two the entire
banking system would collapse because
nobody had any salaries to pay their
debt
so without anyone you know even almost
discussing it the
uh american bank basically printed two
trillion dollars and handed out to
everybody
and unlike um the great recession you
know the previous time
when you give money to everybody in the
system the way they did that's a direct
injection into the banking system and
the banking system then starts to expand
that quite quickly even under credit uh
capital reserves and you can see here
that you know whereas it was a sort of
two times a decade system
now it's expanding a bit faster and the
second expansion isn't really the
government so much this is the banking
system getting going and making more
lending and more money
so that is today's problem now whether
it's stabilizing or whether it's going
to continue expanding i don't know the
eu looks the same most countries are
starting to look the same we are
probably looking at a period of you know
increased inflation
and increasing interest rates probably
isn't going to help that much with that
to actually stop this you need to
intervene with the lending itself and
sort of tell the banks okay you need to
basically be i would just put rules on i
would i would say okay you can lend to
new forms of energy you can lend to
somebody who's never bought a house
before that person over there who wants
to refinance their home and buy a
mercedes or something well tough luck
but you know that's just me
all right
that was the crash course on banking i
probably confused everyone
[Applause]
how can we get involved with this
because
i can tell you now
economists
honestly i'll skip through all this
sorry if you want to see it it's uh it's
interesting but we're out of time
economic models and they have them are
terrible i mean it's beyond uh
pre-copernican um
we are talking you know the best way to
describe existing economic models is
they are trying to fit a very short
ruler to a very long curve and it's even
worse than that because there's a whole
sort of set of papers basically called
calibration
which is you know how to get your model
to you know fit the data that you're
getting
and yeah if you take a short ruler and
you've got a system that's sort of doing
this you can fit it it's actually more
doing this to be honest but anyway um
you can get it to fit the data for a
certain amount of time and then you know
it stops
they're not going to get out of this on
their own they really aren't they're
trapped in basically textbooks that are
presenting them with false falsehoods
about how the whole system works
a very complicated system and no tools
to analyze it properly
so
i feel quite strongly that we sort of as
computer scientists as network
specialists as programmers and it is
quite fun actually to build economic
simulations and crash the banking system
um need to basically provide them with
tools and there's a huge amount of work
to be done and if you want to be sort of
you know talk to me about how perhaps we
start organizing this please catch me
after the talk
by all means play with fred needle if
you want if it doesn't work for you call
me i'll
get you up and started
it is free for non-commercial use and if
you want to do something commercial
we'll figure out some
way other than that um
one thing we could all do
and i would advise you to do it just
personally
figure out for the country you're living
in what your monetary expansion rate is
is it two times is it three times four
times whatever
and then start a movement to correct all
financial numbers for expansion in m3
and especially government debt because
there's this constant thing of oh my god
the right-wing people say the government
is spending more and more and it is
because there's more and more money in
the system every year and so they get
more and more tax income because of that
they're fairly hooked into the whole
cycle and yes they're spending more but
prices are going up and you know if you
actually look for example at how much
the us government
is receiving as a percentage of the
total money supply it's getting smaller
every year
and i could give a separate talk on why
that is and it's essentially because
money is piling up in the financial
system and can't escape into the other
system so we get more and more rich
people well actually we get fewer and
fewer but they're more rich
and
you know
the government's getting actually less
money to spend every year as proportion
of the total money supply and nobody's
really sort of thinking things through
in that level
there is a fair amount of correction of
you know they will correct for inflation
well that's fine
but you know
the figure of inflation is we're
producing more and more every year as
well so it's a bit of a misleading
statistic
it's a function of both the amount of
stuff and the money supply so i think
just correcting by the money supply is
the way to go
um
or were they correct by gdp and yes
that's another slew of problems so
at any rate if you would like to be
involved in a sort of open source
movement to try to develop economic
models that are actually based on real
economies and not fantasies
get me after the
talk thank you very much for listening
if anybody has questions please move to
the mic one question per person few
minutes left um what so what are
generally the differences between
threadneedle and this minsky software
that steve keane talks about a lot
the basic difference is i use double
entry bookkeeping
there are several models minsky is one
of them that are based on sort of the
balance sheet view
and that's the level above
and that would be great and i think it
would work well it does actually it's
better than just anything else the
problem is that there are some things
that can quite important things that can
be different at the double entry
bookkeeping level but the same at the
accounting level and we ran into this in
iceland funnily enough um
negatively amortized loans which is a
form of loan where the capital grows
rather than shrinks
the double entry bookkeeping there
really matters in terms of how the
system behaves and yet the accounting
view simply doesn't catch it
double entry bookkeeping is
uncontrovertible it's a protocol it's
just like tcpip we can audit it we can
be sure of it it's the atomic level of
banking system i would strongly
recommend we go with that
but yeah that's between me and keen i
guess
hey
i get the impression that most of the
problems you discussed here are entirely
a function of the fractional reserve
system where
banks loan money they don't actually
have and that if you would require them
to only loan when did they actually have
most most of it would go away is that
true and if so why is this system
necessary well um
it's a good very good question about the
necessity um you would get a different
set of problems is the evidence we have
from simulation
why is the system necessary well it's
really really hard and the crypto people
have been discovering this to scale to
the planet
right to have a monetary transfer system
that allows you to go into you know from
iceland and go into an atm in tokyo and
take up money is no small achievement
and the system you've just described
probably wouldn't be able to do that
um and i'll you know it's hard to prove
these sort of things but i will point
out that crypto essentially reinvented
fractional reserve banking
right they did you look at teva for
example it's got loans on the asset side
um and they did this very very quickly
so it's actually an interesting question
is can you stop people reinventing
fractional reserve banking right because
it's statistical multiplexing and
actually most networks when you get into
them you know your isp it basically
takes a 10 gigabit per second line and
it sells it to 100 people one gigabit
per second each that is a form of
fraction reserve banking or statistical
multiplexing it works until everybody
wants to stream the same thing at the
same
time so if you can design a network
system that scales that meets fishing
consensus problems and that separates
completely money and banking i think
everybody would be a lot happier but
until we can do that we're stuck with it
cryptocurrencies exist and assume that
bitcoin can scale to b money which you
currently can't but assume that it gets
there what effect does that have on the
existing banking system
um i think that would probably replace
the banking system but let me point out
um
and i've published a paper on this
although i couldn't get into a journal
because they wanted me to solve the
problem it is provably impossible for
bitcoin to scale to
that kind of level it's based on a full
mesh network and the scaling properties
of a formation network are order n
brackets n minus one number of nodes
you can't scale bitcoin to anything
close to what would be required and
that's why people have reinvented
fractional reserve banking with it you
know it at some level it's a really
elegant solution
and then you look at all the problems
that come with it and you go oh my god
uh on a scale of one to ten how badly
our solar panel leasing companies gonna
screw us over
i have no idea um
honestly i'm sorry i don't know anything
about that
um
but it's gonna screw us over a lot more
if we don't do something about global
warming
all right
[Applause]