[Music]
the talk now
will be about uh bring your own identity
how you could run your own
identity server and use that to
authenticate against other
services like google or microsoft or
whatever
and how you could enable this trust
relationship a topic that is
rather complicated rather um
very interesting in the current times
and
yeah all or more
i'm not qualified to talk this so we
have two speakers with rick van rein and
henry manson so please give them a very
very warm round of applause
thank you
um
i have a smearable very small business i
do stuff with cryptography open source
protocols i'm probably the only one here
but over the years i've
constantly been annoyed by how poor
authentication has been organized
also in open source actually and open
protocols i think it should be trivial
as trivial as dnses and i know dns is
complex but for an end user it's not
noticeable and that's the level of
understanding you want to reach because
then people don't
mess it up so easily
and that dns is quite simple right you
have an authority defying the names
exporting them over the network and
there's a resolver that can actually
verify yes these are the names and
thanks to dns seconds even secure
why don't we do this with authentication
and if we can please give users maximum
control over their online presence
because
i don't like if somebody else decides
who i am and whether i'm allowed to
continue to exist
or whether i'm allowed to be removed
from the scene
[Music]
i don't know if anyone if you ever
deleted the count for somebody who
perished who died and that's terrible
you have to jump through all sorts of
hoops with the third party providers
also um
if you're a security officer officer in
the company you would like to set a
certain security level say always
two-factor authentication for example
what we see now is that service
providers like github for example
decides
you need to start using second factor
authentication because we think it's
important but
as a as a user you want to make that
decision
um
so
basically what we've been working on
over the past few years is something
that we bring to users explain to users
bring your own identity you're just
someone at your own domain name like you
have an email address under your own
domain name but how we can make this
happen with identity
this should be trivial and it can be
because
every
relying party can can connect securely
to any other domain using dns hectane
and tls we have the infrastructure to
know who we are talking to to what
domain we're talking
and there are standard sv records for
quite a few identity providers kerberos
this ldap this diameter
diameter is radius but designed for this
sort of crossover thing so it's
the easier choice in this case but there
are standard as fee records for this
sort of thing
that together means you can trust you
can find an identity provider under
someone else's domain and trust it
and
this identity provider then of course
has the prerogative on the usernames
whether john exists and whether joe
exists
it can be trivial
in practice it's far from trivial i'm
looking at really big screen trying to
read it i shouldn't
um yeah i know so
credential handling is very often done
in applications and that's a problem
because an application programmer has
quite different
ideas and wishes and things he wants to
do than a security programmer so what we
end up with is passwords the lowest
common denominator if we're doing that
all the time i can't make a mistake if i
do that too
shouldn't we just
tell the application programmer we
authenticated this guy this identity you
can trust that should be enough
um credentials managed by foreign
parties i think are a disaster
um you can't withdraw you can't expire
you can't
why can't i make an identity that
expires in three weeks ideal for web
shops right
also
if other parties manage them they need a
recovery protocol
you can't have a local administrator
overriding things
so you need some mechanisms and some
jumping through hoops to do this and you
end up supplying communication details
which
means a privacy
problem
so um
and there are many solutions that look
like the sort of thing we're doing but i
found that most of them
um are web only or in other ways
protocol specific but usually that
leads to web only meaning imap has to
reinvent the wheel meaning just about
any protocol has to do it again
so um
in terms of technology i used i don't
say bring your own identity because
that's like how users would experience
it but we speak of realm crossover
and there are ways of doing this for
quite a few common authentication
protocols already and we made small
extensions to existing standards and
could then make this happen cecil in
case you don't know it it means that the
server sends you a list of mechanisms
you might lose use might be something
like plain text or it might be gss api
or might be digest md5
it just gives you a list and the client
chooses with which mechanism to to use
and then they start passing tokens back
and forth interpreted
through that mechanism
until the server says yeah you're
welcome well no you're not
this is a very generic thing and it
allows you to negotiate what you want to
do you might go for a simple password or
you might go for something as fancy as
coveralls
kerberos in case you think it's
old-fashioned let me rephrase that into
old and fashionable
it works with symmetric keys so in a
trivial way it's always been quantum
proof
and it's already been designed to prove
a campus with curious innovative
students
pretty much what we have on the on the
internet today where everybody is
challenging security over time and it's
with to the test of time with of course
crypto updates
um
and lastly certificates can be used for
tls signing encryption and we also see
ways of doing realm growth crossover for
that so i'm going to talk about these
three realm crossover mechanisms
and hungry later on is going to one of
them
um so for sassel
um sasso is embedded in just about any
uh authentication protocol it's amazing
it's almost everywhere
so if you can
support sassel it's wonderful
i know http doesn't have sassel so we
built that don't worry we've got you
covered
um
and to make this work we designed a new
mechanism for sasel that's one of the
extensions we made it's
a pretty trivial extension that anyone
can make basically we call that essex
over plus
and that's like an end-to-end tunnel
that wraps around a standard social
exchange and i'll show later on why
and
basically you have an intimate server
that wants to use something that
um passes this cecil and then in the end
knows that you that he's talking to john
example.com
so this is from my internet draft so
that's why it's a ascii art picture
is it readable
good thanks
so let's say the application at hand is
email but keep in mind it could be
anything but let's say we want to have
an imap server for a group and it's
hosted under some sort of domain
somewhere
and john
who has an identity under example.com
wants to use that
and this will be the identity provider
for example.com
so john and example.com have some
somewhere sometime in the past set up an
account
now what john does is he says i want to
talk to the time app server number says
yeah like you first got to log on
because i need to know whether you can
see this group and perhaps it wants to
see what mills you've already seen
so it starts successful exchange
and what the foreign server does is
pretty much it says okay i see sx over
plus being used that means i'm not going
to resolve the password locally like web
servers very often do
i'm going to pass on the request and the
essex over plus has a beginning where
you can see what domain it goes to
so it's passed on to john's domain it
just says example.com so it knows it can
pass it on and it does all the things i
just mentioned as a vlookup tsa it's
okay
and then just passes on the samsung it
just sits in the middle pretty dumb just
passing back and forth to social
packages
and at support the identity domain says
yep
this is indeed an account that we have
and it's called john
it doesn't say you're not example.com
because he knows that he validated that
using the sfe and all that all that
stuff
um
so the identity domain only says stick
john in front
so now the foreign server knows it's
talking due to john at example.com it
can relay back the okay
and everything can happen as it is
[Music]
so
what did we need to do for this
um
i meant to use diameter and it is like
radius but rage is optimized for trusted
internal networks and diameter is more
optimized for
realm results sort of thing so
mutually untrusting domains
so we needed to define a couple free
address value value
attribute value pairs to carry
the samsung content back and forth
[Music]
that's pretty much all plus of course
the sx over plus mechanism
and we've implemented this stuff and it
works like crazy
as i mentioned um we thought the cool to
demo this with http so that's what we'll
show you so we have an authentication
mechanism for http that actually pass
the sassl
so then you get in this picture
web browser speaking sassal over http
to to a web server and that in the back
end can use the identity domain
and something else i'm also doing now is
i'm building it into pam so you could
use in sudo for example or in
the console access from container for
example
um that also means your very simple
small container doesn't need to know
what counts it can just forward it to a
trusted internal
node
um cabros is entirely different but i
think this is the goal path for for what
you want to do because
kerberos does single sign-on you log on
in the beginning of the day you get a
sort of meta ticket and you use it for
the rest of the day to get additional
tickets without effort
kerberos even has realm crossover
building but it's static
meaning i ask my
kerberos controls
it's called key distribution center so i
asked my kerberos realm controller
please hand me a ticket for a service i
now want to see and it says oh gosh i
don't know that one
but i know the realm that does so it
says i'm going to give you a key that i
share with that realm and you can use
that to ask that realm
for control so then you have
the client identity uses um it's its own
realm and the service is at another
realm
and this is real course but it uses
static keys that have been
pre-configured like shall we say
the name of marquette yeah let's do that
and then it's set
all we had to do to d to extend this
is to
basically say first of all if you ask
for a service that i don't know i want
to know what realm it is what covers
realm so what domain
so it needs to be able to look that up
in dns well that's a text record it's
pretty simple
except when you need to pass it through
itf but um it's a pretty simple idea
um and then the next thing is these two
cover servers when they see gosh you're
asking me for surface through dns i can
look up what realm it has but now i need
to exchange a key
so the two
key key
distribution centers so the
realm controllers for kerberos get in
contact and do a key exchange which
basically is a key extraction facility
that's standardized in rfc 5c of
o5
basically they use the master key
add some seeding and add some strings
and that ends up being
a key that the two end points have
without explicitly passing it it's
lovely mechanism
and from then on it might be for three
weeks for example and
the client realm would do that
for um
um or everyone in the client realm can
use these keys to address any surface in
the surface realm
and of course it might also be done the
other way around but that's independent
um so this is a really efficient uh
system and also covers bloody fast so
after the first has come through you
really
have
very fast access to a remote surface
and this conserves the internet that's
pretty much the idea the entire internet
can use this mechanism and use kerberos
for all their authentication that
something covers can do now
so those are a few very simple things we
added
to make this possible
certificates we haven't done much on
this but we understand how to do this
um certificates have these funny names
in their subject right
they're actually an ldap location
so they would look like user id is john
and maybe organizational unit an
organization or whatever and then the
domain is split in a number of
components the domain is very long i
need to walk along and for it but this
is basically a location in ldap
and that is standardized
that is just something we don't do very
often but it is a standard
and even if you know the domain part
it has been standardized that you put
ldtp in front
find a find sov record and then look up
the ldap server
of course ldap can be encrypted with tls
after starting less call
and then you can continue with the
um with dane to make sure that you're
talking to the right one so yet again
the same structures
dina
records and you're there you can look up
things because
these are locations for objects and they
made may have attributes with x59
certificates
pgp keys so you can use signing your
encryption
with someone you haven't talked to
before
and the interesting thing is
it uses a slightly different name but
openpgp has this installed if you use
minus r on pgp or gpg you can actually
pull in
based on the email address pull in that
key
if they set this up
realm crossover can really be done very
easily
and an extra idea that we're trying to
get through and i think people are
listening
is
why should i use an external authority
to sign the users in my domain i would
very much like to be able to just
publish a root certificate for so for a
local ca and publish that uh
with a dane record and client then could
do
that sort of things
it's all in the pipeline we'll see
imagine
mail servers they talk to each other and
when one domain sends something to
another domain
um they need to trust the identity
that's been supplied to them imagine
adding authentication here
that definitely makes it more difficult
to spam and it also makes it very
pleasant to select because between the
ones you trust and the ones you
may trust or may not trust so it can
make you switch between white listing
and great listing your mail server can
be really valuable
and email of course was designed in the
time that everybody trusted everyone
with 32 computers online that was safe i
suppose
um but you can actually expand on that
quite well
and
basically use these issues to retrofit
more security on smtp
sip that's used for calling
not just audio but it's generally used
for telephony and video calls and all of
that
with a pleasant thing that unlike all
those platforms that we have like zoom
um if you use ipv6 it's very trivial to
make use to use direct connections
so just call ulrikitopophotos.net
you will be connected
um
imagine adam roenke's over there you
know who's calling because you could
check
um
you would know somebody is scamming you
and you might even look up information
in the enum records for example to see
what kind of person it is and
um you might even find key material
there so you could start an encrypted
call
helpful i would say
um
http well henry is going to show all
about that because i think that's one of
the lovely
yeah he came up with a wonderful way of
building this into mozilla using a
standard that is new but that was
already in brazil but
in theory it
can be rolled out in other browsers as
well but they also adopt this new
standard
um
doing this for
doing session for auth uh http
authentication means you could add real
course over there
bring your own identity so log on to
gmail
if they if they would support this of
course but log into gmail using your own
identity managed under your own domain
and you want to stop using it you just
delete your identity on your own
identity provider if you want aliases if
you want to do stuff with groups
whatever you want you're in control
if you lose your password
you go to your local admin you have it
changed locally on your domain
i think that beats having to
having these 30 seconds expiration that
gmo uses while they don't implement
grain listing properly
um and here too i mentioned that
applications
are um
applications have problems with
getting this information getting to the
information a web server can easily set
a number of environment variables and
pass the information over to scripts
so
we made a simple protocol to allow you
to
if you need to implement diameter in
every single server it's going to be a
hassle because diameter isn't easy
so we made a very simple wrap-up
protocol that basically says we've got
open authentication close requests and
responses that can be multiplexed
and it this turns out to be very easy to
build into an application we also made
instead of just a protocol we also made
a library to use this
and we have demonstrations for
synchronous
threaded and event driven applications
so forked
fog based thread-based and event-based
and this
usually we copy these things and get
things working very quickly
and what this assumes is that within
your domain you have a central node
that runs diameter and quick uh
quick diacesal connects
to to that node so you have one place
that basically is the client for
authentication
and all the others basically just use
that
so
we have had funding but we can also hand
out some of that to other people and i'm
very pr pleasant i'm very pleased to say
that
um our work on cecil works is well
project name we had we did all sorts of
nut and bolt work on sassel and it's
been sponsored by anilnet
including the pam module i just talked
about um
realm crossover uh as as a mechanism has
mostly been sponsored by ngi point which
is a european union project
european union doesn't really like to
offer you facebook logins and if i have
to be honest i don't very much like to
say facebook is now going to design
decide that i can log on to this site
that holds all this personal information
about me
somehow i think
that's challenging them too much
offering them too much
some of these
ngi ngi pointer funds are remaining
and um
as i said with the quick die cell it's
really easy to add to make a model
extension to your server and to actually
implement this so if you're interested
in this we can probably help you with
some funding
so contact us contact me
for example
and what we'll be looking for is things
with the most impact so if it's generic
it's interesting
if it's a frugal proposal we can do more
of those and if it ends up in the core
distributions we say hooray um
so if you think this is interesting if
you
want to implement it talk to us and
um
that's where i
hand off the microphone to henry
if you download these slides then there
are many links to
documentation in backgrounds
um i won't go over those now but
if you download them there's extra
goodies
good now to train libra office
terrible program
thank you
hello hello yes
i will continue uh the talk of rick by
demonstrating
http social
which i
introduced already
and
it
i have to look up a little bit because
this is my first speech
heart of the page hustle
is a new http authentication protocol
that's a standardized diverse way to add
new http protocols
as the name already says
it
involves headed the disaster protocol
which allows you to specify the
mechanism in the software protocol
itself and so it's
it could be the only
hd
http protocol there
sasha provides for choosing a mechanism
while the http authentication protocol
contains the mechanism that is
almost all http
authentication mechanisms
choose one specific
authentication mechanism
and social habit that allows for
any mechanism to be used
heart of the social was invented by the
previous speaker
which one uh thing in mind that rayan
kazowi just mentioned and his essex over
brisk protocol
which we will have which will be the
mechanism you choose
when you want to have the arm crossover
but
http also allows for conventional
mechanisms to be used which don't allow
for crossover
there is a draft on it and it's shown
there and that will be
available on the slides edit that is the
last protocol which
contains the latest updates
next slide
here is the headers i can do the firearm
this is the demonstration of a
conventional hcp social exchange the
most used one by the way
and it's very simple
you try to out
to visit the website and you get
you are not outright you have to log in
and then the headers
the browser reacts by showing a pop-up
that the login is required and it shows
some
http message which is always on the
top of the
top of the box and this is something
like now you enter the secret area
something like that
and that's the way i'm passed in the the
www authenticate
header
and
the client then responds in base 64
encoding it's not encryption it is just
a simple encoding with username and
password and then the
the web server checks whether those
characters are correct and they either
succeed or not
next slide
this is uh
a flow how it goes which
has our new http social
mechanism
and you can see that there is a one
extra ping pong so i had so to say
and the first authenticate from the web
server is here i have my list of
mechanisms i support
and then you can choose one of them and
the realm is exactly the same in the arm
which is used in the basic in the basic
authentication mechanism this is just
something you can show you're now
locking in some secret area
and the next what at that time headers
i will show you in a minute
instead of the standard
properties from the browser itself which
is built in all modern browsers
we show up a
public pop-up box is shown by an
external program that is not a browser
with an external program it's not allows
you to not only allows you to enter the
credentials but also which mechanism you
want to use to log on
and that is all all happening in the
artsculture in the left side
of this diagram
and then here you can see here as a as a
demonstration
that the
user chooses digesting d5
to too low home
and then it's almost the same as a
conventional
conventional uh
http authentication mechanisms and just
the
that is the
web server sends challenges which the
client has to make a response on and the
only extra parameter we use is the
so-called service state s2s in this
diagram
that's something the
web server
the server can send to the client and
the client always have to send this same
state back in the next request
and that's your that you
can see and
the same
string has the same string which is sent
by the server and sent back by the
client
and then uh in the case of digest 75
business as usual and then the
credentials are checked and when the
credentials are correct
you get
an okay or
authorization refused
there's the
this light and then the most complex one
here this is the one which crossover
and uh
uh
it's using the same apple and had the
same software
but now
uh
the server header clients not select the
digest 75 but the esx over protocol
but then
that is the the my
the
proper works of the new client program
has extra fields which you can
fill in
in that are the alias and the client
domain fields and most important is of
course the client domain that's the
domain
which it's just talked about which you
want to log on to identify yourself
and the alias is used for
showing the entity which the foreign
server has the the middle server index
diagram will see that is i can
authenticate the summary
but i can uh that is the foreign server
can see a totally different uh identity
on the the identity you want to
provide to the server
headers and i will show you in a minute
how that looks look
drop
pop books
box looks like
uh let's see then it happens on the
first head after the
client has chosen essex over protocol
it's nice to
indicate what's inside the encoded
client-to-server field here what you see
there and then i have just to make clear
a little bit how
crossover works that that contains the
client domain you want to log on to and
not to be confused with the realm which
is shown in our proper box head it is
at a client domain you filter in the
popup box on the of the client program
let's go to the next slide because
header here i have the components which
are involved in our
our
setup which i will show you in a minute
here the this is the on the left side on
the purple side we call it magenta box
is a native client which is a c program
which does the real authentication
and i i built this and like fortunately
it was possible because
browsers have standardized the way
plugins work
and one of the possibilities you can do
is so-called native message messaging
which allows a browser which is the
yellow box
which runs inside the browser as a
javascript as javascript extension when
you set it up correctly head and
plugin is allowed to talk to an external
program and you have to
organize it you have to
organize it yourself so ahead of not any
program can talk to the browser which
will be a huge
security risk
and on the right side we have a server
it can be an apache module but when i
first started for an lnet had to to just
show that this concept works i used for
example a java servlet to do the to do
the work and it was of course only a
conventional
a conventional mechanism which was used
and i think everything i mentioned here
is done
and uh yeah i can next slide is okay
and here
you maybe you will recognize some of the
components which
rick shows in his
realm crossover targ
because
here are the components in the apache
server in the identity provider
these three things
i have no pointer but the blue the green
and the red box are the same components
which rick showed in his slide
had how the anchors of work said the
three parties the
the
apache server contains the three
diameter client
which talks to
possibly a different
a different
three-dimensional server had a
different
server on a different domain
and a
free
diameter allows for that
and
i will have to have a look because it's
a little bit complicated
and it was very hard but this is
because the the apache model which is
used here which is
capable of uh
uh doing b had a d major shuttle is one
of the two
patchy modules i wrote i start with a
simple one which really involved that
the entire authentication was done in
the apache module on the same server
and this module which allows for
to authenticate on an external diameter
server is called the header module for
the dma to shuttle which uses a trusted
quick quick dia social protocol between
the
blue and the green box that is correct
click and this is the essential protocol
this is protocol you invented
and the digital this is we have created
a demo for this and then you can really
see here that there are three parties
and that
headers client
services can log in using its own domain
and then the authentication succeeds and
that is on one of the next slides
yeah hey
here you see the uh
headers on
on the firefox browser you see the new
problemworks every three places the
public works of the browser which you
all know where which only contains
a user in the password field and here
you can see the
fields i just talked about
the first one is
very important that you see the same url
as in the browser so that you know which
resource you are accessing
and
along with the user and password fields
that is re-entered for dots and you can
see the alias and the your domain fields
and in this login session i just used
conventional
login so i didn't need to use
alias and your domain and i think the
next slide shows the
uh
no no that is not tonight that that's it
i'm afraid
because i didn't include headed this is
over yeah sorry then i uh so i don't
have a picture which includes uh because
this is things i just talked about
headed uh
that are the features you can choose but
in uh
in a crossover situation which you can
you can see in the demo we have on our
we have sticks and we have also
uh
virtual machines on which you can see
all of this work and then you can see a
client domain aloha happens i forgot to
include that slide
and
that's my talk my first talk to to be
honest
[Applause]
thank you very much both of you um we do
have some time for questions and answers
so if you line up the microphones we
also
allow
a comp no provide the possibility to ask
questions uh through the interweb so
just a second i would like to check with
the signal angels do we have any
questions unfortunately not so good for
the gentleman in the first row uh please
ask a question
i have to actually uh so first of all um
do i understand correctly that you will
then use something like dns sec
to
set up trust with
parties that you do not know
yup all right a dns day ntls usually
all right
question number two is
so saml
obviously is not another way for cross
realm authentication is that something
that you compared with i think
some of the problems with the cecil
seems that you still are men in the
middle
which over complicates it a little bit i
think if you do samuel you completely
redirect and you just wait for the
answer yeah definitely
if you
log on to your email you have to use sas
home so that's why we have three
solutions because sometimes
a protocol says use kerberos use sass or
use whatever else
um saml can usually be
included in a protocol and among that is
there is a sample mechanism for sasha
so give an http cell so you could
actually put saml in there but i know it
has an embedding in http already so
that's senseless
unless you want to give the client a
choice and i think that's valuable
two questions line up at the end and ask
a third question thank you next question
please
so thanks for the talk in your example
you said like we can
give the authentication to
the local provider
which may up the
security of the of the user
but what if the local provider actually
decreases
the security of the user so the
the the the web shop of whatever is in
the middle
actually
doesn't want to provide
your
local
authentication
party
because it's less secure than what they
can offer themselves is there something
there
in the protocol
you split my brain by using another term
and i'm not wondering whether you mean
left or right
are you talking about local
authentication as in the quick diocesal
receiving note that passes it over free
diameter or are you talking about the
identity provider that received the free
diameter request okay let me give an
example like if i log into my bank i
need to fill in my my my username
password and then to affair for instance
but what if my local provider only uses
like
username and password so my bank would
actually say no you cannot use your
local provider because it's less secure
than what we can offer your bank
wouldn't know
your bank would only see who as whom you
logged on and you are in control of the
security of your bank account
i have an advice for you to do it well
this by the way is very much what banks
like because they are not interested in
security they are interested in covering
their ass
true
and you're interested in getting the
best security probably better than you
sorry
if it's it's it's it evolving into a
dialogue let me cut this off here for a
second
feel free to come back um or
continue this in the park there's
another question lined up so please um
hi uh thanks um i have a question that's
sort of usability related do you have
any ideas on how to guide a user into
which authentication method they should
choose
because choosing
digest md5 i mean iu and he understands
that my mob doesn't no but your mom
probably has a system administrator who
insists on particular practices
not really
of course we would like to address
we would like to encourage the user to
use crossover when as it goes over
whenever possible because then you can
use that is the only protocol currently
which uses your own identity provider
and all the other protocols are
a normal stock speaker that the
authentication takes in place in the
same domain as the server yeah but i you
are i think also making the point that
um if you give people more freedom to
choose they might shoot themselves the
foot
and it's also if you take email as an
example you don't usually configure in
your email client which specific
uh authentication method you would like
to use your email client sort of chooses
one that's sort of absolutely to some
degree you do
because it's sassel and you do say stuff
that you won't allow over uh
plain text connections for example
um
yeah but there are ways of setting these
things and
given that you have one
option available or three and you
basically what sasel does it matches the
overlap between the server offering and
the client
ability
and finds a good one maybe the best one
but if you're willing to accept all
three options then it might choose any
um
so yeah you would want to control this
to some degree
thank you
thanks i see a discussion group forming
at the bar after the talk yeah yeah yeah
we might get drunk if we don't before we
get to the next question on the mic are
there any questions on the interwebs for
the speakers
hero signal task any questions
nope i see i see shaking heads so please
go ahead uh a very practical question
you mentioned the apache web server you
mentioned firefox
obviously there's no reason it couldn't
work for other browsers other web
servers right
sorry um there is an engineering
implementation
like i can answer the question uh
currently
there was some kind of standard
being built for all browsers and
currently you know where there are only
two real ones left editor reality's home
and home contest safari currently even
internet explorer and of course home
home itself is
the one engine and only
a real
other engine is still firefox
and uh in principle it
would have been possible to implement
this on home as well
but there's one uh
addition which firefox added to the
native maker
native messaging
which involves that
you can intercept http request
and then
the
firefox multiple ring can wait
in the form of a so-called javascript
promise
for the answer of the external program
on
on a request
and unfortunately uh firefox is only
part of who implemented that
and uh up to now
i mean it is a standard there's no
reason why others couldn't yeah but
there's no current use case we define a
use case so we hope you've
otherwise i couldn't uh create a demo
which i created
for have for this
not only crossover but on the entire
http social and external program
we really wanted to pull credentials
away from the browser i somehow feel
iffy when i need the same environment
for looking adverse advertisements and
logging onto my bank so you want your
credentials outside the browser and
underneath the application so in the
http layer these were very deliberate
choices you could of course implement
this entirely in javascript but then you
wouldn't have access to kerberos for
example unless you build entire kerberos
in javascript which might be a bit of a
security problem
did we answer your question yes thank
you very much
long answer but a good one thank you
very much for that we have yes please
um
a couple of quick ones uh i was
wondering about replay attacks i didn't
see any any uh binding into crypto
protocols in here or did i dismiss it i
couldn't read all of the slides from any
decently designed protocol
you have an explicit connection that
wraps everything that goes on
http made the choice to have independent
packets
that have no notion of connection no
identity to link them
and you can send others in other
connection that is a big problem
and that
we managed to get the secure
but the replay attack answer because of
this design usually is use https
i'm sorry the web doesn't have a better
answer so we don't either
yeah um
so that's actually why um some of the
newer authentication protocols
tie the
um the https parameters into the
authentication um it's it's called
universal second factor utf and but
anyway yeah yeah in cessal terms it will
be channel binding and we do that yeah i
i
i can elaborate a little bit on the
implementation of crossover in http
shuttle
at though acp itself is stateless
introduced as
a server-to-server token in the in the
http headers
and uh
those
the implementation of crossover in
diameter contains the so-called session
id
which
will be
disposed by the diameter
when the
session is complete
and so when you then try to replay that
if i'm correct the diameter won't accept
it because that session id is no longer
valid
okay
i want to that is the
s2s
headers in our most of our current
implementations is not
the real state of the of the of the
server but only and
in the industry say indirect
that is the session id of a diameter
session
but not a
state which uh uh
authentication is currently in because
then you are totally correct when you do
that i even made a proof of concept of
that because we would like to have the
uh
headers that have for normal protocols
the http server to be stateless but then
then you can very clearly see the the
indeed the risk of a replay attack
because of course that succeeds here
because then you don't have the
challenge response system anymore
because you have all the state it
doesn't matter whether the state is
encrypted or not you have all the state
into the s2s and then you can just
replay the last
to speak
to the you can replay that and then
you're immediately locked in
that is that is indeed a quite a big
problem every uh happy i found out and
together with uh
some guy
called steph which is really involved in
this project who pointed that out as i
posted to use it on his photo calling
came up with it
and the only way
perhaps we have to investigate it
further but the only way to circumvent
it is indeed using uh a secure protocol
such as http but he's right it is not a
complete answer to replay attacks um and
i do have to move that conversation over
to the bar because unfortunately out of
time i'm very sorry for that so please
keep another last warm round of applause
for rick and henry
you