[Music]
i want to tell you a little bit about
dna and
hacking the dna because like oscar
already said it's surprisingly digital
which also makes it sort of our thing
in a way
and part of hacking dna the way
professionals do it is remarkably
using words like that we know like
there's even a thing called shell code
in there
which is just like the shell codes that
we know
so i'm going to start off very briefly
by thanking all the people that made all
the nice pictures that i
lovingly borrowed for this presentation
if you go to the url you can see the
credits exactly who made them
oskar already introduced me so i'm not
originally a biologist but i started
studying dna in 2001
and over time apparently i managed to
fool some people
that i'm a real biologist so i was
allowed to do some research in delft
university
and um
and some of you may know me from a
presentation on the sarskoff ii vaccines
which was read by
1.7 million people
it's an interesting thing that means
that a lot of people really really care
but i've never written anything that was
read by 1.7 million people so
apparently we want to know about this
dna stuff
i also managed to fool some magazines
into publishing my research
but but it's for real and it's sort of a
joke i fooled them now this is real
research and it turns out that if you
are
thinking like a reverse engineer if you
are thinking about big data sets you can
go to dna
and invent stuff that other people have
not seen before
so and you you could do that if you had
oodles of free time
but then you could do that
so i'm going to talk about
manipulating dna but i want to make it
very clear that i'm talking here about
the technology i'm telling how it works
i'm not here to tell you hey you should
all go out and hack your dna or your
dog's dna or your
partner's dna dough don't do it and i'm
also here to pour a little rain on the
parade where you might have gotten the
impression that we have crispr now and
you can just crisper dna in any way you
want and it will do what you want and
no it doesn't
so
that was the bad news the good news is
that some really cool things really are
happening but we are not about to be in
a place that
you could modify and modify my dna and i
would become thin
you could however modify my dna and i
would be dead
that's entirely possible
let's not go there
so dna
millions or billions of nucleotides or
bases
so we we all exist
contain around 3.3 billion bases of dna
that's what we always thought later we
found out that some people have like six
percent more dna than other people
there's a lot more variation between us
than we thought this is relatively
recent discovery
and while our binary stuff is zero and
one
in dna we have four molecules and we
call them a c g and d and these are
organized in chromosomes and cream genes
and what blows my mind and it should
blow your mind as well and if it doesn't
blow your mind i will give you free beer
we have four billion years of life
and it is all using atom for atom the
same dna
now when i look back at my presentation
five years ago
i already could not read some of the
files i had made because by the time the
software had changed
this is four billion year old code
and it's still using the same molecules
if that doesn't excite you i don't know
what will
so there are some more analogies we have
dna
dna is like super stable
we sometimes can dig up neanderthals or
other ancient
organisms like a hundred thousand years
ago and we can still read their dna i
cannot read the cd-rom from 10 years ago
um which contains less information
so that is like super super solid stuff
but it's so solid that like a cd-rom it
doesn't do anything by itself so there's
rna which is a far more active form of
dna but it degrades in days or hours
and from rna we build proteins
we are all proteins we are a room full
of proteins our skin our proteins our
hair uh our nails etc so we are built
out of proteins but the proteins also do
stuff
that's really the doing things of life
the components of life and these are
made out of amino acids which are like a
little lego blocks
and you put them together and you get a
protein
so how much dna is there
and this is a sort of impressive list we
have viruses like that are 800 bytes
these are true artists
there's 800 bytes that can make you
really ill and unhappy
and and then of course there is the
famous one sarskoff ii 7.4 kilobytes in
the room with us right now
i'll almost guarantee it to you 7.4
kilobytes it costs a little bit of
disruption
um
then we go up to a bacterium 750
kilobytes which is sort of doable you
can read the bacterium and people
actually sort of go through all of the
dna for bacterium and learn stuff and
we'll also do that later on
and a typical human being is 750
megabytes
and that goes for everyone even if you
are larger it's still 750 megabytes of
unique dna
so how do we go from dna to these
proteins that build us
and that's this little machine this is
the world's most impressive 3d printer
this is the ribosome
and you see this chain that goes in that
says
that's not really that way and that goes
through
and that assembles the yellow
things that attract the purple or pink
amino acids that make these proteins
biologists are sometimes very strange
people when the protein is small they
call it the peptide
and no one knows when it becomes a
protein
this is how they roll
and
they love messing with you i'll get
some more examples of that so this
little machine is a 3d printer or
actually it's a 1d printer because it
takes this ribbon of rna
and turns it into a ribbon of amino
acids and then interestingly this ribbon
self-assembles and folds itself up into
all kinds of interesting shapes
there was a lovely movie here ah there
is a lovely movie here that you can see
but i cannot
let's see if i can make it play
yes it works but this is the same thing
in black you see this rna chain going
through the machine
and all these things fly in and out they
bring the amino acids and you see that
gray thing coming up there and that is
the amino the amino acids being
assembled into a peptide or a protein
and this just goes on and on and if you
watch this presentation at home it goes
on for multiple more minutes because all
kinds of cool things so now the thing
flies in
let's see does it come
ah
well it's taking its time
okay you should just watch this at home
you go whoop what it just goes on and on
and this happens within you right now
even as we speak
billions of proteins are being assembled
now
how do we know
how does the thing know
yeah is it working yeah it's working
this is the instructions
for an important protein and it actually
fits on one screen
and
and when this is made
and then another protein is also made
and if you want to impress biologists a
protein always starts with an m so if
you ever see one that doesn't start with
an m you can say like you're wrong mr
biologist it's this little trick
so here's another protein it's a bit
smaller and when these two assemble they
combine into one of the most impressive
materials known to man i have it here
for you
human skin
which if you think about this is a
really impressive piece of technology
can stand water it doesn't tear it
disinfects itself
and the source code for a key part of
that is on these two screens
continues to blow me away
so
this is a table of the op codes
of an ancient cpu
this tells you if you put these bytes
into this cpu it will do the following
things
if you look at this table
you can already see that some thoughts
went into that so there are all
columns that are empty where the
designers were probably planning to do
new things but they left space
and in some places they left a little
bit of room in between so you can see
some sort of structure in there if you
study this you might understand
something about the people that made the
6502 cpu
we have this
2300 year old rock
and on this are
is one
boring document written in two scripts
of egyptian and ancient greek
and because it's the same document three
times this stone helps us understand how
language developed
maybe three thousand years ago 2300
years ago it's a very impressive rock
this is the table that does dna and
amino acids and it's 4 billion years old
this is a lot cooler than the rock
if you stare at this thing
the more you learn about this table so
we see for example that uh cgg maps to
argonine
and you have these other few things
there are t a a t a g and tga map to
stop codons that means the protein ends
here stop whatever you were doing you're
done
there are three of them
probably very important
the more you stare at this table the
more you start to see structure in there
and some people are really convinced
that someone designed this table
i don't think it was designed by someone
but still
the more i look at this table the more
sort of impressive it becomes
how do we know that it's 4 billion years
old
we can actually trace the evolution of
life we now think that it started in
these sort of black smokers or some
something close to that
but we know from the way this split up
that the code has not changed for at
least 2 billion years and probably
longer
i find that impressive
now finally we're going to talk about
hacking the genome and editing dna
why would you even do it because if you
mess with it you might make worse
well first there are people walking
around and they have terrible diseases
probably some of you in the room have
that and you would like
to have that fixed
and sometimes we just know there's this
little bit of dna that's wrong
if only we could change one thing your
life would be a lot better
but we also have people walking around
with unfavorable dna that we know that
you are at risk or maybe at risk of
severe disease later in life you might
not want to be at risk of severe disease
disease later in life
the other way we manipulate dna
is to get bacteria to work for us for
free there are our angels that way
and
we haven't got these bacteria to make
vaccines hormones and medicines for us
all the sarcophagus ii vaccines that we
got against corona
almost all of them came out of bacteria
which is very nice of them because
usually we associate bacteria with bad
things happening this is one of the good
things happening
we might one day also convince bacteria
to fixate
carbon dioxide for us which would be
really nice because they can do that
kind of thing if only we could tell them
that they should do it and maybe one day
they'll listen
we also can manipulate dna to
instruct our immune system to fix cancer
is nice
and finally that's the part where it's
going to be very active you could also
win the tour de france
if you want to modify your own dna and
there are also going to be people that
need bigger body parts and would like to
manipulate their dna
and it's probably going to be happening
don't do it
so what could go wrong with dna
sometimes there's just a typo in there
one thing changed it's just one letter
should be a c it's a g and that could
already disable a whole gene
or
it could the gene could still work but
now do the wrong thing
the other thing that sometimes happens
is there are people that come from
regions where there was lots of malaria
and they have dna that protects them
against malaria which is nice
that dna might also give you a blood
disease which is not nice
but it was a good trade-off when these
people lived in or their forebears lived
in countries with a lot of malaria
one of the most terrible things that we
recognize as computing people is let's
say you have a serial connection serial
connection
and you miss one bit
and everything now shifts one bit
that means that it becomes
unintelligible nothing useful ever comes
out again
dna has the same
issue because it takes three dna letters
to make one amino acid if you take away
one amino acid
all sorry one dna letter all the amino
acids now shift and they all become
wrong this is very bad
and sometimes you just get a mutation
that means that the gene stops in the
middle which is not good because you
were attached you also wanted the rest
of it to work
so how long have we been
working with
modifying genomes
it turns out we've been doing this for
thousands and thousands of years already
which was not what you might be
expecting
and for example this this wonderful wolf
entered our lives
and
that thing downstairs is still
substantially a wolf
it's actually 99.9 wolf
i did not improve
i think
but we were able to do this because
there was enough genetic variation in
the wolf
that if you just sort all the sort of
good bits or the the
bad bits from the wolf
you end up with that thing so that's not
changing dna it's just moving it around
the same thing we see all these lovely
and healthy vegetables on the right
these are all one plant
so
the brussels sprouts and the kale and
the broccoli and the cauliflower are all
one plant
except someone bred it to emphasize
different parts of the plant but this is
if you have a dna sequencer at home
which i do
you could sequence your brussels sprouts
and they would look look just like
broccoli
so
this stuff all happened
thousands of years ago and it did not
require any special laboratory stuff it
just required sorting the variation that
existed
between the majestic wolf
so you take the smallest wolf from the
litter you take the nicest wolf from the
litter and in the end well you end up
with that
and um
there's a lot of variation
in here and i'm going to skip a few
slides but this is a real picture and
that sort of embodies the
genetic variation
within cows it is a real picture but it
must be said that the smaller ones are
all female cows and the big one is a
steer but still it's a very big cow
and uh and this is just not manipulating
dna just moving it around
skip this one as well
[Music]
actually so when people were breeding
plants sometimes there was not enough
genetic variation in the plant to make
an interesting plant people were bored
they had lots of time and no regulation
and at some point someone figured out
that if you just put some radioactivity
next to a plant
it will mutate
and this creates some lovely flowers and
this has been done for for decades
already and i think there are like 2 000
different plant species that were just
generated by putting radiation into them
and hoping that the plant would become
better
and uh
it works don't do this on people
um
they don't like it
so this was like
extra super super special
diabetic people people with diabetes
many of them need insulin
and the insulin hormone is a very small
protein it should be simple to make and
we cannot do it it's very interesting we
cannot do it we need to get
animals to do it for us
before 1979 or even before 1995 if you
wanted to make insulin you had to
slaughter hundreds of thousands of cows
and pigs
to get a tiny bit of insulin from them
which was wasteful and smelly and it was
not good
and they didn't like it and
ridiculously early these people
before they could even read dna they had
figured out how they could make the dna
that creates protein
and put it in bacteria
and these bacteria then said oh well we
still speak the language after 4 billion
billion years we understand your dna
humans we are now going to make insulin
for you
at first they only made a little bit of
insulin until they understood that
bacteria do speak the same dna but they
have a different dialect
and by that i don't mean they speak a
different language just they use
different synonyms so where
animal dna uses a lot of gcc as a codon
maybe the animals of the bacteria use a
different one
and in a ridiculously short amount of
time they could stop slaughtering these
hundreds of thousands of animals and now
insulin gets made by bacteria and
sometimes by yeast
it's like very impressive but how do you
do that how do you get the bacterium to
take your dna
and listen to it
it turns out
bacteria also have sex
so it's
nasty enough to know already that we are
sort of inhabited by bacteria but
they're also
doing things with their pelas
and um
and and
this means that if you get a bacterium
in the right mood it will just suck up
dna from the environment
and you are not going to believe this
but i swear it is true
with one of the most used bacteria for
this kind of stuff one way of getting
them in the mood
is to feed them alcohol
it really is true
the biologists continue to mess with you
once they have found a bacterium that is
willing to take up dna from the
environment by feeding it alcohol for
example they call it competent
which is not what happens to me when you
feed me alcohol but anyhow
you give there are other ways to get
them but this is one of the prime ways
to give them ethanol and they suck up
dna from the environment and they think
like hey let's do this stuff
okay so that's very nice because these
things make hormones for us medicines
vaccines so thank you
adding dna to humans because we'd love
to hear about human beings how can we
fix our dna how can we improve our dna
and the thing is there are lots of
viruses around that already want to
improve our dna
and we do not want that
we are against that so our dna is very
well protected has lots of defenses
against people messing with it but there
are a few viruses that can do it
and one of the most famous one is hiv
the one that gives you aids
it's like really good at inserting stuff
in our dna
and so they started making medicines and
stuff with that but people were like are
you injecting aids into me
so they now call them lentivirus
which is the same thing
but it sounds a lot better so if someone
says this is a lentiviral based approach
you're like that's aids right
but but still of course they took out
all the scary bits and stuff so it works
but um but still what this does is you
take some dna that you want to insert
into a human being you put it into this
lentivirus and that then goes to your
genome and puts its stuff
somewhere
that's a bit of a problem
there are other viruses that do it
slightly smarter there's a
mysterious adino associated vector that
we don't really understand why it exists
at all but is a virus that takes a
little bit of dna and just leaves it in
the nucleus doesn't insert it just
leaves it there which is like very nice
and
and then another way of doing it that
was very disappointing to people they
said it's going to be like super hard to
get dna into a human cell
and to integrate it and someone said can
we try a really small injection needle
no it's not going to work
okay it does work
and um so this is
that that works as the way you think it
works just
someone with really good eyesight and
and it works but the problem is that
person can only do one cell at a time
and um
to improve that they also these these
biologists they cracked me up they they
made a gun a dna gun
and they and and they put little gold
balls in there coated with dna and go
and it's called biolystics
and um
so that helps because that can do like
like dozens of cells at the time
but the problem is we we need to do a
lot more than that and the challenge we
have there it looks a little bit like
this these are so-called phone books
there were massive data leaks when when
sort of
telephone companies would print
everyone's phone numbers in there
and you can see this is a lot i estimate
that each of these books contains around
200 megabytes of information which is
slightly less than the human being but
the challenge of editing human dna is
that you must search and replace
through these books and through all of
them
and you can see that it's going to be
real work
nevertheless we can do it
um sickle cell disease this is the one i
mentioned that if you have
this makes you almost immune against
malaria but can give you very nasty
blood disease and make make you
extremely unhappy
and this is now
i almost yeah i think this is fixed i
think we got this we got the solution
for it now
but the reason why it works is you
this is a rare case where you can take
cells from your blood out of the body
into the lab in the lab they infected
those cells with viruses they check it
everything went right
then they make a lot more of these cells
then you go back to the patient
remove those cells from the patient
that's the scary part for a bit
and then you put the fixed cells back in
and
it works
it works tremendously well it's also
tremendously hard work
but it uses one of these lentiviruses
and we know what that is
to insert a fixed gene and it mostly
gets inserted in the right place
mostly that's the sort of scary part so
how well does this work
these are on the left are people before
the treatment and every red
block there is a severe event where they
had to visit the hospital because their
sickle cell disease
got them
bad enough that they had to go to the
hospital and in yellow is the people
that have been treated and there are no
red markers there anymore now i have to
warn you you will read a lot about
successful gene therapy and most of the
successes are not that successful
most of the news is hyped up
this is for real
this is 100 score
maybe the light for five percent is
that's okay but this is an extremely
impressive result where we were able to
just insert an improved gene and improve
people's life tremendously
this one is also very impressive cancer
we hate it
cancer
the way cancer survives is that it hides
from our immune system if our immune
system could recognize the cancer cells
it would get rid of them
what we can do with gene therapy is
educate some of our immune cells and say
look this is what you should be doing
pseudo kill the cancer cell
and it actually does that
and
this is not as successful
as as this slide so we're not in this
territory yet and it doesn't work for
all cancers but when it works it's like
tremendously impressive and it worked
because we were able to tell an immune
cell here are your dna instructions this
is what you should look for
it's amazing
i'm going to skip this one because we
mentioned it already except for the last
paragraph this is a virus by which we
can insert a tiny ring of dna into a
cell it's very helpful from this virus
the biggest challenge is it's like
really tiny
that means that only a very small
payload fits in there that means if you
want to exploit it if you want to put
some shell code in there it has to be
like super super brief
finally crispr who here has heard about
crispr
yeah well it is nice it really is nice
because it allows me to show you this
picture
this is a bacterial virus called a phage
that's for real they really look like
this people are like is this an artist
impression
well the color is an artist's impression
i have to admit that otherwise this
bacterial virus actually looks like this
and to prove that on the right there is
a photo
it actually does look like that and how
does a thing like this operate in the
head there is a bunch of dna
and then it does what you think it does
it goes sits on the bacterium and then
drills down injects the dna so
it really does that and bacteria they
hate it
they really don't like that
and and they want to put a stop to it
so
many bacteria
have specific enzymes that recognize
specific dna sequences and when they say
when i see that dna sequence
i'm going to kill it
which is somewhat of a problem because
that means that the bacterium itself
should not have that dna sequence
because otherwise it would kill itself
if you do a simple statistical analysis
on any bacterium you find that they are
actively avoiding
some sequences because they know it will
kill them
so and by the way i this is my own
invention and and this you can do this
as well if you download dna from a
bacterium and you go hunt for rare
sequences you will find stuff and much
of that stuff is not really known in the
literature because they are not big
computer geeks over at biology
and we are
now crispr
and this is crispr has been around for
ages it has been around for billions of
years but we knew about it for a very
long time already
and the biologists and i love them by
the way i just want to clarify that but
they turned out their understanding was
exactly the wrong way around
because we knew that crispr was there we
could see it in bacteria but we didn't
know what it was doing
and what it looks like is you have
bits of yellow repeating dna they're not
yellow in real life but
repeating bits of dna with some random
stuff in between which they called
spacers
and everyone was really interested in
what are these yellow things doing and
and these spaces
it turns out the spacers
are
the immune system of the bacterium
these spacers
they have in be between them copies of
small parts
of the dna
from
the viruses that attack them
so in the dna there's an instruction
if you see
the following dna kill it
and this can evolve it can learn from
new phages
but the risk of course is if you have
this instruction if you see this dna
kill it
is that you start killing yourself
which is like a virus scanner that
detects itself because it's full of bad
stuff
and nature has been clever about this
it always adds a few dna letters before
the killing sequence
without actively mentioning them
this is how the bacterium
prevents itself from killing itself
it's like really nice
so what does crispr actually do and i'm
gonna skip a few slides but i'm
the key thing is you may think crispr is
a thing that edits dna that's probably
is that is that what your impression was
i think crispr yeah i think so as well
it doesn't it breaks dna
the only thing it does it breaks dna
that's what it does
so if you think like hey i'm going to
edit my genes with dna it's a bit like
i'm going to edit my genes with dynamite
i'm going to tear them apart
and the trick that we do
is we make the dna kill itself and
crispr
and then it's like really broken
and when it happens we also inject
sort of suggestion to the cell why don't
you fix it like this
and then the cell because it's like
super broken sometimes takes up our
suggestion and fixes itself so that's
really nice but if anyone tells you that
crispr is there to manipulate dna crispr
is only there to break dna
so
the hype around crispr
if you hear from california where people
are ready to crisper yourself into
health
we're not there yet we're not there in a
long
way
but in a lab it does work so you can do
many things with it in a lab
but you cannot just shoot the crisper
cannon at someone and hope that it
changes all your dna
and in fact when you do that if you
deliver
a crisper
payload if you inject it or whatever
your body goes like oh we need to break
this down
send it to the
liver which means that the liver is the
only place that we can really crisper
right now now it's a good thing that the
liver is one of your top 10 organs so it
is good news that we can add it there
but that's the only thing we can do with
it so it is not as hot as you would
think
now
more doom
do we understand how dna really powers
life
because if you're going to change it
it's best if you knew what it was doing
and sometimes we do and i really like
this one this is an important algorithm
should i go to the kitchen
i should go to the kitchen if i'm hungry
and if there is food there
that's an important human algorithm you
shouldn't go to the kitchen if you're
not hungry and you should also not go
there if there's no food
and in expressed in a sort of c like
language
if i'm hungry and there's food in the
kitchen go to the kitchen
we find this exact algorithm in bacteria
this is a piece of dna and if we are
hungry if the bacterium is hungry that
cap thing attaches to the dna
and it says can you please make this
protein
but that's only the first condition am i
hungry
the other condition is there actually
something we can do about the hunger
and that's when there is lactose around
if there is lactose around
then the bacteria says okay i'm hungry
there's lactose i'm going to convert
glucose
i'm gonna make glucose from the lactose
we understand this one really well
that's because bacteria are nice
bacteria are simple bacteria are like
these tiny computer programs that we all
rely on
human beings are these giant blocks of
java enterprise
and we have no idea what they're doing
[Applause]
we're all made out of java people and i
want to give you a real example
when we started to look at well when we
when the human genome was first
sequenced we thought we would find a
list of all diseases in there
so this is the gene that makes you fat
this is the gene that makes you smart
it works nothing like that and one of
the first things people try to figure
out is well what causes blue eyes
because it's a very simple thing to test
you can just look at someone do you have
blue eyes and then you can look at their
dna and see can i find in the dna what
gives you blue eyes or not
and lo we found it
we found a very powerful
mutation and it gives you blue eyes
so where is this mutation is it in a
gene that has anything to do with ice
no it is in the haircut2 gene which is
involved with dna repair
so there is a mistake or a change in the
haircut2 gene
and that gives you a different eye color
which makes no sense at all
then we found out that if you make this
small change in the haircut ii gene
the oka 2 gene becomes less active
well thanks for that
um
it's like yeah i only changed this
little thing and now the whole stack is
down i don't know why
but anyhow this tiny change in hair ii
suppresses the ochre two gene
what does the oca2 gene do well
it makes the p protein
what does the p protein do
we don't know
something something with color
it also changes some other things in
your life
in the color but we don't really know
so that means that this is our level of
understanding and this is actually one
of the best studied
mutations we have because it's one of
the first one that was discovered and it
is caused by a mutation in an unrelated
gene that suppresses a gene that we
don't really know what it does but it
gives you blue eyes
so be careful when you tinker with dna
strange things might happen
because this is the other pie chart
that tells us what is all the dna doing
and the red part the tiny part over
there that's the part that we are
reasonably sure what it's doing
and then there is stuff
and a lot of this stuff can be compared
to if you have an old computer project
and you have lots of files around and
you change it a few times there are now
three directories called misc
and um
and there's actually once once we
revamped it all but we didn't finish it
but we left the files around because
they might be useful later on
that's a lot of what you see in dna
a lot of the other parts you see in dna
so all kinds of viruses that have
successfully infected the dna have
meanwhile been killed but
yeah it's just we still keep it around
for some reason
there are a few plants that have cleaned
up their whole genomes and kicked out
everything that wasn't immediately
useful and we have very much not done so
but it turns out that these parts are
important
because if there are changes in there it
turns out that we do change
for example the the blue eye gene is
actually in a part of a haircut ii that
actually doesn't do anything
but it does change your eye color
the future
will you hack a genome and will it be
yours
um
is it loading yeah this is stuff you can
buy online this is the bento lab on the
left it's really nice
mini pcr on the right
this is pocket pcr this usb powered pcr
machine you know from the dna tests
you can just buy it and it's super fun i
have all of these things and i've done
my first dna experiments at home
and i'm not even good at this kind of
stuff
but i was able to just detect dna and
and and see what was in there and it
works
and you can just order this stuff online
it's still somewhat special but
the machine on the right
is actually a dna sequencer that will
read dna
and it is actually this big
and
i pondered bringing it but then i
thought about how stuff breaks on
campsites so i didn't bring it but you
can buy that thing and read dna in your
own house
if you want to order dna you can go to
this site eurofins you can just paste
the dna in there and click order
and then they send it to you and then
the billing process is extremely
complicated
i don't know why but the ordering of the
dna is rather easy
this is you can buy this thing crisp at
home
and it's meant for crispring plants so
you can do some experiments with that
stuff
but you can order this and
and do it
so it is coming closer to our world
um but don't do it because it will
likely kill you
or give you cancer so i'll just i want
to as a disclaimer
you can order this stuff but don't do it
there are some people however that are
willing to take risks
and many of them are in the tour de
france
and um and there are a bunch of genetic
modifications that you could make to
your red blood cells that might very
well improve your cycling performance
and i think that these people
also looked at this page like well you
know
if i don't win the next stage then
what's what worth what's my life worth
anyhow
so but the only way you're going to
figure that out is you if you actually
sequence the dna from a tour de france
cyclist and see that they changed
and you're like hey you have new dna now
so
weird
some predictions
like i said you might get the impression
that we can just simply crisper your
hair color
soon and probably not
but the stuff from the sickle cell
disease and this pseudo killer cancer
cell stuff that is going extremely fast
right now and that spent like 10 years
in the lab but it's now coming out of
the lab and actually curing people so
you'll be hearing a lot more about that
and but we will continue to focus on
terrible disease because we're not quite
ready yet to modify someone's dna so
that they get a bigger
nose or whatever
in the future
you might get you might enter the
territory that people say we can change
your dna because it will lower your risk
of future disease
and that might be something that is
worth it for for some people but this is
already like 10 years in the future
and um
[Music]
but the thing is so these are
developments for like the next 10 years
but i'm a bit worried about the lower
line because this technology is now so
widely known
uh there might be people not only tour
de france people or just people with
very scary diseases that have hope
and of course the hope is
we want to give people hope but
it is now easy enough to to mess up
uh your dna
so summary we can make bacteria sing and
dance for us if we give them a little
bit of alcohol
and uh and they make things for us which
is nice we can fix dna cells in the lab
and that has saved the lives of many
people now because i could not even
address all the ways in which this has
worked
it is a lot harder to fix
a living human being
but there are viruses that are willing
to help and it might well be that in the
future we find a virus that is precise
enough that will deliver a fixed gene in
the right place because right now it
delivers it somewhere
we understand very little about what
most of dna does
and we should be very careful tinkering
with that and the final line is really
your digital skills
are really welcome in this field
so
if you study dna it is entirely possible
as an outsider with only a few years of
hard work
uh to actually discover something that
other people haven't seen because we are
not scared of like hundreds of gigabytes
of dna and uh and we have a reverse
engineering mindset
uh that can very well be helpful
and with that i would like to end my
presentation and thank you for your
wrapped attention
me
[Applause]
excellent are there is even time for
questions are there questions
there are microphones in the middle and
i can't really see if there is anybody
there
[Music]
and otherwise if there are no questions
please please if you have a question
please walk to the microphone yes
microphone one
not working
i think two plants or something or three
in the plant it has gigabytes of
can you please perhaps even move up
because on the stream we won't have any
audio
can you there's another microphone in
the back
that one does work yeah
yeah so in the presentation at some
point you showed there were two uh life
forms with
one of them having three 33 gigabytes
yeah
you just crossed it
yeah there the bottom two ones yeah and
i was interested to find out why
why so much
that's an extremely good question and uh
for the marbled lungfish people are not
actually sure if it's only one fish
it might be actually two fishes with one
genome
we're not really sure uh but the other
thing is that
there is a theory that says that the
more dna you have
the more variation you can harvest
which means that you could see and this
is an information theoretical approach
that you can see dna as an antenna for
harvesting potential information about
improvements
and in a way it might be good to have a
lot of dna
um
it might also be
accidents history biology is full of
weird accidents and
it is not unique so it's not 33
gigabytes of unique dna it's lots of
copies of the same dna
but the honest answer is we don't know
thanks and thanks for the great
presentation
there's a lineup yes next
so hi uh so you're saying that we can
help right and so in what specific ways
would software engineering skills be
useful like what specific things so i
can give you a very nice example of that
um
there are sometimes that biologists they
do
research on five bacteria and they
report well in these five bacteria
the following restricted sequences are
present and we write a whole paper about
these five bacteria
and you can read that paper
you can go to the website of the ncbi
which is the us agency that gathers all
these genomes
and repeat the analysis not on five
bacteria but in 32 000 of them
and we can do that because we know how
computers work and if we want to rent a
big one we rent a big one and suddenly
you just amplified their work by a
factor of thousands and probably find
lots of cases where their hypothesis is
correct but it is not correct and this
is simply a matter of scaling up work
that was very difficult for those people
and that could be easy for you and then
you would maybe learn something about
bacteria that before that we just didn't
know
thank you
hello sorry i missed most of the of your
photograph
but
i'm imagining that
when we managed to
manage the climate crisis afterwards we
should take care about plutonium and
collecting it
so and i imagine that we could create
creatures or a food chain that would
partially
eat plutonium and collect it and that
way
collect it so we can harvest it and put
it together in one place whatever and
treat it somewhat some way which we have
to invent
um what's your thought about it is this
is a scary scary thought for you
that we could one day um create a
creatures or even food chain
for this specific um
um eindhoven
yeah
so the question i think is could this be
like really scary
and could we for example make a
bacterium that just eats plastic
which would be nice for the bacteria but
it would sort of suck for all our
plastic things
i think with plastic it would be very
different to
draw the barrier between plastic and
non-plastic things so this would be very
dangerous in my opinion i i think you're
right and we're still struggling with it
so the european union has really said
that you need to get permission to do
anything with gene so all this stuff i
just described there's a ton of
paperwork in the european union and not
in the us i'm not convinced that the
paperwork we are letting people do here
is even good enough to make sure that
nothing scary happens
but just to we could talk about this all
night but i'm pretty convinced that this
stuff could be like really scary
yes so don't do it so don't do it at
home
is there a last short question we have
only time for one i i hope it's short i
don't know um for your blue eye
example you said there is some junk dna
that normally does nothing yeah but in
this case it does
yeah so it obviously doesn't do nothing
yeah my question would be how do we even
determine which parts of the dna do
nothing yeah so we don't
there is one there's one answer to it we
can take a cell
and look at all the dna that is
currently being converted into rna which
means that it's active and then we check
if we can find that rna in the dna
and if we do you end up as one of the
red protein coding thing
or as the
well
no there's not it's not explicit here
but
we can only really know the stuff that
we see that is active and for the rest
we don't know what the influence is
so
and also i
i sure if i said that it did nothing
then i should not have said that it is
stuff that we don't immediately know
what it is for
this concludes
i think we have to conclude now because
of the time
thank you all yeah i'm around outside so
if you have more questions you can just
please please follow bad outside thank
him again for this great call
[Applause]
you