[Music]
then next up is introducing csert.global
if you love the internet we need your
help so the internet is in a downward
spiral and there's a community to help
that
and with me on stage is edward ryuz who
is the global chairman of c-3 and he
will now take the stage please give him
a round of applause
[Applause]
thank you very much
on this wonderful evening
i will make it quick tonight so thank
you very much for being here i want to
introduce you to csert.global
it is a new foundation and we want to
explain what we're doing why we're doing
it why we believe that this is an
important job and that we want to ask
you for help as well
so first let me introduce myself nicely
and i have been
on computer since 1985.
i was quite young back then so i only
see
64 back then my first pc in 1991
i fried my first main board shortly
after that and started working it in
1996. now this all is a tremendously
long time ago
but what this means for me is that i was
here in computer science and computer
security
since before the internet came about
and i love the internet you know the
reason why i'm here i believe is also
that i love the internet very very much
so from the 90s i worked for various
companies
and
i started actually doing volunteer work
at divd
in 2021
shortly after victor haefers one of the
founders of the ivd rss
asked me to start csr.global which is in
essence an organization
wanting to do the same things as the avd
does but then internationally tremendous
honor for me
how could i say no i didn't and i'm i'm
here today
what i want to talk to you about today
very simple story really is as much as i
love the internet the internet has a lot
of problems i think the internet is in
dire straits
a group of volunteers
many of them are here today
at the front row
hello and are trying to do something
about this and they are tremendously
successful and very proud and honored to
be working with them
um but there is a problem because many
times they not only do research and find
vulnerabilities
they even scan the entire internet and
find where those problems actually are
but is that enough that is often not
enough sadly
and this is where
csr.global comes in
we try to take those findings and take
them across the home straight
because only knowing where it is and
what the problem is is not enough you
need to find an owner for a problem
who's willing to solve it
because if you don't the problem is
still there
and that requires a lot of work and
that's what we we're here for
let me first start with what i believe
are the biggest problems on the internet
i believe we have ttl problems
and it's not the ttl you might know
it is different kind of ttl
the first t stands for tech
the internet
is created by nice old wonderful
scientists confused all scientists maybe
who built this solely on trust
and that is fantastic
but once there are people on that same
network that we don't trust
there's no technology to actively
counter that the internet
has been suffering
from that building on trust and that old
school technology ever
into the 2020s now we all know
the symptoms of this we know we all know
we run ipv4 when ipv6 is already
decades available
and hypothetically way more secure at
least much more difficult to scan
but we don't use it
and a lot of software that we use on the
internet is built by for-profit
organizations with managers and
deadlines
time crunches software supply chains are
a mess
even if you know what kind of software
you use you don't know what's in it etc
etc and this means
that for example at the end of june
when i checked the cve database there
were 22
292 of them in there
and
147 of them had a score of 9 or higher
which means we need to do something
essentially right now
so add this to the facts
that scanning the internet takes
motivated individual
about three hours nowadays
you know it's the internet is not that
big if you consider
and whenever something happens like
exchange vulnerabilities or whatever
more than a hundred individual groups
start scanning
and are in a red race both the good guys
and the bad guys
trying to out scan each other in order
to find the problems the bad buyers guys
want to misuse them the good guys
want to disclose them
so the internet has technology problems
the second problem i believe is there on
the internet is trust
there is either too much
or too little trust
but there are seldom the right amount of
trust
at the right time
and this is a problem too at least this
is a problem for us
so look at these three little
photographs i'm showing you here we have
google
we have solar cells
and we have a hacker defacing my website
back in
2007. who of these three you reckon
wanted to help me
and you're right
it's not the first two ones
the first two ones we know now
right there's a lot of trust by the
general public in all kinds
of technology big tech we all trust
google
we point our dns servers to 8888
we trust our solar suppliers and we
trust their app
as divd is just close
not always a
smart thing to do but how what what else
can you do
and as a matter of fact this third
gentleman that defaced my website back
in 2007
he left a little message where
he could be reached on jabber
so i did i contacted him
and it was a brazilian gentleman and he
told me what was going on he told me
that i had a vulnerability in my open
ssl implementation in my apache web
server
so it's sometimes not always obvious who
you trust or who you can trust
i understand that very well
but one thing that's absolutely true
they're seldom the right kind of trust
at the right time
in the right process
so trust is a big problem
and then the third ttl problem the l is
law
lawmakers
don't help us a lot
they are lagging by at least 10 years
and they're pretending like the internet
which is this big big
giant global community
is not
it's very difficult to geofence the
internet
but they still try to
and they're running their laws and
they're building their laws and they're
building their alliances
based on borders
and this is seldomly aligns well to
something as fluid and transparent as
the internet
big tech have now more power and
leverage than governments
and you can say well you know
why should i care well they are not they
don't have a seat in the united nations
maybe they should have but they don't
they make their decisions without a lot
of check and balance and these decisions
impact us
and coordinated vulnerability
disclosures there's so many of them it's
treated super different across all of
the globe
so
i pulled the news item from from the
internet this says the department of
justice
will no longer prosecute ethical hackers
who try to test security
what do you reckon is the date of this
new item
what do you think this is a u.s news
item
how old is it
five years ten years
how about
five weeks
only five weeks ago they proposed a law
where ethical hackers
could not be prosecuted
and this is how vastly different
ethical hacking and coordinated
vulnerability disclosure is treated all
over the world
and that means
if we want to scale this process
globally
we need to deal with different kinds of
laws and jurisdictions
and that means that someone is going to
need to do a heck of a lot of boring
work
but by golly
we need to do it
otherwise this global process will not
kick off
in essence no one is responsible many
organizations take
part of the responsibility
but no one is responsible there is no
one responsible for the internet
so
the only thing you can do is taking a
little bit of responsibility in areas
where you believe you can take a
difference
and in 2019
a group of dutch volunteers probably
don't need to know and tell you who they
are but they're the dutch institute of
volume vulnerability disclosure led by
victor haefers a wonderful other people
osgrid osborough
chris von trov and many others they do
fantastic work i'm very proud to
volunteer with them today
they do fantastic research their two
outstanding processes
i would say is research their capability
to find and feel what is making a
difference in technology today and dive
into it
like
the solar panels this is super super
relevant because in large parts of the
world
there is
a war going on which is impacting energy
consumption globally everyone wants to
dive into solar cells
but now we know that this isn't always
without risk for the end user
cassaya is another prime example of
where they felt something wasn't quite
right
they thought maybe those msps some of
them very small were using this software
to manage their many customers
gaining direct access to their customers
premises and doing all kinds of
administrative tasks
now of course when they found it was
very much
broken and there were a lot of leaks in
there
this was a huge huge thing
so they do fantastic research and
they're going to keep doing that
and globe caesar global's going to
benefit from that as well but the second
thing that they do very very well
they are one of those more than 100
organizations that scan the internet
within three hours after something is
happening
they not only scan but also the results
then get aggregated and run through an
inform process
so what they do essentially send abused
emails
and it is wonderful that they're doing
that they don't need to do that but they
do
because they're just wonderful people
they want to take responsibility
and they do it very very well
but informing can be very frustrating
which is why i created a little graph
for you
and this graph shows you the measured
response on for example i think with
exchange we sent something like 40 000
emails to abuse email addresses or
addresses we got out of the security.txt
and this is the measured response
about 1 in 200 emails
got a response saying oh wonderful thank
you so much
we love your work keep keep it going
another one in 200 said
go away you're trying to sell me
something or
i'll call my lawyer if you don't stop
hacking me
the other 99 percent silence
or bouncers
but that's how hard it is if you want to
automate
your warnings
which are fair and coming from a good
heart people should heed the warnings at
the same time they don't
so informing can be frustrating
and this is why we need to be global
because if people don't respond and they
don't act
on what we can
tell them the problem is still there the
internet's still vulnerable
speed is security and in order to be
more speedy we need to build two global
things the first is trust and the second
is an understanding of law
and acting
according to local ethics
and trust we believe we can build
with our chapter structure it's there to
respect and understand
and adapt to local culture
and we aim to build chapters wherever
they are needed
and allow for people to work
under the same principles the same code
of conduct
and the same values
as divd
but do it internationally within a
certain geographical
area
but we also need sector access because
every now and then taking a
vertical slice from a cake will yield
you way more surface instead of a
horizontal slice
so building bridges to sectors that need
us most
and finally we need to build relations
with people that can endorse us
we should not underestimate for example
how important it is
especially in the beginning when you got
a scanning email from divd
and people were asking
were these guys sending me all these
emails about hacking and all that kind
of stuff
when the government could tell them no
you can trust these people you know we
have absolutely
we have nothing to do with them but we
know them and you can trust them
so these endorsements and building this
trust and having someone who will vouch
for us
we need to find them as well
and in that way we can start filling in
the little
areas in the globe
so in readying for the future the divide
board
had a very uh forward-thinking plan and
they split up the initial foundation
into several foundations i think i'm
missing even two
i think i'm missing a club and i'm
missing um maybe another one but these
are essentially the or the new
foundations that are going to do it divd
will still be there
for the research and the scanning inform
process and csr.global
will be the organization responsible to
take it internationally
and then we have of course wonderful new
additions like the dvd academy and the
fund from where we can fund wonderful
new forward thinking projects
and within
are season.global so this is our
responsibility this is how building this
network works
so imagine there is a severe
vulnerability let's just say um it's
already out there it has a cv number
it's in the press whatever so
um first thing we do is we find if it's
scannable if it's scannable we do quick
research we create scripts and we start
scanning the entire ipv4 space that's
done pretty fast because there's only
4.29
billion
ip addresses which is not a lot really
not with our infrastructure
and then we try to map the results where
we get positive ones to automated emails
these emails then as we can see in the
graph are ignored
right and this is where caesar global
comes in we take the extra effort
we geographically
we send it to our chapter structure to
start spreading it locally
in individual geographical regions
and we take it through our partnerships
into different sectors for example
um could be we have been making friends
with the msp space
we have been making friends with the ngo
space
um and these affected parties then may
even call their search
their local source saying hey who are
these guys and they will then tell them
how you can trust cesaro global these
are good people you can trust their work
then more vulnerabilities are mitigated
and faster as well
this is the essentially the design
that we want to do
and it will make sure
that the giant
giant checkerboard that we're trying to
fill is the world relevant to ipv4 space
with chapters
and with sectors
and we won't rest
until we cover
the entire
checkerboard that is the world
which is 200 countries
and lord knows how many sectors
but building a global trusted cser
network is hard
we have been working quite hard at it
we're actually very proud we have
started our first
chapter in the uk
but we need of course help
this is where you come in
you get something as well
because i can tell you from experience
the experience of working with the
talented and passionate people is
something that will that will be very
very good for your soul and i can
recommend it to anyone but you will also
meet international new friends
and you will get support
and they will definitely help you be a
better person
and a better professional
this is the promise that caesar global
will make you
but what we ask is people who believe in
making the world a better place
willingness to invest time to fill that
darn matrix with us
and
we need people to agree with our core
values and code of conduct
that's very important but essentially we
need to conquer the world we need to do
it side by side
and we can't have differences about how
we do it
so
if this sparks your interest
there's many people you can get in touch
with
you can get in touch with vincent
leonard
mariela sharresh victor myself any divd
member
and a lot of them sitting here
those are the people with the black
shirts
with the yellow logo on top of it they
can refer you as well
i want to do a big shout out to our
co-founder victor
i hope people many people know why
don't call him
wait a little bit until you do that but
let's all do a big shout out to victor
because he's essentially the reason that
many of us are
[Applause]
here and i want to do a big shout out to
our uk chapter leads scott mcgrady
gerard and dave
welcome on board guys we are so happy to
have you and i will see you in a few
weeks
and our supervisory board
um that's ronald prince michael
barkmeier michiel prince and of course
edwin van andel
so
all of these people pivotal in what we
do
so give them a ring give me a ring if
you want to if you want to see how you
can help
thank you very much for your attention
and hope you have a wonderful mch
[Applause]
so we do have some time less left for
questions if anyone has a question
please line up at the microphone in the
middle
stand close to it so that we can hear
you microphone in the front please
thank you for the wonderful work
one question regarding contacting abuse
contact do you
just email the app use that domain or
you just check rar databases for the
abuse contact for the ip address space
like aaron apnic ripe
[Music]
this is actually a question i can
better refer right now to divd as i do
that um i don't know make customer do
you want to you want to
take that question
then let us come to this you want to
thanks leonardo you can have my micro
[Applause]
so in contacting people we use various
ways to track down contact information
abusing information for ip block is one
but preferably a last resort if you have
a domain name
from certificate or something we can of
course mail info ads
security ad etc at the domain if they
have a website we can scrape it for
security.text or some kind of privacy
contact and those are the various ways
we try to get in contact great thanks
another question is regarding threat
intel like how do you prioritize like
the cves if for example in nation states
is after one cv do you go after that or
is there any kind of protection
yeah yeah so um so we look generally at
risk at the highest amount of risk to
the largest group of people
we try also to be as apolitical as we
can in our decision making
so that's typically where we look at
so
it is a little bit of a an art if you
will
um it's super difficult if you look at
cves you know the first two pages all of
them have score 10
right so so where do you start
and and and this is really where the art
comes in sometimes there's a lot of work
being done already by vendors you know
they're on top of it they really you
know they they know what they're doing
you know even though it's super bad you
know let them have edits and sometimes
it's something that we think well we
think we think people are
really underestimating this one so we'll
invest in effort there it is an art yeah
thank you
are there any more questions
if that is not the case then i would
like to thank you for your talk and your
work it was really interesting and great
good job so give a nice round of
applause please
thank you
you