[Music]
so i'm here on behalf of the divd we're
a dutch collector of of volunteer
helpful hackers
and we aim to make the digital world
safer by reporting vulnerabilities we
find in digital systems to people who
fix them who can fix them we have a
global reach but we do it dutch style
open honest and collaborative
and that sometimes makes people unhappy
so
i'm a bit stressed out
because this just happened
this is a statement from the vendor
saying that
that account that's named super admin
is in fact not
a real system administrator and is not
subject to our testing group
with sort of abilities to carry out
function tests
we are just informed once in early july
and then took the actions immediately
they asked and then they asked us not to
give this talk
so
this can either be short
or not
[Applause]
open honest collaborative we're not
going to propose this disclosure we've
given the vendor till
20 minutes ago to come up with a
reaction
i've not yet received such reaction
i will check my phone at the end of the
talk
so my name is frank bredeck i'm case
handler for divd case 2022009
i'm a crisis manager at the afd and my
day job is the cso at super phyllis this
is how you reach me
and it all
started with an honest
tweet from celestine one of our divd
researchers who noticed that her parents
had solar panels
that were had omnic converters in them
and omnic went bankrupt and now the
inverter is sending its data to solarman
in china
funny haha in a kind of gdpr way
this talk although it is an issue that
data of european citizens just gets sent
off to china this talk is not about gdpr
i was expecting a sigh of relief
but the tweet was followed up by a tweet
from yeller
smart
showing how he logged into
solarman with the superman user
super admin user
so who's yeller yellow hashem he's not
here he's taking a vacation
well-deserved vacation but he's the main
researcher on this and some people may
know him as schizo-ducky
some people know him a little bit more
than others
um
what does yellow do well he's a
programmer architect does devops is good
at finding passwords in things like
public github repositories he's done
hundreds of responsible disclosures in
the last three years
if he knocks on your door he's in
trouble because he didn't have to knock
he could have just walked in he had the
key and he's too is surprised about all
the brands he's been able to get into
so far
and he needs to add one
so this happened in february and um
yeah now what
and back in february uh sorry back in
april 2021
the ivd wasn't what it was now we were
still developing what we did what kind
of cases we took
and it does not qualify as the ivt case
then
it does now by the way
so we reported it to solarman we did
help yeller reach them
and although we didn't never got a reply
back
the password was changed a few days
later
case closed
life goes on and we fast forward to
february this year and yellow reads the
blog post by john from camper i don't
know if you're here young but if you are
a good post
um
about problems with connected
inverters
and that made us wonder
or it made yellow wonder
is solar man still okay
not really he could log into the super
admin account again so what have we got
what did we find in the github
repository
uh yeah that's solar man but not this
one
so solar man claims by themselves that
they are professional remote monitoring
and management is my addition
solution for
devices
devices from solar man solas omnic and
ginglong
mostly inverters loggers and batteries
and um yes these were the super admin
credentials for the monitoring platform
so what could we do
apparently with this account
read the data of all the users and we've
confirmed that we could see names we
could see addresses we could see email
addresses we should see current and
historical generation
we could create and delete users
change configurations calibration
offsets
read and clear errors in the converters
download firmware versions
upload new firmware we have an upload
screen
yeah basically this is the list of build
your own inverter botnet
um
we haven't tested this because of ethics
and our code of conduct
proportionality if you want to do
um responsible disclosure you have to to
be
your measures your tests do not have to
be worse than what you're trying to
prevent
also it has to be subsidiary that means
if you can use the smallest a small
hammer and a big hammer you should use
the smallest hammer possible
this would have been too big a hammer
at the wrong time
but we did confirm the data in there we
did confirm that gui showed us these
possibilities
so what numbers are we talking about
well these are the numbers from february
and remember it's winter in february
globally there were over close to a
million plants locations with solar
panels
of which 42 000 in the netherlands 7 000
in
germany 7 000 in belgium and about 13
000 in the uk
together producing in february
10.03 gigawatts
that's serious numbers so what's the
impact for the netherlands well if you
take 40 000
plants
with an average of between 4 and 10
kilowatt peak per plant
you add some bigger plants like the ones
we've listed here
you can buy
come up with a combined power of 400
megawatts
that's a little bit bigger as this thing
here and that's the 1025 electricity
plant on the whole health of the rainy
thousand
yeah so what could you do if you had
admin
install custom firmware create a botnet
use lateral movement so move from the
converter further down into the network
physically damage or overload the
converter
that could lead to bricking it or
overloading the device
we could block the vendor out change
their password see how they yeah what
would do that
could you hurt the grid
i don't know i'm not a grid expert
i know some
people who
know something or know people who know
something
one plant shouldn't be a problem
and it's not a novel idea to hurt the
grid
this was sent around during the farmer
protests earlier earlier this month on
the 4th of july
to all farmers and owners of panels and
windmills
let's all turn off our solar inverters
on the 4th of july wind power 2 we want
to make a statement that 20 of all green
power comes from farms if we do it all
at the same time we can cause outages
turn off at 4th of july
mid of day bam
this is a forward and message to forward
well
if a bunch of farmers can come up with
this idea i mean i know farmers are
smart but
nation states
i think they're smarter
and taking panels offline is one thing
but what if we go and use and use it to
do aerobics exercise
take it up and down and up and down that
would cause a serious problem on a grip
or
take all the panels in the north of the
netherlands offline and then once power
is ramped up there turn them back on and
turn all the power in south of the
netherlands that would be fun we have
gps coordinates
so
getting this fixed
was a long and windy route
this credential was actually committed
to github on the 5th of august
2019.
we discovered them in april of 2021
it was changed
in february we noticed it was working
again
and we opened the case and by the way we
welcomed yella as a researchers in our
midst
in the ivd
we contacted the dutch national cyber
security center we notified the vendors
on the 9th of february
we worked with the ncsc also on the 20th
of february they worked together they
contacted nccnl and this china cert
we mailed china cert
we
got a little help from the dutch embassy
we got a we visited the
chinese embassy ourselves
um finally there was contact with china
cert
and then
things went really quickly china cert
really did their job it's like 17
the contact
vendor changed the password repository
github repository was deleted
but this thing was exposed for
777 days
at least because we don't know when it
was turned back
what happened in between
i don't know
so it's fixed
github repository gone
password changed
well yes we resolved the situation where
everybody could potentially mess with
these devices but
there has to be a super admin password
somewhere
a party has to control this
is that a desired situation well the
dutch ministry of economic affairs and
climate has blocked the chinese company
from bidding on the construction of what
they call the stop contact
a wall socket at sea
and they did this because
they think
having a chinese company controlling
this much power on the grid is a
security risk
so
what about those solar panels
you may wonder why doesn't anybody do
something about this
well grid operators and energy companies
have no authority over what happens
behind the smart meter
if you overload your local grid your
fuse burns you're off the grid
problem solved
they can't put any regulation or any
enforcement in place
building codes are about electrical
safety
and we have an authority for
iot
and iot devices but yeah they can only
interfere when devices are
insecure
there's new regulation underway that
requires registering and certifying
devices if you want to sell them to
consumers
which you probably can circumvent by
going to aliexpress directly but
different manner
but even if these devices themselves
ever become 100 secure
you're still have a foreign party that
controls a major amount of power
in the grid
so that brought me
back to the opening talk that miko
hipponen gave
where he said
we're doing security we're no longer
securing computers
we are securing society
so statement from the vendor
let me check
i have a statement
[Applause]
dear frank this is way and i'm
responsible for marketing department
thanks for your reply and thanks for
any way for dutch ethical hacker finding
is an issue a issue for us
at present we're absolutely off the
court with the upcoming disclosure and
communication time left us is extremely
limited
it's an opinion
for now i can only say
firstly the account is subject to
testing group and not a super admin
account
which later we can prove provide proof
in details
secondly uploading firmware via the
account is fine
but no actual control function is
workable as real operation needs averted
verification and subject to
authorization from inverter
manufacturers
okay
thirdly the account is not related to
any account of other customers and won't
affect their pv plans
at last the account is now in safe
condition i hope that means they
implemented two-factor authentication
therefore believe we believe that there
is no effect to tv planned operation in
the system
in case you want to go public with the
case please do keep above facts in your
statement
as
we've done
and we expect not to mention the product
name in disclosure too late
and won't expect any exaggeration before
clarification i hope i didn't personally
i think we can create long-term
cooperation with your organization to
offer services to our customer in much
more secure way i hope so too
so we're really grateful that they are
reaching out that we are in contact now
uh we want to thank the china cert for
help brokering this contact um because
obviously good with everything coming
from china
that's really important that we have
good international cooperation on this
and with that
any questions
[Applause]
thank you frog we have about 10 minutes
for q a so you don't have to walk all
the way to the uh
which is over here so if you have any
questions beyond this talk you can
always find these guys over here
they have lots and lots and lots of war
stories going on so
half of them are not disclosable at all
so it's a bit of shame um any questions
nobody
well
i have
we have one question
have you looked at the hardware
architecture of the inverter and do you
think it would be possible to
for the output ac voltage to to shift
the phase alignment
relative to the grid so
so according to the statement of the
vendor
the firmware somehow can't magically
control this
um have we taken
people kind of get pissed if you take
their inverters because they have them
for a reason
um
anybody who has a solar man inverter
well we we've they changed the account
so we don't have the control now
um so no we didn't this wasn't the
hardware investigation for us this was
just a software investigation and a sas
platform
where we found the password from so we
haven't
um we're really curious though so if
somebody's willing to uh sacrifice their
uh their solemn controller and i guess
the likelihood just increased a little
bit
um please come by the village
thank you very much yeah are you a big
fan of project aurora and okay thank you
very much um please give frank a big
applause and thank you for your
[Applause]
thanks