[Music]
all right so i love this crowd because
you're here for one of the most hardcore
uh talks uh in the whole schedule i'm
very excited about this myself so the
the title is nuggets of shannon
information theory and our presenter
christian will be guiding you through
things
in his 1948 scientific paper a
mathematical theory of communication
claude e shannon introduced the word bit
the article laid down the foundations
for the field of information theory
which in turn opened up the way to
digital information processing
christian will present an accessible way
three nuggets from shannon information
theory
so take it away christian
all right thanks a lot for coming
as uh the herald just said my name is
christian schaffner i'm a professor at
university of amsterdam and i've been
teaching a course about this topic about
information theory for the last few
years to master students so i've now
taken on the the challenge of
compressing this whole course into like
40 minutes just for you so enjoy
i hope i i have time to cover some of
the nuggets some of the gold pieces of
this theory of shannon
let me start off with kind of a
philosophical question namely what is
communication
and we are communicating all the time
but how do we actually define this
ever thought about that
yeah i see
yeah i eating first
yeah
yeah very good so it at least involves
two parties here's what khloe shannon
proposed the fundamental problem of
communication is that of reproducing at
one point
exactly are approximately a message
selected at another point so indeed
there's two players alice and bob yeah
your two hands and uh alice wants to
communicate with bob and wants to send a
particular message say zero one one zero
and then hopefully after communication
has happened bob
thinks that alice has been sending this
message and so that's a way of defining
communication
all right so
let us take us back a little bit into
the history of wireless communication
this can go all the way back to
smoke signals
now you can imagine that's that that has
been used for maybe hundreds thousands
of years
you can imagine it's not very efficient
yeah it does reach very far you can see
smoke from far away but like sending
actual messages that's probably rather
hard
um
zooming into a little bit the second
half of the 19th century when maxwell's
equations were derived and people
started to understand how to handle
electricity and people like this guy
here giuliano marconi
demonstrates a wireless telegraph so
instead of using a wire and using morse
code you can actually do this without a
wire wireless
and in around this time as well 1920s um
fm radio was demonstrated here by edwin
howard armstrong here on the beach with
his wife
so back then around this time
things were mostly analog and there was
some ad-hoc engineering a bit what
hackers do here as well tailored to an
application but there are big open
questions like
is there a general methodology for
designing these communication systems
how can we actually reliably communicate
in noisy imagine these devices are very
imperfect there's a lot of problems with
them
and how fast can we go in principle
and these questions were answered by our
hero the hero of this talk claude elwood
shannon
and he is the father of information
theory as you just heard before he is
the one who vented the word bit
he is a graduate of mit that's a
famous university in the us
massachusetts institute of technology on
a totally different topic and algebra
for theoretical genetics so he knew a
lot of different things and then after
that he joined bell labs so bell labs
was really the place to be in this time
as a scientist and during his time at
bellaps he also rejoined as professor at
mit and here's a funny thing i would
like to read out so when he returned to
mit in 1958 he continued to threaten
corridor walkers on his unicycle
sometimes augmenting the hazard by
juggling
no one was ever sure whether these
activities were part of some new
breakthrough or whether he just found
them amusing he worked for example on a
motorized pogo stick which he claimed
would mean he could abandon the unicycle
so feared by his colleagues so so this
was a funny guy and i think he would
have loved to uh to have the experience
here at this hacker camp and as as you
just heard he likes juggling there's
actually a little movie i want to show
you
um let's see if that works
um i downloaded it so maybe
constructing these juggling clowns
to become more intrigued with the
problem of building a real juggling
machine machines like this only give the
illusion of juggling they have a complex
mechanism but the uh
props as we call never actually
leave the ground they're all held up by
black wires and so on
and so far they know no one had ever
built a real juggling machine uh
occurred to me that i would like to try
to do that
the juggler's skills cannot yet be
engineered to build a device that could
imitate him dr shannon had to simplify
the problem when you bounce juggle
the
ball is almost stationary so you're not
wasting much energy all you have to do
is give it a little
toss like that and then we'll come back
to the same height so you're saving a
lot of
energy uh
the
one can see how easy it is another
aspect of this is that the moon ball is
moving slowly when you catch it
wc fields dr shannon's juggling machine
lacks feedback
it can't sense variations in its toss or
catch and so must rely only on the
repetitive dynamics of the ball's fall
and bounce in order to maintain its
rhythmical cascade
[Music]
cup like hands help make up for the lack
of feedback catching and funneling the
balls back onto the optimum path
the mathematical analysis of juggling
that's the end
they see
i haven't seen any juggling machines
around here so
pretty cool building this uh back in the
in the old times
and there's some more links on this side
actually everything is available on
github there was the the the link to it
at the very beginning and i will show it
yet again at the end so you can also
download the slides and also click these
links there's a a biographic new movie
about him and the bit player so if you
want to know more about shannon you
should watch it it's great
so what did he do he actually answered
these questions so he wrote the paper
called a mathematical theory of
communication published in bill
technical journal and introduced a whole
new field of research namely information
theory and answering these questions we
were asking before what is communication
what is information how can we compress
it how fast can we communicate it's all
answered in the first half of this paper
and my whole course was just about the
topics of that and this talk as well
so here is the one slide summary of what
he did and what is what is the the core
message of information theory
unfortunately it contains a lot of word
that you don't understand yet
so at the end of the talk i will come
back to this slide and hopefully you
will have an idea what this is all about
before that i want to just give you an
idea
so let's try to to read this text
so um normally i just call somebody up
and ask him to read does somebody dare
i see someone home
yep go ahead at the microphone
the alice found at first was in
managing her flamingo yep she succeeded
in
getting its body
tucked tucked away comfortably
enough yes under her arm i'm gonna guess
yes with its
legs hanging down
generally
just as she had
got it very very very good and so on it
will get harder
but this was very well done obviously
native speaker probably that helps a lot
so let me illustrate a few concepts with
this so one could wonder like um if we
want to compress this english text
apparently what we could do is just
leave out some letters
right you could just simply read it out
no so we we can kind of just leave out
the black letters and we will save some
space and compress this text
but of course we wonder like how can you
do this optimally how do we can
compress this text all the way down so
that we can recover it perfectly that's
one of the questions we're going to
answer
another thing is if you send this text
over a imperfect channel
and that sometimes just erases some some
letters like here some erasure channel
then how can we actually make sure that
we can recover from that and that's a
topic called error correction that we're
also going to touch upon and then you
can combine these two and say well if
you want to want to send this text over
a communication channel like how do we
do this optimally somehow should we
compress it first and then put in more
redundancy so that it revives the
channel or
and again that is answered by
information theory so we'll get there
before we can start oh well just very
quickly the reactions to this theory
when when shannon came up with people
like what
the error-free communication in noise
how how should we do that and it turned
out to be a bit more difficult than than
predicted it actually took about 50
years maybe 60 years to actually figure
out how to actually do that
so practical error correcting codes have
only come around in the 2010s
achieving the limits that shannon
already predicted like in 1948.
nowadays applications of information
theory are everywhere in particular for
instance the research that i do on
quantum computing quantum cryptography
we use entropy and we use information
theory as tools to do things about that
in machine learning in
physics there's thermodynamics in
philosophy of science economics biology
communication theory you name it there's
a lot of information theory out there
and used everywhere it's great
so finally that was the overview now we
got into a little bit more the technical
part and in order to get started i will
have to tell you something about
exponentials and logarithms so here is
afraid of logarithms
one
and a half two three four okay a bunch
of people are afraid
and we'll have to cover it because it's
essential part let's start with
something you
we unfortunately know
exponential functions yeah so how fast
does the virus spread well if on day
zero we have one person infected
then uh if this if the r number is two
then on the on day two there's gonna be
two new infections and every day we we
move on here we add a day we double the
number of infections
and uh you see in this column here you
recognize the powers of two
so
every good nerd should recognize these
numbers as powers of two
okay that's the that's the easy part
that's the exponential part
they kind of go um here to the right in
this table so for instance and 2 to the
3 that's a
simplified way of writing 2 times 2
times 2 that's 8.
another example is 2 to the 5. that's
just 2 times 2 times 2 times
32.
and the logarithm is the inverse of it
so the logarithm to base 2 of x of a
number x is the a so that if you raise 2
to the 8th power you get x and in this
picture simply the other direction
now so you um for instance here you have
512.
the logarithm to base 2 or 512 is 9
because 2 to the 9 is
512. so logarithms they were invented
for easy calculations because they
translate multiplications on this side
here on the right to into additions
on the on the left
and here's a little example so if you
want to multiply for instance 512 with
eight
then you you could do this an easy way
if you recognize them as power of two
you can write them two to the nine times
two to the three well these are all
powers of two so you only wonder how
many times and did you multiply 2 with
itself so get 2 to the 9 plus 3 so
that's 2 to the 12. you can look that up
as well here so it's 4096.
so there's a little rule we used here
namely that 2 to the a times 2 to the b
is 2 to the a plus b and the logarithm
it does the other thing the other way
around so if you just write the same
equation with a logarithm on both sides
well then we can write the log of this
multiplication as the log of 5 12 plus
the log of 8.
and so that turns this multiplication
into a sum 9 plus 3 is 12 and that's the
same result before
so important to remember is this rule
about logarithms i'm sure you've seen
them once at school log of c times d is
log of c plus log of d and a little
version of that is the log of one over d
is just minus log d because log of one
is zero
yeah so maybe a quick refresher of stuff
you have seen once upon a time of course
these functions are not just defined uh
on the integers but you can draw nice
curves so here are the two plots
um so the the log is the inverse of the
exponential function and here some kind
of noticeable numbers two to the zero
anything to the zero is one
two to one is two so if you notice three
points zero two and also two to the
minus one is a half then you can
basically write this this function you
could also draw it yourself
another thing then for the log the same
um
kind of points to remember log of 1 is 0
because
2 to the 0 is 1 and then log of 2 is 1
and log of a half
so that's
minus 1 that's here yep so far so good
now another little thing i want to
introduce before kind of starting with
information theory are probability
distribution and we're gonna stick to
the simple case just discrete so no
continuous distributions and you can
think of them in terms of programming
languages just as a list of non-negative
numbers so they can be zero but they're
all bigger than bigger or equal to zero
and they sum to one that's it
so very easy example is a fair coin just
50 50. whenever you flip a coin you get
either one or the other outcome with
probability 0.5
a little bit more advanced are biased
coins those that are not fair so here
you have a distribution of say b and one
minus p this they sum to one if you add
and the p is something between zero and
one but not a half i mean otherwise
would be a fair coin
okay still pretty simple another kind of
extreme case is the so-called uniform
distribution
here is a picture uh this pie chart of
for n equals five so you have five
possible outcomes and all of them are
equally uh likely to occur so it's just
one over five zero point two
probability for every outcome
okay those are easy examples a little
bit more complicated examples you might
have seen as well is the binomial
distribution you don't really need to
know what this
these these formulas here are but it's
basically the probability to obtain
exactly k heads when n times flipping a
coin with bias p so you get something
like this
this this pie chart here and that's
maybe a good moment where i switch over
to the
jupiter notebook that i made for you so
you can download this from github you
can make all these tables you can uh
did the plots that i put in the
presentation you can reproduce and you
see the codes how to do it so here's a
fair coin a bias coin uniform
distribution
and um and then there's a little thing
to play with here binomial distribution
where you can actually choose the number
of coins you flip and you get like an
interactive chart of like of these
distributions you can play around with
that here just to get an idea what these
distributions are
maybe the next thing you we want to do
is another
example for a probability distribution
here i read um in alice in wonderland
and i take the first 100 000 characters
i kind of clean it up a little bit i
strip everything but the letters and
space
and then
i just count frequencies so if i run
this i get i get something like that so
these are just frequencies that means
how many times
an e occurs that's the most frequent
english letter how many times a space
occurs there's actually this big big
chunk here and then t a oh so that's
kind of the the letter frequencies you
can get
so that's actually my next example here
frequencies you can always do this kind
of statistic and then just count the
number of currencies divided by the
total that's another distribution you
can work with
all right final thing before we actually
get to the nuggets um we want a sample
from a distribution so we want to have a
black box this thing up there with a red
button every time we push the button we
want a sample from this distribution so
um for instance from this fair coin
let's try to do that again actually in
the in the notebook you might i mean
you're probably more familiar with that
than i am so there's some random
function if i just evaluate this a few
times then you see i get apparently i
get a float a floating number between
zero and one
so now we want to turn this into a coin
it's just a 50 50 outcome
well a little bit of thought will bring
you to this now you kind of just check
whether it's smaller than a half or
bigger i mean that then look at the kind
of first digit after the after the comma
and then you then you know what the
pitch should be so so this kind of
simple transformation turns a float
between zero and one into a random bit
and what we actually did is just kind of
unfold this this this pie chart into
into this interval between zero and one
and then we threw a random number here
between zero and one and depending
whether it ends up on the blue part on
the orange part we we call it a zero or
one as an outcome or blue or orange
and
actually this turns out to be a good
thing to do because we can do this for
other distributions as well so if we
have this distribution we can also kind
of kind of wrap it up and then throw
this number and that turns out to be
here so so here a sample would be the
screen thing
and let's do a final uh example with
this more complicated distribution again
we can unfold it and and kind of run our
random number and here is the little
program um that does it and it's really
just figuring out in which interval you
are so you kind of start with the first
interval and then you kind of add one
until you hit this random value that you
picked before and return that label and
it's
nothing really deep going on
and then you can sample so this is just
doing it like 60 times and you get a
sequence like this so it starts like d a
e f so here we have some some
gave them some labels it could also be
colors or
but um that's kind of a random sample so
i every time i push them i get a sample
from this distribution
yeah
with me great now now it's what happened
okay because now we start wondering like
how surprised we are
so if you have an event with some
probability p
then the inverse of this probability one
over p is actually a measure of how
surprised we are if this event happens
well if you have a big probability well
then we are actually extremely surprised
if it happens no one over p is going to
be uh huge if you have a small
probability to start with if you have a
big probably the same well not so
surprised i mean of course it had
but the funny thing and bear with me
we're gonna measure this logarithmically
in bits so we're gonna actually gonna
look at the log of one over p and this
is a positive number because of the
rules we saw before again easy example
that's maybe the most important example
as well
a fair coin
if you just flip a coin you are log of
one over a half and that's log of two
one bit surprise to see in a particular
outcome so if you flip two coins you're
two bit surprise that's kind of the
reason why we use the logarithm it kind
of nice nicely adds up now to flip a
bunch of coins then we are that many
coins surprise bit surprised to see a
particular outcome
okay now
let's look at the other examples of the
distribution let's look at the uniform
distribution
um in this case we are
the log of one over five so that's log
of five so two point three two two bit
surprise to see any particular outcome
so just one sample from this
distribution
kind of gives us roughly um 2.3 um
fair coins of surprisal value so it kind
of gives us a measure how to compare and
literally if you do two samples we have
two times this so that's roughly like uh
4.6 fare coins sample so you can
actually compare surprise we can somehow
measure how surprised we are
and that's that's going to be the key
for the next thing so now a little bit
more tricky is a biased coin because
then we can wonder how surprised we are
on average
so let's say we have this unfair coin
i'm gonna comp then we just compute and
we basically just say okay if we get
this blue part that happens with this
probability 0.0.1
well our surprising value is log of 1
over 0.1 plus well the big chunk is 0.9
mass and surprising value is log over 1
minus 0.9 you can
calculate that put it in the in the
jupyter notebook or whatever in your
calculator and you get 0.47 so it's just
some number but again it's like kind of
like half of a coin half of a fair coin
surprise to see a particular outcome on
average of this distribution
and of course you can do this for any
value of the of the bias and you
actually get this very nice curve this
binary entropy function
and if you were a student in my course
then you would have to really know this
function really well because you can do
a lot of stuff with that in theory
theoretical computer science it's a very
important function and you see like at
0.5 the fair coin you have exactly one
bit
of average surprise
and if it's if it's certainty if it's
zero or one well then you don't have any
surprise
all right now we're basically there
where we have the first nugget and
that's simply that definition and
actually it's the definition that's used
in this picture here next to shannon's
face there is the definition of shannon
entropy so the shannon entropy it is
defined
like this so the entropy is called h of
of this distribution is just the average
surprisal measured in bits it's really
literally what i just talked about it's
the sum of the probabilities p i
multiplied with the
surprising value measured in bits so the
log of one over p i
yeah so okay great we can define it so
it's a number if you give me a
distribution i can compute this number
or you can compute it the computer can
compute it i wrote a very simple program
for that again it's in the it's on the
jupiter notebook and it's really just
this sum here some check that you
actually input a distribution
but you start at zero and then just kind
of add up um p times the log two of p
and you have to watch out a little bit
with the minus so here is not one minus
p that's why there's a minus here
but that's the the rule from before
okay so once a mathematician gets
a definition then you kind of want to
understand it no the hacker kind of want
to want to understand what what it's all
about so you want to check some basic
properties
first thing to notice is that shenan
entropy the average surprisal is
actually positive it's bigger than zero
sometimes it's zero um but it's only
zero actually with distribution that
have a certain outcome if you're not
surprised if there's just one outcome
that happens with probability one then
it's actually zero otherwise you have
some uncertainty it's a measure of
uncertainty of surprisal
and the other extreme is if you have
uniform distributions we already saw
that for five outcomes then the entropy
of this distribution of a uniform
distribution is actually log of n it's
the log of the number of outcomes you
can have
so that are the two extremes and then
there's some nice computation trick i'm
just going to show you i mean one can
prove it but
maybe goes a bit too far
um so for instance if for this
distribution here you can notice that
somehow it's like nicely split in half
you can understand this distribution as
coming from a kind of random process
that first decides whether it's on the
left on the right so with 50 50 you go
up or you go down that's one bit of
entropy
and then um here in the upper half you
want to decide whether whether you're
blue or orange whether you're a or b and
that's again a 50 50 choice so with
weight 0.5 you go up and you have
another bit of entropy
or with a weight 0.5 you go down and
then you have a uniform distribution you
have one over three to get to one of
these other outcomes
and and that's kind of a kind of nice
cute way of computing entropy and
students would practice a lot to
actually do that we don't have time
unfortunately but we are also going to
practice a little bit because now you
know these rules so
order these three distributions in terms
of entropy which one has the highest
entropy
yep
the right one has three bits yes
and where which one has the lowest
the middle one yes indeed so here are
the entropies they're all uniform
distributions then it's easy it's just a
log
so this is log of 5 2.3 this is log of 2
is one and this one has three bits it's
eight possible outcomes very good the
next one is slightly more tricky same
exercise
because they all have six possible
outcomes
which one has the highest entropy
the left one here
why
because it's uniform yeah
probably yes
so indeed this is uniform distribution
this is actually the maximum you can get
with six outcomes indeed and then
between these two which one has more uh
entropy
uncertainty more
surprisable value i see somebody
pointing
pointing right indeed so this one kind
of has bigger chunks so indeed if you
compute it again jupiter notebook it
will tell you um yes this one is
actually pretty close to the uniform to
2.45 and this one has significantly less
um because you have these big chunks
where you're not so surprised even
though there's some small ones but i
don't have too much that much weight so
somehow
it doesn't give that much entropy okay
now we know how to compute entropy let's
do something with it let's do let's use
it let's put it into action
and here comes the first kind of concept
how do we actually measure information
so remember this black box we press this
red button every time it it spits out
some like coins in this case fair coins
coin flips sequence of coins sequence of
random bits just uh flipped at random or
with some different distribution of more
complicated one i showed you how to do
it you can kind of generate sequences
like that and now we're wondering like
how much information is in this in in
such a sequence
and here's a kind of clever idea again
shannon's idea of course
you have the data
and
if you want to find out how much
information there is to what we could
try is to compress it
we can compress it down to the minimal
number of bits let's call it l so you
see some something big here coming in
and something smaller coming out here
and
but we want to do it in a way so that
you can inflate it back so we shouldn't
be uh we're not allowed to lose any
information that that's it's called
lossless compression it's not what you
do with pictures often like jpegs you
can make them really small but you lose
quality you know you cannot get that go
back whereas here we want we want to be
able to go back we want to like zip now
we do zip then you can unzip and it's
and it's back to normal and this number
this minimal number l we will call the
average information content it's kind of
what is in there no like it's kind of
the crucial stuff that is in there and
we measure it in bits per symbol so here
we got bits and we measure it per symbol
that we that we had in our original data
okay great we can define it like that we
can define information like that and now
comes shannon and says well this l is
going to be pretty much exactly the
entropy of the data distribution
yeah so
somebody
picks this distribution i can compute
the entropy you know you practice that
before
and that's going to be a kind of a bound
or this is going to tell me pretty much
how much we can compress this
information down to its essential part
and that's that's really cool
and of course once we get such a claim
in mathematicians we have to prove it
so
i'm not gonna really do it um
unfortunately you don't have time
especially this this direction it's not
that hard but you need a bit of math so
the harmony when we when we want to
prove like such an equality
what
mathematicians do is we show both parts
we show a lower bound we show upper
bound so we show that l is small or
equal to this entropy
and we show that l is uh
smaller equal and bigger and equal so it
must be the same and this part i'm
actually not gonna go through except
that here's the proof but you will have
to read some more stuff to understand it
but the upper bound i'm gonna do so the
upper bound is saying that we will give
a compression method
and to show that we can actually
compress
a
data sequence from this distribution
that reduces roughly the entropy of bits
per symbol
and that's really a very nice procedure
that you should all know it's called
huffman coding
who's uh ever heard about huffman coding
oh you guys come here and you already
know everything okay
okay just quick recap um not all of you
have seen it it's very easy actually so
that's why i can i can show it so here's
how what you do given a probability
distribution
combine the two nodes with the smallest
probability into a new one with a
combined weight so here i've already
nicely ordered them by by probabilities
so you start with this last two you
combine them into a new note that has
the sum of these two probabilities then
you just continue keep on doing this you
have now zero point three zero point two
zero point two five and two five so you
have to take the smallest of the
remaining ones these are for instance
these two my here have a choice then if
you have a choice doesn't matter what
you do you could just pick any of them
and you combine these two into a new
note now 0.45 so what remains is 0.25
0.45 and 0.3 so now we have to combine
these two 0.3 and 2 5 to get 0.55 and
then the last step you always combine
two to get one because all the numbers
sum up to one so that's a good check if
the end you have to get the one
okay so that's step one we're done
now we can go backwards we kind of uh
label this and we've created the binary
tree this is the root of the binary tree
this one and we just now label the path
with zero and one so here zero one we
have a zero one here zero one here zero
one here and if you kind of follow that
thing back then we'll get the codewords
over here
so for instance to get to the a we have
to go down here so we the one and then
the zero to go up and that's the code
word here one then zero
or to go to the last one to this e we
have to go down one down one down one so
again one one one yeah that's it these
are the codes this is these are the code
words and the binary code words to
encode this uh this distribution
according to these symbols
and the claim is that this is basically
optimal this works really well
um just to show you i mean somehow
intuitively that's the right thing no
because actually the the symbols with
small probabilities get long codewords
it's the ones that you start with you
actually want to use the long code words
for those stuff that doesn't appear too
much
and for those with high probability you
want to use short code words now that's
that's intuitively what you want to do
if you want to compress
and here's a kind of a real world
example namely this letter distribution
that i was talking about before so
here's the whole table and here is the
huffman code for these letter
frequencies so
the space was the most common character
and indeed that's here on the bottom and
that's
the code where just zero one because
yeah you have to go up zero and down
then you're already at the space
the next one is e is down here you have
to go one one zero i think for e yeah
one one zero zero actually go up twice
so you got such a tree and that's the
huffman code and the claim is that this
actually
gets you pretty much to down to the to
the shannon entropy so here the entropy
is about four bits so again
so if you have this distribution and you
got a sample you're uh you're about four
bits surprised so it's like flipping
four fair coins
okay uh let's see i did a little
experiment
to kind of verify that this is really
true again all the code is in the in the
in the jupyter notebook you can just
actually do it yourself
not very hard
um so i took alice in wonderland and the
first hundred thousand characters and if
i just store it stupidly
using ascii code
that's also a code no it's uses eight
bits per character then obviously you
need eight hundred thousand bits to to
store this thing
so let's be more clever and use a
huffman code instead so just use the
homicide from the previous slide and
indeed and the number of bits is gonna
be roughly four hundred thousand
and that turns out to be very close to
the shannon entropy to the four hundred
thousand times one hundred thousand so
that's exactly what shannon predicted
that you kind of need um
four here this number is four per source
symbols there we have hundred thousand
source symbols so that's very close to
each other
and you can also do the same thing with
uh with uh independent letter samples so
instead of using alice in wonderland i
could also just take a hundred thousand
samples from this distribution
independent samples and i've got pretty
much the same numbers
storing them stupidly is eight hundred
thousand using huffman code is pretty
much
what we expect
and then there's one column that i
didn't do that i don't show you yet
so i'm gonna zip this text
so i'm gonna zip alice in wonderland i'm
gonna zip the independent letter samples
what do you think is going to happen
yeah
which one is way better
it is better somewhere
but not for the other
okay so here here we go
it is pretty good it is actually better
than the huffman code in zipping alice
in wonderland english text
but it's actually worse here um so we
actually beating zip here if you just
have independent letter samples
yeah because you have to think a little
bit about that why like why is this the
case
but the reason is that there's much more
structure than just letter frequencies
single letter frequencies in english
text you also have diagrams and trigrams
and you have words you have
language structure no sentences if you
can exploit that well you can be better
and that is what what zip does
apparently quite quite cleverly it beats
it like big time
this won't work on independent letter
sample because there's no there's no
bygrams i mean there's just trivial
diagrams so there the huffman code is
really good but here you actually um win
by it and that means you have to be more
clever in compressing you can be more
clever if you have more knowledge about
your data
good
final part i saw something like 15
minutes
final part one more nugget to go and
this is actually by far the hardest part
and so i i noticed that i had to
simplify a lot and so i'm i'm gonna be
very um hand-wavy um at least for a
mathematician speaking i'm gonna be very
happy
anyway i'm already um so here we have a
noisy channel a noisy channel you can
model it mathematically as a conditional
probability distribution don't worry
about it it's it gets an input x and it
kind of outputs something y it's kind of
messed up a little bit so it's noisy so
it's not the perfect it's not outputting
perfectly what whatever comes in but it
kind of distorts it a little bit and
here is the most famous example it's
called the called binary symmetric
channel
you have an input it's just a bit and a
zero one and with probability one minus
epsilon it survives the bit it just
outputs the bit that was input and with
probability epsilon it flips the bit and
let's say epsilon is
zero point one so with ten percent
probability just flips the bit it's a
noisy channel that yeah you can put in
bits but
like ten percent of them are going to be
flipped and you don't know which one
okay
now
how do you cope with such a channel so
here you have our bsc with an error
probability 0.1 but you want you have
some data
and you kind of want
to survive this channel you kind of want
to encode it in a way that
that you can recover the original
message so if a message you kind of want
to encode it in some way so that after
you recover you get what what comes back
from the channel you can decode it again
so that you recover the original message
and there's two uh figure of merits here
that we kind of want to optimize
on the one hand there's the code rate
that's like how many times you actually
have to use the channel per bit you want
to send
and we want to make sure that we have a
good chance of recovering the original
message
so these are the kind of things that you
want to optimize and of course let me
give you examples so kind of a stupid or
kind of trivial example is um we don't
decode at all
just send whatever you get so if the
message is zero one one zero well just
send that over the bsc well we could be
unlucky that some bit is flipped and
then well we're lost the rate is very
good because we only use exactly the
channel once for the every bit we want
to send but the probability of success
is obviously the 0.9 per bit which is
not that great
so here's something more clever
namely repetition code so instead of
sending the bit once send it three times
just the same bit so if you want to send
zero just send zero zero zero if you
want to send one just send one one one
etcetera and then about ten percent of
these bits are going to get hit with an
error you don't know where but you have
a pretty good idea to to recover you
could just use majority vote no in this
box of three if there are two zeros
still then probably the third one was
also a zero
now that that actually works quite well
the raid is not so great because it's
only one third we kind of
use the channel three times for every
bit that we want to send but you we
boost our success probability per bit
quite a bit
so that's that's kind of some some easy
examples of codes there are some better
codes like the the following one the
hemming code who has seen the having
code
the same guys as before
okay so very quickly here it is
so you can use
four message
bits and you add some parity check bits
some three more bits and here's a nice
graphical way to illustrate how this
works so here's an example let's say we
have this message bit 0 1 1 0 so we put
them in these circles according to this
scheme here so we put the zero at m1 we
put the one at m2 we put another one on
m3 and then the zero here
and now we just want to make sure that
all the circles are happy the circles
are happy when they are even parity so
if the sum of the the entries of the
bits in the circle is even so we have to
add a one here to make one and one two
so that's that's a happy circle here we
need to add a zero to make this circle
happy and here we have to add a one to
make this circle happy
and that's it so that's kind of the
encoding scheme and it's easy to see
that if if some bit gets messed up
actually doesn't matter which one we
will be able to recover as long as only
one bit for instance here if we hit this
bit with an error
then we can easily figure out that it's
this bit because we can again check
which circles are happy this one is
already still happy this one is not
happy anymore because it's only one the
sum of the bits and here's also another
one that is not happy so it must be in
the intersection of these two circles
where the error occurred so we can
correct that back to a1 and we're good
and this actually works for any place
where the error occurs so we can cope
with one error here the rate is kind of
okay 0.57 and the success probability is
like 93 you see there are many different
error correcting codes actually maybe
that's the topic of the next talk i'm
going to give in the future they can
actually study this in detail here's a
little illustration of the hamming code
actually which is kind of funny so
there's the bits you encode them with
additional bits 30 bits then you hit
everything with 10 noise and you can
still recover the picture kind of
reasonably well by by decoding the way i
just uh illustrated
and
finally
um so here are kind of our two figures
of merit the error that we want to keep
small and the rates that we want to make
high so good codes are here in this
corner
and what shannon finally the final
nugget by shannon is that actually every
channel not just this binary semantic
channel but any channel has a capacity
so you give me a channel i can compute a
number c for this channel
and this c is the kind of a magic
magic bar that says there exists error
correcting codes that can cope with this
noisy channel at any rate that is below
that c
so for this example i could compute for
the bsc with zero one 0.1 probability of
error this c turns out to be 0.53 so
it's actually where this line here
crosses here at the zero and shannon's
nugget here tells us that actually we
can we can get as close as we want we
can get the rate up to 0.53 with
arbitrarily small error
so that's really amazing so it's kind of
he's claiming basically this line here
that and this line exists for every um
for every noisy channel
and that's kind of what people thought
what what how can you do that
unfortunately the way he proves that
it's it's ingenious and it's actually
very nice to see that the proof but what
he does is just each picks a random uh
error correcting code
so they random codes are extremely good
at these things unfortunately they're
very impractical because you cannot use
them in practice decoding them is very
hard and that's why it took like 60
years to actually achieve these limits
in practice to actually make it
practical enough to actually do this in
practice
all right that brings me to the end
what you've learned from this talk
hopefully is something about
exponentials and logarithms about shell
and entropy here these two formulas the
entropy and actually the capacity of the
channel is down here
a little bit about data compression and
about error correction and now i can
actually come back to this slide because
now you actually understand
um data compression if data is sampled
according to some probability
distribution then there's a ultimate
data compression limit and that's the
entropy h of this distribution in error
correction you can model a channel with
a conditional probability distribution
you can attach a number to it the
channel capacity and finally you can
reliably communicate if and only if the
the entropy of the stuff you want to
send is strictly smaller than the
capacity that of the channel where you
want to send information over
yeah
that's it
thank you very much for your attention
and i'm happy to take any questions you
have
reminder that uh ebay asking questions
should come to these microphones in the
middle
um are there any questions nope none
from signal excellent
so we're all just dazzled by this
display and so nobody has a question
oh we have a question
hello thanks very interesting
i was wondering is there a theoretical
limit if you have a noisy communication
when you can no longer reliably get
anything across yes
yes so basically in this figure that i
wrote that's exactly this line it is a
heart
a hard limit
so if you if your rate if you come up
with codes or if you have codes that are
going beyond this line
then you then your arrow will explode
so it's really this is a sharp border
as long as you stay below then there's
ways to do it if you're above it's over
if you write exactly on the line then it
becomes interesting then there's people
figuring out how exactly it behaves but
it's basically a sharp a sharp border
so yes there's just yeah
channels for instance i mean if you
imagine a simple example of the of the
binary symmetric channel that flips the
bit with probably one half
it's not gonna get you anywhere because
actually then this this is the binary
entropy of one half is one
so you have one minus one you have the
capacity of zero you cannot you just get
random bits as outcomes then everything
is randomized you cannot see anything
from the output
yes you're talking about noisy channels
do you have like some guesstimations how
noisy our i.t channels are nowadays
um
but what what is the id channel we have
in mind
ethernet violence whatever oh okay well
those are error corrected
there's in the in the background uh
there's error correction going on but
for instance uh think of like uh
transmitting satellite images no that
was just the the the james uh what uh
telescope unfolded and these pictures
were transmitted that's like from i
don't know thousands of kilometers away
the the fact that they can make this
information can make it down to earth
it's because they put a lot of
redundancy in it now they use error
correcting codes to make sure that this
transmission actually works
so usually the the actual noise depends
a lot on the distance right it grows uh
maybe quadratically or you can draw it
grows with distance so the closer you
are the easier it is
okay but for everyday applications
is this like every 10th bit is flipped
or is it way lower oh this i think is
way lower i mean for just by
communicating on ethernet no they are
it's very low extremely low thanks
final questions
oh one final question go for it
uh uh bit time gentle
but
i
was too distracted by computers at
school to actually learn any maths
so like bits of this i kind of
understand because you know i've
transferred a lot of data right for my
life
but but
at some point i need to go back and
learn maths where would be a good place
to start oh um actually there's many
good places so um
in the github repository that i'm
linking here there's like all the links
that i consulted when preparing
on the readme and there's a lot of like
nice instructional videos for instance
about logarithms from like extremely
simple to brutally hard um so i think
there's a lot of very nice explainer
videos out there for instance
um then it depends a bit on your on your
taste yeah i mean yeah i've tried now to
kind of make it a bit accessible but i
know i'm a i'm a mathematician so i
don't know
how much i succeeded but i think usually
like playing playing around with things
like trying to program it just like see
playing around with on this jupiter
notebook this will help a lot yeah cool
thank you you're welcome
well let's uh we've come we've run out
of time but uh
you you should grab christian outside
the tent
afterward obviously if this is a
compressed version of his whole semester
lecture he's got a lot of knowledge in
there uh he can unpack using these
patterns so let's uh thank him again for
for his
thank you
[Applause]
maybe maybe one last thing i would ask
the organizers to have a shannon field
next time we do mch no like there should
be a
without without shining we won't be here
so shuttle field perfect