[Music]
good evening and welcome to mch 2022 day
4 intent battery
um
you probably know that battery i mean
battery no we have we are talking we are
not talking about batteries but battery
powered cars so here with me on stage is
martin hereford uh to talk to you about
um
demystifying tesla's bluetooth ii
passive entry
entry system please give him a very warm
round of applause
thank you very much for the introduction
and thank you for being here
i'm talking about project temper today
and this is as you can see here about
tesla cars
it's the fourth time that i'm giving
this talk but actually i was adding
quite some new stuff as well every time
i did it
i tried to make an effort and add some
new things
right
so
about trifani.org you might have seen
the logo in the lower right it's it's a
group logo that is almost pretty retro
already because that was 18 years ago
when we started together or more than
that
together with colin mulliner
and me and we did a lot of bluetooth
related research
back then of course mainly bluetooth
classic
and we were participating in some test
events with the bluetooth sig which is
the standardization body for the
bluetooth protocol
and
we were helping vendors back then with
their smartphone not smartphones with
their feature phones and symbian phones
stuff like that in order to
have like
not the easy low hangings of bluetooth
vulnerabilities
so and about me i'm from salzburg
austria pretty much like the herald he's
not from salzburg though he's from
vienna
and i'm a regular participant and also
speaker at some instances at c3 in
germany so which is the yearly ccc
congress since
98 without missing even one
and i also
am the author of the tesla radar app
which i will talk a little bit about
later
and of course i own a tesla myself
because
always renting or having to rent one in
order to do tests just didn't
work out for me
and a little bit of memory lane my first
camp that i participated was actually in
2005 it was what the heck it was in
linde also in in the netherlands and i
found a picture of me talking
like in in one of the old flickr
accounts that is still linked up in the
page and as you can tell no difference
right
and back then i was talking not only
about bluetooth security and stuff we
found one of the projects i was talking
about back then was also
car whisperer my first project that went
into the automotive direction and what i
did there we were injecting audio
messages into cars with hand presets and
that was a lot of fun that was possible
back then because of standard pin
everybody used
so it got a little more complicated with
teslas they use obviously not a standard
four-digit pass key in order to unlock
the car
they do it for
driving though as you might know maybe
as a show of hands how many how many of
you do have a tesla or driver tester
all right so that's like 500 percent
more than usual because usually it's
just one guy
me
all right but that's at least some more
that's cool
and um this talk is about
telling you why you should be really
careful using the tesla phone as a key
and also like the nfc
some of the things
have been mitigated
but project tamper was investigating the
bluetooth low energy interface that
tesla has in their cars
and this interface that i'm talking
about is primarily found in all tesla
model 3 and y
but also on the new facelift variants of
model s and x so it turned out that this
phone key feature which got introduced
with tesla model 3 turned out to be a
kind quite popular thing and it's i i
believe it's also going to be in the
roadster whenever this appears
and um
it's it's like the thing that tesla puts
all their effort on
and
it's just an estimation that about two
million cars to date do have that
feature
[Music]
and what it also allows is not unlocking
the car or like
driving it it's also like
having a continuous id so tracking
and identifying vehicles on the radio
level is pretty easy
and also you can like send messages
there and how you do that i'm going to
show you
so most are not most some of the things
have been fixed by tesla over the time
some of them partially so i talked about
one thing that got mitigated but kind of
reopened by one of the attacks i'm going
to show today
and other or most things are findings
that
came from reverse engineering the
official tesla app which is an easy
process as you might know the only thing
is of course they use obfuscation so you
have a lot of guesswork as well
so
the original research started with tesla
radar in 19 but it
it intensified in 2021 when playing a
little more with the app and looking
into that communication
[Music]
all right phone key
what is it it's like the the big
innovation that they had you use your
phone
as your car key
and that's a pretty good idea
and i said it's going to be part of
future models
so what's like the ways to unlock a
tesla of course you guys that own the
tesla already know that but for the for
the ones that don't i explained that in
a short slide here so you have like your
phone which is pretty capable of using
like the network based api which you
require to have internet for
then it's the nfc
protocol which is in purple here which
is used for directly interacting with
the car
and then you have bluetooth with kind of
in the middle and as said here vcsec is
the protocol which is spoken from the
phone and also from the key fob via
pluto's low energy to your car
all right nfc card
these are the ways you can read that
later on
um
to unlock or just summarize that here
a little bit and due to timely
constraints i'm also not going to show
the videos which i have like linked in
the in the presentation and that's going
to be your homework to show afterwards
or to watch afterwards
so a little paul for the five people
with teslas so how would you unlock your
tesla usually like with the key fob with
the phone key or with the nfc card show
of hands like key fob
[Music]
one two three
and with the phone key
one
two three four is that right all right
and with the nfc card
still one
one all right good
so that was uh the official result from
the tesla from the twitter poll i did so
like 83 percent back then are using
phone key including myself i do own a
key fob though which costs a fortune for
i think what it is
and
right phone key is the thing that most
people use
[Music]
usually how does that work the
smartphone finds the vehicle it has some
indicators that show that this is the
right vehicle to talk to
and it connects
because the car would act as a ble
peripheral implementing a generic
attribute service that you can interact
with
and there's no pairing required and this
has also some background maybe why this
is not required and of course you can
unlock unlock your car you can start
you can open the franc
do stuff like that
so whenever
this car advertises a gut service there
will be a name like a standard attribute
or carrick
a service and also a two-week
characteristic and the from vehicle
characteristic and pretty much also is
very intuitive what's going to be done
with these characteristics i guess
as well it's exposing an
ie beacon structure and i think that's
mainly done in order to have iphones
natively detect the car with all that
background process optimization i think
they built that in because apple makes
it really hard to have a background
process that does not rely on apple
technology
[Music]
yeah and the advertisement is like
pretty easy to find out so there's this
uuid and then they have a major and
minor id which is part of the ibeacon
specification and these are like the
attributes that an iphone along with the
device address of the car would
recognize the car for it to be connected
[Music]
and as well the name
of the vehicle has some cryptic input
or in
cryptic stuff right so
whoever scans for ble devices next to a
tesla will find a few of like these
names starting with an s and then
there's an eight bytes hex
sequence hex encoded sequence ending
with a c in the most case i guess most
of you found that already so c i believe
stands for the center interface then we
have a driver side passenger side and
the rear side but these names are guests
because like passengers side on the
right-hand drive would be the driver's
side so i think they kind of messed up
there already
so
but the thing the eight bytes in the hex
seemed random to me at first
and they seem to be unique to a vehicle
and
they are always turned on
and unique to the vehicle and that kind
of led to the thing with the permanent
id so anybody with a phone could tell
whether my car is in the proximity of
bluetooth or not
which is a privacy privacy issue which i
pointed out in 2019 to tesla and that's
also when i
published the tesla radar app which is a
showcase for how easy it would be to
spot a tesla over a larger
area given that there's enough people
with a bluetooth phone participating in
the tesla radar
ecosystem and
in a way it is allowing to stalk people
right and even though the apple air tech
implements way more security and privacy
features in their tech technology
so they randomize their ids they are
really hard to really
track and then reliably track but even
this caused a
massive outcry in the in the privacy
community that this is not a thing that
they should do of course
slipping a tesla into somebody's purse
is hard but
that would be the maybe the reason that
tesla permanent id never got that of an
issue
so i had a correspondence with tesla and
they said well
we know that is the case but we don't
change it because as long as there's
camera cameras everywhere that also film
your number plate we don't see a reason
of changing anything there
so i think
that was the reason when i made that app
public
and kind of show how big of a thing that
could be
and first it was for showcasing privacy
issues then it was a game for tesla fans
so there's some gamification in there
there's a ranking actually tom is right
here in the second row he's like the
number one tesla spotter for a long long
long time
and
yeah give him
and i i don't know how many ten
thousands of teslas you spotted but
you're like the number one spotter even
though you're not on that ranking list
anymore because your super observer is
currently under maintenance right
right but very good work
and of course it's a it's a big data
collection for work i think there's a
statistic from may and there was about
unique cars in the network from about 15
in the meantime 50 different countries
so
there's a lot of players and if you
found this interesting i have to say at
the moment i'm having technical issues
with the app so just allow it
communicating on wi-fi please if you
want to use it
because it kind of re-transmitted a lot
and causes a lot of and i have to find
out about that
so but back to the thing with the eight
eight characters that are hex encoded or
eight bytes that are hex encoded and of
course it's unique to the vehicle and
the win would also be like the vehicle
identification number is also a thing
that is unique to vehicle so it encodes
a manufacturer id a model type and so on
and
that is hashed i found out
hashed with the sha-1 and then they cut
out like the they butcher it up and say
only the eight bytes are taken for the
vehicle and the identification
so it's really hard to reverse that
process since it's a cryptographic hash
right so what i did is creating a rather
small rainbow table of about
um
20 gigabytes and it has a pretty high
hit rate so i can track back from that
eight bytes uh hexing code
i can see what the win is and can also
see what the model would be of that kind
of identifier i also could find out like
if it's a performance model or worth
stealing if i'm behind a locked garage
door
so it's a pretty high hit rate at the
moment i will have to add new wins to
the index so the austin gigafactory has
a different signature i would have to
add that i didn't even do that now but
there's a little room for improvement
but it works rather well
and
also what i did at christmas when i
found out that
key bin or like this vin reversing thing
i thought it would be interesting to
take my new
tripod and mount an antenna on top
and put it in my car
so the side pocket of the model 3 is
ideal for doing that so i put that with
the antenna and went through a whole
germany to the gigafactory four
and because i'm in salzburg which is way
down there
and i drove along where the new battery
factory is going to be and also giga4
and there's the highway and always
aiming my my antenna inwards right to
the to the premises
and what i found there was of a lot of
research prototypes and you know from
the wind they do have an r which is
interesting but was also was interesting
there was a lot of ble like carjacking
devices things that could be when you
tamper with them pretty dangerous for
the people working there
but as everybody knows tesla doesn't
care a lot of people working there right
so and actually this is a video that got
presented in may and it's been a similar
video two days earlier so that's part of
your homework you have to watch that
several times for the youtube algorithm
please and it's about how you would pull
off the
relay attack i i will talk about that a
little later
and also there being able to do a relay
kind of triggered me and said that's too
easy right
i contacted the buck bounty team at
tesla again
and told them that i believe this is an
issue because what really happened i
tried that the first day and i had like
this two raspberry pies connected and i
had one in the car trunk and one in my
office and i was able to just drive
around as long as in the office my phone
was close to that
relay right i was able to drive to
salzburg like 20 kilometers away i
always had my key card with me because i
just as a fallback solution just to be
able to drive it without the phone
but thing was that was too easy because
it was an attacker set up with two
raspberry pi's like really really cheap
and tesla says yeah
it's a known limitation of the protocol
but in order to be safe please use pin
to drive which is a four digit
numerical pin that you would have to
enter before you are able to drive the
car
which does not really mitigate the risk
of being rubbed right there's also a lot
of stuff in the car which is unsafe in
the end right
but um also i had a similar attack and
also i tried to present that at pound to
own and they said no it's out of scope
because it's not
it's not too binary or it's like you
have to have a key for that and we don't
even have that
right
so and i i was interested then so what
are the security features that you have
enabled in your car is it one
none
is it two sentry mode is it three pin to
drive or is it for both so one non who
has none you have no none of these
features
all right two
sentry mode who's using that
all right one and
who's using pin to drive
one two yeah quite some
and both
send remote and pin to drive
all right so that's a little bit of a
trick question because twitter only
allows one answer so combine the the
lower two showed that only one third is
protecting the car with pin to drive
that means like in many cases attackers
would be able to drive your car away
just by doing a relay
and for some reason sometimes this other
raspberry pi on the picture disappears
it's libreoffice i don't know why that
is
but that was the setup for the thing so
to the left side you see the phone then
you see the raspberry pi number one
which is running attacker on the right
hand side there would have been the
other raspberry pi also with a bluetooth
dongle and talking to the car right
gateker allows you to see all the
messages flying by there like hex
encoded bytes
uh stuff right which didn't make a lot
of sense but you could intercept that
and you could also inspect that and
inject that and you could some do some
on
real-time modification of the stuff you
see
but it started making sense when i was
digging a little into that and i said
there's these characteristics and can
pretty much tell that this one is like
in direction of the car and the other
one comes from the car
but what really turned out to be
happening there there was a protocol and
that's the vc sac protocol
and that's a protobuf-based bot protocol
and um you found it's easy to have found
like indications that this is used for
that
and it's it's used for phone key key fob
for the tire pressure subsystem
maybe for uh back-end communication
because there's some messages in there
that would imply that and also maybe for
other use cases
so
it started in app version 335 and you
have to see that the tesla app the
official tester app is for a lot of more
products than just for the model three
so that's why it's not version one so
they use it for the power wall they use
it for s and x and all the models of the
car and also now for the model three and
why
that have that phone key feature and
that way this is
just been introduced in april 2018
and i said this protobuf file which is
like a description of the protocol was
really easy to instruct with the pbtk
tool in the beginning but they made that
a little bit harder with version four
when they switched library to to wire
which is also the same kind of protobuf
implementation but just by another
vendor and different regime because
protobuf is google right and
it has a very similar output and i'm
going to show you a little more of these
messages soon
so i said this is the history so i just
took like one protocol file of each
version and you see there's quite some
growth over time at the moment is i
think this is not even up to date
anymore so it's been two months or two
and a half months since there
77 messages 45 enums which i craft out
on this really small small small image
the blue
things are the things that are
referenced in the code on the android
app because that was easy to find out so
what's actually active code use
and these of course were the interesting
bits to look at
and
also like if you see and that's like the
first example here
you see like with the green prefix this
is the length of the thing
coming
and it's not easy just to modify the
length and do some buffer overflow so
this is optional right but there from
there on
there the message is encoded and having
that proto file that you were able to
extract and now is also like available
in the vc seg archive on github
you can decode that message with the
product tool
and what's happening is like one of the
easiest requests is to see
what are the whitelisted keys in that
vehicle and that's an information
request and you do not have to be
authenticated for that it tells you all
the key ids and you could also get the
the um
the public keys of the of the enrolled
keys which is not a big deal because
it's a public key half but what's
interesting to have seen is that there
is a service key in every vehicle you
can like use it and it looks like from
the signature as if it was an nfc key
and this nfc key has a public key that
did not change a lot so i think for
years and years they're using the same
service key which makes it a little bit
of a risk that once one of these service
keys
surfaces on ebay this is going to be a
problem but this is not what we are
talking about so we have like also
uh nfc keys the ones that you get as an
owner these are looking like that they
do not have a crypto counter
the phone key does have a crypto counter
is a rolling key thing
and that has to do with being able to
have the passive unlock functions
enabled so like without touching your
phone you would be able to enter the car
like in any other keyless systems
and that's what a key fob would look
like on that level
of course these
whitelist entries are connected with
roles that imply permissions and the
service key would have all of the
permissions all the nine permissions
that are defined in the protocol are
given to the service key makes a lot of
sense and usually as a phone you just
have four of those it would be the local
drive local unlock lock and the remote
unlock and remote drive
the nfc cards also have the permissions
of adding stuff to the whitelist because
it's got a it's necessary once you have
that nfc card you use it in order to
whitelist your key
and there's a message type from vcsac
which is pretty comprehensive because it
contains all the kind of submerged
message types that are possible to be
sent from the car to your phone
and of course there's also like one of
the most common examples you see
authentication request here that's
whenever you pull the handle
it's from vc second you message to your
phone and you would have to answer it
correctly for the car to unlock
and also there's like a command status a
vehicle status where it tells you
whether it's locked or unlocked stuff
like that and then the other side of the
spectrum you have the 2vcs message
message which embeds all kind of stuff
so unsigned messages come also in a few
different things
and these are used for messages without
a direct security context but are also
used in order to encapsulate messages in
a signed message that do have a security
context
and that's some assigned message there
and as the name implies you've got to
have cryptographic keys in order to do
that and vcsec uses asymmetric keys
based on the elliptic curve cryptography
key pairs and that's like the open ssl
command in order to generate a key for
that yourself
and what then happens once you whitelist
that key and you know the protocol you
would have to tap your nfc card but then
a shared secret is derived by the tiffy
helmet key protocol and then you can use
your key with the car once it's right
listed and send signed messages to it so
that was a lot of guesswork but i
finally got that working and the crypto
algorithm used for the
whole process is the galway counter mode
with associated data it's best known
from ssh because it's a really stable
implementation it's really secure and
it's a very good match for the use case
it implements a rolling code so you have
the crypto counter that always has to
increase and then you have additional
data which is used as a challenge
response for the passive entry functions
and
it's intending to
prevent replay attacks of course
also the rolling code
there's some differences though the
shared stickers is 16 octets but the
invocation counter or the crypto counter
for the gcm usually is eight bytes
tesla is using four bytes for that and
that's also making sense because eight
bytes if you see like every keystroke
with ssh needs a next value and here
like every signed message that you send
to the car is like one counter up so
it's like four bytes already a lot for
that
right and there's different
signature types that also became become
important later on so you have like ones
of the gcm with and without a token or
like the present key also as a signing
method
there's like different actions i don't
go too much into detail here you can
read that on the slides which are online
already and also like in the vc sec
project called archive
different things
signed message example you see there's a
pro tool above message as bytes encoded
in here then you see the signature type
it has there's the signature key id
things for the car to verify the phone
i'm talking to possesses the secret key
that i do know the public key of
what can you do with that
since
unrestricted requests include that you
can enumerate the keys you can see how
many keys are enrolled for this device
for this vehicle
how many apple how many android devices
are there how many nfcs
you can find out about that
and
the process of whitelisting a key just
requires you to have
like that nfc card
and usually you log into your tesla
account so that's what the official app
is doing and since you have like access
to the owner api with your login you get
a token you get the win identifiers for
all the cars that you are permitted to
lock and unlock
and finally your app goes ahead and
finds the vehicle and begins the white
listing process
it would send an information request and
get like the public key of the car
receives that and also then sends
information requests to get the list of
white listed keys then it tries or it it
asks the owner to tap the key card
and then with that authorization
on the b pillar or fast care blade in
the middle
this car is getting in the car finally
the the phone asks again show me again
the white list of keys and once this key
is on there the process is done
and there you go with the authorization
timer attack so out of convenience tessa
decided in august last year that it
would be really great if i was
if i was like as a car owner
tapping the nfc card would get in the
car
it would be so great for the owners
using the nfc card just to be able to
drive without any any further action
without any further key card action
right
so what they introduced was the
authorization timer 130 seconds that do
not require an extra tab for that
bad news because during this time frame
attackers were able
to also enroll their own key in your
vehicle without you really
noticing it right there was no
indication on the screen and actually
there's also a presentation in that
video it's also linked on the trifonite
page
also homework please watch it several
times and give it a thumb
and this is about
the staged thing where you can also
force a user to use the nfc card because
usually if you do have a phone you won't
bother using your nfc card but there's
some situations where you in the easiest
case just use it a 2.4 gigahertz jamming
jamming device and would just jam the
frequency and the phone would disconnect
and in order to get into the car you
would have to use your nfc card for
tapping it
and there you go the the
authorization timer attack would have
become possible
and owning a key on the device does
allow you to lock and unlock the vehicle
and to drive the vehicle
but
that's also when tesla said yeah use pin
to drive so people with the key cannot
drive your car they can rob everything
from the interior but not driving
because you have to enter that four
digit key
and that's when i did another video that
shows how easy it is to bypass this pin
entry just by sending that remote drive
command to the car which intended was
intended to be used in the summon
feature where you can say like in the
parking lot police car backed out of
that really narrow space because i want
to get into that
and
this pin to drive dialog just disappears
when you send that command so
tesla was not really happy about that
information getting into public but
right
and then there's something else which is
fun to play with tesla has a really
broken authori uh trust model so i i put
in here cartman there you know that
and it's like that cars
the tesla car always would say respect
or torrija and then would not even
ask
that or
so every message that is sent from the
car to the phone
is trusted by default so the car never
has to prove to the phone that it's
really the car right so this is an issue
the other way around of course the phone
would always have to prove by by signing
a message it would have to prove i'm the
real device right but not vice versa
and of course that's like the next step
was how to emulate it a a car
so the phones will talk to me instead of
the car
and of course you would have to expose
an iep construction like the car also
would do and then it was a little bit
tricky because you would use the
extended inquiry
format in order to
the extended enquiry response which is
not easy to do with the blue blue z d
bus api which i was first trying to use
there
i ended up using
a python library
which is able to do that and there you
go and you can look like that test the
car and you also would have to use a bd
address
and set your bluetooth address
accordingly
but once you did that any phone would
talk to you thinking you're the car
and since you never have to prove you
are the car
you can tell it
like hey your key is not valid anymore
so once i the the phone would connect i
would say please send me an
authorization and the phone would go
ahead send that or with authorization
next thing happening the car says
sorry you're not on the list it's like a
bouncer at the disco right
and the problem would go ahead and say
show me the guest list i'm sure i'm on
there and the bouncer would go
see it's an almost empty guest list
you're not there
and then the phone is convinced and says
right i dropped the key and i say
goodbye you i don't bother you anymore
and that's how the key drop attack works
users locked out would have to use the
nfc card in order to get back into the
car which opens that window of that
authorization attack where attackers
could put their key in the in the car
right again it's like a little tricky so
be careful when having like issues like
that
but turned out that the key that was
stored
in the device in your phone was not
really deleted so
it was dropped but it was not really
deleted that means next time you talk to
the car it would be clear in a short
time that the car
knows the
the key and your phone still knows the
key so it's kind of a soft red
restoration and not a full key
enrollment so again
this could be attacked
[Music]
by oh there's a small demo i will skip
that this just shows how the tool works
in order to drop the key of a car pretty
easy here with the evil bit this is not
anymore in the in the current version
so it's like a little different naming
there but you see how you present that
car with that almost empty guest list in
a way and the phone just disconnects
so but there's a new attack as well
that's new for this conference here it's
the crypto counter confusion attack and
the thing is that
you cannot only tell the phone that
you're not on the guest list sorry you
could also say well that crypto counter
you used is a little bit
smaller than expected i could make up an
analogy story for that shorter than
smaller than expected i don't do that
so
the phone key will ask
and when you tell it right so this
crypto value is too little too small
because it's not allowed to roll back
that counter for for a reason
and tess is really strict with that and
does not allow the crypto
counter to be lower than last time
because of replay attacks
and of course there's also confusion
going on so the phone app will ask the
card so all right it's smaller value as
you expected so what is the value that i
should use in order to send you signed
messages
and the phone uh the vehicle or the fake
vehicle would say
well
how about 4.2 billion
and that works right you can set all the
32 bit value to to the maximum
and that is putting also some trouble
onto the owners because as you know the
key is not deleted even when you say in
the app or right i delete the key
re-enroll it it's still in there and the
counter is still that high
so
usually the owner would have to
reinstall the app in order to get rid of
that old key and been able to enroll a
new key for the same car
and if you combine that with the key
drop attack this is even faster so it
really is a mess at the moment so the
state model of the car just do not play
very well with that
and
it's funny to have seen that the ios app
allows a maximum value of 4.29
an unsigned in 32 but the android app is
using a signed in for that verification
so just half of the value is allowed as
a maximum value to tell the phone to be
using the next
and what's what's happening if it's at
the highest value so the counter cannot
be increased anymore so the phone is no
longer able to send signed messages it's
pretty much useless for that purpose
but if you have if you really de-install
the app reinstall that have a new key
enrolled with the white listing process
of course you expose yourself there
again but also if there's two devices
with the exact same name which usually
doesn't happen in teslas when you enroll
keys i observed that every time i unlock
the car with my new key which has the
same name there seems to be some
security mechanism to be kicking in
because what the car then does is for
some reason it asks me to tap my nfc
card on the b-pillar in order to drive
there you go key injection again so this
is opening up again that vector that
every time the owner gets in the car
once the drive has to tap the nfc card
the attacker could enroll a new key
again
so this is not good in a way
and
this is another example for a message
here it's when
the car wants to know like about the
current counter value so where the the
the temporary tool would say is like 4.2
billion what else does it tell you it
tells you about the token which is used
for that
passive entry
a passive entry thing right so
i said earlier
passive entry is relying on a challenge
response scheme
so it would ask for authorization at the
car the car would then reply back with
the correct counter number
and also
within
with the challenge which is in the token
here built into the answer so that means
whenever
the car asks me to do the passive entry
the phone would use that encrypt the
answer so there you go challenge
response and of course this relies or
this process relies not only on the
counter being increasing but also about
the token being changed very often
because once this token is not changing
you can just take that and be offline
and ask
be the evil car again
and ask the car
for authorization responses
and that's what the authorization replay
attack or key extra or authorization
response extract extraction attack does
it's just that so you get that token
from the vehicle and then you go to a
restaurant wherever this owner sits or
in the airport
and you ask and you just pretend to be
the car again and you keep asking the
phone for authorization responses with
that token that you have in the car
because it turned out it doesn't change
over days so it's really a long time
same token
pretty bad right and then what you do
you collect these authorization
responses via the temporary tool
a temporary tool and then you dispense
it with a temporary tool both these
tools are on github by the way
so that's that's how easy that would
work
and that's been it for the new attacks
and of course there's some tools and
resources on github during the talk i
was mentioning the vcseg archive a
collection of all the protofiles
extracted so far
there's like
the temporary tool where you temporarily
impersonate a tester and do like stuff
like the key drop attack and the crypto
counter tag and you can also you see
like the message you receive
encoded like to human readable form
so it's pretty neat maybe if you need
help
just contact me and of course the other
side the vc set line would be the
tempora tool
and
you use that in order to send messages
to the car that you craft yourself
there's also some
authorization collection mode
implemented in the news version where
you just dump the authorization
responses to a file that you or that you
read from a file and just dispense them
from there
and there's this vcsek archive which
also comes with a decode script that
help you read the messages that you
receive
and there's also that tool which is
basically a wrapper for the api that i
made public on rapid api where you can
put these eight
hex encoded bytes to and it would spit
out
a win
maybe also the model for sure but the
win is a premium feature
and last but not least there is an app
which is planned i plan to program that
it's like 80 ready it's called tesla key
and it doesn't talk to strangers because
root of all evil if you may agree or not
is that the official app talks to
anybody also at moments when this is not
even plausible so like why should my
phone open the car when i'm not even
close to it question number one
question number two why should that be
at three o'clock in the morning when my
phone is on the charger and in the home
network or why should it talk back to a
alleged car when it when it's booked
into the office network so like a lot of
plausibility checks with which are
pretty easy to implement actually and
these will be part of the tester key app
which you can
follow on twitter in order to get
informed so it's still i i think i put
some much pressure on me saying that
this is
released in q3 of 2022 but uh
i'm not losing the hope right so
conclusions relay attacks are possible
nfc key cards are dangerous
and the app should be improved in many
many parts right
and also the vcsec does not stand for
vehicle control security as many and i
did assume i was hoping it stands for
security it stands for vehicle control
secondary which explains a lot by the
way
and again we see that here in that use
case also convenience like the 130
second counter the inability to switch
off the permanent id things like that
are
like really bad for security again
so
you might ask yourself so we were
talking about the nfc card and also the
phone as a key what about the key far so
the key fob is a little bit special i
found out i got one as said but it's not
talking to me so i don't know what i'm
doing wrong i'm always nice i'm getting
i got it a new battery even
and it doesn't really want to talk to me
but i'm on that and working on that
also some credits there is very similar
work by a guy called dax in ireland big
credit to him because we got in touch
and turns out he's an amazing guy
also to the maker of attacker
sandeep who did the noble blino
framework which gatek is using
and and also to josh belder who helped
me with knowing about that remote drive
in the command that makes the pin to
drive dialogue disappear
so you might think well i got that
implant in my hand for starting my car
is it too late
and the answer is no it's not too late
you can chop off your hand anytime
or you just know the protocol and delete
it from the white list right also
possible whatever convenes
so thanks for your attention i think we
have like three minutes left for q a and
also here there's a lot of links that
you can follow in order to see the
slides
to to get in touch with me
to fund my research on patreon all there
thanks very much for your attention
we actually got four minutes for q a so
please queue up at the microphones in
the middle um if you keep your egg
questions short and the answers as well
we can fit everybody in and i think
there's also a little surprise maybe for
sure for quick and short questions
there's might be a surprise in it for
you so please usually i have motor balls
with me but it's too hot for that now
there are stickers tesla radar stickers
and every questioner gets one and you
also find them on the sticker tables if
you don't want to ask a question
all right
questions please
don't be afraid
well
all right so maybe we have some time for
demo
no i'm just kidding
so
thanks for the talk a short question
can you make a very easy automation that
just turns off your bluetooth when it's
on the charger and and it's after a
certain time and turns off uh turns it
on again automatically in the morning
that would mitigate a whole lot with the
whole of that effort
it would be possible to mitigate a lot
but usually people are really used to
using bluetooth because of the
smartwatch they have things like that it
would be inconvenient to disable
bluetooth in for everything what i would
like to see is a little switch in the
app right temporarily disable that would
help a lot as well
it is what i do my bluetooth turns off
off at 10 o'clock at night and on again
at 7 in the morning
makes a lot of sense
half your sticker
it's a special one i signed it for you
later
[Laughter]
all right any more questions there's one
more please
close to the microphone okay thanks uh
first of all great talk thank you um did
you take a look at the implementation of
ble and especially the proximity
implementation of the protocol itself um
yes actually they
is still on there
this is an interesting message i because
there was too many messages in the
presentation already so this is about an
alert that you get or that i got when um
the signal strength or the proximity was
wrong the readout for all the sensors
was too high actually this is not the
there you go so we have an alert there
and it shows that the readout of all the
rs's eyes was too too high for this to
be a real unlock event so there's
something to it but i think it's not
security related it's just for the
upcoming roadster that does not have
door handles anymore so you get there
with your key
and the right door opens i think that's
what this is for and this was just the
confusion that turned out to be
generating that alert so there is
something about proximity maybe we talk
about later a little bit more if you
like i will be around yeah sure yeah i i
read somewhere online that the blm
implementation was
it would also be a good mitigation yeah
i i'm able to fit the last one in if
it's a short question and a short answer
i will try my best i have i have two
short questions oh
don't they use
measurements of time to reply to
mitigate a replay attack
and
the modern car keys use an accelerometer
so if you don't have your car moving
your key moving it
doesn't work
questions i do my best to be really
short in the answer the first question
is like time of flight how long is the
delay tesla in the protocol is very
generous with that so it's like about
more than 100 milliseconds maybe 200 in
order to also have like old phones being
able to play the game right they have to
be really generous there and that also
played out very well with using a vpn
which also introduces delay
second question was
ah what was that
can we app disable the
unlocking if they
so so it's in the protocol already so
the phone may tell the car whoa i've
been moving so i have movement good the
car would then decide whether it would
allow unlock but the thing is this
message from the phone i'm moving is an
unsigned message so you can inject that
and the overall decision is taken by the
car
right so it's like a stupid approach
again
and on that bombshell i will end this
talk please give a very warm applause to
martin harford
you