[Music]
hello everyone uh the title of this talk
is technology did not create
misinformation and it's not going to
solve it either
uh basically
yep there we go uh try not to waste your
time there's a lot of research to be
done a lot of people
are doing a lot of research a lot of it
is fairly awkward a lot of it is useless
there's a lot of wasted money so i'm
here to talk through
what we can actually do where hackers
can help
and how to stop putting good money after
bad okay so who am i uh as mentioned
before i'm the lead technologist of the
duke university reporters lab in the
sanford school of public policy because
academics like longer titles and
apparently that makes us more important
um i'm a journalist computer scientist
i've worked as a reporter and
photojournalist around the world i live
in new york city
and i've been working on misinformation
since about 2015.
previously i lived in worked over here
uh in bosnia with a couple of the folks
up front and so i've been dealing with
this from a lot of different origins and
a lot of different places okay first
thing we're going to do is go over some
nomenclature words matter i hate
definitions they get in the way people
get really pissy about them however a
couple of them are really important
including misinformation so what this is
is it's false information and it's
spread without malice this is your aunt
this is your uncle this is your mother
this is you it's me sometimes i've
definitely done it spreading
misinformation on accident you think
it's real you think what you're sharing
is important and then what you end up
doing is pushing it out on accident
second one is going to be disinformation
say this is the same information but its
intention is different so instead of
accidental these are the people who are
creating it who know it's false this is
the disinformation that we're discussing
and when it comes to fact checking
there's two variations so
this usually uh goes over with
journalists but i'm just gonna make it
just uh go over it real quickly for you
guys so that if you hear it in a couple
different contexts it makes a little bit
of sense
the first type of fact tracker that
really existed within journalism in
general is internal fact checking and
what that is is you do an investigation
you write a piece you spend weeks you
spend months you spend years on it and
then somebody else in your organization
at your publication what have you goes
through and fact by fact tries to
reconfirm a lot of this right so you can
call people you can make sure that the
stats add up etc uh the journalists
hands over their sources and you run
through it
uh sometime in the mid 90s
people started considering what external
fact checking is so taking those
techniques but flipping them out and
using them on people who have made
claims in public politicians scientists
uh you know what have you
and that's the type of fact check and
i'm going to be talking about today it's
the type you've been hearing about for
the last decade it's the type that's
really been uh increasing in size around
the world there's over 300 fact checkers
these days
okay
so
can technology solve misinformation
no
it cannot uh there is no algorithm there
is no ai model there is no anything that
is going to catch all misinformation and
make truth valid
and you know there what is truth anyways
but let's not get into the universal
philosophies here
but it's not anybody that says this is
going to fix misinformation on facebook
including facebook by the way
is wrong
now
is this information caused by technology
this is the problem it is not so that's
a good thing right you can't
you don't have to take full
responsibility for creating
misinformation with technology because
it's always been around people have lied
since the beginning of time you know the
person standing in this you know running
a stall in athens says to the customer
that the person next to him is going to
cheat him and their bread is better
however did technology make
misinformation much much worse yes there
is a burden on technologists
on programmers on people who increase
the spread
unfortunately this is a problem it sucks
i know but what can we do
let's talk about the types of
misinformation let's talk about why
technology is not going to solve this
stuff it's subtle
okay first
what you can get is really ah obvious
and really bad misinformation this is
the stuff that you know sometimes you
can catch this is stuff everybody pretty
much ignores except the true believers
in the first place so what you have is
something like this
the food runs out
new york times is accused of normalizing
cannibalism this was created by sputnik
the propaganda piece from russia that is
banned in europe i found out this
morning when i tried to visit their
website i forgot about that uh it has
been spread by infowars within the us it
is weird it's while nobody actually
believes this crap when they read it
right like almost nobody this is the
easy stuff here's another one
joe biden obviously did not resign from
the white house this was spread on
facebook it was uh published by
politifact
third one
public health of scotland will no longer
publish covet 19 data because somehow
it spreads
aids i i
again this is just random right
this is coming out and so
this stuff isn't what we have to worry
about
when we talk about misinformation and
fact checking in general this stuff is
easy this stuff is you know whatever you
can dismiss this it's all mostly spread
on fringe organizations anyways
so
that's not a problem
this is where we start to get in trouble
these are also fairly obvious but
they're way more dangerous right um
turkish observers us and eu hindering
russia turkey efforts to solve food
crisis and mediate peace this is also
from sputnik this is trying to actively
screw stuff up
right this is trying to actively mess
with peace processes with food this is
going to actively hurt a ton of
people in africa sorry i use profanity a
lot
um
thank you
all right this is another one this is
actively spreading
lgbt uh hate across the u.s this came
from
i it was uh
i forget exactly what publication but it
was a fairly well-known one in the us on
the far right
and
this is you know obviously on the face
of it you're gonna look at and be like
that's insane sure but it sounds like it
could be real
this is another one
in the same vein this is from full fact
in the uk
and then we get to the really tough
stuff this is the this is the place
where people don't realize why
misinformation is so hard for computers
to understand this is the subtle stuff
this is the stuff that sounds convincing
politicians are professional obfuscators
that is their job when they get up on
stage when a newspaper publishes their
job is to make everyone in the audience
believe they heard what they wanted to
hear
right and so oft when it comes down to
this sort of stuff there's different
ways of looking at it in the first place
and then people will believe it a little
bit and that's where you get into danger
so for instance
social media posts make unsupported
claims about zilinski's income and net
worth
this is trying to discredit
the entire ukrainian attack right this
is trying to subtly make people a little
less sure that they should be supporting
one side or the other
same here
this
was published i actually before i saw
the fact check i heard multiple very
smart people i know discuss this exact
piece of misinformation
as a way to show how subtle and smart
you know putin is by releasing this and
showing he's siding uh with pakistan
right
unfor you even see it says rt whoever
made this is good of course this isn't
true
uh somebody fact check this the original
image if you do a basic reverse image
search is it's putin on a
massive video call with like 30
ministers or something like that but
whoever released this was trying to push
a very specific agenda by making
something seem convincing it's not
aliens take over the world it's russia's
aligning itself with very specific parts
of the world
and this is another one this is from
nigeria
every hour 50 people die as a result of
diseases related to poor toilet hygiene
the sad part is it's actually worse it's
actually 61.
um and so they're even underplaying it
and this is
the really important fact thing that i
want to get to
the point of misinformation in general
and this is why technology is not going
to solve it
is that
it is to convince you to trust nothing
it's not to convince you of a single
individual fact it's not to convince
anybody in this audience that a very
specific conspiracy theory is correct it
is to barrage you to inundate you over
and over
and over and over and over with more and
more stuff until you are so sick of it
you don't care anymore
and everybody in this audience is
susceptible to this right it's not going
to just be
your parents your grandparents your
cousins etc it is everyone i feel it's
to promote apathy and benign neglect
like i don't care anymore screw it and
that's why
subtle just taking down and
fact-checking individual things is
really
it's it's a band-aid but it's not
it's not gonna you know it's not a
suture
and so
you really really have to think about it
this way it's like i can i can write an
algorithm they'll fact-check this one
piece of information
great
that is not the problem thanks and it's
probably only going to be for a very
specific
silo a very specific type of topic that
you can write an algorithm for general
intelligence is not coming along right
so let's do something and take a look at
the current stat structure of fact
checking this sort of whack-a-mole
i want to say first this is important as
i said it is a bandage it's it's going
to stem
some blood but it's not going to stop
it's not going to stop it in the long
run
however
i'm not even sure you can fix it right
i'm not even sure that this problem is
fixable but maybe we can
drop it down just
just a little right
okay
so here's uh one fact check and this is
this is one of the big problems that you
get when you do this sort of thing
fact checkers are pedantic
they like to be very specific which
computers are very good at too the
problem is you can miss context now
these people are my really good friends
they're full fact in the uk they're one
of the best fact checkers in the world
however
they fall into this trap as well sure
the picture wasn't from davos 22 as it
claimed
and davos isn't technically a climate
change conference however
the point is that they're all still that
everyone's still flying private planes
all the way over which is ridiculous
right and
davos isn't technically a climate change
uh conference but it comes up it comes
up at these meetings so
is this context explored in the story
yes but is are people gonna scroll past
this probably not
here's another one
uh ted cruz says some stuff about james
comey
uh that obama you know appointed him
right
but that he couldn't
that anything this is uh
factcheck.org in the u.s
and again they're missing these
subtleties about what he's trying to get
at he's trying to seed a little doubt
about everything right that james comey
in the us if you remember the stories
can't be trusted anymore but they're
focusing on the very specific details
about it and just trying to knock down
this one fact while ignoring a larger
narrative and sometimes they get it
right but sometimes they don't here's a
last one
because ron desantis opposes any
background checks on guns
even for violent criminals
they rated it mostly false
the problem with this is that ron
desantis is the governor of florida
uh actually
it's pretty much true because he
supports a constitutional amendment that
would remove all background checks in
the u.s so yes
yes he didn't specifically say that he
doesn't support
background checks or that he opposes
them
but if you look at just a little bit
further down the path he actually does
right and so you get this these sorts of
problems
and i'm running through my slides a
little quick but
i imagine there's going to be a lot of
time for q a so if you guys have
questions please feel free to uh think
of them and come up to me later okay
so
hi everyone
i'm mr happy
uh fact checking is you know i've just
been standing up here talking about fact
checking for a long time about
how it's completely screwed over how
nothing's going to happen how nothing
can work so what can we actually do
what can we actually do what can
technologists in this room what can
hackers in this room what can academics
in this room what can just really smart
people which i'm assuming you all are if
you decided to sit in this camp for like
six days at least and hang out with each
other
what can we all do
well there's a couple options
but my favorite one
is this so i've been working on
this sort of technology for a while and
not necessarily the tracking but the
collecting of misinformation and try and
tracking of the misinformation itself
we have huge databases all over the
world
of pretty much every fact check that's
been made since about 2015. uh i have
one
google has another they've actually yeah
everybody hates on the big companies and
don't get me wrong i will too but google
has been heavily supportive on this
and they mostly use it for putting a
fact check in like their search results
but it's a huge database and it covers
almost every country in the world where
a fact check's been published including
you know so you got the indians you got
the brits you got the french etc um
my question though
is instead of just tracking how a single
piece of misinformation spreads how can
we track who's making this
um
there's this really interesting
statistic
from the center for countering digital
hate that came out in 2021 uh in
february and early march
they tracked misinformation on twitter
and facebook and 65 percent of it around
covet vaccines i should say 65 of it was
created by 12 people
12 total people created 65 percent of
the misinformation around covet the lies
what's this called what they are their
lies around covid
in the world
they tracked they they examined like i
don't know a million plus posts and on
facebook it was like 73 twitter was
another ridiculously large number but if
you had
averaged it out it came to this
if there's only 12 people doing this
maybe it's not as big of a problem as we
think right
these are people with an agenda these
are people that are trying to
specifically put out the information
to inundate you so they're not
you know just random people making
up like it seems to me it seems
sometimes that it feels like
so what i'm curious is
are these profiles
actually trackable not just from
you know when they publish one thing and
see how that spreads which is important
and a lot of people are working on it
myself included
however
i want to see who's make i want to see
what sort of influence a single account
a single maybe person
has on the wider infrastructure we need
to think bigger than the individual
pieces of lies and that's something that
people are struggling with
because
it's hard
this is hard stuff who has anybody in
here ever tried to just
like drink from the twitter firehose
anybody
yeah no nobody
okay so if you ever have i mean i'm
talking back in like 2010
was the last time i tried it because it
was so much it's just a shot of water to
your face like a fire hose it's
literally called a fire hose and you
will be pushed up against the wall
there's so much data coming through
every single second that is literally
impossible for a normal researcher to
manage so you work on small data sets
that is a problem
um because we need to figure out how we
can more quickly analyze these things
maybe not store them
but really start looking into stuff
so
a couple of the other problems that
you're going to be finding
what is even misinformation to a
computer
um context is important
if a politician stands up in the middle
of the day and says the horrible thing
that the horrible tragedy that happened
this morning
okay what's a tragedy what's this
morning who's he talking to where is he
at this this can all be wildly different
right there could have been a train
train collapse in barcelona and also a
wildfire in california he's probably
talking about the
train
if he's in europe he's probably talking
about the wildfire if he's on the west
coast of the u.s
but computers not going to be able to
tell these subtle differences right the
audience you guys are fine computers
can't figure this out ai is terrible at
this
you know what is a tragedy
i don't know i mean it depends right the
definition is very fungible to a lot of
people to everybody in this room you
probably have a slightly different
definition
and then you get to
the biggest problem that i've been
working on which is
matching claims to something you've seen
before so you can start comparing and
tracking that right because especially
well english is my expertise but i know
in this is true in pretty much every
language in the world
is that you
a piece of information can be reworded
and restated in a totally different set
of vocabulary
right so
so someone can completely switch it
around completely change the words and
now you're you know if you're doing a
word embedding model
you're pretty much screwed at that point
because yeah maybe a couple percentages
off can infer some stuff but as soon as
word defect gets a completely different
sentence it's going to start going
utterly sideways gpt3 if anybody wants
to ask about that is not good at this
it's actually terrible at this because
it doesn't actually reason it just looks
at huge typical models
and
when you get to the next point which is
recognizing new claims you haven't seen
it completely fails
pretty much everything completely fails
because you can't tell if something's a
lie automatically
it's not just statistics right it's
people
saying you know various restate
restating
reasons for a war 300 years ago
so
that's going to be the biggest struggle
that we're running into
if we can even get to the continent
in the first place because private
groups are screwing
all of this up for us
i love encryption encryption is awesome
it really makes it hard to try to figure
out who is saying what and where and
when
so you have small whatsapp groups or
large whatsapp groups that
that uh have very specific membership
requirements signal is the problem here
um telegram a little less so because
it's a little bit easier oh that's
billowing um
but
trying to get into these where the
pieces of misinformation
my theory is are often uh created and
you know sort of
battle tested before they get spread to
the wider community is
an incredibly difficult prospect um
one that
the companies don't really want to work
on because that is not in their benefit
right people should be able to talk
privately i agree completely i'm in a
bunch of signal groups i mean
heck the uh
camp that i'm here with all started as a
private signal group we won't let
anybody in but
it's an ethical dilemma feel free to ask
a question about that if you want to
talk about it a little bit more find me
later
but
do we you know at what point is
misinformation worth invading privacy
i don't know i don't there's a lot of
people in here i imagine would say never
um
but i'd ask you to think about that for
about three seconds longer and just sort
of roll it around in your head
okay so
why do we even want to do this though
what's the purpose what's the point if
we're never going to change anything
anyways what is the point of all of this
what is the point of trying to write
algorithms to track this what is the
point of trying to figure out who is
saying what
well
it's really standard journalism
questions it's who's making it
who is doing this
who's paying for it which is often you
know the most important follow the money
why
are they doing this what is their
purpose are they trying to discredit
somebody are they trying to just throw
chaos like a lot of reports have shown
that
again i'm american so i'm going to speak
to this i apologize i know this is
mostly european audience and i hate it
when american speakers use nothing but
american context it
drives me absolutely insane but i'll
just use this one actually no it works
for brexit too so uh chinese
the chinese that it was found out
i was talking to a researcher just a
couple days ago
didn't support one candidate or another
they didn't support one person or
another in fact they supported both
sides they ran campaigns to have them
fight each other i mean russia did this
too they had they would set up counter
surveillance or not counter protest
against a protest they had also seated
and set up this is this isn't my water
bottle's annoying me i'm sorry guys um
uh they they would set up a protest and
set up a counter protest and then watch
each other them fight each other the
point that point was just to show
discord it wasn't to do anything it was
just just throw a wrench in it
and can't and that is a huge problem so
when it comes to this can we cut off
this head can we stop these people
ahead of time can we
censorship is another touchy subject but
can we sort of proactively censor these
people after
again after they've been doing a lot of
things but before they
really build up the momentum and start
huge massive campaigns this is going to
be a problem
right they start small and then they
gain credibility they gain traction they
gain followers and then it's so big that
the major social media companies start
asking questions on whether or not they
should be taking down in the first place
this is
this is a struggle so can we cut this
off can we stop this at the source
so my idea and i want help with this
please help me please
please talk to me if you want to work on
this is can we fingerprint these fact
check these
uh misinformation and lie creators
is there a way that we can come up with
a system that looks at the vocabulary
the style etc and finds deeper patterns
so that when we get a new piece of
content
or
even we can look at it historically
know that at least they're probably
created by the same people we might not
know who they are
we probably won't know who they are for
a while but if we can start grouping
pieces of misinformation it's important
so we want to identify the new actor
early as i mentioned
and
then we can start looking back at
historical
records and information and see
where we went wrong in the past right we
can learn from our mistakes we can
better insulate ourselves
we can
you know do a mea culpa everybody screws
up but let's see what they tried to do
before and let's see what we can do now
okay this will also help us detect new
trends
i hope
because new
topics come up you know every fifth day
there's there's some new
storyline they're trying out and they'll
they're going to try it out in small
groups first they're going to try and
see if it if it sort of bleeds out a
little bit but if we can see that early
then we can start
counteracting it even earlier and you
know maybe that's not important for some
of the big obvious lies but if the lie
is instead around i don't know is russia
going to invade ukraine
i'm wondering if we could have detected
that in you know november a little bit
better
are these big
questions are these big ops
easier to find
so let's
i don't know i think there might be a
machine learning algorithm
methodology to this that can find a
deeper hidden pattern
we'll see
i'm not i i
i want to try i want to try everything i
want to throw the kitchen everything but
the kitchen sink at this and if anybody
out there wants to help i would very
much appreciate that
okay
there we go
anyways um
as i said i talked a little bit quick at
the beginning so i sort of finished this
up a little early but thank you for
hearing me out um this is a really
important topic this is a really complex
topic for a lot of people to try to
understand and i'm sorry if i did uh not
the best job at it i think i tried
um please
try to understand where we're coming
from
recognize it yourself talk to people
about this explain you know it's not
just that single lie it is way bigger
than that
and let's try to build some tools to
actually make this better this is my
contact info i'm not going to put my
phone number up there like i usually do
because i don't want weird people
calling me um but if you have any
questions i'm here to answer them it can
be about this fact checking if you're
curious in general journalism the
computer science behind it
um
whatever you want thank you guys
[Applause]
thank you christopher so if you have
questions please line up behind these
microphones you probably know the drill
now that's the first question
thank you hi chris
the thing you said at the end reminds me
of something called the attack framework
from metra
which is related to exploits and apt
groups and it's both a framework for
categorizing the methods they use but
also naming them and which groups you
use which methods so maybe you could do
like a parallel for that and if somebody
knows of a parallel for that for your
users then please say so yeah that's um
wow that's yeah absolutely um i i think
i've heard about that program and it
definitely was part of
the inspiration for this sort of idea of
like how can
in my notes i didn't bring it up but
like can we create a cve program
basically for misinformation and
spreaders of it yeah thank you for that
i'd love to talk later
from the
behind microphone
hey chris nice talk uh you should be
swearing more this is not u.s television
here uh sorry about that god
damn
um there was one aspect i was slightly
missing that is um i understand that
some people just want to see the world
burn i get that yeah but many do it for
for fun and profit
um
if i look at
people from alex jones up to um
zuckerberg they make money with that
isn't draining the swamp also a strategy
absolutely yeah there are a lot of
people funding a lot of this um
however they're in my experience they're
not the ones actually creating a lot of
the initial push for the pro for the
misinformation for the lies as i showed
earlier there's that uh story that was
on infowars but it was originally
published by sputnik so the russians the
russian propaganda department actually
had something to do with that and then
it was spread in these more local
organizations
oh hello speaking of the russians uh
i noticed from my personal experience
that
when the invasion of ukraine began
the amount of disinformation that we
were seeing on other topics
disappeared
and
we saw a new influx of different types
is is that something that's modelable
and trackable
you know that's what i i think it is
that that's the thing so like if we can
fingerprint these creators that
fingerprint
will i hope spread across from content
topics right so it's more than just
it would be fascinating to see who
switched their uh misinformation
creation from one topic to another at
that exact moment that would be
absolutely amazing and really indicting
against you against uh you know the
whole organizations and such thing
thanks
so um please use both microphones
well the next person or the first
microphone please
hey chris thanks for your talk yeah
really important stuff so
what do you think could be a role for
legislators in this could you make laws
or something that that helps us in this
quest for banning misinformation
yeah um why did i get a stick mic all of
a sudden
okay
can you hear me everyone can remember
okay cool
um you know that's gonna that's that's
interesting because as an american
our standards of free speech are very
different than in a lot of europe um i
mean you know substantially they're
quite similar but there's various very
very interesting uh specifics that are
very different and so
how what how do you do that what is
what is misinformation there's so much
you can never say that everything's a
lie right like you can never
it's going to end up filling up the
court system so much um do you
how do you punish somebody first you
know
accidentally say something that was
wrong yeah right but there there must be
some role for legislators in here for
like maybe big money ban big money in in
on on twitter accounts or something like
that there must be some way we can help
there right you think maybe we'll talk
after but yeah let's talk after because
i need i need to roll that around in my
head for a second yeah please um the
other microphone first please uh but
yeah i was first
yeah okay then the first microphone
first
hello uh so i find it interesting that
you focus on identifying the original
sources of misinformation the the and
especially in your response to the uh
when you talked about alex jones and how
he doesn't create this misinformation he
just takes it you know and then um
yeah so
uh i find it interesting that you focus
on
uh the original creators quote unquote
instead of those who amplify
uh the um the spread of of
misinformation because for me it is uh
you said that it's difficult to get into
those you know closed groups and and and
all sorts of things it's difficult to
identify those um those original
creators
but on the other hand it is quite easy
to identify those who
pump up and amplify right so why not
attack the problem here and at the
amplification level right when this
actually becomes a problem when this
actually gets spread to millions of
views
instead of trying to find the uh
original creators sure um because that's
being done
i want to think bigger i want to that
nobody's really looking at this question
for the most part i want to go deeper
there's a lot of people including at
these major organizations who by the way
know
who these people are they could take
them out tomorrow but they're not going
to take alex jones off because he has
you know five whatever billion followers
um
but yeah i wanna i wanna i this is a
different problem
that i'm trying to focus on uh not just
the spreaders but i wanna know
who is behind it you know but you know
investigate like investigative reporting
you want to go as deep as you possibly
can and then build it up from there
thank you
other microphone please
yeah thank you
um
yeah fake news and propaganda has been
around as long as humanity is around
that
in your presentation you mentioned that
technology is amplifying this but
shouldn't you say
surveillance capitalism is what's doing
the amplification and not technology
itself
could you expand a little bit more on
why how surveillance capitalism would be
causing them
by optimizing all the algorithms for
attention and polarization because if
you push around fake news people in
clickbait people keep clicking or sure
so yeah so that definitely doesn't help
at all
that is def that makes it much worse
but also the fact that you can spread
information instantly anywhere in the
world even before it's amplified by some
crappy algorithm shitty algorithm sorry
i should swear more um
[Music]
is
is re is one of the big causes right
without the internet you couldn't
amplify it in the first place the fact
that sputnik can post something and i
can read it in brooklyn new york means
that
that is way more con that is way more
likely to spread in general if i was
living in brooklyn new york in 1975 i
could not get a copy of pravda right
okay but the likelihood that you're
reading it that's caused by
by this algorithms that are pumping this
around not disagreeing there at all that
is absolute that is absolutely true um
like i said
it made it technology made the whole
thing much much worse that is that
that's that those are part of that
technology is technology part of the
social and you know
economic system yes
um
but
you know at some point i i could have
gone you know if i wanted to do just a
lecture on the economics of this that's
a whole different thing
okay
next question please
so
i had an immediate uncomfortable gut
reaction when you started talking about
building a tool to track down who said a
thing yeah and maybe you could reassure
us a little bit about why you're not
creating a scary tool that bad people
will use to go after activists
absolutely true because i'm a good guy
um
yeah right that's what we all tell
ourselves
it's how i sleep at night um
the bad guys probably have a lot of this
already they're just not letting anybody
know
um that's
that's right fall on that um
it's a really good question and it's an
ethical question that we needed that we
would need to discuss um
at some point every technology you know
technology is neutral can be it can be
can be good and it can be bad there is
no neutral technology and only bad users
and that's a good point it's
something that we do really need to
discuss
but at one point what point is
do we just throw our hands up then and
say well they could do whatever they
want because we'll never find them
i don't know like where where what's the
trade-off here
okay aaron needs going to follow up on
that real quickly
i guess one of the
one of the reasons i sat down and didn't
ask the question the first time is i
thought to myself well most of the
people that are trying to make the world
better are not particularly ashamed of
it
so i guess it would be interesting to
focus on what kind of activism needs
that kind of anonymity and whether you
would be putting them at risk right
but it's worth thinking about
absolutely and um let's have a beer and
talk that over a lot more
yes you can
do probably a lot of more questions
after the talk with a group of people
so going deep into the questions next
from the cyber guy
oh
hi i'm cyber guy um
okay two things uh very quickly first
your premise is a technology will not
solve the problem but i happen to know
that you've been developing some
technology to help solve the problem and
i'd like you to tell us a little bit
more about what exactly that is second
thing um
we know that there are fact checking
websites out there but most people don't
visit them and so most people will never
see a fact check and uh so can you talk
a little bit about how uh what kind of
strategies we can employ
to
improve
the general public's ability to defend
themselves against misinformation to
understand the context and nuances of
what's going on thanks yeah thank you uh
those are great things um
thanks for you know asking me to promote
myself a little um
so the big the so at the duke reporter's
lab the big thing that i've worked on
over a number of years which is
not a failure but it's definitely not
good enough what is automated fact
checking so i said that you can't
automate fact checking and i know that
because i've tried a lot
um
the big thing that we built is the
product called squash i did not name it
my boss did because you squash bugs i
guess um
the
code base is called something very
different but uh basically you can
listen to um it listens to speeches by
politicians debates etc automatically
transcribes it all and then uh runs it
through another system created by a
group at the university of texas at
arlington that can detect fact-checkable
claims from something which is harder
than you really think it's way harder
than you think uh but it's really good
at it especially for american political
speech
there's another group in argentina
that's written something uh there called
checkiado that does something very very
similar and is excellent in spanish
especially argentinian spanish although
they worked with spain too on the uk
folfact did something similar too and
then so you get the full
claim
and then you try that clay matching you
try to figure out if somebody else has
checked this before
and then show that to straight over the
video
sounds awesome the problem is we're only
at about 50 60 percent of accuracy when
it comes to claim matching and because
the topics change so frequently it's
really hard to build up enough of a data
set around a specific claim from a very
specific race
uh the other thing that i'm working on
right now is an archive of fact-checked
media one of the big that's what's gonna
hap help i hope with the tracing is that
right now when some a piece of social
media is fact checked that video image
audio is taken down pretty quickly
hopefully that's sort of the goal the
problem is then we have this structured
data that is completely meaningless
because you don't actually have the
image it was fact checking or the meme
or the video or what have you and so
we're building
a entire archive that lets you that will
automatically download all this the
moment the fact check is created
hopefully before the platforms take it
down and then that's searchable that's
reverse image switchable reverse video
searchable text ocr etc
and with that
i'm we're building up this huge data set
that i'm hoping we can start
looking at for this finger check
when it comes to
how do we get people to
read fact checks
good god if you could figure that out i
have a lot of grant money for you um
the problem that is the big problem you
end up with a preaching to the choir
issue basically nobody would go to a
fact check website that doesn't alright
that isn't already you know
agreeing mostly you know with the fact
that proof
can't that there can be
truth that people lie
and so you sort of have to reach them
where they are
one of the big things is
uh google putting search res uh fact
checks directly in search results has
been really useful
um facebook yes they've done something
good uh they have the fact check
insights program where fact checker they
pay fact checkers to fact check stuff
that has been reported and when that's
done
it everybody that ever shared it
gets a notification with a link to that
article that checks uh what was said
so every single person that shared it
can read it
what else can we do it's going to be
challenging we're thinking about putting
stuff on like you know petrol station
tvs
it's a throw stuff at the wall
yes
there are two more questions in the
audience first the pink t-shirt please
yeah um thanks
i appreciate the thought to identify
the actors behind that especially when
there is a very small group
but i have to admit
out of curiosity because i can't see the
effect if these actors are known because
in my impression is it doesn't make a
difference for anyone spreading
misinformation
what the sources um if i know hey that's
russian propaganda they don't care they
spread it anyways what's the
benefit of knowing these actors
so it's
it's good just to let people know people
should be at least be able to know right
what who created what they're reading
but also this is important for policy
this is not just for the individual user
it's
going back to the legislation question
this is good for policy
makers to understand where this is
coming from that what they're spouting
the facts or the you know statistics and
misinformation they're repeating often
on
you know in parliament buildings uh is
wrong and where it came from they
if we're talking about censorship that
is somewhere where you can start we
can't start if we don't have the
information about where who's creating
it in the first place right so it's
really a bigger policy it's bigger
technical thing it's it's bigger for
it's bigger than just to the individual
user
the other microphone please
yes one question about
outright lies evolving in somewhat
plausible theories that reach mainstream
or reputable media
i'm trans this is my topic i follow and
they see that a lot with transphobic
talk that started as outright obvious
lies
but
certainly evolved into the gender
critical movement as they call
themselves
so what do you do about that um
well
as you said they started somewhere and
so i'm hoping we can find where they
start before they start evolving and
moving right it's it's like um trying to
catch a invasive species at
when it's you know rolling off the
ship at the docks
rather than scouring the forest for it
um
what you can do after the cat's out of
the bag that's a really tough question
um it's something that i've been
struggling with for a long time and
there's so many topics where this has
happened right um
flat earth pizzagate etc in the u.s and
it's just becomes really really
challenging at that point but that's why
i want to see if we can cut off the head
before it grows too big so that we can
stop those early
[Music]
so
next question please hi thank you for
your talk i was wondering um who should
be trying to identify the head and who
should be the one trying to cut it off
um like should it be academics uh
journalist doing the research and on
who's who the heads are should it be
government i know government is really
struggling with the question how to deal
with mean sofo because you also get into
the freedom of speech
but also i don't know i guess government
should do something right so what are
your thoughts on on this one
i mean government should do something
and um when it comes to cutting off the
head they're probably the only ones that
can in a lot of ways them and the big
platforms of course
so
you know it's not the message it's the
media right so who can
you know who has the ability to stop
that spread of those specific people
when they're or organizations or what
have you when they're identified um
that's going to be government that's
going to be big tech companies that that
sort of thing um it's definitely
journalists and academics um hackers
please for the love of god um
should absolutely uh i think should be
the ones doing the research when
government starts researching this of
course they have been right cia mi6
they've
gchq nsa they've all been doing this um
for years i'm sure um but they're not
making it public because it doesn't
benefit them to make it public it
benefits them internally
we'll see if anybody hey where's the fed
come talk to me um
yeah thanks sorry i wish i had better
answers about the government it's it's
tough and it's every country is going to
be different because every country has
different laws you know the freedom of
speech in thailand versus freedom of
speech in
argentina you're going to struggle on
both sides
last question please
yes
so
i was thinking a bit that for now all
these measures research is going into
somehow you know treating this condition
that's affecting the public but if you
you know continue with his analogy maybe
it's also better to look at the
let's say immunization of the population
because maybe there is a fertile
substrate for misunderst like for this
kind of discord to spread because as you
said it seems like the
real you know
end game is to actually you know see
this course between the public uh in
various you know groups or the old
public you know of a nation
or
and so maybe is actually due of course
there is no control group for this
because you know the technology crew
with these new problems we're facing
like climate change economic conditions
worsening you know the decline of the
middle class so maybe
it's also that we should think about you
know changing also
white people are more prone to share and
fall into this kind of misinformation
and
you know
mistrust towards the
government for example
and
yeah i don't know it's more of kind of
an open question yeah absolutely and
that's something that a lot of people
are looking into so you know how do you
educate the youth how do you
educate adults uh how do you make them
less prone to believing this stuff in
the first place um
my usual answer is that's awesome it'll
solve the best information problem in 20
years when those kids grow up
we have a problem now um
adults
it's real piecemeal um the group
politifact who i'm quite good friends
with in the us have tried this a lot
they've done they've had a lot of
success on ver but it's very limited
scale by like going to public libraries
in these small rural towns and literally
saying basically doing this like ask the
fact checker
and
then surveying and it turns out yeah
people tend to trust uh the media and
fact checks more afterwards and trust
the people that you would normally get
it from less
uh the problem is you get like 20 at a
time
so what what what are you going to do at
that point right um we need there's a
lot of resources if anybody's out there
international fact checking day is the
day after april fool's day
get it
um
april 2nd
and there's a ton of education resources
including curriculum
and uh
christ i don't even know how many
languages but at least eight um yeah we
hit the main ones for sure i'm sure
dutch is on there
and um
so you if you're an educator or somebody
looking for
that sort of stuff that's available and
there's a lot of researchers around the
world working on the education
standpoint i was just hanging out with
one she works at temple university last
week who's making some great strides on
it
yes
thank you we are running out of time
thank you for all the great questions
and thank you