[Music]
so hello everyone
good evening today i will be talking
about the smart home i didn't ask for
so my name is neil samia i'm a security
researcher working at kudelski security
and i have interest in privacy
data processing at scale and i'm a huge
linux fan
[Music]
so what is this about basically i'm
going to tell you my story with a smart
home and first we'll talk about how i
analyze network traffic
then how i analyze the tablet itself the
findings i discovered and how i
disclosed those findings
so once upon a time
i was looking for a new apartment and i
found one for rent and decided to rent
it
and the day i moved into this new
apartment
this was on the wall
so it's a wall-mounted tablet that runs
an app in kiosk mode so there is no
apparent way to to escape that app
and you can use it to control assets
inside of the the apartment such as
motorized blinds control the heating
turning on and off the the lights
and when someone rings at the doorbell
you can also open the building's main
entrance door
and more and more buildings
come pre-installed with such smart
devices and they have very deep
integration into the the house or
apartment
and
tenants who rent the the apartment
become
dependent on on these devices because uh
they really have to use it to do
day-to-day tasks and one example of that
is for example if you have a balcony and
you have
blinds that are on the outside of the
the windows and if the blinds are down
you cannot get out on the balcony and
the only way to get on the balcony is to
turn the blinds up and you have to use
that tablet to to turn the blinds up
there's no other way no manual knob or
anything
so this really creates a dependence on
the the smart device
so this tablet can be used directly but
there's also a feature that lets you
pair a smartphone to the tablet uh it
can be an android or ios smartphone
there's an app for that and when you
want to pair it you click a button on
the tablet it's going to generate a four
digit code and then you have 60 seconds
to enter that very same four digit code
on the smartphone app and if it's the
right code then it gets paired with the
tablet
and once it's paired you can use it
to connect things inside of the
apartment from anywhere on the internet
so at that point i was really skeptical
and started to really wonder what the
security of the system was like
so this brings us to the first chapter
network traffic analysis
so i had a look at the android
smartphone app that's called esmart live
and i quickly saw that it mostly
produces encrypted traffic so there's
not much to be seen in the cleartext
traffic
so
i was like okay we can do a
man-in-the-middle attack to see what's
going on and see the clear text traffic
here if if there's no special protection
so i used a pixel 4 smart smartphone
that's what i had it was running android
11 and i rooted it with magisk just
follow the tutorials
and
since android 7
the apps on android only trust
systemwide certificates and you cannot
install them directly you have to you to
install user search first
so what i did is i used an extension
that you can install directly from the
magisk app called move certificates
and that can be used to move a user cert
to a system-wide search so that then
your cert is trusted by the the app
so that's what i did
and
just analyzing the traffic so we see
that there's very little https traffic
but the meat of the traffic is using
xmpp which is a chat protocol
so to intercept the http traffic i used
a tool called medium proxy but we could
have used burp suite or whatever
proxy you'd like to use
and for the xmpp traffic at first it
looked unencrypted but quickly during
the connections the traffic gets
encrypted because they send a start tls
message and then the rest of the traffic
is encrypted so we need to also
intercept that traffic and do a man in
the middle here and most https proxies
just do https they don't do xmpp so here
we needed another tool
and
one that worked for me is called xmpp
midterm and this is what i used for the
man in the middle for xmpp
so here we have an example screenshot in
uh in wireshark where we see um
an xmpp message in the clear so we could
decrypt the traffic and here it's just
um the tablet sending us an invitation
to a private room on the xmpp server it
will see
why that is used next
and to put that in place um
i just set up a software wi-fi access
point on my laptop that gives us a new
network interface let's say p0 and then
use the rooted smartphone to connect to
that software ap so that i can intercept
and collect and capture the traffic on
the laptop
and for the https proxy so i just used
meetum proxy like i said and just
instructed it to save the tls handshakes
to an ssl keylog file and then we can
use that file
inside wireshark just go to the
preferences browse choose that file and
it's going to decrypt the traffic for
you
and for the xmpp proxy it's very similar
it's just that apparently the app was
checking for the domain name that was in
the certificate so i had to generate one
that had the domain name
xmpp.mysmart.net so that works
and then same thing we just run the tool
say that we want to save the tlsn checks
to an ssl lock file and do the same
thing with wireshark
and finally last thing that was needed
is we needed to do some redirecting to
some ports and some addresses with ip
tables so that the the traffic goes in
the right direction
so in the end we see that the
we could actually see the
the traffic in the clear so the app was
not doing any certificate pinning
and the inside the xmpp messages json
payloads were sent and here we have an
example of one of these payloads so for
example here when i was on the app i
clicked the button to turn on a light
and it just sends like a payload where
the body says turn on asset number 13
and 13 was a light
so
i tried also to see
to understand what the app was really
doing just seeing if we could decompile
the the source code of the app and see
if it's readable or not but it was
obfuscated so we could have tried to
reverse engineer it but that may have
been a lot of work and as one famous
security researcher who did the keynote
yesterday says if it's smart it's
vulnerable so there was probably a
quicker way around this so i decided to
move on
and this brings us to chapter 2
analysis of the tablet
so the goal was to see how the tablet
works
and
first is there a way we can connect to
the tablet to analyze it
so it turns out
the front panel
plate of the tablet can be removed it's
just
sticking with magnets
and it reveals there is a micro usb
cable there
so if you have the right
right angled micro usb cable that fits
in the plastic you can just connect it
to a laptop and
see what happens maybe we have usb
debugging enabled or something like this
and so just for the record behind the
tablet there was a hole in the wall and
inside that wall there was a chip
and
there's a an ethernet cable that goes
inside that ship and this is where the
tablet gets its
network connection
so using the cable
we immediately see that usb debugging
was enabled on the tablet by default so
we could use adb to connect and
see what we can do
and just doing adb shell
we see that we are roots on the tablet
so these guys are delivering tablets
that are rooted and have usb debugging
enabled by default
and the tablet runs android 4.4 which is
pretty old i would say
so one of the first things i
tried to do was to enumerate what apps
were installed on that tablet so just
did adb shell pm list packages and we
see that here i stripped the output but
there was four apps that had my esmart
in the name so it looked like these were
apps made by the the vendor
and there was one app called quick sshd
that looked like an ssh server that was
installed on the tablet
so then using another command we could
get the the path but the apk file was
[Music]
located on the tablet and then pull that
apk file and get it on my laptop
so that's what i did
and so the targets uh that i identified
were these four esmart apps so there was
a tablet app manager app ota app and a
launcher app and this ssh server the
quick sshd
so what i did here i just used edx to
unpack and decompile the apks
and sometimes
it could not decompile
all of the code so some functions
sometimes could not be decompiled but it
was good enough for me
one other way would have been to first
convert the apk file to a jar file for
example with
something like ngrfi and then use more
classical java decompilers such as the
one you have
built into intellij that's called front
flower but i tried that and
it ran for like three hours and it was
still stuck so jdx worked better for me
so after decompiling that i had a look
and
the four esmart apps were actually not
obfuscated so it was really easy to see
what happened there
so here we have a screenshot of
some part of the codes that was
[Music]
testing
that was inside of the tablet app and
the
here it's part of the code that is used
to
unlock the door when someone rings the
the main building entrance door
in the code we also also see that there
are four different versions of the
tablet hardware so the one i had
installed in my apartment was the rk3188
but there's mentions of
three others
c91 c93 and finch and apparently some
versions of the tablet are running a
different software or do different stuff
maybe they have a different ui
it looks like there are at least two
versions of it inside
what i also did next is i copied
files from the tablet that were in some
specific directories that could be
interesting like data data and the sd
card folders
in data data there was a specific
directory for each app and in the tablet
app folder there was this file called
door ip.txt
that contained the ip address of the the
main building entrance door so
10.500 that was for my building
and in the code like we've seen in the
in the screenshot before here
what it did actually is
it just does an http get request to some
url on the door
ip
and that just opens the door
so there's no authentication
you just have to be connected to the
internal network and that's it you can
replay the the traffic and open the door
so
that's what i did and
here's a quick video so just for the the
video um i had my laptop plugged to the
internal network inside the apartment
had an ssh server running on the laptop
and i connected to that using my
smartphone from the outside of the the
building to open it
and the smartphone was just
doing the http request to open the door
[Music]
and that's it just open the building
[Applause]
so in my neighborhood
there were actually six buildings and in
each building there was eight apartments
and in each apartment there is one
tablet
and just one building door per building
and then you have the apartment doors
but these are not connected you you have
to use a physical key to open those
so all of those tablets and the door are
connected to a switch and then all the
switches are interconnected so basically
the whole neighborhood is connected
so
they shared the same network and what i
did is
i was connected in that network and
looking at the ip address and i was like
okay tenderlode and 5.7 i mean building
e apartment 7 it looks like there's a
logic in the naming of the ip addresses
so you could just like target
a specific tablet or a specific door you
could you can just guess which one it is
but just by the
the number and the ip address so for
example if you want to target the tablet
inside building b apartment five it's
10.00.2.5
and if you want to target the door of
building b it's
10.0.2.100. the doors are always.100.
so i tried to ping the tablets in my
building first that worked and then i
tried to ping stuff
in the other buildings and
it also worked so
so yeah it looks like
we could open the doors in the whole
neighborhood
i didn't do it for legal reasons but
when i reported it to the vendor they
didn't deny so it looks like it would
work
and so just as a reminder
you cannot open the apartment doors
right it's the main building door you
still need a physical key to get inside
the apartment
so this brings us to the
findings chapter
[Music]
so after analyzing the non-obfuscated
decompiled source code
this is basically an overview of how the
whole system worked so we have an
android smartphone
that runs the esmart live app
and
that smartphone when
you start the app it's going to connect
to an xmpp server
and join a public room on that server
and the tablet runs multiple apps the
tablet has the tablet app which also
connects to this xmpp public room on the
xmpp server
and
when
a smartphone tries to link to pair with
a tablet
and it puts the right four digit code
the four digit code is actually sent on
the public room and all the tablets are
kind of listening there and trying to
see if someone sends a message with the
expected four digit code and if that
happens the tablet is going to create a
private room
join it and then invite the the
smartphone app inside of that private
room
and once the tablet and the smartphone
are inside of the private room
the tablet is going to interpret all the
messages that are sent by the smartphone
and that's how basically the smartphone
tells to turn on lights
control stuff inside the apartment
another thing uh there is something
called a web platform
um
that is actually used by the manager app
and this app is regularly checking
whether there is any commands to be
executed from this web platform and one
of those commands
is actually instructing the tablet to do
a remote port for wording on an ssh
server that they call the tunnel server
that is hosted by the esmart vendor
and this is actually used
by a technician that works for esmart
when they want to do remote
troubleshooting so it just basically
opens a port on the tablet so that the
guys can then connect back to the tablet
from the tunnel server and
diagnose and troubleshoot problems on
the tablet remotely
and they can do this because there is an
ssh server that is always running on the
tablet
so as i said
when we start the smartphone app it
connects to the xmpp server and both the
tablet and the
the smartphone app have something called
a jabber id or jid that is something
used in the xmpp protocol and this value
is derived from
some random value
and the mac address of the device
and when authenticating on the xmpp
server the the way it works is it uses
password-based authentication with sasl
and the digest mg md5 mechanism the
password is just this jid
and sorry the username is just this jid
and the password is a hash
of this jid concatenated to some random
value
and registration
appears to be open on this xmpp server
and this is actually what the tablet
does when it first runs so when they
deploy a new tablet it's going to
register
basically generate credentials generate
a jid a password using that the the
technique described above
and
register on the xmpp server and then
connect using that the next times
so they both join this public room
and when there is an invite
the tablet creates a private room
that is named as its jid
and then
concatenated with at
conference.mysmart.net
and when pairing is
successful it invites the smartphone
inside it and then as i said it's going
to interpret the messages
so i was wondering is there a way we
could
remotely exploit this
because the the room name is just the
gid plus some hardcoded string so maybe
there is a way we can guess the mac
address or maybe just connect to the
xmpp server and
since it's open registration you could
just create an account connect there and
enumerate the devices that are inside of
the public room
so i reported this to the vendor and
they said that someone else had already
reported it
and that they had patched it early 2021.
so this was an actual issue in the past
but now the rooms are invite only
so this is just a screenshot i mentioned
the web platform before when you go to
that
url you will just see a login form and
this apparently is
smart for sending comments but also for
the agency that owns the building for
example to send messages to tenants in
all the apartments
so i mentioned this tunnel server
and
it's actually so
just an ssh server and the
the technician uses to remotely
troubleshoot
and
the authentication that is used is just
password authentication
and it's actually using an md5 hash of
the password that is stored in a text
file inside of the the tablet
i tried to brute force it but it looks
like it's a very long password so
there's no easy way to to brute force it
even if it's md5
but there is another way that we could
go around that
um actually since the tablet runs the
ssh server and we have access to it the
tablet has usb debugging enabled
we are roots on the tablet so we could
modify the ssh server so that
it logs all of the login attempts so you
could just dump to a file
when the password and the username when
someone tries to log in
and that someone could be the technician
right
so you could just pick up the phone call
these smart guys
and say hey i have a problem with my
tablet can you remotely troubleshoot it
and you just wait for them to send the
the remote port forwarding command
then connect back to the ssh server and
collect the password that's in the in
the log file
and
one thing that is also
problematic here is that all of the
tablets in the same deployment so for
example in the neighborhood they have
the same password so if you were to do
that you collect the password then
you're on the same network
so you can connect to the other tablets
that are
in the whole neighborhood basically
because they all have this ssh server
running
have the same password
and these tablets they have a camera
they have a microphone so there's like a
real privacy issue here
and the tablets are also rooted so if
you get ssh access on your neighbors
tablet then
it's game over i mean you can run
commands from there you can turn on off
the lights control the your neighbor's
apartment basically
so what way to remediate this
would be to not use public authentic
not use password authentication for the
ssh server but use public and private
key authentication
so this way even if we control the
server there is no way to get the
private key
and another thing is that this server
doesn't need to run at all times they
could just shut it off and turn it on
only when it's needed and when they need
to troubleshoot they already have the
the web platform to trigger the command
so they could do it at that point
and some other findings
so the the tablets are all on a separate
internet connection
and
the owner pays for it so
you could enable
a wi-fi hotspot on the tablet and get
free internet
since i'm not paying for it
you could also uh
spam the the pin codes the four-digit
pin codes when you are trying to pair
the smartphone with the tablet
so there is no uh throttling when
sending a pin so you could just try all
possible combinations and wait for
someone to try to pair a smartphone and
i guess you would be connected to a
random person's tablet for a while until
they figure out that it's not the right
device that's connected to their tablet
i i guess you would also get detected
pretty quickly but
you could still be able to connect
so this brings us to chapter four
uh disclosure
so just a quick summary of the the
findings
so usb debugging was enabled by default
on the tablet the tablet is rooted
we can open the door of other buildings
if we are on the same network
the tablet runs an old version of
android that doesn't get security
patches anymore
the apps on the tablet are not
obfuscated
there is no certificate pinning on the
android smartphone app
the ssh server on the tablet uses
password authentication so
we could collect this password
and there is no rate limiting for the
the pin code for pairing
so
in december last year i reported all of
these to the smart team via email and
they acknowledge received the next week
then the next day they gave me an
official response to all of the items
but i i thought it was not really clear
because
some some of the points
maybe were not really well explained so
i offered them to to meet them in person
because they were not too far from where
where i lived
and
we had to wait just a bit because it was
almost the holidays and then in january
i
reminded them that i wanted to meet them
to explain the impact of the findings
and finally we settled on a meeting date
and finally we met
mid-february and explained all of the
issues and they said they were going to
work on it and prepare some fixes
and finally in may i notified them that
this talk was accepted and that i was
about to publicly disclose it
and i received a response saying that a
fix was in progress and that it will be
deployed this month if the the final
tests were successful
and then i had no news but i i checked
in
like two weeks ago and they had disabled
usb debugging so it's not enabled
anymore by default and the ssh server
has been uninstalled from the tablet
so in conclusion
yeah smart devices should be built with
security in mind from the start
these devices have really deep
integration into the house or the
apartment so it can lead to privacy
issues and really bad consequences
even
if if it is hacked or even if the system
goes down like you could not even go out
on the balcony if if it's not working
and the blinds aren't down
and if you want cool research just put a
smart device in a security researcher's
house
so thank you do you have any questions
so
thanks a lot we have about two minutes
left and if there are any questions
please ask them bye microphone in the
back please
hi a cool talk by the way um did you
were you able to figure out the protocol
that the tablet speaks to your smart
house so you maybe could replace it with
something that's not
that terrible
that's that's a good question so i have
not looked at what the tablet
does when it speaks to the the actual
assets in the apartment what i just saw
in the code was that it was opening a
connection a serial port and
i guess it sends something to the module
that was behind the tablet inside of the
the hole but i haven't looked at it
okay
signal angel do we have any questions
from the internet nose so microphone on
the front please hi
thank you for your talk
you said
the tablet had a microphone and a camera
and are there any intended uses for
these devices
yeah that's a good question so inside of
the apartment i think the camera makes
no sense because when someone rings at
the door from the outside
you can see them
from inside the apartment but they
cannot see you so the camera should not
be there and in my apartment i just put
a sticker on it so nobody can see it but
for the the microphone yes because you
can talk to the person that's on the
outside when they ring at the door yeah
okay and we are out of time and i would
like to thank you for this very
interesting but quite frightening talk
so one round of applause please for
nails
you