[Music]
so welcome everyone uh it's very nice to
see that so many people show up now
tonight
um I'm not in the real deal machine I'm
interested in new machines and it's kind
of new for me also and one of the first
things I saw was uh this kind of event
and it's called a live coding and I can
bike gem and by GEM is a friendly get
together and just make some nice coats
and see what's uh what's going to happen
so with this pretense please give a big
round of applause for tick 80 bite damn
yeah
now I'm gonna give the world to honestly
because he's better with take 80 and
stuff so here you go
well I'm also not a real demo sooner
even though I have participated a couple
of times and
mostly lost but sometimes one in this
case I'm a scene consumer but I do know
a tiny bit of tech 18 so I can try and
explain what the coders are doing
[Music]
so
let's see is everybody ready is the
referee ready no
the referee is not yet ready
[Music]
what are you seeing
oh
[Music]
so for people new to the tech 80 the
tech 80 is a fantasy console a fantasy
console is not a proper real console
that you might know like a Commodore 64
and MSX a Nas a Sega Dreamcast whatever
those are real consoles a fantasy
console is a New Concept made
specifically for time constraint coding
and bite size constraint coding the
whole idea is that you take a modern CPU
and still apply some limits to it
because demo scene started becoming
boring everybody can make nice awesome
stuff with all the power of a modern
computer so it was decided to make
fantasy consoles someone decided I don't
know who the tick 80 is one of the more
modern fantasy consoles and it has the
option of coding in Lua in JavaScript
scripts in many other languages
but in this case I guess they're all
going to be coding in Lua
and you have a tiny screen resolution I
forgot the screen size
anybody knows
[Music]
nope
240 by
by
136 pixels so that's a tiny resolution
you have a small bit of memory which I
also forgot how much
it's complicated okay let's keep it at
that
and the whole idea is that
[Music]
um
people get a time limit in this case 40
minutes and also a size limit normally
that's calculated in bytes
265 bytes 128 bytes this time we're
going for
64k
so that's a lot of typing in 40 minutes
yeah
I don't think anybody's Gonna Fill the
size limit
um
let's see we're still waiting for the
networking stuff to be set up correctly
super Rogue is doing an awesome job
there
[Music]
and blinner is doing some hat bobbing
luckily we have a good DJ
IO
[Music]
would be interesting if we had people
here on the field that know something
about computers they might be able to
help
[Music]
you got it you have the green lights
foreign
[Music]
yes we have some people on the screen
so as you can see uh
glenry is on the
left side while sitting on the right
side Lynn is on the right side sitting
on the left side
I think we are almost ready Let's have a
look at the referee
are we ready
almost
[Music]
so the DJ can start whenever he wants
oh
[Music]
[Applause]
thank you
[Music]
let's get going
thank you
[Music]
yeah ready
Get Set Let's Go
there is no subject this time so it's
all creativity
as you might be able to see it says
function tick
and that is the main function of a tick
80. every clock every screen refresh so
60 times or 50 times a second this
function gets called and whatever is in
there will be
shown on the screen
and if we look at blenry's screen on the
left we see that he is making some
shortcuts instead of maths in
ETC it's just sin caused by square root
all that kind of stuff makes it a lot
easier and less time consuming to type
and also in case of a size constraint oh
we're at 509 bytes apparently
um in case of a size constraint version
this actually does matter
[Music]
foreign
is going to be drawing some lines
and blendry is going to be drawing some
triangles
[Music]
am I gonna be controversial when I'm
saying there's a Camelot
steps that Lynn is drawing
[Music]
[Laughter]
I'm terrible with names even names of
effects so you can tell me anything it
is
[Music]
if this relaxing life coding is making
you want to join in
you should visit demozoo.org
it has a nice list of upcoming
competitions
that are going to be a lot more frantic
[Music]
I think blenary is making a camp field
with trees or something
starting to look interesting
[Applause]
[Music]
foreign
glenry is going for
[Music]
foreign
is adding some
green functions as far as I can remember
that is
a roster line so L would be the Ruster
line neurons of vertical
[Music]
poking scary things into memory
thanks Lynn for fixing me on this one
wavy keference bars
[Music]
foreign
as you can see
Lua is a very easy language to get into
it also has a lot of stupid quirks
for example Ares start at one
I'm unfortunately all out of Lua rulers
otherwise you can have off by one errors
in physical objects as well
which is a fun thing to do
for variations of fun
[Music]
thank you
Lynn is setting up an interesting Matrix
of sine and cosine
functions there
showing that you can actually start at
zero
[Music]
the first 10 minutes have passed
and so far we have an interesting dreamy
campsite
some conference bars and a whole lot of
moth set up to do some interesting
circular things
[Music]
ooh interference patterns
Murray
or is it Moyer
do we have anyone who knows how to
pronounce that stuff
why
[Music]
[Applause]
don't you
know
[Music]
foreign
that's starting to look really nice
there on Lin's Noire patterns
[Music]
thank you
that is starting to look like a laser
Firehouse in the Field of Dreams
[Music]
[Applause]
foreign
[Music]
that is really tripping up now
thank you
[Music]
foreign
not to promote alcoholism here but demo
scene competitions are best enjoyed with
a nice interesting beer
[Music]
or bacardicola
and for everybody in the tent who
doesn't have headphones yet in five
minutes the speakers will be turned off
and it will become silent disco mode
only
[Music]
luckily we have a countdown timer so
that would be 22 minutes on the timer
foreign
[Music]
is screaming internally but not very
loud
[Music]
needs more cat noises
[Applause]
[Music]
thank you
since I see a string on the string
length I'm gonna be guessing that there
will be some scrollers in this
production
[Music]
thank you
drink beer not microphone
[Music]
deliveries field is becoming more
intricate and intricate with
more moving parts
[Music]
since in the tick 80 within the tick
function everything is drawn
from top to bottom every frame it is
important to see where you put your
stuff if you want to have your lasers in
front of your campers
or in the back
it makes a difference at what time you
call them
[Music]
foreign
if you get excited about this stuff and
want to try it yourself the tech 80 is
open source can be downloaded from
tech80.org I think I'm not entirely sure
but if you Google tick 80 it's very easy
to find and download for your
preferred with operating system
that is starting to become really trippy
on Lin's screen
foreign
[Music]
and a friendly reminder when leaving the
tent please return the headphones
they're pretty expensive
[Music]
thank you
I'm seeing some flamethrower field
effects with the lasers on the camp now
[Music]
thank you
and while blendry is making an MCH 2022
postcard to sent home
Lynn is making a meow tunnel
[Music]
that is a big meow
the meal fits really well with the
classic Murray design
[Music]
foreign
mark
[Music]
there's a drop shadow on the meow
thank you
[Music]
since Lynn is all out of ideas and now
screaming externally does anybody in the
audience have any ideas
[Music]
foreign
we might be getting a field mic for
people to
give ideas
a Christmas tree
a Christmas tree yeah
well why not yeah
2017 defense had a Christmas tree yeah
let's continue traditions
[Music]
handing out ideas doesn't mean they will
be incorporated it's just a slight hint
towards the competitors
[Music]
then add a rotating cap
oh that is a nice water effect that
blendry just added
distorted mirrored
[Music]
foreign
to make it easy for coders the standard
pellet in the tick 80 has the colors in
a sane order
that makes making rainbows a breeze
[Music]
foreign
is doing with the mouse function though
[Music]
ooh then it became a real silent Disco
laughs
well everybody give it up for Io he was
doing very well
and once his windows is rebooted he'll
probably continue
[Music]
do you need any help
okay we'll just wait
foreign
[Laughter]
music let me talk some more
and I have absolutely nothing to say
um I saw some growing rainbows some
flowing rainbows there
that's starting to look really nice
and it also looks like iOS getting ready
to get some music going again
for now it's just still input only input
[Applause]
all right I'm going to take a little
check test yeah yes
hello yes there we go I'm going to take
a little break from chiptune if
everybody's all right with that uh we'll
get a little more energy in sound good
yeah let's go
[Applause]
awesome
hello Dave
[Music]
Souls was
fun
well since IO is teasing me I'll tell
these Souls what's up
the demo scene was first started in the
early 80s in the cracker scene because
all those cracked software you have to
present your cracker group and make some
advertisement for yourself
and how best to do that by showing your
coding skills your graphic skills your
music skills
and those intros well
at some point in time turn out into
Bigger Productions
full demos multi-disc demos
and with the passing of time and
different platforms
there came the PC with tons of
graphics cards and everything became
boring
luckily fantasy consoles were invented
to make it less boring by adding
new constraints because constraints
breed creativity
[Music]
you know what would look really nice
with That Bouncy rainbow
some of those wavy folks
[Music]
they wouldn't okay
then let's not
[Music]
[Applause]
sorry for influencing you there
in the meantime blenery is setting up
some very interesting array
data
I have absolutely no idea where this is
going
[Music]
and as it says on
the Beamer now go to
lifecode.demozoo.org for more
information on upcoming events
which are a lot more frantic because
instead of the
40 minutes that we are now using usually
it's 15 minutes so can you imagine this
kind of stuff made in 15 minutes
well that's a postcard I would send home
to my mother
[Music]
[Applause]
the rainbow is now starting to look more
like a plasma of some sorts thank you
[Music]
[Applause]
I think these are the amoeba now living
in the dishwashing water at heaven
[Music]
foreign
participation is
not mandatory but preferred if you have
anything to say walk up to the
interruption mic and just drop it
preferably not physically because also
microphones are expensive
[Music]
[Applause]
foreign
[Music]
just under seven minutes remaining
morning
[Music]
the dancing drop shadow reminds me of
what I saw last night trying to get to
the toilet
[Music]
[Applause]
that's cheap
[Music]
if anybody wants to add sheep you can go
take your fingers walk to the parking
find the sheep and start adding
[Music]
foreign
with only four and a half minutes
remaining
we have Blobby meows
[Music]
thank you
and on blendry's side one of the most
photorealistic 8-bit MCH 2021 postcards
I have ever seen
[Music]
foreign
ing If This Were a size constraint
competition people would be stressing
out because the dark bar below is red
which means they're way oversized
unfortunately well fortunately both are
almost 1K
which is a nice
Target to aim for probably
perfect score
[Music]
what would be the perfect score well
that completely depends on the
competition in this case the perfect
score is whatever we think is the
Perfect Score so probably one three
three seven or something
um in normal size constraint
competitions it's usually 265 bytes
um 56 256 bites
rolls are really weird
[Music]
I really like the
scene switching in Lin's presentation
[Music]
[Applause]
with now only one minute remaining
please give it up for both contestants
and possibly do a group countdown or
something if you feel like it
[Applause]
[Music]
the party is bouncing at blenary screen
with MCH 2022
a humongous Moon
lasers Flames everything there
watery reflections
and on Lynn's side we have meow meow
meow meow meow meow
with a couple of pretty classic effects
I'm not gonna say whose bars they are
because I'll probably be lynched
there's Blobby plasma and there is also
a lot of Murray
foreign
[Applause]
please remember to put back the
headphones where you found them
because we would like to do this kind of
thing another time in the near future
yeah and also please stick around
because was this was only the first
round
everybody give it up once more for lin
and blinery
and their residential DJ IO
foreign
that was pretty awesome thank you both
question will you be putting them
on demo Zoo
or on the tech 80 auto load e thingy
I forgot the name of that thing you know
probably know it
[Music]
well in that case we're gonna have to
force Havoc to save it somewhere
okay perfect
compo thank you Lynn
we're gonna be preparing for the second
round and I'm gonna be doing something
nobody else should be doing smoke a
cigarette
[Music]
foreign
so the next round will be two new
competitors or well
collaborators
whatever you want to call them
it's gonna be super Rogue
here on the left and guest man on the
right
and I don't know when would it will be
starting but we'll find out soon enough
well probably once the referee is done
smoking
quick reminder please don't smoke
thank you
it's bad for you
what is also bad is not bringing back
the headphones so a quick reminder to
drop off the headphones before leaving
the area
another small reminder
even these monitor speakers will be
turned off or are turned off yes they
are turned off so the only way to hear
all the fun is with the headphones
foreign
[Music]
and if you think this kind of stuff is
funny go to demozo.org scene.org
poet.net or any of the other demo scene
related informational websites
[Music]
and if specifically you like the idea of
bite battles size constraint coding
please join lovebite the next Edition
will be Valentine's weekend I guess
Valentine's weekend
and there will also be a showing of this
at hacker Hotel
[Music]
in a specific room with nice plush
couches and lazy fat boys to lay on and
all that kind of stuff
[Music]
foreign
so let's have a look at the referee
[Music]
are the coders ready to go
both coders are ready to go is the DJ
ready to go
the DJ is finishing his drink
and ready to go
okay
[Music]
so let's make it a bit quicker we are
counting down eight seven six five four
three two one
coders start your fingers
this time we are not swapped so it's
guest man that's actually on the right
and he wants a theme so whoever walks up
to the microphone first
and shouts a theme a microphone runs
back it's over there next to you
[Laughter]
llamas and guinea pigs
unicorns
and or unicorns
llamas and or guinea pigs and or
unicorns
[Laughter]
[Music]
so both super Rogue is from the
Netherlands and is a MS-DOS expert
and guest man who's from brexitania and
this is ZX Spectrum expert
[Applause]
s both have a bit of experience doing
Lua on the tech 80. they're uh super
Rogue has done six competitions here and
won five of the is that right
did you win five rounds out of six
damn
you're good
and guest man participated four times
and won half of them
[Music]
so the theme is llamas and or guinea
pigs and or unicorns
[Music]
guest man already has a field to put his
llamas unicorns and or
guinea pigs in
[Music]
for people new to the tech 80 The Tick
function is called every frame so that's
60 frames a second
and
after that he is doing some clear
screening setting a timer
every 30 seconds of a 60th of a second
I'm terrible at math
and drawing trying to draw a Cubist
llama
on the other side we have super rug
who is doing some more interesting
things and emotional support animals are
being delivered
on stage
[Music]
two perog has a
worry that is on ADHD or crack
foreign
[Music]
you probably know who wants you to do
this
[Music]
[Laughter]
super Rogue is making a tunneling
warrior-ish thing
[Music]
for people terrible at mouth Epps is a
absolute so negatives get turned into
positives
[Music]
and people terrible at drawing a
rectangle function takes x y x y and
color
the A10 somebody can explain it better
than me because it's a tangent thingy
which is when you take a sign and a
cosine and do some tangenty things
if someone actually knows moth they can
probably explain it a lot better than I
can
foreign
[Music]
isn't about
ejaculation but a square root function
[Music]
it's a nice colorful tunnel that is
relatively static still
on super Rogue side
and guest man has a capybara looking
animal
going on
[Music]
Ellie is not just a name but an ellipse
so that takes X Y another x y and then a
color if I remember correctly
[Music]
I'm getting some attack of the mutant
llama camo soft
Vibes here from guest man's side of the
screen
don't forget
oh God
oh my God
[Music]
if you are at all interested in this
kind of stuff please visit
lifecoding.demozoo.org for more
information upcoming events past events
and the most awesome size constraints
and life-coded Productions you can
imagine
thank you
[Music]
well I'm doing a terrible interpretive
dance the interpretive coding
competition continues
with another 21 minutes on the clock
[Music]
I am seeing shocked llama face
that llama must have seen some capybara
or and or guinea pig and or unicorn in
the field somewhere
super Rogue is
trying to model the exact details
of the Unicorn that was presented to him
I don't know if it's helping but it
might
[Music]
next function in line triangle it takes
three times x y and a color
in size constraint coding this is a
terrible thing because it has
an enormous amount of parameters
[Music]
if you're enjoying the music please give
it up for ariello our residential DJ
[Applause]
[Music]
well I'm seeing that neck length
variable in action now
[Music]
foreign
action here
on superoxide
[Music]
and meanwhile guest man's llama is
bouncing around
[Music]
thank you
and the Music Died
so time for me to tell some more about
demo scene
and there are
hundreds upon hundreds of demo parties
every year some are dedicated to a
single platform for example in March
I've recall correctly next year there
will be X 2023 which is a Commodore 64
only party so only people 40 plus are
allowed
sorry Lynn
[Laughter]
there are some Amiga oriented parties
for example I forgot
um Atari oriented parties like outline
where nobody gives a that's Atari
oriented and just puts in demos on any
platform imaginable
there are big events like evoke
um
revision that even has a satellite party
on a mountain
that is boozembly where there's just
alcohol being drank and Happy Hardcore
techno music being played on
technically completely Amiga mod
there's Nova and the where is Nova
Nova in the UK
so there you can only use BS something
something plugs for your computer which
is completely impractical in a European
Union where everybody uses shuko
but other than that luckily they do have
230 volts or plus minus some volts
50 hertz so that's pretty much okay
um there's many many parties and
everybody should go to one when they
have the time the soonest party is evoke
that will be in Cologne and that's the
5th of August if I call Rico correctly
so if possible I'll be there I'll try to
be there won't make any promises
[Music]
and over the years I've seen that most
of the fun demo entries are actually in
size constraint competitions first there
was the 64k 4K but nowadays 1K up to and
I don't want to distract super Rogue
while it's doing some very hardcore moth
what is the smallest competition we have
at lovebite
this is 60 bucks
16 bite competitions so literally 16
characters and 8 byte showcases so I
mean my name is longer than 16 bytes
my birth date is longer than 8 bytes
and yes you can demo it's gonna say in
here I forgot to mention field effects
which is the demo party that happens at
EMF camp
awesome
if anybody has shout outs for more
events please walk up to the microphone
or any other interruptions of any kind
we are also past the halfway mark of
this shoulder well it's a show
competition not really a competition
and in the meantime guest man has a
dancing llama in a field of rainbow sky
super Rogue has a wobbly eyed unicorn
it's only wobbly eyed because of the
interpolation of the Stream
[Music]
nice
and yes when leaving the tent please
remember to give back your headphones
they are expensive and we want to do
this another time in the very near
future
[Music]
this is also the first time a
a coding challenge has been done in
silent disco Style
[Music]
[Applause]
and I kind of like it
[Music]
so any new functions well the CLS clear
screen you give it a color
and that gives you a nice background
color for example
or I'm guessing a field of grass color
[Music]
I like the color scheme the cool color
scheme that rug is going for with the
bluish hue
[Music]
foreign
nice
the Unicorn now has bouncy eyes
[Music]
foreign
the Unicorn looks like it's
put its stand next to The Gruffalo
Village and never heard of Garofalo
before
[Music]
foreign
for people just entering on a new uh the
tech 80 is a fantasy console it is a
memory and resolution constraint device
that take uses Lua in this case to
program
and every frame The Tick function is
called and all the code is executed and
drawn on the screen
[Music]
that tunnel is starting to turn
foreign
[Music]
I think guest man is adding some
rotating stars that represent the
European Union missing one star
[Music]
in the meantime super rocks stunnally
trippy unicorn is flashing its eyes at
you
with only eight and a half minutes
remaining
[Music]
the Unicorn now has flashy feet
or at least legs
[Music]
and On guest man's side we're getting
some
Starry effects star gloomy flowery
things going
[Music]
if there's any developers in the room
you might notice that demo scene is like
naming variables in terrible ways that's
mostly because of size constraint coding
because what actually is a ux a UI
[Music]
gas man adding some more colored stars
to his Sky
[Music]
foreign
is adding some
nostrils or other parts to the Unicorn
we have guest man adding colorful stars
or removing some of the corner redness
of the Stars
[Music]
foreign
trying to prove that he's not only a
live coder but also a life modeler
[Music]
and there's still no mathematician who
wants to explain to me what an A-10 is
[Music]
anti-tangent
arc tangent so how does that work
[Laughter]
[Music]
well the art tangent basically
calculates the angle between the X and Y
so give it X and Y and it makes the or
it calculates the training of the uh
angle of the triangle
so the straight parts of a
H 90 degree triangle thank you so
basically you can usually get the
direction if you know two points
that is very handy yes that's also all I
do with architecture for the rest
probably all the useful things but I
just see it as X and Y two degrees or
gradients thank you that is very helpful
I've learned something here today
I hope you've all learned in the
audience that tick 80s are awesome
size constraint and time constraint
coding is Awesome Life coding is awesome
and that you should really go to
lifecoding.demozoo.org and check out
some more events like this
and when leaving the tent please
remember to return your headphones to
the Box you found them in
[Music]
foreign
's hippie llama in a field of flowers
is Dancing Away happily
and super Rogue is adding some text to
his production
[Music]
foreign
and we now have less than two minutes
remaining on this last round of
exhibition competition life coding Lua
byte coating bite challenge bite Jam
there is no name for this so let's call
it a
bite petal fmch
[Music]
guess man just gave the Llama an awkward
haircut
[Music]
which was meant to be a necklace
foreign
[Music]
with less than one minute remaining
please give it up for both guest man and
super Rogue
[Applause]
last minute tweaking on the
positioning of the lettering
[Music]
and we are almost done in
10.
nine
five
four three two one
everybody Give It Up to Our Guest mom
super Rogue and our resident DJ IO
[Applause]
and of course our referee havoc
well and for me I'm anus or onion and
hope to see you at a demo party in the
very near future
[Applause]
[Music]
also thanks to Dave workhouse for
arranging all this
and everybody here in the audience for
keeping up with us
[Applause]
thank you everybody
[Music]