[Music]
let's get started good afternoon my name
is anjon brauer i am a software
developer when my father
bought a commodore 64 i was six and it
was fun you had those floppy drives and
those tapes but the games were so
expensive so i went to the library got
some books started typing the basic code
and you learned debugging really quickly
because the editors of those books were
not that good so with
some
pencil you start editing and you learn
how to debug and i never stopped coding
since
i'm a professional developer for 20
years been working for no protocol for
the last six years you might also know
me from batch team qt pass or angry
nerds podcast
hello good afternoon i'm lord berglue
other people know me as mendelma which
is also not my real name
i do weird things with computers at the
moment i'm also a crypto and security
architect at the dutch ministry of
health
i'm a hack 42 board member it's the best
hacker space in western europe
i'm a foia request
phonetic to annoy the government and i
like to talk about weird interfaces and
connections
but not today today we're talking about
something that you might have heard of
some people call it corona some people
call it covet 19 and in february 2020 it
arrived in the netherlands
so how this all started and what our
talks about
somewhere in march 2020 there was an
epitome
and that was very interesting for us as
hackers because it was live streamed the
dutch government well mostly rome
rosendale who has a talk together with
breno the winter at abacus here tomorrow
at one
they they did an epithon to do a corona
melder notification app and there were
lots of companies with lots of
interesting ideas that all could not
physically or
lawfully work
so
a lot of hackers had a lot of big mouth
started talking about
laughing at it so to say and then ron
rosendale did a smart thing and i said
if you all know so well
prove it
so
he started hiring hackers for example
brenno de winter and breno started
looking around and thinking
who do we need to do this kind of stuff
well we need people we can trust
people who build camps like this i mean
those are people you know you can trust
you can rely on
so at one point somewhere in october
2020 just after i think the second
lockdown or before
whatever measurements were there but i
know the winter called me and he said
hey buck yeah i have a question for you
do you have some time left some spare
time no
yeah but it's in for the state and for
the world country and can you do a few
hours per week and for a few weeks and
said yeah i could do that okay that's
fine yeah i have to work but
things have need to happen
um so it was for a contact it's a
municipal healthcare organization and
they need a better contract tracing app
and a web app to do their work correctly
so i worked on that a bit and meanwhile
vaccines started to appear somewhere in
the near future
so
november 2020
working working
oh no vaccines are here um during a
lunch break there was some chats at the
ministry of health about registration of
them but yeah there are solutions for
that right well turns out there weren't
solutions for everything there were
solutions for the municipal health care
for massive vaccination campaigns but
that's not what the first vaccines are
going to the first vaccines are going to
healthcare professionals
people in old age homes
those kind of people and they don't get
vaccinated
by the municipal health care system they
get vaccinated by our boat doctors so
all of a sudden i get a call from
bugblue he patches in breno in the call
and brano says do it for the country we
need you yeah just a few weeks it's a
simple web app but it needs to be secure
and safe you have a proven track record
of doing that kind of stuff we need you
so yeah i started working
so 15th of december 2022 it was the
third lockdown or the fourth i really
forgot but we all remember it
at nine we had the start of the first
workday which was unusual for me because
i never get up that early
at 10 there was a basic design ready we
never changed it at 11
they were the first commits to the
brahani banani repository because we
were plan c we were not meant to be the
vaccination registration portal no we
had to be a bit undercover so we took a
github
organization 91 divock ln which is
nlcovit19 in reverse and we started
in making some interesting repository
names there
um later that evening first review so
what did i do commit first well ci
continuous integration pipelines
linting testing static code analysis and
then because we had a design we knew
what had to come in we knew what had to
come out i started doing it all test
driven
and
the next day yeah anjan needs to go
shopping because sometimes you need to
eat eat so he puts on the face mask
walks 10 meters to his near supermarket
and
he gets a call from renault hey we need
a picture for a web shop because we need
to hide it whatever so onion takes
picture of the new banana web shop we
put it online and there we have the
first governmental in the future to be
soon web shop for bananas
luckily help arrives because the second
day of work all of a sudden i get a team
i get two developers from the hacker
scene people you might know and they do
their first commits they
make a pull request and everything gets
red crosses because of my very tough ci
rules so that was a good start next day
my birthday
uh yeah i do a quick remote party with
my family because
you can't do it in person
so then we come to the 22nd of december
and we're searching a hosting provider
for when this might be plan a
that's a little bit of work because
almost everything is closed the
government is completely closed in
december from the 4th of december till
the end of december you cannot request
anything because of the budget is being
closed
getting hosting everything science is
very hard so but we found three
providers and we did assessments which
provider would be the correct one and
what could help us the best and we found
one so
that was good 23rd of december we also
need to store secrets
um all the data that we collect has to
be encrypted and where do you store
secrets in a hardware security module so
they can't be
uh can only be used and can't be taken
out yeah so hardware security modules is
you get the real stuff they need to burn
in tests they need some set up time and
yeah it was somewhere like christmas new
year's nothing could be done it takes
two weeks and we had a deadline in the
first week of january so
it's not going to happen but we got the
solution we found very smart people
working in our team already thank you
brenno um he has friends everywhere
that know things and
we found a solution it's called ub keys
they are basically also a hardware
security module there you can store in
secrets you can generate secrets in them
they are not to be taken out
and you can hang them on your keychain
yeah but also you can put them in the
server in the data center and
physically put a label over it and have
it all in nice procedures and it's just
like a hardware security module
your key is pretty nice yeah they're
pretty nice they're cheap hard they're
cheap which is not the biggest thing
they're available you get them next day
order even on 30th
23rd of december
and they're capable and they have
standard libraries and software to
integrate with all your software
so i said christmas oh no
yep work day 10.
um from this point we have been working
for 10 days straight i mean the weekends
are also work days right and 13 hours a
day
but yeah this is a day like no other we
just continue working uh we get our
first sysadmin on board because well
it's nice to have software you also need
to run it somewhere
and
we found the data center but now we need
to provision the servers luckily we get
a sysadmin and also we get a dba because
what is the best way to store
more
postgresql is just the best nosql
databases
what i was looking for thanks
luckily the dba team came redundantly
supplied because they're two brothers
and they work very nicely together
uh 26th of december there was
an interesting peak in the number of
covet
infections in the netherlands and we
finally have a good schema of how this
stuff should be run yeah it still works
this way so then we skip some work days
because we're working hard
31st of december we have been working
for two weeks now non-stop so we were
ordered to stop working at six in the
evening and not at least not talk to
your colleagues anymore reintroduce
yourself to your friends family and all
the people living under your attic in
your house um there were no fireworks
because it was forbidden so yeah at 12
o'clock we had fireworks do some
sleeping oh no fireworks yeah so do some
sleeping then on the only side of that
on the first of january
yeah we would not do a stand-up at them
because all this early stuff let's just
do weekends and holidays we start at one
that's probably a better idea
also we got the first machines
provisioned by the
new sysadmin
and we had to change the application
name because someone decided
that
brani banani is not something they want
to present to parliament as a solution
for registering covet vaccinations
so the name was changed to brba it
stands for
totally not stands for granny banani no
no it stands for behind strategies from
bison assets or short as we shorten it
for breno and barbara
we told them afterwards
so it's not the secret um then we have
the lolling weekend so you can just keep
working you have no distraction from
other people all management is not not
all management but all the government is
on holiday and on weekends so it's
double better plus goods
and we start continuing um
but yeah now we also i also get some
normal developers i mean the ones you
can or double click order from
agencies
and i've never managed the team before
so i call my good friend ronsbach you
might have seen him
last time we were here doing a talk
together with me about privacy and
penises
um
i gave him a call and luckily we were
just bouncing off some ideas got the
whole idea to do simplified scrum just
every day early meeting
well 10 is early for me
and asked three questions what have you
done yesterday what are you doing today
what do you need from anybody else in
the team or outside of the team
that worked and we also got our data
models from the national institute for
public health and the environment
to do some data exchange because well
registering covet vaccinations is
interesting but
we need some science to be done and
they are the ones doing the science yeah
so we tried to exchange the data and we
found out that exchange should be
exchanged to a secure exchange so we can
exchange the data in a secure way to
exchange it yeah ftping csv files is not
something we would
do it's the industry standard we set
another standard but we also got the
data models and data models are nice
especially within government they make
large big data models you feel so dirty
after reading them that you need to go
to shower so we got a lot of showering
a lot of showers uh january 5th
application is ready which is a good
thing because it's gonna have to be live
the next day
we do some loss testing in our future
production environment because everybody
knows you do development testing
acceptance production but in practice
nobody does that everybody does it in
dutch the optaway or in english dpta
acceptance always comes last just look
at the stages of grief
and if you want to know more about doing
stuff in production there's an
interesting batch talk this tuesday at
13 40 on this stage
so but 5th of january we needed to have
credentials handed out to a lot of
people working in hospitals and people's
homes and all those things
more in buenos talk but we needed
some help to distribute it not normal
companies it was in obtainium
they had no people they had no time so
we called the military um seems to have
some friends there which was not the
correct way to do it but it worked out
very well in the end nobody got fired
over this
ah january 6th this was early for me
seven in the morning you log into the
server four eyes because everything has
to be done with at least four eyes on
there
you delete all the registration data
from the production database
you drink a couple of beers and you go
to sleep
so next day
yes
finally first vaccination
it was a nursing home worker and she got
registered through
brba
good meanwhile there were some other
projects because we're working hard on
this but also there were some other
projects as an industry they were
working on qr codes this one you can
actually scan and it will show you
that's a demo code um
we decided together that you can have
more privacy with less data which is not
a revelation for us but for some
people in the government it's very new
um
in europe like this qr code this
contains a lot of data that contains
first name last name date of birth uh
where your vaccination was all those
details
in the netherlands we decided we don't
need that much information
but we'll come back to that for you and
we start a small uh in the application
but it got extended with the european
connection and now you can travel the
world around with it um
we also started to have it printable by
medical personnel
because that will work for everybody you
don't yeah you need somebody medical
staff when they vaccinate you and that's
all or test um but we also got you can
request it by snail mill if you don't
have anything digitally
you can go to the website and print it
or you can use the app
and yeah those european codes they
contain all that data but do you need
that
do you need for your
cinema for your pub for your restaurant
do you need to know someone's full name
date of birth where they were vaccinated
what they were given no of course not
all you need is to be able to check
their identity so we got initials first
letter of first name first letter of
last name if applicable um and
the date of birth without a year yes
that was all that is in the dutch
domestic qr codes the app was made way
more fancy because it made you interact
with the ball between two qr codes which
switched every minute um it's very fancy
crypto based on hobby by the irma team
if you want to know more about it then
tomorrow at nine here
but meanwhile
we just had about truncating data yes
our first data delivery a lot of people
have been vaccinated a lot of people
have been registered we need to get that
data to the national institute for
public health and the environment
and we did get it to be sent encrypted
this time uh public key encryption
and we do an export and because of the
very slow hsms we can we use the ubi
keys it took us two hours well you do
that in a screen because four eyes two
people looking at the screen
over jitsi and we do the export it runs
for two hours and the sysadmin says well
my screen is stuck i said well mine
isn't so i type hoi space exclamation
mark exclamation mark so the next line
was command.found and the output in
file.nc was empty
because the other guy was pressing enter
a lot
yes
so we run again another two hours we
copy that stuff over to the national
institute for health and environment
and the other people in the jet seas
shout date day date i type date and
ta-da we had 10 minutes to spare then i
walked out in the snow to take a very
relaxing walk and i got a nice t-shirt
in the mail a week later
so
but back to the serious business the qr
codes um it should be work for everybody
because um if you are making something
mandated by by law then it should work
for everybody um what we did was um make
a basic solution that worked for
everybody healthcare workers just type
in everything and press print and but we
don't hate healthcare workers so we did
optimizations it's the 80 20 rule if you
can optimize it for 80
and you have only 20 of work left and
then you do it again and then you have
20 of 20 left and you do that a few
steps like four or five and then
healthcare workers don't start to hate
you it's very nice
um
yeah and also we try to do credentials
for all the images but sometimes it's
very hard to find meme sources so if you
know who made this please tell us we'll
fix it
but yeah there are exceptions to
everybody every rule
you can make as nice system as you want
but not everybody gets fascinated by the
municipal health care organs qr code via
dda because it's registered somewhere
some people don't
even
have have a way to authenticate to the
government via dgid or
didn't get vaccinated in europe yeah um
because they travel abroad by a plane or
by ship and they get vaccinated in a
walmart in america and then yes how do
you get in touch qr code um there are
solutions made for that it's a lot of
hard work
but the idea was leave no one behind but
also
we try to have a bit of data hygiene
because else you get a data dollhoff
incomplete data really hurts people if
you need two vaccinations and only one
is popping up
the other one is gone and now somebody
says yeah but you can print it but it's
not complete and but i need to take an
airplane to my family in somewhere for
my parents who are on their deathbed
yeah no you can't fly because now your
data is not registered correctly well
yeah business rules are important you
should define them well so what does
this data mean what does the data
represent delete all the data you don't
use
always because um
if it leaks if it if it's not there it
cannot leak you cannot abuse it you
cannot use it for things that it's not
supposed to be used for
we're hackers we misuse everything
what's not supposed to be used for don't
do that with people's personal data and
especially not with sensitive data like
medical data and
when you do something with data always
refresh at source
there's something with caching who'll
come to that
and you should have exception routes
because and have them ready day one
because you can't have true equity if
all marginalized people who already have
to do
run through hoops have to do it again
and again and and again but also you
have to prevent those exemption routes
that we've built
to become the rule
uh it would be very stupid if you have
someone go through loops go to their
care professional get a printed qr code
and have to redo that every three months
so
we worked hard on getting that stuff
done
also for attributions you know
newspapers say
source
youtube so we say source newspaper
oh
all that hard work
comes to in
to a point of going live again
the european qr code system gets live
and our minister of health wants to meet
the people that build it
normally
in the dutch government all those kind
of conversations go through cisco webex
which is a terrible chat application
and
the
we said yeah that's fun but no just come
to our place come to meet hack42 yitzi
and he did and the first thing he does
is send this twitter image
so yeah that's easy to get it cleared
because it's already public and
the second thing we do is ask him are
you wearing a seatbelt
and yes he showed he was wearing a seat
belt uh so yeah of course and the
informal tone was set yes
so then you have had half will have a
lot of discussions about political about
2d 3g 4g 2g plus 2d minus 3d plus 3d
mining 1.5 g 2.5 g really they invented
a whole lot number of g's for this um
it's a lot of political discussion and
you never know what the outcome is for
people who don't know anything about the
g's it stands for
it was all german but in dutch vaccine
and it's uh that they made different uh
um combinations of that and gave it
different numbers and nobody knows what
it means
so but we had to prepare for all the
options because then the politics might
say that next week we should have these
rules and that should be enforceable and
how well
we were doing news driven development
and some places because the information
was faster through news outlets like
new.nl
than through the official lanes of
communication so make it configurable
sign your configurations and have it
work that way
yeah so then we come to the two hardest
problems with computer
naming things cache validation
especially for amy off by one errors
so off by one hour's birthdays
um a birthday is not a date
it can be
a birth year it can be birth year in a
birth month so you don't have birthday
don't store it in a date column you see
everybody does it everywhere and it's
giving us
real lot of
hassles to do this some points in the
government they do this correctly and
that's where it gets starts to get
incompatible and also not everybody has
a legal birth date
we didn't know that so the second thing
is naming things or we name a lot of
things this is called the stage all the
things are humans we name them
not everybody has a first name not
everybody has last name not everybody
even has a name or a legal name and for
character sets
my dear friends at every government
place that use it latino one is not an
option use utf-8
and for one special department taylor
text encoding should not be used anymore
since the 90s
[Applause]
cashier validation yes so how do you
delete data you don't know about because
we as already said don't cache start at
source if possible but if somebody
prints out a qr code or has a yellow
booklet and you want in to invalidate
the information in there is that even
possible
we know that it's not impossible until
you start attaching claymores to yellow
booklets which was declined by request
so
it's impossible at some point so always
assume that once data is out there it's
like
oil it will stay there but we'll get
back to this
yes
good thing we have all those exception
routes because estimates are always low
how many people do you think will need
to be registered via those systems well
ten thousand fifty thousand well
it was more like a million
queues started showing up at schiphol
airport because people couldn't fetch
their test data in the app
people didn't even know they needed to
be tested and all the test facilities
couldn't get their data out soon enough
we had people whose name in the passport
was different than in the government
database
which is weird because they should be
have been made from that database but um
yeah things happen um but this is a
manual labor intensive process so if you
want to scale it up you need more people
and that's what we know all that
shortage of workers it starts to get
more expensive so try to avoid it try to
avoid big data when i was waking up that
morning um i read that there were queues
at scripple i do a stand-up where is our
sis admin well he's at skripal what is
he doing he's buying new inkjets for the
inkjet printers why were they inkjet
printers or was it breno that got your
body inkjet printers it was breno
he was setting up the network because
public wi-fi was a bit flaky
anyway big data yeah big data we try to
avoid it
we try to have decentralized storage
because sources are decentralized and we
want to have a source much as possible
we use strong authentication
the client controls the data so you get
to first see what data is fetched from
you you can review it before you even
start to use your data and we use as
little as data as possible
we tried to talk to the european union
about it
that sadly failed in some parts
so ethics and social impact uh in the
netherlands we have a democrat democracy
well a constitutional democracy
we have a parliament they make rules and
then we try to implement those law with
as
most freedoms as possible
and
that is really hard apparently for
government workers because normally they
just look at laws and go by oh yeah we
could interpret this very strict
try not to
also the covet virus is hard to battle i
mean we are missing a lot of people at
this event
because they got tested positively and
now had to go home
also outcome isn't sure we don't know
how this thing goes how long it will
continue so we have to implement
failsafes for a lot of that stuff and
all the temporary restrictions we have
to
make sure encode that everything that is
temporary
stays temporary yeah because normally as
we hackers know nothing is as temporary
or as as permanent as a temporary fix
yeah the the cable you duct taped to the
wall 10 years ago still hangs there it
works perfectly you're never going to
fix that
that's not an option if you do
things like this
also
when battling the coronavirus um yes you
have your expectations that vaccines
work
um we found out that they don't work
just a second after you got them uh
dance with johnson was not a very good
experiment
but you don't know if and if it worked
and vaccinations people couldn't get
infected it would be
very fine and then some of the solutions
would have worked better so you don't
know but if you wouldn't have built it
you couldn't even use it then
so then we come to the privacy and the
security part of it um we have uh
privacy we have security both are very
difficult to do correctly and a lot of
people have this false
idea that there is a balance of privacy
and security no there is not that is
utter you can't have privacy
without security you can't have security
without privacy so you make sure it's
encrypted everywhere if your data your
database is encrypted and you had
database administrators cannot see the
data
when they falsely
might see some data they see encrypted
blobs and that's it
and that's protecting them but it's also
protecting the data so privacy and
security come from both ends
so we try to implement technical
security first that means that like
encryption of data and then procedural
security like database administrators
are not allowed to view the data that's
the second one and we implemented them
both of course in every occasion because
that's the best thing you can do
security is like an onion layers oh yes
finally i got my vaccination
and i can load it into the app that's
awesome next
yes
in the future because what are you still
doing there
now we're
we're helping out
we found out that uh
there are some big um
challenges
challenges this was a challenge thank
you there are some big challenges within
the government to replace smart cards
with authentication methods
we need to open source all the things
and every thanks to the question
everything we open source is a european
union public license
but we have more to do because at one
point
our government decided
that we don't use qr codes in the
netherlands anymore so the world privacy
preserving knight thing
yeah it's gone
um it's still open source it's still in
source you can still build it but it's
gone it's not used anymore you're not
allowed to use it anymore but what about
those printed qr codes then yeah they
still exist and you can rebuild source
and then check them because the public
key is available so i can see oh yeah
this was signed by the dutch government
yes yes yes
so we found a solution it's a wall talk
to explain why this perfectly makes
sense but
the idea is that it might be a very good
idea to publish the private key
because once you have published a
private key you can do everything with
it you can check the integrity was it a
real good private key as you promised
always
but also you can make any qr code in
anything in the past or the future with
this key as this key is no longer in the
trusted list
it's not it's nothing anymore so
um
tomorrow night i have a talk sorry
tonight in clairvoyance i have a talk at
10.
i'm not going to deep in this but if you
have questions about it please ask me
afterwards i have a question why is that
keynote in an hsm
oh yeah we did fancy crypto and the hsms
don't support those
yes
so that's why you need to go to the gabi
tool
um so we have some time left i think for
the questions heroin yes
and if you don't know a question you
cannot come up with a question we
provided you with an array of example
questions
[Applause]
and um
i think that's very very kind for the
audience but i'm also curious if there
are other questions than these or people
have questions which relate to this list
perhaps first also check if they're from
the signal any questions not yet
who wants to start with the first
question
running
running for the microphone of course
what was the most complicated thing that
you had to do what's the most
complicated challenge that you gave
because you now had a story of all the
challenges or at least the bigger ones
but what was the hardest one to solve
government
try to talk with normal civil
government workers
who have been there for years and do
everything in procedures that have been
existed since the stone ages
yeah i kind of agree yeah
so
the whole 2g discussion then went going
on
um
a lot of people would say well 2g
excludes people from society because
they would have to be vaccinated to get
in somewhere did you have any
discussions within the team yes yes
actually yes not only with the team
because this was a real discussion point
with us and we did have a discussion
with the minister who called him about
this because he knew we as a team uh
were very vocal about it and were very
uh ahead our opinions and we had also
discussion with the minister it was an
open discussion um which was not
recorded and there are no notes from but
so we could really say what was on our
minds yeah we could tell our points of
view why we thought 2g was a very stupid
idea and we got answers why
the government wants or at least the the
thought about it yeah why they did want
it and it came down to
lowering the number of cases in hospital
because vaccinated people get less
seriously ill
so it wouldn't stop the number of
infections it would just lower the
pressure on caretakers
you're welcome some more questions
so you had a slide about government
models and i gather you don't like them
but could you maybe uh elaborate on that
or is that yeah
um no no no i can't i can't explain this
it's uh because they make data models
and they make data models all the life
and some people have the job of making
data models so their only job is make
more data model in the data model so you
get
pages and pages of very old made to be
printed on matrix printers data models
that are extended with different images
to be printed on
needle printers and really that's what's
existing right now if we print some of
the data models of
the rfvm what is it the
public health and environment
database they use for uh for covet
tracking
if we would print it in readable print
it would take this entire screen for
that data model of interconnected lines
with all kinds of
weird combinations of older data types
so
they they put every exception in the new
version of the data model and then and
every time it was have you seen this bit
in quadrant a 53 35 and i'm looking at
ah i have to take another shower
because so this is
so good
does this answer your question
okay
so
how many systems did you guys have to
develop to get all this working
and are you still developing new ones
nah we're not really developing new ones
we started with binding uh older ones
together because the some of it because
of the speed of development had a lot of
shared code and why not just combine
them into a shared code base uh for
maintainability so we made one
we started with number three and we got
to 12 and then we started with engine
number three and we went to ten
and then we have some other systems so
you can calculate i think it's
35-ish uh different
github repos yeah something
unfortunately not 42 no but there are
other teams working
how are you even allowed to give this
talk um because
because because because very easy
you need to know how the government
works we were told upfront that you need
permission so we know that yeah without
permission giving this talk is
frowned upon and we could get uh some
warning that was the worst that could
happen but okay um so what we did we
asked somebody who was allowed to give
some clearance and uh he asked advice at
some other person the other person said
yeah my advice is to do it and he said
yes and as this government they didn't
read the documents because they didn't
have the documents
that's how it works
[Applause]
i believe in the beginning there was
also talk about the tax services
being the hosting party uh that was uh
for corona melder that was before we
started
and yes the dutch tech services do a lot
of i.t
and so they have housing and they might
have something available
that didn't go very well due to some
things in parliament in the press it was
not the people there it was uh more it
was politically not doable and then yeah
the team then uh uh found a solution so
that's all fixable the tax office does
work for us as we said there's a way to
get printed
documents sent via snail mail
we wanted to get the seibe to print them
because they're the most famous for
getting envelopes on dutch people's
doorsteps
like all the traffic tickets and stuff
they didn't want to couldn't whatever uh
who's the second best at printing and
getting it on your doorstep the blasting
deans so the text office is our postal
service
okay thank you you're welcome
and i really really want to know the
answer to the last question oh that's
very easy i can explain this in detail
yes at once we had the ministry of
minister of justice
mr harper house and he said those people
at ndo they're they're magicians and
then our reply was it's only magic if
you don't know what you're doing
[Applause]
very good question
corona check is currently shutting down
or at the end of
of development and i was wondering that
published a private key
um
what if corona check ends up being
necessary in some form then then you
just what happens then you just generate
new private key put a public key of that
private key in the trusted list in the
app and you can continue working only
everybody needs new new documents to
prove uh against what the rules are new
code yeah the printed codes are expiring
anyway in the near future because of the
data restrictions that were on there so
um they everybody would already have to
print a new paper then do it with a new
key if it needed to be used again
thanks
you're welcome some more questions we
have example questions
left
please please
does not exist
yes yes it exists and it is running uh
in uh trial now
uh
pop is uh well we were talking about
exception routes some people in the
netherlands don't have a social security
number for example ukrainian refugees if
they come here and they are not
vaccinated they are asked would you like
to be vaccinated and then they get
vaccinated by the municipal healthcare
organization
of the municipality of wherever their uh
asylum seeker home is
and
how do they get their data well they can
now with their uh patient id and their
date of birth and the second factor is
either sms or email
and pop is not a vlan but is a product
of the vlad team and fly is not a pop
very clear yes next question
so i wonder why the
european qr codes are bigger
than the netherlands qr code even though
the storm
because because they now that's not true
the dutch qr codes are uh sometimes
bigger
um but the europeans contain a lot more
data
so that was my question actually why the
netherlands is bigger in size but has
less data because of the encryption
that's being used to provide you more
privacy
so um yeah go to the gabi talk if you
want to know all about how they use it
yeah that's two more nerves sunday
nine i think uh some more questions
can you repeat the question
yeah what what's with all the cats yes
once with all the cats nice very simple
we had breno on our team and branno uh
yeah as we said at the start uh the
first application i started working on
was called brani banani and that wasn't
for a big loaf of bananas or anything
but
one of breno's cats is called brani and
the nickname is banani so brani and
banani became the first two parts of the
stack and then later his other cat which
is a really whiny whiny cat called zyko
oh no
so we got kaiko and zyko in there as
modules and we just started naming
everything cat names so if we had a new
module we're just asking the team does
anybody have a cat name for us oh yeah
we have casper oh yeah we have millions
the good thing is i have a cat that's
called monster
so that's with all the cat names
question here from the back
is it a good idea to block the recall
certificates using uvci specifically
um
this is a good idea to to list
yes and no it's very hard to identify
which certificates you need to recall
and it's only possible with the european
certificates because they have an
identifier in it the dutch ones are
privacy preserving as said
and
there are ways to
block the ufc ice and there's now a
scheme in europe to do that and
currently the only ones i know that are
blocked are the very obvious uh fake
ones we had the ad of hitler qr code in
the media
mickey mouse
but also ones that are found in
in some stings with massive collections
of uh fake documents
yeah and also the qr code from emmanuel
was blocked in the netherlands is it the
smart way of of blocking i don't i i
don't know there are not so many ways
you can do this because privacy also
makes risk but can you take somebody's
passport when it's stolen if you don't
know who stole it
does that answer the question
more or less
well you can find us afterwards for more
details if you want
more questions
otherwise i do have one because
you have this really nice list and you
know all the answers because you
prepared them yeah are there any
questions where you would not know the
answer to or would not be allowed to
there are two questions i'm not allowed
to answer
but they're very private
all the rest is now
let's make this very clear we work at
the government the government is uh open
there are laws about it there are laws
about reusable documents codes other
things the laws about being open
we know that we work there we know and
and you get used to it that your email
that you're sending there can be
published in some point in time if
somebody requested
um it's yeah we're very open so if you
say if there's some secrets you have the
passwords but i don't have access to the
computers so it would be my
password the only nda i have signed is
for medical data that i see so
nope
all right anyone for the final question
the question is oh monkey box
um the question is uh
does this also can be used for other uh
diseases
uh well yes uh we already have uh monkey
box check monkey box uh melder and
everything linking to the current corona
infrastructure and we've made it very
configurable so
yeah it's it's
virus agnostic so to say
so and since it's open source yeah it's
very easy to fork and make a monkey box
variant
yes we anticipated on reusability
yes i'm not going to repeat what set he
was here in france because
so if people really want to know perhaps
they should check on you um because uh
indeed that's andy's talk so with a very
big applause for the speakers wonderful
thank you very much
a very well deserved applause thank you
thank you thank you
you