[Music]
welcome everybody
tonight this first night
we have someone here
who is going to introduce us to how to
inscript resist and subverse
in the governance of the internet
infrastructure i hope at least i'm quite
interested
in what nielsen uber has to tell us here
because um we might not be afraid you
told us that we'll not have to be afraid
about your talk
so keep your weapons down um
keep your phones open
and
i give you the word thank you give a
warm welcome to niels
let's go i am super excited to be here
today with you on uh on mch and i'm
wired up like beyonce so uh let's hope i
can give you the
that you are looking for tonight so
thanks so much for being on your first
night and chose not to be dancing but to
actually think and talk about the
governance of the internet
infrastructure i got a little test here
on the screen
and that says that the internet
architecture social technical imaginary
guides facilitates and legitimates the
internet infrastructure but actually the
infrastructural norms serve to evaluate
and instruct the governance of the
internet
right now you don't understand what this
means by the end of the talk you will so
let's run that test again by the end and
then we'll see where we are and if i've
succeeded
i'm neil stenover i'm a postdoctoral
researcher at the university of
amsterdam
and we'll talk to you about my phd
thesis
and it's very cool that i'm talking
about this here
because this work actually started at
home
and that's where i met some of the
people that i'm still doing the research
now with so that's something i'm very
excited about
the work continued at shaw
and now i'm presenting it to you at mch
so that is great
i got five of the copies of my book for
you so if you actually like it
come and pick it up who wants a book
yes can someone distribute it thank you
so
then you got a way to read it and book
the pdf is in the description so you can
read it that way as well
and at the end of the talk i got a fun
announcement for the future
so i look at communication
infrastructures
and i do that because i think that
changes to the globalizing world are
being written not in the language of law
and diplomacy but rather in the language
of infrastructure
and if infrastructure is the language of
the changes then standards are its
grammar and that's why i look also at
the standard setting of the internet
and when i talk about the internet
infrastructure and its governance i
explicitly look at the interconnection
and physical layer of the internet
the physical layer are all the antennas
satellites cables and routers and the
interconnection layers are actually what
make it into one network
and this happens in institutions of
three and four letters such as the ietf
icann rers ieee 3gpp and itu
but this is not a new thing
communication infrastructures have been
around for the longest time
around
in the 19th century the british had a
telegraph line that covered all of the
world
and that was important because it
changed the british empire
from a colonial
to an imperial power
it allowed the british to have
control
directly from london
over an uh empire that vastly expanded
topological means
a topographical means and they
controlled it through topological means
through a network
communication networks are always a
proxy for power and are intrinsically
linked with militarism and colonialism
the telegraph as i said changed
colonialism to imperialism by
establishing centers of power
so
networks established new centers of
power
and in war for instance the first world
war the first thing that happened was
that the allies cut the connections of
the uh of the german telegraph lines
now in ukraine we see again that
infrastructure is an object of attacks
however
there is a difference right now
because all parties seek to make the
network function not only for them but
still connected into this global network
this says something about the meaning of
the internet
we now live in late capitalism
where countries were ready to shut off
networks of capital
such as swift
but they were not ready to impose
sanctions on the internet infrastructure
so what this means that internet and
communication infrastructures are
foundational for how the whole world is
run so it's probably very important that
we look at how these networks are
governed because that also says
something about how the world works
and infrastructures are always
relational
they are not just the physical things
the things that we can kick
but there are also the standards the
agreements the labors and institution
that make them function
and when we talk about networks
we do not we should not think about that
global network as one thing
because something can be a global
network and we can be very different in
different localities
so we should listen to people on
different parts of the world such as the
great thinker in ukraine svetlana
matayenko who is working and writing in
ukraine right now please follow and
follow her work
but it also means we should think about
people who have other practices and
languages for instance ramsey nasser
once wrote a programming language in
arabic
and he called it engineering performance
art
and i asked him why ramsay do you call
this engineering performance art why is
it not just engineering well he said
because it will never work
because the internet structurally
rejects
everything that's not in a latin
language
that means that the earliest application
of the internet or one of the first
email
works perfectly for many of us
but if you if your name is in a
non-latin language friends if you're
chinese
and you cannot have an email address
with your own name in your own script
that means that that global internet is
very different for other people
in different in different areas with
different languages and it can also make
few people at home but it can also
exclude people and it does this all the
time
so submarine cables now connect the
whole world but if we actually look at
how it's ordered
it provides a particular ordering of
power extraction and control that
reproduce power
uh repressive power structures as they
exist and reinforce power structures as
they have existed over the centuries
so in this first part of the talk i'm
going to cover a part
that was uh
that looks at specifically at the
internet engineering task force
so the internet engineering task force
is one of the oldest bodies that produce
the internet and you might know it from
rfcs who of you has ever read an rfc
right so then you know that if you start
that an rfc is an abbreviation for a
request for comments but if you start
commenting once it's an rfc you're
actually too late
because then it's already a foundational
document but previously it's called an
internet draft
and when it's an internet draft
in people from the internet engineering
task force discuss how it works over
mailing lists this is a photo of the
internet engineering task force in uh
uh in toronto canada
and this was actually right before the
meeting during the meeting where they
decided that the internet engineering
task force could not have a meeting in
india because the infrastructure there
was too bad
and what then happened was that the
power went off
and what was so funny that the meeting
just continued in the glow of all the
screens of the laptops and no one
actually
gave gave even a small hiccup
so this also shows ironically that it's
the people
that make the infrastructure work on
what they expect it to work and how they
expect to do business
so to do this it's important to
understand
how this work is guided and for that i
use i borrow a term from a sociology
from science and technology studies it's
called a socio-technical imaginary and a
socio-technical imaginary is a vision of
how something should work that brings
people together to create something
and the electronic super highway is an
example of such a thing
so what is so interesting about the ietf
is that it produces these rfcs and
they've done it since the end of the 60s
in the same format
and all the debates happen on mailing
lists which is great for researchers
such as me because it allows us to do
computational analysis of all their
conversations but also to analyze all
the archives of all the discussions of
how the internet is works what are the
rules of the road
so i did a qualitative anal a
quantitative analysis of all rfcs a
qualitative analysis of 50 rfcs
qualitative and quantitative analysis of
mailing lists a total of 35 gigabytes
and almost 2 million emails of 955 email
lists and participate participant
observation during four years and 11
meetings of the ietf
so
what i thought
what i would find there was many
different socio-technical imaginaries of
what people thought the internet would
be
what it would be for them
but what i found is actually there were
three things that they all said that the
internet was three foundational
principles
the first one was the end-to-end
principle
and the end-to-end principle says that
intelligence in the network is at the
edges the network only exists for
datagram transport that it has low
complexity and high robustness
but at the same time when you look at an
rfc
1958 this end-to-end principle is not
just a technical principle
because read with me here
the community believes that the goal is
connectivity the tool is the internet
protocol and intelligence is end to end
rather than hidden in the network
and while doing
participant observation you find many
different ways where values and ideals
are stored
one of them is on t-shirts
many of you will be wearing t-shirts
which communicate ideas and identities
and here it also shows that this is also
inherently political and this is then
also shown again in another rfc
3935 and it says the internet isn't
value neutral and neither is the ietf
we want the internet to be useful for
communities that share our commitment to
openness and fairness we embrace
technical concepts such as decentralized
control edge user empowerment and
sharing of resources because those
concept resonates with the core values
of the ietf community these concepts
have little to do with the technology
that's possible and much to do with the
technology we choose to create
this sounds more
like the manifesto of a group of
anarcho-syndicalists than a standard
body of multinational corporations that
run the internet
right
so that's a funny thing to find so let's
see how that works out
so there's the second principle of
permissionless innovation and i cannot
reiterate enough
almost every interviewee said these were
the main things so permission innovation
permissionless innovation says that
there should be no barriers to the
deployment of new protocols there should
be no need to negotiate with entities in
the middle of the network
and this is probably a response to the
telco era where in the telco era
intelligence was in the network and the
endnotes were dumb
uh the endnotes were dumb and the
network was smart but now in the
internet it was turned around and in the
network was made dumb just to transport
packets and the end points were smart
but it was also a response arguably to
the accessible use policy of the arpanet
and the nsf net that said that no
commercial traffic was allowed on the
internet so up to the early 90s no
internet so if everyone ever anyone ever
tells you that the internet is a product
of companies and capitalism it's not
true it was publicly funded made at
universities and with government money
but in the 90s this changed
the third principle was that of openness
and that has three parts
network openness that any endpoint on
the internet should be reachable for any
other end point and that new endpoints
can be added
they should consist of open standards
that are voluntary and freely accessible
and of open governance that's
transparent open participation and have
open archives exactly the principles
that allows me to research it today
and that then results in very
interesting
configurations such as this the
unofficial motto of the ietf which as we
reject kings and presidents and voting
we believe in rough consensus and
running code
and this was an ex very explicit
reference to the international
telecommunications union that has that
has governed previous networks such as
the telegraph tv and spectrum
that does voting and that is governed by
countries no the ietf would do so based
on rough consensus and running codes
does anyone know how rough consensus is
established in the itf
it is indeed humming so if we want to
decide about the length of an ip header
and it would one should say 128 they'll
say 265 and i would be a working group
chair if you believe the header should
be 128 bits please hum now
you got the concept right so that is
quite amazing that this is how the
internet is governed and how the
decision making is designed right
so the work of sandra brahman shows that
explicit discussions about rights and
freedoms as we've seen in these rfcs as
well as social impact of technologies
have featured in rfcs since their
beginnings
so now we take a step take a step back
earlier i already gave it away
if we need to pinpoint
the start of the internet
what event would it be
what is this
sputnik the lounge of sputnik satellites
in october 1957 by the soviet union
it emitted what time magazine would call
those chilling beeps
beep
this device that was exactly my weight
and it was shot into the into the
atmosphere
and that was actually there
was a symbol of the technological and
scientific advancement of the soviet
union over all civilizations on the
planet and that instilled enormous fear
in other countries
this led the u.s to invest in a network
that could resist a nuclear strike
and that caused the distributed nature
of the internet
so in the end of the 80s and early 90s
what happened
the fall of the berlin wall right so
that's when the u.s government seeded
direct control over the arpanets the nsf
nets the es net and it led to the
establishment of commercial internet
exchanges
and to the formal institutionalization
of the internet governance regime that
we know now such as the internet
engineering task force the internet
society and regional internet registries
but at one of these first meetings of
the internet engineering task force
a german
statistician
raised his hand somehow the
statisticians are almost always german i
don't know why but he said if we
continue
handing out ip addresses
at this rate
within three years we cannot add new
devices to the network anymore
and that would be a great problem
because then the internet could not live
up to the concept of uh of openness
anymore right because new endpoints
could not be added to the network so
what happened
the introduction of network address
translation
this meant that routers would have a
public ip address but that but that
there were inter private ip addresses
that would be shared over several
devices
what happened as well there were
increasing security considerations the
internet was no longer comprised of
trusted actors so firewalls were
instated and there was a perceived need
from network operators to differentiate
business models and provide quality of
service caching and prioritization of
services
so a lot of networks started to do a lot
of bad things to the network they were
not just solving ip but they were adding
control inside the network
and this rise of the middle box added
functionality to the network not at the
edges of the network but in the network
itself
and this led already in the beginning to
an ossification of the network
so in this introduction of
directionality of not boxes which caused
not all endpoints to be able to connect
to all other end points directly
introduce a direct directionality which
created two classes clients and servers
users
and producers
and that made the importance of servers
way more important than that of other
devices this device
has way more capacity than any web
server had for the longest time on the
internet but still we cannot simply host
a website on this because it's not
reachable because of carrier grade nuts
and this created a new affordance
structure in the internet architecture
and an example of this is tls 1.3 so
you're all familiar with transport layer
security that's allowing for the s in
https the most used secured
encryption algorithm on the internet
but in the development of tls 1.3
they came across a big problem
people were experimenting with tls 1.3
but it wouldn't work on the network
why not
because all these middle boxes were
expecting only tls 1.2
they did not know what tls 1.3 was so
they would simply drop the packets of
tls 1.3
so
tls 1.3 to be deployed now needs to lie
to all the routers in the middle by
saying actually i'm tls 1.2 but then
when it reaches the end point it says oh
sorry i'm actually tls 1.3 but i had to
lie to the network
this means
that if we want to design the network of
the future it needs to look like the
past
this is the result of middle boxes and
ossification of the network
but tls 1.3 was actually still quite a
success
and this cannot be said for the stream
control transmission protocol
the
stream control transmission protocol was
supposed to be a more efficient
replacement for tcp
had multiple streams multiple
transmission paths no head of blocking
and it's actually described in 39 rfcs
and it worked perfectly in the lab but
was blocked by almost all nets
and this means it never really reliably
worked on the internet it worked in
almost it works on pretty much all telco
systems but it never works on the
internet
so the first rfc of satp was
published in april 2002
and the last rfc was published in
november 2017
and people indeed blamed the network for
this
but someone swift in to solve the
problem through the rise of quick the
quick udp internet protocol which is a
stream based protocol similar to satp
but
developed by google
and google could develop this because it
could do a b testing between the biggest
browser in the world chrome and almost
servers everywhere in the world google's
content distribution networks
and probably you have been taken part in
the testing of quick without knowing it
because you were using chrome in many
different environments and thereby
passing information back to google to
see how and whether it works and which
versions of quick actually worked and if
it didn't it would simply fall back to
tcp
so quick is actually a pretty great
thing because
it includes tls 1.3 so encryption it
does congestion control loss recovery
and it's built on udp pretty much the
way i'm presenting i'm sending you way
too much information all the time
so what it does what it does do with
this encryption after snowden of course
got a lot of interest but it does not
only encrypt your information it also
ensures that only you and google have
that information and all control over
data streams is taken from the hands of
the network operators so they cannot
inspect the traffic anymore or route it
based on
stuff they get from the data analysis
so what we see in tcp is sin synoc if
you do it with tls synths in ack then we
negotiate keys and tls control and so
you have a lot of back and forth
in quick
this would go way
quicker
so
quick was a win right so oh well that's
end well
well
maybe not because only a large
transnational corporation such as google
that had control over the largest
browser in the world and the largest cdn
network could gather that information to
develop a new protocol and actually roll
it out
quick tooling is not readily available
for everyone yet
and quick deployment will arguably
strengthen consolidation of google and
these large parties because other people
have less access and possibility to
shape and change
information streams
also
it is much harder for privacy
researchers ironically to understand
what google is doing so all the
research done on cookies
is not as easily done now because
network researchers cannot look at the
data streams and the practices of google
because the line between you and google
is encrypted at all times
and the network operators
one can think one you know are not
pleased because they also have less
control over their data streams
so the former chair of the ietf told me
that you now if you want to deploy
something you need to play in some of
the operators or vendors earning models
in order to get something deployed
so that is quite different from the
imaginary at the beginning where it said
that everyone could deploy everything on
the internet all the time right
and if we then look
at the the authors and affiliation of
the authors of the rfcs we see that
actually a relatively small number of
companies are setting the rules
for the development of the internet
architecture and infrastructure
so these myths these social technical
imaginaries might be important for what
they reveal including a genuine desire
for community and democracy but also for
what they conceal including the growing
concentration of communication power in
a handful of transnational media
businesses
so the socio-technical
architecture imaginary and itself
regulatory governance model have not
been able to safeguard freedom and
equality of researchers small companies
or individuals to innovate on the
internet protocol level
and permissionless innovation for the
purpose of retaining openness has
undermined itself
and the end-to-end principle
corporate interests have become a
first-order considerations for protocols
to be adopted and implemented and
political conceptions of the
architectural imaginary are fading into
the background
the importance and size of the internet
architecture has only grown as we now
see that everyone wants to keep
everything connected all the time and
within the societal implications
but the societal implications are not
structurally considered in the
standardization of the internet
so
some considerations have taken up such
as the mentioning of security in rfcs
so here in 1990 it became obligatory to
have security considerations in rfcs so
they are mentioned in all rfcs
privacy is increasingly mentioned
but
if you look at the length of the
security considerations
there's a lot of copy paste and they
might not be as thorough as we want them
to be
so to think then about other
conceptualizations together with corinth
and other people we developed human
rights human rights protocol
considerations
to develop ways that you protocol
developers could think of how their work
impacts human rights
so to show you how
this was actually taken up in the ietf i
show you the first human rights protocol
considerations
in the first rfc that came out after
this namely rfc 8492
that says
the most fundamental of human rights is
the right to protect oneself
the right to keep and bear arms is an
example of this right
implementations of tls passwords can be
used as arms kept and born to defend
oneself against all manner of attackers
criminals governments lawyers etc
therefore tls password is a powerful
tool in the promotion and defense of
universal human rights
so you see there are very different
understandings of human rights in the
community
so now let's continue to the second part
where we look at norm conflicts in the
governance of transnational
and distributed infrastructures the case
of internet routing
so in this next part of my research i
try to understand how norm setting and
norm conflict work in distributed and
complex transnational infrastructure
such as internet routing
so you know about internet routing right
you know that the internet is a network
of networks these networks are
autonomous systems autonomous systems
have an autonomous system number these
are assigned by regional internet
registries and regional internet
registries also hand out ip blocks to
these autonomous systems and between
them they're route internet traffic
and that happens through the border
gateway protocol that does announcements
who has control over which ip blocks uh
and and filtering happens based on that
and is secured through rpki sorry if i
go a bit fast sometimes i'm a fallen
over letterbox but if you have questions
we have we have time for that
so you see all these different networks
they all have different numbers and they
route network uh traffic between them if
they don't have a direct connection to a
network uh where they want to the the
connection of this uh the computer with
this ip address wants to reach
the computer with this ip address it
asks the computer of this network us hey
do you have this network no but i'm
connected to that network and through
that packets get routed all over the
globe right and if one connection gets
gets cut it finds its way through other
ways through that network
so this is a way of the way all these
networks are connected but that seems to
be a very technical and
not very value-based approach
but some really important thinkers of uh
early internet architects already said
in an important paper different
stakeholders that are part of the
internet bio have different interests
that may be adverse
accommodating this tussle is crucial to
the evolution of the internet of the
network's technical architecture
but currently routing decisions are made
based on a mixture of efficiency trust
and economics
and this is facilitated by the rir as i
earlier mentioned so i thought let's
design an experiment if we could do
routing based on other principles
so what principles could these be these
needs should be relevant of course they
should be applicable and these should be
existing frameworks i didn't want to
come up with a new existing new
framework and these frameworks should be
transnational such as the internet
so what are the frameworks that you
think that i could use for this
of course you're all beloved gdpr
so if a network says hey we respect the
gdpr
and you as a user only want to route
your traffic through networks that
respect the gdpr it would be cool if
networks say hey i respect gdpr right i
thought that could be useful
or even
if networks could say hey
i respect human rights and particularly
the united nations guiding principles on
business and human rights that made it
possible for also to understand if
companies respect human rights
so for that
uh i proposed an introduction of two
objects in the ripe database namely the
as set gdpr which would say that the
members of this set declare to be
compliant with the general data
protection regulation of the european
union or the asu and gp which would say
that the members of this set declared to
have adopted and implemented the united
nations guiding principles on business
and human rights
so i announced this
i tried to get networks to sign up to
this so that we would actually get to
route over only human rights respecting
networks wouldn't that be great
people didn't agree
no one signed up to these as sets
why
seems like a good idea right
so i argue this is because of
infrastructural normativity and the
interview i basis on the interviews i
did with the people that responded to
this
so norms are the common values of
society and the collective expectations
of property behavior of actors with a
given identity and they have four
aspects namely identity behavior
propriety and collective collective
expectations
so i from that i found that there is an
infrastructural norm of voluntary
interconnection that network operators
are expected to produce interconnection
based on voluntary bottom-up
collaboration and trust
and they believe that the network
facilitates and engages in
interconnection through the bgp protocol
that in this case ripe coordinates and
facilitates interconnection through the
ripe database everyone has control over
their own networks and interconnection
is based on incentive structures and
enlightened self-interest
and the reason given
given to me
why
gdpr and human rights should not be a
basis for routing were based on
technology saying well the routers do
not really allow for that why would we
prioritize implementing that in software
for an institutional response the
database is not meant for that this is
not what we intend to do we don't do
politics we're we're here to be neutral
and impartial
this is not how it's done based on
identity but also economy there is no
economic incentive to do this no no
other company asks for this no user asks
for this why should we do this
so what norms get resisted
so everything that complicates or
hampers inc
interconnection
laws such as the gdpr but also ethical
frameworks such as the ungp
jurisdictions such as schengen routing
which was also rejected but also
sanctions and security measures
and
this was also something that was
reflected in a recent call when uh the
ukrainian government asked for the
blockades of
of russian ip addresses
right swiftly respond the ripe ncc board
quickly responded that the executive
board of ripe ntc is committed to taking
all lawful steps to ensure that the ripe
ncc can provide undisrupted service to
all members across our service region
and the global internet community
the ripe ncc will publicly document all
its efforts to ensure that the registry
registry is not negatively affected by
laws regulations or political
developments
so the ripe ncc is committed to take all
lawful steps available to ensure that
the russian military
keeps on being active on the internet
you could call it impartial as rype ncc
does
are not so neutral indeed
so the voluntary interconnection norm
instructs the community of network
operators to create more interconnection
between and among networks and resist
any norm or value that could hamper that
so the internet governance is guided by
internet architecture social technical
imaginary arc
anchored in architectural values and
and process values such as openness and
transparency and the socio-technical
internet architecture imaginary serves
to guide and facilitate the process of
norm development and legitimizes the
current institutional ordering even if
they are
concretely subverted in practice
remember only google could actually do
that
and infrastructural norms exist to
instruct new norm development and
evaluate norms that are being introduced
and introduction of norms is only
successful if the candidate norm serves
the interest of these significantly
represented groups and the new norms are
not in conflict with the overarching
infrastructural norm of voluntary
interconnection
and then by now
you should be getting this
so the internet governance regime
i'd argue undermines its own authority
scope and legitimacy because it resists
norms that are in the interest of nation
states and individuals
we need to rethink the network
ideologies that underpin the foundation
of our information society
the internet infrastructure get much
less attention and platforms algorithms
algorithms etc even though it impacts
everything that happens on top
we need new network ideologies
right now we might be at a new sputnik
moment
come think with us
and for that we are establishing the new
critical infrastructure lab to research
power contestation in the global digital
infrastructures and we're doing that
together with maxi gus
and fika
so if you want to think with us about
this we will be thinking and working on
this for the coming years so please come
come talk with us after this ask
questions and we'll hope to be studying
this with you come find us today
tomorrow or any given day and um
thanks so much happy hacking
thank you niels uh
thank you both as well for collaborating
here it was a fantastic speech i expect
there are a lot of questions here we
have a couple of minutes couple are
there are the questions from the
internet let's start there
no
no one then someone here in the hall
okay please sir take a microphone there
there's another microphone in the back
so if someone wants you
um hello you said that the introduction
of network address translation kind of
led to this split into clients and
servers
you think maybe ipv6 could undo this in
a way
thank you
so
what we
so for the longest time
this is what we hoped right
but if we now see uh um
we see different things happening with
the deployment of ipv6
and the first thing was
to be observed that there were
carrier-grade nuts all over ipv6
and but at the same time we also see
that
uh censorship measures are not working
as effectively on ipv6 as ipv4
so for an end user there might be some
advantages but if we look at structural
ways in which networks are managed
unfortunately
we see that a lot of these behaviors
from ipv4 roll over into ipv6 and that's
where we see that it's really not just
the technology but also the cultures and
identities and incentives of the
engineers and the companies that are
working on this to not have completely
separate stacks but to manage ipv6 in
the same way people have managed ipv4 so
unfortunately
the way it looks now not yet
yes next question please
hi
so you showed the participation at itf
which is heavily skewed towards large
companies
do you
want to invite the hackers to actually
join itf and the regional registry
communities
to change what's happening there
this is a question of conscience
and i think i don't have the answer
so i think there is not one way to the
future there are many different ways
but i think that that it's very hard as
you've all known within your company
within your own cultural groups within
your own social groups it's very complex
and hard to change a group's culture
and it's very hard to change
set embedded interests
so i definitely think we should
participate
regain control regain knowledge and
understand how things work by
participating in these bodies but at the
same time we should also think of
alternative economies and alternative
ideologies on which
global communication networks should be
run
so
yes and no
so i do think that we have a lot to
learn from these uh from these
institutions and don't get me wrong i
don't think these institutions are bad
but they have developed in a particular
way to run the networks based on
particular cultures and particular
incentives
when i introduced this work in a
in the ietf and in ripe people said
don't bring human rights you're
politicizing things
but at the same time
economic economic values played in all
these measures all the time
and even
economic interests are part of bgp4
so
financial incentives are seen as not
political i think this is structurally
wrong and i think we should find a way
in which in which we can develop a new
social technical uh imaginary and a
network ideology that make that makes
network function in different ways
especially in the light of the rising
inequality in the world and the climate
crisis that is right ahead of us
please
so you also said that
the
philosophy and or norms of the internet
development
uh came as a reaction to how the telcos
were structured so where do you see
this um
uh the the the changes coming as a
reaction to how the internet functions
right now where do you see this coming
from and where could people
kind of go to enjoy except for your lab
but like where else do you see this
coming to replace the old internet with
something new
well interestingly there is a lot of
interest actually intel code development
so
a lot of the new research we've been
doing in the past years is actually on
the rollout of 5g
and telcos have a benefit over the
internet is that every 10 years they
have a new generation of technologies
so a friend of mine asked me why was god
to why was god able to
to create mankind in six days
because there was no pre-installed user
base
and
where the internet is continuously
backward compatible telco networks can
start over again and again and again
every 10 years
so
5g is a huge push for a new networking
but you also see a huge discontent among
people against the roll out of the
technologies that's taking form of the
burning of masts
so we see that there is a discontent
and we see that in regulation we see
that in the actions such as burning of
mass about how the internet political
economy is functioning
so there is now a moment a political
moment to rethink these structures and i
think we shouldn't
let that depend on individuals because
that's almost as saying fixing the pro
fixing climate change happen with taking
a plane or not eating meat no
this is an industrial level problem that
we should address also through nation
states and large movements the internet
was built through investments of nation
states where gaia x went wrong was by
giving it over to companies that took
away the vision from developing actually
a new network and standardize what they
were already doing so i think we should
be courageous and find new ways but new
ways are never built in all structures
so if you're asking where does the new
come from i cannot say but the new
internet will not come from the internet
whoa
whoa thank you very much neil sinova for
this fascinating and really intriguing
speech there was a lot of things to
discuss afterwards i hope people can
find a way to you to do that yes thank
you thank you very much give a warm
and have a great a great great mch 2022
all
you