okay okay everyone yeah my name is
Alexei and today we are going to talk
about car networks is used and some
things in automotive and you know it's
already a hot topic and a lot of people
talking about it and can try to make
something interesting for you
unfortunately are not able to bring
hardway here let's reason for it because
it's heavy and it's actually located in
Russia and belongs to my friends not to
me but yeah so anyway I prepared few
demos and so I want to say that I have a
lot of slides and not enough time
because we're now is not enough for me
if I am going to skip you boring slide
like you know this Who am I and so on
you could see everything on the slides
that you don't need additional comments
probably and that's why I just you see
where I'm walking in what is my
background and I came from and a lot of
things so let's go to switch it's
another slide I want actually about this
one I want to spend to this few seconds
because we have a community in Russia
it's like a white-hot let's call the
tripod kakak hackers and they written in
automotive things and actually I need to
say thank you to this community because
everything I done they test it on new
hardware and I got a lot of feedbacks
from them a lot of information and it's
like we all work like a community here
it's why I put them in the slide and you
can see they have different interests
some of them reverse engineers someone
going to build their own stand for car
like capitals of wheels and so on and
thanks to those guys and let's go next
it's like going to be disclaimer because
all this automotive fixed all starts
with saying same things like Charlie
Miller philosophy that it's really like
this and this automotive industry has
some issues it's true but it's not so
bad as of people talking about like the
second security they don't know what
they're doing and actually not yes they
like everywhere else there are some
security issues automotive knowledge
exclusion here so but a lot of people I
know they work for the motive and
actually my company is also not security
company I'm not working and will provide
any security services I'm working in
company who like B's in automotive
development and a lot of guys who trying
to make things secure but there are some
reasons why it happens that or that this
so anyway just disclaimer that I'm not
going to sell anything no blame
automotive industry and this like going
to be like you know this into a lot of
attack vectors very big surface attack
surface and this is true but I think
most of you already know these things
and I don't want to spend again time and
yes you could probably attack GPS and
spoof GPS you could try to inject virus
friends into child pressure system
wherever yeah
it's a lot of different things and
because my tropical like testing pen
testing vehicle and this is not only
can't can is very small part of all
these and actually this last part and
you already have car compromised but how
you get into the car specially remove is
very weak and interesting question and I
believe a lot of new research will be
published soon by a lot of guys because
a lot of people really work in it and
probably connected cars also interesting
things because they're it's a
toxic-waste extended now this with all
these backends and internet things if
you compromise internet service for car
you probably could compromise the car
itself like you know the so application
unlock doors from the forum they have
synchronized from internet series and so
on and so it's once again attack
surfaces really beacon not concentrated
on downtown security but I'm here more
concentrated on local interfaces like
local interfaces which is like obd2 port
and so on but actually it's much more
more interfaces like local access points
from the car you use be port actually
some cards like Ethernet over USB so if
you connect simple Ethernet adapter or
USB or get access to other net network
of the kind a lot of things could be
done here but again we are concentrated
tolkien sedated on Khan and that's why
I'm going to talk more about cont here
and again and I need to mention the
research done by Greece and Charlie
three or four years ago about Kahn
networks different topologies and what
you can do is is you how you could
affect control work on the car and it
was a really good research here I just
want to mention that yes canvas is one
of the main but is not only one buses a
lot of buses in the car
it's like kilometres of different wires
inside the car but converse with
responsible for controls and
communication between different devices
like engine you know still powers to
your component and logs a lot of
different things and maybe main
defensive mechanism what automotive
vendors do it's a physical segmentation
of network because canvas is broadcast
let's hold broadcast because if you
before me was device and they can frame
signal or other devices on this can will
receive the signal and already this
device decide by itself is it it's
supposed to be action for for for me or
not and that's why automotive vendors
and they try to do some segmentation
like critical pathways are isolated from
like say over GD agnostic or head unit
entertainment buses and I just want to
mention it here and yes again can frame
is actually come boss it's very simple
technology very simple protocol like
physical layer and transport layer is
very simple and maybe I just want to
mention the most important like fields
and con frames arbitration field I call
it ID because actually it's also works
as identification like maybe source of
message but or destination but actually
there are no such terms of like source
address or destination dressed like an
IP it's only ID and already
different interpretation could be done
on different layers that arbitration
field here is not designed not for Iggy
but for I'm ticklish as a anti-collision
system because it's a differential pair
and dominant big here is 0 so if device
put 0 it's like signal in the bus and if
we don't want to have collisions how
it's done here so let's say we have two
devices at the same time the right
message they synchronized by clock so
they start writing at the same time and
the first filters you could see at
arbitration field so the both of them
write 0 on the paths and at the same
time we read in the message from the bus
and they see zero but let's say and then
an our next second device sent one to
the bus but first device and zero to the
bias what does it mean it's mean that
the second device who put one in the bus
has higher arbitration field voila
ideally value is higher but when it's
read from the bus it's C zero because
the first device with lower arbitration
field whether it send zero and its
dominant beam so it's zero so that's how
the second device understand that the
third and another device in the network
right now writing this with higher
priority because zero in the network and
stop sending signals is his time so
probably it's important because it's
from security point of view it's also
for Assigned of denial of service
situation we could send a lot of
messages with like arbitration field 0 1
or like very low value and it's mean
that our other devices couldn't
communicate anymore because they think
some more important things happened in
the bus and probably also try to miss
this light and very fast explanation but
actually it's what Charlie million peace
elastic did is lost their research I
wanted to show that con bus it's
probably it's like love tape of your
resource of your test it's not the first
because if we are talking about the
motor tack vectors and I already
mentioned before it's more important how
you get into the car and for example
here you could compromise that unit is
like million different ways like
stackoverflow in the browser
or use of too free in the browser and
they gave like Cuban eggs and on the
latest version of communiques has an ex
and XLR support so I mean there could be
done a lot of research in this area and
this is really interesting topic but
then they need as I mentioned before
head unit has no access to privileged
con like it's critical to access to
engine for example because in different
isolated con segments so they need
second exploit to have a local privilege
escalation attack and they need to
compromise another component of the car
like gateway su is the best option here
and if you compromise gateways you we
already have access to all buses that
connected to this issue and then you
could already sent message and try to
control the car yeah also I want to talk
about local vectors because cars very
interesting and think and actually on
this side I'm going to talk about like
you could put something inside your car
like you could remove the front panel
you can get access to current bus
critical converse connect a small device
that action ISM and min the video but
with Jason modem and then put this panel
back you will never find this device but
your car a back door it like physically
backdoor it and yeah that's like
possibilities what you could do and it's
mean yeah remote control but ok I'll
skip this so it's very simple ideas and
not related to really to what I want to
talk but this one probably focus more
it's also local vector but already it we
are talking about real crime but you
know this whole remote attack Dexter's
exported screw for resources but you
never thought about here attack like who
hath explored Sampson and did some
damage but I believe you heard about
tips that three guys who really
interesting into your car networks
unfortunately and they have a different
thing so they could do with your car for
example yeah you have immobilizer keys
and there's some cryptographic things
there and let's say T if he don't have
this device but he still able to
steal your car because of different
things one of these they use like
different devices that's called exploit
there's easier to have an analogy here
so they have different exports but
unfortunately fortunately they don't
export real box an issue they use like
common architecture design issues in car
networks it I never heard about like use
of to free an engine issue to bypass key
as a noun but who knows maybe in the
future anyway they really want to access
to canvas to bypasses immobilizer for
example checks and start the engine
result keys and when I talking about
unauthorized car Naxos it's not only
obd2 deeds they know where is your real
critical important compasses for example
the third picture they just make a small
hole in the door they found the bus
canvass connect to this the press the
button the send a signal unlock door
now those unlock the complete of the car
now they try to do something this engine
the same techniques I will show later
IGS about it and the second picture the
send a probe window goes into the car
remove lump of the top connect to the
campus because it's lab controlled
overcome but also this can't had access
to something more interested for the and
for for these teeth and yeah this real
case it is how they work and this is
black market like with exploits you
could find forum and they sell the
Chinese devices for some prize they have
this forum people who are charged if you
could trust people they have semi
gratings for criminals and the device
looks like on these pictures and yeah
this is how how it is and yeah I
mentioned here the protocol I saw 14 2 2
9 1 which is UDS and this is if you
remember I told you that canvas is just
8 bytes
data and at all but modern communication
is it's not enough advice to know how
thought what if you want to send 17
bytes so it's the next level like next
ocean model we will option you have
videos protocols it's already he could
send any lens message you like
and you GES based on this OTP protocol
it's diagnostic service protocol it's
like Albany but in UTS you could do
changes on the issue like you could
reset keys probably update firmware
change parameters of your issue and
that's why these devices could be used
for Dylan as well and okay so that is
good I mentioned a lot of bad things
that actually current research not about
dead things it's also good guys here
like security researches and the problem
here that can information about con
traffic and cars is not published on
publicly available so it's not
documented and researchers need to
understand everything by themselves
that's why we have a lot of different
countries right now open sourced and
also there are a lot of guys could learn
some development like fluid management
too small connected car devices you
could work and in Amazon you could buy
it and those guys also need to do some
research to understand how they could
control what information they could get
from the car and from the car network
and of course anti-cheat system they're
also based on common like custom
entities systems a lot of good guys
doing also research in this area
also there are ugly things I called it
ugly because it's not crime like
directly against someone but people want
to reset Milledge counter of the car to
sell it like as new and of example car
got into crash and I'll bet pirate they
want to change this Arabic since Elvis
car but then they need to reset V in
code of this are bad devices to put it
in the gutter I mean a lot of things
happen here and guys who build in
automotive which is not me I'm security
guy from like other I came from
penetration tester for me it's also like
new I don't know what they know and
these guys they don't want to share
information it's a thing they keep
everything for themselves and yeah and I
came to the situation than a lot of con
tools in the market market on the open
source and actually in the market as
well and they cool they really good they
do
what they designed for but for me I
wanted something else because if I want
to do many the media what I would do
with this script so I need somehow to
automate the speeds to create a
man-in-the-middle another problem that
model guys not guys who making tools
they making them for special hardware
they do actually make a hardware they
want to sell it and they - and for me
it's also not convenient because I want
to work with all Hardware possible so
that will exist of them on the market so
I want to have Hardware independent
software I want to have RPI if I want to
do some unit tests X not all and
integrate my controls with some other
software which could be used from during
developing that back I want to do to
have validation test automatically so
something like that and I want to cover
all the different models that I could
connect together like I want for this
test for the another testament to
connect it like another way so it's like
if somebody is in the new radio
interface something like that so I have
different models they connected together
and have a solution for this situation
and in a pivot so firstly it happened in
February so it's pretty fresh and buggy
software but yeah and yeah that's what I
want to say it's engine support multiply
interfaces so you could do man in the
middle you could do whatever you want
you have a lot of ready to use models
like father's you just Connors black box
scanners statistic analysis features and
a lot of different things I have
supported right now just to hardware
just because I bought my money and at
support for this but it's very easy to
extend for any other code very hardware
it's also support can socket in case you
want to use it yeah I think a speech
this one because yeah you could have
gone over TCP so you if you want to have
a read distributed for some reason if
you want it I don't know in this
situation it could be useful but in my
case my friends in Moscow and I live in
Berlin I want to work with Scala oculus
and for me it's one of the solutions how
I can do this
but it could be done for any other
reasons
this is the design and architecture of
my device of my device my software like
it's unique unique flexible and you
could use it in different situations so
main idea here that I have a lot of
different models I connect it into pipe
and I have scenario which is described
in config file and have step 1 2 3 5 6
then loop again in 1 2 3 so it's like
infinitive loop and scenario repeat from
time to time again and again and half
infinitive numbers of pipes so I could
do it like in parallel so format at this
example of my name is the middle voice
firewall so then in this case count
tools action as firewall I connected
with two devices to one wire and captive
I'll connect one and one device to
another went another device or all
traffic goes for consoles and I could
block any messages I wanted see what
happened and this is config for this
setup so I have two models for one
interface for another interface and have
one model for firewall to block and then
on one pipe I read from first interface
then I write the second interface of the
second pipe I read from second to
FaceTime mm face so and this is an
example of man in the middle and I wrote
and this is how we describe an actual
config file for controls it could be GUI
interface with this config but I
actually have no time to do this so it's
right now confer calmly in text mode I
think give give developer API else key
but is right about how I could create
your own models with on any business
logic you need and it's pretty simple
you could do this it just general cloth
and you override methods so that's all
and I want to say sorry about the
commutation
which yeah countdown almost the one and
main developer of this think and don't
have enough time to make a good
documentation that I had come have use
cases describe it how to use it and what
we can do with type of tests and so on
and for today's session because I
realize I don't have
hardware to show you something like how
a grill test to use cases that you could
use I have idea to create a virtual car
I was inspired by the guy called dn5
because he created jakka for himself we
do not see but he is not a good thing
for me I think it was he but the thing
here that I decided to get my own
emulator but based on cantos engine so
each issue is module 4 controls and each
pipe is in different conversation
emulated so physical is relation related
issue level emulation here and can get
ways also just the model for con tools
and all these monster act as one car
like a real car and it has UGS services
RPM engine and doors lights and so on
yep let's have look like so you could
run it you have some controls not few of
course it's just simple small and like
stand demo stand but it's enough to
understand like how cars works and let's
finally start to talk about actual test
and what you can do and why you need to
do actually here from this step I don't
want to concentrate more on the like
contours can do that or that it's it
will be not interesting to talk I want
to talk about like metal many different
methods you could do and can network and
different techniques tester or other guy
could and do on the car network example
here the simple to think you can do is
start of work with obd2 port because of
accessible you don't need to destroy
your car very easy and yeah by standard
pin 6 and 15 always responsible for the
agnostic comp bus but I want to say for
testers you could see here and I have a
lot of make model specific thing and
actually a lot of not a lot of some of
vendors they put other converters let's
say to be in 1 and 9 or 3 and 11 they
could be additional
that's like not by standard but enter
decide to use this pin for access to
additional composites and for a social
it's not a bad idea to change this model
specific pins to understand what
actually they're probably it could be
another can bus that first thing you
start and then if you finally already
have access and you could see some
traffic from the so BD and Keewatin side
probably not much because it's just
diagnostic you can't probably send like
signals to engine and so on but we
already talked about ug as before that's
used by attackers by tips and for do
some changes in views use to make your
engine start and this thing available
from obd it's important because new JS
it's like diagnostic service unified
diagnostic service and it's designed
that you for example came to service
centers they connect special vendor
approval
software do some Diagnostics you do some
changes on your issues like to make
mirrors softer and local like any other
any customizations at all could be done
on the on the sea level you can do only
from service center but they do it from
an uncommon cars click on modern cars
from UGS protocol which are each
available from OBD port and if you have
this software somehow download it and
you have friends in service center you
could just sniff traffic to understand
how it works to for example some
identification works and so on or you
actually could you just reverse
engineering of these tools and
understand more and more but one of the
examples it's not this button this
button it's you just come it's by
default that say i don't have these
tools i don't have this vendors tools
and but i want to find these UGS
services which i don't know
so it's the same analogy with port
scanning with tcp port scanning so here
we want to send can train to OBD port
with some ID with you just request and
see if response on this request came if
you saw them you DSL it exists on this
ID if not then
next ID and enumerate all IDs like
Corsica and it's pretty simple and
probably it's implemented in other tools
but I also did it here in controls it
works these two models come again pink
and mode start and I could actually show
you this some demo you'll be not so
boring so first of all has got my car
start second come close and I try to
find the mouse yeah so let's ship so
this is car a car me later has consoles
I started and I go to car interface and
it can be going little bit yeah this is
our car we could start engine it could
make her p.m. more here because unlock
lock tongue lights so on and we want to
find UDS services so we it's like karma
later such that the second controls like
different tool which is connected to OBD
port here Celia
yeah you can make it bigger yeah yeah
I'm very bad in HTML and CSS okay so you
know but I have a lot I have control
interface and it is just front-end have
web api so you could if you want you
could write any web interface you like
means and let's see what we have in obg
tool here so BG it's not start and we
could see as it's on obd2 so all this
you generate messages here and you could
see this and this gain pink we have
configured to make scan on this range of
ID's for services number 49 which is
authentication request so we check we
try to request identification then we
just press button start here wait and
scan will be finished and then if some
UTS response happened the mode start
should able to catch this as a UTS
session opened so as it should push here
now I've static for let's say you GS
and it's very small I try to make it
bigger it's not so easy without mouse
but ok it's here
service with number of 7:01 in hex
response on CID request with this data
which is probably seat for one
certification and that's how we found
the black box methods we found the
active available UTS service from obd2
port okay let's just an example how easy
it could be done and mcduck to probably
presentation no presentation
really okay let's go and this is example
from real car from the guys from Karpin
they just connected to dare try and do
scan for service number 10 which is
entered diagnostic session and a lot of
device replied here I just want to
mention that real life is always
different from what you have thought you
could do it from the books but car
hacking books because in this case huge
a subset is was different and how we
could understand that this is response
because you send let's say they sent
request with ID 1 and then we got
response with 89 so difference between
ID is 9 is 9 and it's by default like
described in u.s. protocol that each
response should be plus 8 by plus h-2
request because there are no again there
are no source of destination address
it's very difficult to understand who is
sender and who is receiver here that's
why in this protocol they have this
trick like a response should be plus 8
from response to the plus 8 from request
but in this car a response this offset
but different it's not standard and you
need actually also you could very easily
add instead from the traffic yeah but
yeah time is going and we need no
solution as examples another example we
have 2 diagnostic tools for this car we
also connected and could sniff and you
could see a lot of interesting data fact
which is use you have names for this
issue and controls could detect ASCII
symbols in this traffic so you could
understand what this issue is about but
more interesting is identification and
in this example hehehe and on my friend
he tried to run some change action so he
has issue like mirrors in he want to
disable this after clothes like a
mountain also it should be changed as
parameter an issue so here are the
diagnostic tools on this section and
sniff it with scan tools and this is
result of the sniffing and as you can
see the first part
is identification here so device
diagnostic tools send the request for
identification and they goat from the
car response and then they send second
request with another wall it's actually
key and feed so they sound did some
magic and get the identification key and
send it back to the device after that
they already could use another you get
comment code right by identifier and
they write some data to this parameter
so they have ID like cable IDs which by
parameter ID and voila so they have ID
which is probably five twenty or just 20
yeah 20 and the wall and then send it to
the device and the response work twenty
is written than the right something else
and then they confirmation they read the
same parameter to check if what they
read as I try to write is actually
written to the issue that's all fashion
sniffing in countries like you easily
could restore this session step by step
and if you ask about identification yes
it's in from issue and this is house
code from the tester device but then you
just after we're honest second at third
time you even don't need to do rather
than generic is very simple
unfortunately you can see the last part
of the fact that adjust a function of
addition so they have feed they have
been called they add pin code to seat
and this is actually our key so even not
exhort and if you know how to do
authentification if you want to create
some custom you J's to see totally
restore the whole logic from this but
because I mentioned that Khan is the UGS
is important for
thieves I want to show the DML I have
here so let's back to the car I'll stop
it and let's remove immobilizer keys
from this car okay I first need to
remove keys and here you not see how we
do this because I actually follows calls
wait a second I need to open I don't see
back here ah let's not be
examples lose faster on everything so
have controller here for engine and have
key let's remove the mood and save and
start crying Snoopy here because two
screens and then go to the car
and if we press start mashing happens
without without key they are not
authorized to do it probably hip ii yeah
but we could do other things but we can
start engine everything right and then i
go to the demo think here and let's say
we drill withdraw and do a hole in the
door yeah
connect to the bars and we want to send
a signal like unlock door to be more
so I know the comment how to do this
and if I send it nothing happen probably
I think you can check your probabilities
in wrong yeah it should be here sorry I
send it to obd2 and because obd2 is not
allowed to have access to cabinets
nothing happens I sent it from yeah so
now we inside the car
now we could connect to obd for example
and this is a think UDS key for access
to the device is Charlotte I mean if you
know it's for one car you note for all
cars keys for immobilizer it's unique
for each person that's one of the things
that could be hidden so a tackle if you
don't know you're in a blazer key but
you know the eds key so what you could
try to do and this example he use this
key here let me just copy it because I
don't remember engine right sign it to
copy you geez come on
home button okay here seeker
and then we try to out not here here
she's not here I can see from this yeah
exam right and we do identification and
now we could write a parameter if we
because we already certificated in UJS
and identification will be 50 50 50 5 5
5 5 5 5 and we said in Yuki which is 17
X 0 let's make a 0 1
so probably now we reset keys from su
engine and now because we know this key
we could try to start this engine and
first we need to get the VIN number as
well because yeah from here I don't see
really I think I copy everything so we
set up a wing code here and our new key
which is 17 years and now we could try
to start a car
this that and yeah and now we have RPM
and everything so this is like example
in this simulator how it could be in
real life I can say this is example one
to one because it I'm not the thief but
that's how it's supposed to be and but
actually a lot of different situation
sometimes these can came this their own
is you to start engine they connected to
your car and use this issue to control
engine not the original one so there a
lot of different tricks and techniques
that these are using okay 15 minutes you
need to read up yeah but first need to
switch the presentation yeah this
scenario was shown and let's go to the
next thing actually is not a commercial
but it's very popular book that's what I
said I could put so I hear a everybody
heard about it and I also bought it and
read it and it's good book and do you
remember the beginning I sent the common
how to unlock the door like I put some
something so this the think actually
originally I didn't know how I don't I
didn't know this comment I need to do
some research to understand which
comment it should be and for example in
this book I really like a good example
you could dump a traffic is when you
need an action where this unlock comment
happened then you replace half of this
traffic and see door unlocked or not if
not then replay another house and pusher
to be unlocked then you take this house
and again it's like binary search it's
cool technique and it works and in this
book you could see like how you could do
this from scripts like replay I give
from the disease and as a quiet so
boring I mean it's car network is really
you could do a lot of automation in this
and unfortunately I found no tools that
could do this so that's why one of the
reason why I have started doing controls
but first I need to find the right
canvas it's another task for the tester
because like for black box a lot of
wires like a lot of wires really it's
kilometers of wires and you need to find
converses and what our car continues and
in Russia for their car they use simple
multimeter and they check the resistance
because if a car network is terminated
from both sides resistance should be 60
or if it's disconnected 120 so you could
find the time bus based on these simple
things of course if you have more
advanced devices for know how to English
in Russian called of slow growth but
yeah you could do it actually this
multimeter is very simple and what they
how they did it and this is last
pictures how they inject into the canvas
because I really don't recommend to do
any cut in the car it's not good idea so
we just took simple needles and connect
it clearly connects and first method I
want to present here which is very
simple it just different difference like
difference of two sets it's much faster
and simpler than replaying half by half
so we have first traffic dump which we
call it set one with noise we collected
traffic for example for two minutes and
did nothing for the castle just normal
traffic if nothing happened on the car
then we collect the second jump of the
traffic which is where is even happened
action like unlock door and it's a small
amount of traffic but actually for few
seconds it could be like 1000 different
countries because it's a traffic lot of
traffic in the bus and then you do a
simple deep and find the difference
between these two traffic's and probably
the difference will be what you are
looking for it's an example again from
real car well from the same my friends
from Moscow from me hi you and you see
and the first on the first picture it's
like thief how it looks like it's not
thousand pockets it's already just 20
different frames and it's much easier to
find the frame you're looking for in
this set then in $1,000 place but even
more it's too much for me I decide and I
add the additional filter like how many
different changes happened because let's
say in this frame it could be
I am as well because every p.m. changes
all the time and the bus is a lot of
different colors but it's a lot of
different we don't look it because
lock/unlock is with primary structure so
it's one rather and another so we could
set in for example in control filter on
only two different colors and see
already only four different messages
already here by statistic you could see
this is five five five and one so this
is one probably what we looking for this
is five it startles us matches messages
before it was 80 for example and now it
became zero it's because before it
statuses it's always sent door closed
closed front door closed left door
closed and then we did this action and
they changed of course they changed back
now it's opened that's why it's also in
the deef but if you put filter visually
one you find exactly this responsible
like main even we are looking for needs
much faster than doing replacement yeah
I think I do not show I mean it's very
simple I don't want to show this on
emulator just because of time but yeah
yeah and then they took another car and
it's more interesting case and the
default ready really big and if you set
filter onto on the to Wallace you can
changes from one color to another it's
also a few and there are no unique like
by count you can say what what about
exactly what exact message here and if
you put of course one there are no
unique messages so the answer is
somewhere here and it's not difficult to
find it by here playing one by one but
skew and it's not as clear as in
previous example I just want to show the
different classes different logic and
that's how I came into second method
I just specially created for black hat
just finished yesterday and it's based
on abnormalities so we're looking for
abnormalities in the traffic just iPhone
all machine learning cuckoo but no
machine learning to not good thing
everywhere here you could do machine
learning but education period will be
super-long van shape even simple replay
will be faster so I try to use another
method like these simple statistical
analysis and abnormalities detection so
I check for two things first beat that
has been changed is diff diff method
change waters like different levels for
example want to agree it's all three
different values but if you choose this
method it's same beat changes all the
time so for us it's not interesting
we're not interesting to make difference
between 1 2 3 because if same beats
changes all the time probably it's noise
so I have a history of all changes and
which beats has been changed and I
remember this bits for each ID and also
I remember the time between same frames
so it's 10 each second okay I remember
this minimum time and on-stage seconds
when I had a second set of traffic
action even happened I do the same I
understand the minimum time and for each
IV and beat this have been changes and
compare if new beats found its
abnormality funny that's how for example
rpm excluded by default because it's
almost same not always but always same
bit changes all the time and a lot of
noise to remove it very fast and next
stage free I do correlation between
different events so if this change it
felt and then after this another ID
change probably these two events are one
big event so I collect all these things
and output for same traffic from
previous example I got session
extraction it's like if you do door
unlock it's only these frames let's say
interesting for you and they sorted by
time here and biologic like let's first
change happen with the traffic then
there's a second change headed for
another it probably it's correlated
because this happened just after this
then other change in habit then
infiltrate the message start sending
more of them and so on and it's lucu
because by logic of course unlock
comments somewhere
the top and statuses on the bottom is
just biologic but it's still not all
what we can do and next step will be
automatic detection even this out like
human participating so what we could do
now when we have the session extracted
by abnormal us busy statistical method
we could replace met each one by one
from this session and then check if
these changes happened so if you replace
this message and this change is not
happened then this message did not cause
this changes so it's not what we're
looking for
then we'll replace second frame from
this list and we see the air that's now
changes this value changing from this to
this this to this and all this happened
so it's mean this is what we're looking
for and actually even it by follows you
could easily see that it was changed so
this is what what eight eight eight
eight became two two two two and just up
to this all this CEC like EE CEA a to EE
and also it's important because same
mechanism has closed I dissolve it's
like door one door to door three to four
and they have eyes they have the closed
eye Dean Wallace let's change it while a
second from fifth to eight bits they
change it from one to two such acts
loops like this is statuses of the doors
and this is common and then it's back so
looks like it's like button it was
pressed during this time and it's
released and it could be done totally
automatic and probably as if I want to
show on the stand the emulator I mean
it's me
I start different example
so what you have in the car let me share
this car status
let's close doors okay let it be
unlocked whatever it doesn't matter
hmm start it so in what start let's
check we see here we see some traffic
here nothing just make a minyan and now
we can go and
and make a trade session on the butter
set zero so Jian controls
it's a lot of different butters you
could operate with so by default it
starts if you put current status that
all actions and buffer default buffer
with index zero and it's how many
friends here think it's all because
nothing happened with the car its noise
it's what we could use for low on for
training so we do here training press it
then we could see here yes we found how
many think unique ID and we down
training so now we could switch to
another book here here and then we could
do an action on the car say lock and go
back so you don't need this before
anymore so let's see so in buffer zero
we have already some traffic and we
already made the Train and before one we
have 200 something I don't see from here
frames and we could try to extract a
session so it's an index one
and it's result what we good here it's
this example very simple I mean you
don't even to replace yeah its first
message then just change it happened and
this is another correlation information
so probably you say this comment is lock
and this is door status one go into the
head two doors its portico but I also
want to show back to the ground make it
unlock again and egg to this one and
let's try to have to run after the text
feature hope it works with button yeah
you see door closed
and as a result here let me share them
see from here yeah this is all right so
we have the opposite so you really don't
need to think too much I mean some
things could be really automated in
canvas and that's what I try to do yeah
I see I have only 5 minutes and a lot of
things to talk about
it's ok and I want to say have a lot of
features and development for example
automatic field extraction because it's
also interesting tasks because you see
yes it looks like one message but there
are could be different fields in one
message and we could for example this
feature done by my friend Sergei he
doing solve one by one each for all
sequence to see which beat changes more
often than other for example if to beat
changes in two different ages of field
probably two different fields that's how
this is again from real traffic it could
apply this mechanism is this idea to
select probably this's rpm and this is
peak because covers and in statical
position of move it during research and
we could separate speed from rpm from
one message and
actually yeah and also I have a metadata
support and controls so if you think you
know what you have found you could
create metadata config file for your
project and then you could document and
then data extraction will be already
automated from these messages you could
detect rpm value and it's probably speed
and what comment which this ID is
responsible for this then if you give
this information to another researcher
for him it will be easier to understand
what you have done
and so on okay faster that already
showed you at how let's also customize
algorithm to detect loops because very
often we encode send for example in
loops like repeatable encode this means
never change and they don't use the so
TP for this type of the information they
use custom like counters you could see
it's like 0 1 2 3 0 1 2 then they
repeated again and again so I haven't
lamented something like we could we
assemble this chain and get the ASCII
string so it's also could be useful and
a lot of other things not only research
I want to talk about validation tests
and how you could do it this controls
example it's very not that idea to
validate and with it this is con gateway
and of course you have example one bus
and another bus and you want to be sure
that the configuration of this device is
meet your requirements and the problem
and automotive that requirements done by
the tape automaker but this device done
by some company not by so it different
company who did this device yes for yes
by request offender it's like a
relationship between them but
technically different team different
person and of course like vendors they
need somehow to validate what they
bought so probably it's one of the way
how they could do this and I try to
implement it some controls for example I
sent
oh oh tests like unit tests from one
interface
and another interface of contacts I
connect to another part of the device
and check which message passed which
knot and it could be done like automatic
that okay time is time and I want to say
also about five ink actually there are
you could do five ink and a simple thing
I mean you understand for the southern
cards but problem in car networks and
it's very difficult to understand if
this frame you did for like four
thousand cows some wishes because you
don't have debugger attach it to issue
device you probably could do this it's
okay it's one of the solutions but in
general if you send a message to the can
box you don't know what happened all if
something set it or not and you don't
know if you've hasn't found something
and that's why you could do a little
different things and I think here link
to some paper of some academic guys who
work in on this area but I also found
that the same algorithm I implemented
for automatic door unlock detection you
could use four thousand because I have
no time I can show it right now
simulator that idea is the same you doof
I think you learn your algorithms and
you do father
and then you see correlations happen
between messages in fasting and other
messages of the company for example you
have like my device send message h ii
you did fasten and it stopped sending
message and you could definitely say
after which message it happened so here
it's me you could do this man and it's a
lot of fun ok next thing is outer gate
systems and fortunately I have no time
that you think here that you could use
controls for prototyping because yes
it's very difficult to create a device
and connect to car check something then
you need to black device to the reflash
you could create a prototype and
countries on Python like this all
business logic very simply connected to
real car
check your logic on the flight to change
the code and change it from the real
boards
stance or real car so it could be
helpful for developer and here I have
example of an intuitive system so first
idea because I had no time I can show
that now but I could at least say a few
words first we could connect our device
before like we could cut the engine a
card can before the engine issue and put
our device and the device do additional
iterations of example it could be
anything in my setup and actually I to
this idea from real customer data system
in Russia you might need to put a secret
sequence actions inside collective like
you know like fatality Mortal Kombat
like up up down up up down and then you
could start your car without detection
you can do this so I did the prototype
of this for one animal later and it
works but this is that idea because if
you make a mistake here you lost control
of your h2 engine so another idea
collect connected in concert in parallel
then if your device press nothing
happened but this is the same idea it's
checked for left right left right secret
sequence but if we detect the engine
started its immediate the same common
stop so you could it's like for for for
intruder it looks like he could start
and then second it stopped so he its I
also took this idea from leo prototypes
for the zone in Russia and Italy it's
custom and it acceptance ideas it's a
very popular idea and how can do both
the receiver and some pork and the guy
promised to put it on open source he
didn't gives I can say anything but she
tried to make a machine learning system
and here for his own machine he made an
education process for first step and
then he checked that RPM speed should be
also correlate and if it's not correlate
and probably some attack happened ok and
yeah this is contributors who helped me
a lot and example my wife did all this
graphical design he think Kakao is
some algorithm for bits or detection
tube detection algorithms and so on and
so I think I have time for question at
least maybe one two questions so oh
sorry I have a lot of information not
enough time yeah my fault but if you
have questions please welcome David
suggestion of where you could get like a
car park form to actually test you go to
John Kerry actually buy a used car or
can you find integral individual pieces
on eBay or something for example yeah mm
probably if you remember the second
slide there was a picture of this so you
could buy pieces on eBay but do you have
problem because there are no information
on how you could connect those devices
together how to made a power supply and
for example some issue devices they
before they start looking for other
issue devices and you couldn't start so
you need to chose to do small research
and then you could so then you could
connect it and actually a friend of mine
sir Gary he worked on this or he bought
all these details as separate details
and he starts connected and keep has
kilometers of wires in his laboratory
and yeah it's possible and it's much
more safer for you to I'm going to do
research because it's really not the
best idea to do research in your own car
yeah but eBay is one of the sources and
also in Russia for example we have a lot
of crashed cars and you could detail
some distressed car somewhere also so
it's not a big problem big biggest
problem you don't know how to connect it
this the biggest problem
and gentlemen we're all the time if we
give a hammer for thank you