good afternoon ladies and gentlemen
today I will introduce our work on AI
based antivirus and using active
learning system my name is Molly and my
english name is Thomas and from company
by two and I also like you have heard of
deep learning and also the android APK
file ok let's start with a story tell
years ago my first job was virus analyst
who let is really a boring job every day
account a lot of virus samples and they
are let us detected by our competitors
but we missed so many example I know it
is a virus what I need to do is just 2d
compare it with Ida Pro and the growing
the mouse to find a signature and then
copy and paste the signature by the
sequence to a text file so at that time
I had a dream that one day the computer
in front of me and take replace only to
handle virus samples so I can have time
to have a talk on blackhat but nothing's
come true yeah ok
but worst thing one thing I learned from
laptop is a experienced analyst can
identify a virus variant
like these are examples this is a become
how that apk file if the enemy sees code
like these in the red rectangles click
and he'll if we if his a virus at once
he didn't read the code to understand
the logic but he has seen so many very
simple circuit is put on amis a new
virus of variant is just like a new
hundred and number six he has seen so
many six so he can tell if it is a six
at once this is image recognition which
is one of the best applications of deep
learning so this is the first reason we
want to use his learning being anti
virus another reason is the Android
malware has has been growing too fast
and the signatures efficiency is
declining even more faster and you see
the lab the figure shows the total
number of Android malware these years it
has to reach 15 meetings and you can see
there is a leap year basis which is not
kusa and the red figure shows shows the
signature efficiency against the touting
dodging is a popular Android malware
family which has to a lot of variants
you can see in 2013 when signature can
catch almost 30,000 thousand samples but
in 2016 16 when system and signature can
catch only result in starting samples
and the worst of all I have no high
Kong's for new virus variant so we know
we're underneath so how to think of
other ways for example AI paste
antivirus that's not high relate depend
on manpower this is the roadmap of our
mobile mobile antivirus engine they
started with us to interpret the rules
which is which like anyone else and then
we found many large
families have obvious behavior rules
next we develop our code base the rules
which can match some opcode value
sequence and have some logic relief
I finally we got to the happiest people
earning certain people union has two
stages my training stage the other is
prediction stage the input of training
stage is training data size in all suit
in this 15 meeting android APK files
including malware PUA and v9 apps the
first and most important that infinite
stages feature each squad instruction
will have structural type features the
typical type features and in kill hotel
features these features some of which
tend to feature continuous value and
some others has zero one values and the
continuous work and continuous value has
very different range and the
distribution of the range is very uneven
so we need to do no more efficient
feature normalization to make to align
the data to a same range and the
negative distribution and eliminate
possible when I get the normalization
normalize the data we can input them
into the deep neural network for
training and we change the data on hydro
hydro platform is an open source the
people learning platform we are to
improve network structure we add our
radicular and we also use the pass out
encoder to get high quality and
invariant features and we also get
custom configuration tunings after
trimming our negate models between the
Miller model and the puree model
separately with live models we can do
prediction
t-carr apk from testing data size
Express these features and normalize the
features and the input normalize the
data into the model to get a prediction
result and is it Miller
APU a open-air that's the three strategy
will be the focus of today's talk let's
look at the first one feature extraction
tip learning system cannot accept an apk
file as input so we need to tell the
city what should be looking for that
will be informative in making this
decision is its feature extraction we
have structural features to statistical
features and empirical features such as
structural features is mainly about
information of aggregate file structure
for example the number of you two
beauties Phoenicians in Android manifest
file the number of picture file in our
us directory the size of ISDN recurring
the number of classes starts with our
comm slash the number of classes starts
with our travel slash the number of
fields with Clark bling the number of
measures which has parameters greater
than 20 you can see that the structural
features is very intuitive and primitive
that's exactly what we want
besides structural features we also have
knowledge related to features such as
statistical features and empirical
features example of statistical feature
uses
if that the DA we discriminate you
screening certificate sir we we collect
certificate files from all the sample
from the training data size and then we
count the stream occurrence of each
field then we follow this stream email
address equals AB game at a mobile comm
this string appears in in mail where if
the 52 times light appears in denied ABS
so we'll use this screen as well feature
and empirical features is many are based
on virus underneath experience for
example are yes evacuating the educate
Excel it's time to store the result well
such as structural pictures and axonal
but personally found that some may are
sometimes put executable file into is
directory so we used if is directory has
executable as a feature similarly we
have if a site directory has a TK file
title feature since deploying existing
only accepts real number as input so we
need to convert all these features to
refer to real numbers some of the
features can be converted to zero one
value for example if our yet theater has
you execute about file if it is higher
in the value is one if not two value
theorem somewhat values cloning the
cover to a continuous value
continuous value has very differently in
written series of seven and the there is
an and there is a median number in these
features so if this number input into
the TV neural network
actually the streams where the small
valuables will soon be surprised and the
in fact over small so most small value
features will be greatly reduced
so we need to a landed theta into same
range and in fact that a terrine the
distribution of each range is is not
even we will we need to make it actually
I realized possible
this is the feature normalization and it
is very important and we have done a lot
of work on their system details I dearly
feature data up a constant distribution
we can use the standard score
normalization to align the data to to a
closing - closing interval between minus
1 and 1
it's perfect but in the reality is much
more complex
for example the feature the size of
certificate file this features
distribution which looks like this now
what you call an parallel with y axis
this brownish distribution this is a
very bad feature because is not
discriminating the thing cannot make the
ceiling depend on the dumbest feature
all the samples has value in this
feature so however when they are
double-checked the data I will we found
that this is actually an knowledge
problem there are some very large values
at the far end of x axis x axis so we
used cutting techniques to cut off the
noisy data then the journey distribution
transform to this one it's amazing how a
vertical line transformed to a multi
model distribution
and this is a underneath is a maximal
batter because it is much more
discriminative like no word : but this
can be a little introduction can be
further optimized because and you can
see it there are six peaks in this new
solution is not even so we use cutting
light techniques again to cut it into
six constant leg distributions and then
we can use standard normalization to
align the data to a closing travel
between miners run around another
example is the file numbers being apk
file in a decade Patrick the parent
numbers in apk Patrick package if
distribution looks like these is a long
tail distribution for it for this one we
can use compiled normalization which is
fine controls and that can divide the
data evenly and then allow each division
to close interval between minus 1 and 1
and this is a key part of this training
the katrinak stage you have to find the
appropriate algorithm based on your own
data characteristics and it's effective
of sitting the precision of our system
has increased by 9% this normalization
so then after normalize we can't
normalize data we can input them into
the neural network streaming this is our
network
this is a typical feed-forward
artificial neural network which has a
value input layer when output layer and
the three hidden layers we include the
network structure we also add a
procedure layer the difference between
residual layer and the common hidden
layer is that confident layer only
accepts input input from previous layer
and your digital AR will receive input
from not only previous layer but also
the layer before previous layer is
called identity identity has no weight
from parameter or we can say the beta
parameter of identity is always equal to
one another character the input layer we
have 571 continuous features and we have
664 the robot features totally 1230 file
features you may think of 1000 features
is a little small for for the deep
learning but I want to say is good
enough we have spent a lot of effort to
reduce the feature from 10,000 to 1000
and more importantly once on the feature
can work on mobile phone and milk
we will discuss the production
deployment in the next slide ok another
thought about the training process we
use Spock encoder to change this network
first house encoder is unsupervised
learning algorithms that can fund high
quality and environment features
enterprise back propagation and settings
the target value to equal to the input
like this schematic diagram shows by
placing some constraints on the network
for example most of the new roads new
rains should being active and we get two
parts out encoder using auto encoder is
the main difference between people
learning and actually am yes
after training with Ock encoder we train
it with the label of data now let's look
at some configurations of this neural
network we use tons and remove as hidden
layer activation function you can use
sigmoid but these two functions is is
much faster than sigmoid we use video
you use multi class cross entity as a
cost function and we use 88 dark out as
a learning method and we use softmax
as a final layer activation function
Francis ultimax
microscope can be used for multi
classification problem and the training
package is twenty to thirty one hundred
classics will cause overfitting and
let's eat so when we cut the models our
China we can call models then we can do
the prediction this is the production
development of our sitting we extract
features on the phone and then send the
features to the cloud we do prediction
in the cloud considering the performance
and inside the prediction result to the
form the whole process only takes 140
milliseconds and the traffic is 1 KB for
80k to evaluate the detection for
performance
let's check the ROC curve now this model
is between
July and the task against the paid taxes
imposed on tool and you can see that is
this needle model has very good
detection because it's recall is almost
a is 96% and the for the pollak you Rick
is almost zero now let's look at a model
lifetime this model is trained on
January and the test against every tile
samples are January March May and the
tool and we can see that the recall rate
has dropped by seven point six in six
month six so see from these figures we
can know and also the model has very
cool detection performance by the way
about it need to continually continue
with the training with the label data
otherwise the recoil will drop yes
let's talk about the limitations first
people learning can provide explanations
for if detection results loss as we n
can do it but tip learn economy it is
because there are too many parameters in
the hidden layers but if it also has the
benefit that attackers
don't know which feature caused the
detection for is a malware either and
besides that the features are mainly
primitive information such as the number
of files in apk and the size of a
directory so it is hard it's more
difficult to evade detection second and
uncertain can't understand coda meaning
is learned in a unique recognition way
so it don't even try to understand the
coordinating pearl it's built on static
analysis and the lack of dynamic
instruction and last the concept
learning
need
continue the training with label data we
have seen in NASA figures and it also
has advantages for example more
difficult for you eight we have just
discussed and it has a fixed of sizing
model the size of a traditional
signature database grows with sample
size linearly but the people learning
model the size of deep learning model is
only related to to the network structure
for our system the model size is owning
two megabytes conclusion feature
extraction is the key step virus analyst
appearance and how to encoder and how to
find the valuable features and this
system is designed to detect Anglo
malware but these measures can be used
in detecting male wearing other
platforms last how certain if learns in
image recognition way is effective only
in detecting male very vibrant virus but
it is a concern in a speech recognition
way maybe it can understand the code
meaning and then read the code logic to
uncover a new malware family not manatee
what we are going to do next
welcome to contact me for any reason and
welcome cooperation and partnership with
us thank you all
[Music]
ladies and gentlemen we have time for a
few questions anyone has one high
technical talk you mentioned that you
need labels input right for your
training you what input labels label
labels yes label data and where did you
get the label data from oh yes oh how a
team of focus on mobile and you are so
we have a lot of prowlers and cats and
holes and we also have somehow exchange
with other security companies okay
thanks
yes oh thank you hi great talk
why do you have to normalize the data
before opening into the neural network
so what I just put the numbers
straighted rather than normalizing them
why normal sorry or so why do you have
to normalize data before putting it into
the neural network oh yeah for for two
reasons and further days the data has a
very deep in the region some really from
ten to hundred and other it's really
from 102 billion
so if these data including into the
neural network some peak values will
surprise the rat I mean surprise the
effect of small values the the neuron
even neuron accepts a very big value it
will be others I don't know how to say
other
it was to talk in couple SAP small
values so we need to align the data into
a single value range and the other
reason is
this is not enough because daily is not
implicate highs not even look at the
yeah no cat is a vertical and then all
the older samples have same value this
feature isn't used to these for the
system because it may come to make it
excited by this feature so we need to do
the to make it the dissolution as even
as possible
I could talk then can you mention
something about false positive rates
about what are false positive rates of
detection hot sales positive Oh sauce
was lack of all calculate okay you see
the the Jacques Rogge shows a full
positive rate then the x-axis of a
rocker in the middle figure is the for
the positive rate of our model has very
good detection the faulty voltages and
the first goal of little Susan is to is
to control the for the parking rate or
the precision because we want to use
these to attend every test and it
actually it's already attended every
test on January this year ten words is
these comparative tests the photo
Pollock you read is very important for
these comparative have test and because
even you have one for the full parking
rate will get punished very severely
civilly so the first go of listen is to
control the precision or for the parking
rate but I think the deep learning
sitting you can give running to active
antivirals now control the precise
precision of all calculate too much it
through the latter goal and the recall
is the most important point of listening
[Music]
question thank you
hi thank you for TRADOC thank you
so ah he must recognizer neural networks
have been added his line of work of
adversarial samples and basically what
people have sold is that you can do some
specific changes that you put in very
small like say less than 1% of the
features of the pixels and cause the
network misclassified are the input so
given that you follow a similar line of
architecture in here it's very important
to correctly classify have you looked
into this area of like this algorithms
causing miss classification saying like
changing one feature by a very small
value and this will cause the network to
output a different value so yeah I was
wondering if you are aware of this area
and whether you are planning to test
such algorithm audience your system
sorry I don't understand your question
very clear we can close about yeah yeah
so basically what's happening is that
image recognition neural networks there
are this line of work that you can
basically caused them to misclassify
inputs here you have an input which is
an elephant and by changing to pixels
you got a network to classify it as a
cut out with very high precision with
very very high confidence so I was
wondering whether you are aware of this
because you follow a similar
architecture whether you have tested any
of these algorithms against you know
your system let's discuss after pox ok
wait to taste it thank you ladies and
gentlemen brothers I'll to thank Thomas
cool on
[Applause]