so thanks for coming by fellas and today
we are going to introduce a new
exploitation I mean a new technique by
attacking Windows by windows and my name
is Lee Joe and this is my colleague in
Leon hi everybody
okay well clothes from the tents and
pitching manager so this is an outline
of today's presentation first of all we
are going to introduce about this
ourselves our teams and then we are
going to have a brief view of the
old-school stylez to explore the Windows
kernel and then we are going to talk
about the Windows 10 limitations and I'm
going to introduce the zero to one
exploitation and my colleague in here
will introduce the one to zero
exploitation okay so first of all being
will introduce the team okay Jairo madam
is a debugger and damn well the
neighbors in the Senate what the article
is just having to introduce our team we
have several members she is our team
leader good days idolizing flash on the
PDF in memory allocation created me and
I'm responsible for find the windows
color very rapidity and the writing is
point microSD 14 PDFs clearly and the
way I are doing five jobs road miles
doing a accommodation traveler ability
expectation in photo in 2016 we call the
system privilege by hiking Adobe Flash
in unity three seconds and I want the
title mask of vampire tunes a high score
with kimchi also we call this privilege
and achieve the price in Japan by
hacking Swiss for for ye all on one
second in 2016 we received 14 six
acknowledgments for Microsoft and Adobe
today we will show the techniques of
winners color is coach when we use the
important and kicked on should we start
okay so I'm going to introduce the first
zero to one so basically if we want to
exploit
if we want to attack the programs in
userspace or the programs in the kernel
space we have to deal with three
problems right so the first one is where
to write a second one is what to write
and third wise what can we do right now
so for the first question I think
everyone knows that we should interrupt
the normal procedure of your process and
force it to jump into our shellcode and
then what to write actually we want to
you make use of the abnormal T and make
use of them and the third one is after
we alter the data what can we do to
reach the final destination like
escalate the privileges to the system
privilege and all gain whatever we want
so in the old days we want to attack
Windows XP or Windows 7 so these three
questions are quite simple so we need to
focus on a structure that is called hell
dispatch table we can call a pair
function that is anti curious system
information to get the loading addresses
of all the kernel modules and we add
some offset and we can finally get get
the hell dispatch table so this hell
dispatch table is kind of a function
distributor there's a lot of functions
starting address in this hell dispatch
table so what we need to do right now is
to replace one or many of them many of
the starting address with our shellcode
address in the user space so then when
we call the function int curing interval
profile which has the kernel version of
the insecure interval internal profile
and the kernel version will find the
address of the starting address of in
the house dispatch table which now is
our shellcode address in the user space
and execute the our shellcode so it is
very easy for out school days but I
think the the Microsoft security
engineers are quite smart right so they
create to several of the protections to
fit in this action
so I think there are two most effective
ways so the first one is the integrity
verification and the second line is at
MEP so for the integrity verification
the system well we both know the process
has many attributes so that integrity is
one of its attribute so so so the
windows will check whether the process
is a high integrity user or a low
integrity user if it is that it is a low
integrity user when we call the function
ng Kure system information to get the
loading base address of the kernel
modules then what we have right now is
only a set status access denied so some
of the hacking teams they create some
ways to do to you know to buy passage
because they found some of the
information leaking vulnerabilities so
this information leaking vulnerabilities
will give us the information about the
loading address but you know this is
another vulnerability so we have we have
to use two vulnerability to you know to
gain our final reach our final
destination the other protection is
called SME P which refers to the
supervisor mode execution protection so
basically the list protection will
forbidden the CPU or the system to
execute the code in the user space so
what if we if we just round the code if
we just do like the old school days we
replace the share code address to the to
the address in the hell dispatch table
and execute it then what we have right
now is a Blueskin right there we go
nothing from right so some of the
hacking teams are very smart so they
came up with the ideas of the RO
keychain I think everyone knows it's ROP
chains they use the ROP chains to remove
the SM EP protection but in order to do
so the firstly they also need a
information leaking vulnerability to get
the loading base address of the win32 k
driver and then use the ROP chain to
close to close the protection so
basically we need two vulnerabilities we
need the ROP chain and we both know
creating or constructing this kind of
ROP chain is very difficult or very
annoyed so everybody is upset so this is
going to be our new exploit method so
our method has many advantages we can
use it on all windows operating system
no matter it is x86 or x64
we only need to trigger one time we can
bypass
SM EP we do not have to create any of
the ROP chain we just only change one
beat in the kernel space and we can
bypass the kar SR and now I'm going to
introduce the details of it so back to
the three questions where to write
things Microsoft does not allow us to
use the empty curious system information
to get the loading address but there's
something that they did not you know
they do not fine so this is a key shared
infrastructure actually you can see the
two share info structure has a kernel
map is in the kernel space but if you
loading the user 32 dot DL a other
dynamic a dynamic link library so this
kind of memory will be mapped into our
user space automatically by the function
MN of view of section mm map view of
section by that function so basically
that the data in the GTR info are mapped
into the user space so this is a kind of
information leaking vulnerability but
Microsoft did not regard it as a
vulnerability
maybe they were fix it in Windows 11
wins 12 I don't know
so as you can see that we had
the P hat the P hat is a is a member of
the hen hen reentry's handle entries so
this P hat will point to a window object
also it can point to a menu object so
I'm going to focus on the window object
so basically what we need to write is in
the window object so what's in the
window object there's a very very
important structure that is called tag
window object so window is the basic I
think is a basic objecting windows we
always use create window API to create a
window and then in the kernel the kernel
will create a tag window structure so in
this tag window structure it has many
important information like the the
parent window like the window process
like the name of the window like the
window extra data so what should we do
right now I think we should focus on the
windows extra data let's look at the
structure of the tag window so you can
see there's a member called Phoebe
window extra what is CB and window extra
Phoebe window extra is actually the size
of the window extra data section as you
can see at the bottom of this structure
so we could use two API to control the
tag window structure the first API is a
set window long and the second one is
get window long but there's two parent
that it is strangest index what is a
index actually we can regard the window
extra data section as a array as ad word
array so basically the egg index is the
index in the window extra data so what
we need to do what we could do right now
is to use that window long to write
something in the window extra data and
we we can also use get window long to
read the word in the we
extra data by using the n index param so
so this is a case that it's a normal
case so so we can see that we have two
windows the window one and the window
two and between them there are other
objects so in window one we have the
Seabee window extra the value is hex
eight and we can see that this is a
binary formation of the CB window extra
in the position three there is there is
a one and the others are both zeros so
what if we change we change the high
speed to one what do we do so yes we
just change the AK window extra size
from a very tiny size to a very huge
size so in our case the original science
is eight right and now we change it to
two gigabytes so as you can see right
there so basically the data just behind
just right behind the tag window of
window one becomes our extra data so we
could use the set window long to modify
the data right to modify the data are
just a regard these this stuff as our
data so we can use that API to change it
what what we can change it whatever we
want we can change the data into the our
you know future for our future
exploitation so how can we read from the
kernel space okay since now we have
changed the window extra data size from
eight bytes to two gigabytes so that
means the window 2 is probably by by
modified to the extra data of window 1
so now let's focus on a member that is
called string name
name has three members the lens the
maximum dense and popper so this offer
actually contains the character of the
window - but now we can change the data
in the window - right so basically we
can set the buffer to the place we want
to read and then we call internal get
window text to read whatever we want in
the kernel space is that amazing
so the thing we can also write something
to somewhere by using the API MT user
depth set text what we need to do right
now is to set the buffer to the place we
want to write and then we call this API
function and you know our data are
written to the position we assigned so
basically we can call the set window
long for many times we can reset the
buffer address for many times and we can
you know read and write anywhere we want
okay so now how to access callate our
privilege from the normal user to the
system user basically we just reverse
engineer wizard to reverse engineering
of the get windows thread process ID and
we found a relationship between the tag
window structure and the process at the
write the process structure so as you
can see in the window attack window
structure also a member called PTI the
PTI points to a tax read info structure
and textile infrastructure point to the
case read structure and at the offset
220 in case tread structure it points to
Delta member called process and it
points to the process structure and the
English process structure those are
talking those are talking of our process
but the windows help us why because if
we do not set our parent window to our
window windows will force the desktop
window
as our parent window so basically we can
use this phone with parents in our tag
window to find the desktop window and
through the same procedure we can
finally reach the CSRs SDXC the system
process and at the same offset we can
get the system talking what we need to
do right now is to use these two API use
this two API set window and a get window
to read the talk and from the system
talking and then we write it to our
talking position so this is going to be
our escalation process so this is a real
case the CVE 2016 zero one seven four at
first we load a font into the kernel and
the kernel will create a PFF object and
then with free the PFF object but
actually in the kernel somewhere stores
the reference of the PFF object and then
we immediately reallocate the same size
of the memory and we you know this is a
definitely I use after free right and
then we free the phone to again and
finally reach the step reach the Step
five step five is the assembly code yeah
it's right there so our X the Registrar
X is actually controlled by us we can
let the rx point to the at the tag
window as the offset DF at the tag
window and then plus they're a hex 3
plus taxi and we will reach at the
highest bit of the CB window extra and
now what we need to do now is to execute
the assembly assembly code that is or
the war PDR our X and plus hex Eve and -
and we can change the size of the CPU
window extra to from zero to two six
zeros so in the part phone we are
attacking the flash and we are using
the flesh to execute anywhere in the at
windows edge and we escalate the Aja's
process the privilege of the edge
process to the system process privilege
and then we escaped from the sandbox we
complete this word you know we complete
this job in three seconds and we won't
the 50,000 reward and the surface pro 4
so in other case there are two assembly
code right there yes as you can see
reserved basically what we need to do
right now is to make the SEBI window
extra as large as possible so that we
can control all the data just right
behind it so if you do if you get it and
you will make a success so in summation
where to write we need to write the CB
window extra so what to write actually
we just change one bit of the SEBI
window extra and make it make it as a
very large size so what can we do right
now after we do that stuff we can read
from anywhere we can write any value to
anywhere and we can steal the chocolate
of the system process to our process
that is a whole procedure of our
exploitation from zero to one okay so
now and my colleague in will introduce
another technique which refers to one to
zero and how do experiments color
benefit from the Oratory won't the
previous presentation give us the answer
now we have a new question if we come up
our beach form 1 to 0 how can we do the
same job let's have a brief view of the
function and TDD arkad part unicode
enrages this function calls from at once
and the return at first its course gie
get Forge unicode arranges the first
korean HTC is the hand of our device
context our font has been selected into
the device context before releases the
second
RMT banana we will get the range size of
the photo only then decide is Scylla to
indicate free tobacco and we will get
our temporal memory buffer we call GI
you get quarter equivalent radius of the
end since the Purim to use a memory
buffer so that is the rich data would be
rich into it we deliver the data from
one color to user space and the
frigerator bottle and one two three four
five of steps is seems to be very simple
however it is no security in the same
force sometimes UMI's look this may be a
winner of energy let's consider a
situation where her chip has of what one
got small ranges suppose is that is one
the other got not religious suppose is
said is 10-under we have to straight so
the a and s really be they are both
doing infinite loop so the a cross then
P GDR get partially decoded ranges
excuses the thumb steps so the B do the
same do days to they can job is we are
layers more and a large point we must
have a person agrees so the B is
negative small radius
points on into DC so it equals GRE get
point of a decoder ranges for function
and get the small side one-third is
adequate on memory power which is only
one part then serve is negative energy
religious function G DC so there we are
should a called gie catalytic arranges
again with the mom bytebuffer
lawsuit a we office the Nigerian watch
so turn by veggies data is going to be
written through one page plan for what
will happen we will catch all overflow
so this is the civil year 2016 is 3 3 5
5 they hope for this we already happen
with one second we are tied John my
computer my procedure Nagar I said
before question and not they need a
system right fourth so and not to sit
and let them do you reckon condition
after all the headers I could control
the ar-15 register then with the help of
this awesome code and ar-15 register I
cannot buy one bit of angular chain it
from one to zero just make field
position to now we have the floor and
the ar-15 but how could we avoid what
about to be extra as we mission before
we could turn four to zero or his
fourteen to his ten but it seems to be
useless we re still cannot modify the
next tag of destruction
what about a flight there is a lot of
flags in title in the structure we
control some of the flag with beat from
one to zero but I didn't find any
perfect when you appreciate is for it
let's record to show you pour in handle
infrastructure the opposite his 10 is be
type it show us the type of objects
pointed by Pete if you think the object
is a clip data if you see the producer
is a monster if we clear with the four
from the six and twenty two two three
four the clip data objects to the menu
object so we have our type confusion
whether of energy I can control the
printers in the menu object and the
modifier other memory
it sounds good and actually our words
are who for the who exploit based on the
ticker technique before however this is
not a general solution what if we need
to modify the position zero oppositional
three so I started to find out why
there is a more general report the
answer is the rabbit Court in each race
32 km yes they were like tag event tag
Emmanuel tiger monitor the results in
occur objects memorize offices eight it
means the river count of the object if
some other objects report and there is a
reference counter eight one in the color
there are two functions which can be
used to modify the naka budget what is
it an SMS knock it's a it is used for
increasing the reference card the other
function is a general statement and not
it is used for decrease in the reference
code if we could destroy window or
destroy menu the function is an mark
objects destroy will be involved it will
check whether the roof counter is there
or not if it is not the object we are
not be destroyed if I zero the object
will be freed let's have a look at
another physical object in Windows menu
we can cope with minor API to create our
menu at the same time the color courage
or title menu structure we can call a
pendant menu appear to open down menu
onto another one right here request to -
menu a and the melody and the call open
the menu of all photons the data
structure in the color is showing us
here at menu 8rg items furniture array
and the three items educates the account
of the members in the array in our case
there are four items and the P sub menu
all welcome to might be so the reference
code of MIDI is 4 which is right here in
the scenic object since there is no
other manual pending chairman B we could
see it is a signal at
is thorough and agitance points to none
if we call the to a manual to destroy
maybe we will be failed because the
scenic object of many P is for the
system reveals us to do so with the help
of a floor and our 15 register we can
translate knowledge of the melody to be
zero
what can we do you know so we can't
destroy many freedom memory of many be
to be notice that the piece of manuals
they are pointing human be so afraid
object after destroy might be we have to
call until the deficit text immediately
to set our name for window if the window
a slowly the our memory would be
educated from desktop heap for storing
the name string what happened even the
name inside the same as might be the
system we are educated in might be
memory files which we just destroyed I
can see the lemon stream to be any data
so I can still the many base content
that you be elevated against it is a
point of many P to Engler many beetles
to be afraid memory so in turns to be a
fakir menu
so right now HP submenu appoints to your
fake memories what we do now is to make
a simple fake menu which is the three
items to one and nature as items points
to your memory we control in that memory
we fix our item structure and so there
is P sub menu member to your document
with opposite hits 18 you know my
situation let's be several menu appoints
to our tag menu structure now we've put
each point you're tagging the structure
in the middle we regarded as our tag
menu structure which we rip your bottom
menu what we care is the CV when the
extra which is also deep
no manual data in the water menu now
let's presume no together we can state
information of our manual bacon insert
menu import EPA there are two marks
which we are interested in when we
specify the malleus mask
in my menu data we will see the
development data of the title menu we
will specify the mask mm applied to sub
menus we will associate the data with
many data of the submenu one after
another
let's look at the picture we rebuild our
chair before manually sub Amir some men
used to be many B now it becomes a
freaking manual which is control valve
the effect of menus submenu is the water
manual which point to your takamina
structure in the middle
Maurice versus artistry mask we will
finally set the virtual menus DW
metadata that means we are finally set
the CP window extra window one we could
resonate the Previn digital system as we
said before to be notice that the three
atoms of the water manual is zero so the
operation of the city sub menus data
will be stopped
the watching menu the action and ggd
acted for generally couldn't register is
ad data you - mm SP - it has 15 years
privacy's to encode and also nobody
notices and the microsoft dinner changed
the code of the function for - mm oh
dear - one from will of 2002 will stun
from symmetry B's 216 for pete's sake
for Caesar remains the same what the
deal is with getting the instead post
and as a educating memory so again is a
data or the same so this vulnerability
exists in all the windows you can see in
the export and mission before I
use the window and the menu those are
the basic objects in windows and SEO for
be administered in GPS travel I can
match the attack and get decision
privilege by any user the update shows
show in the PowerPoint with the unit 10
15 11 16 forbid if you want to your taxi
other windows you know only needed to
adjust the offset now needs the justice
Rosa mode let's take our summary how to
import window scroll up a tiny bit from
1 to 0 the answer is the writing's arrow
to toggle menu screen lock object so we
create another user out of green
whatever finish because Tecna mean you
and the resist is living with the extra
port a comment I use the manual objects
for the job you could appear another one
if the object has pointers and you can
rotate her to the 40 dosages all set
always thank you for the coming any
questions
[Applause]