privacy as we know it is dead over the
last several years countless leaks
whistleblowers news stories and and so
on have revealed a massive
infrastructure that Orwell couldn't have
even imagined just built to collect your
data and surprisingly I'm not actually
talking about government certainly
that's there but that's not what really
scares me
I'll admit I've worked for government in
the past the US government specifically
and what I saw there was a large
infrastructure in place to look for
catch and punish any abuse of the system
what concerns me is is left that because
that actually worked very well in my
experience but what we're starting to
see is private companies having similar
capabilities without that oversight and
potentially without the ability to have
that oversight so big data the the
Wikipedia definition here data sets that
are so larger complex the traditional
data processing applications are
inadequate to deal with them so we're
talking so much data we don't know what
to do with it or what we even can do
with it
but the question is often what's being
collected and that's a really tough
question to answer because it's what's
not being collected is probably a better
question right this this seems to be the
approach collect everything you possibly
can and figure out what to do with it
later we've got tons of storage capacity
right and the algorithms typically have
not been in place to actually process
much of the data now we're starting to
see that change so
the promise of big data is huge right
we're starting to see some of the
applications of it these are these are
actual headlines so Big Data
technologies will play a key role in
diversifying Saudi Arabia's economy away
from a huge dependence on oil revenue
and and even the impossible right or at
least almost not to be a possible is is
being attributed to big data and and of
course I'm sure everyone knows the the
adage if a headline ends in a question
mark the answer's no within the first
paragraph the answer was in fact now but
this is the type of thing that we're
talking about big data resulting it and
and it's really world-changing a lot of
a lot of potential so that the title of
the talk is breaking big data evading I
really wanted to be evading meaningful
analysis of the metadata of your life
but that was too long so just evading
analysis of the metadata of your life so
why would we want to avoid this if if
we're talking about the Cubs winning the
World Series and reducing oil Doyle
dependency and and curing cancer so I'm
going to propose a slightly more
simplified version of the definition
here so data plus algorithms equals Big
Data IBM did a recent study that showed
three point one trillion US dollars
trillion with the T that's one thousand
billion u.s. dollars lost per year from
the US GDP based on bad data so we're
taking in all this data we're doing a
ton of analysis on it and and then we're
making decisions based on that
information but it based on the
conclusions from the data plus the
algorithms
so this is four and a half times the
value of Apple that we're losing every
year based on bad data so as a bit why
is the data bad as you can imagine tons
of potential reasons one figuring out
how to parse a bunch of data is not
necessarily the sexiest job a lot of a
lot of focus is placed on other aspects
of the bad data sources there every
reason you can imagine for any data
point to be slightly incorrect
corruption of data certainly so we have
to inspector this into the the
definition here so let's say bad data
plus algorithms equals big data the
algorithms are good though right and
maybe not so Kathy O'Neil released this
book a little over a month ago weapons
of mass destruction and it's fantastic
as it turns out these algorithms reflect
the biases of their creators so we're
really looking at algorithmic
confirmation bias here so and this is
not in a really overt or measurable way
so we're seeing that some of the
conclusions down the road may be
different than we expect and there's a
tendency in Western culture that the
fact of the fact right and and we
perceive these as facts unfortunately
the algorithms may not be as accurate as
we presume them to be so now we're
looking at big data plus I'm sorry bad
data plus biased algorithms equals big
data and and I would argue that you
could almost change this to say big
delusions
and this is what we're making this is
what we're hoping to cure cancer right I
don't know if anyone is has seen North
by Northwest the Hitchcock classic if
you haven't I highly recommend it
so it's a fantastic movie in the movie
Cary Grant's character is out to watch
with some some customer of your
colleagues and over the intercom in the
background
someone pages George Kaplan and and to
please get the waiters attention there's
a phone call or a message for about the
same time Cary Grant's character waves
to a waiter to call them over to order
something and the people watching for
who George Kaplan is which it turns out
to be some spies see Cary Grant through
this and and so it's the classic case of
mistake and I'd mistaken identity the
next hour and a half as it plays out in
quite fantastical ways but great movie
this is this is very much what we're
potentially looking at when it comes to
this bad data plus biased algorithms and
it doesn't even have to be bad data
imagine if your cell phone is connecting
to a cell tower and in one particular
place it happens to also have some
terrorists connecting to it and then the
next day you're texting your friend who
the day before was texting someone else
who is texting the same someone in that
same terrorist group and so on and he
played us out and very quickly you can
potentially algorithmically be linked
with some bad guys with nothing to do
with it or any other number of ways you
can imagine this villain right you don't
even have to be in the same hotel and
and raising your hand to get to the
waiters attention to thrust into this
world that you may have nothing to do it
unfortunately our our normal techniques
here don't really work against big data
there's a lot of OPSEC information out
there the grubs OPSEC briefing is
fantastic option has traditionally been
geared towards hiding from police or
intelligence or things like that and i'm
not going to talk about that at all but
so we're going to talk about controlling
what metadata you're putting out there
into this big data machine and limiting
information you might not want
associated with you personally so along
with all these leaks were revealing some
of this infrastructure we've also found
out some things that actually really
work and and one of them is encrypted so
to quote Edward Snowden properly
implemented crypto systems or one of the
few things you can rely on now properly
implemented I'm sure everyone here knows
just how difficult this can be but with
doing algorithms and a good
implementation you're probably pretty
good right but so what let's assume that
all of this content is encrypted email
content message being phone call packet
payload chair there's all things that
are fairly easy to crêpes maybe maybe
not for your mom or your grandma but I
think everyone here is probably really
well versed at disk so let's assume
that's encrypted along with that there
are a lot of things that aren't
encrypted so this is the classic
metadata right sender recipient
participants link source destination so
let's look at a quick case study you got
Allison Bob Alice gets an email from
British Airways and then Alice's phone
is in Seoul and a public post to
Facebook Seoul is so fun meanwhile Bob
texts Cindy and and I forgot to add
Alice and Bob are presumably happy very
happily mate so Bob texts Andy
Cindy text Bob Bob Uber's to a hotel
Cindy Hoover's to a hotel bob has a
charge fairly large one on his on his
credit card at the hotel then there's an
uber from the hotel to the restaurant
another very large charge at the
restaurant ah-hoo we're back to the
hotel then maybe the next day and we
were from the hotel de Bob's another one
from the hotel de Cindy's we got the
obligatory text and Alice's back and
what is anyone confused about what just
happened there
[Music]
there's there's not a shred of actual
content in this right this is all just
metadata so this is these are the things
you can't encrypt or at least maybe you
can but but they're much more difficult
to encrypt than the actual content and
this can reveal so much so Hoover did
this I don't know if anyone is familiar
with this but we were put out a blog
post called rides of glory and you can
imagine what this might be they started
tracking rides from like a bar to a
house at say 1:00 a.m. to 3:00 a.m. and
then another ride from that house to
another house in the morning and then
they tracked this across massive amounts
of data over a year and it was all
presumably sanitized not tied to any
individuals but they were able to
determine what neighborhoods what days
etc were optimal for what I can't and
and this is your privacy right so it was
funny it was really interesting actually
I'm sure a lot of people were marking
days on calendars like oh I'm going to
go out this day but I
ultimately this this could easily be
tied to you as an individual by anyone
with access to this data so but we all
we all probably know metadata is really
really dangerous the only caveat this I
I kind of lied to you before there's a
there's more to this quote than just
that
unfortunately endpoint is security is so
terrifically weak that NSA can
frequently find ways around it and
replace NSA with everyone the talk
yesterday about flipping bits was just
fantastic if you miss it be sure to
catch the video because it was
completely amazing what they're able to
do influence security is terrible and it
just seems to be getting worse that that
talk really Illustrated to me at least
how bad how bad things are so input suck
there's an ancient adage in the security
world right two types of inputs those
who have been compromised and those who
will be now run in 90s that started to
change and people said well there are
two types of endpoints those will be
compromised and those who don't know it
yet I just say there's a new adage
everything's compromised and this isn't
fun right fear uncertainty doubt because
what isn't compromised has permission
from you so another case study here's
Bob 9 p.m. and he pulls out Google Maps
drives to the pub his phone GPS also
shows Bob's driving to the problem then
Bob checked in at the pub at 2:00 a.m.
there there's a much more reasonable
charge for Bob at the pub and any drives
home then 6:30 a.m.
Bob's driving to work so his insurance
app on its own has permission to
location data has GPS all of this sort
of stuff and and even more frightening
what if his insurance company and his
credit card provider are the same
company so now can do you think we can
expect a spike in bob's in trend rate
after after seeing well okay he was
driving really fast to the table maybe a
little too slow and weaving on the way
home and then only four and a half hours
later probably not enough time to
metabolize gosh 9:00 p.m. to 2:00 a.m.
worth of beer driving to work so I this
is this is an example of the way that
we're going to very soon start seeing
this data being used against us so I'm
sorry yeah well so so the gentleman said
very soon right now a very good point I
I haven't seen any spikes in my
insurance although I don't exhibit those
same behaviors so I don't know I it's
it's certainly in the works I don't know
that it's actually being put into
practice yet so your life past patterns
your habits what what sites you're on
what you like where you get your news
but what channels you're hanging out in
IRC all the sort of thing it's fairly
trivial and let me let me also include
in that account certainly things like
this but anything that is unique to you
and surprisingly a lot it there was
there was a long time when it was
with the masses but you have to consider
that when everything is a data point it
becomes much more difficult to blend it
so your locations even if you have your
GPS turned off which cell tower is your
phone connecting to the routes you're
driving your favorite locations that you
go your home and something else let's
say that your car doesn't have like a
LoJack or a GPS built into it you leave
your phone at home and you go for a
drive
presumably no one will be able to track
you right so in the u.s. we've started
to see some private companies donating
cameras to police departments and
they'll put them in their cars and drive
around and this camera is constantly
looking at license plate they'll grab it
parse it send it off to the cloud where
or the company who provided the license
plate then read this it says hey is
there a warrant out for this is this
person you know it is a car stolen
things like this good things right if
your car gets stolen and you report it
and a police officer drives by it it'll
catch it what we're starting to see also
though is that this might be used in
ways that so you know the old adage if
you're not the customer you're the
product is a great example of that so
these companies are starting to sell
this to like collection agencies things
like that so now your location is a data
point even without you doing anything to
cause it to be then it's certainly with
red light cameras and things of this
nature
it's we're seeing a lot of that as well
so your interest the things you're
searching for things you're posting
even even teams that you like or
whatever your interests are
I'm from Arkansas originally so I got to
put the Razorbacks up there if anyone's
familiar but all of all of these things
come together to form a fingerprint of
you right your friends
so who you're in touch with all of your
social media and as I mentioned before
who you're in the same place at the same
time with so this becomes more of a data
point right and and you see a lot of
this in certainly on the government's
either there been a number of movies
demonstrating this type of thing but
even what aisles you're walking down in
the store what causes you to stop and
linger for a second this is being
tracked too and even your feelings so
something called sentiment analysis
where things you write reflect a an
emotional state or an interest or
something you like something you don't
like and anything you write publicly
publicly is being sucked into this and
as they do this sentiment analysis they
can actually and it can be language ed
not agnostic too so it's it's pretty
fascinating technology but it can pretty
quickly result in determining your
interests what you how you feel about
things is being used to predict
elections and quite effectively which is
also kind of scary but it's a and then
approach your parent so this is this is
good stuff here the FBI operates the
next generation identification
interstate photo system face recognition
service that allows law enforcement
agencies to search a database of over 30
million photos to support criminal
investigations the problem is what do fi
FBI photos look like
it's straight on and then to the side
right
conveniently Facebook has millions more
photos from every angle with millions
and millions of people going in and
making sure all the data is correct so
their database is much better than even
the FBI's and and again and I'm not
picking on Facebook or any particular
company but the amount of oversight over
private companies versus governments is
dramatically less so and in a very
everyday I feel more and more like I'm
in a William Gibson novel I'm so we're
starting to see makeup and hairstyles
designed to Ebates facial recognition it
looks fairly bizarre but and and there's
also a anti paparazzi scarf let's come
around it anyone seen it but it's a
struck that's highly reflective so if
you put it on and someone takes a flash
photograph they reflect so much light
that everything other than the scarf is
black in the photo which would
potentially work with IR as well right
so surveillance cameras tend to put out
a bunch of IR light and this week this
this is really cool now now we are
seeing some glasses designed to not just
mask who you are from from facial
recognition but to potentially make you
appear to be someone else so you could
actually frame someone with what's pants
and then you're writing so style metrics
this is it's also called authors
authorship attribution there's a ton of
tough stuff out there and you can
algorithmically look through large
bodies of text build an author profile
and then compare that to text by an
unknown author
and was a great deal of certainty
determined that it really was that offer
so I included this paper actually
implemented this in Perl this year just
kind of messing around and testing it
out and it actually works fantastic and
there there are a lot more people out
there doing this with a lot more
seriousness than me and so Dartmouth has
put out a tool called a knot amount
which takes in it'll you can create an
authorship proper profile of yourself
and then put some text you've written in
there which will then try to make it not
match here your profile right so there
are tools you can use to avoid this but
this becomes kind of a pain right
another technique I've seen is putting a
body of text in there Google Translate
translating it from language a the
language the language B the language C
and language C back lynge by that point
you have almost complete gibberish but
you have to ten come in and make it make
sense again but then it's it's very
unlikely to be tied back to you except
you sound like an idiot
right your timing so what times of day
your active when you're posting on what
forums when you're traveling somewhere
this this right here it actually looks
like snacks so you know people are
sleeping sleeping eating and then get a
midnight snack that's actually it's
actually a time analysis of shark
attacks sort of snacks but but that's
harder to track than you are so when you
tweet when you post on Facebook when you
when you do anything really becomes
significant and identify you there's a
fantastic talk on pattern analysis
yesterday which I attended and it was it
was really top-notch encourage you to
check out
the video that is relativistic all this
comes together to form what what in in
the government world is called battery
of life analysis it's a fingerprint of
you based on all of these things and
much more and we have well the way we
have to think about this now
so 5-10 years ago you could envision it
as well as long as the people watching
me don't detect when or what I'm doing
then it's hard to it's hard to do this
right except now I have to consider that
everything I mean everything's a data
point so anyone with access to the data
just like uber with the rise of ROI
anyone with that access can do this
analysis almost trivially and and then
combine that with the potential for bad
data or biased algorithms in it it's
really easy to see how things that we do
can impact its in unexpected ways a
really good example of this is take a
home loan typically we think ok they do
a credit check and they're not basing
things on let's say our race right in
fact in a lot of the West certainly in
the u.s. that's illegal
unfortunately the algorithms are basing
things on that so if you if you google
racist algorithms there's their spell
pot that's come out recently about this
where people are being denied home loans
based on sting said that frankly are
appalling
so a quick look at pattern of black
novice so again we're not looking at
individuals or analysts doing this where
how was was an easy choice here but so
you have it two locations you're at rest
your friends your feelings your metadata
all being pumped into this machine
that's been trying to make sense of it
and so out comes you except it's not you
that's it's what we'll call a persona so
everything you do everything you use
everything you say is linked to a
persona and if you're not intentionally
doing something and very intentionally
and very technically active doing
something in a way they won't have that
link to your persona then it's links to
your true persona even the things that
you really don't want me to you right so
it's uh it's it's all in there and
anything absolutely anything can link to
personas and if we're trying to evade
having activities associated with us
then links are bad so I this before the
drugs offset OPSEC briefing is
absolutely fantastic ton of videos
slides are out there if you haven't
watched it please do it's really good
it's it's probably one of the best OPSEC
resources I've seen so just a quick one
slide refresher for anyone who's missed
it and it's this is real fast here's one
of the fundamental premises paranoia
does not work retro actively so we have
to be mindful of this going forward not
go back and pick things so for any
persona one account one persona one
activity one phone number one persona
one activity one connection one home one
device one location and short want
anything one use and I'm sure that some
people are saying but Dave what about
the
one use seriously
so other options have it I'll tell you a
quick story about my best friend says
time I was five like I mentioned I grew
up in Arkansas which goes a familiar
it's right in the center of the US and
very woods and mountains that type of
thing so my best friend is kind of the
proverbial mountain man no Facebook no
he has the phone but it's he barely uses
it yeah he he he you know ten years ago
he's like I'm not getting in on any of
this stuff all my information out there
I don't want people see you in what I do
I all that and so I call it the mountain
man approach right largely after him
so unfortunately and that worked for a
long time today though let's say you
meet someone and they don't have a
facebook and they don't have any of you
Google oven there's nothing out there
they have no profiles on anything how
likely are you to believe that it starts
becoming more of a data point to not
have millions of data points then then
the reverse right it's it's easier to
hide in the middle of a haystack than it
is off here by yourself in fact this
this source is fantastic it came out I
believe today or yesterday when I knew
what this is from Reuters when a new
American diplomat arrives for duty at
the US Embassy in Moscow or Beijing CIF
CIA officials say Russian and Chinese
intelligence operatives run data
analytics programs that check the
digital dust associated with is referred
name if the newcomers footprint and that
dust social media post cell phone calls
debit card payments the too small the
diplomat is flagged as an undercover CIA
so the the one sure approach of not
having your information out there
results in you being more of a target
then in putting up the right amount of
data right so so this is this is the
essence of this hawk is is designing
what data you put out there to represent
the persona you've chosen to be
available one of the best ways I found
to do this is to actually kind of go
through and look at points of failure
right so it's sort of harder to teach
really good practices because
unfortunately there's there's no
one-size-fits-all and object so this is
a true story step one go to Harvard step
two take a really tough class don't
study at all for the final exam and then
the day of the final wake up and realize
oh crap so what do you do to get out of
it email bomb threat apparently don't do
this obviously so this this gentleman
woke up at about 8:00 a.m. his test was
at night at 8:30 he pulled up his laptop
open it up logged in to tour went via
tour to gorilla mail emailed a bomb
threat to to Harvard officials the
Harvard PD the Crimson witch is
Harvard's newspaper turn off his laptop
and anyone to take the test
as expected right at nine o'clock when
when he's sitting down with everyone
everyone comes in and he gets evacuated
with all the other students
- easy right I mean now he's got at
least a day maybe a few days to get
really prepared for the test except that
the police wouldn't talk to Grohl now
and give us the mail said now this
connection came in to get for so
dead-end right I mean conventional
conventional wisdom goes well we're not
going to catch it if he came in via tour
except didn't they looked at Harvard's
Network logs at 8:30 a.m. on that day
and guess how many people were using
poor on the Harvard Network for because
they went knocked on four doors and one
guy freaked out so this is this is a
really good illustration of sometimes
offset doesn't work the way we hope it
does
I stole a slide from the grog shop sack
presentation and again I'm not saying
there's anything wrong with the
information to prevent present I
completely agree with it
what he says is VPN equals privacy tor
equals anonymity so when you connect to
tor you're routed through several
servers around the world non knowing
where they are in that and that chain
and you end up coming out on the
Internet
with no real way to trace that back to
you fantastic technology the exit node
as it's known is controlled by whoever
has the willingness to operate or exit
mode right giving everyone in the world
anonymous access to their connection so
who might do this well a lot of people
who might want to see what's happening
there's there have been a number of poor
exit nodes controlled by a nefarious
characters in organisation so the
conventional wisdom goes
connected tor then connect to a VPN over
tor so that even the exit node isn't
being monitored and you have both
anonymity and privacy so the way the way
the drug says this tor connection to a
VPN okay VPN connection the Tor go to
jail except in this one case where the
significant data point and and I'll
remind you everything is a data point
and we never know which ones will be
significant in this case the significant
data point was that there were only four
people using tor so how do you reverse
this and done the go to jail line and
done VPN mentor he wouldn't be in jail
so the moral of the story is you really
have to be mindful of your particular
situation and what data you're creating
and how that can be used against you so
that's that's really the moral of the
story so what about Bob we've got we've
done a few case studies with Bob so
we'll we'll do some more now Bob he's
he's single now and and he's got nothing
to do so he decides to take up whatever
activity is what we'll call it so he
takes up activity and Bob lives upstairs
from a cafe he goes downstairs he uses
their Wi-Fi pulls out his laptop opens
up a VM and does that activity so how
many points here are connectable to Bob
and and feel free to be actively engaged
here you hollow out a number or anything
I'll start
so one he lives upstairs from the cafe
so there's location so it's the same
location this this Wi-Fi so it's a
connection right but it's conveniently
connection that's very closely tied to
his location and then is personal
laptop so you got the same hardware so
we've got at least three points that
link Bob to this activity and in this
case so very very easy for someone and
especially for an all-knowing you know
machine learning Big Data algorithm to
start tying this activity to Bob
there's also time right so time of day
Bob works from 8:00 to 5:00 he goes to
the pub from 9:00 to 2:00 and so we've
got from 5:00 to 9:00 where Bob does it
activity right so there's there's timing
as well over time this becomes easily
linkable to Bob so let's let's try
something else
Bob now drives across town to a
different County
he brings his phone but turns it off or
alternately he has one of those little
Faraday bags that he puts his phone in
that blocks all the signals right he
uses their Wi-Fi and uses a proxy or
uses seven proxies and again V in my
personal laptop so anyone want to toss
out any potential issues No okay so
we've got the drive so at least the
location is potentially not hobbled in
unless he took this car or unless he
took an uber or else he took a cab or
anything else that would potentially
have a data point linking him to that
ride to that location I would argue that
you probably can't have that that at
least something is going to tie it to it
whether it's the police car driving by
the vehicle or a GPS tracker or an we
ride
or whatever else right so it brings this
phone but turns it on let's go back to
the mountain-man situation so now all of
a sudden Bob's always active he's always
texting Cindy or whoever else and now
for four hours not only is Bob's phone
turned off but it's just nowhere to be
found and then when it comes on it's
across town so again sometimes it's it's
more noticeable when there's a lack of
data so then you get their Wi-Fi with
the proxy and the personal laptop right
again same hardware so we've got a lot
of these same potential issues this is
this is a much tougher one to track
right public transport to a park with
Wi-Fi this phone is on but it's at home
the users tour and completely separate
hardware so anyone seeing any potential
problems I see several there they're
just probably a little harder to find so
one public transport has a ton of
surveillance cameras and things like
this right so with all the facial
recognition unless you're doing
something to try to mask that it makes
it tough the phone is on at home this is
this is a great alternative to the black
hole of turning it off or or the Faraday
bag right except for one potential thing
we're still back to the mountain man
today oh because now he's not using a
song so where you'd normally see 50
outbound text messages and a few emails
and you know so Facebook activity or
Twitter or whatever now you're seeing
nothing so again
this is this is better than every other
option we've seen so far
but it's still not great then separate
hardware that's fantastic so what's the
problem with using a VM on your normal
machine - then do activity yeah so so
what if you what if you alter your MAC
address and software uh yeah right so
one there's probably a few seconds where
that doesn't take place I'll tell a
quick personal story I was I was doing
some research at my office on tour over
our network and I always at my office
I'll do a VPN to tour so that I don't
set off a bunch of flags that someone's
using tor at the office I had tor tor
browser open I popped up my laptop typed
in my password and and did the VPN
connection within seconds our IT guy
popped his head is like are you outdoor
and and it was fantastic it was a great
sign that that was working but even in
that split-second you can you can sell
out that a fight right which really
brings us to information tends to leak
in ways that we least expect it a good
example of this is Pizza sounds it
sounds kind of funny but consider this
let's say you're at your office and you
have a really big something happening
acquisition a big big project with a
customer or something like that if I'm
outside your office every day counting
food deliveries to your office on an
average day will expect to see you know
some some normal number but when
something really big is happening no
one's leaving the office so they're
ordering more food so I can actually
tell that something's happening based on
the amount of food
and and parking lots right so this is
this is called Pizza int and parking lot
it ant being intelligent so when you
walk out of your office and all of your
executives cars are in the parking lot
at 7 p.m.
what would you immediately think
something's up right if they normally
leave by 5:00 right let's say they do so
you're walking out of the office and the
CEOs charge in the parking lot two hours
later than normal if you track this type
of thing
gaily then all of these little data
points really come together and and
really start to show things
so in summary assume everything is
compromised be aware of links between
any activity and yourself look at your
own pattern of life and understand it a
really good way to avoid doing something
that would tie that to you would be to
understand what you're normally doing
and then operate outside of that in ways
it would be unconnectable to you and
then watch out for leaks where you least
expect them and I'll actually put this
put out a request to this audience
so he's black that we've got some the
most technically talented people in the
world right here so I've been working on
this research for quite some time now
and it's really really difficult to
evade some kind of link between any
arbitrary activity in yourself at least
technologically so as we talked about
yeah there are ways to do it but it's
really kind of reverting to old
techniques so I'd ask you to look into
this start looking at ways that we can
actually increase our privacy which is a
direction no one expects us to go
there's the saying there is no privacy
get over it
and I'm not quite ready to get over it
and I hope that everyone else in this
room feels the same way so with that
there any questions I'm happy to have
you to try to address some real quick is
your time okay so we got a couple months
any any questions all right
well thank you for your time
[Applause]