hello blackhat we are very happy to be
here and showed you your late latest
research regarding compression side
tunnel tags
let us first introduce ourselves I'm
ever here is Genesis and Dimitri's where
researchers at the University of Athens
in Greece and this is a collaborative
work with professor Angela chaos with
share in cyber security and privacy at
the University of Edinburgh as we assume
that most of you already know that a
bridge broke HTTP and 34:8 back in 2033
13 people who break upgraded from stream
ciphers to block ciphers to the ES and
so they were safe but rupture in 2016
attacked HTTPS with block ciphers what
we're going to show today is a generic
defense for a compressor side-channel
attacks we propose it it's the best
balance between compression and security
regarding the other proposal and we will
launch today a number source
implementation of our defense in many
popular web frameworks so we will talk
about the next one our is the history of
compression side channel attacks and the
attack vector and then we will move to
the city XD sense we will define the
origin the secret and the cross
compression of the city XD sense the
permutation we will discuss the CTX
architecture and then we will release
our our new tool and to we'll talk about
future work so in 2012 crime was the
first attack to successful a attacks egg
it by in side channel compression it
targeted HTTP requests mostly headers to
hijack sessions and steal cookies and
took advantages of the characteristics
of the deflate algorithm
which is the the most popular
compression algorithm of today it hinted
at attacking responses although it
didn't implement it and after that crime
was mitigated by disabling the
compression at the TLS level so no no
side channel compression attacks for
HTTP requests were possible time 2013
exploited compression on HTTP requests
it exploited compression by measuring
time time transmission instead of size
payload and because of that there was no
need for money the middle-ages next with
bridge again 2013 exploited HTTP
response body the main secret was some
tokens some secret tokens
it has had stream ciphers and added some
methods to bypass compression noise due
to the compression attack the admin pool
2015 rc4 is considering secure and
that's why most website moved from
street side from stream ciphers to block
ciphers and that's why now ESA es is the
industry standard
Roger 2016 exploit compression against
HTTP responses
it attacks block ciphers AES and in
order to achieve that it performs
statistical analysis and bypasses a
noise and length hiding so even in the
latest versions of TLS a 1.3 roger is
still is still possible roger is a
production called framework which
automates the attack and makes the
process much easier and the last was a
presenting black Satya USA 2016 it's
heist which abuses the way responses are
sent of the TLS several level by
changing the TCP window
and again like time there was no need
for a money in the middle what agent so
uh let's go quickly through the attack
methodology how compression attack works
I want to ask the audience how many of
you have have seen any of the
compression side channel attacks before
like breach or crime or time by a raise
of hands okay so most of you have seen
this I'll go through this real quick so
the idea here is that we have about two
plaintext tests on our score test and
test underscore Rand and if this
compresses this and we compress this as
well then this will have a better
compression ratio than this one because
here this some sort of repetition so if
the plaintext is partially secret and
partially controlled by an adversary and
it's taken through a compression
function then the adversary by measuring
the length of the on on the network they
can tell if they actually hit the
correct secret so that's the big idea of
the this attack and the two components
these two two constitutes constituent
components are the reflection this is a
part of the plaintext controlled by the
adversary and then the secret is the
part of the plaintext that is the target
of the adversary and so if we go to a
diagram like this this is the adversary
they're targeting a victim on the
network and then the victim hits an HTTP
website like Gmail and the attacker
makes the victim make several requests
to Gmail for example by make it by using
Java Script on some different website
here they're injecting some code to do
that and then they measure the TLS
encrypted responses on the network and
extract the length from that because
length is preserved across encryption so
that's the basic idea and if we look at
Gmail a response for example you see
this exactly what's happening there is a
this is a search page of Gmail and it
includes two different things here is
the CSRF token if the adversary feels
that they can impersonate the victim and
then if the attacker puts on the URL
some search curie this is
like that in the HTML like this so if
they search for this it's reflected and
then if these compressed together well
then the attacker knows that they get
the correct secret and they can do that
letter by letter so that's the basic
idea and this is already what breach is
doing in ruptures doing timewise okay so
at this point we'll introduce our
defense which are and mitigates attacks
that use this vector so we will this is
the CTX defense and what this defense
does is protect context by using a
periodic manner in order to separate
secrets and avoid cross compression
between secrets from different origins
so this definition of whistle introduces
some notions that need to be explained
firstly what is in origin so we say that
an origin is the party that generated
the secret now this party can be either
the web publication or a user that uses
this web service and we will say that
all secrets that were generated by the
same origin will be compressed together
and we will allow cross compression
whereas a to secret that were generated
from different origins will not be
compressed together so for example if we
have an inbox at Google in books we see
that we have some mails and the sender
of the emails could be used as an origin
so the purple ones were generated by Ava
which is one origin and the orange ones
were generated by Demeter's with who is
the different origin so these all these
generated some secrets and these secrets
well secrets in the HCP response can be
anything practic technically any part of
the response which is encrypted can be
considered a secret but in general we'll
say that the secret is any piece of
information in the response that can be
accessed only when the user is loading
so this can either be some
a financial data a SSL token some
private messages or emails or other
sensitive data so for example in our
previous example we saw that Ava sent
some emails and the body of those emails
can be configured and considered secret
now all bodies of all the emails are
secrets because they are set its data go
ahead for the user of the service but
different secrets we generate by
different origin so the purple bodies of
emails were generated by Dimitri's and
the by Ava sorry and the orange ones
will generate images so an orange email
is a secret generated by a different
origin than a purple email and in that
case we say that secrets like emails
that were generated from the same origin
are allowed to compress together so all
emails that were generated by Ava will
be compressed together whereas emails
that were sent from a different page
people will not be compressed together
so we will not allow cross compression
and what is cross compression okay let's
say with two elements in plain text
we have element a you have a lemon B and
if we allow cross compression then the
presence of a during compression will
affect the compression of B so for
example if we're using lz77 algorithm
for compression and we have plain text a
concatenated with B where a is secret
one and B is secret too then when using
cross compression LC 77 will actually
use a pointer for the second secret
string and it will so show to the first
secret string so the compression will be
something like that this is an example
of a course compare
if we don't have our cross compression
then uh both of these plaintext a and B
would be a so l77
will not use a pointer and how can we in
general protect from our secrets from
this side child they were proposed many
solutions for solving this problem and
in previous papers which they proposed a
disabling compression altogether now
this method obviously solves the problem
because
compression is the side channel that
allows this attack however the
performance penalty but will come from
disabling compression altogether is in
real world terms unacceptable so we
can't actually disable compression a
second proposal would be to change the
compression function and change it in
order to prevent cross compression
between secrets and reflection or
adversary generic data in general but in
theory we are we're finding so far that
all good compression functions are
vulnerable and we don't have a practical
example of a compression function that
actually prevents side channels like the
one we saw before so this also is so far
not a good solution
I third solution could be to modify the
web server and the compression module
that runs on the web server in order to
[Music]
annotate different parts of the page and
not compress these parts together but
this also has some problems because in
this case we have to both change the web
server and the application level
services and also this is this method
actually makes it really kind of hard to
achieve good compression rate so
it's in a middle ground but it's not
that easy to actually develop it and a
third solution would be to actually add
some random data which prevent the
attacks from reducing easily what is a
good compression and what is about
compression so when we run the different
candidates in our attack adding random
padding would probably hide the fact
that good candidates compress better
that bad context and this was actually
implemented until s13 however in rapture
we are it showed that this method is
also susceptible to alignment using
alignment alphabet to result in blocks
in block alignment in the block ciphers
or it is also susceptible to statistical
analysis so it is actually kind of a
half measure it doesn't solve the
problem it just pushes it to the future
our proposal is actually to change the
response blinded so this is in the
middle ground and we have implemented it
in order to prevent these side-channel
attacks
okay so city X protects HTTP responses
since we already said that due to the
mitigation of crime that no compression
attacks are no longer feasible so City X
is only for the responses
it runs ended at the application layer
so there is no need for modifications of
the web standards or the web server and
is obtained as we will show from our
experiments it's the best balance
between performance and security we
achieve this we achieve full prevention
of complete latex recovery just by a
slight compression size increase and
with just a small time performance
overhead so what we propose is a
successful defense for all known
compression attacks
such as
all these mentioned before time crime
Brits so what the application developer
has to do in order to include CTX
defense to hit their application they
need to import two libraries one for the
server side or the specific a web
framework they use and for one for the
client side then they need to select
which portions of the color of the
context are considered fifth secret and
define origin for its secret now if we
we can divide our whole response in many
origins we could have one origin per
secret but this is the same as a
completely disabling compression which
is no dude and we could also have one
origin for the whole plain text which
would result in no CDX protection so we
need to define the origins for its
secret here is an example we have a for
loop this is a template and we have a
for loop for emails and we want what we
want to show is a table it's the center
of the email and then the body and what
the developer has to do so as the city
expect the sensitive part of the
response which is the email body is that
we see a we use CTX protect tag and we
use email and email body and email
sender email body is our secret and
email sender is our origin after that he
has to include CTX permutations this is
a script add projection which includes
all the permutations for its origin and
the final one the physics object is the
client now if we didn't use a CTX
protection what this
the response that would travel through
the network and this is it would be
encrypted okay but this is the response
that the server would send now if we use
City protection what an advisory would
see is something like that instead of
the city XProtect tag we have this deal
here which is a data set X origin with
an integer to define which origin this
is and then we have the secret the email
body per muted and now this is not easy
and advisor can distinguish and it can
perform a set channel compression attack
now let's talk about permutations we
need first to define the secret alphabet
this is we need to to know what all the
characters that the secret may include
it could be a ski it could be utf-8 or
anything else and then we we perform a
sender Adam permutation for the secret
for each origin we know network see it
secret sorry for it secret out of it and
we used fishery Yates south logarithm
which is which performs an unbiased
permutation meaning that each element
has the same probability of being chosen
then we permute the secrets using the
the origins permutation that we
generated before and then this this HTTP
response with the per muted secrets or
TLS encrypted and traveled and
transmitted through the network
once on the user's browser we apply
inverse permutation and we typically we
decode the secret here is an example of
how this happens we have two origins or
it's in one and origin two and here are
are the permutations of course there are
more but here is what we're going to
need and we have two secrets from origin
one secret one and secret two as you can
see this is a permitted secret we use
the same permutation for the same origin
so secret and secret are the same and
okay one and two are different because
they have different permutations and for
the secret generated from origin - we
have a completely different permutation
because the different origin and a
completely new permutation has been
generated the power of the bridge attack
lies under the assumption that we can
perform multiple requests - to the
target and after that do some
statistical analysis what we were
implemented is that parity Theory
response we have nuclear origin
permutations so multiple requests are
made multiple pred and different
commuted secrets are being transmitted
to the network statistical analysis is
no longer feasible okay so at this point
we have found that there is a problem we
have found that there are some attacks
that use compression in order to bypass
security we have developed a defense
that actually mitigate this problem and
we want to argue why this is a better
solution than other proposed methods for
mitigating these attacks
so we'll perform some experiment in
order to measure our defense we take the
size overhead that is added to
once so this is actually the kind of the
body the man who is penalty when the
server is sending the responses over the
network and the time performance which
translates to the server time the the
time the server needs in order to apply
CTX and the time that the client needs
in order to deeper mute the secrets that
were sent over the network so our web
page is basically a 650 kilobyte HTML
page the uncompressed page is a 650
kilobyte this is a fairly regular in the
real world systems like YouTube or
Facebook the timelines are about that
size we use the 50 origins so with we
assumed that this page in this page the
content was generated by 50 different
people or channels or even the
application that generates CSS tokens
for example and we assume that one
percent of this web page is actually a
secret so we distribute this one percent
to the 5000 it is equally now 1% might
seem a little low or might seem a little
high it it is actually kind of higher
than real-world systems use because we
found that for example a facebook front
page had like 0.5% secrets and all other
stuff in there are cDNA libraries or CSS
libraries or static HTML code which is
not a secret actually so 1% my inner
example I'd be a bit exaggerated for a
facebook timeline for example but with
is actually a good rate to s
our defense and well this 1% is equal to
deviated origins so we say that there is
one secret position in the response
priority now even if there were multiple
positions we City X allows cross
compression so even if we use like two
or three secret petitions this X would
actually be compressed together so it
doesn't make that much difference in
considering our experiments okay
and we run these experiments and we
found some kind of interesting results
so I will compare our defense with the
other proposals the first proposal was
to desert the compression altogether and
as I said at at the beginning this is
actually kind of bad in performance
terms so if we disable the compression
in this web page with these heuristics
the size overhead will be a one-point
1000% so the response that would be
transmitted over the network would
effectively be 12 times or so other the
compressed one but we sent right now so
that obviously introduces a bandwidth
problem and also again depending on the
network that the user is using or of the
server this might result in actually a
few seconds delay of loading time in the
response so I think that for a fairly
regular big application that has not so
many like a thousand clients this is
kinda bad this is really bad
a second proposal that was actually used
by Facebook in order to prevent exactly
bridge from stealing Caesar tokens from
Facebook was masking secrets and what
what this method does is
a secret and it generates a random
string of the same size and it applies
an XOR of the mask the randomly
generated mask and the secret this is
done for every response so obviously a
in every response the transmitted secret
will be different and we the attacker
cannot use the statistical analysis to
find the secret but this method actually
what this and practically give that is
disable compression because if you mask
a secret then the data that will take
the place of the secret will be
practically random so they will not
compress well with the rest of the page
so in this case you actually kind of
disable compression for secret and also
double the size of those secrets because
each time you have to include both the
the master secret and the mask in order
to apply the de masking in a client so
in this case if you practically disable
compression for altogether for secret
you have a about 21 percent size
overhead so the the face that will be
sent over the network will be like one
point two one times the the size it is
right now and well that doesn't sound so
bad it might result in a in a few dozens
of milliseconds delay for the network
transmission or the web server to apply
masking it well in some cases if you're
not so worried about performance or if
the secrets are that important and you
don't have any other solutions well it
could be a solution yes you could
probably use it but well we propose City
X is actually allows for a better
compression ratio and that is because
we allow compression of the secrets and
because the permutation is the same for
all secrets these will actually compress
well because the protected secret will
have the same statistical similarities
done the unprotected secret although it
will obviously be different because it
is per muted so in this case our
experiments so that when using CTX for
this same webpage the size over
will be about 5% which translates to
approximately 7 kilobytes of data that
will be sent over the network compared
to what is the place right now and this
delay on the server side in order to
generate all the permutations in order
to mask all this to permute yeah all the
secrets in order to create all the div
tags and send it over the network and
deeper muted on ohmic lines and actually
so the web page is a few milliseconds
time like for 2 to 10 milliseconds so
this is pretty good this this
performance penalty is in general could
be considered acceptable either for
large applications that have millions of
clients because what this does is
actually mitigated a serious problem
with every little performance penalty
and well up to this point we have seen
that there are some different elements
and some different parts of the defense
that actually change how it runs and
these parts are the origins they are how
many secrets are in the webpage so if
you have like 1% of the webpage to
secret compared to 90% well this
obviously will affect the performance of
CTX because there is much more things
that needs to be permuted
and also if the total response is bigger
than
CTX will also have a different type of
performance penalties because civics
indeed adds some constant length of data
and that is for example the div tags or
the jason that included that has the
permutations in it or the actual CX
client script tag so what we have found
is is that the more origins you use the
worse the performance of CX will be and
that actually makes sense because if you
use more origins then a secret will be
divided in more parts so compression
will be disabled for those parts and the
compression rate will go down so
performance will also go down and while
deciding which origins you want to use
is actually a good it should actually be
taken into serious consideration in
order to avoid a performance penalties
that what could be avoided for example
also if the total of secrets in the
webpage are going up then performance
also goes down because the more secrets
you have to mask - the more secrets you
have to protect so the bigger the other
per muted our data in the response will
be the longer the permutation to be
applied will be so the server side and
the client sides that actually apply the
permutation and the D permutation will
take longer so that actually makes sense
however if there are more origins a more
secret pair origin then because CTX
allows cross compression the performance
will go up because the compression rate
will be better so secret will be
compressed together because they come
from the same origin and the length will
be actually small
and smaller because our compression will
be better
and finally if the total response goes
up then the performance will also go up
because as we get and that kind kind of
addition because it's not so obvious at
first why what happens why when the
total is bigger we have better sex
performers and someone might consider B
K if it would it could be possible that
the more the bigger the response was the
more the thicker there were and actually
that would result in in a worse
performance but the thing is that we we
have a bigger is a response then the
actual bite size that will be included
as an overhead in the compressed text
will be sent over the network it's
fairly the same it's not that different
so for example for a small page and for
a fairly large space like Facebook the
overhead penalty in bytes will be from
seven to ten it's not that much however
the more the beginners response of the
the less the impact this overhead will
have all the actually a performance so
for a large web page these seven or
eight or nine kilobytes will be kind of
hidden in the large the larger context
of the response so only if you use a
bigger response and when you have a
bigger application CPX actually is even
better so this is a diagram that shows
exactly this the the x-axis is the
response size so we started from a
thirteen kilobyte web page this is the
not compressed HTML response of the
webpage and we go all the way up to 650
kilobyte a web responses like Facebook
like YouTube like Twitter and what we
see is that the Left y-axis is the
percentage of overhead penalty that city
exerts so for a really really small web
base like 13 kilobytes
the penalty is kind of large yeah the
CTX will result in about 2.2 percent
overhead in the response so with if we
you have a web site that sent back 10 or
20 kilo byte responses CTX will kind of
double or results in 2.5 times the
vegies content that would be sent if you
were not protected at all but what this
means is that actually the the actual
and data but are sent which are sown at
the right y axis will be about a bit a
bit over five kilobytes so because it is
a small web page five kilobytes make it
a gator of different a difference and
yeah it will actually be compared to
what you had before it will be much
longer but as you evolve your
application you add more stuff you add
more functions you add more features and
the response grows larger but you
continue to use DX and CTX actually
continues to add the same amount of
response by it it goes from five
kilobyte and we see that for us the
response page grows larger the purple
line actually goes down because this is
the percentage of the
X penalty and the orange line will well
it will say the same at about some time
and then it will it will grow a larger
but in a more spin a smoother way so for
example for like 500 kilobyte page you
will add five point five kilobytes of
data and this actually means that you
are kind of double the response because
yeah you still have used to use 50x it
still visible compression up the point
but if you use a web application that
sent back like six hundred kilobytes
responses the added data will be like
seven kilobyte so the actual overhead in
percent percentage terms will be about
ten percent which is totally stable it's
a four because four in six hundred
kilobytes well seven don't make that
much difference at all okay so this were
absolutely the experiments that what we
as we run so I want to show you a little
bit about how how this works ckx
architecture will go through the server
and the client side a little bit so how
does it work what the server does is it
goes through the the tags that you have
on your Django or whatever service out
using and it generates the new
permutation for every origin so if it
sees a new origin it will generate a new
permutation and notice that this is
basically just a a replacement cipher as
these are cipher lock kind of thing
right and then this permutation will be
stored for each one
virgin and apply to each secret if two
secrets share the same origin then the
same permutation will be applied to them
and notice that this happens every time
a request hit this hits the server so
the permutations are different every
time and this is why this works
basically and then at the end of the
HTML body in the way that you saw the
HTML code there's the tag that you saw
with the permutations this basically
includes the data that allows the client
to unfirm Ute so this is just a jason
like data painted to it so that's the
service side part and then the client
side part just does exactly the opposite
so it looks for these specially crafted
div tags and then it goes through your
dom once pages to load it and also
parses adjacent to find out what the
permutations of servers and then it
applies the permutations in Reverse on
each secret so that the original data
can be recovered okay so today's a big
moment for our team because we're making
this old sort of this software
open-source it's actually right now open
source on on github we just made it
public you can go here to download it
and install it and you can also go to
our website on CTX defense com2 to
download and install it so today we're
launching it for three web frameworks on
the server side one is django one is
fisk and one is no js' a note reyes you
can use a bunch of different templating
like jade and it works well with the
expressed framework this is MIT license
and we're also providing a client which
is published on Bower so you can install
it on your websites right now and play
with it yeah and these of course the
Python endnote frameworks are on pi pi
and npm everything is public okay and
then we're hoping that you will take our
code and maybe implement it in different
frameworks
we are the Python and JavaScript
libraries that we have showed here while
we have provided specific
implementations for Django in flask and
Express we have also provided generic
libraries for the cryptographic part so
you can just reuse these and build your
own for your own framework or your
custom web application like Ruby on
Rails and then this implementation works
for limited encodings so limited
alphabet we are hoping you can
contribute with different encodings
because otherwise it's not very usable
so what yeah if we only support ASCII
and utf-8 maybe some languages will not
work well and then if you want to also
go on our github one other thing that we
want is to support client-side
frameworks like react so that this
protection can also apply on Jason
restful endpoints I would be good okay
so the key takeaways is HTTP plus gzip
is still broken even if you use TLS 1.3
this is still attackable we showed you
also some examples of interesting
interesting as aerial cases where
there's the reflection is not very clear
for example this one adversary
controlled email body and one victim
controlled email body and the adversary
can use that as a reflection which is
quite counterintuitive and then CTX is a
solution to this so we invite you to
start using it start reporting bugs and
show us if it's good or not tell us what
you think so that's it from us and we'll
be happy to take your questions
[Applause]
[Music]
are there any questions
oh yeah so the the HTTP headers are
typically not compressed if you use
lowest version of TLS the request is not
compressed at all and the response is
not compressed and then the body of the
HTTP is compressed but that that doesn't
quote the header the header defines a
compression method so you're safe on
that any other questions before lunch
okay so let's go back to the email case
that's a good question
so say here the problem we saw with
breach is that if the adversary
extending the victim emails say that
immediately is the adversary here and
he's sending me some emails and these
are specially crafted reflections and he
was feel whatever ever has sent me on
this other email that's that kind of the
attack model there if the mid-race is
able to find out one word from this
email this will compress together so if
we use the same permutation for these
two then these will still compress
together that's kind of the point but if
we use a different permutation here and
a different permutation there then these
will more compress together but the
emails from the same origin will
compress together to achieve better
performance so that's the reason we are
we have to have separate origins okay
any other
all right thank you very much
[Applause]