welcome to our talk today my name is
Todd berry I lead the security research
for the advanced threat analytics
product in Microsoft and with me attack
ready a researcher in the team and thank
you all for coming I know this is a hard
hour the last hour the hour that
separates between you and your drinks
and London and so on so hopefully we'll
keep it entertaining and hopefully you
would enjoy that so what are we going to
talk about today well we would like to
take you along to the journey that we
had and we had extracted quite a few
insights in our journey to protect our
customers against the targeted attack
and some even philosophical insights
about being gay cyber judoka using the
attacker forces against them and so we
would start with the primer on targeted
attacks really real fast and I'm sure
most of you already know that and then
we'll take a deeper dive and we will
analyze a single test case of lateral
movement reconnaissance and we start by
knowing the enemy and dissecting the
attackers TTP's tactics techniques and
procedures also it will talk about
recent development in that area and they
will discuss in their bloodhound as I'm
sure all of you heard of and so it today
in end is a bloodhound the arsenal talk
so a big round of applause - Andy yeah
so and you can also cheer him up after
the talk and go talk to him great day
great guy and great tool and we had
taken one step further with an
autonomous lateral movement
proof-of-concept tool then we would want
to leave you just with the problems we
will talk about defenses against
defensive moves classic defensive move
how to blog how to detect how to prevent
such attack and hopefully we will
convince you you can take it to the next
level
and use these attack techniques in order
to defend your own network and we will
discuss two specific defense in fact it
I will do that and discuss how lettuce
can be used to detect pass the hash and
how some our reconnaissance can be used
in order to detect a local user attack
so let's start okay so it's very very
obvious and but we need the Sun Tzu
quote in every security presentation
that in order to win in any battle but
specifically in the security information
security battle you have to know the
enemy and in fact this is a pretty messy
situation today
all unlighted defenders know that they
should learn about their attackers ttp
tactics techniques and procedures and
build their own mechanisms and TTP's in
order to fight them and also defenders
are using red team of pen testers in
order to exercise and simulate attackers
move and and exercise and how to stop
them and be better trained and be better
in protecting but that's not what we
mean in adapting a attackers tech tactic
of course you need to do a red team you
need to rehearse and mimic the attackers
but that's not judo yet the DiGiacomo
dos says that of course to be boxer is
very important you need to defend you
need to stop you need to mitigate but
you can take the knowledge that you have
gained and use it in order to a better
defend your own network apply the same
message that the attackers do and apply
them for defense and hopefully by the
end of this talk you would be able to
convince you this is not just a nice PR
and phrase but also something quite
actionable that you can do on your own
so let's take a little bit this is a
little bit of a philosophical slide that
the
right so why in the first place and
defenders are able to learn from
attackers because in the end of the day
defenders and attackers are very much
the same we all wear a head be white hat
or black hat but it's still ahead
so defenders and attackers make all
network a deployment in other terms
defenders will call it proxy on network
monitoring attackers will call it men in
the middle or eavesdropper same goes for
hot deployment either an agent or
malware depends on where you sit and
privileges both attackers and defenders
strive to use as little the lower
privileges as possible because they
don't want to add any additional
requirement to their attack tool or
defensive tool integration both both of
us try to live off the land attacks
don't want to bring extra binaries to
the environment and defense a product
does not want to make do not want to
make customer to to buy another pervert
another product so and the expertise is
quite the same we supposed at least to
be well-versed in always internals and
networking both attackers and defenders
so it's very similar and domains and
therefore it really makes sense the
defender will be able to learn from
attackers and with that let's talk a
little bit about targeted attacks and we
use the attack kill chain model in order
to model their advanced attack so in the
first phase attackers are able to
penetrate into a single machine within
their victim internal network most
typically by launching a phishing
campaign and eventually someone would
click the malware or malicious link and
get compromised but this is just an
arbitrary user not necessarily the user
that we are after their data or the
attackers after their
his or hers data and now that the
attacker has a single a computer they
control they want to advance within the
network move towards as many computers
as possible in order to gain the
ultimate privileges in a Windows domain
the domain admin credential and using
the these credentials they are able to
gain domain dominance either by directly
installing something on the domain
controller or just pulling that out of
it maybe doing a distinct to get all
keys information from the domain
controller and then they attacker have
the keys to all the doors but they are
not winning yet because they need to get
some specific data out of this network
and be able to accelerate it and only
then they can call them the campaign to
be a successful one and this is a data
the domain that Microsoft 88 it's
focused on and we try to a unlike a
single link cuts that chain and so to
make the defenders win and just a - it's
important to understand where we are in
plate because to see the problem that we
are facing so are a gateway usually see
traffic from flowing into the domain
controller so it does see a lot of
traffic intercept traffic authentication
stories Asian other protocols but it
does not see traffic that doesn't go to
the domain controller and it can't see
encrypted traffic going to the domain
controller and we will address two of
these two problem these specific
problems and we'll show how using some
attackers method who are able to
compensate for the lack of visibility so
now let's take a deeper dive into the
lateral movement reconnaissance and they
see in what attackers are doing this so
just to remind us is the attacker goal
in that cell is grow from here that
arbitrary
a random user that they were able to
infect and get to their to domain admin
to the ultimate privilege in a Windows
domain and how do they do that because
every journey starts with a single step
so a single step in that case would be
to move from one computer to another and
attackers use a current computer user
privileges in order to execute on the
target computer on the next computer and
they do that technically by using some
remote code execution tools such as this
exec W max Egremont PowerShell and quite
a few more and the payload did they
execute on the remote computer stills
the users credentials and create a new
session or migrate to the existing
session and attackers do that repeatedly
these steps one after the not after the
other and until they get to their
destination of the domain admin an
important note is that this process
requires some high privileges on the
target machine because as you would
expect not anyone can execute any
commands on remote machine you probably
have to be an admin on that machine in
order to execute on it remotely okay so
how can we get methodically from here to
there and the physical world the answer
would be a map they are in the computer
science lingo it would be a graph and
specifically directed graph in which in
this map the cities are computers and
the user that are logged on to them and
the rows are computer and user
permissions so a computer a would have a
road to computer be if logged on user on
computer a have code execution
permission and privileges on computers
be in order to build the map attacker
needs to note this three ingredients
that we'll talk in the next slide about
them specifically they need to find out
about the cities where the users are
logged on the roads user permission
two computers and destination who are
the domain admins there a suckers
destination and all of this knowledge
must be gained just as a low privilege
user account because if it's already a
high privilege account then the
attackers had won and this kind of
activity is called reconnaissance it's
taken of course from the military domain
it's all about gaining knowledge on
anniversary in a hostile environment in
this case the attacker adversaries asked
the defenders and this is the graph that
I stole from Def Con a presentation of
bloodhound and because it's very good
and let's drop the matter for that's
what's going on which we use a bob we
see use upon let's see if we see this is
the Bob okay you see user Bob and his
member of a group IT admins and we
learned that group IP admins are admins
on computers everyone and we learned the
attackers learn that user mary has
logged on on computers everyone has
session to it and she is also a member
of the group domain admin so it really
shows us it showed the attacker a path
how to get from user Bob to domain admin
so let's break it down to the specific
phases of it specific steps and let's
take it one step at a time so first how
attackers learn that user Bob is a
member of group idea that means well
this is very easy it's a simple
command-line do a go to your Windows
computer do if it's member of domain and
do let user slash domain and the
username and you will see a lot of
interesting data but the user including
group membership so and that user Bob
will give us a and the attackers its
membership same goes for net groups all
kinds of interesting data and
information about groups and their
members and you can do full enumeration
all users all groups or just for
specific entity and over the network in
manifests itself as you can see the
allow lower
ten side is some our protocol traffic
against the domain controller so if we
are monitoring the domain controller we
can see that and require permission and
maybe it would be surprised but any
domain user n domain user can learn
about all members all all users of the
domain all groups even if it is not or
she is not a member of any of this a
group and we can see a screenshot of
that command and just enumeration of
some big domain and a list of users
reducted the list of user is returned
okay the next step in the attacker plan
is to okay we learn the Bob is member of
group IP I mean let's learn what group
IT admins can do maybe there are admins
on computers everyone and to do so you
can utilize this powershell commandlets
getnet local group written by a
colleague of md very screwdriver right
and so this is a publicly available you
can go grab it from github and using
that command a the user can list local
users and group on any machine and again
requires permission any domain user can
query any computer and over the
networking manifest itself again it's
some are traffic but this time against
the queried computer and not against the
domain controller as we achieve and you
can see screenshots of the output of
this command and we queried the client
one a computer and got a list of the
groups on that computer and of course we
can list the a group of a lot of
administrators local group of
administrator and files who are the
local administrator on that computer and
the final step was to find out that on
computers everyone who is logged on find
out that Mary is logged on on it so if
this functionality is implemented in the
Nets s tool it this is a very old tool
it
was the banner said it was written on
January 2004 some more than a decade ago
and what it does it uses the SMB service
and the sob service can be queried
remotely for active session who is room
a remotely connected to the SMB server
on the machine and in reply it returns
the IP address and the username of this
user over the network in many sets
itself is SRV SVC protocol traffic
against the domain controller again if
you monitor domain control traffic you
can see that and requires permission
again like motive any domain user so but
how does it help attacker to find out
who is logged on well every logged on
user fetches group policy from the DC on
in a periodic manner when they when you
log on you fetch group policy and also
in periodic manner every one hour and a
half and group policy are sent over SMB
so if a talker and queries the domain
controller who is connected to your
version B you will see a portion of the
clients that are currently downloading
and their group policy over SMB and by a
querying foreign let's say an hour and a
half all connected users should connect
and grab group policy and attacker
periodically samples a domain controller
for user
there are connect of SMB and is able to
see who is connected where uses in the
lower and in the end of this a sliders
screenshot that nets s against a ADC and
returns is the admin is user at the
admin is connected from I gather 1002
and using that we can discover all the
whereabouts of all the user all of the
on user and specifically use a marriage
that is connected to seven one so let's
put it all together so we had use above
and discover the attacker discovered
is a member of a group ID admins using
the netskope command then using a guest
net local groups against computer server
one the talk has learned that IT admins
are insect administrators auto
administrators on sever one and they
discovered by sampling and periodically
with net says the domain controller for
SMB connected users they found out the
user Mary's logged on on sever one and
she is a member of group domain admins
again that group or net user on Mary and
so we have all the ingredients attackers
that let's have all the ingredients and
to do their job also attackers got a
little bit lazy and saying oh map is for
old guys it's so many well we need the
navigation apps the this generation
requires a navigation up don't want to
do the hard work themselves so they have
bloodhound and developed by again very
scooped guys and you can go on download
it play with it yeah try it on your own
network you will be amazed with the
results you would find something
interesting I can guarantee ok and it's
not just a graphic tool it's not not
just present of this connection in a
nice graphic manner it allows you you to
to do all kinds of queries and most
importantly find shortest path from one
user to another specifically from the
user that the attacker of ten tester
controls to the domain admin and show
the path ok so we had imagine let's
imagine an autonomous lateral movement
to ml where that automatically executes
blood down star reconnaissance well we
can imagine that quite easily compute
shortest path the domain admin well it's
already part of say blood down this that
should be easy and the mirror then
automatically do the lateral movements
suggested by blue the blood downs of
bloodhound like a functionality
and now we can you can open your eyes no
need to imagine anymore because we said
well we're even lazier than blood down
guys
because navigation app is for old guys
we want an autonomous vehicle and sauna
most car that's what's going on today so
we're telling that bloodhound dog to go
fetch and an autonomous lateral movement
to developed by Microsoft as a
researcher Tama or aka Sal to dot now
that's how other Tom more talented Tom
and get bloodhound a exported graph its
photos a JSON is attack plan input and
then execute that attack plan a remote
code execution with the remote
powershell partial remoting and
credential have a think from memory with
mimic ax so let's see a demo of it no
want to see a demo
[Music]
I think we're good to go so this is the
attacker control user is a to Elm client
size PC the attacker on execute blacked
out reconnaissance and fits the result
into the bloodhound a database in UI
which is there is a nice simple graphs
but we want the paths and from the
control user user to that we have all
the way to domain admin and this path
traverses through and three different
computers and three different user we
will export that data into JSON and then
fit it and to go fetch it's written in
Python and it takes as an input that a
graph don't worry if you don't see too
much because we'll do zoom in one two
okay this is oom and this is attack
blender and three steps in it and
divided to five but it's really three
step three machines that the attacker
has to traverse through and we can see
the attack is already on its way and me
we were executing using remote
powershell and mimic us on that path and
ntlm hash is a cross extracted on the
way are prompted to the screen outputted
to the stream and we can see that that
finally the tool was able to extract the
administrator a hash as an executed
attack plan as suggested by platen so I
think this pretty much impressive I
think so and we won't leave you just
with the problems now it is coming to
help at all save us all with the defense
so die okay so walk us through the
lateral movement attackers battle moon
movement tactic and several contents
techniques now let's see how defenders
can defend their domain so many dos
attacks so firstly that defenders would
like to do is blocking those attacks or
in our case how them
if we're talking about the local users
and groups connaissance where the
attackers trying to get as much
information from our domain machines
about the users and their permissions
there is needed over the protocol name
sama and since Windows 10 there is a new
registry valuable energy poverty main
restricted remote sum which controls the
access to this exact same protocol so we
can edit this photo call and move any of
any domain users allowance and add the
domain all only local administrators and
permission and since Windows 10
anniversary update by default you have
this option I mean somehow is already
hardened the only local insiders can
remotely call this protocol and there is
a huge group policy settings that can
control this poverty and we are lucky I
so they can have them the local user and
group another thing that the fellows can
do is detect ok detection is quite
simple they can detect the many in this
case we have abnormal access to
resources in the domain environment
these are that they compromised the
attack is compromised is performing
access to many machines in order lame so
this access can be monitored by a
security device in this case you can see
a screenshot from a ta which tells us
that user two which was compromised by
attackers we performed many access to
various a machines in our domain in this
case 25 and normal resources were
usually accessed only 6 so we have
abnormal detection of the users behavior
ok
we blocked the attackers from accessing
our users and groups say from local
machines but the next test we want to do
is blocking them from getting access to
users
and groups in our domain which are not
local and again the this query let user
net group also goes over their sam'l
protocol and if the defenders have
Windows Server 2016 they can edit the
same registry value and remove or set
the access onto local min status and if
a normal user or regular domain user
tries to get for example in this
screenshot an egg group domain admins
which gives me gives it the domain
address in this domain you'll get access
denied and again you can detect this
query also again you have a summer
traffic to the domain controller and
this time the network and device detects
the query and over the protocol somehow
and it can detect the user the exact
user that they found that action from
which a machine and which method on the
protocol was caught in this case it's
that you can see it what it's the I know
what all users okay some user would
would like no all the users in this to
me okay so the next thing that we like
to block is getting information on
logged on users in this domain so as Don
mentioned autocracy is the next tool
against the domain controller to verify
and which user is logged on on each
machine and which IP this access this
method called has a specific registry
value in the diversity we start in this
case is s obviously system equal as you
can see in this screenshot and this
value this registry set property
contains an access control list which
tells the tells us who has access to
this method
so the defenders can remove the
authenticated user group manually or
they can use the tool that wrote message
tool that does it for them and we need
that one day anywhere a regular user
tries to not just the domain controller
to get access denied as you can see the
screenshot below and again detection is
also possible in this scenario in this
case we are talking about the SLV sec
protocol which is the SMB protocol so if
you have a natural device that monitors
the traffic to the domain controller you
can see that a leafless administrator to
perform the SMB nasturtium emulation and
you can tell exactly which users were
exposed to display so that's even better
for forensic so investigation on some
attack
okay so we've locked the ethics but we
told you that you can use the specific
attacks in order to have a better
details so let's let's start with the
nexus in example in order to understand
how we use the nexus for better results
we need to talk about a little about the
ntlm authentication until until an
authentication the user tries to
authenticate itself against a remote
machine this server the user who's
trying to authenticate itself sends the
authentication request to be the
magnitude domain controller and the
domain controller sends a verification
and the federation data in case for the
successful authentication but this
traffic between the server and the
domain controller is done via secure
channel which means this traffic is
encrypted so if you have a security
device that monitors this traffic it can
do anything with that possibly so why
are we talking about ntlm and I tell
them is very common in attacks in some
attacks and killings essence such as
pass - okay were the hashes can tell and
hash and Intel in real attacks it's
still possible and sometimes a theorem
is done by default was in such cases you
have all the tattoos that
get an upgrade to tables all you use
some attack against the remote machine
by its IP a lot at DNA and this case
calvo's can't really world or sometimes
we have chaos failures where the
operating system downgrades
automatically to internal application so
as i mentioned earlier since we are
talking about secure channel between the
server and which delegates the 10th
occasion to the domain controller we
have a visibility problem ok we have a
security device that monitors this
traffic and the only thing that you can
know is the opcode which means the the
letter that was being called over this
protocol in this case we see here the
method and they include the encrypted
data that came with this a method for so
we can't miss the user information we
can know which user was performing this
application and from which machine which
helps us identify pass the hash generics
so how can we overcome this problem well
here comes the NHS a 12 once we detect
successful ntlm authentication we can
extract the source IP which is the
server that was delegating this
authentication and to form against the
server the necess recon ok that would
give us the user the profoundest that
open the session and the IP that it was
always involved we also implemented this
scenario in different tube but it will
be public soon then let's see so if
you'll have a look at the entire
application again
so we've detected a successful until an
authentication our security device once
not just against the server delegate
this application and we got the user one
in this case and it's IP address so the
visibility problem resolved
that's
a quick demo I'll show you this side
exactly that's a second
okay here we have our domain controller
okay let's run our security device in
this case a wire sort and filter on ntlm
authentication and let's go to our
machine this is a machine now and violet
let's see who's the user is the one and
it's IP is 1000 - okay you can see here
let's perform some remote access to
another machine in our domain in this
case 1000 10 and we will do it by type
II so you have until Annunciation ok
we're successful academic education and
access the SMB server on that machine
and let's go back to our domain
controller here you can see gentle an
application the IP that delegate this
application and as you can see here this
data is encrypted so you can only see
that the opcode 31:39 Morse code so
let's use matches against 1000 10 the
source ID server IP and as you can see
here we have user 1 access from the 1000
- which is the attacker issue ok
okay so that was Nessus let's see how we
can use the sam'l protocol which gives
us the ability to query our local users
and groups and first let's understand
why local users is important are
important for attackers mainly for one
example we have a problem in many
organizations that there are existing
users on any machine local
administrators the same identical
password usually this is done by IT
admins that install add their own user
to the whole day domain machine and they
give it literally the same name or the
same strong password but once you have
attackers that compromised
one machine they can extract these
credentials and use this use a local
user to move laterally into another
machine allowed me so we can see a
report from Fotolia that this a lot of
movement technique does the hash of
local teen status was successful in 60%
of the dentist another problem that the
attackers use the local user for is
persistency okay they add their own
local administrator to the the
compromised machine usually no one
notice that in this case you can see
that let the user admin name admin was
added to the administrator group which
gives those attackers and the ability to
get back to this machine with this user
service it since we are talking about
the local users the authentication means
locally okay so that's mean that it's a
problem to us if we are monitoring the
domain controller and traffic no traffic
will be noticed or will be seen in this
channel so our network security device
can see it and again we have a solution
for that
this is what the summer queries fans
inhale we travel we can theoretically
clay local users over the summer
protocol on any machine in our
environment get user information get the
group ownership and with that we can
discover several detection which I will
go into details soon enough but info
title it's abnormal login patterns boot
for the tenth privilege group for this
occasion toss-up configuration issues as
much more let's see exactly what I mean
ok so it will quarry very a computer
periodically and get and compare the
last one time of a user with the
previous time that we see this is a log
log in you can see the Tamaki user logon
the user never logged onto the scene and
now we see that it did block one and you
can detect that and alert on this and
another thing that can be easily
detected is the brute force attempt in
this case we can see the bad path of
count property again with the same
technique it was zero before and now
several thousand of say let that passes
on easy to detect a brute force and the
ethical path of the detection is also
something that is quite easy to detect
because if we have a duplication of a
hard life and all machines or export of
the ends you can see that the same
easily on different machines and with
the same path of last set which is 64
bits may tighten that will trigger and a
detection of duplication which can be
abused or exploited by attackers when
the last thing that we can detect is the
addition to the administrative group or
any other group privilege group in this
case we monitored a machine at a one
time and and and the next day detection
of the next time we saw
delicious ezel was added to the group
two-dimensional group so you have a new
detection thank you so Thank You ty for
providing the optimistic part of this
talk I try not to ruin it with the last
say three minutes okay so you might have
asked yourself okay II we had presented
something about do Rotom Bob boxing so
what defender should do what should they
choose so they choose to be boxers and
block or enabled these all these API and
use them and we say why not both you can
actually in this case have your cake and
eat it at the same time so for example
for reconnaissance api's so as it I had
shown there are ways to harden them and
limit the access to this API and indeed
why should any users all users have
access to it but we can still live a few
user or one specific user that is able
to do just that and equip the hour a
monitoring system with the permission so
we we still get to use it for judo
using that against the attackers but the
attackers have really a slim chance of
landing on that specific user and
abusing it and we can still keep our
detection open it's not like okay we
block that so attacker wouldn't use it
now we just need to tweak our detection
algorithm and detect also excels at them
so in this case I felt the attempt to
retrieve next session information will
detect an alert in Microsoft a DEA or
any other solution and the second
question that you might have is well you
showed us quite a few nice things
hopefully you think it's nothing and but
is it really general or is it just
something that you happen to find so and
we're showing just
two sinks and telematic Asian visibility
with net session Nets s recognizes a
local user visibility with summer
reconnaissance but we still have some
topics that we didn't discuss and
because there isn't enough time and we
have all times due to differences for
example a cover defenses a defensive
error injection attackers may use curved
arrows error injection in order to
trigger malicious password change or
encryption downgrade and in fact there
is I saw in in Blackett today Tom Gillis
and the bill document from a dimension
data Belgium if you see them they know a
lot about the triggering vulnerabilities
with a offensive error injection but we
learned that we can use it for defense
for example and this is an elegant way
to block authentication and request that
we feel that is suspicious and prompted
the user to explicitly enter a password
so if the attacker only knows a hash it
would be an elegant elegant way and to
block it and if we are wrong and this is
a regular user then okay it's a bit of a
hassle but we can input a they can input
their password and move on so this is
another judo defense or another place we
can implement it is to do brute force on
brute force if we see a certain a sudden
surge in authentication requests and but
we don't know if it's something normal
or this this brute force and of course
the password themselves are encrypted so
can see that different password or at
the same path of being repeated due to
some error so we can do all kind of
brute force on brute force in order to
find out if it's really brute force or
just some technical problem and we have
quite a few of them so we feel like it's
quite general and and what it really
tells us and you can adapt it when we
record
that you adopted attitude is whenever we
research a new attacker tactic so we're
not just focused on understanding it and
detecting preventing it we also always
keep in the back of our mind we think is
there a possibility can we do something
be sensitively and use that ability and
I think this is a good attitude to take
in all areas of security so let's
conclude what was new in this talk
presented the lateral movement
automation module go fetch in fact of
where Thomas just uploaded the video to
YouTube so you can check it out use the
time to tweet it on the side and so
check his or mine account and boxer
defenses and we shown two ways to detect
some our reconnaissance and meta
reconnaissance from network traffic and
to harden them to enable only specific
user 3 and we had presented to do the
defenses using the attackers strengths
and capabilities against them local user
visibility that is games via some are
reconnaissance and entering lament
education visibility with the Nets s
tool for reconnaissance so if we need to
conclude this talking just one sentence
in order to defeat the enemy if you're
ready to learn the enemy and then you
know the enemy but finally you can beat
the enemy against that enemy and
defeated use their own strength
strengths and capabilities against them
final slide credits and sank so though
our reviewer MD here the so our
presentation gives some insightful
remarks Microsoft ata researchers that
are not here today tomorrow Melina Shima
Cove and kymo and finally last but not
least a Microsoft API designer and
designed all kind of cool graphic things
for this presentation specifically they
go fetch a logo and thank you all for
you for coming here today so thanks
[Applause]