okay thank you very much for coming
this presentation is drama how your dear
M becomes a security problem it's a
particular pleasure for me to be here
today with Michael Michael and I did
concurrent research meaning that we're
actually competitors rather than
co-operators and it's a bit weird
standing here so an old hacker type for
lack of a better word and be here with a
young academic like Michael but I think
it's a great thing we have sufficient
mutual respect for each other that we
can do this presentation together well
anyways let's go on with the technical
stuff this talk is about how leaks
information across security boundaries
what is not about is software it's often
perceived that if we fix all the
software box that we will have safe
computing however if the underlying
hardware is not inherited safe then we
have an insecurity problem so we've
found what we think is a design problem
with DRM and we can use that as an
attack vector the work design is chosen
with intent here it's not a bug it's not
like row hammer where you have a
reliability problem in the production of
DRAM it is very much to the way that DRM
works instead so we will be focused on
an intellect or the problem and we are
to identify this in DRAM meaning that it
applies to other platform as well so you
should just keep that in mind going
through this talk so the takeaways that
we want you to have when you go is that
DRM design is security relevant and
specifically that DRM leaks information
we can use this information to extract
information cross VM across CPU we can
spy another software and we can use the
information that DRM leaks to enable
efficient and targeted roll hammer
attacks so we're gonna start right off
with a demo and for the demo now we're
gonna need a random number between 100
and a thousand so if anybody who has a
random number just scream it out
otherwise take the last digits off your
credit card anon shadow not nine one for
sure to demo please yeah
so what we can see here now is we have a
virtual machine on the right side are
running a normal Linux operating system
with a shell in here and I can show you
we don't have any access to the Internet
we only have to duplicate apt and no
internet connection on the left side we
have Firefox running on our host system
and that is of course connected to the
Internet and our goal is to extract
information from the virtual machine and
send it to the browser so we can get it
to the Internet and maturing i.docked
javascript in the browser did some stuff
and erm found vulnerabilities and then
now I should be able I know I did the
same in the virtual machine they have
now a channel open and I should be able
to get information out of the virtual
machine to the browser so number was
nine one four right so even submit and
nine one it's not the fastest but it
should be quite reliable and we can
really see I type in the virtual machine
and get the numbers out of the out of
the virtual machine without any
connection between the virtual machine
and the host system on the outside and
your credit card number or whatever it
was
you see Yui I don't know is now on the
Internet good so switch back to the
slides can we switch back to the slides
yeah
so what did you see here there were no
software bugs we use zero software bugs
for this demo and we had a real covered
communication from the virtual machine
to the Internet and we just had a
JavaScript running on the host system no
binary on the host system and this is
magic and in the remaining talk we are
going to present all the pack runs and
what exactly we did here to make that
work but first who are we my name is
Maya Schwarz
I'm a student a PhD student at Kass
University of Technology you can find me
on Twitter you can write me an email you
can come to me afterwards so that we can
if you have any questions want to talk
and I'm part of a research team at cars
University of Technology consisting of
beta pestle Daniel calls comedian
Maurice and Stefan mangas and together
we did a lot of research and just erm
stuff and also published paper for the
first part of this all the backgrounds
at the using security conference in
August and this talk is then the
extension of this paper with all the new
cool features we have here so my name is
anders fogh I'm a principal security
researcher with GData advanced analytics
and you can read reach me on Twitter and
by email as well so usually we want to
leak secrets there's nothing no nothing
funny in leaking stuff that isn't secret
and secrets are usually managed by
software and computers so we need to
find out how we go from software DRM and
here our software is symbolized with a
move instruction x86 instruction and DRM
is symbolized by a capacitor if you're
asking yourself why a capacitor well DRM
stores data in capacitors there's a
capacitor for each bit if the capacitor
is charged the bit is 1 if it's
discharged it's zero so we need to find
out how we get from this mob instruction
to these capacitors and the first thing
that happens when we run this mob
instruction is that we
discovered that default 1.1 in the last
slide is a virtual address of the
current process however the CPU needs a
physical address to talk to DRAM and
consequently we need to do a bit of
translation so why do we need to do
translation well back in the late 80s
early 90s
indle decided it was a wonderful idea if
we could run more than one process
securely on a single CPU and the way
they implemented this would was that
they gave each application its own
private virtual address space and then
have a mapping for each process - from
virtual memory to physical memory the
exchange ability is that each process
has its own that is when the operating
system of kernel swaps process it will
just swap the mapping and everything
will work fine this also created creates
a choke point where every memory
instruction has to go through and this
choke point can be used for checking
privileges on memory access and this is
what is happening the operating system
usually takes care of these tables and
if you have a hypervisor in your system
it has a second go on new memory
accesses what actually happens looks
something like this
in the upper left corner you have the
cr3 register this is where the exchange
ability comes in the operating systems
uses differences to swap table every
time it swaps the process down below you
have the virtual address and you see the
uppermost bits are going into this fall
level translation table
called the page tables only the upper
bits are actually used to translate
something
so usually we translate to four
kilobytes the rest of the bits are taken
once too directly from the virtual
address and added to the physical
address so we're doing translation on a
page level and pages are almost always
four kilobyte large there are exceptions
but almost always that is of course a
bit quick for you me to summarize the
paging operation of modern CPUs and
operating systems so we have a summary
slide here of what it's important for
you to remember well what is important
is the most significant bit of the
virtual address determines the page the
page is almost four kilobyte large and
the least significant bits almost always
twelve of them this
offs it into the page only the page is
translated and thus security checked so
these are the facts that are going to
turn into a violation of an assumption
later on so I should also be mentioned
that these page table this is the entire
security check there is from memory on
the x86 meaning that beyond this point
the CPU will think that everything is
good and dandy there will be no more
security checks once we clear the page
tables in security check we run into the
data caches the story here is that DRM
is relatively slow to modern CPUs and
the idea with caches is that you store
frequently used memory for the CPU and
have every memory reference go through
it the caches are so built that they are
transparent to the operating systems and
to programs and tybo slices and
everything else we here as attackers
have a problem with caches that is we
want to talk to DRAM because that's
where we have our problem so we need to
bypass them we need to bypass this
roadblock and we can do this in two ways
the easy way is that indle provides the
unprivileged instruction actually as two
of them seal flush and she has floss up
unprivileged for cash maintenance by
applications we can use that to bypass
the cache you saw javascript and the
javascript we don't have access to any
special instructions like the seal flush
instructions so we need to use a
technique called evict there is a paper
by bruce maurice and manga on this
subject called rule homogeneous that
describes how we can evict stuff from
the cache and thus bypass it we'll leave
it at that there once we have passed the
data caches we arrive in the memory
controller the memory controller does a
lot of stuff but the thing we are
interested in here is it has a mapping
function this is where the physical
address is taken as input and through
the map the capacitor stores the data we
want to read is found which will take us
to how is DRM actually organized so you
have an
how this map is used what you see here
is dim this is what you buy if you go to
a store and buy DRM and you can have one
or more dim in your computer and they
are connected to the CPU through
channels and these that the dim house
front side on the back side and these
are called ranks and on the ranks we
have a number of chips and if we open up
the chips we'll see we have a number of
banks inside each of these Bank have a
row buffer we're gonna be talking a lot
about the row buffer in a moment for now
we'll just have a look what's inside one
of these 30,000 32,000 rows of the bank
and you probably guessed is this is
where we have our capacitors the
capacitors are part of a cell and a cell
consists of a capacitor and a transistor
each this means that each bit takes only
two electronic components is to be
stored the capacitor is there for
control so that we actually get a chance
to read and write the bit now here so
that we don't bore you too long before
it gets security-related this is the
first end of trouble a row is 64
thousand cells meaning it's eight
kilobytes Lodge and security was checked
for four kilobyte blocks so we have here
first hint of trouble
this means says security domains may end
up sharing rows we're gonna talk about
what about those who just didn't want to
bore you so we're going to talk about
how DRAM actually works how you read
from DRAM and internally DRAM is only
capable of reading entire rows this is a
design decision so that you can maintain
only two components for storing a bit
meaning that the entire overhit are for
a very large number of bits so
internally it can only read entire rows
also capacitors in cells discharged when
you read the bits what I mean by that is
if you take a capacitor and put a
voltmeter on it if the capacitor is
charged will see a strong spike and
you'll never see anything again so
reading DRAM actually
stores the content of the cells and the
solution is of course we read the bits
out put them in a buffer and write them
back when you're done and this is the
row buffer this is why we have it here
so say the CPU wants to read something
in the yellow row here then it's the
first rope and the Rope are first empty
so the CPU
tell us we need something from this row
and then we activate it activated
hi is nothing more than essentially
copying the row to the row buffer
nothing more just copy it to the row
buffer and then we can extract the bits
that we needed from the row and return
to the CPU so now it becomes funny if
the CPU immediately afterwards decides
it needs to read some stuff from the
same row again to maybe some other stuff
in the row well now the row buffer is
already full and the CPU can get it
directly from here this is it sounds
like it's less work and the question is
is it faster in fact this very question
was what got me into researching this
stuff so what we did was we measured the
latency of row hits that is when the
information that we are trying to read
is already in the row buffer and we got
this nice graph and then we measure the
latency of reading from memory when
there's a row conflict or row miss that
is when the data we're reading is not in
the row buffer it has to activate the
row before and if we put these two
together we can see that there is a very
nice threshold that half of them the
green the row hits is almost always
faster than the row misses meaning we're
able to distinguish from outside if a
row was in the row buffer or not so we
can just summarize everything up to here
security is typically checked for four
kilobyte pages we can bypass the data
caches to read from DRAM pages of
different security domains can share
bank's pages of different security
domains can share rows and through
timing we can establish row hits and
misses across security boundaries and
the total result is
DRAM leaks information so now that we
have a background on the theorem and we
know how the theorem is organized we can
do our first attack and do a reverse
engineering of the CPU so you remember
this slide we had that a few minutes ago
in the background that's the mapping
function of the memory controller so if
you have data that has virtual address
and then it translates to the physical
address the physical address gets to the
memory controller and the memory
controller then uses a function to
decide where in which location of the
DIMM the data is actually stored this is
this mapping function so this is a
mapping function of skylake computer
here and the problem is we don't know
this mapping function so this is not
documented there is a secret it'll keep
the secret they don't want anyone to
know this mapping function but we are
really interested in this mapping
function so we really want to know if we
have a physical address where is this
data stored in the action theorem in
which bank in which channel in which a
rank in which tip we really want to
notice and that's why we need the
mapping function and as it is
undocumented we have to reverse engineer
it and we want to do it only in software
so we could do that with hardware
measurements but we wanted to do it in
software and we already know we have
timing differences so we want to exploit
those timing differences to really
reverse-engineer the mapping function
from the timing differences only and
here's an animation about our approach
so what we actually do so you can see
here atom and it has two chips on it and
we call each chip Bank and then we see
that this is numbered rectangles in
there that are the rows of this and
after of the banks in the DRAM and then
we just start with one random address
with ristic one completely random
address and this address will be
somewhere in the DRAM and it will be in
one bank we don't know which bank but it
will be in some bank and then we select
more random addresses so this the first
one is our base address and then we
select more random addresses and then we
have Maddie's addresses so we access the
base address and the other address and
then again the base address the and the
other address and so on and we measure
the time it takes to hammer those
addresses and if they are in different
banks then it's quite fast because they
don't influence the row before they each
have their own row buffer it can be
served in parallel so we see fast
timings if we choose random addresses
that are not in the same thing and if we
find an address that maps to the same
Bank in the dim then the timing is worse
so it's much slower because now we have
two addresses in the same Bank but in
different rows and that means it always
has to overwrite the row buffer you
remember a row buffer from before if I
access there the first address it gets
copied to the row buffer if I access the
second address it has to be copied over
the row buffer so that will be slower
and then we can see if addresses map to
the same Bank or if they don't map to
the same Bank and then we choose another
random base address and do this again
over and over and we again see addresses
that map to the same Bank have high
timing different Bank low timings and we
can do that for all the banks you have
in a dram which was random base
addresses from every bank and then find
addresses that map to the same thing
using those timing differences and then
we have for each Bank a set of addresses
that map there and we can see that as a
linear equation system so we have to
physically address as the coefficients
and we have the bank number as the right
side of the equation and then we have a
few equations and a few coefficients and
we could solve that and if we solve that
we get the mapping functions but as we
were a bit lazy when doing that we
didn't want
an equation solver so we did brute force
and that makes my sounds low but it was
really fast to brute-force into the
equation system you only have series or
ones as coefficients and you only have
up to 30 coefficients that's very fast
so it was in the order of seconds to
minutes depending on the computer the
fastest resort for example on this
computer was 6 seconds from starting the
measurement until having the mapping
function and this Lobot was the
measurement so brute forcing the
equation system took a fraction of a
second and we did we developed a toolkit
that does that fully automate it so we
wanted to have to run a lot of computers
so we did and fully automated tool kits
to reverse-engineer the mapping and
that's really fast depending on how much
memory you have between seconds and
minutes we open-source that tool so it's
available on github and you can just
right now pull the repository compile
the program running on your computer and
hopefully until the end of the talk you
will have the map mapping function and
you can compare to the ones we have in
our paper and we did it for a few map
machines so if you have the same machine
you will hopefully get the same mapping
function for new machines you get new
mapping functions so you can really try
that out you don't have to do anything
just start a program and wait so what we
now have is a toolkit that gives us the
mapping function for every computer and
we know which physically address maps to
which part of the DRAM and we can do
that everywhere fully automated and now
we want to exploit that knowledge so we
have that knowledge now now we want to
exploit it with some attacks
so the first thing you know we want to
exploit here is we want to spy on other
people's software through the DRAM and
imagine this function it is really an
imaginary function it's inspired from a
real function that leaks a lot more
information than this one does
imagine you have a scan code from the
keyboard coming in if it's uppercase it
goes into a handle uppercase function if
it's lowercase it goes into a handle
lowercase function now functions are
memory as well meaning that different
memory will be touched if the handle
uppercase function is called then when
the handle lowercase function is called
so we're going to see if we can figure
out which of these two functions are
called
and whether your password uses uppercase
letters or lowercase letters so here we
won't remember handle uppercase and
lowercase a different memory so we want
to spy on the behavior of a victim and
the victim actually won't know that
we're spying on him because he will not
be seeing that we're what we're doing in
DRAM his software will run as always and
he'll probably be in a different
security domain and doesn't have no
knowledge about what we're doing we can
use row hits to get useful information
about this and this is very much like
cache attack so maybe some of you went
to the talk earlier by Clementi Maurice
and Mort slip about Armageddon cache
attacks on arm computers it works pretty
much the same way but it has an
advantage over normal cache attacks on
the x86 this is that DRAM is shared
between CPUs on multi CPU systems so
it's really shared across the board may
need work across CPU as well so how does
it work well we established before that
you can have shared rows that is because
the rows 8 kilobyte large and pages 4
kilobyte large and and the operating
system Maps in pages so how do we go
about this well we start out by the spy
picking a random row which is not really
interested in in this case Rose Sarah
and he accesses some data in it and it
gets copied to the row buffer and the
data gets returned from there the spy
doesn't really care about the data or
the actual row he just wants to know the
state of the row buffer in this case he
had established that the row buffer
should be full with his own memory and
now he activates the shared row that he
shares with the victim
this gets copied to the row buffer and
returned and since the spy previously
had his own memory in the row buffer
from another row it'll take a long time
he would expect it to be a high timing
has a role conflict here however what if
the victim access to shared row before
the spy activated the shared row well
the victim will activate the shared row
it will get copied to the row buffer
he'll get his data him that he wanted
and now the spy activates it but this
time it's in the row buffer he will
retrieve the data fast and he will know
that somebody else accessed this row so
imagine if that was handled uppercase he
will be able to tell that your password
has an uppercase letter in it so this
brings us to two important questions
that are turns out to be very much
related as what is the chance that we
share a row with important victim data
and the second question is what kind of
spatial accuracy do we get I have to
explain this spatial accuracy imagine
that handle up a case and handle lower
case are very small function lying
directly next to each other that means
they would fit in the same page in the
same row and we would be unable to
distinguish between them so the question
here is how far do they have to be apart
for us to be able to distinguish
uppercase and lowercase functions in
this case and well the smallest unit of
physical memory is one page as I keep on
saying it's four four kilobyte large and
rows are still eight kilobyte large and
we need the victim's address and our
address to be in the same row so you are
probably thinking well two pages share
one row well you're not exactly right
either if you think that and why well
not the entire physical page must be in
the same row
and this happens when the mapping
function tells the mapping function and
the memory controller tells that the
page should be distributed over multiple
rows and this happens when the lower
bits which are not translated the 0 to
11 bits are used for this mapping on
skylake for example there are two yield
there are low bits that are used for
selecting the channel and the bank group
essentially the bank and thus the
physical page gets distributed over four
rows graphically it looks something like
this you have on the left side now the
page that we're interested in where I
say where handle uppercases and if we
have an address in that where the bits
are set so that d bank selection the
channel selection is both 0 we will end
up in the green green row below and if
one of the bits here the bank group it
is set to 1 well we'll end up in the
blue and so on and so forth another way
to look at this is here in our bank here
we have a Sandy Bridge with a single Tim
and the mapping function does not have
any bit of the low bits in the low I you
does not use any of the bits in the low
Elevens to map it meaning that we get
the case that we have been talking about
so far the two pages per row this means
we have a spatial accuracy of one page
that is 4096 bytes and our chance of
getting co-located with important victim
data is relatively small because we have
to get exactly the other color or we
don't I can't not see anything so this
doesn't look very promising for spying
but it turns out that IV prints with two
DIMM modules have one bit in the lower
level bit turning out to be four pages
in a row this means that we now have
three colors where we can get our own
material in and then we share row with
the victim it also means that the victim
the the spatial accuracy is now a half
page meaning that we're able to
distinguish between Hanlin
upper case and lower case if there are
only 2048 bytes apart and on the latest
generation of Intel CPUs it's much much
better there are eight pages per row two
bits such as all before meaning that you
have seven colors you can pick fruits to
get collocation with the victim and your
spatial accuracy is just a quarter of a
page and this sort of looks like a
rainbow which is why I call my skylight
computer
Rainbow Dash Rainbow Dash is a character
in the documentary the My Little Pony so
in other words we can deduct behavior
from memory axis much like cache
side-channel attacks it works across VM
costs if you even sandbox because
everybody does memory accesses there's
pretty much no way to avoid memory
accesses no matter what kind of
execution environment you have on the
latest generation on personal computers
we are very likely to be in the same row
as a secret victim information we have
spatial accuracy of 1,024 bytes which is
pretty good it helped us handle
uppercase don't have to be a pretty
particularly big function to push and a
lowercase out even if they are located
directly beside each other in the code
and it gets even better and multi CPU
servers because often you have a third
bit in the lower 11 we have been using
this to spy on keyboard input to Firefox
with just personally doing an example of
what we can actually do with this stuff
I should turn it over to Michael here so
thank you so spying is a nice thing but
that doesn't explain the demo yet so we
have something else we did so another
attack and it's a cover channel so DRM
cover channel first of all we have to
say okay what is the common channel so a
common channel is if you have two
programs and they would like to
communicate with each other and that
sounds pretty normal but in the case of
a common channel they are not allowed to
do so so what does mean they are not
allowed to communicate with each others
all the normal channels are either
blocked or monitored so for example if
you have two programs and they usually
communicate over the Internet or
using files or inter-process
communication shared memory whatsoever
that's either not available due to
hardware or software limitations or it
is monitored so that means you have a
monitoring program running on your
computer and if the monitor detects all
these programs are do they want to
communicate we abort them so there
shouldn't be any communication possible
so we have to exploit some side channels
in order to get a communication running
between those two programs and in our
case the side channel is of course the
DRM so in this animation we have again a
DRM Bank and I'd like to explain what
the primitive here is that we can use a
communication through the DRM without
anyone noticing it and if no chance to
block that so we have a send and a
receiver application and they agree on
some DRM bank they can do that
beforehand so it can be hard-coded in
the application it doesn't matter that
can also agree on that we don't care
about how they do it it can just be
hard-coded and they both the sender and
the receiver use one row inside this DRM
Bank so use different roles and the
receiver does nothing else than just
reading its data from one row of the DRM
Bank and the receiver is not interested
in the data at all just on in the excess
times so at the first access this data
will be copied to the row buffer the
timing will be high we ignore the first
reading but afterwards
every time the receiver accesses data
which maps into this dear M row it will
always already be in a row buffer so the
access is really fast and the receiver
sees fast access times and knows it's
data is in a row buffer and then the
sender can access data in its row so
what happens the rows are in the same
Bank so they have the same row buffer
and if the sender accesses data in its
bank it will be copied to row buffer and
the old row buffer is gone
so the sign that just accesses this
doesn't care about the data
it's just interested in setting the row
buffer to a defined state and if then
the receiver again accesses the data in
its row it has to be copied to the row
buffer first because it was overwritten
by the sender and this leads to a high
access time so to send at the receiver
ceased now it has a high excess time so
the transmitter must have sent something
by accessing its row and what is the
scenario here so the scenario is we are
trapped inside a virtual machine without
network access as we have seen it in a
demo at the beginning of the talk and
there's absolutely no communication
between the guest and the host so
imagine you work at the company you get
a virtual machine for manual analysis or
with sensitive data in there and you
really don't want to have data going
from the VM to the internet so you have
a isolated virtual machine no
communication communication between
guest and host and then you have a host
system that is connected to the Internet
but you're not allowed to run any
binaries on the host system you're not
allowed to install software there run
something there with just a normal host
system that is monitored and then you
don't have any software packs so there
are no parks in the host in the guest or
in the virtualization software so
absolutely no way to exploit something
in software to get data out of the
virtual machine and what is the solution
here we can implement a coverage handle
in Travis script so we have this house
system and most of us would have a
browser running on the host system if
it's connected to internet and therefore
we can also run JavaScript inside the
browser which is considered to be safe
and we can use the DRM as a side channel
every computer will have DRM in there
and the DRM is of course shared between
the virtual machine and the host system
so we have side-channel here we know the
time differences and we have this travel
script running on the host system inside
the
the only thing we have to do is get the
victim to visit our page with this
trauma script so we have also seen that
in a demo at the beginning with this
Firefox running with the JavaScript on
the page and it was to receive a foreign
information and we use this Romy's
attack primitive we shout before so the
only thing is we have descendant to
receive I agree on a bank at the
beginning so this is hard-coded in the
application we can choose any of the
banks and then inside the VM we have
this binary running this malware or
whatever that wants to exfiltrate the
data from the virtual machine to the
Internet and in the JavaScript we have
this script running that just matches
access time to the data we can match
access time also in JavaScript and see
if if there was a row conflict or not
and if the sender inside the virtual
machine wants to send data out it
accesses its data inside the virtual
machine to send a 1 and if it does
nothing then that's interpreted by the
JavaScript just a low access time as a
zero and it looks something like that so
that's an actual measurement from the
JavaScript we see you can really see the
differences between row conflicts and
row hits so we have this low and high
access times and we did always a few
measurements for every bit so to be
absolutely sure that's correct so in
this case we did at 10 meter runs per
bit we sent and we can do an overlay
here use the average very simple see the
0 and the 1 bits that are transmitted
from the virtual machine to the
javascript in the browser and the actual
communication is based on packets we
don't want to stream the data because if
we lose one of bits or more bits then we
are out of synchronization and the whole
data is corrupted so we decided to use
packets here with a two-bit preamble to
see that there's a packet starting with
an error detection codes because of
course we sometimes have it flips 2g
noise
or scheduling interrupts so we have an
error detection in there that detects
this corrupt packets then of course we
need a sequence number to have free
transmission working and with that we
can reliably transmit data so the demo
at the beginning we have approximately
11 bits per second that might not sound
very fast but it's absolutely reliable
you've seen it in the beginning we have
zero percent errors and that can still
be improved so we have multiple ways to
improve that for example by using fewer
retransmissions which means we have to
somehow correct the errors we only have
error detection in there that discards
packets that are destroyed but we could
go for error correction forward error
correction and correct any bit flips we
encounter and then we can also go for
multi-threading the new JavaScript
standard allows us to have
multi-threading in the browser so we can
transmit multiple multiple bits in
parallel using different banks so we try
to the native code and we get up to 500
96 kilobits per second
between CPUs and inside a virtual
machine so that's pretty fast but still
for stealing data from a virtual machine
to the internet imagine credit cards or
private keys 11 bits per second without
any errors is still fast enough good and
now that we had now that you know how
the demo worked with another goodie that
we can do with this DRM reverse
engineering so many of you probably
already thought this is somehow maps to
row hammer especially if you were paying
attention during the introduction and it
does map quite well so let me just do a
recap of how row hammer actually works
the thing with capacitors is that they
don't just lead charge when you read
them out they leak charge over time all
by themselves for this reason we need to
refresh DRAM every once in a while and
how we do that is we read the row into
the robot
for and right at back of the capacitors
are all refreshed
this happens every 64 milliseconds and
normal computers all the time so the
thing is that cells leaks faster upon
proximate access that is if a
neighboring cell is accessed the cell
will leak faster and this means if we do
enough proximate access bits will start
to flip because capacitors will drain
charge will no longer be charged and the
bit will be zero afterwards so how do we
do this in practice well we already know
that we can activate a ro copied into
the row buffer and return it to the CPU
from there now because it's already in
the row buffer we need to access another
row to get proximate access so we pick
the green row here our annex and stop
and get copied to the row buffer we have
our approximate axes and then we go back
to the yellow green row yellow and bam
we have bit flips so this is how ro
hammer works in the two minute version
the problem with ro hammer is where are
the victim row and where are the
neighboring rows having a gigabyte worth
of memory gigabytes worth of memory in
your computer you have have to search a
long time to find actually something
that really maps well to victim data
because you don't want anything from the
victim you want the important data and
the first solution by se ponen do lien
in their Google and blog post was
spraying spraying some very old method
that hackus has been using for a long
time and it works by filling memory with
security relevant information and just
by poor chance rule it's something
randomly if the memory is full of
something
security relevant what they did was page
table entries you remember we discussed
page table really shortly this is the
entire security system for the memory
subsystem of the Intel x86 meaning if
you flip it in a page table weird things
can happen and security can be
so severely broken they also did an
attack on the chrome sandbox the Native
Client and here they did not spray page
tables they sprayed sanity checking code
so if somebody write and that plugin for
a new Native Client in a malicious way
there's lots and lots of sanity checking
code in there and if you start flipping
bits randomly Santa at some point in
time you'll hit the sanity checking code
and it will no longer check for sanity
but for insanity and we have a security
break and we can leave the Native Client
sandbox a problem with this method is
not everything can be sprayed imagine
attacking a private key say you want to
flip a bit in a private key so you can
factor it afterwards well it's kind of
hot to tell a victim that she should
copy his private key all over the memory
that life doesn't work that way so there
was a talk here at blackhat Europe
earlier flipping Shoei and what they
figured out was to use deduplication
deduplication is when an operating
system or virtualizer is idle he starts
searching for identical pages in
physical memory once he find the
identical pages in memory he uses the
page table and system to map them into
the same physical data so that each
client access to fills the same physical
data but have their own version of the
data this actually turns out to leak
physical addresses the way it works is
you allocate a very large buffer you
start hammering a random you see where
your bit flips are then you modify the
page to match that what you want to
break in the attacker and then you sit
around and wait for the deduplication to
find your page merge the page with that
of the victim and then you can start
hammering on the same place as your
Hemet before and you'll soon flip a bit
in the victims context the problem with
this method is that deduplication is
turned off in any serious cloud the
series is in quotation marks I
really mean it quite literally I think
if you do not if you use deduplication
in your cloud you are not a serious
cloud provider now although it's default
off in most operating system not just
because of row hammer but because there
are there attacks and deduplication it's
just a bad idea
so this is where we come in we know the
mapping function meaning if we have
physical address addresses of the victim
data then we can actually calculate
where his stuff is in DRAM we can
calculate where the rows that we need to
attack the victim is we can calculate
everything and some other researchers
they are quoted here found out they
could actually use that to hit a private
key and flip a bit once you flip a bit
in our psyche you can actually factor it
and figure out what the real key was the
real problem here is for this attack to
work you need physical addresses
classically we have the prop pitch page
map but that is now privileged in part
due to row hammer however I co-authored
a paper recently that show that on most
operating system we are capable of
getting physical addresses from virtual
addresses even on privileged and there
are other kinds of leaks for example if
you Lee should you leave using not using
four kilobyte pages would start using
lot pages two megabyte or one gigabyte
pages then you leak a lot of bits of the
physical address as well and the way the
cache works actually turns out to leak
information about physical addresses as
well so knowing the mapping function
actually brings you very very far in
terms of figuring out where this stuff
is you want to row hammer there is a
very interesting application here yeah
it was once thought that only ddr3 RAM
was vulnerable to throw him a problem
because testing it did not turn off any
bit flips
turns out the ddr4 it's much more
resilient to row hammer but it doesn't
ruled it out however knowing the mapping
function we could as the first team do
bet bit flips and ddr4 Ram because we
could very
efficiently takut a row we could we know
the exact neighbors and we can just
start looking for them instead of
looking for stuff in the entire memory
and this is what enabled us to do the
first bit flips in ddr4 Ram so there's a
fourth solution and this goes back to
the spying stuff if we were able to
invoke victim code safe you can make him
use this private key by accessing his
website well then you can use the row
miss primitive to locate the bank
workers in and if you're very lucky you
get to get to be in the same row as the
know as the victim and then you can
locate the exact row where he is using
this buying method we saw a show before
of course this isn't perfect but it does
to actually improve accuracy if you
remember we're very likely that is very
very likely to be in the same Bank as
the victim because a bank is 265
megabytes meaning we're able to tell
what 265 megabytes the attacker the
victim important information is in and
that is a lot less than gigabytes worth
of memory also we can map our attack
aggressor rows very efficiently to the
same 256 megabytes and we could get
lucky and have row
colocation with the victim anyways that
is pretty much it for our talk today we
hope that we have made clear that we
think that DRM design is security
relevant we hope we have showed that we
can covertly actual trade information
that we can spy on other software and
that we can enable efficient and
targeted brohamer attacks so if there
are any questions we'll be happy to take
them
it's really difficult to to mitigate you
saw in the slides that they moved its
you put ever more bits into the lower 11
they do that to get more parallelism in
the ramp so you can read sequentially it
is really difficult there is one thing
the cache is in a way for much much much
of this stuff so if you don't have
access to the seal flush instruction
that gets much more difficult much
slower we lose accuracy we have to don't
have any really good medications you can
do stuff like detective with performance
counters but you're bound to round up
with false positives so it's it's a
difficult thing it's a design issue in
my opinion
not that I know of Michael do you know
something no not nothing off
no one should remember here it's not
really into this issue here the core
reason is dear M and into to my
knowledge does not produce dear M you
could probably reproduce these kinds of
tack on any processor it doesn't depend
on the processor it is about the DRAM so
we also did this attack on arm so it
works the same on smartphones and for
AMD for example they even release the
function so that's not really their
problem that and it'll doesn't make it
as secure by keeping this as a secret
it just manages tip step harder for us
because we had to reverse-engineer it
first on on into London arm but yeah I
don't think they see it as their problem
it turns out the D mapping of the Rose
is really primitive so we don't actually
do that but you but the mapping is
really primitive
any more questions
okay
yeah yeah you know where artists will be
hot with this one because I left office
back there Oh God
maybe you were just run over yeah if
there's any other questions
we can take them we won't meanwhile
Maikel slide number 30