ok so I think it's time welcome everyone
I am at Utrecht and today I will be
talking about effective effective file
format fuzzing specifically some of the
techniques methods and the results that
I've had during the few years of passing
that I've been doing at Google so a few
words about myself I work at project
zero what is relevant to the talk is
that I am a part-time developer and the
frequent user of the fuzzing
infrastructure that we have their
internally and it is very related to
what I will be discussing here today I
also play CD f's and generally
interested in all sorts of vulnerability
research and software exploitation so
today I will be talking about what
continues real-life offensive buzzing so
fuzzing for actually finding bugs that
you can probably exploit or in my case
report to the vendors and I would like
to talk about how each of the stages
that is part of fuzzing is typically
implemented and what you can do better
to actually improve your results and not
find more bugs and so this is going to
be all shown on the example of several
different pieces of software that I have
passed in the past including Adobe
Reader Adobe Flash Windows kernel and
some other open source software so let's
start with some very very soft basics we
probably know what fuzzing is so it's
just the software testing technique
which is most often automated and it's
all about the speeding in valid data to
the software that we are testing so in
the case of my talk now the software
part is just commonly used programs in
libraries which can be both open and
closed source the important thing is
that they are written in native
languages and this means that they can
be used for memory corruption style all
zero-day attacks and on the other hand
the inputs are just we assume that they
are files of different structure which
may be documented or undocumented and
their process by the software so it that
they can be websites outlets images
videos and stuff like that so
in general the scheme of fuzzing is very
simple we just have a loop inside of
which we choose an input mutated fit it
to the target and then see the target
has actually crashed or not if it has we
save the input and if it hasn't then we
just proceed of course this is still
very simple but while the general scheme
is very very easy it's that the thing
that is easy to learn but it's it's more
hard to master so if we try to dig deep
into how to pass effectively we have
several questions that we have to answer
so you have to think about how we choose
the defaulting target in the first place
how we generate the inputs where do we
take them from weak we have some base
corpus how do you how do we mutate them
and there is like a huge list of things
that we actually have to consider some
of these things are taken care of by the
buzzer that we are using if we are you
use an optical phone but if we are
trying to create a filing system on our
own for whatever reason then we actually
have to think about all of those things
so I will I will discuss some of those
things and try to answer to the best of
my knowledge how to how to make them as
effective as possible so let's start
with gathering the initial culprit of
input files probably most people doing
fuzzing actually go through this step
because it is a desired step in a
majority of cases for several reasons of
course it makes it possible to reach
some code paths immediately after
starting the passing so we don't have to
recover all of this file structure by
ourselves we already have a good
starting point we have we may have some
complex data structure inside of those
files which could be either very
difficult or impossible to generate even
if we have code coverage information
available and even if these constructs
could be created by for example using
code coverage based passing we are still
saving a lot of time by doing a the
initial corpus generation and of course
if we have a specific purpose of of
files in a in a format status for
example PDF we can reuse the same
because 2fast different projects
afterwards so this contact methods of
doing this is as follows first of all
many open-source projects actually
already include extensive sets of input
data for testing that we can use for
example we add a ten-pack project which
is a video and media processing library
has something called ffmpeg faith and
it's a system for regression testing in
ffmpeg and it already has like hundreds
of interesting files that you can use
sometimes these files are not publicly
for everyone but if you reach out to the
developers and let them know that you
want to test the software they might be
happy to share some of the private
private samples with you and also many
of the projects especially the
open-source one actually include
converters from format X to their own
format Y and the example here would be
the WebP image format which set the
convertor called CFP which can convert
from PNG JPEG and TIFF another thing
that we could do is internet crawling so
it all of course depends on the
popularity of the fast file format but
it's quite an intuitive approach so we
could either just download files through
the specific file extension or with a
specific magic bite or some other way of
of recognizing those files the problem
is that if we are targeting a very
popular file format we turn it up with
terabytes of data but it's not really a
problem if we can distill it to a
reasonable corpus somehow but another
interesting idea is that we could
actually try to ask the actual target
what it thinks whether it thinks that it
supports the specific file or not so
this would be either achieved by using
code coverage again but this tends to
slow down the process very much but in
some cases you can just directly ask the
question to the program itself and the
case study here would be either pro so
as you probably know ida pro has a long
list of supported format this is not a
complete list but it's already a lot of
items here probably several thousands of
them and so when you try to load a file
in either
what happens first if you see this
window which lists all of the format
that it has recognized inside of the
file and you can choose how to load this
file but the real question is how does
this really work
and to find out about it you have to
look into the loader architecture in Ida
and it turns out after a few minutes
that they have a modular design with
with each loader being inside of a
separate file so inside of your
installation directory you have a long
list of files which are basically just
DLL or shared objects or some other file
depending on the architecture which
exports to functions except file and
load file and you have two versions of
each of those files for 32-bit and
64-bit version of Ida so the definitions
of those two functions you can see here
they are also documented in the Ida SDK
they are very simple they just take some
input stream and output some information
about the file so except file is
basically a function which performs some
very preliminary processing and it
returns zero on one depending on whether
either can actually handle this file or
not and the load file is the more
complicated function which actually
takes takes care of the regular
processing of the file when you decide
to load the file and yeah as I said both
functions are very well-documented and
this is very convenient for us so when I
was passing either myself I decided that
I could just write a simple loader which
will iterate through all of those
loaders called the accept file function
and see which file it would recognize so
here you can see an example of running
the loader against itself and you can
see that elf dot l LX actually
recognized the file as else which is
correct so this was very helpful to
actually from a large corpus of files
see which files would be handled by Ida
correctly without doing all those code
coverage information extraction or
anything more complicated like that so
this was very good because it was it
worked with a very high degree of
confidence because the exit file
function actually has some extensive
logic to determine whether the file
should be accepted or not thanks to this
we also knew that which loader exactly
would be able to load so you would know
which louder we would be able to find
bugs in using the specific file we
didn't really have to even start either
because we would just call a simple
function from from a single dll or
shared object and we didn't have to use
any instrumentation so similar
techniques could probably be used for
software which makes it possible to
quickly determine whether it supports
the specific file or not which can be
useful sometimes
so the other thing is after we already
try to get get like the initial large
set of files is that we could try to
distill it and I believe that in passing
it is quite important to get rid of most
of the redundancy into input corpus and
this means both the first one that we
actually start fuzzing with and also the
living one which is being used while we
do the fuzzing and evolve the corpus to
get a better one so in the context of a
single test case we want to maximize the
program States Explorer divided by the
input size which means that we want to
have the highest ratio of bytes to
program feature basically so that the
highest number of functionalities
touched by the smallest number of bytes
and likewise in terms of the whole
corpus we also want to maximize the
whole set of program states divided by
the number of input samples because we
don't want to have too many of them
exercising the same functionality so if
if there is too much data to actually
process using corpus distillation with
code coverage information we may also
try to write some kind of minimizer on
our own based on the basic structure of
the file some sub some file formats have
some basic structure which is for
example being divided into chunks that
have tags or some names this is the case
for sweet files PDF PNG s and many other
files that you can see out there so such
turn rich person can already be used to
do some very quick
before we do anything more complex but
you have to be careful not to build too
deep into the specifications because
then it gets harder and the result is
not as cost-effective as it is where we
just do very basic processing so now the
question is how do we actually define
the program state because the file sizes
and the cardinality which was part of
the expression are both people to
measure but a program state is more
difficult so we don't really have any
good metric for measuring program States
especially with the characteristics that
we would like to have while doing
fasting so we would like then the the
program state to be defined such that
the number of them should be within a
sane range so we cannot really count out
combinations of based in memory it
should be meaningful in the context of
memory safety and they should be we
should be able to easily determine them
during program run time so the most
approximations used today are just
assuming that code coverage is somewhat
equal to program states and of course
this has many advantages because first
of all increased code coverage is
representative of new program state
which is good for us the same range
requirement is met of course because
code copy information is typically
linear in size to the overall program
size and we can usually easily measure
it using compiled and external
instrumentation but this is it
disadvantages is that constant code
coverage doesn't really indicate that
the program state is the program state
set is also constant so we could be
missing some information using this
method so yes the current state of arts
is just counting basic blocks and it's a
it's a reasonably good approximation
because they have quite good granularity
we shouldn't really measure instructions
typically because this is redundant
information so we can measure the code
coverage of basic blocks using a
compiler instrumentation such as G cough
or external instrumentation such as
Intel pin and annamaria and just
identify those basic
books by the others of the first
instruction but the problem with this
approach is that we could be still
missing some information so here we have
a very simple program with a full
function which has a very very simple if
statement so we have three calls of this
function and when we perform the first
call we actually go through all of the
basic blocks through some of the edges
so we could think that we have the
maximum coverage of this function as of
now but if we see this second call we
can see that a new path is actually
being taken a new branch here and the
same goes for the second call as well so
if we just measuring the the basic
blocks we could be missing this
information so another idea to
approaching a measuring code coverage
would be to not measure basic blocks so
not the vertices of the graph of the
code execution but the edges and this is
of course what IFL is trying to do so
they were the first to introduce this
and shift at large and you can write you
can read in the technical void volume
white paper of AFL that they are noting
the combination of the current location
that is reading the code and the
previous location inside of the bitmap
of all basic blocks so yes but we could
also extend this idea even further so in
a more abstract sense recording edges is
recording the current block and the one
previous but we could also record even
more information but by tracking out the
only previous block but also more of
them so for example n previous blocks
and the current one which would provide
even more context as of how the program
actually arrived at the current state
but in my experience the diode edges are
quite a good approximation
because they are fast to determine and
they also they they don't have too much
redundancy but yes so you can also have
even more granular information such as
counters and bit sets so instead of just
recording whether it's specific basic
block or edge
has been reached or not we can count how
many times it has been reached or not
and this can be useful for example when
we try to determine how many times a
specific group has been has iterated
over which could be helpful for example
in a case where we want to go to a
string comparison or some other logic of
that kind so we have all these different
kinds of coverage information that we
would like to extract of course we can
do it using enthalpy nordyne number E or
some other dbi for example AFL uses a
modified version of QM user for open
source we can use the built-in compiler
of compiler instrumentation such as G
cough and VM Co but what I have been
using personally and all the recommend
to to use is sanitizer coverage so
sanitizer coverage is just an option of
other sanitizer which you are probably
familiar with which is a fast reliable
instrumentation for detecting memory
safety issues so it's very useful for
passing it by itself there are also many
other variants such as memory sanitizer
or thread sanitizer etc and one thing
you can also enable whether enabling
other sanitizer is the sanitizer
coverage which at the same time as
validating the runtime of the right
library or program also provides
information about the code coverage so I
am using it personally also the lid
puzzle project which is the project of
costia which will be creator of of other
sanitizer uses sanitizer coverage here
we have an example of sanitizer coverage
usage so we have a very short program
which has some full function which is
only calls if the number of parameters
is 2 so you can just use two simple
compile time options to enable it and
then you can see that after we call the
program with zero with one and two
parameters the size of the output output
files with the coverage information is
different it has either four or eight
bytes so now that we can measure code
coverage easily the question is
what do we do now first of all we have
to remember that just measuring code
coverage by itself is not really a
silver bullet and there are still many
code constructs which are impossible to
cross with just dump you mutation based
filing examples of this would be
comparisons of types that are larger
than a single byte for example or
comparisons of memory blobs or ASCII
strings so you can see those examples
here a comparison with a 32-bit value of
course it's a very difficult to cross
with just a dump buzzer because we would
have to get this this specific 32-bit
value and the same thing goes with the
string comparison which would be even
harder to guess so that problems are
actually somewhat approachable if you
think about it now because you can for
example use approaches such as
dictionaries which are supported in both
AFL and lead buzzer which could be use
to find those specific values that are
being searched for in the code and you
can also get some help from compiler
flags but this is this is someone
complicated to think about because the
somewhat unintuitive approach would be
to disable all code optimization which
would result in fewer hockey expressions
in assembly compressed code constructs
for the basic blocks and stuff like that
so we'd get more granular code coverage
information to analyze but on the
contrary I'll come to have also found
that if you use the oh three
optimization with unroll loops then some
of the short string comparisons or
string signatures are being unrolled to
to just very simple by the granular
comparisons so it's quite unclear which
compilations flags should really be used
for coverage guided passing and it's
probably something that you should
adjust based on us the specific project
that you are trying to pass mmm so in
the past also tablets or monday-- tried
to approach this problem somehow with
another DDI of his that you call deep
cover another
so he tried to extract a more granular
information about the specific
instructions that are used for string
comparisons for example so he
implemented this to measure how far the
execution of the Red Sea MPB instruction
went before bailing out or how many
beads were successfully compared by the
CMP instruction and he was able to use
this approach to be able to actually
recover crc32 checksum required by the
PNG decoders and when I was first
creating this slide a few months ago I
also thought did the idea of Peter would
be to have a compass Pacific compiler
design profiling which would be able to
create very D optimized code with all of
the assembly being maximally simplified
with all of those 32 million 16 bits and
comparisons being unrolled to byte
comparisons and stuff like that so for
example the construct on the Left would
be contained to the construct on the
right and it turns out that this has
actually been achieved in the meanwhile
so in August a research has been
presented resulting in in a LLVM
compiler plugin that was actually able
to perform these the optimizations and
this health ASL to discover several new
bugs and the other part of the ideal
feature would be that the standard
comparisons functions which are very
annoying we could have a compiler based
solution for just having a separate
version a separate piece of code in the
assembly for each of calls of those
functions in the code which would help
us get some more granular information as
well but we still had some unsolvable
problems such as when the value that are
being loaded from the input is actually
processed somehow before being compared
with some signatures and this we cannot
really approach with any of the dump
ideas that I presented before but this
is about damn pausing so we have to we
have to just agree with that so now
we have lots of input files we have the
compiled target and the ability to
measure code coverage the question is
how do we proceed from here and this is
assuming that we would like to create
some corpus management system I would
like to present some algorithm of how I
do it myself so let's assume that we
would like to have the system for
coverage guided corpus management which
would have the following properties
first of all it would be able to
minimize an initial corpus of
potentially gigantic sizes to a smaller
one that is equally useful so on input
we would have any input files and on
output you would have M input files and
information about their code coverage
and of course this should be scalable
this is the first property and the
second one is that you would also like
it would like to use it during fuzzing
first of all to decide if a specific
mutated sample should be added to the
corpus at runtime and to recalculate all
of this coverage information in if
needed so the input here would be just
the current corpus and its coverage and
the candidate sample and its coverage
and on output we just should have the
new corpus and its coverage so yes the
pure work for this is that the set cover
problem so this is the set cover problem
or just a specific version of it which
in itself is just np-hard so we cannot
really calculate the optimal solution in
result reasonable time but we don't
really have to do it and in fact it's
probably better if we just don't find
the optimal solution but someone
somewhat optimal one and there are
actually greedy algorithms which can
find approximate in some reasonable time
an example of such an algorithm would be
that we store the current corpus and the
current coverage and for every new
sample we just check if it adds some you
trace to the current code coverage so if
it does then we add it to the corpus
otherwise we discard it and periodically
we could also optionally check if the
of the samples are redundant inside of
the corpus and remove them too to keep
the general size small but this has some
some significant drawbacks so for
example it doesn't scale very well
because we have to process all of the
samples sequentially and also the size
and form of the corpus depends on the
order in which the samples are processed
so if we start processing the big files
at the beginning and then the smaller
ones later then we would end up with a
very large corpus which is not necessary
so we have very little control over the
over the trade-off between volume and
redundancy in the output corpus so what
I would like to propose is another
design which is as follows for each
execution trace we know we saw the end
smallest samples which reach that trace
and the overall corpus consists of all
the files present in the structure and
the structure can be represented as a
C++ STL object map which Maps a string
which is the name of the sample sorry
the name of the trace into a set of
pairs consisting of the names of the
samples and its sizes so here is an
example on an illustration we have for
some 4 input samples which have some
coverage and then we transform it into a
list of traces which map to a maximum of
2 files per that trace and they are of
course the smallest one here so the
advantages of this approach would be
that this of course can be very
trivially paralyzed with any number of
machines using the MapReduce model the
extent of redundancy can be controlled
via the N parameter with during fasting
the corpus will evolve to minimize the
average sample size by design because we
are storing the end smallest samples we
have at least n samples for each trace
which results in a very uniform code
coverage distribution across the entire
set as compared to just having like one
samples per each trace and the upper
limit for the number of input
is limited but in practice it's much
less than actually the number of
coverage traces times M this approach
also has some shortcomings so due to the
fact that each trace has the smallest
examples in the corpus for some basic
traces we will end up with some
redundant short files which don't really
exercise an interesting functionality
for example for PNG we have we have some
files we just have the basic headers and
stuff like that or just basic headers
and then a single chunk so very short
files which are really useful for
fuzzing but I still think this this is
an acceptable trade-off especially given
that having a such short input may also
enable us to find some unexpected
behavior for example also handling some
other types of MAGIX by the target that
we didn't initially expect so here is
the algorithm in a kind of pseudocode so
the map face is really simple we just
get the code coverage provided by the
input data and for each trace ID we
output the trace ID and a pair of sample
ID and the size of the file so here you
can see it we transform the list of the
input files into a map of traces mapping
to to the samples it first looks like
this and then there it does for the redo
space we just sort for each of the
traces we just sort the list by the size
of the samples and then choose the end
smallest one and output them so here we
start with this input we just sort the
files by size and then we choose the and
smallest ones which in this case is two
and this is our output so at the end we
end up with this list of files at the at
the top and then we just sort it and get
a new unique list and we end up with a
total of three out of four files in the
initial corpus so when it comes to
actual track record for using this
algorithm in my infrastructure I've
successfully used it to distill
but datasets of terabytes to distill it
into somewhat reasonable corpuses and
the examples are our PDF format based on
instrumented PDF you so I generated
three purposes based on N equals one ten
and a hundred two to get some nice
corpus is profiling with different
degree of redundancy and I've done the
same for for free type too
so when it comes to the to the algorithm
of determining whether a new candidate
is good profiling or not the algorithm
is a little bit more complex first of
all we go through each of the trays
which is covered by the sample and see
if it improves the size the size of one
of the traces so is its smallest smaller
than the size of the large largest file
in the set and if any such improvement
is is achieved then we perform a second
pass to remove all files from the set we
have which have the same size as of this
file and that here is an illustration of
this approach so we have this candidate
called
five dot PDF which has size 20 so first
thing we do is that we try to improve
some of the coverage traces here and it
turns out that some of them are improved
so we insert the 5 dot PDF file for two
of the coverage traces and then we
perform the second pass and also replace
two other files which also had size 20
to reduce the total number of files in
the set so this was about distilling the
whole corpus and merging in a single
file and if we want to merge two corpora
then it's also travelled by just
choosing the smallest n samples for each
of the traces that are covered side and
one of the things that I passed and had
some success with using this approach
was Wireshark which I've been passing
since November last year using the
teacher command-line utility with built
with a fan an awesome coverage
I discovered 30
vulnerabilities using this approach and
the interesting thing is that initially
I started with some simple sample files
from the page sample captures for
Wireshark and it was 300 files which had
over 200 megabytes so mostly those files
were very big but upon several months of
coverage guided passing I actually was
able to first create a very good corpus
which consisted of almost 80,000 files
but medium file size was just 47 bytes
so they were really actually optimal for
filing and if you want to test out your
file infrastructure Wireshark is
actually a very good thing to do this on
because the nature of the code base
makes it extremely well
fit for dumb fuzzing because it has a
vast number of these sectors for
different format it's mostly written in
C and operate on very very simple data
structurally so it just mostly compares
single bytes or or some very very simple
constructs in the input file so it's
generally a very great best target for
your puzzle and this is the trophy case
for Wireshark in the project zero
tracker also this approach proved to be
useful for Adobe Flash so I've been
fighting it for many years
not not so much with coverage coverage
guidance but recently I started
targeting the ActionScript loader class
and in the official documentation you
can see that the loader class is
supposed to only support JPEG PNG gif
and SWF files but when I was filling
this with coverage information after
several hours of passing I observed two
sudden peaks in the number of coverage
coverage traces and when I looked into
the input corpus I noticed that the
father discovered two new signatures are
called ATF and III I would correspond to
a format that I didn't know before which
is called Adobe texture format for stage
3d which can have embedded jxr files so
these are two very complex file formats
whose support was not documented
anywhere and I was able to discover
by just using this code coverage
algorithm and I found seven
vulnerabilities in those formats
thanks to this discovery so far so also
when it comes to corpus post-processing
if the files are stored in a way which
makes them difficult to mutate you can
do some pre-processing such as the
compressing them if they are compressed
for example in SWF files you typically
typically have them in a LD ma
compressed form such as with the CVS
signature PDF documents also have most
of the binary streams compressed with
deflate so we can also decompress them
to make sure that the bit sleeping makes
sense and also tight bond forms are
always encrypted with a simple cipher so
as several things about running the
target and several trips so we have to
distinguish between command line and
graphical applications it's generally
preferred for at least for me for the
target program to be common light only
which is quite common on Linux and less
so on Windows most open-source drivers
actually shape with some already testing
tools which are command line which we
can use for fuzzing and this is much
cleaner in terms of interaction logging
and basically everything else in fuzzy
but there are also some graphical Linux
graphical applications for Linux in
which case we can use the X built well
frame buffer to to deal with this and
the thing is that for some applications
the amount of input data processed is
actually dependent on the amount of data
which is displayed on the screen which
is the case for example for Adobe Reader
and my solution for that was to just
start a beautiful X frame buffer with a
very huge resolution and then start
Adobe Reader such that it would have a
huge window displaying all of the pages
at the same time so this is the result
it was a very dumb way to make sure that
as much PDF data was processed as
possible and it really improved the
number of bucks that I was able to find
in Adobe Reader and it's interesting
because that OB reader is supposed to be
a graphical only up
but if you started from command line
with the help common line argument you
can see that it actually has a lot of
common line arguments and while we're at
Adobe Reader I wanted to mention that I
perform some fuzzing of it in 2013 12
and 13 which with some bugs pass at
farms but then in 2014 after the Adobe
Reader for Linux was discontinued I
still had some very like better method
than before so I still wanted to find
some bugs in Adobe Reader but I couldn't
really use a new version because it was
discontinued so my idea was to use the
Linux version and fuzz it on Linux and
then see if any bugs would actually
reproduce on the Windows version and it
turned out that I ended up with over 700
crashes in total in the linux version
out of which 11 reproduced on the
Windows version as well
and they were fixed in in 2014 and 15 so
when the program is behaves there are
certain behaviors that are undesired are
doing thousand for example we don't want
to deal with some generic exception
handlers which would mask the exceptions
that we want to catch and stuff like
that they could attempt to establish
some network connections excusal
interaction and stuff like that and I
have founded on Linux it's very
convenient to use the LD preload to
actually block off some of the functions
that you don't want to be to have cold
so for example you can disable custom
exception handling by masking out two
functions that are signalling cig action
just replace them with no operations you
can disable network connection by just
masking out the socket function and
stuff like that and you can also think
about passing the command line for some
of the targets so some projects have
multiple command line flags which might
we might want to sleep randomly in order
to reach some interesting functionality
especially in an open source project and
the solution to that would be to have an
external target launcher which
determines the actual common line to be
used based on some some data from the
actual input files
and I use that information to to peak
the command line to be used so for
example at the van back where you can
specify the output format in which you
want the output file to be generated in
and if you list this format it turns out
that there is over 300 of them so it
makes sense to try to test all of them
and the logic for the wrapper would be
to just choose the encoder based on a
hash which is generated out of the four
thousand bytes the first byte in the
input file and then execute such such a
command line and another funny thing is
that you should always make sure that
you're not actually losing cycles which
was what I did so this is an example of
free type which is a very convenient
command-line utility called FG bench and
it runs through 12 tests exorcising
values a PA library calls and when you
run it with no special parameters it
takes 25 seconds for example to just
process the file and the important thing
is is the reason for this you can see
that it says number of seconds for each
test equals 2 which I didn't realize it
first I didn't really strike me for a
long time and it turns out that you can
use a special track to actually just use
run every test just once instead of for
2 seconds and this this sped up the
passing by at least a hundred times for
me but I was still able to find some
bugs using this very slow problem so I'm
afraid I had to skip out through some of
the slides here I wanted to also talk
about mutating inputs you will be able
to check out the slides later on there
were some interesting thoughts about
first of all how to mutate the data and
also what ratios to use for those data
because you don't always want to flip a
specific number of bytes but you want to
adjust it based on the nature of the
input data and then I also wanted to
quickly talk about the Windows kernel
for passing effort maybe I'll try to
talk about it really quickly so I
decided to do inbox because I'm a very
huge fan of it it's a software emulator
and I've already used it for
some projects it's not very fast but we
can still scale against that if we use
some more machines that just one so it
has some very useful properties it can
be run on a Linux system it provides a
documented instrumentation API so it
makes it possible for you to interact
with the guests it runs Windows out of
the box which is very simple and you can
easily configure it so let's do it when
it comes to input to the input data this
part was the easiest one because I
already had a input corpus of files
based on pre type
2000 so what I only had to do is to
extract TrueType and OpenType files
because the other one that free type
supports and supported by the Windows
kernel yeah so then part of mutating TGF
in the OTS was the more interesting I
decided that the mutations would be
applied in box instrumentation inside
instead of the gas system itself because
it would be much faster that way the
question is how to mutate them properly
to get the best result because both TTFN
and OTS follow a common chunk structure
called a certainty in which each file
comes it's a number of tables which are
public documented so there are a total
of about 50 tables in existence in total
but only 20 or so are actually important
and one thing they have in common is
that they all are different so they have
a different length different structure
different kind of importance for the
operating system and the parser and
stuff like that so it only seems
reasonable to treat each of them
individually instead of pass the file as
a whole
so the typical scheme I've seen in
nearly every fund from fuzzing
presentation would be that we just took
the whole font and we would flip
somebody's in the whole file and we will
just fix up that the table checks arms
in the header so that windows would
actually accept it but I decided to go a
different way
and instead of passing or mutating a
whole form file I would be passing each
of those tables individually such that I
would get the success to failure ratio
at
50 % so 50% of the time windows would
actually be able to process that mutated
file correctly and 50% of time it would
fail which would mean that we would be
kind of at a verge of the mutated file
being correct so I just wrote a very
simple program to actually determine
what mutation Rachel would be best fit
for each of the tables and either each
of the mutation algorithm to maintain
the 93% correctness and this resulted in
the following table of mutation ratios
for each of the algorithms and each of
the s sng tables so I also didn't set
the mutation ratios to be fixed as shown
in the previous table but I also allowed
some some freedom in that so I set a
range between zero and two times the the
mutation ratio that I determined and
with a trivial piece of code to
disassemble modified and reassemble
assessing T files I was now able to
mutate them in a very meaningful way
being able to control how they behave in
Windows I also wrote a very simple TDF
generator with TTFN instructions which
consisted of the disassembling the PDF
files inserting new instructions with a
python generator and then reassembling
it back and I managed to find find one
extra back with this generator so quite
quite a quite less than with does the
damn puzzle itself and when it comes to
the communication channel between the
ghost host and the guest
I used the Box instrumentation to detect
a specific instruction in this case it
was Elton's
and I used this instruction to implement
operations such as request data which
would allowed the harness in the guest
to request mutated phone data from the
host send status to send status whether
the loading of the phone succeeded or
not and the simple debug print so of
course I had to be very careful to to be
to be sure that all of the memory
regions passed back to box were mapped
in physical memory so I would be done
able to write to each directly I also
implemented
- to harness to be able to get the best
code coverage in the Windows kernel so I
would call all of the available API
functions which were operating on the
fonts and I would list and display all
of the glyphs in the font to be to make
sure that all of the mutations would
actually be triggered in the Windows
kernel I also operate optimize the
operating system to the maximum extent
so I disabled all of the themes disabled
services that were not necessarily
removed most of the system files removed
all our items from outer start disabled
paging and stuff like that to make sure
that the guest system was actually very
quick and we wouldn't be losing any
cycles inside of the box and of course I
also had to make sure that the system
would actually restart when the crash
happened
so I could detect a system reset as an
indicator for a crash in the Windows
kernel and then when I wanted to
reproduce the crashes I would do it in a
separate beautiful box VM and I would
just load the font in the same way as
doing the fuzzing and then check if
there is a crash dump in the windows
directory if so I would generate a
report from that and save it I also did
some minimization but I won't really
talk talk about it anymore but the
general result from this research is
that I found all classes of bugs
basically mostly pull based buffer
overflows but also sum over each user to
fries and other interesting things this
was done in four iterations and this is
not necessarily the end there could be
more more bugs discovered let's see in
the future
so the closing thoughts is that
hopefully after this effort
no more bites are looking the Windows
kernel from processing let's see that is
the case or not either either way
Microsoft has moved from processing into
a user space process which is good for
security but it could also make fuzzing
easier for us and yeah we can still
think about using it as an RCA II vector
because even though it's not anymore in
the kernel but in user space
we can still use it to get some kind of
remote code execution so with that I
thank you for your attention and I'm
happy to answer questions probably after
the talk
[Applause]
[Music]