all right good afternoon everybody and
thanks for coming to our talk we're
going to be talking about attacks and
countermeasures of the ultrasonic cross
device communication mechanisms I want
to begin with telling you a story the
story of a product made by company name
silver push started about four years ago
for the exactly four years ago now that
I notice and after a while a couple of
years later they received a good funding
from a couple of venture capitalists and
this was the moment when they started to
get some attention from from from the
media journalists were starting to cover
what was this technology about and how
the product was working what you see
here at the bottom is one year later the
patent describing the technical
specification of the technology and how
the product works when the patent came
out the security community and the press
started to notice that there were some
oddities in this in this technology what
you see here is a screenshot of an email
sent on the w3c privacy and audio
mailing list by our friends look at we
actually knew him and in saying that he
wanted to raise the current issue of
tracking using ultrasound ultrasound
audio beacons such as product marketed
by silver bush and is bringing up some
transparency issues and is saying that
users are unaware of this of what's
going on underneath and they are even
unable to express and provide consent
opting out it was impossible so this was
when also the media started to write
several articles about this technology
and what could be the privacy and
security implications and I still
remember the first one with an on our
Skype Technica by Dan Gooden because I
have
to have missed the bus that day and I
popped on my hacker news feed and I read
this article this is how all this
project started and then so journalists
were all concerned and as a reaction a
few moments later also the Federal Trade
Commission - connection this is the
excerpt from the transcript of a
workshop that the Federal Trade
Commission held right away in November
mid-november in Washington DC and to
quote some of the some of the
transcripts here
how are the new methods operating in a
way that is transparent to consumers can
this the consumers express any opt-out
do they have a choice there is very
little transparency here for example we
would have to essentially find a way to
make browsers essentially not a mid
sound that human can hear in order to be
able to do some of these stuff so
essentially the Federal Trade Commission
was also concerned about the problems of
this technology we will see what these
problems are all about in a few moment
at the point of these stories the users
started to realize what was going on the
end user a means the end users I mean
and we extracted some of the most
representative comments from the blog
posts that we found on the net there
were some unhappy users this guy here
saying this stuff doesn't resemble
malware it is malware and then we have
some proactive dude saying I want an
arrest level option in iOS OS X - all of
the frequencies the frequency response
in the speaker output at a frequency of
my choice 18 kilo Hertz or 15 kilohertz
my memory fine and then we have some
other funny comment saying do they know
that I turn up the sound during
commercials I know that this doesn't
really sound funny because some of you
might not know what behind this and
that's what we are going to to explain
now at this point the Trade Commission
the Federal Trade Commission took a
second action stronger one
they wrote a letter to every developer
that were using this technology and
we're publishing applications some of
them were probably unaware of it on
Google Play Store and they'd say dear
sir/madam the code included in the
application that may allow third parties
to monitor consumers we recently
discovered that your mobile application
includes a software development kit so a
library created by the company's server
push that is designed sorry that is
designed to run silently in the
background even while the user is not
actively using the application and
finally server push responded to all of
these concerns and they claimed that
they had no active partnership in the
u.s. what we could find was only an
office in California but they claimed
that after the three commission like
took this action they say we're not
seeking any active partnership in the US
so we all thought this was a the end of
it but actually this was only the tip of
the iceberg what we found out is that
there were a whole whole world behind
this technology that was completely
unexplored by the security experts we
found some some sparse some sparse
articles here and there but nothing
really thorough nothing really like a
coop a comprehensive analysis so there
were also other with the sound enabled
products that were never analyzed by
from the security point of view and
there were no scientific examination of
the possible security implications so at
this point of the story I hope that I
motivated at least some of you that it
was worth researching at least me and
the sillies were persuaded enough that
was a you know worth going into and so
bye-bye now I will start giving you some
other background some more background to
tell you what ultrasound tracking really
is technically and then Vasilis will
take over the floor and tell you through
a demonstration
how an attack can be carried out to
complete the anonymize at or user and
then we would explain what are the
reason behind this why this technology
were like failing so much and then we
will give you our response our security
response to the problems so starting off
with the echo system before we can talk
about ultrasound enable tracking first I
need to tell you something about ultras
and to tell you something about cross
device tracking without ultrasound
generally cross device tracking is
several applications such as proximity
marketing etc but let's dig into the
details so you understand immediately so
cross device tracking or xdt you can
think of it as a way to correlate all
the devices that you own essentially so
through an example let's suppose that
our friend John is watching TV and there
is an ad going on on TV and after a
while John
opens his cell phone to browse on the
web and all of a sudden the advertisers
who know that John has just watched that
TV show or that TV advertiser that TV
advertisement they show relevant content
on the web
relevant to what has just been appeared
on TV so this sounds I mean amazing from
the point of view of the marketers this
is the Holy Grail this is what the
marketers would really like to do
wherever you turn wherever you turn your
your site you will have something
relevant to what you have just watched
at home or on your phone right so this
technology I mean regardless of the use
of ultrasounds that we haven't
introduced yet this technology is used
by major advertisement networks in
different ways depending on
implementation we can divide between
deterministic ones and probabilistic
ones so as you can imagine the problem
that they fo solve is how do we
determine that two devices are owned by
the same user so the most basic one data
that we can we can explain is that
mystic 1 so think of using Amazon from
your computer using your using the
website of Amazon and then after a while
you switch to your phone instead of
using the app you open the Amazon
websites and most likely you will left
using you will be using the same
credentials and the fact that you're
using the same credentials basically
Amazon knows that you are the same
person behind two different devices
right so it can show relevant content to
you clearly this is a fully accurate I
mean there is no there is no possibility
of error here the problem is that it's
not always feasible you cannot really
ask every time the users to login into
your platform because you want to
retarget the user for the with the same
content being advertised so this is when
ultrasounds and other cross-device
linking technology came necessary so
with resound beacons is the core
technology that is behind use a sound
cross device lacking with resound
beacons or u beacons you can think of
them high as a high frequency tags so a
sequence of symbols like ABCD that
encode a certain information in this
case this information is this guy has
just watched this advertisement on TV ok
and the good thing about ultrasound in
general is that especially if they are
short-lived they can be easily captured
by by commercial speakers sorry by by
commercial microphones and can be
emitted easily by commercial speakers so
you don't really need any fancy
technology here all you need is a
speaker and a microphone so it's like
asking people to use bluetooth without
luteal essentially so without the old
appearing problems that we know that
sometimes doesn't really work well and
the good thing from the marketers
perspective also from our side
fortunately is that they're inaudible to
us right depending on our ears but most
of them are not audible so more
technically they work in the spectrum
above 18 kilo Hertz in the spectrum 18
to 20 kilo Hertz if you do some math and
you split it into 70
five Hertz trunks it makes enough space
for the whole twenty seven symbols of
the alphabet so you can include the
whole alphabet by choosing the right
frequency and by omitting these Peaks
these frequencies you can send
essentially a message and in this case
we are sending the eh-eh-eh-eh LSU
message which means I don't know a
certain advertisement advertisement
campaign the duration is pretty pretty
short few seconds until there is no real
standard here there is no agreement on
on how content should be encoded how
symbol should be encoded it's all up to
the developers so you can come up with
your encoding which might be more
efficient than this and use it there is
no regulation of any sorts there are
lots of patents but nothing is it not
easily made it to the standards yet
so practically they travel very well up
to seven eight meters they cannot really
go through obstacles such as thick walls
but as I say they work very well with
commercial speakers unfortunately they
are audible by Lara our research
assistant who has helped us in a very
significant way throughout this research
you will see by the end so then now we
have learned that if we combine trust
device tracking application with the use
of your beacons we obtained with the
sonic cross device communication that is
nothing but using water sound to come to
combine information about two devices so
the this is actually all good from the
marketers perspective because they offer
a very high degree of accuracy as good
as the deterministic ones there is no
requirement for user to do any login of
course what we are asking the user is to
install some client-side component on
each device but then the business model
there is very easy you offer a reward
and the user will probably install that
application to get a reward they work
they can be embedded almost everywhere
they can be embedded into TV shows TV
as radio radio Radio emitted
advertisements songs even so they are
quite flexible in the way they can be
used on the other hand require quite a
good engineering effort for creating all
the back-end infrastructure we will see
why is that and they require as I says
on the client-side the installation of
an application from the development
point of view it is nothing different
but from installing a simple
advertisement library so if you are
familiar with advertisement library in
Android we simply have to drop a library
into your application and load the class
and then you're good to go
what happens behind behind the scene can
be explained with this with this
workflow diagram so what we need is an
advertising client of course you can
think about McDonald's we found the
application on McDonald's in the
Philippine making use of this technology
you can think of Starbucks any good
brands who wants to use this technology
then we need a service provider in this
case Shiva push or any other service
provider offering this technology so the
guy saw the advertisement client go to
goes to the provider and say I want to
run a campaign so they create a beacon
that beacon identifies uniquely that
campaign then they go to the content
provider which is for example a TV
channel a radio channels who embed mix
mixes in essentially the inaudible audio
together with the audible audio so what
you get in the end is the same
advertisement the same audio but there
is also the hidden part that you
wouldn't hear then we go home we listen
to radio we watch TV and whenever we
access that kind of advertisement of
that campaign our cellphone which is
listening on background we have
installed the application to get some
rewards our cellphone will pick up those
ultrasounds so that now we can tell
through the back end by reporting back
to the advertisement service provider by
reporting back that we have just
received that beaker and so the loop now
is closed
now the advertisement client knows that
through the information provided by the
service provider we have just watched
that relevant advertisement and then
they can retarget us they can retarget
us by proposing relevant relevant
products and in the end this will
translate in some return on this
investment there are also some other
applications in in the scope of
ultrasound technology for example
proximity marketing this is a product by
shopkick a company in in the Silicon
Valley which proposed to use ultrasound
beacons for indoor localization not
really localization in the matter of in
the sense of positioning of a user but
localization in the sense that a user is
here in this store so if I have a user
and I invite my users to install my
application because I want to offer some
reward some discount then whenever my my
clients walk into the store I can offer
instant deals of something that is
relevant to the fact that the guy is
into the store at that moment at the top
here you see the powered version at this
bottom here you can see the battery
powered version and then you can use
this data the way the way you want you
can study the in-store user behavior you
can retarget users as I told you before
there are rather use this use cases some
of one of the you might you might also
have used it without knowing it if you
want Google cast formerly chromecast
they say in their documentation that
they use ultrasound as one of the ways
to pair your phone with a chromecast so
in addition of wireless wireless pairing
they can use with resonance appear
because they assume that when you
configure your chromecast you are close
to TV with your phone in your hand by
the way we just understood that Google
has acquired leaked login which is a
startup doing some base authentication
so that's that's quite interesting and
there are also other
other applications for this technology
such as Audion measurement analytics
such as in big events if you have like
the application of the marketing
application for that event such as black
ed or a sport a large sport event you
can measure how many people are
currently in to a certain location by
beating out ultrasound beacons and then
collecting them through to these sensors
right so this is the moment of our story
where I realized that probably something
is wrong I mean there is something that
must be that we must dig further and so
I would do the same thing that I did in
real life 6-8 months ago I went to
vassilisa was working in the same lab
where I was doing a research visit and
say hey dude I think we have a little
problem here we might want to look into
this technology because there is
something that smells a little bit fishy
so I will give the floor to two Vasilis
who is going to to give us a
demonstration unfortunately I think we
have a oh yes that's right that's right
thank you thank you thank you
so Vasilis at that point was a PC
student now is a PhD student at UCL but
when I met him we were both at UCSB
together with Shuang how unique frat
Antonio and of course the advisors Chris
crew and Giovanni Vania and he was
working on privacy so I thought this is
the right guy for this project and so we
started to collaborate on this so
without further ado demonstration time
so hello everyone now that we have a
good understanding of how the whole Lego
system works I'm going to immediately go
ahead and demonstrate one of our attacks
because I assume that some of you may
have already started imagining how this
can be exploited so the ingredients for
this attack we need basically victim
with a computer that has speakers and
the tor browser and we also need victim
same victim to have a smartphone that
features an ultrasound cross device
tracking enabled absorb any of the
framework doing cross device tracking
and we also need the state-level
adversaries I will explain this further
a bit later so in order to better
understand what's going on on our demo
I'm going to cut we came up with a
little story so we assume that there is
a whistleblower that wants to lick some
documents to a journalist
however the whistleblower doesn't know
that the journalist secretly works with
a repressive government and intends to
be anonymous here so what the journalist
does is that he asks the whistleblower
to upload the documents through a tor
hidden service that he owns make I mean
claiming that you know you're going to
be safe you're going to store and I
won't be able to know your identity so
the whistleblower is compared believes
what the the journalist says and files
apt or and loads the page so there is a
small lie on this slide and this is the
part that the demo is live so apparently
the network's here doesn't like tor very
much so we have the fallback plan of the
video that we're going to show you and
I'm going to explain what's going on
there we're great but not that great
okay so there is a computer that has a
tor browser loaded it's okay no just
make it okay
maybe from here yeah okay so there is
the phone and the computer has a running
toward browser latest version and there
is the phone so for this specific demo
we use the silver boots demo app just to
be able to show you something on the on
the smartphone but normally you want to
be able to see anything there so what
happens here is just the app now loaded
but is still not listening so we'll
press the button to make it listening
this process doesn't happen normally
normally the framework is listening on
the background and the user doesn't have
to do anything apart from maybe starting
up firing up the app but its purpose its
main purpose something else so now we
are going to visit them on the tor
browser the onion service that the
journalist asked us to visit as a
whistleblower and see what happens so we
visit the web site and it looks benign
at first and then it updates itself
okay so what we have here is basically
what the site updated and it contains
basically lots of private information
about us
so essentially you can see on top the
Google account email address the IP
address that the mobile that the
smartphone has the phone number the
Introit ID please don't call on this
phone number the may of the phone and
the mac address so this pretty much the
anonymizes then the whistleblower and
the protection of it by tor is not
really there so now I'm just going back
to the presentation to better explain
what happened and discuss how how we
actually did that yeah before that I
would like to introduce three tools that
the attacker has at his disposal and he
used she can use them combine them to do
more complex attacks so the first one is
a big con job this is my favorite and
beacon trap is pretty simple in
principle so it's basically a code
snippet that when loaded produces one or
more inaudible because that the attacker
has chosen so this by itself it's
nothing not a big deal however what the
adversary can do is that he can attach
this code snippet to a source that the
big victim is interested in so in the
first case and this is what we saw on
the like on the demo this web page can
be a benign looking web page that the
journalist is going to learn the
whistleblower to visit however this can
be a completely benign website that has
no idea about the attacker and simply
has a store that crosses across site
scripting vulnerability that the
adversary is going to exploit or the
adversary can mount basically money in
the middle attack and just drop this
snippet on them conflict on plaintext
traffic that you observes
or you can record the message and
incorporate this pre-recorded beacon in
these methods so when the victim plays
it the bikaner is emitted as well the
common factor in all this case is that
the framework on the mobile device has
no way of knowing where this beacon is
coming from so what's happening is
basically the beacon is emitted by the
laptop or the organ device the framework
is picking it up but it can really tell
if it's coming from an advertiser or an
adversary so it looks the same to the
framework and this enables the attackers
also do some other things one of them is
beacon injection basically the attacker
is able to post beacons in the
frameworks running on the victims
devices and then the devices are going
to handle them handle them as a normal
beacon so they are going to push them
back to the backend as federic was
explained previously
so what could happen is that an
adversary can walk with his smartphone
on a popular store on Picon wrassle and
then has through his smartphone speakers
he may lead some mantra sounds auto
sound beacons and then all customers who
run across a proto by striking
frameworks with ultrasounds on their
devices will pick them up and report
them back to the company's bucket the
other thing that the attacker can do is
basically a variation of this can also
record beacons from other sources like
an ad or website and replay them to his
or the victims devices combining all
this now we present our fast attack
so our first attack is basically what we
saw on the demo we're going to explain
how we did it so the first step is for
the adversary to set up an advertising
campaign with any provider providing
such services this is step one so in
step two the adversary is basically
capturing the beacon from the beacon
table
and sets and sets a beacon table with
that specific beacon in our case this
was a tor hidden service it can be
whatever resource the attack the
adversities release it to be and then on
the third step somehow led visit the
user to visit this resource so on the
fourth step and when there is there a
lot the resource
his device in this case laptop basically
renders the content and emits the ultra
sound beacon as we see on step five
following that his smartphone is going
to pick up the ultrasound beacon and
report it back on the tracking provider
which is step 6
and of course given that we have a
state-level adversary he can go to the
service provider and say you know can
you please let me know who this could be
guy let me know the IP address and the
other and identifies that you have
collected for this guy
so yeah the whistleblower gets fully
anonymous that way however in the beacon
as we said previously we don't really
have a state-level adversary handy but
what we have is the latest version of
tor a computer with speakers and a smart
phone there which is running an
ultrasound enabled framework so since we
didn't have the state-level adversary
what we did is that we simulated one and
what I'm going to explain how we did
that so the only difference with the
attack that we observed previously is
that on step 6 instead of sending the
identifiers to the ultrasound service
provider we redirect them to the back
end of the adversary a lot that's the
only difference however we want to
stress this point that getting data from
providers it's not that hard so recently
there was this spine story about AT&T
coming up the news where apparently it's
very easy with a administrative subpoena
to ask which doesn't need to be obtained
by a judge by the way to ask for non
content information
yeah step seven seems very likely to
happen interest for governments and
secret services ation there are two more
attacks that we came up with so the
first one is based on the user profiling
that the advertisers like to do so
advertisers always try to audit or at
least in most cases try to profile their
users based on their interests and
behaviors so the attacker can actually
exploit this by injecting beacons to an
unsuspecting victim and fast influencing
the profile that the advertiser is
building for them so as you can see on
the picture the advert the adversary can
simply replay beacons or inject beacons
that he is crafting to the victims
device and then the device is going to
report them back to the backend that's
affecting the profile so of course the
degree that this attack affects the
profile depends exactly on the
implementation that the advertiser has
done the other attack the third one that
who came up with is the information
leakage attack so in this case yet the
attacker is trying to make his profile
identical to that of the victim and to
do that he's basically was dropping four
beacons and he's replaying them to his
own device and then of course his device
is pushing them back to the back end
so again depending on how profiling
techniques work and how the
recommendation system is implemented by
the tracking provider the profiles can
be done they can be made very identical
or similar and then the content pushed
to the adversary will be very similar to
that push the victim's device so after
all these attacks and you know playing
around with the ecosystem we started
wondering okay why are all these things
possible what are the formal reasons so
we did the formal security evaluation of
the ecosystem and we came up with four
points that needs to be considered so
the first one is that we
believe that the threat model used by
lots of companies is kind of inaccurate
the second one is that you design
beacons in the great majority of cases
like some necessary security features
also a fundamental security principle is
violated and there is also a lack of
transparency when it comes to informing
the users and few other things so the
first one the third model is basically
relying on the assumption that the
neutral sounds have limited transmission
range so and also assumes that the
attacker has no physical proximity to
the victim and the attacker is not able
to capture and replay because however
ultrasound scans are traveled reliably
for three meters in our experiments as
Federico said this is like six seven
meters and there are other ways to get
virtually close to the victim such as be
concepts that we introduced previously
the second second area that we like to
point out is the lack of authentication
and encryption capabilities of you
beacons so this is mainly associated
with the use cases that beacons are used
in so the channel the uterus and channel
has relatively low bandwidth that's one
thing the users are available for a
limited time so when you walk in
supermarket you don't want to spend on
specifics you are not going to stand on
a specific location for very long so the
advertisers have a limited time to put
things into your phone plus public
places are usually noisy start
increasing the transmission errors all
these result in a lack of communication
encryption capabilities thus enabling a
plain injection attacks the third
problem that we observe is the violation
of the principle of least privilege so
what's happening is that currently all
the ultrasound based applications need
to have full access to the microphone so
this means that they gain unnecessary
access to also audible frequencies
and if they want to do their I think and
gain access to the Sun spectrum only
this is not possible currently so of
course this comes with some consequences
first one is that if there is a
malicious developer he can misuse this
access to the microphone I mean he can
claim that he will do the SunTrust by
striking or something else
and also if show up on the user or and
another thing that's happening is that
ultra sound enabled apps are perceived
often by users as malicious because it
creates some sort of suspicion gaining
access to the microphone and listening
on the background so the third problem
is lack of the lack of transparency we
observed a large discrepancies between
the strategies that the companies and
the apps are following when it comes to
informing the users so for instance some
companies with doing a better job some
we're not doing we're not doing a good
job at all and the same thing would
serve when it comes to about options
which sort of are a lot it's also
interesting here that framework
developers are in the same position
because we advise their customers who
want to embed the framework on their
applications to follow proper practices
but the there is no much they don't do
much to enforce them into using proper
practices so this results in the
following thing happening so some mba
teams on May 10th announced that they
are going to use a neutral santim
framework to do some proximity marketing
a thing so this is in May the 10th of
May and later in August they got to both
a app developer and the company what's
interesting in this story is that in the
complaint then the user acknowledges the
fact that the app is asking for
permission to access a microphone
however what says is that they are not
given enough information to understand
what the reason for this request so this
goes back to transparency and of course
over privileging use
and then other case here - line 19 start
using framework and then users are
filing a lawsuit complaining that they
systematically decepticon tumors or
communications apparently according to
the lawsuit at least the app is
listening to the microphone for all the
users regardless of whether where they
were in the test or the home or work so
now that we put all those things now
when I would like to give you a much
better perspective how prevalent the
problem is or how and how many users it
affects it affects so the ecosystem is
indeed growing very fast there are new
companies coming out and products appear
at a fast pace however the good news is
that we believe that the relatively low
number of users is affected at this
point so there are about 10 companies
offering good result and tracking
products currently and the great
majority of them is interested mainly in
proximity marketing there is only one
company offering some cross device
tracking and we believe that not more
companies have jumped into this market
because the interest infrastructure
required for this is quite complicated
Plus this whole box lies within the
Federal Trade Commission and everything
else disincentivize them from joining
fearing that they will they may tarnish
the reputation I guess so now that we
have a formal evaluation of the problems
in the ecosystem we decided that it
would be better if we provided some
solution as well so our first the first
part of our solution is the
countermeasures that we develop the
countermeasures are short-term and
medium-term first one is our browser
extension browser extension works in
Chrome what it does is basically filters
all audio sources and remove say
ultrasound beacons before they are
emitted by the microfiber speaking of
the device it uses the weapon audio api
provided by html5 it's a simple - filter
that attenuates all frequencies above 18
kilohertz and to do that we identify all
the audio sources on the page and the
destinations the destinations are
usually the speakers of the device and
then rewire all the audio paths going
from the source to the destination stay
included filter the limitation here is
that because of some technical things in
the html5 this doesn't work with legacy
technologies for instance class is one
example that we found the second cap
short-term countermeasure who came up
with this B is our Android permission so
we created a part for the Android
permission system that allows allows for
a finer finer grained control over the
audio channel and this provides the
capabilities to separate between the
permissions for listening to audible
sound and append the regulates the acts
regulates access to the ultrasounds
ultrasonic spectrum also result this was
for the applications we definitely
explicitly declare their intention to
capture sound from the inaudible
spectrum and then as a result enable
users to selectively filter the ultra
sound frequencies up and fast preventing
applications from performing across the
bust ranking or anything else we also
filed a tour bot report and it's
currently being discussed what is the
solution and if this is something that
tour needs to address or not however we
believe that these are only sort and may
be media term countermeasures and in
order to fix the ecosystem in the long
term would like to argue for
standardizing it so we would like to
initiate the discussion for agreeing or
common uses on beacon format and we
mainly also decide what features
security features ultrasound beacons
will have and then when it's done where
we would be able to develop some api's
on the operating system level so this
api's will provide methods to discover
beacons process generate and possibly
emit them and will enable the apps do
that without any access to the device
microphone but instead they will ask for
a permission to access this specific API
it's very similar to what's happening to
bluetooth the benefits of these are
multiple so first it solves the problem
for were privileged egg apps because now
the applications have no need to access
the microphone it also eliminates the
risk that current applications run that
they may be consider the spying by the
users at which as we saw previously
and of course resolves the problem of
microphone locking so we we saw this in
our experiments what happens is that a
microphone is a resource that when one
up has access to it another application
is not able to basically gain access to
that at the same time so when we were
running in this hunt them crucify
striking framework listening to the
microphone the camera for instance
crossing so the API would probably
prioritize who gets access to the
microphone and so resolve this problem
so now there is a corner case that we
would like to address and this is so key
a developer may say you know I want to
don't want to follow the standard I want
to develop my own beacon format and I'm
going to do it the old-fashioned way I
would like to ask for access in
microphone
to prevent this from happening what we
suggest is basically for Android and
other mobile platforms to filter out the
ultrasonic frequencies captured by the
microphone by default and then provide
them some sort of interface for the user
to grant access to the whole spectrum on
a per application basis if the user was
to do that so now I'm going to hand it
back to the to say derecho for the
conclusions of this talk Thank You
facilities and so we've learned what
cross device tracking is we've learned
what ultrasound cross device tracking is
we've also seen how by reversing some
apps that by some reversing work that we
did we learn how this was implemented in
real world apps and then we gave you a
list of the shortcomings that we have M
also bacillus give you a demo on how
this technology can be abused by a
state-level attacker to D anonymize like
whistleblower for example or any other
user using tor and we've seen that the
key technology the degree key problem
here is that the attacker was able to
get close virtually close to the victim
by simply uploading a malicious banner
or a malicious multimedia resource on a
page emitting the ultrasound that would
have been picked up from the phone and
then we gave you an overview of all the
countermeasures that we provide and
hopefully we will be able with this talk
and with a with a media attention that
we received so far to start the
discussion a long-term discussion I
think will we think will take a few few
years to get implemented hopefully on on
the problem of how can we get to
standardized ultrasounds in the same way
we have Bluetooth for instance if you
can think I like the analogy of the
allocation of radio frequencies like if
you want to use a certain a certain
channel in a radio a certain frequency
you want to transmit and receive in that
frequency please
you want to receive a license for it at
least you need to inform the authorities
that you are using that frequency and
all the applications that are using the
radio spectrum are up to be certified
have to go through a series of
inspections we would like to throw
sounds if they if they are really going
to become the next main proximity
communication technology we would like
them to go through this all these
standardization steps we think this is a
step one where step zero is we have to
make the decision makers and the policy
makers aware of what are the privacy and
security implications of this technology
but there's more to do I mean after that
I say this is that zero and step one
there's more to do step two is that the
developers should start becoming aware
of this and explicitly notify when
they're implementing an app that uses
ultrasound or when they are
incorporating a framework that uses
ultrasound cross device tracking
technology to inform the users what
about what's going on underneath for
example by analyzing some of the apps
that we found on the Play Store I mean
the results were mixed
we found some applications that we're
informing the users about it and we also
found some application making no mention
absolutely no mention about what was
going on we are not sure but maybe some
developers could have just incorporated
the frame or thinking of like being
unaware of this and simply thinking it
as a simple advertising framework that
uses a new technology they were unaware
of all the security implications the
best would be if the developers offer an
opt-out or better an opt-in solution so
that the users can decide whether or not
they want to continue using this
technology or from some point on they
say I don't want to be I don't want to
use this anymore and switch off the
capturing the would resent so here of
course there is a conflict of interest
really like like in any other
advertisement library there is a balance
between
how much advertisement you want to show
and how much you want to like guarantee
some level of privacy for the users so
here there is a very delicate balance
between these two two issues that of
course the developer has to take a
decision on it and then what you see
here at the bottom is as what we found
on a real world application not a demo
application this is real-world
application incorporating the
silverpool's framework so the developer
simply took the sdk from the Civic with
website incorporated it into the where
into a D application and you can see
here at the bottom let me see if I can
move the cursor without screwing
everything you can see here the name of
the app it was history GK I'm not sure
if it's still on the Play Store I think
was an application to read a book or
something like that and it was
incorporating this frame and you can see
that not only it is transmitting all
possible information that you can think
of invading any any kind of privacy
level but also it was doing that in
plaintext and this is not a developer's
choice this is the framework providers
choice plaintext by default not on the
demo app on the framework
so the other step is that framework
providers such as silver bush and the
one that would will come next
hopefully we left to be aware of is that
they have instead of not enforcing
security practices such as in this case
they will have to embed technical
mechanisms to I would say forcefully
inform the users about what what's going
on for instance instead of letting the
developer decide on whether and how to
inform the users they could have some
like notification screen popping up the
first time the user loads an application
that uses this library I'm not sure how
this will be implemented in Android but
there must be a way using a library
framework that when it's loaded in
application for the first time you can
show you can show up a pop-up saying eh
you know this application is using
advisory blah blah blah which is using
ultrasounds if you want to know more go
here if you want to disable this simply
hit disable something like this and
everyone we should which was coming our
I want to stress we want to stress it
again what everyone should do is to
contribute if you want to this
standardization of beacons so that
hopefully we will see in a you know in a
couple of years maybe maybe earlier we
will see os-level api's providing
dedicated access to these resources as
basilica's as explained so that
developers would be able to develop
applications in a fully secure way in a
regulated way that respects the
standards we believe that there must be
also a way although we couldn't find
technically how to do it there must be a
way to squeeze some authentication
information in the very low bandwidth
that the ultrasonic
medium offers and if that is that is
possible then some of the problems that
we have seen such as the reply attack
wouldn't be possible again because every
beacon would be authenticated and maybe
times tempted in a way that cannot be
reused so with this we would like to
conclude and what you can see here is
again our search assistant Lara who
played key role in our experiment I
think again we have a demo demo for
moving her here like that when we were
doing experiment so if there are any
questions we are super happy to answer
them
even now or after the the end of this
talk we also set up a reference website
that hosts all the information that is
useful for anyone who is curious about
this project and for also the media who
who came to us in from various sources
asking us several questions we are
trying to maintain a list of frequently
asked questions so if you have questions
there is a button on the website that
you can you can use to submit a question
and we will try to answer them so if you
want to join us in this effort to secure
ultrasound based cross device
communicate communication techniques go
on you big stack that work thank
are there any questions yes okay that's
a very interesting question that was I
will repeat it for for the recordings
our our friend here is asking if there
is the possibility of implementing a
like anti ultrasound box that I can keep
next to me nearby my office or in into
my office or in my pocket that is kind
of a listening to any ultrasound beacons
in the air and emitting counter
ultrasound so that to neutralize the the
receiver of ultrasound beacons is that
what you are asking
well this was one of the first ideas
that we came up with and this would have
been our shortest term solution so give
you a device that you can you can keep
next to you but actually there is a
problem in the Indus is accel ultrasound
waves when you go very very into very
very short wavelength since they are
propagating in an inner ear like in a
non vacuum space what happens is that it
is very hard to record the ultrasound
and at the same time being able to
counter route the sound to counter to
counter the fact that ultrasound and
actually what you come up with is that
you can have some diffraction between
the waves and actually mix up your
counter wave with the original wave and
so amplify the ultrasounds the resulting
good or sound that's why if you have
like headphones from bose
noise-canceling ones they cannot really
fill the high frequency noises that's
why they have all the
the physical material to try to filter
them they work very well with a long
ways because they have all the time to
synchronize to the wave but that's a
very very just intrusion graph one mark
oh yeah exactly so the question is
basically if those attacks can be
implemented without actually using the
ultrasound spectrum but in in the
audible frequency spectrum right so it's
definitely possible and actually there
are companies that are doing cross
device tracking and similar offering
similar services within the audible
spectrum using multiple techniques
differently different with each other
and usually patented so it's definitely
possible and this is can kind of harder
to deal with but it from our research it
seems that it's a less populated echo
system compared to the ultrasound wall
but nevertheless it's absolutely very
possible last thing to do
[Music]
so if I understood correctly but please
follow up if I haven't you're asking
whether we found cases of governments or
like agencies using these techniques
what okay well we haven't found cases I
mean we cannot really tell that we have
found any case about this but we can say
as the example that provided the
facilities provided that maybe it
doesn't even require you to be Secret
Service's or like the government to
obtain a subpoena in order to go to the
to the provider and ask for the
information that you need so we would
say that I mean I can't repeat we
haven't seen any of these cases but it
is not as hard well depends on when
depends on depends on where you want to
pick up the sound how far you want on
phone well yeah so these are very
interesting questions how we take it
offline because I think there are some
technical are there any other questions
or
oh yeah absolutely yeah oh yes yeah
definitely yeah what I can follow up on
the on the browser extension that we are
providing that that's one-click solution
you install the browser extension and
you have a sort of a personal sound
sound firewall that chops off the
frequencies that are known to be used by
these providers and you can selectively
change the frequency depending on on
your team so you don't really need to
cut off all the older spectrum you can
simply cut off a dangerous one but as
marco said before if we come up with all
your steganography then yes probably the
only solution will be to completely turn
off the speakers we're using so this
would be a nuclear approach right I just
want to kill the echo system it will
definitely work another thing that would
work is that on the latest versions of
Android you can go through all your apps
and disable access to the microphone you
can do this as well but and in the short
term this could be a solution even
though there is a usability penalty I
assume by disabling your speakers in
general what we are trying to do is to
push for a solution that doesn't kill
the whole a persistent but fixes the
security problems associated with it and
yeah there are good cases good use cases
for the ecosystem I mean it's okay to
have a better way to advertise products
we understand this and also if we kill
the echo system that never gonna happen
so we've got this questioner also from
some journalists and I really don't know
I mean it's very hard to convince people
we saw this also in this case that
you're using the microphone but you're
not really listening right it's counter
intuitive and I think I trust them but
you never know like no one would really
[Music]
know in the user sound echo system I
think that apart from being a bit than
apart from being completely apart for
users like not informing them at all
from for what they are doing I don't
think they were misusing the access to
the permissions to access the microphone
we haven't found any at recording the
whole space any other questions
but thanks a lot okay so this this is a
tough question because we weren't able
to you know you don't know what the
frameworks the the advertisers are kind
of secretive with the frameworks they
don't provide it openly on the web so I
think there are references that they
were around 70 apps 67 of things
something like this
the number is kind of unknown I would
say because after the call box laws many
developers basically removed the
framework out of fear for their users so
it's currently fluctuated fans waiting
right yeah so the apps be 67 up who I
was referring mainly to older son first
device striking the users were nearly
few millions I would say familiar
according to google metadata a few
millions user might have downloaded
these applications but the proximity
marketing apps have way more users you
will have to scan the entire Play Store
download all of them and see if you if
you find evidence of the SDK that we
mentioned so it's a it's doable
definitely not trivial and it's a it's a
Google question I mean it's for Google
Inc right you thank you