[Applause]
about us be our Merrin welcome thank you
can you hear me hi um so let's get
started
so today's talk is basically be going to
be about weaponizing the USP army before
I continue how many of you have worked
with the u.s. VMware before nice that's
more than I expected but this is
basically going to be about how to use
it for offensive exploitation or embed
tests so let's get started so I'm
currently a security analyst in
Netherlands I work for a company called
risky but I just joined it like three
months back I've been working in
embedded security for the past 45 years
I mainly concentrate on embedded
security as such finding the bug boots
dumping flash memory and such but
sometimes I also work on ready security
of finding vulnerabilities in radio
emissions and other things that are work
remotely
that's my Twitter handle if you need to
get in touch with me you can use that
that's enough about me so what exactly
the USB my it's basically a handheld
device I really so that's the device so
it should have been in the previous
light but yeah it's basically a USB form
factor device that allows you to emulate
USB connections and do a lot more on a
small form factor so the main reason I
bought an and I'm sure many other people
bought it is because tilde will the USB
armory came into play if you wanted a
small Linux device your most probable
option was to get Raspberry Pi but with
the USB armory you can have something
that you can plug directly into your
computer and play around with the USB
subsystem of the Linux kernel so we will
actually be focusing on the USB
subsystem but we'll also
talk a bit about how to use utilize the
USB Emery completely as an embed device
so um it's got a few GPIO is that we can
leverage later how many of you have
worked with embedded devices before
raspberry PI's Arduino is great embedded
security great so um yeah so I'm trans
own is basically one of the features
that the USB arm I suppose it's
basically security feature we will not
be talking about it much but yes the I
don't thing to keep in mind is if it's
not that easy to get hold off because I
think the crowd supply page is still up
and I'm pretty sure that maybe 5,000
people around the world habit because I
at least going by the sales that I see
on cloud supply not many people have
this
I like the Raspberry Pi of the team fee
it's created by a company called emerge
spot Andrea belladonna you might know
him from his other projects on embedded
security or amber devices but yeah
that's about it for the USP army the
next thing we're going to talk about is
HIV attacks and how it relates to us
today so a 8id attacks is basically
imagining that a person is the right
next year Siddha system and plugging in
his keyboard and mouse and doing
whatever he wants it sounds simple but
using justice it can you can bypass a
lot of security measures implementing
the companies take for example the fact
that you actually might have endpoint
security systems that might block USB
storage devices but are you sure it also
blocks devices that are composite as in
device that a both mass storage an
Ethernet or macerate an HID ear if they
do how do they actually use or how do
they implement it
and hid attacks are something that is
often overlooked because obviously if
you if you are not working on a
headlight system you would need a
keyboard and a mouse to operate the
system and this attack basically uses
that loophole together then these are
not new attacks this is not something
new it's been around for at least five
years now and probably more but in this
talk we'll just see how we can use the
USB are made for such attacks as far as
I know there have not been any
real-world attacks using a type II
devices but at least according to me
we'll probably be seeing them sometime
soon it's also a local attack vector you
don't need to burn zero days and then
tackle a network or you don't need to
find your way inside the building that
your pen testing and the building that
you're trying to attack just dropping a
few USB sticks which act as hid devices
which year program is quite enough and
currently there are both commercial and
open source implementations that allow
you to run various payloads against
devices depending on the operating
system
what type of payload you want a d1
network or not a few examples this
ignition written by Nick emitter
who's the speaker here it is also used
extensively for HID attacks you also
might have heard of the robber Turkey
which is a commercial implementation
which has its own a key script so are at
least for me I started with HID attacks
back when the teens he was popular so
team T is a microcontroller it was a ARM
architecture but the thing about things
is it it allowed you to play with the
USB protocol a lot
if you wanted to create an HID device
that does whatever you want didn't say
allows you to do it it also allows you
to create custom end points and pushed
it in whatever manner you choose so for
a lot of people at least including me
the TV was the starting point for HIV
attacks around that time rubber ducky
also became popular rubber ducky is a
product made by hak5 which is basically
a commercialized version of the deemed
it does not use a teensy but at least
the new emotions do not use it but it's
basically a plug-and-play
it's a lot easier to use you don't have
to muck around with C or CPP to get it
to work but there are certain
limitations
but again I think they've overcome that
with the latest offering the help called
the bash money I think Munich's was
giving it out yesterday yeah so uh
basically bash money is it's a bit more
powerful it again like uh like what I'll
mention later it allows you to compose
the devices basically devices that are
both hid and you hid and master rich or
hid and Ezer net so there are multiple
attack friends through which you can now
infiltrate an actual trade data again if
you want to go to the hobbyist route
something that has been coming up a lot
in blogs reason is the use of Raspberry
Pi zero so much idea attractive again I
mentioned this is a hobbies this one
because it's not easy to like hide a
Raspberry Pi zero even though it's tiny
inside a USB stick
so why did I choose the USB armory for
this presentation many believe the
drones Linux initially I thought that
would make things easier but the last
few days which I did not sleep properly
is probably contrary to that notion but
if it was helpful because it ran the
length which I'm familiar with I was
able to get a lot of things done it's
also the hardware the software is open
source so whatever modifications that
you want to make you can make again it's
the form factor is it just like a USB
device you get a 3d printed case that is
also available online it looks just like
any other USB device up again and
whatever language that you're
comfortable with you can use it from
each Python so you can basically create
your payloads in Python or you can
generate your pillows using Python or
whatever language that you're
comfortable with but the main reason I
use it is because I had one handy so the
thing about it is that right now I'm
using a USB Omni with Windows 10 and
Ubuntu virtual machine I've tested it
multiple times but there might be
interruptions in the demo but then again
I hope I have not pissed off the demo
gods today so the framework I'm going to
use is something I wrote recently called
the offensive armory it's it's currently
a very small tool if it's basically
allows you to it basically automates a
lot of the work that you need to do to
make us be re an attack tool or to use
it as an HIV attack device and just
allows you to specify what target that
you want to attack and whatever payload
you need so it basically is a lot of
starter scripts so basically once you
have activated your USB harmony with the
Omri you can just plug it in and it
shouldn't be look I'll be posting this
later today and my github so just keep a
watch sir
okay so let's more two demos so are
basically the first before we get
started I just want to mention something
that yes Bwana me by default comes with
the Ethernet connection enable on USB or
as an rmdir gadget
so basically give SSH to it if you set
static IP addresses but if you're
playing around with the usb on we end up
if you're working with the USB subsystem
I would recommend you not to use that
for while you're working with USB
because again if you unload the GE third
driver excuse me
then you end up without an SSH
connection so here what I'm doing right
now is basically I am connecting to the
SSH puts on the USB armory so that I
there's a connection even if the device
crashes so yeah my first two demos are
going to be pretty simple it's basically
an hid attack on windows just to pop a
commensal and PowerShell so let's get
started
so this is basically the seal console
for this and I'm going to run offensive
armory light thank you so much Ron
offensive armory and it should tell me
the various options so now I'm going to
run hid um against windows and
okay so it should generate a script
all right now
Oh any theatre yeah sorry okay yeah so
how this works is basically it it has a
script called hid doll research written
by : Lola which basically sets up all
the all the end points and the USB
information that is necessary for the
USB I'm going to work as a hid device
then it uses string to hid to basically
open up the the run prompt you saying
windows are and then it is types command
it's pretty simple ah so so this is
simulate me the movie turn off I'm just
going to reboot and everything works out
yep
and yeah so uh in stuff it doesn't
necessarily need to stop here you can
run water payload you want it is
continues after this
so again my main repository actually has
a few more advanced payloads but yet is
the most basic one in this run command
instead of command prompt we can run net
use or any of the other inbuilt windows
commands but this is basically how you
do it you can even run PowerShell
and now if you reboot it should come up
with a partial finger
that's it for that and again I plan to
add a boat for initial or any of the
other I shall attack framework so
basically you can import modules from
that but yes it's not primitive yet the
next one is it's a composite device
basically the USB armory is going to
simulate a Ethernet plus hid device and
it will be running a DHCP server on the
USB armory so basically when you the
idea is when connected to a device it
would automatically assign an IP to the
device and then you can use the hid
interface to input the commands and
exfiltrate data using the network
interface so something that's been
missing in a lot of hid attacks is a way
to accelerate data so if the device has
a internet connection you could just
definitely get to call it out but if it
does and then it becomes a bit more
complex so um basically right now we
will be creating a composite device and
using inter track Linux this is the one
that usually gives me problems because
right now it's passing through Windows
10 VirtualBox and there are a lot of
other components I could go off
okay
let's restore the USB re-ask of
[Music]
multi-device
so it should generate a script that
would do most of the work and now if we
reboot this is what gets I see
Oh
so basically after setting up a network
on the USB interface the next step for
the USB memory is to spawn a kamancheh
so for this case are just descript uses
the normal shortcut shot keys that is
control all t it generates that and then
just inputs the code there are again
advanced methods available like trying
to communicate using caps lock so
previously before composite devices were
considered another way for the host
which in this case is the laptop running
ubuntu to communicate with the device is
via caps lock or scroll lock or number
lock so the information that what is
being sent is actually available to all
the HID wires that are connected
looks like the payload Ram but let me
just confirm whether it got the data or
not but yeah as you can see it's
basically running netcat and it pipes
the EDC password file okay
looks like the device got a different IP
so earlier there was an issue with oh
yeah this was an issue with the DHCP
server running on the yes family still
trying to find a way around it so that
you can get a you don't need to manually
adjust the IP addresses but it's still a
work in progress but yes this should
work yep and this way you'd be able to
extract data out of the device that
you're targeting obviously this is not
the only way another multi device that
you could use is HIV+ mass storage so
basically it would be simpler than an
Ethernet because the only thing you
would need to do is basically figure out
where it is mounted to in Windows um you
could kick the different drives in case
of Linux you could just go from slash
mount FTB to FTC and figure out where it
is but in that case it's as simple as
creating this image and mounting it
inside the USB armory so I don't think
to keep in mind is when you walk with
the USB armory Justin
yeah you can also do a lot more advanced
attacks so another type that we've
demonstrated recently but that was using
a Raspberry Pi is to use responded pi
which is basically acts as a rogue SMB
server in that way you can even connect
to a device that is locked so all the
attacks that I've shown you right now
will not work if the device is locked
because it's an HID device it's it
involves a certain amount of social
engineering the respondent or PI but
will work with a lock device it
basically simulates an SMB server a
rogue SMB server and you can even get
credentials from all the windows systems
another thing that you can do is
basically input a port scanner via the
hid interface it could be a partial
command or it could be a binary that you
W get in Linux another form of attack is
to use a air sensor so basically it
would connect to the GPIO pins of the
USB armory and so the main issue with
the hid attacks is to make sure the user
is not there now the rubber ducky does
this by basically sending commands fast
which is one way to do it but another
way to do it would be to sense a sense
if the person is in the same room using
a PIR sensor that is where the USB
Armouries GPIO pins would be really
useful so again I face a lot of issues
getting this to work mainly because I
realize pretty late that the latest
version of the yoshiyama image that is
being posted on the inverse path website
it's not compatible with HRT devices so
if if you need to work on this you can
either compile the image yourself
so Colonel 4.4 works the current colonel
is I think 4.6 for the u.s. family but
if you use the 4.4 kernel most of the
devices should work I have a compressed
image which allowed to be putting up on
github but if you need faster you can
ask me I'll just shared with you I
already share a faceless BSEP Lisa's not
working properly for composite devices
up again this is one of the issues that
we just saw basically not all devices
work the same so if you're attacking
Windows or Linux you will have to
slightly tailor your payloads so that
the targets are affected so on the same
vein I try to get the network device the
composite USB plus the network plus hid
device working with Windows and I could
only make it work with Windows 7 so
right now the product ID for the top you
can see now
so basically the product ID and
manufacture ID that's being used for the
composite device is the same that is the
for an IBM network device so this is
done for that Windows 7 would
automatically recognize and install the
drivers it doesn't work that way in
Windows 10 um so again if you're working
with Windows 10 and USB how many but
then again it's it's a it's true for
most embedded devices that you work with
if you're using Windows again you will
face a few issues getting this to work
but straight hid straight network or
just straight master it should work
composite devices have a few issues on
Windows 10 other than that make sure you
use VMware again I have had a much
better result just working with VMware
Workstation rather than Marshall box
mainly because again VirtualBox USB
subsystem creates a lot of headaches
sometimes other than that yeah I already
mentioned about the understand so I
prayed to accredited you anti by signing
and inverse path for the USB armory it
again it it's a very good elegant board
that you can work on its Linux so it's
very easy to use also the documentation
is kind of sparse which is the only
issue most people have what I would
recommend you go on the Google Groups
were Andrea and other members of inverse
pod actively respond to comments or you
can even like ask Andrea directly on
Twitter he would respond for most of
your queries : we'll know for the hid
scripts that are used and a lot of
kernel compilation examples
not by I know how to spell his name but
yeah see ju e th e adding that this
handle ah
but yes that's that's about it for this
two questions