[Music]
[Applause]
our next speaker is andrew zonenberg he
has spoken in the past at hardware.io as
well uh he's a principal security
consultant at i o active and this talk
is going to be extended into a workshop
as well if you guys would uh
like to participate it would be very
nice uh so it's going to be boost your
hardware reverse engineering skills with
a
glass cop client
andrew uh over to you
hello
let me just get the screen share up give
me one second
okay
yeah screen is visible all right yeah it
just took me a second to get the uh
right monitor selected all right so yes
i'm andrew sonnenberg and i'm going to
be talking about gel scope client
so uh as antrik mentioned this talk has
been extended into kind of a mini
workshop so roughly we're looking at
about half an hour of slides with more
introductory background material about
how the software is built how it's used
and so on and then we'll go into half an
hour or so we can run later since it's
the last talk of the day
of interactive demo
i have two live demos on actual hardware
in my lab that i'll do quickly first and
then we'll switch to a bunch of
pre-recorded data that is in the github
repo that i linked in the chat earlier
so if you want to play around with
analyzing some of the same data as i'm
going through it then you can follow
along
so a little bit of background i did my
phd at rpi in 2015 uh
focusing on system-on-chip architecture
security
operating systems and kind of the
intersection of all of those i went to
io active since then i've been doing
primarily pen testing but a fair bit of
research in the side as well
uh interests outside of that have been
more on the performance and deep
embedded everything from silicon reverse
engineering all the way up to
supercomputing gpu fpga stuff
optimization etc and so this software
actually came out of a tool i developed
early on in my thesis for debugging some
of my projects back in 2011 so it's been
going on for about a decade and uh only
recently has it been fast enough and
cleaned up enough to really be more of a
public release
also before we get too into things uh i
am presenting on company time so i
putting io actives logo on these slides
this is not something we are selling as
a product it's an open source tool i'm
developing in my spare time i do however
use it at work i've actually written a
couple of protocol decodes for use on
client engagements when i came across a
protocol that we didn't have tooling for
and so
i find it useful at work and i'm hoping
some of you will as well
so uh just a quick screenshot before we
get too into all of the details of
architecture keep everybody excited
so as i mentioned i've been working on
this tool for quite a long time uh gel
scope client i started in about 2017.
it's a gpu accelerated complete
front-end rewrite all of the ui code is
new and is built on the same framework
libscopal and lipscope protocols as the
original scope client which never got
released because it was never really
stable or mature enough but it's all
follow hard coded paths to directories
on my local storage and all kinds of
things like that and so it needed a
complete rewrite anyway
and so
kind of the problems i'm trying to solve
are test equipment remote control
analysis of waveforms both live
streaming as well as offline potentially
integrating data from multiple sources
and uh generally uh kind of the
long-term vision is for jessica plunk to
become the new radio equivalent for
oscilloscopes so you know anytime you're
doing sdr stuff it's kind of assumed
you're going to be using something built
on top of new radio as like the
industry standard open source tool chain
and so my goal is to make libscopal and
lipscope protocols become the standard
open source tooling for telescopes
and so to support that gall it is
permissively licensed three clause bsd
specifically because i want to encourage
vendors to integrate in both directions
i would like vendors to be able to
contribute drivers for their instruments
i would like to potentially even have
vendors start using libscopal-based
tools officially as part of their
official sdks and official user
interfaces and so on
so as far as timeline goes uh there has
not yet been an official release we are
pretty close to that uh there's a bit
more work on documentation to do
and just general polish fixing random
crashes and things that aren't quite as
intuitive in the ui as we would like so
i'm aiming for that in the next month or
two it's it's pretty close
uh
then version 0.2 is going to be end of
this year into sometime early next year
focus on that is going to kind of be
taking off the half-baked things and
finishing them so for example we have a
bunch of instrument drivers that don't
support all the trigger options the
scope has or don't support digital
channels or don't support the waveform
generator a bunch of you know things
that are ancillary functions that are
nice to have but not critical to
actually use the instrument for basic
waveform capture and so a lot of these
driver completion things are going to be
pushed to version 0.2 uh we've also got
a bunch of things where for example
we've got a protocol decode that may not
implement all of the particular corners
of some protocol
or maybe just doesn't do great
verification it doesn't do a good job of
detecting protocol violations when some
data is not quite well formed and so on
and sometime in that range maybe into
some time later um
i would also like to add mac os support
that is not available right now uh for
reasons that i'll get into in a bit
so as far as target platforms uh kind of
the first tier platform is linux just
because that's what most of our
developers are on uh i'm personally on
debian we've got a bunch of people on
arch fedora et cetera
we have work in progress packaging for a
couple of distros already and we're
working on getting more uh i know at
least the debian packages are in the
process of being upstreamed and the
others probably uh certainly it is our
goal to get those upstream of the future
uh we already have builds in the mingw
repositories uh we have alpha releases
of both portable binaries and msi
installers on windows
uh
as far as target platforms right now
it's only 64 but x86 there's a lot of
hand-tuned avx optimizations and so on
in the code at the moment uh so in order
to get it to run on other platforms i
mean they do have detections for runtime
dispatch so we only use them on
supported cpus but at compile time we're
gonna need to do just a little bit of if
deaths and so on in order to make it
work on other platforms so that's still
in progress um arm64 is gonna be the
next platform we would like to get it to
run on for example apple m1 and so on in
the future so definitely uh arm 64 is
coming it's not available yet
uh
as i mentioned it does not currently run
on mac os the main reason for that is
because
apple decided that they don't like
opengl even though it's supposed to be
the industry standard cross-platform
graphics api and so
apple's opengl drivers are stuck on i
think version 4.1 and we need 4.3 in
order to get compute shaders and so
basically the entire renderer which
thankfully is not that much code but it
is going to have to be rewritten and
ported to something
os x compatible in order to actually run
on mac so we've got a couple of people
with especially recent apple silicon
hardware that are very interested and
working on it but nothing usable yet
um and also i know i saw in the chat
earlier at least one person was asking
about a pre-built vm as of now we don't
have that the reason being that again
opengl 4.3 is required and i have not
seen any virtualized gpus that provide
compute shaders in the emulated graphics
card uh if you do have an actual
physical gpu allocated to the vf via pci
pass through sriv or so on i believe
that'll work nobody's ever tried it but
i have no reason to believe that will
not work but certainly any of the
conventional you know vmware virtual
svga and so on are not going to work
so next let's get into a little bit
about the architecture of how the scope
tile and gel scope client are built
so gyroscope client is the front-end
user interface the focus is on rendering
and dialog boxes and basically just a
nice graphical wrapper around the
underlying c plus api then lipscope hal
is the
instrument driver layer that is in
charge of taking
all of the different proprietary
usb protocols and sdks and uh skippy
commands and so on and bridging that all
out to a single unified c plus api so in
gel scope client or lipscope protocols
code you can just have a pointer to an
oscilloscope object you can call arm
trigger or acquire data and you don't
care what the actual thing is done to
the scope to do that arm
then lipscope protocols is specifically
the protocol decodes math functions dsp
all the things that work on abstract
waveforms and don't care where they came
from and then we do also support custom
plug-ins loaded at runtime plug-ins can
provide uh instrument drivers they can
provide transports they can provide
anything for the filter graph there is
not currently support for custom
rendering plug-ins i would like to build
that into the architecture in the future
additionally it is also possible to
write custom tooling in c plus plus or
language listed plus bindings so that
you can call into the libraries directly
so you can write uh headless scripted
test code that
configures triggers on an instrument
acquires a waveform does a protocol
decode on and does say a pass fail test
or does for example power analysis using
a decoded uart as a trigger in order to
determine when a particular power trace
is of interest and so on um one warning
if you decide to do this until the
version 1.0 release which is still
probably at least a year out there is no
abi stability and so anytime the library
is updated any
custom tooling calling directly into
libraries is going to need to recompile
we are trying for but haven't made an
official guarantee of api stability so
if you recompile the code everything
should work but there is not binary
compatibility between lipscope power
releases at the moment
all right so next up is just kind of a
quick overview of the data flow so we've
got data coming in from one or more
instruments uh you can load data from
files you can create waveforms
synthetically so synthesize a tone or a
pseudo-random bit sequence etc uh then
feed that into the filter graph which
i'll talk about a little bit more later
on and then finally the output of that
is rendered
and so the photograph is a pretty common
dsp multimedia architecture if you've
done anything with
video processing or
new radio or things like that uh you're
probably familiar with photographs and
so lipscope pals photograph architecture
is no different uh you've just got a
series of blocks in this case we've got
two channels on the left only one of
them is in use then we run through a
bunch of processing blocks and then the
outputs of some of them are displayed at
the screen
uh the photograph is using a custom
thread scheduler so we actually take
it's a directed basic graph of uh filter
blocks uh the graph is then uh extracted
for parallelism so any filters that
don't depend on each other can execute
in parallel we use openmp in order to
evaluate the filter blocks in parallel
and then the output of that is then set
to the ui thread for display
uh as far as file io goes the native uh
file format is kind of like audacity if
you're familiar with that there's a
metadata file that in our case is yaml
based that contains all the
configuration about how the user
interface is set up what channels are in
the displays what filter graph box are
what inputs go to where and so on and
then there's a data directory that
contains all of the raw waveform samples
we also can support importing waveforms
from agilent keysight and ride gold
binaries they're it's pretty much the
same file format uh
you can import csv files and in the case
of digital waveforms we actually can
parse the metadata into header comments
you can get the serial number the time
stamp and so on in the csv file then
value change dump and wav files
right now the only export format is csv
we are working on adding more so i'd
like to be able to export to vcd and so
on i would like to be able to support
more vendor formats as well
bi-directionally so you can push
something from say the output of a just
compliant waveform to an instrument or
pull in say a lacroix.trc file and so on
so we're always working on adding more
file formats
uh next we're going to get to the list
of supported hardware i'm just going to
go through all of the equipment vendors
alphabetically
i am going to gloss over this pretty
quickly the slides are going to be
posted afterwards so i'm not going to go
into great detail on each instrument
family uh
vigilant sent me free hardware it's
sitting on my lab bench and i've been
too busy getting ready for this talk and
fixing other bugs in order to actually
write a driver for it so the hardware is
here it's scheduled for support but not
implemented quite yet
um keysight and asylum we've got pretty
good support for a bunch of their lower
end entry-level models i am still trying
to get my hands on some of the higher
end current gen keysight stuff
uxr maybe something a little bit less
nice than that so uh i'm working on
getting a demo scope and as soon as i
get one uh we will have better driver
support it may work on the newer stuff
now it's just never been tested because
none of our developers have gotten our
hands on any
um
pico is one of our better supported
platforms at the moment for the higher
end uh the 6000 e series is fairly
complete uh we still have to support
some of the more advanced triggers
functioning director and so on um i'm
actually going to be showing some stuff
on the 6000 series at the end of the
talk uh we are working on adding support
for their other families uh we've got
some of them partially merged some still
work in progress so we're a ways out
from having support for pico's entire
product line but again it's definitely
coming um and pico has been very
supportive of the project they've
contributed hardware to the project and
uh generally
have been very helpful
uh rygal we've got support for a couple
of the lower end models and then the mso
5000 uh again just a matter of getting
our hands on more hardware to add driver
support uh roden schwartz we have one
contributor working on rtm 3000 driver i
don't know what other platforms it may
run as well
uh siglit has also been very helpful uh
they've sent some additional tooling and
hardware to some of our developers
we've got pretty good support for the
2000 series uh the 5000 series is
supposed to be pretty much the same and
we've done a little bit of testing it
seems to work okay but i still
need to put more time into that uh and
again we don't have quite coverage of
the entire product line but we're
working on it
lacroix is actually probably our tier
one platform right now as far as best
support because that's most of what i
have in my lab and so it's kind of my
daily driver for development pretty much
anything maui based so anything using
the modern user interface is going to be
protocol compatible they're all going to
use the exact same commands and so if it
works on a lot of metal work on often
the one exception is some of the arm
based systems so the wave surface 3000
uh wave server 4000 hd web server 3000 z
and so on i do have a few limitations
certain things that are supported on the
higher end ones are not supported on
those so they're they're a little bit
quirky it mostly works but every once in
a while you run something that's a
little bit funny and so i do have a 3000
series scope that i'm working on adding
better support for but uh i've been
mostly working on the higher end stuff
and as you can see we pretty much have
coverage of the entire product run all
the way back to the dda5000 series we've
done testing on and i believe that's
from
the windows xp or 2000 era and so pretty
much any windows-based lacroix scope is
going to work with jessica klein and
they're actually among as when we get to
the performance section uh you'll see
they're among the faster uh drivers at
the moment too again it's a combination
of our drivers and instrument
performance that really affects how much
waveform throughput you can get in a gel
scope client then tektronix we have very
good coverage of the mso6 the four and
five are supposed to be the same command
set so in theory it should work nobody's
ever gotten their hands on one's test so
if anybody has an mso405 and what's a
try we would love feedback
as far as other tech products again i
don't know what's using the same command
set and what isn't these are the ones
we've tested uh the
performance of the mso i was a little
bit disappointed with i it was
significantly slower than some of the
other uh higher end scope vendors i'm
actually going back and forth with some
of the applications and there's at
tektronix they've uh said that they're
looking at making some improvements in
future firmware uh rigel as well uh is
apparently interested in making some
firmware improvements to uh increase
throughput and so none of that has uh
been released yet but the vendors are
definitely interested and working on
getting faster firmware out so excited
to see where that's going
so next uh we're going to talk about
performance in a little bit more detail
so
the first limiting factor and especially
on lower end hardware is generally the
one that's going to be your biggest
bottleneck is cpu performance fpga
performance and connection between the
cpu and fpga on the scope unfortunately
there's not really much you as a user or
just go client developer can do about
that so you pretty much have to live
with what the hardware has uh although
again we are working on pushing vendors
to try and do more optimization to their
firmware to improve throughput uh then
there's the bottleneck of interface so
anything with only hundred mag ethernet
or usb to water it is gonna be slow
there again there's there's only so much
that you can cram through pipe that size
uh higher end hardware like for example
most of the lacroix tektronix and so on
stuff is going to have at least gigabit
ethernet and then the best performance
is going to come from things that have
multi-gigabit i o interfaces so for
example the uh higher end pico products
have uh usb 3 on them i've pushed
upwards of two gigabits a second of
actual waveform throughput through those
uh i'm working on some open source
designs of my own that are going to have
10 gig ethernet on them uh certainly any
kind of a pcie acquisition card again
it's going to have really good
performance as far as throughputs does
uh this also kind of ties into
optimization on the just compliant
driver side so optimizing for
less round trips sending less commands
don't send state changes if the
instrument's already in the state that
you want it to be uh general software
optimization techniques uh certain
instruments are more meant to pipelining
than others uh the tech mso6 in
particular really does not like when you
send it a command before the previous
commit is finished it'll either abort or
hang or drop the previous command we've
had that issue with sigmund firmware as
well both vendors are aware of the issue
and are addressing it so hopefully in
the future we'll start seeing some
firmware that's more compatible with
pipelining because pipeline was one of
the biggest optimizations i did in the
lacroix driver and it greatly improved
performance being able to queue up a
bunch of commands and not have to wait
for a reply from the instrument saying
oh i'm done you can send me another
command and then add another you know
potentially several milliseconds around
trip time before you can send the next
command
another issue to consider is scaling so
if you go from a shallow waveform to a
deep wave form how does performance
change
a lot of the lower end hardware there's
a really large 01 term and
again this is i think at least partially
firmware limited and i am hopeful that
in the future for more improvements at
the vendor side are going to improve
this so for example the regular mso 5000
series
we have been unable to get more than one
waveform per second of throughput
through it no matter what we do but if
you turn up the memory depth it doesn't
really slow down that much on the other
hand with higher end scopes generally
the on term is going to be the bigger
factor so for example in the case of
lacroix wave runner 8000 series you can
see we go from 40 waveforms a second to
three-way from the second as you go from
80k to 8 million points
and so here's just a quick table showing
examples of the kind of performance
you'll get with anything from say a more
entry level scope like a rival msl 5000
all the way up to some higher end stuff
like uh mccrory hdos uh picoscope 6000
uh this is an older agilent or keysight
stuff but they're still you know a bit
on more on the high end than something
from say rigel and so you can see even
here that the throughput you can get
with some of the higher end products is
definitely way better than something
than you would get from say the wrigler
again the tech episode 6 had a
surprisingly poor showing considering it
was otherwise a really nice scope so i
think it is just a firmware limitation
and i am hopeful a future firmware
release will improve that uh but you can
see that for example the agilent mso6
actually gives you quite nice throughput
in terms of waveforms per second at
child memory and again it can't keep up
quite as well when you increase the
memory depth but you know 30 waveforms
per second you know that's 30fps that's
a nice interactive frame rate
and so here's a comparison looking with
deep memory and so i'll bounce back and
forth between these slides a little bit
so you can see so for example again the
azalean ms06 you can see we go from 30
waveforms uh at 1k points at a million
points we're down to one frame per
second but you know we're still getting
okay throughput you know one one frame
per second at a million points it's okay
it's not great uh meanwhile say the
mccroy hdo at a million points with four
channels would give you almost six waves
per second so that's 300 megabits a
second um and that's with a 16 bit
resolution because it is an hd scope
okay it's 10 bit but they're padded out
to 16 over the wire so that's kind of
your network performance limit um then
the wave runner 8000 down at the bottom
is an 8-bit scope so in our case here if
we only have two channels at 800k points
you're still getting 16 frames per
second so again pretty respectable
throughput
and then pico comes in and blows
everybody away with almost two gigabits
a second of throughput doing 30 frames
per second with a million points in four
channels so if you want fast update
rates nothing else i've seen
can compare to the picoscopes i am
really hopeful that other vendors are
going to start putting 10 gig ethernet
and similar high bandwidth interfaces on
their scopes and so you know maybe two
or three generations down the road we'll
start seeing stuff from keysight and
lacroix and attack that has tango
ethernet on it and at that point maybe
they'll be competitive but right now uh
for especially deep cameras if you're
trying to do a lot of waveforms per
power analysis or something like that
that nothing compared to the picoscopes
um other performance considerations uh
when you're actually rendering stuff you
are gpu performance limited so if you
scroll out and you're looking at a lot
of samples on screen you're gonna be
slower if you zoom in and you're looking
at a few samples it's gonna be faster uh
just as a rough reference up with my
2080 ti on my workstation at home a
single 128 million point waveform takes
about 50 milliseconds so you're looking
at you know 10 20 fps for
scrolling around one waveform um and
that's for just rendering obviously when
you start doing dsp processing and so on
on deep waveforms and it starts to add
up as well
so that actually brings me to the next
topic which is photograph complexity so
if you have for example a lot of
different filters being applied to one
channel it's going to be pretty fast
because they can each run on different
cores and about the threat if you've got
a nice long linear chain where you do
say an equalization operation and then a
d embed and then you do a clock recovery
on that and then you do a protocol
decode using the recovered clock each
one of those blocks can't run until the
previous one is finished and so in that
case you're going to have a more serial
bottleneck and it does become a little
more difficult to get high throughput um
and then certainly you've got
limitations based on cpu and structure
set supports uh any more number
crunching heavy stuff like ffts uh fair
filters d embeds and so on are pretty
numerically intensive and so the more of
those you use the slower you're going to
be
and now we're going to get on to just a
quick look at actual capabilities of
software what kinds of things we can do
with it
so uh here's just a quick list of some
of the math and dsp functions again i'm
not going to go into detail on all this
because we can show more during the demo
uh we've got all your typical classic
embedded protocols so uh you know one
wire can i squared c etc uh we also do
have uh milstead 1553. uh eric 429 is
not supported yet we've got test data
for it there's an open tickets that's
going to be coming soon
we also have and this is a little bit
more unique uh it decodes for jtag swd
and a arm mem ap over swda so you can
see in this screenshot here for example
we're looking at an st link connected to
an stm32 and we're looking at the actual
ad virtual or the physical addresses
that it's reading and writing and so
where this comes from really handy is if
you've got some kind of proprietary
debug dongle and you want to understand
the memory map of a target device or you
want to understand you know what
registers to say for example maybe it's
not on our device maybe it's some weird
proprietary
custom cpu or something like that you
want to really understand how the vendor
debug tools work in order to maybe see
if you can bypass code protection or
something like that
and then another one that uh is much
more commonly seen in the security space
is uh memory protocols so
ddr1 ddr3 i don't have ddr2 or iv yet
those are coming uh i scored ce proms sd
cards five flashes and so we do have a
full product analyzer which i'll get to
more of in the demo so i use this all
the time at work analyzing secure boot
implications being able to look at the
whole list of addresses that a device is
reading see what data it's reading
identify any addresses that are read
more than once and it's it's great for
finding talk to bugs or determining for
example correlations between memory
patterns and maybe looking at power
traces and trying to find where in a
power trace is your signature check or
your firmware decryption or something
like that
we definitely have a lot of stuff
focused more on high-speed serial
there is a clock recovery pll right now
it's just a fairly basic bang bang
control loop i am looking at
implementing golden plls from various
standards so fibre channel sata pcie and
so on in order to be able to actually do
protocol compliance testing so that's
definitely coming down the pipe soon uh
ten being sixty four sixty six
implemented uh 128 130 64 67 are
definitely going to come soon as well
just haven't gotten around to it yet
uh we've also got some nice features for
power analysis and rf so there's a
digital down converter so you can take
in a directly sampled rf signal and get
out iq waveforms from it uh ffts fur
filters
another one that i find really nice is
being able to plot either phasor
frequency against time so you can
directly demodulate say phase shift
keying or c
uh a spread spectrum modulated clock and
so on and then all the usual spectrogram
waterfall et cetera
um
i do a lot of work in open source
networking hardware in my spare time one
of my fun projects has been designing an
open hardware ethernet switch on an fpga
and so i've added a lot of networking
protocol decodes so everything from 10
base t up to 10 gig ethernet auto
negotiation mdio and so on
um
these also off the ethernet protocol
decodes also support outputting to
wireshark over a pipe so you can
actually live stream your decoded
packets off the scope to wireshark and
do upper layer protocol decodes as well
so that's handy if you're trying to for
example find malformed packets going
through a piece of say tcp offload
engine or something like that
we also have the beginnings of some
mobile interface support right now only
mippy defy and dsi we can do full frame
grab off of a dsi waveform as you can
see here we've got both the hex dump of
the packet at the right and then the
actual decoded scan lines in the product
analyzer
maybe csi and some of the other mipi
phis are definitely going to be coming
it's just a matter of getting hold of
copies of both specs and uh sample
waveforms trying to find devices that
speak some of these more obscure
protocols can be a little bit tricky at
times
uh then more on the higher speed stuff
we're beginning to see more pc hardware
showing up in uh the lab at work and so
i've been doing some pcie analysis uh
also we've got dvi right now our
displayport and hdmi are on the to-do
list uh pcie gen one and two were
implemented already gen three and four
are pending as soon as i can get hold of
some hardware to actually look at uh
we've got
full high and low speed usb again usb
super speed is not uploaded yet but it's
coming soon and then intel espy so if
you're doing any bmc or ec security work
that's a nice one to have being able to
actually look at what's going on between
the pch and the bmc and so on
uh and then more on the signal integrity
side we've got some basic equalization i
don't have dfe yet just ctle so far but
that's coming uh channel emulation and
de-embedding so we can take a set of s
parameters and look at a waveform and
see what this waveform would look like
through an arbitrary channel even
simulated or measured off of vna uh you
can do the same thing in reverse if
you've got a signal recorded on some
kind of a test fixture you can de-embed
the cables or the fixture from your
waveform and get a clean signal as if it
would look at the balls of your target
chip
then emphasis insertion removal eye
patterns bathtub curves some basic
jitter decomposition so you can go look
at say
jitter spectrum of just your
periodic jitter or something like that
we also have some single generation
features i use these for channel design
work a lot so you can generate a prbs
you can then convert that prbs to nrz or
pam4 you can then apply channel
emulation or inserting noise into that
and then get a nice view of what a data
stream would look like through a channel
from again say you're running an em
simulator on board layout and you wanna
see what an eye pattern through that is
gonna look like at say 10 gigs nrz or 56
gigs pam4 and so on
now let's just look at a few other
features before we get on to demo uh the
protocol analyzer i did touch on briefly
so it's more of a tabular display of
packets rather than the time domain
timeline view um it is synchronized with
the timeline bidirectionally so if you
click on a packet it will then jump the
timeline to that spot and show you where
the beginning of that packet is in the
time domain view you can do the same
thing in reverse if you drag a
uh cursor around in the time domain view
it'll highlight a row in the product
catalyzer uh you can also do filtering
again kind of like how wireshark does it
so you can search for
any uh
sd commands that are just command 16 or
anything with an lba starting with 314
or something like that
another feature that is particularly
unique is the ability to synchronize
multiple instruments and uh we might see
some of this during the demo i don't
have anything set up live but i've got
some recorded data that got used this so
you can take arbitrarily many
instruments with a common time base and
just cable a common reference clock to
them cable a common trigger to them
and uh combine them and have them behave
like one instrument and the calibration
to correct for trigger skew is super
simple it's basically just touching a
probe from the primary instrument at
each secondary one at a time to a common
reference point it'll do a
cross-correlation and determine what the
delay of your trigger cable is and
calibrate that out
and there's actually uh you just look up
my name on youtube there's a demo about
uh maybe six months ago of a tech mso6
and a lacroix wafer under 8000 series
looking at a gigabit ethernet signal and
towards the end i actually put
one leg of a differential pair into the
attack and one leg into the lacroix
sampling at different rates uh the
lacroix is at 40 gig and the attack was
at 25 gig
and i resample them subtract them do
protocol decode and an eye pattern with
one leg of the differential pair into
each scope
so you can get surprisingly good
synchronization surprisingly low jitter
app i mean i wouldn't use it for
protocol compliance testing but
certainly for decoding an analysis it's
it's more than good enough for most
purposes and so you can do this with
pretty much any supported scopes they do
not have to be the same
and finally before we get to the demo
if you're interested in playing with the
software more or getting involved uh
here's the link to the repository uh the
irc channel uh the discord and the irc
are bridged so uh you can hop in one or
the other and uh talk to everybody
involved
and before we get into the demo also uh
just want to acknowledge uh support from
industry uh we've received development
scopes uh technical support etc from
pico digilen and siglin they've been
very helpful uh we've had some dealings
with uh rigel and tech as well um they
haven't actually contributed any
hardware yet
and so again if you're involved with an
instrument vendor we welcome hardware we
welcome code contributions and we would
love to work with uh instrument vendors
more closely in order to make a better
tool for everyone
and uh thanks to all of the contributors
to the project at this point i think we
just
last week i think we broke 30 people had
contributed codes so uh thanks to all of
you for helping make the project get to
where it is now
and before we get into the demo i will
take questions
so uh andrew i will read it out for you
uh do you have any do you have plans to
create or integrate with open hardware
oscilloscopes in the future
uh yes i do i've got several different
open hardware platforms under
development uh none of them are anywhere
near ready to release yet i've been more
looking again at the mid-range to
high-end because my thought being
it's not going to be practical to be
cost competitive with anything coming
from say right or something like that
because just they make stuff in such
huge volume it's an open source product
in that range it's going to be difficult
to sustain so i've been looking more at
the mid-range to high-end so starting at
say 500 megahertz better than going up
to a couple of gigahertz so yeah i've
got uh designs in progress i've actually
got a full prototype of a 500 megahertz
analog front end sitting on a board in
my lab now
and i kind of put that on hold because
the state of the art and open source
probing was awful and then i spent a
good chunk of last year working on a
open source six gigahertz passive probe
and uh now i'm working on an open source
six gigahertz active differential probe
and so once we get some of that up down
then uh probably moving back to the
scope hardware side of things but yeah
that certainly uh open hardware scopes
are definitely coming down the pipeline
eventually i'm also trying to work with
vendors to be a bit more open source
friendly on the tooling side
again especially pico has been very
friendly to the project and uh
i'm hoping i can get this to kind of
become a more broader industry trend of
instrument vendors being more friendly
to open source tooling for their scopes
and potentially even running open source
code on the scope itself
any other questions
i don't see any more questions but i see
comments that found peter and trevor
that they both prefer picoscope so yeah
thank you guys
uh if there are any questions from the
audience please send them across by the
chat uh we will answer them uh sometime
in the future uh but i think now andrew
you could continue with the demo and
okay perfect
all right so uh just before we actually
get into it i here's just a quick photo
of the lab set up we've got so it's a uh
raspberry pi i believe the latest
generation with pcie and uh so we've got
one probe over here which you can't
really see in this view is on the pcie
clock line and then we've got a
differential probe across one of the
pcie data lines
and
so without further ado
uh what we're looking at now this is a
live feed from picoscope 6824e
looking at the pcie clock and so from
this view it pretty much just looks like
a sine wave or a slightly rounded square
wave you can't see too much detail and
uh zooming out a bit uh you can see
we've got a fair bit of a day right now
it's 200 microseconds we're still
getting 15 waveforms per second so again
the streaming performance of the
picoscope is way better than anything
else that i've used
um so if you want to see a little bit
more detail we can go take a look at an
fft and uh nothing really too exciting
we can see we've got our 100 megahertz
fundamentals got all of the harmonics
and then we got an interleaving spirit
1.25 gigahertz and there's probably one
at 2.5 as well uh yep there's a little
bit of a smart 2.5 gig as well again
because uh we're looking at interleaved
1.25 gigahertz now if we
jump back to
and apparently i did temp the demo
guards a little too much it decided to
take fault on me so be right back
this is what happens when you do live
demos
so now you get to go watch me set it up
so we're going to just set our coupling
to 50 ohms we're using a
10x
probe and we're going to be running at
10 bit resolution and then we can just
zoom in a little bit more and we've got
our waveform back and we're going to
bump up to 5 giga samples per second and
we're back where we were
so you can see it's very quick to go set
things up um
now so if we go to rf and want to take a
look at a spectrogram of the signal we
can go adjust
say well we'll keep a blackman harris
window and we'll do say minus 100 dbm as
the low end and we'll go up to maybe 8k
points
and
play with our color ramp a little bit to
get something a little easier to see and
so again we can see nice straight lines
at all of our harmonics and we've got
our 100 megahertz fundamental showing
through very clearly but what you are
not seeing in this case
is the fact that this is actually a
spread spectrum clock and the modulation
doesn't really show up yes maybe a
little bit of waviness showing up there
but it's kind of hard to see in the
spectrogram and so we can do instead is
we can go to the measurement menu select
frequency and graph and now we've got a
graph of instantaneous frequency across
time of the waveform and it's bouncing
around a little bit because we got some
noise and so we can do is just do a
moving average we're going to do say
samples
and delete that and so if i just pause
so it's a little easier to see so now we
can see the frequency of the pcie
reference clock versus time and go to a
cursor we can go and measure our
frequency of this and so we're looking
at a modulation of about 31 32 kilohertz
frequency
and
with a depth
of
about
400-ish kilohertz in difference in
frequency between our min and max and so
again we can also just do a single
horizontal person so we can see we've
got basically about 100 megahertz at the
peak and then it dips down to about 99.5
megahertz and so this is this is fairly
common with pcia because it's used to
reduce emi by spreading out peaks rather
than having a single strong spectral
line at any one frequency
and so this is an example of where high
streaming throughput is really handy
because you can do really long captures
in this case we're looking at a million
points let's see if we can buff up more
let's do 20 million points
and so here let's zoom out a little bit
more
and so now we're getting about three
waveforms per second streaming 20
million points and again looking at the
spread spectrum modulation over time so
having deep memory and good stream
performance is really nice for that um
unfortunately sometimes that's not
enough and you just want raw bandwidth
to look at higher speed stuff so now
we're going to jump to another scope my
bench this is a
crashed again lovely
like i said we haven't released it yet
this is still a work in progress
all right so now we're connected to a
lacroix sda 816 a 16 gigahertz serial
data analyzer on the other side of my
bench and we're looking at the output of
that differential probe across the pcie
signals so zooming in a bit we can see
details of the individual waveforms uh
we can go do a bit of quick signal
target analysis before we look at
anything else so we can pull a recovery
clock off here this is pcie gen2 so it
is nominally five gigahertz
and
we can do
an eye pattern of that we'll just do
that in the recovered clock and there's
our eye pattern we can change our color
amp a little bit i like this one and so
we can see there's a little bit of
overshoot a little bit of uh ringing
there is emphasis on the line so that's
not too surprising but the eye is pretty
open
uh we're not interested in signal
integrity today we're doing more reverse
engineering focus and so let's see if we
can actually get some data off of this
so we're going to threshold our analog
waveform to get a digital waveform and
then we can decode the 8b 10b coding
and so if we just pause for a second and
zoom in on some of the spots we can look
at the raw 8b10b characters over the
launch so we can see we got a burst of
control characters and we got some data
but nothing really too interesting at
this layer
so then we can go to pcie and
decode that so now we can see we got a
skip we got a bunch of logical idles uh
and then there's okay so we got a little
bit of traffic over here
so we got a data link layer packet we
got a little bit of traffic and again
we're just looking at hexd codes right
now so we can decode that up one more
layer and look at the data link
and we can also
decode all the way up to the tlp layer
but there's no tlps in this particular
waveform so there's nothing to see yet
and so again we're looking at the pcie
going to the usb controller on the pi
and so if we wanted to see a little bit
more i'm just going to start a webcam
that is plugged into
that um
usb port and we should start seeing some
more traffic so i'm just going to open i
believe it's dev video 0 on the pi
and i've now got video showing up on my
vlc session
so we can see here this is a live feed
from the webcam sitting on the bench
and now we can start up our scope and
start seeing some more traffic
oh lovely crushing me again
so we got that and we're just going to
pull up our data link layer we got a lot
more traffic now i'm just going to pause
so it stops flashing so much and we can
go to
we can go to our tlp layer all right
here we go so now we caught a tlp so
we can zoom out a little bit and just
use the product analyzer to navigate so
if we want to see a memrite tlp we can
zoom in all the way here we've got our
sequence number bem right traffic class
zero no flags length of four coming from
device zero because it's the only other
thing on the pcie there's no bridging on
the pi
uh we've got our list of bytes our
virtual address and then the four bytes
actually being written and then we can
go back to the data link layer and we
can see mostly flow control packets
we've got um there's a tlp in here here
okay so we got another tlp here
and same thing
so we've got the raw data coming through
and then we can go and look down to the
data link layer we can see the sequence
number we can see if we go to the end
we've got the crc then we've got flow
control updates and so on
so it's not going to replace a full pcie
product analyzer but if you got a fast
scope and you want to look at the
capture it is nice to be able to do this
level of decoding
so uh that's it for the live portion of
the demo now we're going to start
looking at some of the pre-recorded
material and so if any of you have
pulled the uh test data repository you
can follow along with that
uh does anybody have a request for a
specific protocol they want to see from
the test data repo i was thinking we
could start with either sd card or spy
flash
there is a request for jtag or can
okay uh we do have a fairly small can
traffic example here
so uh this was taken on the hdmi 204 you
can see we've got a couple of fairly
small frames it's just uh one byte of
data in them it looks or actually not
even uh so these are just empty frames
it looks um and then here we got a nice
extended frame with an id and we got
three bytes of data so ecfvo
again not too much to look at
unfortunately most of the can waveforms
i have with actually interesting data
are from client hardware and i can't
show and so this is one of the few that
was just some blank test data
i don't actually think i have a jtag
demo waveform handy i do have
an swd one
so if we go to embedded we've got swd
and so what we're looking at now this is
just kind of the ongoing idle of an st
link looking at an stm32 and i think
it's pulling to see whether the cpu is
halted if i remember correctly and so we
can scroll in all the way here and we
can see actual access to specific swd
registers with the individual bus
turnarounds and so on and then zooming
out looking at the next layer we've got
accesses to the map and then in the
protocolizer we've got
more of again kind of a high level
overview of what's going on and so if we
wanted to filter this we could search
for say
that and
okay i might have mistyped something
um
let's
oh i missed a zero
okay so our address was e000208
and so now we've filtered out just
access to there and we can do the same
thing for looking at uh say um
data beginning with four eight now i've
got our one packet where data starts
with four a
uh so now uh i was gonna jump to either
sd card or spyflash unless anybody has
requests for anything else
uh andrew there are two questions let me
read them out for you yep
can i integrate celia logic analyzer uh
analog signal with a gl scope plan so uh
clay support is on the wish list uh the
big challenge with them compared to most
other scopes is that
they have basically a very minimal stub
running on them and require a firmware
load in order to do anything
and there is at least for the usb 3
based ones i don't think there is an
open source firmware available for them
yet and so being able to use it is going
to require that you have the celia
software installed on your machine and
specify a path to that software so that
we can load the firmware from their side
since it's copyrighted by sale and we
can't distribute it
um so that's most likely going to be the
most viable option for getting support
the other thing is on feel for the older
usb 2 based ones with the fx2 uh fx2
logic analyzer firmware from sig rock
should be usable uh that's already an
open ticket just haven't gotten around
to it yet um
for the usb 3 celia's again assuming we
are using the official firmware we would
need to reverse engineer their usb
protocol because the best of my
knowledge is not documented and so again
it would be great to have if somebody
wants to go put the time into it that's
just a matter of
limited resources not enough developers
too many scopes to support so
definitely if anybody wants to put in
the time would love it
another question
maybe daniel uh can support you in
future uh i move move to the next
question andrew can you unwrap
manchester encoded ask rf packets
um there is not currently a raw
manchester decode we have an
implementation of manchester in use for
ken base tea
the challenge is that manchester is kind
of it's not enough to really be a
protocol by itself because it doesn't
have any uh start stop or upper level
framing or bite sync or anything like
that and so it's it's a little bit
challenging to decode just from
manchester because there's so many
different ways it's been implemented so
for example the synchronization in a lot
of cases is by either a um
analog uh differential zero or by a
squelch
or by a pulse that's too long or too
short and otherwise there's a protocol
violation and so every protocol we've
looked at that influence manchester does
it a slightly different way and so i
think at this point there's two or three
different manchester implementations in
libisco pal each for a specific upper
layer protocol and we haven't really
figured out a good way to abstract that
away to something generic so again if i
would love to have a generic manchester
decode it's just challenging because
there's so many different ways it's been
done
was that the last question
that was the last question all right so
now let's uh go look a little bit more
at some larger stuff uh
we can do
let's look at some spy flash
and so what we're looking at now this is
the uh i believe this is the boot
process of a uh digital zybo so it's a
dev board with a uh
xylen zinc seven fpga arm sock and so
looks like we've pretty much all got
reads and so this is an example of uh
where the flash product analyzer is
really handy compared to just using a
vanilla spidey code because it
understands both spy and quad spy and it
can understand from context whether
you're in x1 mode or x4 mode and then
correctly decode things accordingly and
so you can see again we can go all the
way down to the individual reads and
look at the addresses and the bytes on
the wire or we can jump up to the
protocols or view we can go find say
the first large read where it starts
reading bulk data you can then switch to
cursors and measure the delay from that
read to this read and determine say
maybe there's an area in there that's of
interest for power analysis
i have some really nice data sets that
unfortunately again i can't share
because they're client related
in which i have a full trace of a spy
flash during secure boot of a embedded
device as well as a power trace from a
power rail probe looking at activity on
there
and it's just beautiful how you can see
the spy bus activity and then suddenly
start seeing a bunch of new spectra
lines in the spectrogram showing up
where the uh
check summing and hashing and then the
aes decryption happens and it's it's
really nice to be able to go through and
see all that time correlated again
unfortunately i just wasn't able to come
up with any uh shareable examples of
that
and uh the flash decoders if we pull up
examples of here so uh we do have the
ability to dump raw flash traffic as
well
um and you can select different types of
flash you can do three byte address four
byte address or uh the winbond w25n is
actually nand flash that uses a mostly
compatible command set uh conventional
zx5 it's a little bit different and so
we needed to implement that as a
separate type
ah let's see what are some other nice
things that we can demonstrate
there was one more question from ben
can we import logic capture to use
decoders without a scope
uh yes so uh
waveforms can be imported from uh i
mentioned in the slides um agilent
keysight and rygall um binary files
um wav files vcds and csvs are the
supported formats right now um also i i
didn't mention the slides uh it can also
support uh importing raw iq files from
something like new radio so if you just
got iq iq in float 32 or in date format
or something you can import that too um
i'm also talking with some of the new
radio folks about better interoperation
between uh just go client and canoe
radio in both directions so being able
to use a scope as a direct rf sampling
receiver or being able to do upper level
protocol analysis and just go applying
after you've demodulated something radio
um
so interrupt there is coming as well but
yeah there there is uh support for
offline analysis all these data files
i'm working at are in the scope how test
data repo so anybody who wants can go
pull these files and play around with
them and look at them uh the native file
format is the most full feature because
it supports all the user interface
configuration and so on as well uh but
certainly again we can import from a
bunch of other formats
you can get pretty much anything as a
raw csv so just first column is time
stamps in seconds and then after there
is voltage values
there is another comment question uh
from peter
any support for automation scripting or
plugins
um yes so there is support for uh
plugins in jessica client that are
generally registering new decodes new
instrument drivers and so on uh the ui
itself is not currently scriptable uh
the current model is built around the
api itself being the primary interface
for working with things so if you're
doing offline testing or so on you're
typically going to be building some kind
of a complicated test setup that's maybe
even interfacing with other hardware and
so you'll just be calling methods in
libscope pal and directly calling uh
functions on the scope in order to be
able to configure things or working
directly with decode objects uh there
has been talk of setting up some kind of
a python binder something for scripting
of the ui uh that might be coming later
on but uh certainly not in 0.1 or any of
the immediate releases uh the focus
again has been more on supporting
plug-ins for features for new decodes
and new instruments
any other questions before i continue no
peter just says thank you okay
all right so now let's take a look uh
here's some pcie
so what we're looking at here this is
actually quite interesting so this is a
test waveform of a pcie network card and
so
we're looking at traffic flowing from
the host pc to uh this is an intel one
gigabit nic so we're looking at the tlps
coming out sending the packet and then
the actual ethernet frame coming at us
we're looking at the delays we've got
300 nanoseconds of delay from the end of
the frame being sent over pcie until the
frame starts going out over the wire
so we can zoom in here on the tlp and we
can start seeing some actual traffic uh
this looks like still a part of it um
okay here we go so we're looking at um
let's say
four or five so do we actually have vip
header visibility okay here we go
uh okay
so
so yeah we're looking at the actual
contents of the uh frame going out in
the um
pcie layer here so we're looking at we
got
4500 so this is the ipv4 header we got
ipv4 five words header and then going
out we got our contents um we got some
addressing information somewhere in here
and then we start seeing the payload of
a linux ping packet so 1.0112 etc um
then at the end of that it looks like
the remainder was sent in a second tlp
that probably actually sends the frame
maybe has a crc in it
and then moving forward in time again a
little bit more we start seeing the
actual frame going out on the wire so we
got our preamble we got our destination
and source addresses we got our type and
then we start seeing actual ipv4 framing
going out over to wire ip source test
and then we start seeing our payload
here
and then we can look at this again in
the product analyzer view we can see the
raw packets in the plp analyzer and then
we can jump up to the ethernet product
analyzer and see that as well
and then you can start even lining up
between the different packets so we can
see this was at um
and so we got 45054
and then okay so there's our sequence
number i think maybe um
three nine okay so yep we're looking at
that one i think and so we can see the
actual contents of the pcie tlp are
being spit out here you can figure out
where the headers are for the uh traffic
that the network card is looking at
uh the let's see what are some other
nice uh examples uh sd card is another
good one that i've used a fair bit
so we've got sd command and data bus
viewed separately
we can see on the command bus where it
first starts initializing the card
there's a bunch of polling so the
protocol analyzer actually lets you
collapse packets that are related so in
this case for example um
if we're polling for a bunch of stuff to
happen um like here you can see there's
a whole bunch of polling where it starts
checking waiting to say the card still
says busy and so it just keeps on
polling
but all of this gets collapsed into a
single transaction in the view and so
you can just skip over all that if you
just want to know that sends opcon then
we do all send card id and so you can
see it
since the card id there's no data going
out then we've got the reply to the sim
card id so that's the serial number for
the card that we're looking at right now
all right
anybody want to see any other particular
examples or
more questions about the std code
i don't see any more questions but uh
andrew just heads up that we are almost
nearing time so yeah all right perfect
all right if we want to wrap up now then
let's do that
i mean uh if you still have stuff to
show you can but
i mean i can keep on going for hours
it's more question of what the audience
wants to see
audience should be uh
okay so he has a question let him type a
question
do we see this level of performance on
pcie consistently
um
so could you clarify you mean level of
performance
so heat would you like to rephrase it
explain a little bit more
[Music]
regarding the tlvs
i'm still not quite clear what he's
asking about
in terms of throughput how fast it
decodes them or
okay uh until then uh we'll take the
next question from nicolas
what scope do you use to capture this
data again
uh so it's all in the title bar up top
you can see the info so the sd card data
set right now i'm looking at is from a
la crosse waverunner 8000 series um the
pcie uh that i was just looking at is an
sd86 if we go back to the live view on
that so now we're looking at live feed
from the sda 816
in my lab at home right now i've got the
uh sdi 816 i've got a uh waiver
oh sorry not for you
uh so i've got a uh lacroix waverunner
8000 series 4 gigahertz the lacroix sda
uh
16 gigahertz then a 500 megahertz
picoscope 6824 uh uh digital and alloy
discovery pro uh then the baseline
analog discovery
and so just as a quick uh demo well
we're waiting for the last question i'm
just going to go pull up a channel
emulation example here
so we can do an eye pattern of our pcie
right now
and look at it there and now we can go
do a
ah the horizontal lines by the way uh
that's caused by limited a to d
resolution on the scope so our image is
taller than the number of unique voltage
values applying pretty much any kind of
filter to it usually rounds that off and
you'll see that in the next example
so we can do channel emulation
and
um let's go look at say
um we'll do through a fairly nice line
uh like through this rosenberger through
line so just specified our s parameters
we're going to look at s21 of our signal
through there
and we're going to recover another clock
from that we can do that and then pull
up an eye pattern of there
and so here is the
same signal through that emulated
channel
and did i specify the wrong clock
okay yeah sorry about that uh so i
recovered the clock before the channel
emulation so we got a phase shift
so we just clear and do that okay that's
aligned properly and so we can see it
looks pretty much almost the same uh
through this channel just a little bit
weaker because of loss but if we then
pick a less nice channel
let's see what it would look like
through
let's say this not quite perfectly
impedance matched launched on a samtech
sma
and so it's a little bit less pretty
there
we can then pick something even worse
let's say
let's say one of uh my
open hardware probes
that uh
is only measured to six gigahertz so
we're going to have a brick wall cut off
from the um
frequency response at six gigahertz
we're also going to see attenuation
because this is a 10x probe and so we
can see through this probe it's a lot
more rounded off because our measurement
is only going to six gigahertz and i
mean that's a 3d bandwidth of the pro
but the vna also stops at six gigahertz
and so we're not seeing a lot of the
nuance in the signal here
and again it's uh weakened by about a
factor of 10 because we're looking at a
signal through a 10x probe
all right uh did we have another
question before we wrap up
yeah there are a couple of questions but
i think i'll just take two more and then
we'll skip the rest um so the question
is from
uh
andrei
have have you a flex rate decoder there
with you
uh no i do not currently have a
flexibility code it is on the to-do list
uh the limiting factor has been accessed
to waveforms i don't have any flex-ray
signals i can write the decode with so
if anybody wants to comment on the
ticket on github with a recording of
some flex drive waveforms that will
definitely help
all right uh i'm just reading out some
of the questions uh but you know let's i
will not suggest you to take that one uh
a question would be well there was one
if they could you could show an example
on bluetooth but uh that would be for
later
zahees question is uh
the previous question that he had uh is
do we see consistent throughout opcie
uh three went throughput
oh um so
i actually haven't used a scope that
attaches over pcie uh exactly uh the
lacroix scopes use pcie internally to
connect the uh capture card to the
internal pc however the interface from
that to geoscope client is via ethernet
so that's the bottleneck
um i believe some of the higher end uh
libraries do have an option i forget
what it's called um
that has a pcie x1 link from the scope
to the host pc i don't currently have
that uh interface so yeah right now the
highest bandwidth interface i use jenny
scope has been usb3
all right
uh i take the last question that's from
jan william
uh
he's curious
about your example of spi and em
measurements in secure booth do you
expect it to be full demo on a public
implementation
it would be very useful to demonstrate
the full power of the tool
um
i would like to make such a demo it's
just a matter of again time and
availability of hardware i don't
currently have anything that does any
kind of secure booth that isn't client
related sitting around um so uh what i
actually had i've been thinking about
doing this morning with just getting a
normal not secure boot uh implementation
uh just from say uh
one of the fpga dev boards i have and
just noting the internal power
activities as it boots but uh yeah it's
not as interesting as something is
actually doing false secure but i just i
don't have anything handy that isn't the
nda so
all right andrew i think uh we've had
more than almost 10 questions for you
today so thank you so much for sharing
your research and tool with us and uh
helping grow the community and various
uh
tool vendors that you've been working to
create thank you so much again
all right and uh again if anyone is
interested in uh playing with it more uh
the links are in the presentation uh i
will be tweeting a link to the slides
shortly and so if anybody wants to uh
get involved in the project definitely
get in touch
all right and uh andrew is also there on
the discord server so if you still have
questions
regarding the setup you can
talk to him if you would like to
contribute to his project please feel
free to reach out to him as well it
would be great help
all right
thank you so much
[Applause]
[Music]