yeah so maybe let's continue with the
second part of this session
um
the next paper is
super puck
dishonest majority NPC with constant
online communication
so the this is a work by Daniel escudero
vipul goyal Antigone politics
but none of them have come so then we
have a guest star
Peter Scholl who will present the the
paper
thanks very much for the introduction
so yeah unfortunately none of the
authors of the paper could make it to
the conference so I'm presenting this
instead
so Super PAC is on a secure multi-party
computation protocol where we have a set
of parties who want to securely evaluate
some function on their private inputs
and the specific NPC setting in this
talk is secure computation of arithmetic
circuits over some finite field
and it's in the dishonest majority
setting
so we have a constant fraction of the
parties who may be corrupted so there's
some parameter Epsilon Which is less
than half and we assume that at least
Epsilon n parties will be honest in the
protocol
and the goal is to achieve malicious
security with abort
and the main result in this work is a
new protocol in this setting where the
total communication cost is a constant
number of field elements per
multiplication gate across all of the
parties
and the constant in this work are pretty
good it's it's quite practical and
focused on being something you can
implement
and the nice feature about this constant
communication cost is that if you fix
the number of parties in and imagine the
you know as the number of honest parties
in this protocol increases as Epsilon
increases then the communication cost
actually decreases proportional to 1
over Epsilon
and the protocols divided into these
three phases the online phase and two
pre-processing phases where the first
pre-processing phase is independent of
both the inputs to the computation and
the circuit being evaluated but this one
has linear costs in the number of
parties whereas the second
pre-processing which only depends on the
circuit has again constant communication
like the online phase
okay so in this dishonest majority
setting of MPC I guess most protocols
tend to focus on the harder case of n
minus one out of n Corruptions uh but
this also tends to be less efficient
um so this is things like the speech
protocol and in this case if you want to
adapt these protocols to the less than
full threshold setting and then it seems
like the best thing you can do is just
to remove n minus t minus one parties
and run the protocol among the remaining
t plus one parties
but if you want to do better than that
perhaps the most relevant work is this
GPS 22 paper from last year which also
gets a constant total communication per
multiplication guide but with much worse
constants so it's something that's not
quite so practical
one of the relevant line of work is
there's tiny keys protocol in a similar
setting but for Boolean circuits but
they're the focus of optimization is
more on the pre-processing protocol and
the online phase still has linear
communication
and finally there's another paper last
year called turbo pack which is in the
honest majority setting but also has
constant communication in the online
phase and uses similar techniques
uh so the most relevant work to compare
with
um out of all of these is the one of the
latest incarnations of the speech
protocol called turbo speeds and so here
you can see how that compares with Super
PAC
and notice that for Turbo speeds each of
the three phases have linear
communication in the number of parties
whereas Super PAC has this constant for
the online and circuit dependent phases
and in the circuit independent phase is
pretty similar to how turbo speeds looks
roughly 6n multiplication field elements
per multiplication
so you can see this a little more in
detail on these graphs so here in the
graph on the left you can fix a
particular Epsilon for instance if you
have 10 of the parties being honest
and then you can see that if you have an
NPC protocol with at least n is 34
parties in total then Super PAC will be
will outperform the best previous speeds
protocol for all values then larger than
this and for another data point if you
increase the number of honest parties to
30 then you only need 15 parties before
superpac starts becoming worthwhile
compared with other protocols
and likewise you can look at the graph
on the right where you fix the number of
parties for instance to 32 and then you
know look at what's the smallest Epsilon
you can get away with such that this
protocol is worthwhile and in this case
it's uh 26 percent
and so that those graphs were for the
online phase if you look at the
pre-processing phases then it's a bit
different because here both of the
protocols have linear communication cost
reflected by the straight lines and the
graphs
um but the thing to look at is so the
the blue lines here a Super Pac and
notice that they're often a little bit
worse than the communication costs for
Turbo speeds but not by a huge amount in
effect sometimes a little better when
the number of parties is very large so
you're not paying a huge cost in the
pre-processing to get this benefit of a
constant Communication online phase
the authors also implemented most parts
of the protocol and Ransom benchmarks
which you can see in this table so the
bottom two rows of the table are just
the theoretical communication costs
measured in terms of the Improvement
Factor compared with turbo speeds and so
here you can see that it has in practice
around two to six times less
communication than turbo speeds for say
32 or 80 parties
and then of course the question is how
does this translate into a real world
performance improvements for the
implementation
and if you first look at a high
bandwidth network setting it's not so
great it's sometimes a little bit slower
than Super Pac and then turbo speeds
sometimes a little bit faster that as
you restrict the bandwidth to um to
lower bandwidth settings say 100
megabits or 10 megabits then you start
to get much better performance
improvements compared with turbo speeds
so here in the 10 megabit setting you
have around two to six times Improvement
which pretty much much reflects what
you'd expect from the theoretical
communication costs showing that here
communication is really the bottleneck
okay so for the rest of the talk I want
to give an overview of the main ideas in
the protocol
um so Super PAC is based on packed
secret sharing which is a variant of
Shamir secret sharing where instead of
secret sharing a single field element at
once will share a vector of K field
elements V1 up to VK
and we'll do this by sampling a
polynomial of degree D and in practice
the protocol uses different values of D
at different places so this is a
parameter and it does this based on some
evaluation points first K evaluation
points alpha 1 to Alpha k uh which which
are used to encode the messages being
shared VI as uh at the polynomial
and then the polymerase sample to be to
be of degree D random apart from these
evaluations
and then to define the shares you do
exactly as you do in Shamir sharing
where you define a n evaluation points
beta 1 to Beta n and give to party I the
value F of beta I
and the nice thing about this packed
Shamir SQL sharing scheme is that even
though your secret sharing a vector of
up to K field elements the size of each
party's share is just a single field
element
so then in the protocol
um the online phase has an invariant
which is maintained throughout the
circuit evaluation
which is that at each wire say a y
indexed by some some index Alpha uh if
this wire has a the plain text value V
which is the actual value of the
computation at this point of the circuit
then we associate with this wire a
special random Mass called Lambda
which is not known to any parties and
will in fact be secret shared in some
flavor of packed ticket sharing
and we use this to define
a masking of the plain text value v as
Mu which is V minus Lambda so this could
be given out in public look for
efficiency mu is just given to party P1
and note that at this point for each
wire
the plain tag value V is entirely
determined by mu and Lambda
okay so given this setup and the idea
that we're using practical chairing the
main challenge in any MPC protocol where
you want to exploit pack to good sharing
is that okay you naturally will want to
evaluate say k multiplication gates in
parallel unpacked secret shares but then
as you go through the circuit from one
layer to the next you often need to
reorder these elements of packed secret
sharings to match the wiring of the
circuit which name which you know unless
you're doing a pure simdi circuit will
require some kind of routing or
permutation protocol and that's kind of
the traditional approach to doing this
with many older works
but the the nice idea of this this
protocol is to follow some methods from
the turbo pack protocol in the honest
majority setting which gives you a way
to maintain this wiring consistency with
very little overhead and without having
to do any complex permutation Networks
um so to do this we'll rely on this
circuit dependent pre-processing phase
which will set up special sharings of
the Lambda masks across the circuit
and so you divide each layer of the
circuit into a batches of K
multiplication Gates
which will be evaluated in parallel and
then you take the batch of say left
input wires and right input wires for
each of these batch of multiplication
Gates and then prepare them using packed
SQL sharing so you take the vector of
lambdas and distribute pack chairs to
the parties for this random Lambda
values
so this requires a bit of interaction
and then in the online phase when you
have this setup
you evaluate these gates in the same
batch of K gates at once
and by exploiting the fact that
according to this invariant we defined
P1 will always know these mu values in
the clear
for every wire Alpha then it can just
kind of collect the right set of new
values which are needed for this set of
wires and use these to help with the
multiplication protocol without any any
fancy routing process
um so going into this in a bit more
detail
um so if we have a batch of K
multiplication Gates
with inputs um that wires Alpha and beta
we have these corresponding
Mast values mu for Mu Alpha and mu beta
which are known to party P1
and in the first part of the protocol
for the multiplication gate P1 will take
these and distribute fresh Shamir
sharings or pack Shamir sharings of
degree K minus 1 to the other parties
so note that this is a this is the pack
chimney sharing of K elements of degree
K minus one so there's actually no
Randomness in this polynomial but it
doesn't really matter because these new
values are public anyway
so the the idea of the Shamir sharing
here is just to kind of optimize the
communication
um
and then from the invariant for the
input wise of the multiplications and
also from the pre-processing we have
these Lambda values all secret shared
with packed sharings so the Lambda
Alphas the Lambda betas which will be of
degree n minus K and then the Lambda
Gamma which will be a degree n minus one
and then also their special value
Capital gamma which is the product of
the input lambdas which will be computed
in the pre-processing using some packed
multiplication triple
and given all of these shared values
um you can see that the parties can
actually just take an appropriate
combination of these by doing some local
multiplications and summing them up and
they will end up with a packed sharing
of degree n minus 1 of the right Vector
of the MU values for the output wire
once all the parties have this they can
just reconstruct it to P1 who will learn
the MU value and then maintain the
required invariant
so this is the this is a kind of
simplified version of the basic protocol
which is at this point only passively
secure
there's one more change that is made in
the final protocol
which is an optimization to reduce
communication that this this interaction
in the basic multiplication protocol is
combined with the interaction in the
pre-processing used to create them the
products of the secret shared values
with Beaver multiplication so the
details are important but that saves a
bit of communication
but now the main challenge at this point
is to add active security
um so if you recall there are these two
openings in the protocol where I first
um where P1 distributes shares of the MU
values and then the output new value is
open back to P1 and there was nothing in
the passive protocol which ensures these
things are done correctly
and the solution the authors use in this
work is to apply a secret shared
information thoracic Max
um to make sure that these sharings are
generated and reconstructed correctly
and so for this we use two types of two
additional types of sharings one is
standard additive secret sharing denoted
using angle brackets here
and another is a a special kind of
package Shamir sharing where you just
secret share a single scalar here V and
then kind of pack it into the eighth
slot of a packed secret chair where all
the other slots can be just random and
you don't really care about it
um
and these are used to extend the
invariant in the passive protocol by
adding on some additional
authentications of the appropriate
values
so as well as the the MU value which is
known to P1 and the lambdas which are
secret shared with patch Sameer sharings
we now have authentications of both the
MU and the lambdas so these are additive
shares of me each music mu component and
additive shares of each Lambda component
multiplied by Delta
well Delta is a a random random field
element which acts as a secret Mac key
known to no one and also as a kind of
one-time Global setup you have these
special Shamir sharings of Delta you
know packed into the ith coefficient of
the slot which helps with the
multiplication protocol
and so this is the invariant which of
course you want to be maintained after
multiplication so you get the same
property on the outputs
and
so quickly going through
um so the the final protocol with active
security turns out to be roughly the
same as the passive secure one just with
the addition of these mags
um the idea is that when you when P1
distributes the packed sharings of the
MU values at the start of the
multiplication gate the parties will use
some Max which they have to be able to
verify uh that these mues were
distributed correctly
and
based on the invariant and the
pre-processing we'll have these
additional additional mags used to do
the check and also use
um by taking some appropriate
combinations of them to ensure that we
can get the Mac for the output mu value
these to the next gate
um so uh I think I'll skip over the
technical details here
um but basically there is some some like
nice conversion tricks for conversion
converting from special types of Shamir
sharings to additive sharings
which you can exploit to do to get this
kind of multiplication and and get the
max to work out in the output
um so that's all I wanted to say for
this talk uh thanks for your attention
so if there are any questions
Peter can try to answer them even though
he's not an author
I'm
so I mean one thing I was wondering is
is this for any field or is it like
large enough fields or it should be a
large field for the max to work out
um
it could be that you can you can make it
work in small Fields with bigger Max but
I I'm not sure if they do that in the
paper but also there's some mirror
Secrets Theory being used so are they
like well it should be at least as large
as um what n plus k or something
yeah so not over
um F2 for instance
okay
um yeah if there are no more questions
then let's uh thank Peter again
and
the last talk is called detect pack and
batch perfectly secure MPC with linear
communication and constant expected time
it's a work by itai Abraham
um
this is ravani patil and RP tapatra and
ravani is going to give the dog
complexity of perfectly secure MPC
protocols
so let me Begin by introducing MPC or
multi-party computation
MPC allows and mutually distrusting
parties to compute a joint function of
their private inputs now this distrust
among parties is typically moderate as a
centralized adversary which can corrupt
up to T out of the end parties
and the goals of any MPC protocol are
correctness that is the protocol output
should be equal to the function output
and privacy that is nothing beyond the
function output should be revealed to
the adversary
now based on various parameters such as
the threshold of corruption the nature
of the adversary and so on there are
various settings which have been
considered in the literature and in our
work we focus on one such setting that
is perfect security
here a threshold of T less than n by 3
is known to be necessary and sufficient
the adversity is unbounded powerful and
there is zero error probability in the
output computed
okay so in our work we focus on a
perfectly secure protocols with
malicious Corruptions and primarily we
focus on the communication complexity
so looking at already what exists in the
literature first from the broadcast
hybrid model we see that broadly there
are two categories of protocols one
which we refer to as efficient but slow
and the other one which we call is fast
but inefficient uh let me make this
clear so the first category of protocols
which we call as slow are the ones where
the round complexity actually depends on
the number of parties involved in
and the second category which we call is
fast is where the round complexity is
independent of n
now what we observe is that in the first
class of protocols following a long line
of work the state-of-the-art work of
goyal Liu and song achieves a
communication complexity that is linear
in the number of parties per gate
however the scenario in the second
category of protocols is very different
here to evaluate each gate there is a n
Par 3 amount of communication over point
to point as well as broadcast
channels required just for a single gate
so a natural question that we see is can
we get the best of both these approaches
that is can we get a linear
communication complexity per gate while
ensuring round complexity that is
independent of n
and in our work we answer this in the
affirmative and give an efficient as
well as a fast MPC as we call it
so just to be more clear we look at this
from the point-to-point model that is
when the broadcast channels is
instantiated with a broadcast protocol
so we see that broadcast in itself can
be instantiated with two different
classes of protocols one is where the
protocols are deterministic order of
Enron protocols and the other one where
the protocols are randomized and they
give expected constant round complexity
so we observe that using both the kinds
of protocols for broadcast the work of
goeltol has a communication complexity
that is linear per gate
whereas the work of
the state of the artwork of Abraham
ashero and eni has round complexity that
is order of D that is independent of n
the important point to note here is that
none of the prior Works achieve both the
good features as we call them together
and our work is the first one to achieve
this linear communication per complexity
per gate and Order of depth around
complexity for large enough circuits
so coming to our main result we give an
MPC protocol which has a communication
complexity of order of c n plus D N
squared plus n to the 4 over point to
point channels for evaluating a circuit
with C Gates and Deb d
so looking at it from the broadcast
hybrid model we have a point-to-point
communication of the same order
and broadcast communication of n Cube
and each party design squared
communication here and to instantiate
this we use the broadcast protocol of
Abraham Asher of patil and Patra
which allows us to achieve expected
order of depth round complexity
coming to how we achieve our result
so at a very high level we follow the
Weaver circuit randomization trick to
get our MPC but in particular we follow
a framework which was formalized in the
work of Chaudhary and Patra
so here there are n parties and each
party starts off by using a verifiable
secret sharing VSS primitive to share
random multiplication triplets
so once this is done given that parties
are malicious the multiplicative
relation might not really hold and we
need to verify this
this is where the second component that
is the verify by triple sharing comes
into the picture
and this does the verification of
whether the multiplicative relation in
the triple actually holds or not
so the outcome of this primitive can
either be a success that is the proof
goes through or it fails and in case of
failure we can simply discard the triple
shared by that party
following this a triple extraction
primitive takes in the triple shared by
all the parties and gives out random
multiplication triples which are unknown
to any party
So This Together forms the beaver triple
generation phase as we know it
and following this we can have a beaver
multiplication going on which will just
consume this triples to actually
evaluate the circuit
so what we observe is that if we have an
order of in communication complexity
protocol for each of these Primitives
then we can get an order of n complexity
MPC protocol
and from the literature we have that the
triple extraction and the Beaver
multiplication Protocols are viewer
multiplication Primitives already have
such protocols from the work of
Chaudhary at all and time guard Nielsen
so what remains is the VSS and the
verifiable triple sharing primitive and
this is exactly what the contribution of
our work is
so before moving on to the exact
contributions I'll go over the key
design principles that we follow in this
work
and they are as follows the first is
packing so since we primarily deal with
sharing of secrets in the form of
triples
in order to ensure a low cost we first
pack secrets in a single instance of
sharing so as to amortize the cost
secondly we observed that broadcast
communication is what causes the primary
bottleneck in terms of the communication
complexity
and hence we use our second principle
that is batching of the broadcast cost
across multiple instances of the sharing
and finally while designing these
protocols it so happens that the corrupt
parties can in some sense create failure
I mean they cannot they let at some
times do not allow the protocol to
terminate successfully
and in this case we use our third design
principle that is detection wherein we
identify corrupt parties and neutralize
their power to further obstruct the
successful completion of protocol
so coming to the first primitive where
we have a contribution that is
verifiable secret sharing so VSS is a
primitive which is a two-phase primitive
consisting of a share and a reconstruct
protocol that allows a dealer to share
secrets amongst the parties with the
following properties
the first one is hiding that is at the
end of the sharing phase the adversary
will not gain any information regarding
the secret of an honest dealer
then we have binding that is at the end
of the sharing phase there is some
secret that is committed to
and this is defined by the view of the
honest parties
and finally we have validity or
correctness that means that at the end
of the Reconstruction phase the secret
that has been committed to will be the
one which will be opened and when the
dealer is honest we have that the secret
is actually the one that the dealer
shared
so coming to our main result for the VSS
we give a vs scheme with perfect
security and optimal resilience which
has a complexity of order of p n plus n
power 4 over point to point channels for
sharing P secrets in expected constant
rounds
so what this essentially means is that
when we have large enough number of
Secrets then we get a linear overhead
per sharing of a secret and this exactly
matches the semi honest secret sharing
where a dealer would simply hand out
shares to each party
comparing with the existing prior best
known VSS of Abraham at all
what we see is both rvss as well as
their BSS in a single instance shares
order of n secrets and in fact at the
same cost however we defer in the design
principles that we use
so the work of Abraham at all primarily
uses the packing design principle so you
can think of this as an array of order
of n Secrets packed along the X
dimension of a bivariate used for
sharing
whereas in artwork we use packing as
well as detection of corrupt parties
and this helps us in getting a better
cost when we run multiple instances
together
so the key difference here lies in how
we choose our bivariate polynomial
we choose the degree in such a way that
it allows us to balance the broadcast
communication done by each party in
contrast to the work of Abraham at all
where the dealer used to communicate
order of n Factor more than each other
party
so the way this helps us is when we run
multiple instances of our VSS together
so while the work of Abraham at all
continues to use the principle of
packing in our work we can use packing
batching and detection
so note that here we managed to get the
same broadcast cost that is order of N
squared as we required for one instance
of our VSS whereas in the case of the
prior VSS the broadcast cost depends on
the number of instances that you are
executing
this shows up in the final complexity of
the protocol wherein we get a linear
communication complexity per secret
whereas the prior work achieved a
quadratic communication complexity
so this summarizes our contribution in
terms of the VSS
so looking at the big picture again what
now parties can do is share each secret
using our secret sharing and this will
be shared with a degree t as we require
eventually
and now the goal is to verify that the
product relation of the triples that
they've shared indeed holds
and one way to view this requirement of
the triple sharing
is in the following way so a party
trying to prove that its multiplication
relation holds requires to share in some
sense order of n secrets
now even if we use the VSS that I just
defined which has a linear cost this
would amount to a quadratic cost just to
verify a single secret and this is
beyond what we can afford to get linear
complexity uh MPC protocol
and here is where our second
contribution comes into the picture
so we identify that we don't need a
full-fledged VSS to prove the relation
rather a weaker notion suffices and in
our work we formalize this weak notion
which we call as detectable secret
sharing
so detectable secret sharing similar to
ESS is a two-phase protocol which has a
sharing and a reconstruction phase and
it allows a dealer to share secret with
all the parties and with the following
properties
the hiding and binding are exactly the
same as that what you get in VSS however
there is a difference in the validity
property while VSS allowed the
Reconstruction to always succeed in our
case it might not so be the case
in fact for us one of the following two
conditions holds for our validity
property
so the first one is that the
Reconstruction indeed succeeds and in
this case what we actually have is the
properties of a VSS protocol if this
case happens
on the other hand it is possible that
our reconstruction also fails
and if it does so we make sure that our
third design principle that is detection
comes into the picture and we an honest
dealer who is trying to share the
secrets will identify at least order of
n corrupt parties and make sure that
they can cannot further obstruct the
successful completion
so coming to the result in detectable
secret sharing we give a protocol with
perfect security and optimal resilience
which has order of p plus n to the four
communication for sharing P secrets in
expected constant number of rounds
so note that this amounts to an a
constant overhead per secret when p is
large enough and this matches packed
semi on a secret sharing in contrast to
the standard semi honest secret sharing
which are VSS watch matching
so now if you think about the triple
sharing which essentially required in
secrets to be shared for the proof
if we use our detectable secret sharing
we are still within the bound of linear
complexity which we aim for
so contrasting our VSS with the
detectable secret sharing we see that a
single instance of our VSS as well as
detectable secret sharing has the same
complexity and in fact both use the
principles of packing and detection
but the difference is in the way the
packing is done
so while for VSS we were packing along
just one dimension of the bivariate used
for sharing in case of detectable secret
sharing we pack order of n Secrets along
both the dimensions so you can think of
this as a matrix of values which is
getting packed and this is what allows
the detectable secret sharing to
simultaneously share and squared values
in contrast to order of n which was
getting shared in the VSS
analogously in the case of running M
instances together
we see that uh
our VSS uses packing batching and
detection and similarly the same
principles are used by the detectable
secret sharing as well
and the important part to note here is
that just like VSS our detectable secret
sharing also has a broadcast cost that
is independent of the number of
instances that we are running
so just to summarize the design
principles in our work we have used
packing batching and detection
to get Primitives such as VSS and a new
primitive called detectable secret
sharing
which finally allows us to get a linear
complexity MPC protocol
compared to the with respect to
improvements compared to the state of
the artworks for VSS we have an order of
n Factor Improvement compared to the
work of Abraham at all and for the
Triple sharing primitive our work
improves the state of the art by order
of n Cube and this finally allows us to
achieve the linear communication
complexity that we aimed for
thank you
[Applause]
are there any questions
I was wondering where does this expected
number of rounds come from and if there
is any chance of like improving that or
oh so uh the expected uh is coming out
from the broadcast protocols so all the
results I've described are mainly in the
point-to-point model and uh getting
broadcast with strict constant number of
rounds is known to be impossible due to
work so either you go for order of n
Rams or expected constant point okay
that's also for the detectable secret
sharing you also need yes yes
okay
thank you any other questions
okay so then let's uh thank the speaker
and all the speakers of the session
again
[Applause]