good morning welcome back
okay
today we start with the non-interactive
MPC
the first talk is Black Box reusable
nisk with random oracles by Dubai Shai
dakshita
and the the this paper is presented by
polu so
it's up to you okay
all right hi guys uh as you can tell I'm
not an author on this paper I'm a proxy
presenter for this paper none of the
authors are here this morning so
here I am okay uh and I encourage any
detailed questions to be sent to the
authors by email or on the chat
so let me start this talk by recalling
the setting of secure two-party
computation
and insecure two-party computation we
have two parties P1 and P2 each with
private inputs X1 and X2
and they also have description of a
common function of a common function f
and P1 would like to learn the output F
of X1 X2
and in the literature we call P2 the
sender and P1 the receiver
and after engaging in multiple rounds of
com communication
we need the following three properties
to hold one is correctness that P1
learns F of X1 and X2 at the end of the
protocol
then is receiver security P2 learns no
information about the private input of X
of P1
and Center security says that P1 learns
no information about the private input
X2 apart from what can be inferred from
F of X1 and X2
and we would like these two security
Notions to hold against malicious
adversaries and the security notion is
in the real Ideal World paradigm
and a central goal in the line in the
work of security party computation is to
get efficient secure two-party
computation so we would like to minimize
the round complexity
and towards the school two works of
ishaied Al introduced this notion of
non-interactive secure computation
and again this is the two-party setting
and in non-interactive Secure
computation we have P1 generating a
first round message message one
P2 sending a second round message
message to
and P1 learns F of X1 X2
and this is in fact round optimal you
can't get security guarantees from just
one round
and it should be noted that if we only
care about semi honest adversaries Yao's
protocol already satisfies the required
security properties
and additionally if we replace semi
honest OT
with a malicious secure OT protocol then
the same protocol already satisfies
security against malicious receivers
so the main challenge here
is to protect against the malicious
sender without compromising on the
receiver security
um great so they show The Following
theorem the following theorem says that
for every function f there exists a
non-interactive secure computation
protocol
for securely Computing F in the OT
hybrid model and this has statistical
security if f is in is logged up and
this is due to some theorem about
randomizing Coatings and we also have
computational security for General
f-assuming Black Box access to a prg
um great okay so non-interactive secure
computation has lots of exciting
applications but it also has severe
limitations for several important use
cases and let me motivate one of these
uh one of these important use cases so
consider a patient
who needs a kidney transplant and to
find a suitable transplant donor we
would like to do some sort of DNA
sequence matching so this patient has
some DNA sequence that's its private
input
and to find a find a suitable donor we
can't just reveal their DNA sequence in
the public so we're going to use a
non-interactive secure computation
protocol to facilitate this so they're
going to publish message one from a
non-tractor secure computation protocol
and here comes some potential donor and
the donor has their own DNA sequence
which is their private input and they
send a second round message message too
and the function we're Computing is
match or no match for the sake of kidney
transplants
and let's say it's no match what happens
well we need to find a new donor and
unfortunately the standard notion of
non-effective secure computation we
would have to publish a new first round
message in fact we'd have to do this for
every potential donor that came along
and this is incredibly inefficient and
what we would like is this first round
message to be reusable
so here comes the definition of reusable
non-interactive secure computation
and the works of ishay at all and Chase
ital consider this problem so in this
setting we have some receiver P1 with
private input X1 the receiver has
function f in mind and the receiver
generates an encoding of its private
input and just think of it as publishing
it on a public bulletin board
and now the first sender comes with some
private input x21 and this sender sends
a single second round message message to
one
and P1 can learn F of X1 x21
then comes another sender the same thing
repeats and uh with this with the same
message first round message message one
and P1 can now learn F of X1 x 2 2.
just from receiving the second round
message message to two and this will
repeat for let's say end parties
and the receiver learns the outputs of
the function f applied on its fixed
input and each of these Center inputs
and in this setting
um The Works of each side can actually
be modified so that uh it can be secure
with n reuses where n is actually on
operatory bounded meaning that you
actually have to know n beforehand okay
um and just know that you can actually
get this if you just run and copies in
parallel uh but this would incur a
multiplicative overhead
um and the works of each ideal actually
show how to do this by getting only a
additive overhead so that's the
difference there
and this is unfortunately a severe
restriction because bounding n severely
limits the functionality and of course
the size of the messages depends on this
priorienne
so we'd like to remove this restriction
and now we consider the unbounded
reusable nizzix setting where n is Opera
unbounded
and unfortunately the work of Chase it
I'll show this negative result this
impossibility result which says that
there exists a log depth circuit such
that there exists no statistically
secure unbounded reusable nisc protocol
for computing F in the OT hybrid model
and an OT hybrid model as a reminder
here you have some ideal functionality
for OT and you both parties have Oracle
access to this OT
they also show The Following positive
result and the following positive result
says that for every function of log
depth there exists a statistically
secure unbounded reusable nisc protocol
for computing F in the Ole hybrid model
so by strengthening your what
cryptographic primitive you're
considering namely oblivious linear
evaluators which is you can think of as
a arithmetic analog of OT so OT is over
a binary field you can think of Ole over
some super polynomial or exponentially
sized field
so by upgrading uh by strengthening your
cryptographic
primitive that you're considering you
can actually get a positive result
of course there's some limitations with
this positive result
so first of all early is much more
expensive to implement than OT
and the flavor of OT that ole ole that
we need is some reusable notion of Ole
and this is only known from the DCR the
DCR assumption decisional composite
residuosity
and lastly this protocol for computing
General circuits this positive result by
Chase Adel requires non-block non-black
box use of prg and whenever you have
this non-black box use you incur a
computational overhead because you
actually have to know a specific
implementation of the circuit
okay so the goal of this paper is to
construct unbounded reusable nisc
protocols for computing General circuits
such that they can be efficiently
instantiable from a wide variety of
standard cryptographic assumptions
Beyond just DCR
and it has to make black box use of the
underlying cryptographic Primitives to
remove this computational overhead
and the results of this paper is
srinivasan 23 is that for every function
f there exists an unbounded reusable
nisc protocol for computing F in the
random Oracle model that makes black box
use of a two-round malicious secure OT
protocol
and we just note that the previous work
last year by the same authors show how
to construct a malicious secure OT
protocol in the random Oracle model from
Black Box access to a two round semi on
a secure OT protocol
so as a corollary we can actually relax
this requirement of malicious Acura OT
protocol to semi honest secure OT
protocol
and you might be wondering at this point
is this a contradiction to the negative
results of Chase Adele then Chase it out
prove this was impossible
and in fact they they did not Chase it
out only rules out constructions in the
OT hybrid model
against unbounded senders so this is
that's with statistical security as well
as in a different model
okay
and critically here we are going to be
using Black Box use of a two round OT
and this results in US settling for
computational security
okay and uh this two round OT protocol
is actually more efficient in a two
round Ole protocol as well
and this black box use of two round OT
is actually crucial for the construction
to go through
also this is in the random Oracle model
okay
so
um the first right finally they also
gave constructions a reusable Nic for
General circuits that make black box use
of cryptography and just as a reminder
the the positive result from Chase at
all uses non-black box use of pogs
and an interesting open question is uh
to extend this to the Le hybrid model
without random oracles
so here's some more results Beyond just
reusable nisc
so here we consider the problem of
two-sided nisc here you have two parties
P1 P2 and unlike the previous setting in
this setting both P1 and P2 would like
to learn F of X1 X2
okay and so P1 and P2 will engage in a
first round message message exchange so
message one one and message one two they
don't depend on each other
and then we have a second round of
messages exchanged and after P1 after
these two rounds of messaging uh P1 and
P2 each learn F of X1 X2
and uh just note that if you took a
one-sided nisc and you try to run in
both directions it does not result in
two-sided nisc and why is that the two
uh the two directions could actually
result the parties could actually use
different inputs so it could be that in
the first round maybe P1 learns F of X1
X2 but in the second round
P2 learns F of X1 Prime X2 Prime so
one-sided Nic does not imply two-sided
Nic generally speaking
in the theorem from last year's work by
the same authors show that for every
function f there exists two rounded nisc
protocol for securely Computing F that
makes black box use of a two round
malicious secure OT
okay
and today I'm going to be telling you
about a more simplistic model of
two-sided nisc but the authors also
consider a more general definition that
captures both this simplistic two-sided
model as well as the one-sided model
and I encourage you to see their
formulation in the paper
so what is reusable two-sided Nic well
here the first round message is reusable
but here the settings a little different
the syntax will be where we're going to
be switching the function that we're
considering
so if for example consider P1 P2 having
a common input the description of some
function F1
then in this reusable setting P1 and P2
can now you know generate the first
round message and for this particular
common input F1 they can generate second
round messages that depend on F1 so the
length of these messages will depend on
F1
and at the end of this exchange of
messaging P1 and P2 will each learn F1
of X1 and X2
and this can contain this can continue
for many different functions many
different executions and let's say up to
some n and of course what we would like
is n to be Opry unbounded
and the results in this paper show The
Following theorem
there exists an unbounded two-sided
reusable nisc protocol for computing
General functions in the random Oracle
model that make black box use of a
two-round malicious secure OT protocol
and additively homomorphic commitments
let me just make a note quickly on the
additively homomorphic commitments in
fact
if the party is allowed to maintain an
updatable State across every execution
then actually we can remove this need
for additional this additional
Assumption of additively homorphic
commitments
and just as a quick note again if you if
we can actually relax this to Black Box
use of a two round semi honest security
protocol Again by by leveraging last
year's result
let me give you some quick intuition on
how to overcome the impossibility result
from Chase Adele
so what is the intuition behind
impossibility result
well it says that suppose party one
sends a first round message of all these
two out of one OTS on these bits B1
through BK and what is B1 through BK you
can think of them as some encoding of
p1's private input so think of secret
sharing secret shares
so B1 through b k need to be hidden
and they're fixed across all executions
so this and this will be in the OT
hybrid model
um
and here comes along malicious P2
and what will malicious P2 do malicious
P2 will effectively recover all these
bits
and how will it do it it will make use
of the fact of uh that can effectively
Implement abort Oracle on P1 so what
will P2 do P2 will make a guess for the
first bit B1 it's going to try to
recover bits bit by bit and say that the
real bit is B1 star
what is it going to do
um uh sorry it's going to make a guess
for B1 and say this bit is B1 star we
don't know actually what B1 is and what
you're going to do is you're going to
generate the the message uh M1 minus B
Star B1 Star as bot
and for the other message you're going
to generate honestly
and what you can do is you can send
these two messages over and in the case
that p1's bit was actually B1 star then
it's going to see a real message and
everything is fine
but in the case that it actually picked
one minus B1 star meaning that you uh
you you you you guessed incorrectly it's
going to abort and P2 will see that P1
aborted and P2 will then claim that it
knows uh B1 so either way you recovered
the baby one
and the fact that this first round
message is reusable and fixed allows P2
to actually iteratively recover all the
bits B1 through BK one by one
and this is an issue
so to prevent this attack somehow we
have to ensure that all the sender OT
messages encode valid inputs not bought
and so how would we accomplish this by
making Black Box use of a two round OT
and I would like to clarify that we
can't do this for for all OT sender
messages but we can ensure that at least
a large fraction of the messages are
secure and this turns out to be
sufficient for our purposes
so the sender first generates the second
round
OT message
k c as K executions of this
and after this the sender chooses a
random subset s of the OT executions and
sends this set to the sender
and the sender opens each of these OT
messages corresponding to the set s
and you can think of uh by opening what
do we mean we mean that the sender
reveals the input and Randomness used in
generating these second round messages
great
and now the receiver checks if all these
messages encoded and all these open
executions are valid
and this will ensure that more than 90
of the executions are valid with
overwhelming probability uh right yeah
and good okay and note that such a check
is impossible to uh to make an OT hybrid
model because you don't actually have
access to these second round messages
um you just have Oracle access to this
ideal functionality
and this is actually the key distinction
that allows us to recover the the
previous impossibility result
and unfortunately this approach seems to
increase the number of rounds
and we're also no longer in a two
message setting
right
okay so how do we collapse number of
rounds well we're going to use a feature
from your heuristic so we're going to
compute the subset S as the output of a
hash function applied on second round
sender messages
and now the receiver now checks that the
set s is computed correctly and then
performs the same checks as before
and if the hash function is correlation
intractable
this ensures that more than 90 of the
executions are computed correctly
and there's actually still a subtle
issue in fact uh this doesn't prevent P2
from cheating in a small number of
executions
because in the you know you could learn
10 of the the bits here 10 alert bits
there
and the reusable setting P2 could
potentially cheat in a small number of
execution
executions in each reuse and could use
this information to break receiver
security
so to overcome this uh to overcome P2
from cheating in the small number of
executions the authors will use some
sort of standard error correcting
properties of Shamir secret sharing
and just as a conclusion
the authors gave new constructions of
reusable nisc and reusable two-sided Nic
protocols they're instantiable from
almost all known standard assumptions in
cryptography CDH lwe so forth and the
open problems here are to remove random
oracles from the construction remove the
need for additively homorphic
commitments from the two-sided protocol
and improve the concrete efficiency
and thank you for detention and I direct
most of the questions to the authors
thank you
okay the next talk is malicious secure
Mr nisk in the play model by Rex
Fernando
ayush Xian Elan komarkoski and Rex is
giving the talk
thanks for the introduction
to be focusing on a primitive called Mr
nisk and this primitive generalizes to
run NPC and I'll be talking about how to
achieve malicious security for this
primitive in the play model
and this is Joint work with ayush Jain
and Ilan kumagutsky
so let's start by quickly reviewing the
the goal of NPC so let's say that there
is a set of parties and these parties
have some private input
and these parties don't want to share
their private input with anyone else but
the parties also want to answer some
question about the joint set of inputs
so what MPC does is allows these parties
to communicate to learn the output to
this question or more generally the
output of you know the evaluation of any
efficient function over their inputs
while still respecting the privacy of
each individual party
so in this talk we're going to be
focusing on two important areas of study
in the MPC literature so the first area
of study concerns the security model so
early NPC results focused on proving
Security in What's called the Standalone
setting and in this setting it's assumed
that all the parties are completely
isolated from the outside world where
they're participating in this protocol
but of course this isn't very realistic
because in you know in real life there's
nothing stopping these parties from
talking to other people all the protocol
is going on
so it's an important goal in NPC to
prove security for protocols in this
more realistic concurrent setting
so another important goal in MPC in the
MPC literature is studying the number of
rounds of interaction that's required
for security so in other rounds let's
say we assume we have a simultaneous
broadcast channel
uh the question is how many back and
forth messages do we need in order to
get security
so in this talk we'll focus on these two
goals with respect to protocols that
work in the plane model so that is they
don't have any trusted setup phase and
they don't have a random Oracle
so in this setting along you know
sequence of Works has eventually shown
that it's possible to achieve Security
in four rounds
and on the other hand it's also been
shown that this is the best we can hope
for that three rounds is impossible
and unfortunately it's also been shown
that uh concurrent Security in any
number of rounds is impossible in the
plane model
so in order to get around these
impossibility results we're going to use
a relaxation of security that's called
super polynomial simulation or SPS
and the idea is that so in normal NPC we
allow the simulator to have like an
arbitrary polynomial blob in the running
time compared to its real world
adversary counterpart
um so in SPS we're going to relax this
so we're going to allow the simulator to
have a you know a slightly super
polynomial blow up
so in terms of SPS several Works have
shown that this relaxed definition can
be used to get around both impossibility
results before from before so first of
all it's up it's possible to get
concurrent Security in the plane model
and also it's possible to achieve
protocols that work in three rounds so
the round Berry is also
is it can get around the round barrier
as well
so the goal of our work is to explore
the space at the bottom of the slide
and as a first step towards this I can
tell you that we achieve a two-round
concurrent secure MPC protocol in the
plane model
so now the only thing that's left is one
round so is one round even possible so
it turns out that the answer is no and
there is actually a very simple uh a
very simple argument that can be used to
show this and I'll explain this to you
now so let's say these three parties
Alice Bob and Eve want to evaluate some
function f
and let's say that they have a one round
protocol to do this
so just by this one this protocol being
one round I can show you that it's
insecure now
so let's say Eve is malicious so she can
do the following attack so she can come
up with any arbitrary X3 Prime
and she can find she can determine she
can find the evaluation of f with
respect to X3 Prime and with respect to
Alice and Bob's private inputs uh just
in her head just by replaying replaying
the protocol in her head and she can
actually do this in arbitrary amount of
times as she so she can learn an
arbitrary number of evaluations so this
is called the residue residual function
attack
um and of course this leakage about
Alice and Bob's input is like way more
than what a secure protocol would allow
for so this means that this this
protocol is insecure
okay so non-interactive mpca is
impossible but you know let's say we're
stubborn and we want we don't we don't
want to accept this so I can tell you a
way to get some of the properties of
non-interactive NPC without running into
this problem and the idea is as follows
so this system is going to work with
respect to what we're going to call a
public bulletin board that everyone can
see at all times
and as a first step all the parties are
going to publish non-interactive
commitments special non-interactive
commitments to their inputs
so once this phase is done let's say the
parties want to evaluate F again so they
can do this using a single additional
round of interaction
and uh so in addition this this is this
system is going to allow reuse so if the
parties want to evaluate F Prime now
they can again do this in one round
so by by this the like as the number of
evaluations goes up the the cost the
round cost per evaluation approaches one
so finally the system is going to allow
for parties to join at any time simply
by publishing you know non-interactive
commitments to their inputs and as soon
as they've done this they can
participate in any subsequent function
evaluation phases
and additionally these function
evaluation phases can take take place
with respect to a subset of parties and
the parties that aren't participating
they don't have to communicate at all
for this for these phases to work
okay so this primitive that I just
described is called multi-party reusable
non-interactive secure computation or Mr
nisk
um and it strictly generalizes to around
NBC and it was first proposed by Ben
hamura and Lynn in 2020 but in terms of
plain model protocols they were only
able to achieve a semi malicious
security which is a weaker version of
security where the adversary is assumed
to follow the protocol specification
honestly and no guarantees are made if
this assumption doesn't hold
okay so with that in mind I can tell you
about our main result so we achieved the
first construction of Mr nisk that's
maliciously secure in the plane model
and we do this using sub-exponential
variants of the following assumptions so
first we assume IO second we assume ddh
and third we assume the existence of a
Time Block Puzzle
so in the course of achieving this main
result we also achieve two intermediate
results that we also think are
independently interesting
first we Define and construct a new
strong variant of two round zero
knowledge
and second we also construct a new
one-round non-valuable commitment
and notably this commitment doesn't
require a keyless hash functions
so in the interest of time for the rest
of the talk I'm going to focus on
explaining this new zero knowledge so
I'll explain the new definition and why
we need it
so to uh to motivate this this new
definition first let's quickly talk
about the high-level approach that we're
going to use in order to up to to get
malicious security
and what we're going to do is we're
going to take a semi-malicious secure Mr
nisk like such as the one of Ben hammur
and Lin and we're going to upgrade
security using zero knowledge so this is
a very common approach and the idea is
that is that we can use zero knowledge
to enforce honest Behavior that's
required for semi malicious security
okay so for this part of the talk I'm
just going to sort of ignore the
reusability aspect of a minusk I'm just
going to treat it as a two round
protocol
okay so what are our constraints in this
setting so first there's the round
constraints so we only have two rounds
and second we also know that in this
setting in the plane model the best we
can hope for in terms of zero knowledge
is two rounds as well and this is
because non-interactive zero knowledge
is impossible without setup
so what does this mean for us this means
we can't check the validity of the
proofs until after the protocol is
finished
um so let's think about how this plays
out so let's say there's an adversary
that corrupts some of the parties and
causes uh let's say that this adversary
causes the first round to be dishonest
in terms of the semi malicious protocol
so what this means is that now the
honest parties actually have to send out
their round two semi-malicious messages
before knowing that before finding out
that this round one is dishonest
and in particular if we if we send out
these if these honest parties send out
these messages in the clear that means
that semi malicious security actually
guarantees nothing in this case
so to get around this problem uh what we
would like is some sort of way to send
out an encrypted version of round two in
a way that it's only decryptable if the
first round is honestly generated
so this sounds like a perfect job for
witness encryption so if if you're not
familiar with Fitness encryption the
idea is it's an encryption scheme that
allows you to encrypt arbitrary messages
so in our case we're going to encrypt
round two
and instead of having a public key the
encryption is given with respect to a
statement in NP
and the idea is that if you have a
witness for the statement you can
decrypt
and on the other hand if the statement
is false so in our case if round one is
dishonest
then standard ciphertext
indistinguishability holds so the
messages don't reveal anything or the
encryptions don't reveal anything about
the plain texts
so notice that this solves our problem
already or it seems to at least because
now in the dishonest case if round one
is dishonest then the adversary learns
nothing about round two
but let's think about what happens in
the honest case now so how how can the
parties decrypt now
well so what does the witness look like
it looks like uh you know it has the
secret input and randomness of each
party
and of course
you know it's obvious that these parties
can't reveal these secret inputs and
randomnesses publicly which means that
no one party has this entire witness
which means no party can decrypt
um so this seems like a problem so what
what could we use to fix this well if we
had some sort of privacy preserving
witness that each party could publish
and then the you know this witness for
this statement is a concatenation of
these these privacy preserving Witnesses
um and let's say that these these
Witnesses reveal nothing about the
underlying secret Witnesses then that
would be good right
uh well this should sound very familiar
because what is your knowledge it's it's
exactly that right it's a it's a way to
publish a privacy preserving proof that
convinces a verifier of the validity of
the statement but doesn't but doesn't
reveal the underlying Witness
so let's try to use this so now we can
set the witness that we want to use to
be you know zero knowledge second round
zero knowledge messages from each party
attesting to their honest behavior
during round one
and we can change the the statement that
the witness encryption is going to use
in order to reflect that so now the
statement is that there exists second
round zero knowledge messages which
proves the ability validity of this
inner statement that round one is
honestly generated
and now the idea is or the hope at least
is by soundness of the zero knowledge
protocol this should reduce to the
original statement right
um but now we run into another problem
because uh it seems like now we need the
zero knowledge protocol to satisfy
statistical soundness
um because like with computational
soundness it could be totally possible
that the inner statement is false that
round one is dishonest but there could
exist second round zero knowledge
messages that prove this false statement
even if they're hard to find and
unfortunately witness encryption doesn't
doesn't guarantee anything about you
know in terms of hiding messages that
are encrypted into encrypted with
statements that are not false even if
the witnesses for those statements are
hard to find
so it turns out that achieving a
two-round zero knowledge protocol that
satisfies statistical soundness is
impossible except for like very limited
uh limited sub cases and so the point of
our new zero knowledge notion is to uh
is to provide a sufficiently like a
sufficient uh approximation of
statistical soundness in order to be
able to be used with Fitness encryption
but to still be achievable
and so the notion is going to work as
follows so first we're going to work in
the simultaneous message model so the
first round is going to have a message
simultaneously from the verifier and the
prover
and then this this new zero knowledge
protocol is going to is going to work in
one of two modes
so the first mode we're going to call
perfect soundness mode and the second
we're going to call statistical zero
knowledge mode
and moreover the the mode is going to be
determined completely by the round one
transcript so once round one is fixed
that also fixes the mode
and perfect soundness mode is what it
sounds like so if we're if we fixed
around one transcript that fixes perfect
soundness mode then for any X that's not
in the language there shouldn't exist
any second round accepting zero
knowledge messages
and on the other hand the statistical
zero knowledge mode says that there
should exist a simulator such that in
this mode
this simulator should be able to
generate uh second round messages such
that the transcript is statistically
indistinguishable from a real world
interaction
and we're going to require that the the
perfect soundness mode happens with some
tunable negligible probability mu
um and this is going like it'll happen
with this probability assuming that the
prover and the verifier are
computationally bounded when they
generate their first round messages
and we're also going to require that a
computational approver cannot tell what
mode the protocol is in
okay so let's think about how we use
this new zero knowledge definition in
order to solve the problem from before
so let's imagine that we're using you
know the same setup but we're now using
our new zero knowledge and let's say
that there's an adversary that corrupts
the first round
but can somehow learn something about
the encrypted second round that it
shouldn't so learn something non-trivial
about this second round uh plain text
so the first observation that we that we
can make is that whatever this adversary
learns it should still be able to learn
this information in perfect soundness
mode given that you know given that the
zero knowledge protocol is in this mode
and this is because uh the the two modes
are indistinguishable
but notice that now that we're in this
mode now that we're conditioning on
being in this mode uh this statement
that we used to generate the witness
encryption is now false right because
the inner statement is false round round
one is dishonest and so uh since we're
in this mode there there don't exist
second round ZK messages that prove
false statements
so then if if the witness encryption
itself is strong enough or in other
words if the advantage in distinguishing
ciphertexts is guaranteed to be
sufficiently less than the probability
mu of the perfect soundness mode holding
then we have a contradiction And Thus
We've successfully shown that the
witness that using this new zero
knowledge the witness encryption hides
the second round in the case that the
first round is dishonest
okay so that's our new definition of
zero knowledge and how we use it and so
we're able to construct this new
definition using the following
assumptions
and like I just explained this is one of
the you know the main technical tools
that we use in constructing our mrnisk
protocol
so I'll just quickly touch on some other
challenges that I won't have time to get
into
um which I thought were interesting
um so first when constructing a minus we
had to deal with extraction
um we have to you know the simulator has
to extract the corrupted party's inputs
and so to do this we needed one round
not valuable commitments which we
constructed in the paper
um second we had to you know we had to
make everything reusable in order to
satisfy the Mi definition and this was
particularly challenging in the context
of the zero knowledge protocol it was
hard to make that protocol reusable
and finally when we were constructing
the complexity hierarchy to make to make
all the proofs fit together
um
you know it was it was challenging to to
come up with a hierarchy that made the
hybrids go through and we ended up using
multiple axis of hardness to do this
and I'll refer you to the paper for
details on this
okay so I'll just restate our main
results so we achieved the first
malicious secure amarnisk in the plane
model
um
uh and we also in the course of doing
this we achieved two other intermediate
results which we think
are uh independently interesting so that
concludes my talk thanks
[Applause]
thank you we have time for a quick
question
okay what is the Assumption underlying
that time lock puzzle
what is the Assumption underlying the
time in occupiesel you can use you can
use the RSW assumption oh okay you can
also build it from i o and slow
functions I think those are the two main
ways to build timeout buses okay
thank you thank you this speaker again
[Applause]
okay the last talk is minimizing setup
in broadcast optimal to around MPC by
Van Dam guard Diva Ravi Luis assign
and Sofia is getting the thought sorry
Luis is giving the talk hi so this is a
joint work with Ivan uh Divi and Sophia
and I am going to present it so let's
start with some definition about MPC
well we have our set of parties that
they want to compute a common function
now they are exchanging messages and in
the end they will get an output and now
the security of MPC guarantees me that
nothing except the output is leaked to
the party as long as the functional also
so now an important question is to
understand actually what happened in the
case that the adversary refused to
continue the computation at a point and
just decide to abort what are the
properties that NPC can guarantee in
this case well the first notion that we
can consider is the one of guaranteed
output delivery which says it doesn't
matter what the adversary does The
Honest party are going to retrieve the
output then we can consider a slightly
weaker notion which is the one of
fairness which says if the adversary is
going to return it does not get the
output also the honest party don't but
if the adversary is getting the output
also the honest party though
so and then we can consider as an
incompatible notion which is the one of
identifiable apart
which says well the adversaries uh if
you dial diversary abort is allowed to
recover the output but at this point all
the parties unanimously abort and
identify who caused this computation to
abort
and then we can consider another notion
which is the one of unanimous support
which has the same guarantee of
identifiable abort but in this case
there is no identifiability property
namely if the the computational boards
well the old all the parties or
unanimously or abort and the adversary
is still allowed to recover the output
finally we can get the weaker definition
which is the one of selective abort
which says well some honest if the
adversary abort is allowed to recover
the output and some on aspartame abort
and some other parties instead May
retrieve the output so
if you can see this set of notion you
can see that when we want to require
identifiability we are also asking for
unanimity but what about all these cases
where actually we cannot get
identifiability and unanimate unanimity
at the same time we in our work we are
asking can we still get some form of
identifiability which is still
meaningful in particular what we are
what we design is a new notion of
security which is correlated selective
identifiable about in this new notion if
the adversary aborts well
but the party that aboard the
computation are actually also
identifying who aborted the competition
and let me stress here that honest
parties the Do Not accurate never accuse
other honest parties of aborting
okay
that's in the set of notion of
guarantees that we can consider in NPC
and now I am starting to go more in
details of our work well we focus on two
round NPC
which is the optimal round complexity
and we are asking what is the optimal
broadcast complexity namely which
guarantees are possible of the one that
we saw when we start to limiting the
number of broadcasts around namely if
broadcast is available all in the first
round or in the second round or none of
the round so there were previous work on
this setting but the work of con metal
give a completely character it was the
first to give a completely
characterization in the in two round NPC
setting where we consider a dishonest
majority
answered the same question but for the
case of an honest majority
so the work of damaga the third
does rely on a public infrastructure so
these leaves open the question if what
is the landscape where instead the
particle the multi-party computation
protocol just rely on a common a common
reference string
and that's what actually we answer in
our work
so this is a big table with a lot also
previous results and relations about
that
the main takeaway of this table is that
one of our uh our results actually shows
that if you want to have identifiable
abort and
you don't want to have bro you want to
rely on broadcast just in the second
round well you need to have a super
honest majority and the known as
majority is not enough
okay so we give a lower bound and the
matching upper Bound for a for this
setting among the other result
let me stress other two things in this
table well the first is that some of
this result doesn't hold do not hold
some of the impossibility not hold for
the corner case when we have just one
corruption and I defer to the paper for
for this case where the landscape change
a bit
another important observation here is
that all the positive results that we
have actually do not assume uh private
peer-to-peer channel in the first round
which means that the first round doesn't
assume encrypted program okay
so as an additional result of our work
we study what's feasible and what not in
the cost in the context of selective
identifiable abort
and uh we give a completely
characterization for the two round
setting both in the dishonest majority
and in the honest majority
um relying both sincere smpki
okay and let me stress here that
actually
in this specific setting that I
highlighted the best guarantee possible
is selective identifiable abort meaning
we cannot do better so in this setting
we we actually guarantee some form of
identifiability which before was not
possible since identifiable abort is
impossible in those setting
okay
so that's the general overview of our
result now for the rest of the talk I
will just focus on one positive result
namely the one where there is a
peer-to-peer in the first round
broadcast in the second round I am using
as a setup only CRS and I am relying on
the fact that there is a super honest
majority of users
so the high level idea is that we follow
the same approach of kinetal and
lamborgh but new challenges are gonna
arise since the due to the fact that we
don't use a pki
so let me also stress that here we are
not making use of a public private
channel in the first round
okay
so what is the general blueprint
I am saying I have a protocol that is
broadcast broadcast and that is
identifiable aboard and now I want to
make a compiler which also allows me to
run it when the first round is
peer-to-peer
so the first question can be why we I
cannot just run this protocol over when
the first round is peer-to-peer well
because the adversary can actually send
different in the first round can send
different messages to different honest
party
and then he will obtain different
version of the second round message
so
and this one is an attack that is not
considered in the original protocol
because in the Bro in the broadcast
round in the original in in the original
product the first round is over
broadcast so everybody has the same view
of the first round
so now we would like a mechanism such
that actually the second round is
released
only if everybody has the the same only
if in the end of the first round
everybody has the same view of the
around one of the parties so let's say
that I have a for Simplicity and
abstracting Away some detail let's have
let's say that I have a magic box which
is gonna split out the second round
message of uh of a party
given the first round message is over of
all the other parties
let's also say that still for Simplicity
that this round are just one bit
so in particular we want to evaluate
this box
choosing uh choosing the correct bit of
the of the bear
so if this first round message of the
bear is one well we would like that
everybody has the the green token
and if the if the the first bit of the
of the bed is zero we would like that in
the end of the first on the second round
to evaluate this box everybody has the
blue token
so
on top of this box we would like to have
another mechanism such that we could
share we could distribute these tokens
and in the end of the second round
everybody agrees on the same version of
the token then they need to use based on
the first round messages of all the
other parties
okay so this mechanism was a form of
this mechanism was already implemented
by ramgaretal but they use a public
infrastructure to do it the rely on a
pki
instead we come up with a different
version of this uh this tool called one
or nothing secret sharing with
intermediers
in which we don't we don't make use of
any pki
so and in the last part of uh of this
talk I am just gonna focus on this
specific mechanism okay
so
here is our setting we have these two
token and we want to communicate this to
the other parties based on the bit of of
uh of the bear
so one thing that uh the sender can do
is just secret share
this token let's say the blue token for
Simplicity we are just gonna focus on
one token and let's say that I want to
communicate this this shirt to a
receiver okay
one thing that I could do is just to
send this shirt to the receiver
and this seems fine right but what about
the case that the receiver claims he
didn't receive this share at the same
time the sender can claim that his and
his share and the receiver is lying and
the other party they don't have any way
any possible way to actually understand
who is lying between the two
so here it comes the observation that
actually in our case we have a lot of
honest parties right and we can actually
try and we can actually use these
parties called also intermediers to
actually trace and understand if this
conversation happen or not happened okay
so now to in order to do that we are
going to share each shares again
and send a single sub share to the
intermediers
and then they are the intermediers to
send this shirt to the receiver
now what happened in this case well in
order to not be caught
the sender has to agree at least to n
minus t intermediers okay at the same
time the receiver must must be in
agreement at least with the and minus
the intermediers so that there should be
enough support
otherwise someone will be caught okay
and this is the exactly the observation
that is underlying our tool
so I will give you now a bit more
details about that
let's recall what is our setting well we
have this uh now let's focus on these
two phases there is a phases between the
sender and intermediers and another
phase is between the intermediers and
the receiver right
and uh
so these are two different phases but
actually in our setting in the first
round we are we are relying only on
public Channel and we are only assuming
a common reference string so how we are
gonna actually send this share privately
to the intermediers
what we are gonna do is actually that in
the first round we exchange just public
Keys between each each parties
so each party has a public key with each
other parties
and then what we are going to do is to
do this transfer these two phase
transfers just in one round
so
let's say let's see the sender as a the
public Keys over the intermediers right
for which they have a secret keys
and now what what she can do well is to
use is to encrypt each shares who's the
using the keys of the intermediers
namely for the first intermediaries she
will uh she will encrypt the first share
using the public key of the first
intermediers and so on and so forth and
she will prepare all these boxes right
and she will broadcast all these boxes
in the broadcast round
okay but at this point the the boxes are
only transferred at the intermediers and
we are already at the second round
so how actually we are making also the
second transfer well
here it comes the second observation
right because now the intermediers have
have also exchanged in the first round a
public key with the receiver
so what they can do is to transfer their
decryption capability
and now they are gonna do that well they
are going to encrypt their secret key
using the public key of the receiver
and they are broadcast that in the
second round
okay
so
now the observation here is that if the
sender is not is not going to be caught
well at least n minus t intermediers
will get the correct uh we get the
correct boxes encrypted with their
public key at the same time at the same
time the receiver has at least
easily at least in agreement with the N
minus t intermediers so in total there
is an intersection of n minus 2 tea
party which are agreeing with boso party
and since our threshold is just one
third well this we shown the paper that
actually this is a sufficient to get
correctness so the receiver can actually
uh um reconstruct the correct sub-share
and we are also ensured that the the
malicious user can at most reconstruct
one of these two uh one one of these two
token
okay and that's a
what I wanted to say so thanks a lot
thank you Luisa questions
okay I have a question uh is the case t
equal to one very different from the
cases you presented yeah actually it is
because here in the case still equal one
it makes actually a difference if you
have a private channel in the first
round or public channel in the first
round so we are showing that actually if
your public channel is actually
impossible for the corner case of t
equal one and N equal to four
more questions
okay thank you Luisa and thank you to
all this speaker for the session
[Music]
is
yeah