so good morning everyone
this is a public crypto analysis session
without isageni
so we will have three talks on crypto
analysis and the first one is on the
harness of the finite field isomorphism
Problem by dipayan Das and Antoine Zhu
and dipayan will give the talk
hello everyone so the title of my talk
is on the hardness of the finite field
isomorphism problem and this is a joint
work with Antonio
so for cryptography we rely on the
assumptions of heart problems
most problems in the literature of
lattice based cryptography are believed
to be hard based on a transformation to
a lattice problem and the lattice
problem is known to be hard in both
classical and quantum computer
in this talk I'll present some counter
example where this transformation
doesn't work and we might run into
problem
to start with let's give some reminders
from the finite field Theory
for any prime number q and integer n
there is a unique
finite field of order Q to the power n
but we can have different
representations of the finite field
using some irreducible polynomial so
what you can do is you can view the
finite field as polynomials over fq
modular semi-reducible polynomial so you
take different irreducible polynomials
and you have different representations
of the finite field to explicitly find
an isomorphism between the
representations what you need to do is
find the root of one irreducible
polynomial in terms of the other
representation of the finite field
so in our purpose we need two
representations of the finite field one
is a private representation which is a
sparse and ternary irreducible
polynomial that I will refer as little f
of x and there is a public
representation that is uniformly at
random from the reducible polynomials
over fq that I will represent as capital
F of Y
so the ffi distribution is defined in
the following way
as we sample small linear combinations
of powers of x
and output its representation in the
public representation
oh
so the finite field isomorphism problem
was introduced at pkc 18 and it states
the following given arbitrary many
samples decide if they come from ffi
distribution that is if they have a good
representation in some private
representation of the finite field or
they are just picked at random
so this is basically the decisional ffi
problem
and if I just give a toy example even
for ternary representation in the X
basis the ybs representation looks quite
pseudo random
the authors proposed lattice reduction
algorithm to solve this problem so what
you can do you can consider a qery
lattice that is generated by The Columns
of the Matrix whose ith row is given by
the ith sample
in the set
so for ffi samples there are unusually
short vectors inside this lattice
because there is a good representation
in some hidden finite field
representation
but for uniform samples it's highly
unlikely to have such short factors
inside the lattice and once your lattice
reduction algorithm could able to
distinguish the two cases you can able
to solve the problem
and the lattice reduction algorithms are
believed to be difficult to perform in
practice
the authors also propose a fully
homomorphic encryptions so the basic
idea was to use many encryptions of zero
to encrypt the message so here it works
in the following way
so to encrypt a bit you pick a pick an
ffi sample and multiply it with a small
integer P which is equals to 2 in the
rest of that talk
and then you add the corresponding bits
you want to encrypt
to decrypt you use your secret
isomorphism to go back to the X basis
representation and just take a mod P
operation since the X basis
representation is small once you do this
mod P operation everything cancels out
and you get the message back that was
encrypted
additionally
if you add to Cipher text
and then decrypt it you get the the the
addition of the corresponding messages
also you can do the product of Cipher
text and decrypt it to get the
corresponding product of the messages so
a small thing to note here that after
multiplication in small representation
the coefficient can grow really fast and
that is the reason the authors use this
ternary and sparse constraint to bound
the coefficient growth after
multiplication
so for our purpose we need the trace of
a finite field which is defined as the
sum of the conjugates
this is linear which can be computed in
polynomial time and this is invariant
under any basis representation so it
doesn't matter if you care if you are
dealing with a good represent a good
representation or the battery
presentation the trace is going to be
same
if the if reducible polynomial is sparse
and ternary as used in the ffi
distribution then you can explicitly
find the absolute value of the trace of
the polynomial X basis and this is
basically done expressing the trace of
the polynomial X basis in terms of the
symmetric polynomials Sigma Js
so for the interval 1 to n by 2 minus 1
all the symmetric polynomials are 0 by
definition then there is no contribution
inside the sum all the sigma these are
zero so the trace is not going to
contribute anything so it's going to be
0 every time
for the range n by 2 to n minus 1
since the first half of the symmetric
polynomials are already zero the only
solution for add ice that is going to
contribute in the sum is for the value
rd1 and 0 elsewhere
and this gives a simple explicit formula
for the trace of the polynomial X in the
interval n by 2 to n minus 1. so this is
basically the absolute value of the
trace of powers of x
is D when the corresponding symmetric
polynomial Sigma D is non-zero and zero
when the symmetric polynomial is zero
so why do we care so we care because
once you know the polynomial X base is
the trace of the polynomial X basis in
absolute value we can just use linearity
argument from the trace to bound any
small representation
uh index basis
and because the trace is invariant the
trace of the ffi samples are also
bounded and the bound is like a small
factor of n Square
so just with this observation we have a
very simple attack on the decisional ffi
problem so you have arbitrary menu
samples you compute the trace if they
are all bounded by a factor of n Square
output ffi distribution otherwise a
uniform distribution because for uniform
samples the trace is going to be
uniformly distributed
so we can extend this to get a semantic
attack on the fully homomorphic
encryption scheme
so first let N is odd that is p is not a
divisor of n
then the trace of the cipher text is
going to be small and then if you take
this mod P you you get 0 when the
message was 0 and 1 when the message was
one because stress of 0 is 0 and trace
of 1 is n and p is not a divisor of n
and if p is a divisor of n that is if n
is even then trace of 0 and trace of 1
mod P both gives zero so we need to do a
small modification
so what we do is the following we can
pick any arbitrary fe5 sample that's
what I call C star such that the trace
of the arbitrary ffi sample is not a
multiple of P
then the product of the cipher text with
the the dummy ffi sample that you have
picked C star is also going to be small
and this is because of the choice of the
irreducible polynomial sparse and
ternary
then if you do this trace of the product
of ciphertext with the dummy ffi sample
mod P you get 0 when the message was 1 a
message was zero and one when the
message was one so you have a semantic
attack on the both cases of n
that's what I was going to say thank you
and happy to take questions
[Applause]
the question
uh just a quick question
um you mentioned the crypto system in
2018 yes was there any
um
sort of
anything before that or is that the
first so I think this is the first
proposal after that there was another
signature scheme
but the Assumption behind that signature
scheme was quite different it's like
using a PQ and true sign using this ffi
problem
but the assumption is quite different
than what they have stated initially in
the pkc paper
thank you
so my question is does your attack still
apply if the modulus is very small
uh no so it has to be some factor of N
squared at least
but for homomorphic encryptions like
what they proposed for that you need
this modulus to be sub exponential
and for that like our bound is quite
fine okay thanks
so I have also one question have you
tried to recover the secret key or you
can prove that it's difficult have you
tried to recover the secret key
secretly like the hidden isomorphism so
yes we tried in the paper to do to find
this secret isomorphism but in the
original paper the complexity was in
factorial like you need some
combinatorial argument to find the
isomorphism but in the paper what we did
that okay you don't really need that
Expo that that factorial part you can
just avoid it and just you know find
some short like shortest Vector inside a
lattice to solve it so
we tried it but it still seems to be
hard
but just solving the decision problem
gives you a semantic attack so
that's what we think is more interesting
for this talk
okay thank you very much
[Applause]
so the second torque is a new a new time
memory trade-off for successor improving
ISD in theory and practice by on the way
Acer and Floyd the Dinger and Freud will
give the talk
yeah unfortunately it's Andre giving the
talk sorry no no worries uh first of all
I want to give the credits for creating
this presentation to Floyd and I'm very
sorry you cannot be here to give the
talk himself
so yeah let's talk about our paper
so in our paper we give new time memory
Traders for subset sum and we somehow
unify the quite diverse landscape of
trade-offs out there
by uh outperforming almost all of them
and those also translate to information
set decoding algorithms which are the
best algorithms to Tech code based
crypto and um
we also Implement our our techniques and
obtain new record computations and from
there we obtain a new bit security
estimates for suggested parameters
so let us Define the random subset sum
problem so for subset sum you're given n
integers mod 2 to the n and you're asked
to find a subset of them of size n over
2 set sums to some Target value t
and we will represent such a subset by a
binary Vector e of length n so it simply
indicates if the elements are part of
this subset or not so this Vector has
Heming weight and over 2 then and why
should we care well it's a cryptographic
hot problem which is uh post Quantum
secure but more to be fair it's it's
more an algorithmic tool in Crypt
analysis so better algorithms for for
subsets some have implications to to
other
um other hot problems as for example as
I mentioned with information set
decoding algorithms and information set
decoding algorithms use a lot of memory
in practice so this somehow motivates
studying time memory trade-offs
before I can explain our time memory
trade-offs we need some building blocks
some puzzle pieces
so we will first uh first discuss the
basic meet in the middle algorithm and
see a memory saving technique introduced
by schweppelin Shamir and then Bridge
our way via the representation technique
from holograph Graham and Jew to the
Becca coronjo algorithm which is a basis
for our trade-offs and then we will see
how our Traders work and how they fit in
the picture
for the basic meet in the middle
algorithm uh yeah you you have this sum
and you simply split it in two parts the
first n over two elements and the second
and over two elements and then you
enumerate both um for both halves you
enumerate the X I's and uh the
corresponding subset sums you store in
those lists here and then you simply
search for one element between those
lists that sums to T
and it's not hard to see that the these
lists are of size 2 to the N over two
because there are that many candidates
for the x is for each of the sums and
actually this yeah finding this uh the
subset sum that sums to T can be done in
time linear in the list by some sorting
and searching and so we get an algorithm
with time and memory complexity two to
Zen over two
[Music]
to improve the memory by splitting the
initial sum not in two but in four parts
in four parts of equal equal size n over
four elements so you get a four lists
you enumerate those candidates and uh so
how do we get from there to the solution
then
that's Again by emerging tool lists at a
time
but we cannot measure T now because we
these elements all of four of them sum
to T so we we merge on some artificial
constraint T1 mod 2 to the L where L is
smaller than n so it's like some l-bit
constraint that we introduce there and
then we perform the usual matching that
we did in the mid in the middle
but of course there's only one
combination in the in the lists that
sums to the to the solution so there's
only one T1 for which this will work
so we have we don't know it so we have
to iterate of it
and since we iterate over it uh you will
see that if you do the mass it's an
algorithm that has the same time
complexity as as
a meat in the middle but the space
complexity is only a square root of it
because we could start with smaller
lists but this initial splitting and for
for sums and
then we could keep the list small by
introducing this artificial constraint
so how do we improve uh time wise from
here
that's done by the representation
technique by hog of Graham and Jewel
and the idea is to first blow up the
search space which might seem like a bad
idea in the first place because if you
recall we could only improve with
algorithm because we started with
smaller initial lists if we now blow up
the search space and these lists will
become larger however the idea is also
to increase the amount of available
Solutions of representations of the
solution so how does this look like for
the meat in the middle we were using
this this joint elements in the list so
where we had where we're enumerating
them on N over two of the uh
yeah they had support on N over two of
the coordinates and
um
for the representation approach we the
elements have support over the full n
coordinates and this gives multiple
combinations to represent the solution
as some of such from such domain so
maybe that's a bit abstract let's look
into an example so here is the exemplary
solution is this uh this Vector of
lengths eight and weight four then there
are six different possibilities to split
the support of this Vector uh on two
vectors of length eight weight two
and more generally there are n over 2
choose n over four such possibilities
so in summary we if we use these domains
instead then we increase the domain size
from 2 to the N over 2 to 2 to the
0.181 n
but on the other hand we also increase
the amount of available solutions from
one to two to the N over 2. and we
already see the quotient is getting
better
but how do we get a better algorithm
from here because now if we simply
enumerate this search space we will
simply enumerate a solution multiple
times and we we will enumerate more than
before so the algorithm will be worse
so this is done by Becca coronchu
and therefore they they try to only uh
enumerate a respective fraction of the
search space such that we in expectation
find one of those representations
so how do we enumerate a 2 to the minus
n over a two fraction of the of the
search space
so here we start at the the root of a
tree where we will finally enumerate the
solution and we construct this solution
again as a sum of two elements from this
representation domains we've seen and we
will introduce some arbitrary constraint
mod 2 to the N over 2. so this is n over
two bit constraint and we have seen lag
in the shop at Shamir algorithm I think
I forgot to mention it like if we since
we know that the
uh that's a subset sum sums to T in
total if you fix the constraint for for
one side you know that you have to use T
minus this constraint on the other side
otherwise they do not sum to T in total
so meaning this is really a constraint
of of size of n over two bits giving us
this respective fraction that we are
looking for
so how do we construct this level one
lists now we could simply do a meet in
the middle to get to generate them so we
split those uh lengths n weight n over
four vectors in uh lengths n over two
weight n over eight vectors so if we
concatenate them we get what we what we
need
but we already see that here the level
two lists they are larger than the level
one list which is not optimal so nothing
prevents you from just repeatedly
applying this like adding another level
of representations representing Things N
wait for weight n over four vectors as
sum of lengths n weight n over eight
vectors
introducing a respective constraint so
that you only enumerate one of those
representations and from there you go in
level three to a meet in the middle
so modulo some technicalities further
improvements Etc this is how the Becca
core algorithm roughly works and now we
can talk about our new trade-offs
so here we have a similar illustration
we just removed this fixed constraints
of n over 4 and N over 2 we exchanged by
this variables L1 and L2 and we will
indicate subtrees by these Dash boxes so
the main tree is T and the tree T2
contains level 2 and subsequent lists
and so forth
so in the bcj algorithm we choose L2
such that there is one representation of
the solution surviving this constraints
and if we indeed if we choose it smaller
then there will be multiple of them
surviving which is what we do not want
and if we choose it bigger then of
course we're not guaranteed to generate
a solution at all
but of course if we choose it bigger
then we do also generate less uh less
other elements not only less
representation so we have somehow a
measure to control the size of those
lists
and of course this will propagate so if
we have smaller lists on level 2 we have
smaller lists on level one and so forth
and of course we are not guaranteed to
generate a solution so what we can do is
we can iterate like similar to the
shopping algorithm we can iterate over
this constraint we can reconstruct this
subtree T2 multiple times
an appropriate amount of times that we
overstretched this representations that
are at our disposal
and then we can apply this actually to
any level of the tree so we can again
introduce a larger constraint on on
level one and repeat the substrate
construction at level one multiple times
such that in expectation we generate one
of those
Solutions
and uh yeah so there are some
technicalities that I'm leaving out here
so which actually enable us to somehow
uh control the cost for each subtree
General generation so that we can ensure
that cheaper subtrees are generated more
often and therefore we decrease the time
complexity further
okay this gives us control over all the
sizes in the tree but level three lists
here they are at some point they will
dominate the running the memory
consumption so what we can do is we can
exchange this meet in the middle by uh
as we've seen uh this is a memory
reduction technique or more generally
you can use a framework called
dissection
okay let us put this a bit into numbers
so here we have a plot of the time
exponent over the memory exponent
so the time and memory are exponential
the time is 2 to the Tetter and the
memory is two to the Lambda n on the
y-axis we see Teta on the x-axis we see
Lambda
we see that if the memory is not limited
although if we have unlimited memories
then the bcj algorithm in the lower
right is the best choice and then we see
as a dashed lines uh
collection of more than 10 different
trade-offs that were found optimal in
different memory regimes and there's a
dotted line or improved trade-off
and actually there is an improvement of
the bcj algorithm which is pbss
algorithm
uh which yeah improves slightly and and
we can also apply our technique to this
algorithm to to obtain an even better
trade-off
last but not least let us have a look in
to the results for the information set
decoding algorithms so we here we have a
similar plot with the time and memory
complexity of two modern ISD algorithms
the mmt and the bgmm algorithm
and uh you need to know that those
algorithms they can trivially
interpolate it
can trivially be interpolated to a
memoryless algorithm which is a solid
line we see but if you instead of
trivially interpolating uh use our
improved trade uh trade-offs for the
enumeration part of those algorithms you
get the dashed lines and very
interestingly for the mmt algorithm we
get a result that is similar to the
shopping result that we decrease the
memory consumption without any time
penalty
yes as I said we also implemented this
and we obtained new records on
quasi-cyclic code decoding and also
better running times on on mcalees
and in this table we see basically the
bit security reduction in comparison to
previous works so for example for make a
list if the memory is not limited for
the category once parameter set which
gives security equivalent to aes128 we
obtain one bit improved estimates
sounds surprising that the time Army
trade-offs gives an improvement if the
memory is not limited but you've seen
that the mmt algorithm the memory just
got reduced and memory is quite
expensive in practice so we obtain an
improvement by this fewer memory access
costs
similar for bike and hqc and for uh but
we see that for maclease for example if
we restrict the memory to 2 to 60 bits
then that's where our trade-offs can
shine uh where we get five to six bits
of reduced
um security estimates
so summarizing we obtained significant
speed ups for in the restricted memory
regime
and we unify the subset sum landscape of
of different trade-offs to only two
trade-offs one hour trade-off and one
that is optimal in the very low memory
regime
and yeah if we give the first
non-trivial trade-offs for ISD with
immediate practical impact
thank you very much the papers online
and the code is on Floyd's GitHub
is there any question
just a quick question um for the
restricted memory did you get those
results for bike two or uh for the
restricted memory so in the bike and hqc
case the algorithms uh don't use that
much memory so even for the optimal
instantiations they use two tools of 50
to 40. this is why we why we don't have
some here in the slide thank you
okay uh so under GitHub you have all the
experiments all the code is available
sorry now I know what the canyon had for
a problem because I couldn't understand
it well ah sorry uh under GitHub page
you have also experiments and the code
ah yeah on the guitar page the code is
online the experiments so I think Floyd
provided the scripts to rerun the
experiments I don't know if all the
experimental data that is basically used
to generate things later is also in
there in like raw format but I can check
okay thank you very much so thanks
speaker again
[Applause]
so the last talk of this session is
um a new algebraic approach to the
regular syndrome decoding problem and
implication for PCG construction by
Pierre Barrio and Martin oy garden and
here I will give the talk
right so yes this is a joint work with a
moctan and we present a
an algebraic attack on the regular
syndrome decoding problem
and with with that we we want to to
attack parameters from pseudonym
correlation generators
so let's start with the decoding problem
so the right skew so you're given this
Matrix G of size K times then and this
Vector Y which has length n
and the goal is to distinguish whether
this Y is of the form mg plus C where e
is your error Vector of amino AC or Y Is
uniformly Random
see also you have a row formulation
which is equivalent in theory which uses
a parity check Matrix h and a syndrome s
and finally maybe some of you are more
familiar with the LPN assumption so here
you can view LPN where the number of
sample is n and the secret size is K but
here the number of samples you must
imagine it as always of the form K to
the one plus Alpha where Alpha will be
constant between 0 and 1. so you don't
have so many samples
and also the noise so the ratio T Over N
is a extremely small it's not constant
so in this talk we are interested in the
regular version of the problem and it
consists in choosing a very particular L
distribution so how do we do
um you assume that small n is equal to
capital N times T where T is still the
weight and to generate your error first
you will pick a t random blocks of
length capital N but of I mean weight
all one and the final error will be the
concatenation of these blocks so by
construction you see that your error has
in Detroit T but it's very particular
the non-zero coordinates will be a very
specific position
okay
so why are you interested in this
problem
in fact already the decoding problem or
LPN in this quite part of Learners
regime is already quite useful in in
Secure computation
and on top of that if you add the
regular distribution you can get even
more efficient constructions
okay
so here I have taken the example of a
pseudo-random correlation generator so
these are specific Primitives in this
area
and their goal is to generate what we
call a correlated Randomness so this is
a very useful ingredient to build such
Primitives
so here I will briefly mention one
example whose goal is to construct
Vector already so which was introduced
by burrito
so I won't Define a vectorally but just
imagine that you want to produce
some additive shares of a long Vector U
which must look zero on them so it will
share between two different parties
so for that they rely for the first step
on function signaturing and what disc
Primitives allows you to have is
additive shares of the first Vector
which is long but which is sparse which
is Vector e
and actually in our case it will play
the role of the error why because the
second step is where LPN shows up you
will obtain this final Vector U by
applying the Assumption on this error
vector
and the important here is that you have
two ways to do it
either you are in the Primal setting and
in this case the vector U that you send
is your noisy code word y so mg plus c
or instead you can use your dual setting
and in this case you send your syndrome
so e times the transpose of H
and why is it important in our case
is that because it will lead to
completely different parameters
especially the code rates K Over N will
be extremely low in the Primal setting
but mostly constants in the dual
settings so think about one fourth or
one Earth
and finally if you use a regular error
you can gain
in the first step the cost of FSS will
be smaller
okay
so now in terms of attacks on the
regular syndrome decoding problem or LSD
the thing is that they do not exploit
the regular distribution
so you have this full claw attack or
which is called also gaussian attack so
the goal is to guess a k or three
positions in your vector and then you
just solve a linear system
you'll also have isds which have been
just mentioned by Andre and you have a
statistical decoding this is a similar
technique it's just the Dual version but
the thing is that in this tiny algorithm
we don't really care because uh in fact
the folklore attack will be the best one
okay
our contribution is to give a new type
of attack on RSD which is an algebraic
attack
and this time it will be really specific
to the regular noise it doesn't really
apply to to the plain version of the
problem okay and the nice thing is that
we can beat some previous attacks
especially when the code rates is low we
will see why in a few slides so these
are typically the parameters which are
used in the Primal setting
okay
so the first ingredient in in an
algebraic attack is an algebraic system
so how you murder your problem into a
set of equations and here I will
describe the case of a binary field okay
because it's a bit more simple
okay so my unknowns in my system will be
these error coordinates I have n and I
also denot by EI one of the T blocks in
my error
so clearly the first set of equation is
this one it's quite naive because you
know that the r coordinates are in F2 so
you have these equations for free
so the two other parts are a bit more
interesting they rely on a regular
distribution because here in this Vector
e i we know that there is only one
non-zero coordinates so this means that
if you do the product between two
distinct coordinates in this Vector you
will get zero so this gives you this
second set of equations
and finally over F2 you even know that
this non-zero coordinate is equal to one
so this means that if you sum all the
elements in my Vector I get one and this
gives me linear equations here
and the final system that I get I just
have to add this parity check equation
so which comes from your IIT check
Matrix
okay so what are those equations they
are linear in our error coordinates and
how many do I have just as many as a
number of roses in age so n minus k
and here you have to notice that n minus
K is also equal to n times 1 minus the
code rate so you understand then when
the code rate is lower we can gain over
these parts and that explains so why our
attack is more efficient here
okay
so now uh I have my system let's talk
about solving algorithms
so maybe you're familiar with Grosvenor
basis or linearization Etc but yeah it
doesn't really matter so much what
matters is that you can express them in
this kind of way so the first step is to
start with your system
and you multiply the equations by
monomials okay so once you have done
that typically you will fill a matrix
which is called the Mercury Matrix which
is this thing
here I describe the make only Matrix of
the homogeneous version this means that
I start with polynomial fi's which are
homogeneous
I multiply them in such a way that all
the polynomials that I get this
polynomial modifies or all of the greedy
and then each row of my Matrix will go
into such a polynomial and the column
will be indexed by all the monomials of
the greedy
and actually in the homogeneous case
there is a famous result which states
that at some point doing linear algebra
on this matrices up to a degree that
which is called capital D here I can
solve the system
and clearly in fact this degree capital
D which is often called solving degree
is a key parameter to estimate the
complexity because once this degree is
known the complexity is just the linear
algebra in this Matrix so essentially
you just have to know the number of
columns or rows if you imagine the
Matrix is square and this number is
exponential in in capital okay
so in the rest of the talk I will try to
explain how we derived the value of
capital D for our system
so this is the key part in the paper
because you see that although over all
the system is quite nice
and we are going to do that with what we
call the earlier series of of an ideal
so I will consider this notion makes
sense for homogeneous ideal so here I
pick nomogeneous ideal ion I also denote
by Rd the vector space which is spanned
by all the polynomials of the greedy and
finally I to the D is just the
intersection of I and this Vector space
and in the case of an homogeneous ideal
I get a vector space of finite dimension
so the message about this object is that
Albert series are really nice it's a
very great object but sadly they are not
known in general for
most of the polynomial systems that we
have
so why is this object nice so here you
have the definition but the important
thing is that you you see the wrong of
the Mercury Matrix appearing so if we
know this inversaries we can recover the
wrong of the microl matrices and once we
have the wrong we can predict the
termination of the algorithm
also if you take a bit more time on this
definition you notice here that you have
a dimension of caution spaces and this
is typically the way that we are going
to compute them Computing the first this
Dimension and then it will be trivial to
get the final adversaries
okay
so here I don't have an homogeneous
ideal so I need to get one and for that
I will take my polynomials and I will
cut all the lower degree parts so I get
this system sh so this is a system which
doesn't really make sense to be solved
because we have lost the information on
the lower degree part but it will be
important for the analysis
and another important property of this
system is that it is Zero Dimensional uh
so very quickly this means that my
inverse series will be a polynomial
and The crucial Point here is the degree
of this polynomial because it will be
rated in a very strong way to the degree
capital D we are interested in so
essentially uh in the remaining of the
the talk I will just explain how we
derive the polynomial and once we have
the polynomial we can
derive a cost for for solving process
okay
and the important thing is that we are
going to keep these two parts in our
system
one after the other because one has a
very strong structure it is this part
which just comes from the regular
distribution
and it's structural but hopefully we can
manage to to analyze it easily because
you see that here my homogeneous part of
iOS degree are already specific
they are just monomials
so in fact we can get the dimension of
the quotient spaces here in a very easy
way just by doing Simple combinatorics
we count the number of monomials which
cannot be divisible by these two set of
monomers
and once I have my
my Dimensions I just can recover the
first inversaries really easily
but now there is a remaining part which
comes from the party check equations and
here it's a bit trickier because
because
um I mean we cannot really analyze them
in the way that we have done for the
structural part and here we require an
assumption
so what the motivation here is that I
said before that
um
were not known in general but it turns
out that for random systems these are
one of the only classes of systems for
which they are known
so essentially we are going to treat a
disparity check equations as random
equations
the only subtlety here is that we
already have a quotient ring that we
have analyzed we need the randomness of
these equations in this question twin so
this is our assumption here
so if you're familiar with it it is
really close to the notion of regularity
or more precisely here semi-regularity
which was introduced by birthday and
forger okay
so from this assumption we can obtain a
distillation for the adversaries
so here you have the previous series
that I have computed before and here you
must see you must understand this Factor
as depending on the number of equation
and minus K that we have added here and
the fact that Z appears linearly is just
means that we have added linear
equations okay
and finally I said that we wanted the
polynomial so here we don't have a
polynomial so we just truncate after the
first negative coefficient because since
my polynomial count dimension of vector
spaces negative coefficients will not
make sense
so finally if I put all the results
together I obtain this inverse voice
okay
so record you uh this inverse series was
a polynomial and the degree of this
polynomial was highly related to the
solving degree of a system because
we add essentially D minus 1 which is
equal to the degree of this polynomial
so how do we obtain it in practice we
conjecture a generating service with
infinitely many terms are we and we are
interested only in the positive ones we
just pick the first known positive
coefficient this is an index and from
this index we can recover the degree
capital
okay and finally when once we have the
degree capital D the rest is just
trivial we just have the cost of linear
algebra I I assume that the Matrix is
square here so I just have the number of
columns and the number of columns is
just the number of monomials okay and
here you notice that the linear algebra
exponent I consider a dense linear
algebra I do gaussian elimination I
apply traditional equation
so actually the best cost that we obtain
is not really this plane technique there
are small improvements but I will go
very quickly because they are really
standard and if you want to grab the
description in the paper
so the first one is what we call the
e-breed approach so it's finding a
trade-off between system solving and
fixing variables in the initial system
so here uh I I recall you that this
error has a very small weight a very
small t
so the more clever way to fix variable
in this case is just fixing variables to
zero in our Vector because with good
probability it will be the good guess
and if you think about it it's quite
close to the an algorithm for instance
the virtual algorithm also which is
equivalent to Branch but here
we are going to fix much less variables
we don't need to fix K variables we just
need to fix the right amount so that the
system that we obtain after fixing these
variables is easier to solve
I have another
trick which is called Excel with demand
so the ID is to use the fact that in our
microly Matrix all the rules are really
I mean the main color Matrix is pairs
because the the row weight only depends
on the weight of a parity check
equations even at a year degree so at a
degree we hope to gain on this part so
there is just a subtlety about the
termination of this algorithm but we
analyze it in the paper also
and just to conclude I will give some
numbers so maybe some of you just care
about that so here are all the numbers
so in here I just pick parameters which
correspond to the Primal settings so
here if you compute the code rates K
Over N you notice that it's very small
and in fact the the rules for which we
gain the most correspond to either even
smaller good weight yeah
okay
so essentially it was what I wanted to
say
so if you have any questions I think we
have time thank you
[Applause]
is there any question
yes just maybe something stupid but
concerning the hybrid techniques did you
try the stuff we did with Vanessa where
you just do hybrid in a weird way that
that is slightly better for for concrete
Dimensions actually for the hybrid case
we have not been very far because we
were quite concerned in how fixing
variables changes the analysis of the
initial system we did we add
for instance the only ways we consider
if the approach was fixing a
error free coordinates the same way in
each block almost which gives us I mean
we can keep the same analysis
essentially
we also tried fixing variables in some
blocks but not in others but we have not
I think we could imagine any involved
way in fixing variables uh like any ISD
algorithm you can try to interpolate
with this and you could fix the hybrid
in this way so yeah maybe we should
discuss this offline but it seems that
the yeah what you really would like is
to fix a variable in a way that would
make Big D decrease so that you get
something better in the end yeah it's a
good method okay see you
thanks for a nice talk did you also run
experiments to see if the systems coming
from the parity matrices do indeed
behave semi-regularly
um we tested for if you take a random
parametric check Matrix it works fine
the only thing we could try also I think
is in this kind of primitive sometimes
they choose a party check Matrix which
is the local so sometimes the weight in
the byte segment fees is low we have not
tried but I would say that
um
if the system deviates from a random
system it doesn't really imply that I
mean maybe if we do some further
analysis we can even obtain better
results if we I mean the the structure
can be like a difficulty to analyze but
it can be also benefit for the attack so
I don't know
thanks
hi thanks for the great talk and the
nice analysis can you clarify the
novelty compared to the Arora gay
algorithm over structured LPN
um in terms of
I'm not so aware of what they did I'm
more familiar with technique for lwe
it's in the same place it's the same
okay so I think I mean I'm the same but
it's in the same okay so I would say
that the novelty in our work is not
about the modeling because it's a super
naive okay it's about the analysis
because I think that our reggae was
always analyzed assuming that the
equations are regular
oh I mean they didn't really do some
theoretical analysis of the behavioral
system because they notice that the
system behaved as random one in our case
we will try to analyze it
and I think the most interesting thing
is that this kind of system where you
have a random part on a part which is
restructured we can find it in other
parts of crypto analysis and the I think
it can be applied to other kind of
system like this so it's the analysis
that is yes
I think it was very nice thank you
okay so thank you and uh yes we have to
thank all the speaker of the session
[Applause]
so the next session is at 11 40.