well first off thanks to confidence for
having speak I really appreciate the
opportunity and I'm looking forward to
share to you guys I've given some talks
on similar to common topics before but
this will be my first time giving kind
of this inner iteration of the topic of
neurodiversity hiring in different
companies so to begin a little bit about
me I'm a cyber threat researcher with
IBM's x-force iris I am also the CFO of
mental health hackers advocating for
mental health issue awareness in the
security industry and running events to
help kind of bring awareness to that and
support individuals struggling with
mental health issues we are looking for
sponsors so if that's something you want
to talk about please let me know and
then the reason I'm giving this talking
kind of the key qualification I I have
if you want to look at it that way is I
am an autistic security individual
working in the industry to start off I
want to give some disclaimer zhh first I
I don't have any formal background in
psychology or any subject medical
training in this area so I'm not
claiming I do I have read a lot of books
and articles but in terms of real
expertise I don't exactly have that yet
I have future plans but for the time
being please know that my my talk is not
a medically certified presentation but
because of work I've done through mental
health hackers and giving my talks again
although I'm not a therapist I do have a
lot of people who message me so I have
had the exposure to a wide variety of
issues that individuals are facing in
the industry which kind of gives me a
unique background on this and lastly as
I said in my about me I am an autistic
individual so a lot of this is personal
experience I'm not really sure how I
ended up in Poland speaking in front of
50 people about this topic but I did so
clearly something is going right for me
so start off let's talk about a high
overview of neurodiversity
essentially the concept the way IBM
their kind of catchphrase is to treasure
wild bucks so individuals who think
differently in this talk I'm going to be
focusing on autism ADHD and bipolar
disorder specifically but really at a
high level the concepts and the key
themes in here are going to apply to any
individuals schizophrenic individuals
individuals facing anxiety disorders
depression those kinds of things so so
the key theme applies as neurodiversity
which is why I gave the title itself
another disclaimer again neurodiversity
just like any other diversity within the
subset of individuals facing different
conditions autism bipolar disorder etc I
cannot give a presentation that fully
classifies all those situations or the
key phrases kind of saying as people say
is once you've met an autistic person
you've met one autistic person you
haven't met opening out to every
autistic person so I will talk about
like different traits and different
roles that will be well-suited but I'm
not saying that every individual
interested in security has to fall into
those roles or will match those specific
traits one thing I found interesting
when I was looking at kind of the
diversity within these subgroups is a
tweet that came out from an autism
advocate she kind of asked autistic
people like you know there's a lot of
stereotypes which which to unify and so
someone said yeah I can't do math I hate
math
stop saying autistic people are good at
math another person was like eye contact
it's great I love looking at people in
the eyes and then shortly after she said
okay there's stereotypes but some
stereotypes are fitting so which
stereotypes do you follow along the
lines with and there you go I'm good at
math and I'm terrible at eye contact so
just because some stereotypes are true
and will apply to some individuals and
are actual psychological traits involved
I
contact there is many autistic people a
psychological incapability to establish
eye contact but it doesn't mean every
autistic individual can't so the same
things with everything I say
know that there's plenty of individuals
who don't fit those keys so keep that in
mind
so why at a high level should you be
considering neuro diversity initiatives
looking at individuals for your team
first you're gonna have a wider spectrum
of capabilities by hiring only
neurotypical individuals you have a huge
area of thinking why various thinking
patterns that you're not gonna get from
a neurotypical individual one analogy is
sports and I used to try and like list
different positions in American football
but then I realized I know nothing about
sports and so that kind of failed but
the general concept is you don't you
could have the the best goalies in the
world but if you put all the best
girlies on the same team you're not
gonna have the best soccer football team
in the world because sports they require
a wide diversity of skills you want
people who are fast you want people are
strong you want people are good kickers
who are good goalies building a team
based on one really good skill set is
gonna make you good at that one that
single thing but when you come up
against teams with a wide diversity of
backgrounds of thinking patterns you're
gonna be more capable in the long run
second by supporting individuals with
disorders as they're likely already some
in your organization that you may not
even know about creating an environment
in which they feel comfortable and are
happier they're going to be more
passionate they're going to produce
better work you're gonna have a longer
term employees staying there because
they feel that their environment is
supportive
however happier employees isn't really a
level talk when you
tell them you want to hire some people
create hiring initiatives focused on
neurodiversity a CEO isn't gonna think
happier employees depending on the
situation is worth the costs so what's
the sea level speak of this first reduce
staff turnover so a statistic related to
this is that direct replacements cost
for a role can reach as high as 50 to 60
percent of an employee's annual salary
and as the total associated costs such
as retraining up that new employee and
all the different equipment recycling
and all that you can reach up to 290
percent to 200 percent of an annual
salary just to get a new employee and
which obviously that's a lot of money
being spent especially in the
cybersecurity industry we have a very
high turnover rate due to the demand
when you there is always someone willing
to pay you more to go to their company
and 33 percent of companies it's found
that employers believe that employees
with disabilities if the environment is
cater really works with them they're
less likely to leave just because it is
more difficult for a neurodiverse
employee to find an environment they
thrive in so there's a lot less of a
chance of employee turnover which in
turn equals cost which you know the CFO
and CEO are interesting keeping down
second is consumer appeal for example
the number of people number of children
diagnosed with autism plus their direct
relatives such as their parents
grandparents and cousins counting that
out in the US alone is about 55 million
people meaning 17 percent of the US
population in some way has a
relationship to an autistic individual
was found that consumers are more likely
to switch to a company a different brand
or a different provider if they have
show outward support for a cause that
they related that they
feel connected to so that's 17 percent
of the US population who if they look at
a company that's saying we support
autistic individuals we want to help
them you know Aaron autistic employees
are speaking out saying they're happy
there's a good chance that you'll have
consumers who are looking to switch to
your company partially based on the fact
that they know you're supportive of a
cause that's close to them and
regulatory compliance this one I kind of
if he putting in because it is kind of a
controversial thing and somewhat and I
guess it may be less applicable to
Poland as I don't know you're you're
hiring laws but in the u.s. at least a
lot of fiber security companies probably
most of them have a contract with the
federal government for services or
products or whatever they may need and
if you work with the federal government
or any government agencies they require
a certain percentage of your staff be
disabled in some way including what are
considered neurological disabilities
autism bipolar depression so whether a
good reason or not if you really need to
pull strings with the c-level tell them
that those autistic ploys you're going
in are meeting a quota so one thing I
really try to hit on in these talks and
when I'm talking with both neurodiverse
individuals and managers is it's a
give-and-take relationship in the power
of neurodiversity by Thomas Armstrong he
talks about some key principles
associated with neurodiversity and one
of the first ones principle number five
I believe is that success in life is
based on adapting one's brains to the
needs of the surrounding environment I
as an autistic individual live in a
world designed for neurotypicals and
thus I have to adjust some of the ways
that I live day to day
in order to adapt to the normal world
but as I said my key point it's a
give-and-take
part of success in life is also based on
modifying my surrounding environment to
fit the needs of my innate brain this is
called Nate niche construction which
I'll kind of mention that term again
later but basically though I can do
certain things to to meet the
environment that I live in and learn to
live in that environment my success is
also partially rely like that I need to
be in an in an environment that's suited
well for me too so I'm guest start off
kind of focusing on autism spectrum
disorders this is probably obviously
when I'm closest to on the one that most
healthy comes from personal experience
so so the challenges I and other
autistic individuals may face our
communication whether that be
interpersonal communication speaking in
front of large groups obviously I've
done okay with that but interpersonal
communication knowing how to communicate
with coworkers and my manager is a bit
something that I more challenges with
kind of an obsessive nature not
necessarily always impacting the job but
it can impact the personality in the way
that interacting with an autistic
individual can be much different and
sometimes an uncomfortable experience or
something that is considered weird by a
neurotypical individual who is is seeing
the obsessive behavior you know someone
who you've probably encountered as most
of us have probably encountered autistic
individuals and it's that person who
wants to talk about trains for half an
hour no matter how hard you try to
change the subjects it just won't work
and eventually you're in a situation
where you're like how do I get out of
this and so that that kind of thing
though it doesn't impact the ability to
do the job once you get in a situation
like that you're less likely to want to
hire or work with such an individual
lastly weak executive functioning and
there's some areas of plan
and how work is completed and the
understanding of how to perform work and
business functions there's some
struggles in those areas however saw the
strengths and extreme attention to
detail autistic people see things on a
more granular level than neurotypical
people which of course can be a great
strength for security professionals
expanding further to IT an example is
Quality Assurance testers you'll find a
lot of autistic people in those roles
and that a lot of companies with autism
hiring initiatives are hiring for
quality assurance testers because we're
the kind of people who can pick at every
little issue and find all the problems
which can be annoying in a general sense
where that's not an important part of
your job which is why roles where you
know it's a good thing when you're
pointing out the tiniest of mistakes is
is a strength and lastly high
productivity one of my strengths is I
can probably do three to four times the
amount of work that a co-worker can do
I'm not sure why but it's something I've
found in multiple jobs and that I've
heard from other employers of autistic
individuals it's just how my brain works
I'm able to do more work so you're
getting you know four times the value
when you're paying me you're paying me
the same as another employee but you're
getting four times the value so or so so
nish construction like some things again
this is definitely not an inclusive list
but again I give the little things that
don't hurt an employer in any way but
are often overlooked to some things that
can be super important modulation of
sensory input one of the big aspects of
autism is hypersensitivity whether it be
two textures sounds taste that kind of
thing for me I have a severe version to
certain textures of food which doesn't
really affect my work
stuff but it is something where this
kind of makes me weird I seem like a
picky three-year-old when I'm eating but
I just have a lot of concerns like for
example work thing is I'm very very
particular about what I wear I struggle
to do my job if I'm not comfortable and
so finding roles where I can wear what I
want you know obviously appropriate
clothes but I can wear jeans and a
t-shirt and not have to dress up in a
blouse and dress pants and stuff like
that that was something I literally
considered when I was job hunting is
what do I have to wear for work and I it
was negative points if I had to dress in
business attire and then stimming this
is again something you may see kind of a
stereotype of the flapping hands for me
it's when I'm sitting down typically I
cannot stop shaking my left leg and
depending on the situation and my
emotions or my my energy level it may be
pretty like noticeable but in the end
like does it really affect you if
somebody's moving a body limb a little
bit so not not creating a judgemental
environment or pointing that out and
just accepting that it's something the
person does can make more of a
difference than you think so
some negative job laments some jobs that
individuals may struggle with
multitasking something where the person
is working on one thing and then you
want them to switch to something on no
notice or like here do this and this and
this and this all at the same time by
the end of the day high level of
socialization again I've met autistic
people who love like being I know some
people autistic IBM errs who are in HR
roles
or who travel to customer sites but
there's a lot of us who would prefer to
work in an office alone and you know I
like having a team but I don't like
having to go out to other teams or
having to work with customers so I fit
well in a role where I just have my team
to talk to and there's other liaisons to
deal with manager
other teams lastly tied to the nish
construction rolls with a century
overload are probably going to be more
difficult roles to handle okay a
positive job elephants roles we're
autistic individuals are gonna tend to
exceed our ones with routine repetitive
tasks and logic so we we like to know
what we're doing what's going on
so roles such as incident response are a
bit more difficult I love doing digital
forensics and incident response but I
admit that the but not knowing what's
going on or like last minute like hey
you got do this now that's a bit more of
a challenge whereas a routine in a role
I am now with threat Intel where I have
a task and I'm working on that task and
is kind of procedural I like that
repetitive tasks so again less security
specific but an example that people
understand like data entry that's
something that there's a strengthened
and even better about that is that's
typically the roles that most nerves
typicals hate the mundane repetitive
tasks which those are the ones that I
love so my current role there's a lot of
Intel data entry into our database and a
lot of like cataloguing of data and a
lot of like fixing of you know human
error type things and nobody loves doing
that but I love data entry and
categorization and so I'm the one who
will spend hours sorting through the
database looking for any typos and
fixing those and going through all the
data and tagging it so that that gives
me a strength and I like it
others like not doing it and so it works
out for everyone
and again logical tasks tasks where I
can I can figure out problems and follow
a path of logic again there's creative
autistic people who who aren't as strong
in the logic areas but the one of the
common thinking patterns is logical
so what are some example draw barrels
matching this obviously I'm in a threat
research role and I find that's very
suitable typically it's a set schedule
you know of a specific time I'm not
being called at 2:00 in the morning for
an incident I'm looking through data on
processing data I'm understanding a
logical path throughout hunting again
that attention to detail really comes in
with threat hunting part that being able
to sit through millions of logs to
identify a specific activity the
pivoting I love the logic of I have a IP
or hash and I want to find related
indicators I want to find malicious
activity on a network based on that
stuff so the hunting roll and then
vulnerability analysis I've done a bit
of this and it's not really my cup of
tea but the part site there were parts I
did like about it just having these
reports raw data and having to sift
through it and find ok what's actually
relevant to my company what do these
vulnerabilities mean how should I
prioritize that kind of thing so moving
on to bipolar disorder I worked with a
bipolar security analyst on this section
which I'll mention later who is and so I
I've kind of got both some research in
books and his opinion so some challenges
faced obviously the key characteristic
of bipolar disorder is the mood swings
the ups and downs euphoria depression
rage typically not great for a work job
that you just decide one day you don't
feel like working or you you know you
come in angry and you don't want to deal
with people when your job deals with
people so a second aspects typically
less with bipolar in general but more
Soccio a schizo affective disorder is
psychosis I've the bipolar and
schizoaffective individuals I've talked
to said that really becomes a problem at
work when they're in their space no one
understands what they're going through
and you know they can't focus on work
with the psychosis kick in and
kind of related to the psychosis the
distracted thoughts especially during
the major mood swings all those thoughts
you're having distracting from the work
the strengths though there's pretty
strong empathy and individuals with
bipolar disorder energy during manic
states during a manic state a bipolar
individual gets that that passion that
high productivity that kind of other
things similar to what I talked about in
autism and creativity so there there is
that creative spin that not all logical
security people have so nish
construction
bipolar individuals are going to be well
suited in an environment where they feel
that meaning purpose they have a goal
that they have to focus on hands-on
environments where they get to work with
their hands and also being able to work
for oneself as opposed to being in a
more traditional environment working for
an employer so so the example job roles
cybersecurity analysts is a good role
penetration testing and social
engineering where the key ones though I
kind of talk through with some bipolar
individuals is kind of that empathy and
the also the the nature of kind of
penetration and social engineering like
jobs people too a bit more flexible of a
schedule and being able to work in that
period of mania and and work through
that so that's that's those are good
roles for those individuals last key
category is the attention deficit
hyperactivity disorder so this is
definitely very common I'm sure everyone
in this room knows someone who has been
diagnosed with ADHD if you haven't
yourself and it's very common in the
security industry mental health hackers
we had someone come forward needing help
and we posted on Twitter hey can we get
some feedback and dozens and dozens and
dozens of tweets
from ADHD security people talking about
their experiences so so the main
challenges are weak executive
functioning as with autism again that's
things like planning prioritization
scheduling things that are kind of
business centric skills that are
typically important job role are more
challenging for individuals then
hyperactivity being one of the key
aspects of ADHD kind of not wanting to
sit still in an office all day and
struggling in certain areas of that
focus maintaining focus strengths
actually include hyper focus which seems
contradictory to the fact kind of both
the stigmas and and those kinds of
things that most people assume it's
super distracted they actually ADHD
people are able to hyper focus on
certain things it just isn't always the
thing they should be hyper focusing on
but in a state where they are focused
and interested on a task it's an extreme
level producing high productivity and
great work and then hyperactivity again
though it was on the challenges slide
it's kind of also strength in the way
that in the right job role that
hyperactivity can be channeled in a way
that produces high quality work a lot of
work high productivity and stuff like
that niche construction the kind of
environments that these individuals will
thrive most in in most cases a role with
physical movement being able to use that
energy in a physical way as opposed to
sitting in a cubicle for eight hours a
day an environment would change where
you know whether it be TAS change
location change role change that kind of
thing being able to swap back and forth
high stimulation environment similar to
the energy being able to channel that
hyperactivity into an environment that
acceptable and hands-on activity is
generally more interesting to such an
individual as opposed to rote routine
activity so the job elements kind of
translated from that niche construction
that may be ideal for such an individual
is being able to travel or move around
frequently whether that means being able
to travel to different states countries
cities for engagements or it just means
movie around in the buildings or in a
location to be able to channel that
hyper activity again working with one's
hands being actively involved with new
situations almost opposite to what I
like about the routine same day day ADHD
individuals prefer to be able to change
what they're working on and see new
things and try new things
handling emergencies you'll actually
find a high concentration of ADHD
individuals working in law enforcement
or in fire departments because that
environment of kind of high adrenaline
is something that that works very well
and working for oneself another place
where you'll find a high concentration
of a PhD individuals is CEOs of
companies they tend to thrive so example
job roles from the emergency perspective
and kind of correlating the love for law
enforcement work and fire department
work is Incident Response errs obviously
that correlations there that being able
to chase down a threat the adrenaline of
an attacker and a network figuring out
what happens stake of the company is on
the line is the perfect environment
hunting being able to get into a hyper
focused move and follow all those paths
to find an attacker again the adrenaline
of we know something bad is happening
but we've got to get the whole scope and
consulting roles specifically because of
that being able to travel move around
and then especially most consulting
roles here
security you're on an engagement doing
something for a few weeks but then
you're off to something else so that
that change in role so where the key
takeaways for all the potential people
in this room for the neuro-diverse in
the role so the lessons I've learned and
the things that I recommend to people
you got to recognize your strengths and
weaknesses I know what I'm good at
I know what I'm bad at and I've learned
to kind of articulate that to my
managers because I know that I can
thrive in a situation where I can
leverage my strengths and I know that
bad things are going to be happen if I
put in a situation where my weaknesses
are you come out more I learned what
works for me
that niche constructor that that kind of
learning to work in an environment I'm
in there's some things that I have to
learn to do differently that individuals
that are neurotypical may not for
example kind of related to my like
clothing fabric sensitivity these pairs
of jeans I have six pairs of them and
those are all my jeans because you know
I'd rather have six pairs of the same
jeans I don't have to think about what
pair of pants I'm wearing in the morning
I don't have to worry about trying and
picking out no clothes and like those
little things that are kind of weird and
maybe hard to you're out I found are
like the things that reduce the stress
in my life and help me kind of maintain
the balance and the peace and so I I
save everything I buy on Amazon so that
I can hit reorder if if the pair pants
rips I can just replace them with a new
pair quick and then self-improvement is
self-care recognizing that that you do
have a medical condition that requires
treatment and care whatever that tree
may be again that's finding what works
for you maybe you want to be on
medication maybe you don't therapy is an
option
working out exercising alone can be that
self-care you need
to feel better about yourself but
whatever is making sure that you you
also take into account that you are
treating a medical condition and so you
need to identify what's needed for that
and take the appropriate iemon steps to
do that as an organization if you're in
the c-suite or if your organization is
looking to you for recommendations what
can you do well first promote
neurodiversity show to potential
employees to consumers to your staff
that you are a company that respects
neurodiverse individuals and even
promotes that and so beginning just the
the culture of here here is the kind of
organization we want to portray
ourselves and be a kind of environment
we want to make look into neurodiverse
hiring initiatives
there's many big companies search autism
at work there's this kind of overlapping
organization composed of different
companies such as JPMorgan Microsoft IBM
and sa P just to name a few that all
have hiring programs internally
specifically focused on creating a
recruitment process that works for for
autistic and other neurodiverse
individuals since the hiring process is
another aspect they handle differently
there's there's programs already set up
for example IBM in order for us to do a
hiring program it's not just some people
internally we work with an organization
called specialist stern where basically
they are finding and working with and
training autistic individuals and then
hoping place them with potential
employers who are contracting with them
kind of like hiring a recruitment agency
but focused on autism support managers
and employees so create an organization
where if them as hey I have this
employee I need to make this on
Commendation can we make this work be
willing to work with those managers and
employees and lastly something not as
common to find
in organizations but for all employees
not just neurotypical and neurodiverse
but also neurotypical employees
investigate how you can offer mental
health benefits look into health care
plans that will help cover therapy costs
and stuff like that so it's not as
common you may get great health benefits
for any physical conditions but then you
go to get therapy for your depression
and all of a sudden nothing's covered
there so and those things can be
expensive so as an organization look
into the ways you can do that
another example being like mental health
PTO making sure have mental health days
that your employees are required to take
to take a day off and just relax and
make sure that you're not burning out
your staff from stepping down it's here
to the manager level the main thing for
managers is to accommodate and adjust
learn that the management methods you
use for your neurotypical employees are
not going to be the same ones that work
for your neurodiverse employees and
learn what that means it takes time it's
a different experience but we're looking
whether it will work advocate advocate
for your employee both among your
coworkers you know make sure that
they're supported by their own team make
sure that if they need anything your
management the managers management is
supportive in helping and that the
organization recognizes that its
managers and employees find this
important and then actually this one's
probably the most important is patience
and understanding there is going to be a
learning curve for both the manager and
the we especially for first-time
employees entering the workforce they've
never had to drop before and they
themselves haven't learned how to adjust
to their environment so it's important
to recognize that it may take some time
and there's definitely gonna be some
hiccups you may not typically experience
with a neurotypical employee who kind of
naturally understands the business world
the
this world and having a job is an
environment that was created for them
essentially you're gonna experience
challenges especially early on and so
just trying to stick through that and
not immediately dismiss the employee and
decide that it was a bad hire because
there are some challenges early on
because neurodiverse individuals again
adapt we learn how to work with our
environment but we can't learn what we
don't know so we need a time to adjust
and we will adjust as a co-worker what
can you do
awareness just making yourself aware of
a situation that individuals may have be
in this is a good you know general
recommendation like even if you don't
know your co-workers or neurodiverse you
know keep in mind that everyone thinks
and works differently but especially in
a situation where you know you have a
co-worker who thinks differently and
works differently understanding that the
way you approach them and they approach
you will likely be different than what
you've experienced in the past one thing
always push with my new teams is to ask
questions and learn my teammates who
come and ask me questions all the time
about certain things and I'm happy to
answer I prefer you ask rather than just
accepting social stigmas and stereotypes
ask me and I'm not going to be offended
like I want you to learn like it does me
no good for you to make assumptions or
just be mad at me ask me a question and
maybe I'm doing something that I didn't
know I was doing I can learn from the
experience too and again patience and
understanding
I might make you mad or stress you out
or something ask questions learn point
things out but also work with me and
don't you know hate me as a co-worker
early on when I'm still learning so I
specifically wanted to shout out to a
few people who have helped me out
Patrick Putman he's the
bipolar guy was working with he's very
forward about his stuff and he has a
blog called the bipolar hacker so you
can check him out and read his work that
he's done on this ask him questions he
was very helpful and answered a lot of
my questions so I really appreciate that
Amanda Berlin or info sister on Twitter
she's the CEO of mental health hackers
and by bringing me in and heavily
involving me with her organization I've
met a lot of people stuff and it's it's
been a great being a part of that and
really important me that of course my
manager Nick Bradley at IBM he lets me
travel and come and do these talks which
is really nice and additionally through
some challenges he's adjusted his
management styles when I say something's
not working for me he figures out a way
to make work so it's really important
that he gets recognition for that
because not all managers can handle a
situation to present at conferences on
work times I forgot a conclusion slide
so that's it so thank you for letting me
in for coming to this talk it always
makes me happy to see a relatively big
audience and know that you know the
message is getting out I always say if
one person learned something then you
know my time here was worth it so did
anyone have any questions I can answer
like I said I like questions yeah
[Music]