I'm delighted to
here and so I'm really happy to see how
this is growing and see so many of you
coming it's a great event and a big
welcome to everybody I hope you enjoy
your two days of the conference I'll be
going with you for a journey of how to
secure and how not to break PKI by
assistance or non I use K standard to
use case of a user in a more advanced
case when there's not only server
certificates births or client
certificates so there's a client as
typical use case in in UBS that we need
also to authenticate him he's
authenticated the server and he wants to
sign some transactions with his digital
signature so all the cases which are 11
to to those and aware attacks are
possible I won't be talking about as a
silver and abilities and and protocol
how to attack the protocol this happens
from time to time and and can be
monitored I'll be talking about more
relevant things from like perspective of
you potentially building those systems
securing those securing those systems so
I'll be talking a little about the
server certificates the the client
certificates the code signing which is
equally important as you want to secure
your whole environment and this plays a
role about the digital signature so
signing those financial transactions in
our case but this might be something
else as well and I'll be talking about
the more practical ways so to attack
those kind of systems finishing with
some be a checklist and and they'll be
time for her questions so first quickly
about myself and our sponsor I have more
than ten years building advanced
cryptographic solutions
everything from coding the crypto
libraries myself that were securing
blu-ray and to this day they are
securing blu-ray a lot of applications
throughout the world
building on top of that various workflow
solutions of a crypto 11 something crawl
so you will call a blockchain right now
so we can huge experience to UBS where I
have a pleasure to building and leading
some delivery structures we have some
great guys and we were working on some
really cool school stuff so to give you
a picture of UBS is a really great
opportunity for me to be in such a big
institutions just to give you a picture
we have several data centers we have
thousands of servers supporting ten
thousand thousands almost one hundred
thousands of applications this all needs
to be secured but at the same time you
want to be very Swift you want to make
sure that developers when they do their
solutions that there can be put to
productions as quick as possible so we
try to make this journey possible from
the credentials perspective for where we
are managing the credential lifecycle
and delivering solutions in in this
endoscope
so with such big infrastructure we have
everything in UBS and it's really
amazing to be able to work in such a
company in half I don't know if there is
any other company like that that you
have those type of challenges that the
infrastructure is so big so many
platforms so I really enjoyed this we
have millions of credentials and this
has to happen quickly it has to happen
securely we need to be able to rotate
the credentials very fast we're doing
really cool stuff there too to make this
happen
including some of the lightest which is
compliance a scout so when developers
want to make their solution happen it's
enough that they use our staff and then
they're compliant they know they're
secure we are the experts they don't
have to worried and they have to go
through tedious processes of releasing
application in this very highly secure
environment if they use the solutions
that we were building and providing to
the whole UBS so just quickly some areas
in security which are hot topics right
now we do use artificial intelligence
it's coming basically everywhere
including threat detection we have some
really cool proactive security hardening
we do data protections everywhere
we have very highly sensitive data of
our clients that we cannot be
named and we want to protect their their
channels and all the data in transit and
and at rest a lot of cool stuff in in
via metric and and of course the cloud
and automating the whole things with
lots of robotics initiative or all the
or all around so now to the to the topic
so why why even why why pikia is
important and what attack vectors are
possible through PKI and to the PKI how
to how to attack it so it's a golden
standard for authentication and
reputation in it egg routine right now
secures probably most of the protocol
stats are used every day from from
emails web software distributions it's
replacing traditional signatures as all
institutions want to be digital and be
able to provide this this way of making
transactions to to our customers to to
everybody so I'll be talking about some
some cases like the first thing you
think about PK is I have to protect the
private key but there's much more to it
PK is not only the private key there's
much more to think about
and also there's much more easy ways to
attack it then trying to steal the
private key but this is the important
part so I'll be focusing first on on
this this is a very very big target for
for hackers all around the world to try
to get access to the to the CA or or our
the server's private key so what what
may happen right so if somebody come
from Isis the the private key gets
access to it first of all the reputation
of the company may may might be damaged
imagine like the front page of such a
big enterprise which is being hacked or
displays something something else it
would be a huge reputational damage
there's trade secrecy IDs with client
identification clients client data is
something which is sacred for us we have
we have clients we were managing
portfolios some of the richest people in
the world to be the client of UBS you
have to have five million dollar
in free cash so not invested in free
cash to even to even be a liar so the a
client so we early treat this data
secret with all the segregation of
duties and all the security principles
so we keep this information secret we
keep our trade information secret it
obviously can influence world markets if
if some information about the most we
will like what would would leak there's
personal information of our clients and
and also employees of course there's a
lot of transactions the amount of money
which is going through our system is
tremendous so we want to secure secure
that our resources and and sometimes
it's also human human life
so the standard case as everybody knows
it and I'll be building on that and
going through with you fufu the journey
is a server certificate when you want to
secure basically your you your website
so how this happens in in ki KI as you
you well know you have the root CA
usually it's somewhere offline in bunker
there's no online access to it and there
are certificates there which which are
valid for many many years and they're
only used to issue the intermediate CA
and then the intermediate CAS are issued
for a particular protocols like for
example chateau for particular use cases
like for example code signing or
securing servers so you have the
structure and in the end you have your
certificate which is which is to be
trusted
the root certificate must be distributed
to your environment and this happens
through the OS and for the browsers
depending on the combination of web
browser it's a combination of the the
the OS delivering those those trust
answers to you together with with with
the browser so you have it in your in
your browser and then when you finally
receive the certificate has shown on the
on the bottom in you in your in your
browser the whole chain is is verified
up to the top you see that okay the top
certificates is in my trust ring okay
Rusted I do this green bar so inform the
user that he can he can proceed that
this assist assist this is trusted but
now in in more detail how how this works
so to get a certificate and I'll be
going through all those places how how
to potentially attack them and how
important it is to to protect them to to
show you how difficult it is and how
many points and vectors of attack are
possible and where might in in the last
decade and more so first of all you
there's a registration Authority which
has the obligation of verifying who you
are so if your if the certificate is to
you then that you're who you you present
is the certificate is to some domain
verifying that you have the ownership of
the domain giving this okay stamp of
acceptance and sending the message to
the to the real CA okay this was
verified issued a certificate and the
left certificate goes goes to you you
can install it next to your private key
and use it to secure your your server
send the certificate to any client that
that connects to you equally important
this is validation so there's a
validation Authority usually it's the
same thing you can think of its it might
be as simple as providing the CRL
meaning for vacations lists and I know
CSP protocol so you want to make sure
that those certificates if they're valid
for example for 40 years there might be
a situation where something happened it
got revoked you want to check that the
certificate list is still valid before
you you really trust this so that's
basically the the whole picture and
infrastructure in in one picture now
let's have a look at how we can try to
attack it so the first thought is okay
still the private key and this happens
and this happens a lot if you if you
observe the CRLs which are which are
issued this this happens on like
hundreds of thousand cases where this
happens this has to be monitored and
it's very important for for everybody to
to monitor outlets the servers do -
first of all detect an incident like
nobody I hope
assumes that their servers are secure
like anna always will be you want to be
able to detect an incident and be ready
to react to whatever the incidents don't
mean so that first detects and and then
reacts to to the to the incident so so
this happens it's usually hard in in
some in most of the really relevant
cases does this private key is stored on
some HSM in some in some hardware you
really cannot gain access to to the get
a copy of the private key you may there
might be some other ways of just trying
to get the use of the private key which
which may allow you to do some things
that's very hard to get the get the
private key itself and of course or more
security relevant cases where this key
is stored in some file this file should
be protected and it happens that this
this this this file is compromised it
leaks maybe because it was transferred
to some other places maybe to some load
balancers or some monitoring
infrastructure to peek inside the
packets to see what's happening there
this key might be in multiple of places
maybe it was the management structure of
the living the delivering the key in
place wasn't really done so maybe the
maybe it's somewhere in the distribution
package maybe the whole process is not
done right and there are multiple points
of attack to to to actually steal such a
key which we've seen in a in in a file
moving moving forward there are cases
where and even with with Microsoft for
example somebody pretended to be a
Microsoft employee and the registration
authority trusted and she issued the
certificate so always remember that's
usually the technology the technology
behind security is good enough but
there's always people in in it and in
such a complex system like here there
are multiple attack vectors that involve
social techniques and people and
mistakes and and usually mistakes in
management of the infrastructure
so even if there's some nice policies
writing okay this is our our practice
statement they are not followed and
allow for four things things to happen
so this is one possible attack
pretending to be the company then
something that also happens is to to be
able to somehow idea of collaboration or
by hacking the infrastructure the
systems gets get good hold of the
registration authority which sometimes
is not the same thing as CA sometimes is
something external sometimes this is
partners so for those big companies that
sell certificates is often partners that
act us which is registration authorities
and it happened that that they got
hacked and some certificates were issued
that allowed to pretend to be the and
the legitimate site movie moving forward
sometimes it's it also happened in a
past that the credentials used by by
this Registration Authority got got
stolen and somebody was able to connect
to the to the C infrastructure and then
an issue whatever whatever whatever he
wanted so all this leaf some trails so
it's usually detected and usually quite
quite fast but not not always the ulti
might think you dream of as a hacker is
to somehow get hold of of the CA itself
and compromised because then if you're
inside this here you can cover your
tracks you can cover the logs and then
it's really might be really hard to
determine what certificates were really
issued which should be revoked and then
it sends up with revoking the whole the
whole tree which happens for example
with some Nordic company which also
served government so a big issue
everybody had to rotate their
certificates it was a huge damage to not
only the the the company that provided
the certificates but also to those that
that had to manage the incident in the
end
then if the CA is using some old
algorithm d5 it's it's been shown that's
their collision attacks and and it's
possible now to like forge a certificate
so you don't have access to the private
key but just by doing the collision
attack you're able to forge a key which
would look like like a real one and then
the validation data maybe the
certificate maybe the incident gods got
the tag that maybe the certificate got
revoked but maybe you're able to
suppress for example the the validation
data so for example Midas URL not
available in this validation environment
where it will be checked maybe you can
reply the OCSP like the previous one
which is still valid but which says that
the certificate is valid multiple
attacks that that can happen in in this
place so quite complex system very
crucial that if there are practice
statements policies that they're
followed that's the personal handling
this this is trained and and it's really
not always the case because this is a
great business model like how much
resources do you need really to like
made another five bucks and get a
certificate try this it's infrastructure
is in the place and and it happens that
there's so many CAS in the world that
are trusted that sometimes the security
aspect really lacks because of the great
business model that wants to scale and
issue as many certificates and as fast
as possible to basically earn money for
for those for those companies one
additional attack which is possible is
is modifying Trust if you're already in
the system it's really done right so you
can do anything you can display
something different to the user you can
trick him to trust your servers you can
modify trust this is this is done so
what did we gain or attacker what did
that occur gain by by getting access to
Turkey which pretends to be to your
company he first of all and these are
multiple scenarios
depending on what's the motivation of
the attacker it might be a nation state
that basically wants to East drop on the
whole nation maybe there's some protest
and it happened and quite frequently
that where there were protests for
example China issued some some
certificate authority controlled by
China issued our health care certificate
if I remember right that allowed to
eavesdrop on like for example Microsoft
Google whatever you want connections
from from people to to the server is
enough you so you're the least
privileged attacker you just can use
either up on the encrypted communication
and and even even that depending on the
scenario if you got the the the private
key in this this will allow you to
either up or the standard money the
middle attack and then you see
everything and you can also modify
whatever happens but this is also
sometimes so these are some
nation-states scenarios there there are
other scenarios when you basically use
BKI as an attack vector itself because
once once you have the the private
certificate you are able then to try to
launch some other types of attacks and
then get you ultimate goal of getting
access to some some data control of the
infrastructure at the points that I was
talking about before so now we were
talking about the servers but now the
user so this is not for every Tuesday
this is not a standard case but it is it
is for us so you also want to have
authentication of the clients or have
the mutual TLS it's basically the same
process somebody has to verify who you
are issue the certificate and all the
attacks vector stock I talked before
apply here
equally what's may be nice to mention
here is and to be aware of that this
allows to not only act as the client
itself and whatever he can but this
gives an attacker some really nice
abilities to try to hide from monitoring
software because if he attacker has
trusted
certificate and key and can login to
your systems from an unencrypted tunnel
maybe your instructor is not really
monitoring that so maybe if he has this
encrypted tunnel to your server you he
will be able if there's my for example
end-to-end encryption he will be able to
launch standard SQL injection or other
attacks on your server that will avoid
evaded detection an interesting case how
to leverage attacking PGI to answer
other attacks and code signing this is
the the hackers dream control right so
to be able to have a science software
that that would evade your assistance
measures your antivirus measures and
it's been shown that if the infamous
strikes nets where the drivers were
signed by a trusted signing certificate
many many other cases were basically
hacker once he already either tricked
somebody into installing some software
which the system will show that this is
trusted so it will evade the mechanism
of detection of the operating system
then there were some research showing
how this can be also used to evade
detection of antivirus software
I think they ramped up and and are a bit
better now but what few years back it
was possible for example to evade
antivirus scanning just by copying the
signature and and then because of
optimization of how antivirus software
works if the antivirus software served
at okay there's a there's a signature
not verifying it at all ok let's let's
keep the dis probably is trusted and and
this this was it was possible to write I
remember right eighty percent of
antivirus software at that time so
hopefully this is this is better now
and what's important to note is again
the the processor the whole procedures
around maintaining such infrastructure
are not really done well and it's I
believe is just getting worse as a
result
research shows that
80% of such abusive certificates that
there is for co-signing can be still
leverage for for up to six years which
only shows how people are lagging in in
applying the right practices updating
their vocation lists and so on and so on
and now when we we were talking about
the channel and now we so we had one
certificates to the Authenticator
obviously we have another one to do
signing you cannot use one certificate
for and private key for for both so now
we have the client authenticated and he
wants to assign some some transaction
maybe multi-million dollar transaction
that he wants to invest in some stock or
other things he like to ask us to do so
he has his his private key he has the
public key of the recipient he encrypts
the the message which is sent that's I'm
relief well understood to you how this
works but I wanted to talk about some
more this is not usual attack vectors
this is at least nobody really admits
that this this this happens but it's
still it's not reported but it's still a
valid attack point I haven't found
references saying that this happens but
I think it's a very valid use case and
I'm sure somebody's is trying to to make
those those kind of things happen and
what's interesting when you have a
digital signature is that it's important
to be sure what is the part of data that
is being signed and that this data
cannot be changed so for example if
you're signing our word document and
this so the clients is wrong a word
documents on transaction okay I sign it
and I sent to the server but maybe there
was some dynamic content JavaScript or
order in this in this format that would
allow it and meaning that a different
result will render to the person signing
it and a difference to maybe person who
is later viewing this for for execution
or our system so even more important and
and/or interesting cases
our that there are ways to to trick one
file to be both so you can have one file
for example a PDF and teeth that will
depending on what extension you will add
to it will open a completely different
valid document and this is made possible
because for example PDF just requires
that the header of the PDS is somewhere
in the first if I remember 1000 bytes or
something like that so you can have a
tiff file which is also a PDF file in
rendering comfort lis different a
different thing to the person who is
viewing it just by tricking it to open
in a different software or just
modifying the the extension so
ultimately and this is one point which
is which evades almost always is that we
kind of try to forget that in the end we
are using making all those transactions
on a very insecure devices right this is
the devices you use usually are not
really secure so what is shown on the
screen
cannot be guaranteed to be really what
what what what is what is what is
intended another part important
specifically to the digital signatures
is not to not to break it and I saw in
my in my professional career enormous
amount of times when for example xml
signatures were broke just because the
people that made some systems further in
the in the pipeline didn't weren't aware
of how to treat signed documents and and
the signature was was damaged in transit
on an in storage or by including it in
some some bigger bigger structures so
this all has to be taken into account
people usually don't understand that
even if they di at one white space that
this breaks the signature right and then
you have some crazy conversations trying
to explain why this why this matters so
be aware of the of the signed parts that
they cannot change and even more
important is with signatures that you
want to be you have the signature if
everything works this is fine but in the
end you you want it and you keep
- in case of some dispute so the client
comes or maybe there's a magnetic bank
transaction and and says that I didn't I
did I didn't like this disorder right I
I didn't take the loan for five million
and and I don't have to give you the
money back right or whatever that that
that might be or one bank which is
crisis I work with frequently sending a
transaction to another bank to buy some
stock sell some stock and you want to
make sure I the receiving want to make
sure it came from the right person and
then another and the person standing
cannot cannot repute that this this was
sent by him so this is it's very
important to be able to have access to
all the the validation data needed to
the proof in case of disputes that this
this really is a valid transaction so
you have to store for example C RL or
CSPs on depending on the how complicated
the use case is use of advanced
signatures it may be much much much more
and this is important in case of long
signature so maybe the signature was
valid when you received it but maybe
next day the the the signature of the
certificate of the user got hacked
so if you didn't do collect the evidence
at the time of receiving the certificate
and and secured it you won't have
possibility to truly prove that the the
the signature is valid because the key
was compromised or maybe one month later
the simply does the certificate expired
in a very simple case again but if you
didn't collect the evidence you cannot
prove in case of dispute that that it
was really the other person or the sub
CA gets gets compromised or the whole
Arg or it gets compromised because
there's some new mathematical
breakthroughs or simply in computer
speeds that allow two might attacks that
were before unfeasible and there are
ways to to protect from all of that by
actively maintaining the signatures in
something that you might now
call a blockchain of trust
basically resigning the evidence you
have with newer stronger better
algorithmically my training is having
multiple sources of the distrust and
building this this block training of
trust you're able actually to even prove
100 years from now that such a signature
was valid which is important where we go
in the digital and we want clients to be
able to make those long-term
transactions with through electronic
means this is this is then becoming
really really important consequences are
obvious if if an attacker can converge
by eye their access to the private key
or by being able to manipulate the
document or other means be able to trick
the system he can like someone or the
system do something that was not not not
intended in all the thing I was talking
before so the signers can can deny that
it was them signing document if the
whole infrastructure is is is mismanaged
other cases where signatures are are
used for for integrity of logs again to
either be able to audit or proof in case
of dispute can be can be compromised so
a lot of consequences that that will
happen and now about more practical
types of attacks so everybody thinks
about the private key and gaining access
or or gaining access to at least to the
usage of private key for example if
there's an HSN maybe it's not really
important that you get the copy of the
private key if you are able to to
control the design Inc device and make
it sign whatever whatever you you want
but this is usually really hard he's
protected as I said before in some hsn's
so there's a much easier use case which
is as research shows used in more than
sixty percent of of cases and this just
makes two steps don't want whatever free
software to generate a certificate issue
it in one minute
and then modify the trust either whoever
is your thought attacking the server
client modify the trust and it so
happens that usually everybody being
pushed by business and so on they always
are concerned about making the
application work and when it works
they're happy and somehow it sleeps that
the validation environment is equally
important it's not a privacy issue you
don't have to protect the Trust's or as
the private key but you have to protect
this integrity and this somehow escapes
and as a result in more than sixty
percent of cases this this is the nine
vector of attack just modified restore
and then you avoid all this
infrastructure you're just using a
simple key you generated in a minute
with your some free software and some
cheap computer of yours if you're able
to modify the trust and and again much
other much easier waste and then trying
to get access to the private key are
possible sometimes it's possible to
again attacked the validation
environment which which usually doesn't
have such protection as the signing
environment maybe you're able to
substitute the data which is being
validated so or in some other way
attacked the application validation
components there to conclude the
opposites resolve and just make the flip
right because that's that's that that
happens or us was saying before I try to
attack through for the validation of by
replying OCSP that was so valid maybe
one minute ago maybe this it's still
within its expiration and you can you
can try to leverage that and obviously
add hidden code right to the software
validation environment so a lot of much
easier usually cases than attacking the
private key which has all the controls
in our bank for example private key has
like the most secret level of
action right you don't want to attack
that some-some checklist I'm I'm
[Music]
starting to finish my my examples so
make sure that your private private key
material is a secret but also remember
about the integrity of the trust and the
validation environment and of course
review code sometimes it might be some
some malicious action by by some
internal people and it's usually very
often is that it's some internal
employees may be of revenge or something
else putting something in the in the
code I did so myself thinks in the code
what we've done even not intentionally
but some things that that needs to be
this is something that needs to be to be
checked and for for the digital
signature case it's really important to
know what the signature is assigning and
what's the meaning of the data which is
being signed so if there's no dynamic
content can be changed somehow
substitute it or this double meaning
form as being being used and then
they're all dispute cases so you want to
make sure that this is not the signature
is not damaging in storage and and is
simply available to you and when when
needed and equal you have to access to
all the validation data needed for for
verifying it and they're really nice I
enjoy those those cases anonymously with
long-term advance signatures which
require this block chain of trust you
really might want to make sure that you
do that if you expect or wants to be
able to validate the signature even a
month from now a year from now ten years
from now very very important any
questions
to to come to me after after the
presentation I'll be happy to speak with
any of you
thank you for participating please visit
our booth at UBS we have some cool stuff
for you and enjoy the conference