good morning the pleasure to be in
Cracow pleasure
first confidence something I might have
for this talk
anyway we almost have to like go down so
yes my name is Joseph slow ik I am NOT a
hacker
I am a dedicated defender I'm a blue
Timur I got my start in US government I
was a naval officer doing a various
cyber sorts of missions and then I was
at the Los Alamos National Laboratory
running the incident response team for a
while but as part of that work one of
the things that always drove my passion
was the idea of threat intelligence and
while that's something that I do and
while I'm still a dedicated defender now
I'm doing this more or less on my own
terms in the private sector in the US
for a industrial control system focused
security company called Drago's so I've
been there for a little over two years
now focusing on the ICS landscape but
still taking that very threat
intelligence focused approach to what it
is that I do now you might think about
this like well threat intelligence where
is this coming from for you and well my
background is a naval officer certainly
has the cyber aspect but the community
that I was in included intelligence
operations so usually when people hear
that I have a passion for cyber threat
intelligence they assumed that I was an
intelligence officer however I was not
my opinion of intelligence officer is is
varying depending upon the intelligence
person because you have various
stereotypical ways of looking at what
these sorts of people do from you know
what the public thinks that we do to
what some people might want to think
that they do to what they really do
which is making lots of powerpoints but
irrespective of that my field while I
did lots of cyber sorts of things was
really dedicated towards technical
intelligence so signals intelligence
analyzing radar and then cyber was just
one part of the things that I did and a
lot of the motivating goal behind that
job was to provide the people in the
ship or in the aircraft or whatever with
near real-time data about threats that
they were facing which is something that
I've brought with me into the more
traditional network defense field now
and something that I think has a
significance for how we conduct cyber
threat intelligence from a pure blue
team perspective in the current
environment so what are we going to talk
first we're gonna talk about what's the
purpose of intelligence because if we
don't get clear on what it is that we're
doing I don't think it makes sense to
talk about this so lay the groundwork
for some common definitions then we'll
talk about what threat intelligence
means from an operational standpoint
before moving on to this concept of
indications and warnings that real-time
threat intelligence aspect and then
provide some examples and applications
to illustrate what we've talked about
and provides some ways of taking this
back to your organization so first what
is intelligence so back when I was a
student I'm older than I look
the gentleman by the name of Donald
Rumsfeld was secretary of defense for
the United States and he had this quote
that many people made fun of because it
sounds pompous ponderous etc that there
are three kinds of knowledge are the
things that you know which okay we know
the things we know that's fine
there are the things that we don't know
about but we know that we don't know
them there are known unknowns and then
those are the things that we don't even
know that we don't know so that sounds
kind of silly but when you think about
it a little bit it applies to what we do
from a network defense standpoint so we
know what we know I know the hashes for
the latest version of sofa C or wente or
emote ed or something I know what I
don't know I don't know the latest
variant maybe but I have a reasonable
understanding for how this malware works
or what its command and control looks
like but then there's the things that I
don't even know I don't know what the
adversary might do next what they might
change to for operational purposes and
that I really know just not don't even
need to just find out but I need to
figure out how to figure out I don't
even know that in the first place so it
seemed circular in a fashion but it's an
important way of understanding what the
goal is of what we're trying to do and
furthermore when we start talking about
intelligence it's not a
one-size-fits-all application instead
intelligence really depends on who your
audience is so this is a image
illustrating from a military perspective
as sort of the concepts in question that
really things run the gamut from big
picture strategic perspective all the
way to the tactical day-to-day operation
standpoint and what's important to
realize with this image is that your
product your message the information
that's most
relevant varies depending on your
audience and if you're not modifying
what it is that you're saying and how
you're presenting it to who it is that
you're presenting you're probably going
to result in a message that's not going
to be received very well or even
understood all particularly well and
when we talk about intelligence - there
are three primary things that it
requires to be useful so first off has
to be accurate um if your intelligence
is not accurate then what what are you
even doing you know just roll things up
we don't care anymore but it also has to
be timely it's one thing to say and this
gets into the concept that we'll be
talking about in greater detail today
you know I can provide you with great
information about something that
happened ten years ago what does that do
for you now it informs you on something
that happened previously but it doesn't
necessarily help you with what's going
on right now and lastly it must be
relevant so if you are defending a bank
or if you are defending a software
development company that has a lot of
intellectual property and I give you
lots of information about hacking
elections that's interesting is it
really relevant though maybe some of the
TTP's behind it might be for how things
initially started off but you know how
groups hacked Facebook or whatever
created lots of social media profiles it
doesn't matter so it's not relevant so
ensuring that we have these concepts in
mind makes the product we produce from
an intelligence standpoint useful but
that use like I implied earlier is going
to depend on who your audience is so at
the very highest level talking to your
c-suite your CIO your C ISO the board of
directors or your boss perhaps or
whatever you have this big picture
strategic level like what's going on you
know or what what is it that the Chinese
maybe are trying to steal in terms of
intellectual property based upon current
planning by their government okay
you know that's useful potentially from
a big-picture planning perspective but
your sock doesn't care about that at a
mid level like okay well what are the
sorts of things going on on a day to day
on a not necessarily day to day basis
but over time that I need to invest in
in order to make sure that I'm meeting
what's going on in the
Fireman so your sock managers your
incident response managers the people
who are setting budgets deciding what
tools to acquire what sort of landscape
do I face that's going to inform the
decisions I make that are going to
impact operations for the next three six
nine twelve months and finally at your
tactical level what's going on right now
what phishing campaign is going on right
at this moment or do I anticipate in the
next week how does it behave and what do
I need to do to detect it respond to it
and then remediate it so a very
immediate sort of level detection and
analysis and that's really what we're
gonna focus on mostly for this
conversation that doesn't mean that
these don't matter it just means that
your strategic and operational audiences
are much smaller generally speaking even
though they're very important and really
this talk is meant to inform the
immediate defender to make him or her do
their operations better to respond to
threats now when we start talking about
the intelligence as a process you know
really we look at this as a sequence of
events that we begin with an operational
environment move on to the collection of
data distill that into information and
then from that produce some sort of
deliverable but oftentimes when we look
at what's provided from commercial
threat intelligence that the things that
we emphasize are the data aspect and
then the intelligence aspect what's
missing well we've talked about you know
your phase 1 you know gather a bunch of
data something mysterious happens and
then phase 3 I have a threat
intelligence report either a private
report that you paid many you know much
money for or a public report that's part
marketing part threat intelligence or
whatever but what happens in the middle
is kind of missing and so you're left
with this sort of bifurcation this
division between what happens very
immediately data and then what happens
after quite a period of time generating
intelligence and ignoring what's in the
middle
hence the talk meet me in the middle
anyway so if we look at this
you know threat intelligence reports
many of us are familiar with these sorts
of ideas they're finished reports or
it's a narrative that describes an event
campaign a piece of malware maybe that's
a separate topic whether or not that's
actually intelligence we can talk about
that at the bar maybe later but you know
lots of detailed information in here
that requires a lot of time effort and
analysis to get from that data
perspective to a finished intelligence
report thus it's not going to be
something that you get immediately after
or while something is occurring but
often weeks usually months potentially
even years after something happens so
it's after event has taken place your
backward-looking you're always sort of
backward looking because these are
always responses to things that had
happened but in the case of a finished
intelligence report you're significantly
backward looking because you can only
produce this after a period of
significant analysis and production so
examples of this range from the sort of
foundational aspects of our field you
know the mandiant apt one report the
initial big bang of commercial threat
intelligence reporting to really good
malware analysis reporting like
semantics Stuxnet dossier things that
are controversial like Kaspersky
slingshot report especially if you were
in the u.s. it was a good report though
two things that are just really bad
the Norse growing cyber threat from Iran
report that is the report to look at if
you want an example of what not to do in
a threat intelligence report and they're
out of business so I don't don't worry
about them yelling at me but anyway so
that's good you know we have examples of
that but what about something that
defenders deal with on a daily basis
indicators have compromised you always
hear people like you know I need the IOC
s I need the iOS either do something or
whatever you will see you know IOC s
ideally or contextual but usually IOC s
as we receive them to act upon our
atomic in nature it's a single data
point an IP address a hash value a
domain they're nice and then it's a
speedy quick way to transit transfer
information to communicate it to other
parties but they're lacking in the sense
that it's for the one on the ones stance
they could be highly variable in terms
of the quality you know are you getting
good IOC s or you're getting bad Auto
C's am I getting the hash value for PS
exec or for you know the hash value for
Muni cats what does that really tell you
because it's trivially easy to change
the hash value of mimi cats the source
code is on github I can do whatever the
hell I want with it thus the hash is
meaningless so it's a lot of
questions for what actual value I'm
getting out of them even if I can
transmit them and receive them quite
quickly so for example the indicator of
compromises that initially developed was
a not a single data point but multiple
data points clustered together so when I
see this set of hash values court along
with this registry key or whatever I
know that I have an indicator of this
specific type of compromise there's a
lot to be said for that idea it's not
perfect but it gives you some idea of
you know if a and B or C then alert
there's some contextuality built around
that the problem is is that when we talk
about indicators of compromise what we
get are these this is the grisly step
report that the us-cert released in
response to Russian meddling in US
elections and it had a lot of iOS ease
like if you're just strictly judging by
quantity this is a good report but if
you're judging by quality it leaves a
lot to be desired because yes I have
values and even though they had the
presence of mind to say comment explain
what this was none of these are actually
filled in so I don't know what any of
these are for is that a
command-and-control address was it a
domain used to deliver a file is it a
domain that was a compromise legitimate
address therefore maybe I shouldn't
block it but I should alert on it so
this seems like it's good but I refer to
this kind of as information security
junk food you can devour lots of it very
quickly and easily but it doesn't
nourish you at all it doesn't really do
much for you and then as we start
getting to these atomic not very
contextual examples of an indicator then
we want to start talking about ingesting
them and using them at machine speed so
this is just one example there's plenty
of commercial examples of this as well
of a us centered initiative on trying to
get organizations to share I OCS rapidly
so that they could put them into their
defenses right away well that sounds
good except if you want to do something
like block Google or block Microsoft or
you know blacklist PS exec which your
admins might be using or something along
those lines this is how you do it
because you're just ingesting
information without analyzing it which
can lead to very bad things like your
users can no longer get to Gmail or
users can no longer resolve DNS
depending upon what how your environment
is laid out so can be very bad so from a
coverage perspective iOS sees us to get
quick alerting and response you know
it's beneficial in the sense that I can
do something fast but I lose the ability
to add context or any sort of additional
information around it while intelligence
reports can be very thorough the win32
Stuxnet report is hundreds of paetynn
120 ish pages long it's very interesting
and very detailed and very in-depth but
as a result of that though it takes
months to put that sort of analysis
together if not longer so if I'm talking
about an incident that's happening right
now in real time it doesn't do a whole
lot for me in order to help respond to
that
so what we're missing is here so we've
talked about raw data those IOC's we've
talked about the very fancy intelligence
reports but what about just minimally
enriched data things that we've taken
the raw feed from and added just some
minimal bit of context around so that
while we're getting something fairly
quickly we've also managed to add a
little bit of extra information around
it so that we understand one one it
might be - we verified that it's
actually bad and three made sure that it
might be relevant to the audience that
we're talking about so in supporting
operations intelligence doesn't exist in
a vacuum
if intelligence existed on its own then
I don't know although if you look at the
news recorded future was just acquired
for like 750 million u.s. dollars so
evidently we're doing something right
but for an intelligence to be functional
or useful or valuable it has to support
actual defence operations but in order
to do that we're all indicators as we
see with iOS see reports aren't good
enough because it's gonna make us make
mistakes it's gonna let us feel like
we're doing something even though we're
not doing much at all and the finalized
reports are good but they're not timely
so what we really need to do is enriched
information that provides indications of
hostile activity and warning of
malicious behavior that can be
informative and time-sensitive so
getting back to that concept of
intelligence needs to be
relevant accurate but also timely in
order for it to be operationally
relevant so my background on this I
hinted at this the very beginning of the
presentation so I was what was then
called an information warfare officer
there now called Cryptologic officers
because as a community but the community
I was in is very confused about what to
call ourselves but the idea though is
that you get sailors sitting at consoles
and darkened rooms on a ship or whatever
that are just trying to figure out like
okay I can see for example that I have a
radar track or I have something that's
picked up on a sensor somewhere and
based upon that data point I can
correlate it with another data point
what frequency that radiates radar is
operating on or some aspect of the
communication that's been intercepted
from that particularly unit and
correlate that with a set of information
to figure out what it is so I can
differentiate not just that we have a
contact somewhere out there in the world
but I have a contact whose radar happens
to map on to this type of aircraft which
given the order of battle for where
we're operating correlates to this
platform for this country that doesn't
like us very much
therefore you should care about this I
haven't figured out what its intentions
might be I haven't figured out what the
broader strategic scope might be that's
for the intelligence analysts to do
months later but I've informed the
people that I'm directly supporting that
hey there's something that you should
probably care about that's out there
here it is and based upon what
correlating information here's what you
might want to do about it
so you don't have the complete picture
but it's a lot more than just saying
there's a dot out in the middle of the
ocean somewhere and we don't know what
it is it gives people who are operating
tactically enough information to start
making informed decisions about for self
defense well this is a concept that
sounds pretty useful from a network
defense concept as well so to reference
another American with Polish heritage
Richard Beit lick and closure I worked
with his wife Amy who is also a very
brilliant intelligence analyst he
defined sort of a concept of indications
and warning from a network security
monitoring standpoint in his book the
Tao of network security and what's
important to emphasize about this if you
could read quickly but the main thing is
really a
understanding that the indications and
warning part is dialed in to are focused
on hostile behavior what its indications
are in warning of what may be to come so
this very threat focused very much
attack focused as opposed to either
informative educational like you might
see in an intelligence reporting or very
atomic and unenriched like you see with
an IOC we're trying to add on not just
that something is happening but context
around it so that we know from a
defensive standpoint what we could do
about it
so what inw avoids attribution
attribution is a touchy subject because
you know you never want to say like oh
the Russians or the Americans did this
or whatever because then we'll prove it
how do you know this or whatever like
that's an entirely separate line of
conversation takes a lot of work a lot
of analysis which means it takes a lot
of time so we want to avoid that in this
case but also we want to avoid adversary
intent so from an indications and
warning perspective I don't care
necessarily beyond the strict
functionality of a piece of malware what
it's for I don't need to care if the
French are trying to steal nuclear
secrets are trying to gather political
military intelligence or whatever from a
strategic perspective I just need to
know that I see Animal Farm in my
network and here's what the
characteristics of this bit of malware
those are all topics for
backward-looking let's you know
understand what the incident involved
and I can write a report on it later but
for in the moment defense that doesn't
matter it doesn't help your sock to
respond to what's happening well instead
we need to focus on is differentiating
categorize threats does this malware
spread is a command can
initial access tool is it a some other
sort of tooling or whatever and how do I
respond to it one of the characteristics
of this network traffic is this IP
address or domain adversary controlled
or is it adversary compromised and what
does that mean for me and those informed
offenders who enable their response do I
block it do I let this go so I can
capture some traffic to see what's going
on before I respond how do I remediate
this malware do I need to just delete
the file wipe the machine or do I need
to take the motherboard out throw it in
a wood chipper and never use that device
again because I've had some bios-based
you know in firmware a rootkit or some
other exotic thing in mind how do I deal
with the threat in question
but in saying this it's important that I
get some grief from traditional
intelligence analysts it's like you're
saying my job doesn't matter like no
your job does matter and in fact these
positions these roles work together
fundamentally if you look at this as a
cyclical process is that cyber threat
intelligence tracks the overall threat
landscape what apt 28s malware looks
like what equation groups malware and C
2 functionality looks like and then
informs inw by providing the data that
indications and warning uses to enrich
individual observables so that from a
day-to-day operation standpoint you're
in the field tactical intelligence
operation is taking what's observed and
matching that against what is known
about the environment to produce an
enriched set of indications and warnings
about observed behavior in the
environment but what's important is that
that just doesn't sit in isolation and
not just isolation in the sense that I
inform the Sox that they can respond I
also need to inform my bigger picture
CTI analysts that hey this is what we've
observed so they can begin to modify
their picture their bigger picture of
the overall adversary environment which
lyn feeds back into the context and
background that I use on a day to day
operational level to categorize inform
and enrich the things that I observe in
my environment so really while I've
talked about only one particular and
unfortunately rather ignored piece of
the threat intelligence picture your
traditional threat intelligence
reporting still has quite a big role to
play as long as the sides are
cooperating because ideally what we want
is cyber threat intelligence provides
this big picture overview this in-depth
analysis of what the adversary is what
they do who they might be
and then combines that with the security
operations team who provides that
day-to-day defense of the network to
result in a real near real-time very
much operationally focused threat
intelligence indications and warning
that enables active real realistic
defense within the environment so to
illustrate this a little bit I'm going
to talk about two examples both of which
I worked on in my own shop for drago's
but have a lot of other
public commentary on them so crash
override and destroyer the 2016 Ukraine
power event and then the Shamoon three
event and its potential relationship to
apt 33 which I think is also helix
kitten I might be wrong on that
I don't know crowd strikes names as well
but anyway crash over I didn't destroy
her so January 2016 lights went out in
Ukraine for the second year in a row
lots of media reporting and then black
cat talks blogs etc that is Robert
Lipowski from ESET I presented it
onstage with him at blackhat USA about
this back in July of 2017 August of 2017
whenever that was so it sounds like an
event that we knew a lot about you know
we had lots of reporting and newspapers
etc but if we look at how this event
played out did we really do a good job
so the event itself happened in December
of 2016 at the time there were
suspicions that oh did this happen again
because we had the 2015 power event but
there was no information sharing no one
really knew what happened unto mm excuse
me until in January he started getting
sources news articles from like reuters
and from other services that Ukraine was
convinced that this was a cyberattack
but still no information for why they
knew that at least none public so I can
say from a private perspective since I
was still in the US government at the
time that we were kind of confused what
was going on within weeks and months of
that event as well like well we think
this might be happening but we're not
really sure so if you were another
electric utility in Ukraine or in Poland
close to Ukraine or in the United States
you didn't know what was going on and
how to defend yourself against a similar
sort of attack if this even was a cyber
attack it wasn't until in June of 2017
late June it that that ESET D'Andre goes
published in-depth reporting on the
malware of what the crash override and
destroyer framework did how it
manipulated electric distribution
operations so it was really good from
ICS now our standpoint but again if I
was a network defender responsible for
defending an electric utility yeah I
know what to see when crash override
gets in the environment the very last
stage of the attack but I have no idea
what led up to making that attack
possible so from a defensive standpoint
I'm still disadvantaged
it wasn't until October of 2018 that at
least publicly among other things I
published a white paper which could be
viewed online or whatever and gave some
presentations about the attack lifecycle
in question how the attack was actually
facilitated how initial access into the
industrial control environment was
achieved what the adversary did to move
around all those necessary steps you
would need from a defender standpoint to
stop something like crash override or in
destroyer from affecting your operations
in the first place so if we look at this
from a raw data sharing standpoint we
were almost a complete failure there
were hashes available in June of 2017
but that was seven months after the
attack took place hashes are trivially
easy to change and are very brittle or
very easy to adjust or whatever and so
from a defensive standpoint you're not
leading people with much to respond to
and thus there wasn't really any
information to allow for that whole of
kill chain whole of attack perspective
until almost two years after the attack
took place for defenders to act on from
an indications in the warning
perspective we might have eventually had
a success in that we were able to inform
operators and asset owners of how this
attacks like a look place but it wasn't
until a long time after the event itself
actually happened so anyone who is
seeing crash over like crash override
like precursors before October of 2018
was kind of left at the mercy of the
adversary without having that
information from an intelligence
perspective if we look at intelligence
trying to provide a backward-looking
overview of the event in its entirety we
need to do a bad job you know the
initial reporting and some of the
initial aspects of the malware was ok
once we got a fuller picture of what was
going on and access to more data
enriched that a little bit more so that
was good but like we've said earlier
from the perspective of a actual
electric utility defender it doesn't
make a difference at that point because
we could have had the same adversary
operating in other environments and
insufficient information was available
to let them know what to look for for
molera TAC ok so I fell on my sword for
that one because I think myself Drago's
we could have done a better job
not going to speak for anyone else or
whatever but you know just things that
we need to think about another example a
little bit more recently so in December
of 2018 we had the third round of the
Shamoon wiper attack took taking place
in Saudi Arabia a little different and
that the entities that were attacked
were foreign owned entities operating
within the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia as
opposed to Saudi entities themselves but
again those are minor details we can
speak about over beers later the main
thing is that this was covered all over
the place Sherman itself hadn't really
changed all that much so everyone jumped
on this immediately like haha we saw
Shamoon again but what was interesting
about this is that a few weeks after the
initial reporting of like Shamoon
happened again
McAfee came out with some public
reporting that linked what was observed
to a advanced persistent threat labeled
apt 33 by fire I we call them the
McNally I'm at Drago's because we all
have to have our own names um another
topic but linked apt 33 activity in the
year or longer prior to the Shamoon
event as being the precursor to
deploying the wiper framework oh that's
very interesting from a defender
standpoint I would have wanted to know
that or know some indications of that
that might take place because then I
could react appropriately to seeing apt
33 activity and then shortly after that
fire I publicly released a report that
confirmed more or less what was reported
by a McAfee or McAfee x' okay
projectors going up and down sorry but
that sort of confirmed McAfee is
reporting it yes like we saw this or
whatever they gave it a name overruled
or that apt 33 operations did seem to be
precursors to deploying Shamoon within
victim networks like oh that's really
cool except at this point you already
have networks that were wiped let's B
does that to you so and I had a caveat
to this actually so I do not know what
fire eyes private reporting was so if
you're a fire eyesight's subscriber you
may have been fine
this is a public reporting item and
there's the argument like well you only
get what you pay for and if it's free
like you know good luck to you
but anyway from the standpoint of
did we do a good job I mean maybe we did
so reporting was fairly good and coming
out almost in real time in reaction to
events which is good but we're talking
about a wiper here and one that spread
fairly widely within Victim networks so
it's one thing that you know hey you
know a day later after I got hit by
another version of this truck wiper this
is what happened like well my networks
already wipes you hadn't helped me at
all you just gave me a reason why my
network is wiped so that might be less
than helpful but again the caveat I
don't know what the private eye site
reporting may have been so maybe for
fireEye customers this was very valuable
because they were getting an indication
of hey we see this entity getting into
networks not 100% sure what they're
doing but here's what's happening so you
could be prepared for whatever may come
next but what we could have done better
really depends on the accuracy of that
apt 33 attribution because from a public
reporting standpoint at least and some
private reporting that I'm familiar with
while this entity had been tracked
somewhat hadn't been tracked very well
that you know oh we know they're active
we can say that their tactics are trashy
and they're very noisy and easy to
follow we won't pay attention to them
that much and then they end up deploying
a wiper bow ok that's pretty bad so what
we needed to do is really provide better
indications of what this entity was up
to within networks so that victims in
question could have responded to those
potential intrusions well in advance of
this adversary being in place to just
deploy a wiper widespread and victim
networks resulting in significant
dislocation so let's wrap this up I
think I have a little bit more time
where are we right now so really what we
need to do is inw bridges a critical gap
between raw data which can lead us down
wrong paths because we don't have enough
information behind it yet and finalized
threat intelligence reporting which
perhaps is waits too long before we're
able to do anything valuable with the
information in question security
operations benefit from this because now
your 'suck while they're not getting
data instantaneously that's not called
good threat intelligence that's called
magic but what they are getting is in
fairly real-time information about what
it is that they're seeing to better
respond to events as they take place as
a result of that they can do their jobs
better they can identify like Oh
see weird communication coming out of
the network like oh you know I
understand maps on to registration
patterns similar to what fancy bearer is
known to use so this is more than just a
weird network connection this is
potentially very bad see - and I should
act accordingly but the thing is is that
and I say this as someone who works
within the cyber threat intelligence
industry is that has an industry and
even as dedicated shops within companies
we don't do a very good job of actually
putting this into practice everyone
wants to emphasize the sharing of the
IRCs and everyone wants to put their
hang their hat on writing the very fancy
1020 hundred page report I don't know
why no one reads the hundred page report
but you get it so the thing is is that
in order for inw become a concept that
does end up helping the sock enabling
better defense is that CTI has to buy in
that this is something that we need to
do whether that means embedding analysts
within the work center or some other
action that we really need to start
embracing the idea of bridging that gap
between just collecting the raw data and
then writing up something lengthy about
it weeks or months later so what can you
do this is kind of like the most
important slide like oh that was very
nice Joe thank you for telling me what
do I actually do about this well among
other things from an analyst perspective
we need to lose some measure of pride
that instead of just like oh let the
machine generated iOS C's go out we
don't care about those I want to write
the big report and make a name for
myself and give a black cat talk or a
recon talk or something along those
lines like no your defenders really need
you to do this sort of work so it's not
just a question of getting your you know
rolling one sleeves up and diving into
the data to do that correlation in
near-real-time but also being more open
to yeah I don't know the complete
picture yet but here's what I know right
now this might change a little bit but
based upon what I've gathered and what
we already know here's something for you
my sock tier-2 defender can take action
for within what we're seeing in the
environment right now sharing groups
also can buy into this a little bit as
well so I don't know who here is part of
like a nice sack or you start talking
about the national level certs many of
these organizations are organized just
like private sector CTI providers where
you have one
the VOCs sometimes shared
semi-automatically and then over your
reports and nothing in the middle
sharing groups need to open themselves
up to better communication and find
mechanisms to share not just you know
those two types of information but
events as they're happening to the
benefit of defenders because otherwise
you're putting people at a disadvantage
we're all of two attackers that have
much quicker development cycles than we
do unfortunately and we get behind the
curve finally from a vendor perspective
you know we as vendors need to get
comfortable with reporting before the
whole story so this is something at
Drago's that I've put together is that
yes we were released reporting within 24
hours or so of observing something
knowing that we don't have the full
picture and letting our customers know
that hey you know this might change it
might not be accurate right now but
here's things as we see them at this
moment more plan can do this this is
something that I did in the Navy when it
came to things like tracking radar
signatures for example it allows
defenders to at least get part of the
picture to begin taking some informed
response even if they don't know
necessarily where everything is going
and then you know along those lines
tailor products at different customer
needs - many times it seems that threat
intelligence products are really geared
towards one audience the strategic
audience this is what the Chinese are
doing in with relation to intellectual
property theft across these five
industries that's really fascinating to
read but if I'm the watch person or the
incident responder or the security
operations center person I don't care
about that so much because it doesn't
impact my day-to-day operations that
much so as customers we can put pressure
on vendors to say hey this report is
very interesting but it's interesting
for not the people who are actually
responding to events on a day-to-day
basis can you help me out by providing
something a little bit more and last
thing I forgot - for what we could do as
analysts you know one of the things that
I did when I was running an incident
response team and not doing dedicated
threat intelligence operations is I
didn't care about the IOC s unless I
could take that iOS C and either pull
the malware myself from virustotal or
pull the domain from a risk IQ or you
know something else along those lines
and actually analyze it myself because I
realized that I wasn't getting the
detailed information necessary to
actually take action on it what the
malware does how it behaves how it
ties into other campaigns the hash
didn't tell me that so as consumers for
the time being until everyone else
catches up that's kind of what we need
to do ourselves because no one's helping
us out or supporting us with that sort
of work for us
so what we're all turnit looking to do
is again you know trying to find
something that's timely that we're
getting information in sufficient time
to inform and enable our operations
personnel to take defensive actions
that's descriptive that just just
doesn't say that this hash is bad this
IP address is bad but no this IP address
is being used for a encoded form of c2
associated with this threat actor that
behaves in this way that told me enough
in a sentence or two for me to take a
very informed response to what it is
that I'm observing in the environment
and lastly needs to be actionable
so just because I observe something what
does that mean being able to tie that
back to a certain type of adversary a
certain type of method of behavior means
that I can then begin anticipating what
defensive responses are necessary in
order to counteract that adversary so
that's all that I have I have some time
for questions
I think the podium actually I'm not sure
what timing we're on right now if we
have time for questions or not five
minutes for questions if not or if you'd
rather speak offline I will be around
the conference and you could certainly
hit me up through various means but we
had a question hi I'm okay without the
mic I'll repeat the question for the
audience too
I think it does to a certain extent
depending upon industry I think the
financial sector has probably done the
best amount of work I know I am NOT as
familiar I know some of the UK
organizations and I'm fairly familiar
with North American operations has done
a reasonably good job in coming together
to do some of what I talked about in
terms of not just sharing but trying to
share valuable information and I think
the important lesson from that is that
none of that was required instead the
financial institutions took a look at
the environments like oh my god we're
losing money and no one's helping us we
have to do something about this in other
sectors especially when you start
talking about sectors that deal with a
question of both proprietary and
reputational issues about being breached
whereas everyone assumes the banks are
always gonna get breached or someone's
always gonna try and breach the banks
you start talking about technology
companies or utility companies I know
one wants to know that they got breached
because that sounds really bad that it's
probably gonna take someone forcing to a
certain extent to make that happen
unless organizations can be more
comfortable with real understanding the
need and then doing so voluntarily and
then being willing to open up to each
other to show what's going on though I
hope that helped fine okay there was
another question in the back I thought I
saw a hand earlier hey Joe marching from
fire I advanced practices yeah you
mentioned in one of your first slides
that from indications and warnings
perspective the capabilities of malware
shouldn't be relevant to the incident
response team but would you agree with
me that when you're responding to a wipe
out malware destructive piece of code it
actually matters right yes yes yes so in
that case I either misspoke or there was
a misunderstanding so the distinction
I'm drawing is the intention versus
capabilities if that makes sense so yes
if I know that this piece of malware
either is or is the prerequisite to or
link to an adversary that does a wiper
or crypto mining or you know something
else or whatever
it's important that tells me what
something does what's less important is
why it doesn't I was what I was trying
to get at so thank you for asking that
question
others had that take you confusion
because yes the why yes looking back I
care but in the immediate sense of
responding to it whether it's mandiant
is going out or advanced practices is
looking at something in real time like
we'll figure that out later but the
capability aspect is most important
because that's gonna tell me both what I
need to do right now and what I need to
expect later from the defense so it
makes perfect sense thanks okay yeah
thank you for asking that okay I think
that's all I will be around thank you
everyone for sitting through this and
for dealing with you know inviting me to
speak in English and Poland so because
my your English is a lot better than my
polish so thank you very much everyone
[Applause]