thank you for having me so
self i'm Buuren item Eric I'm an master
student at tu Eindhoven in the
Netherlands I'm a teaching assistant for
several graduate and undergraduate
courses and in my spare time I'm a
security researcher my main interests
are hardware security and sandboxing and
virtualization in commonly used
enterprise products such as Adobe Flash
and Adobe Flash what I'll be talking
about today starting with some of the
flash runtime basics are we going
through an outline of the sandbox
security architecture and then quickly
moving on to flash exploitation two
scenarios one in which I'm going to
escape the local sandbox and one
escaping the remote sandbox and for each
of these two I'll be demonstrating
several examples of leaking information
stealing local files and stealing
Windows user credentials and finally in
light of recent efforts by various
vendors to deprecated flash I'll be
talking about flash its future
specifically the gaps that are being
left open to exploits by current current
plans to deprecated flash so Adobe Flash
I'm sure you're all familiar with it
it's a plugin that runs inside your
browser but you can also use it to
develop applications for a desktop or
your mobile phone and some of the use
cases are web animations but also
streaming DRM protected media
browser-based games audio and video
conferencing and basically any
general-purpose application that you can
think of and it's multi-platform
so it runs on all contemporary operating
systems
so a flash application starts with
writing ActionScript code and this
ActionScript code compiles to what is
called an SWF binary now this binary can
then be embedded in HTML pages which is
the most common use case but it can also
be embedded in PDFs compiled help
manuals HTML help manuals and most
importantly it can also be embedded in
office documents now running a flash
application if you're running a flash
application if we're running one of
these sandboxes and today I'll be
talking about the top two
starting with to remote sandbox the
Royal sandbox basically allows the flash
application to access remote servers but
it does not allow the flash application
to allow the local file system local
ways file system is tsx opposite it
allows accessing the local file system
but it does not allow accessing remote
servers so suppose you have a local file
like an HTML file embedding a flash
application and you try to open it then
it will be running in the what it's
called local with filesystem sandbox and
if you have a look at the adobe
developer documentation there are
actually two definitions that are
relevant here so I'll briefly go through
them first one defines the local with
filesystem sandbox itself and adobe says
this is the default sandbox for local
files SWF files in the sandbox may not
contact the internet or any surface in
any way so pretty straightforward but
then there's another definition that is
important here and
Adobe in this definition Adobe defines
what constitutes a local flash
application so a local SWF file
describes any file reference by using
the file protocol or a UNC path which
does not include an IP address or a
qualifying domain so here it's already
starting to be a bit tricky a bit wordy
and a bit ambiguous in a way especially
this file protocol and this UNC path
what are those actually and how does the
exclusion of an IP address or qualifying
domain effective formative protocols so
I'll come back to those questions later
but first if you've ever used Windows
File Sharing you will most likely be
familiar with this screen and what
you're actually I'm using under the hood
is a protocol called server message
block or SMB and closely related to SMB
is the universal naming convention or
UNC now UNC is a Windows concept to
express as a be passed to well an SMB
server and these resources can be
anything from shared files to devices
and named pipes you can use any of these
host identifiers IP address domain name
and what is called a net buyers host
name which originates from Windows
networks it's it's a type of name
resolution so if you take all this into
account of course this raises the
question what the paths are accepted by
flash so let's have a look at some
examples the first one will be accepted
by flash well no because there's an IP
address in there the second one some
server comm no because it's a domain
name
the third one intuitively you would say
no but the answer is yes
and this is only the case if you're
referencing the local host name so in
this case some PC so the other scheme
that's being accepted by flash is to
file your RI and if you want to have a
look at the definition you have to go
back all the way to 1994 this is
actually the entire RFC and the most
important bit is already on top it says
that the file URL scheme is used to
designate files accessible on a
particular host computer but this scheme
unlike most other URL schemes does not
designate a resource that is universally
accessible over the internet so this is
quite an interesting exception because
below you already see there's a host
identifier in there but it turns out
that because the RFC does not specify
which protocols should be used to fetch
this resource basically every
implementation out there just ignores
the host identifier and just assumes the
path to be referencing the local file
system so here's an example on Windows
just the word document host is on the
local C Drive and well apart from the
former RSC there's another one just
highlighting some non-standard syntax
variations but that's pretty much hits
for the file you arrived so in terms of
flash flash doesn't really impose any
restrictions on the file you're right
under the assumption that you cannot
express remote pass so there's nothing
to restrict okay so if you want to
escape the local sandbox now first let's
summarize what we have so far so
we have to look with file system sandbox
and it lets us access UNC pass and it
lets us use the file schemes but the
flash restricts UNC to local hosts only
and the file schemes takes only local
pass so the question is if you want to
escape the local sent box where do we go
from here well let's go back to past
expressions on Windows flash is a
multi-platform runtime and on Windows it
uses the win32 shell FBI now there's a
book over here that I found and it says
Windows 2000 but it's actually much
older and it's quite an interesting API
in the sense that it has a pack of
tricks that you can use to do some
interesting stuff and one is this you
can express UNC tags inside the file
scheme so in our example we have this
path to a remote resource in the UNC
syntax but if you want to express that
in a file scheme you simply add another
slash swap forward and back slashes and
then include the entire UNC URL now
flash actually parses this as being a
local path so for now we can access
remote resources from the local sandbox
so this is of course interesting we just
escape the local sandbox but we want to
steal some files so the approach is
basically you append local content to
the SMB resource requests that you make
a couple of basic steps so you read the
file that you're interested in and then
you take an account of the SMB path
restrictions so the file you're reading
you need to split in at most two hundred
and sixty bytes and then URL encode
whatever content it has then you append
the chunks to all the SMB resource
requests you're going to make you make
the requests and only attacker ends you
capture all your requests and reassemble
the entire file so let's have a look how
that works in practice on the Left
there's the attacker machine and on the
right the victim machine so first I'll
be running an SMB lover scripts that
access an SMB server and on the right
side the victim will be opening this
very trustworthy looking file and as you
can see it reads the winners hosts file
and sense it in chunks to the attacker
side and as you can see we've started
reconstructed the entire file on your
attacker end ok so we can escape the
local sandbox we can export rate local
files but there's something interesting
going on here because apparently we can
access remote SMB servers so for me to
trigger the question can we actually
leverage SMB for other kinds of attacks
so let's talk about SMB in particularly
SME authentication as a/b supports
various authentication schemes and one
of them is called Antillean ntlm v2 and
in this scheme you lock on user a
username and a hash of to user passwords
and there's a challenge response
mechanism involved so I'll briefly go
through how that works we have a user
and the user enters the username and
password to log onto the Windows machine
and instructs the Windows client who
connects you to server now what happen
is the client sends will send a username
in plaintext to the server the server
will respond with a challenge and the
client will use this challenge to
encrypt a hash if to use a password and
then send it back now after you if
everything went well then basically the
user will be authorized to access the
resources on the server now this seems
or might seem a solid approach but it is
not really there is an attack called the
SMB relay attack and again I will
briefly go through how this works so the
username locks onto the Windows machine
and then will try to access some
resource on the server but this time
there's an attacker in the middle and so
what will happen is the Windows client
will send the user name and then means
the attacker has to username now the
attacker will forward to username to the
server and the server will respond with
a challenge and that means the attacker
has the challenge sorry I'm moving too
fast the challenge will be forwarded to
the client and the client will use this
to encrypt a hash of the password and
then send it back and that means that
the attacker obtains the entire block
now since the attacker already have to
challenge this means the attacker can
trivially decrypt it and obtain the hash
of the user password this entire block
is then again forwarded to the server
and well that basically means that the
attacker can authenticate himself
impersonate himself as the victim so the
bottom line is the attacker actually
obtains the plaintext username and a
hash of the user password so if you have
this ntlm hash what can you do with it
so first of all you can mount what is
called a pass to hash attack
one approach is that the attacker
authenticates on the third-party host
that the victim is allowed to access and
that's the scenario we've seen on the
previous slide one other approach is
that the ascend attacker authenticates
on the client machine but this was
eventually patched for Microsoft and the
third option is that the attacker tries
to authenticate against the remote
desktop surface which interestingly does
not work on Windows 10 because got
patched but it never got patched on
Windows 8.1 and Windows Server 2016 if
I'm correct here now finally if that all
fails you can try to obtain the
plaintext password and you can do that
by using rainbow tables and you can also
try to brute force the hash and to give
you a rough idea basically an eight
character password permutation can be
found in under six hours and this is a
number from 2012 so you can imagine that
with today's hardware it will be much
faster than that right so what does that
mean for our attacker scenario well we
have our malicious flash application
running on the victim PC so basically we
can instruct it to connect to an SMB
server of our choosing
so what we can do is run a Python script
called SMB trap an SMB trap is basically
a Windows user credentials logger while
acting as an SMB server so going back to
our attacker scenario the application
will try to connect to the attacker
control server but there are something
different this time because Windows will
try to authenticate as a guest now
obviously this is not what we want so we
tell the clients that it cannot access
the resource without authenticating and
basically this restores the regular
logon procedure which we've discussed in
the previous slides in that in the sense
that the
kind sense the plaintext username to the
server the server sends back to
challenge and then the clients will send
back a hash of the password encrypted
with that challenge so here's an example
how you can turn that into an actual
attack be running as a beat trap and on
the victims side will be again opening a
local file this time we'll be opening it
in Firefox and as you can see we just
escaped the sandbox and I put a rainbow
table in there so it as a be trap
managed to match the hash against this
very secure password so we can export
eight local files we can disclose them
to a remote server and we can also steal
Windows user credentials so I've been
having a look at how this is actually
possible and it just turns out there are
a number of fundamental issues in
sandbox policies so starting with these
arbitrary definitions of what
constitutes a local file and what
constitutes the local with filesystem
sandbox there are very wordy and very
ambiguous and apparently Adobe's
developers didn't know what to do with
it either so that means that this this
blacklist approach does not cover all
corner cases like the examples I just
showed and it allows to turn
remote Pass actually into into a local
path and so this renders flash subject
to well known as a be vulnerable ''tis
now the interesting thing is is for
mobility is House Department as agnostic
it worked in all browsers and chrome and
etch are actually two special cases here
because they apply their own sandbox on
top of the flash hand box but despite
this mechanism the not going past the
the path to that are created was just
being accepted as well now it turns out
that the sandbox policies were largely
unmodified since Flash Player 9 which
was released in 2000 exists in six so
that means that this for mobility has
actually been present for over ten years
it was fixed in Flash Player 23 and in
this version Adobe introduced new
sandbox policies basically the they
dropped the entire local with file
system sandbox and there were also all
the local file system API is because
they had no user anymore and local
networking became the new default
sandbox which is pretty much similar to
the remote sandbox in the sense that you
can access remote servers but you cannot
access the local file system so this was
it was a change that required web
developers to refactor their existing
applications for local file system
interaction developers had to move to
html5 techniques which at the time was
still being considered a competitor to
flash and interestingly it also covertly
added some restrictions to SMB access in
the other sandbox the remote sandbox and
I'll be talking about that later
okay so here are the lease notes for
Flash Player 23 and well the new sandbox
policies they seem a solace approach but
there's no mentioning of this remote
sandbox so for me it is triggered a
question Hey
with this sandbox b4 roll or would they
have patched this vulnerability in the
remote sandbox as well so moving on to
the remote set box
it turns out that they actually did
change the remote sandbox and well
basically the wrong sandbox now rejects
human C and file style paths and in fact
it rejects any URL which is being
prefixed not being prefixed by HTTP or
HTTPS so it turns out that flash 23
actually introduced a whitelist approach
and so if you want to escape the remote
sandbox you have to think about other
options so let's go to back to SMB and
back in 2015 there was a new new
publication on a new attack and it
basically works like this you have an
HTTP client and it requests some file
from a remote attack control server and
the server will respond with a 302
redirect header but in the location
header it will not put another HTTP
resource but a reference to well the
same kind of file style UNC path that I
previously showed in the previous slide
so this vulnerability it's actually well
documented and it turns out that it that
it effects all of these win32 API
functions so any application that uses
any of these functions is actually
fallible and this trigger to industry to
patch their software
so obviously this trigger question
for me is Adobe Flash vulnerable as well
so I test this for this using this setup
and I'll briefly go through how it works
we are going to have the client with our
malicious flash application the clients
will try to download a file from the
attack control server the server will
respond with an HTTP 302 referencing
this file style UNC path and then if
everything went well the client will
connect to our middle Isha's SMB server
so the first try it didn't really work
so here's a Wireshark trace and we can
see that while the flash application is
actually doing a request
there's no SMB traffic in there but
there are some other interesting things
like this thing on top it says there's a
get request for a file called cross
domain dot XML this is pretty
interesting because I didn't program my
flash application to do that so it turns
out that is cross domain that XML is a
reference to what is called the cross
domain policy file and if you're
familiar with HTTP course it's it's
pretty similar in that it's well in this
case it dictates when the SWF is allowed
to reload resources from a different
domain other than the one is this hosted
on so for example if you have a flash
application and it's hosted on domain
a.com it will not be able to load any
resources from domain be calm if the
main build condos not authorize the
flash application to do that so again
here's that with definition and the most
interesting thing is apart from it being
again very wordy that there are also a
lot of reference to domains but we're
actually interested in is what happens
when we're switching protocols
redirecting for HTTP to SMB now there's
nothing in the spec that that tells us
why the attack is being blocked but we
do see that the Wireshark trace shows
the cross domain direction now being
requested from the machine that's
hosting the flash application so that is
already contradicting the specification
but I figured okay you know what let's
just construct a least restrictive cross
domain policy this is just a few lines
of XML code telling the flash
application it's it's okay you can
access any resource on this domain and
now I'm going to show you what happens
when we feed that policy to the flash
runtime so on the attacker side I will
be running two scripts one is a web
server and the other one is as a beach
wrap and we'll be using edge this time
on the client machine navigating to the
web server and as you can see we've
again escaped the remote sandbox and
managed to obtain the user password on
the attacker side so this one Realty
actually broke though week's patch for
the former vulnerability and it exposes
Windows user credentials to a remote
server and it turns out that well the
problem basically is inconsistent
powerful relation this whitelist
approach is seemingly very solid but the
check is only done once and it's not
being applied to any redirects the
interesting thing also is that it
affects Firefox Internet Explorer and
Microsoft Office but not chrome and edge
and chrome - were probably not for a
role as a response to the previous
vulnerability
and for Chrome we can actually see that
this this is this that this is the case
so Chrome has this nice developer tool
called net internals and we can actually
see what happens when it processes the
redirect response and as you can see
here it does not take to redirect
because it's being considered unsafe so
this one reveals he was fixed in Flash
Player 26 and well basically it does so
by applying improve validation to
redirects as well the interesting thing
is that it's required again refactoring
from for existing flash applications
because it now dropped support for SMB
altogether and also it was a bit of
fortunate that this change was not
actually reflected in the change logs or
the developer documentation so the
future of Flash I'm sure you've all seen
this announcement back in August 2017
that Adobe is going to demarcate flash
by 2020 and so I figured it was a good
idea to have a look at what the industry
is doing to deprecated so from the
browser perspectives across the board we
see all sorts of measures like vendeur
curated blacklist or whitelist some form
of click to play and we also see that we
the plug-in will basically be disabled
by default at the end of this year and
plug-in support will be dropped by early
2020 or late 2020 in some of the other
cases what is interesting though that
Internet Explorer is an exception to
this because there are no is
restrictions to flash until later this
year
in response to web de web browser
vendors deprecating flash the web has
moved to open web technologies so for
streaming
there's html5 video for web UI
animations there CSS and J's video
conferencing there's web RTC and for
games and anything else we have the
canvas WebGL and web assembly and as you
can see this has actually resulted in
reduced market share from flash down
from almost 26% in 2012 to 3.5% at the
end of May of this year now this
obviously triggers the question is flash
the thing of the past
well web browsers are not the only
attack factory in fact Flash Player is
distributed via mandatory Windows
updates at least until 2020 there are no
further announcements by Microsoft yet
at this point and this is especially a
problem for Windows 10 and Windows
Server 2016 and up because you cannot
opt out or uninstall Flash Player on
Windows 8.1 Windows Server 2012 or two
it's a little bit better because you can
actually uninstall flash but you will
need to do so with each Flash Player
updates and as you can see in the
screenshot right here they do get
released very occasionally so basically
this means that the attack surface
remains outside browsers and one of the
most important
attack vectors here is office because
office does not restrict Flash content
at all from office 2010 up to to our
office 2019 there is one minor exception
if you're running the office 365 version
then you are protected and as for the
rest well you can embed as an SWF in
PDFs in compiled HTML help files and
because Internet Explorer does not
restrict flash at all well basically if
you can get ahold of a internet for
based web browser control you're back in
business and also when you manage to
invoke the Flash Player control through
for example PowerShell or calm or the
window scripting host
so the takeaway that I would like to
give with this talk is the parsing
seemingly simple in performance such as
well a file pass it can be well can be
deceptively complicated simply because
of the diverse landscape of parameters
that you have to take into into account
like this URI scheme specs which are
very short and very well ambiguous in a
way there's OS specific interpretations
so if you offload for example file path
processing to the OS then you need to be
extra careful
there are sandbox policies that you need
to take into account if you're running
inside a browser then there's that and
also well the OS that you're developing
for it has specific vulnerabilities that
you may or may not want to have to look
at so basically there you really need a
structured approach for something as
simple as parsing file input file paths
to capture all corner cases so all the
issues
I disclosed him to Adobe they were all
patched the deployment process was a bit
unfortunate because it broke existing
applications twice documentation was not
updated but the fix turns out to be a
solid approach the industry efforts to
duplicate flash well it generates mixed
results I mean we're seeing the web is
migrating from flash to other
technologies and most of the browser
vendors are also deprecating flash but
two other major attack vectors like
office and Internet Explorer are still
vulnerable because they do not impose
any restrictions and well the fact that
Windows issues mandatory flash updates
does not help ire so basically the
attack surface is still significant and
the advice I would like to give is
regularly review the need for Flash
Player develop deployment and well
disabling it really is not enough you
really need to uninstall it so if you're
interested in the vulnerabilities I've
put up two blog posts with some more
technical details and I'll be around
here at the conference and you can also
reach me on Twitter thank you
[Applause]
any questions no questions think