okay so our talk is named The Revenge of
the script kiddies most of you probably
know the term but script kiddies refers
to young people running scripts that
they didn't write themselves during
their free time to hack different things
usually not in a very experienced way
but in the next 50 minutes what we're
going to show you and is that script is
no longer the property of just script
kiddies anymore but rather a tool in the
hands of much more sophisticated and
advanced attackers okay let's dive into
the agenda then we'll introduce
ourselves and then to our content so
we'll start by presenting banking Trojan
or financial malware or bankers we call
them all these three names it's
interchangeable for us so just so you
know after we do this short introduction
will present three different examples of
scripting languages in different phases
of banking Trojans attacks so we'll see
infection we'll see the download
we'll see code execution and we'll see
encryption and decryption finally we'll
conclude and go on to the rest of the
amazing talks that we have here before I
forget I don't think many of the
organizers are here but we'd like to
thank them dearly for having us here
this is an amazing event in my own
opinion and it's a pleasure to be here
okay so my name is affair I'm a security
researcher in a data center and cloud
security company named Guardi core I'm
part of the labs team and we have a nice
website that you can check for our
publications I also wrote a tutorial on
reverse engineering about a year ago if
you're a beginner to the field of
reverse engineering you're more than
welcome to check this website and tell
me what you think and or we'll take it
from here
Thank You Phil so hi everyone my name is
all I work for Proofpoint
part of cloud security team first of all
we would like to thank the still
this research was mostly conducted in
IBM labs while we walk there and we want
to thank them for allowing us to present
it here so let's start what's the basic
concept of financial models so they have
to wait and for an online session to
takes place before they can start
hijacking the session that fact makes
them want to infect as many machines as
possible as fast as possible it's very
crucial and we shall example later on
how Romney did it also it's important to
know that the target is the end-user
himself and not the bank the Mallo is
aimed to steal money from the end-users
sometimes the bank will give them the
money back but still they want to take
the money from the end-user themselves
so yeah
the end goal is money and they achieve
it using two ways one is in session
where the Foresters will transfer money
from the victim's account to their
account or the mule account that they
made before and the other way is just
swapping accounts so when you try
transfer money the money will actually
go to the victim to the foster account
instead of your account so their PA
account for example and try to transfer
money for a friend tomorrow we've
changed the number of the bank account
so it will go to a mule account in other
ways come take over my Wells use remote
access tools also today most banking
most banks is browser fingerprinting
which means that they want to know what
plugins did the user have on system
what's the encoding for the languages
what's resolution and a finger paint all
of it when fraudster try to do ATM
they must mimic all of those properties
so what's the flow for a financial model
first of all usually it all start with
spam campaigns and after a spam campaign
is sent users usually bite the bait
and the Machine gets infected after that
Marla will try to get persistency and to
gain control over the browser after
having gained control over the browser
he will usually try to perform some web
injections or basically will try to
alter the web page itself
and change the context that the user
sees I will show examples later on and
the other thing mothers try to do is to
redirect the user to a completely fake
website also we'll see example later on
and eventually they want to get off it
and have a great success so spam
campaigns we all know we love them there
is no need to get into those or most of
the marvels begin with spam campaigns
then they achieve persistence using
startup folder registry keys task
scheduler we all know and love the gig
and we will today will show you some
cool tricks that rahmatan go see that
does they still use the desk scheduler
but they have cool tricks and then they
aim to control over the browser it's
usually done by code injection and
hooking of API functions most of the
time is done by using windows function
and creative mode thread so on the right
side you can see Firefox function theory
Dampier right being hooked and jump to
some unknown place of model code what's
nice about hooking these functions is
that model don't need to handle SSL
encryption and decryption they get the
data already in clear text so they just
take it before or after Firefox has
already done the encryption or
decryption for them which is cool and on
the left side we can see trick about
code 11 called parser injected to
browser and this is not working
nice yeah you have another one
okay
yeah stop talking
yeah so as I said before there are two
types of attack web injections and
redirect in web injects you basically
the model basically insert malicious
code into the original web page sauce
they actually alter the page the HTML
code whatever they want to do and in
redirect redirect attacks they will
usually redirect the user to a fake
website completely tailor-made to fool
them so it the website will look exactly
like the original banking website it's
just a completely fake one and let's see
example for those two so first of all I
have to say that we were not allowed to
show real bank examples so we did the
best we could
so on the left side we can see Google
and username in Booga Jeff is trying to
log into his email account and Google is
saying that they will never ask us
season for his grandmother's favorite
preferences and on the right side after
the mod well altered the page we can see
that they actually asked for his
grandmother's favorite pet and they we
said that Google will never ask for your
favorite pizza so usually it works for
most users they can tell the difference
the other way that Marvel uses is just
redirection so again we can show little
banking web page so just imagine my
little pony wedding is a real Bank
website what you can see is that the
address is still there and the icon
necessarily icon is still there the
website icon is there the topic is there
everything look exactly as it should be
but instead of getting to your bank
website you get into completely
tailor-made fake website it's made
entirely to steal your credentials or
details or just folio so now that we
know that Marvel does it we have the
question of how we knows which targets
to attack and the answer is model
configurations so the model store attack
in configuration files usually they will
be encrypted on the left side we can see
trick bot as those this configuration
config file and on the right side we can
see goes east all these models and
configuration inside the registry it's
are encrypted so there is not much we
can read here after the corruption it
will look something like that so now we
have a trick bot list of servers IPs and
ports that it tries to connect to in
order to fetch modules form below that
there should be a list of targets the
thing about trying to attack so there
should be a target and what you do it
when you reach the target on the right
side you can see an example of free
injection so you can see the function
get login it ratifies that the username
and password exists and user enter them
and then it calls function calls copy
string to clipboard which basically
steals this and I mean pass all the via
the function above and now fill will
continue thank you for the nice
introduction do we have a clicker I
can't live without the clicker thank you
okay so as we promised before we had a
nice overview on banking Trojans and now
is the time to actually get into some
real examples
so the first banker we're going to talk
about is named earth Smith or go Z or is
SP again different names we call the
same family the same thing ok so just a
little bit of background on earth sniff
this is a malware sample that's been
around with us for many years actually
the source code of earth sniff leaked in
2015 and this led to many of its module
being used by other malware families as
well so the most recent one I can think
of is Dana bot for those of you who know
Dana bought used earth sniffs web
injection modules so the actual
JavaScript code that is injected to the
browser during the session was used by
other malware as well now these are
exactly the modules I was interested in
when I worked in IBM because we
investigated the JavaScript code that
was injected to the browser and we
signed this code to detect malicious
activity in the banking sessions so to
investigate those modules and this code
we had to actually infect our own
machines and this was not an easy task
at
the first attempt we tried was trying to
infect completely clean machines in
fetching a sample from the wild and just
double-clicking the executable file on a
clean machine and hoping for the best
but this didn't work because earth
sniffs command and control servers went
up and down almost on a daily basis so
we just didn't manage to download the
configuration onto the machine and we
didn't get any web injections of course
so the other approach we tried was to
run a sample on a machine which already
had the malware configuration and what
we basically did is we fold earth leaf
to think that it was running on an
already infected machine when it
actually wasn't we just had the
configuration in the registry and we
thought that running the sample with
this time work but once again this
didn't work we wrote a very nice Python
script that took registry values
actually I forgot to say we why we had
access to the registry at all
we had access to end-users machine
because we were getting from time to
time reports on fraud and we were able
to connect to machines in the wild which
were infected
so under full agreement of the end user
we were able to read the relevant
registry values and fetch the malware
samples as well so what we tried to do
was to read the registry on a victim's
machine and copy the relevant values
onto our virtual machines and then run
the dll on this machine but this didn't
work as well so our second approach
didn't really work and there were no
JavaScript injections to the websites
which we knew were targeted by ER sniff
for sure so we had no choice and we had
to take a deeper look into the malware
and what we found out was that earth
sniff cared for a value named security
identifier
which is a per user value that our sniff
used as a randomization seed to generate
names inside its configuration so what
we were actually missing was to take our
virtual machine and give it the security
identifier of the remote machine that
was infected so what we had to do was
basically add another
step two our Python script and use this
tool named CID change which is available
online we just changed the CID of our
local machine we said the local registry
with the values we saw on the victim
machine
we ran the DLL and this was actually
successful and we could see the
JavaScript code doing web injections and
redirects and everything that earth
sniff was doing at the time but things
are not so fortunate all the time an
earth sniff decided to go Sylas
completely and so we didn't have any
executable to run anymore
and we I looked sort of like that we
decided to read the registry because
this is the only thing that we had so we
we we've taken a look into the registry
values and as you can see much of the
data was just hexadecimal values huge
ones actually representing both the
configuration of our sniff and it's
actual modules but among all these
where's the laser here do I have a laser
I don't know if I do there is one line
here with capital S as a key never mind
where you can actually see plaintext
code and this is PowerShell code within
the registry so a lot of hexadecimal
rubbish but one entry which is actual
code this was interesting a nice thing
to mention was that when we double-click
this entry this is what's showed up
nothing Windows registry doesn't display
data which is too long so we knew that
this data could be exported of course
and we took all this code and dumped it
into a file and this is what we got now
I shortened the strings a little bit
just to make things more readable but
this was the actual script the whole
script it was five statements long we
had two function declarations as you can
see one a variable assignment in between
the functions and to invoke expression
statements how many of you read or
written PowerShell code ok that's nice
not too many I'll just
say that IEX and a voc expression stands
for the evaluation function in
powershell which mean it's taking a
string and it treats it as if it is code
and just executes it
so the equivalent in Python for example
is the eval I think or in JavaScript as
well
okay so let's dig in to this code
actually we can see right away that the
two functions are handling base64 data
we search the documentation a little bit
and we saw that the first one was
converting base64 data into an integer
array where the second one was using the
first function to convert basic C 4 to
an actual string so this part we knew
the next thing was to figure out what
the data was what this variable was so
once again we decoded basics T for data
dumped it into a binary file open it
with our favorite hex editor and this is
what we saw there was a lot of op codes
of course but then we ran into this part
where many function names appeared so we
see the C runtime functions like
memcache we see Windows API functions
like create process and at this time we
realize this was actually like shellcode
payload ok nice that's our that's some
information for us we can assume that
it's somehow executing code here but we
still have some more insights to draw
from the script so let's go for the
first invoke expression statement when
we decode what's within the parameter
this is what we get a lot of PowerShell
code let's clean it up a little bit
actually this is too long for one slide
so I split it into two what we can see
that our sniff is doing here is it's
creating a PowerShell class whose
members are Windows API functions from
kernel32 modules so we can see get
current thread ID open thread queue user
ABC and sleep and in the second part
it's creating yet another powershell
class word imports get current process
and virtual alec so at this point we can
kind of assume what it's going to do
there's some thread management here
memory allocation something is fishy and
there's of course the payload the
shellcode itself but to really make this
whole picture complete we'll take a look
at the last statement that we have here
and the last invoke expression evaluates
to this so as you can see we have the
exact functions that earth was importing
from before
let's prettify this thing to have the
punch of this script so air sniff is
actually allocating memory in the
current process that's running which is
the PowerShell context and it's
allocating just enough memory space to
populate the shellcode as you can see
payload length and it's giving it read
read and execute permissions and then it
copies the payload on to the newly
allocated buffer and then it just runs
this code by providing Q user a PC with
the buffer address and the current
thread so this is how our sniff is
executing code using the the registry
value now as you can see it does it by
creating the classes and importing
Windows API functions now how does all
this get run in the first place so our
mentioned before that banking Trojans
are still using very classical methods
and as you can see what our sniff is
using here is the task scheduler which
is a very classical trick but actually
there's a twist here it's not running an
executable file because as I mentioned
it went Silas so there is no executable
file to run instead what it's doing it's
running a completely benign program
built-in in Windows named for files and
if we zoom in to the value that is being
executed with every scheduled task this
is it so it goes through the windows
system32 folder and it's just iterating
on all the files there recursively and
it's looking for a file that matches
this blue pattern over there I don't
know if you see a P star double-l dot
star e which matches PowerShell of
course so air sniff is looking for a
file for the PowerShell
cutable and it provides it with the ICI
flag which stands for encoded command
and there it gives it basic ste 4
encoded commands to execute
let's employ our best trick and decode
this data and this is what we get
so PowerShell once again invokes an
expression where it's fetches the
registry value with the actual
PowerShell code so this is end to end
how ursin if it's executing malicious
payload on the victim machine with every
reboot of the machine because it's
persistent without having a file on the
file system why is it using script at
all so first of all file as malware is a
stealthier malware in the sense that it
made antivirus scanner engines more
easily so if you know the scanner engine
just periodically scans the file system
looking for signatures in earth sniff is
obviously escaping these checks also all
the malicious activity is done from
within the PowerShell program which is
allegedly benign and is part of Windows
so yeah this is our sniff and it's usage
of automated scripts and the next
example will be the Ramnath malware
which or will present Thank You fear so
before I want to talk about Romney I
want to talk about three topics in
Windows so we'll all be in the same
level the first one is Windows DP API or
data production API so basically it's
simple to keep the graphic API it's been
around since Windows 2000 Microsoft
provided it for developers to have
easier life to encode encrypting to keep
data it enables symmetric encryption of
any kind of data which is nice it has
two different scope one is current user
and one is local machine when you use
the current user one if you decrypt
something only that user will be able to
open it and if use the local machine the
data will be available to all all users
in those machines and the good thing
about local machine is when you encrypt
using it
you can actually get some files from the
machine and he kept it locally and
current user
but the encryption is based on the hash
of the password of the user and this is
all sounds very promising if you click
on the link you'll see a lecture that
was given last year saying how not safe
it is say basically you can tell us
everything but your secret so not as
safe as you wish they will be
Benjamin Dell being tweeted some time
ago that friends don't let friends save
passwords with dpi API and he said it
it's almost like little text passwords
however today many applications use it
for legitimate reasons home for example
easy to save all of the users personal
data the passwords everything inside the
browser and mimikatz can pretty much
fetch everything from your DPI
information and it is also a decrypted
it was written by Neil soft long time
ago but you can just give them some
files and it will decrypt it for you
another term I wanted to talk about is
LAN bus or living off the land banners
and scripts and also libraries it was
called by Christopher Campbell and Matt
rebel and they build cool repo currently
there's 96 binaries which is basically a
list of files that you can use post post
exploitation you just enter Windows
machine and those files should already
be there waiting for you it's a list of
files and whatever you can do with them
or we can abuse them to do things that
usually are not allowed not supposed to
do I'm mentioning this because one it
uses long bus and we'll see it shortly
and the last term is a messiah wente
malware scan interface it's part of
Windows 10 it's an interface standard
that allows application to integrate
with animal products it's not limited to
Windows Defender
every auntie model can and integrate
with it and most of them actually does
integrate with them it was already
bypassed few times
that link you can see cyberfest it these
memory patching to do it and the reason
I'm talking about am a size because Ram
it is abusing it also will see shortly
and now we can start talk about Ram it
so Romney is operating since 2002 got
taken down at 2015 that fact doesn't
hurt him doesn't interrupt him from
disturbing new versions almost weekly
the latest known from a financial model
is named camellia they name each model
which is cool and campaign not so long
ago they were able to infect 100,000
machines in two months which is really
really cool as I said before Marvel has
to have an active session so they want
to infect as many machines as possible
100,000 machines in two months is very
fast and exactly what am I wanted so
they succeed in that Amit comes you can
load any model they desire they have the
HIV and C model which is hidden VNC this
allows them to trick browser
fingerprinting tools so they can just
connect your machine have a remote
connection hidden remote connection to
your machine open your browser and
connect to the banking website it also
come loaded with key logger screen
mobile cookie go grab a phone girl many
browser injections and more and what's
nice about run it and most when an
advanced financial marvels the 2d they
can create and add new models in a very
fast time so how did I get to Romney
while I walk photo still someone called
and say every sample I needed to have a
look at it and send me some files and I
just double-click it and nothing
happened and we did the same experience
experiment a few times and after a few
times just open the scripts and I
started to use some function call
unprotect after some researching I
realized that this function was part of
dpi API we will see it shortly
so eventually just infected a machine
which Romney and saw that there was this
randomly generated name a GPX something
that runs every 15 minutes after login
and what this task is doing is basically
of calling wmic
which you can see it'll read about it in
Lowell bus and WMA seas creating calling
a vbscript
which resides in a row something folder
and now let's go into the folder into
the scripts so we can see that the
folder has three files at the X T VB
script and a PowerShell script and when
trying to opening the VB script it looks
a bit obtuse cated just let's verify it
now it's much more readable now it's
easy to see that they'll look to check
whether your system is 32 bits or 64
bits and they open the appropriate
powershell version then they try to run
PowerShell in a hidden window while
bypassing the execution policy of
Windows it seems to be how us to
accomplish then they call the some
powershell script we will now look at
the powershell script so I open the
PowerShell script and this is what I saw
a little bit unreadable just rename some
variables now it's much more readable so
we can see that they took some txt file
read it and then call a function called
called unprotect this function is part
of windows DPI api and the scope was
local machine so basically the model
encrypted himself using windows api api
and now it it opens that that means that
if you took the files to your own
machine you won't be able to decrypt it
yourself
you have to do it on the victims machine
and in order to decrypt it in the
victim's machine it's really easy task
to accomplish all you need to do is that
this line out file and now we will have
a pretty output with a complete tag txt
file and we'll see it really soon so
this was the original text I don't know
about you guys most experiments on my
machine looks better than Oh more
readable this one it's obviously
encrypted so now we have the cryptid
file because we did it before we use the
out file function and this is what it
looks like
it's pretty readable you can read it it
has some meaningful names but obviously
as you can see the topic it has some
random means so we start browsing the
file and I started to test 2006 on it
line which is a lot when all of a sudden
I bumped into a remark over there know
that comment said this is still get work
address but instead of PowerShell
converting his thing to a pointer you
must do it yourself and I was thinking
wait this doesn't really look like
yourself obviously he copied it from
somewhere I just put this comment on
Google and Google did invoke inflective
the injection which is part of power
sploit basically it allows for
reflective the injection via PowerShell
it's really cool tool and my next step
was to compel the original version to
run its version the version on github on
the right side we can see the version of
github on the left side you can see ROM
its version so instead it's it's pretty
much the exact same thing
it is also scared it really badly and so
we changed some function names use the
bed office Kato when it really made our
life easier now we wanted to see what on
it actually added to the code so we just
browse to the end of the file and we can
saw see this thing initially we saw this
function which reflected the flexion
assembly load some basics default string
so all we did was the Coley string put
it inside a binary file and load it with
our favorite dotnet the compiler and now
this is what we got you can see that the
function name is disabled and it did
close the library called a Masai dot DL
arrow and after that he does get back
address to some function in AMS I
changed the protection creates new
buffer
basically it's cooking 101 obviously the
mother is hooking a Masai functions we
talked about it before about what is the
NSA and he does it in order to avoid
detection you actually use the same
method that cyborg published you just
changed the buffer a bit
so that that tells us that raw meat is
up to date and reads blogs which is cool
so now we know that the function does
this able a Masai we can rename it to
disable a Masai we also notice that the
model has some outputs things some debug
string left which is also bad OPSEC and
we see that it calls the sable MSI then
it declared our original file name and
basically
Ramnath don't want the doorbell or the
model itself to stay on the machine they
only want the payload to be on the
machine so they declare file and of the
Mallory and they stop it delete it and
eventually you can see that they create
new payload it starts with 45 a as most
of you probably know it's the magic
header for NZ so we can guess it's an
executable file and then it does invoke
reflective be injection basically runs
loads that file into PowerShell and run
it from PowerShell context and that's
most of the scripts job and now let's
just recap so the architect the
architecture was a scheduled task that
ran Randall all best wmhc lat exe that
called the VB script the VB script when
the PowerShell the PowerShell read kept
an R and a txt file and yeah the
question is why script so Romney did it
for multiple purposes he decrypted a txt
file using scripts he bypassed IMSI he
did some code injection even scripts and
actually it's a bit hard for antiviruses
to detect it because they're encrypted
the payload in each machine and romney
did a pretty good job because used many
many scripting languages VB script
powershell the test rescheduled trick he
also have complex architectures we just
saw before it was pretty it took some
time to unveil everything and to figure
out why does every step of the way and
that's it we will now continue with some
back swap
you sew back swap will be our last
example and more particularly what drops
back swap onto the machine which is a
dropper named Astapor Nemec on some
background on back swap as we do for all
malware so this malware was first
spotted in March of last year it started
by actually targeting Polish entities
like banking institutions and
cryptocurrency exchange platforms but
soon it realize that apparently there is
more money in Spain and it moved to
attacking and targeting the sixth
biggest banks in Spain now back soap is
using simple yet very very cool
techniques to do with gigs to do its web
injections and the information stealing
and I'll show you some examples first of
all back soap is using bitmap images to
hide its binary code within benign
programs like a ladybug and when rare
for example so it actually uses images
and it's been using Putin images as well
as Cartman's bottom also a nice thing I
saw when I investigated back swap is
that the actual code injection to the
browser was done through the address bar
so I just opened a banking website and
all of a sudden I saw the URL disappear
from the address bar and some JavaScript
code pasted there so it was a matter of
a second but I could actually see that
and that's a very ridiculous method of
injecting code to a browser because it's
very visible also the injected code
actually stays in the browser history so
if you type JavaScript in the address
bar you can actually see the code that
it's that it injected back stop was very
very nicely researched and they're
absolutely great two blog posts that
I've read and I highly recommend one is
by Michael and Peter from ESET and the
other one is the evolution of back swap
written by ty Cohen from check point if
you want to further read on this malware
then I really recommend
so let's do some storytime when we
worked in Trusteer a customer contacted
us and told us that there was a fraud
case in a victim's machine and the nice
thing was that the end user was just
willing to share the sample with us and
we were obviously very happy because
temp samples are great right and so we
agreed and in turn we got these so there
was some archive file that when we
extracted this is what showed up eight
JSE files some sharing the same size as
you can see but I'll have different hash
values so eight distinct jst files we
had no idea what these were actually
this was definitely not a sample we're
very used to binary files and eggsy's
and stuff like that so yeah what was
that we just decided to perform the
shortest and dirtiest analysis we could
and this is gonna be the next example of
back swap so we opened the file the
files are one of the file with our
favorite editor and this is what we saw
a lot of rubbish this was not fun to see
but our next step of course was to ask
Google what JSP was because to be honest
I never ran into JSE files before and we
saw that these were JavaScript encoded
files and of course obviously the next
thing we had to do was to find a decoder
for these files to be able to read them
and we found this project on github
named SCR deck we simply ran it on each
one of the files and we got some
readable nice files a little obfuscated
but this this is obviously nicer than
what we had before okay so we had now
eight files each one had around 60 K
lines of code resulting in half a
million lines of code that we were
definitely not about to read but we
decided to just take a brief look to see
what's in there and we noticed that each
one of the script files started with two
function declarations each one is
calling
the unescape method on some parameter
and each one of these functions were
called thousands of time from within
each script so we figured out these were
important functions and we decided to
just print out what they had to offer
now since they were called thousands of
time we figured out that they were
decoding something and we decided to
just add our own variable to each one of
the scripts here we named it accumulated
string we added one more line to each
one of the functions to actually append
the unescape characters to our new
variable then we ran this thing on an
isolated machine of course because once
again we didn't know what these scripts
were so we ran it from the command line
and this is what we saw nice plain text
decoded and the even nicer thing was to
find out that this was connecting some
machine some remote machine at this
point of course we understood that what
we had in our hands was a dropper or
droppers in floral and definitely not
back subsample but we were smart at this
point and we could actually fetch or try
to fetch the sampler from the command
and control servers of course we googled
all the indicators that we saw like some
parts of this URL and we saw that this
was the Oh stamp or an emic odd dropper
which worked closely with the backs of
malware and this was also covered very
nicely by a third poll and yeah so this
is the end of our quick and dirty
solution backs up by the way a nice
anecdote it's also moved from JSC to
PowerShell which indicates some trending
PowerShell usage in the world of malware
which is interesting and after all these
examples and real-life case studies we
can now conclude what we've seen today
so banking Trojans financial malware is
moving more and more functionality from
binary files to scripting languages and
we saw the scripts integrated in various
parts of the attacks so we saw the
infection itself with the download of
back swap we saw code execution from the
registry for example
with earth sniff and we saw how Ramnath
was using scripts to encrypt data
specific for the machine it was running
on why are they using script so we
mentioned that a little as well scripts
are easier to hide from anti viruses
engines and also I would like to say
that malware authors are just as lazy as
malware researchers and scripting is
easier than compiling C code I don't
know maybe some of you think differently
I like writing in Python and eventually
this thing works I mean they get all the
functionality they want using these
methods so they still managed to make a
lot of money out of their cybercrime and
yeah this is it
so we're down here thank you very much
for being here at 9 o'clock in the
morning yeah thank you so much also for
you it was very great presentation