a lot of you are probably familiar with
what Yara is you build the rule it's
kind of like a signature and you can use
it to hunt malware now a lot of these
rules that you see that are being built
are built only using strings and when
you start adding in things like a string
out for stations the strings no longer
work so if you look at malware from ten
years ago for example and you look at it
the same malware today
your er rule probably won't work so
basically I'm going to show you how to
build your rules that are actually going
to last
while threat hunting so just to tell you
a little bit about myself let me get
this
okay just so my name is Jay Rosenberg
and I'm a senior security researcher on
the global research and analysis team of
Kaspersky also known as great formerly I
was I led the research at a startup
called
Intel labs where we created a code reuse
technology and I've been reverse
engineering and programming for about 14
years now when I focus on a threat
intelligence malware analysis and
reverse engineering okay so just a quick
overview a couple basic things with
yarra that just a little introduction
the next part will be building and
building and managing data sets now data
is really important when it comes to
building proper yarra rules that work
the next part will be going into using
our for threat hunting because you can
use it in multiple ways like if you want
to detect something and you build the
our rule differently if you're actually
hunting for new threats then I'll be
speaking about building string rules
using unique strings from the binary and
then building rules from the actual code
and then I'm gonna do like a case study
with apt 15's malware or ours fox or
mirage and show you how to build a rule
with that
so yarra basics so this is just like the
basic syntax for a yard rule on the top
and just demonstrating like a C style
comment you see you have like the rule
the name you can add some comments some
metadata and a condition now the
metadata is actually really important
because you don't know where your rule
is going
and if you don't add comments and made a
data someone else who picks up your rule
might not know what it's used for so
it's it's always good to to add some
information to your role and this
clicker is not working so one of the
main modules that you can use with Yara
is the PD module now this allows you to
read information from the P header this
is the most commonly used library that I
use they have one for LF if you're more
of a Linux person now you see like first
it's checking for the header the MZ
header by looking at the first two bytes
of the file five eight four D and then
it's checking if the file is exporting
get module hair delay and then it checks
the number of sections and if it has
three sections and all these conditions
are met then you have a valid match so
as I said before building and managing
these data sets is very important
creating successful rules the more data
you have the better so there's a few
essential data collections that I
believe you should have one of them
being a small clean collection now these
are files that you know are clean you
don't want this collection to be too big
because when you're testing your rules
if you have if you if you make the
collection too big then it might take a
long time to run the our rule and you
don't want to run a yard roll over a
large collection if you're gonna have a
lot of false positives so you want to do
this first with a small clean clutch and
check it against that and make sure you
don't have any false positives the next
collection that you want to have is a
large clean collection now
if you pass the first step with the
small clean collection now's the time to
run it over a larger sample set of more
clean files and if you pass this then
you want to you want to search it over
files that you know are classified as
malicious usually when you do this you
want to categorize them into families
like maybe you say you have some Lazarus
malware or you have maybe t15 malware or
Tortola whatever it is and categorize
them and or if you just have a bunch of
files you know are malicious you can add
them to their just unknown and the last
collection you want to have is just
random data random files the more data
you have the better you know you you
might get this is stuff you don't know
whether it's clean or it's malicious
this is just a data set of random files
that you might find connections that you
didn't know existed before and other
malware to the same family is right
after that you're looking to hunt for so
there's like a big problem when it comes
to getting data I come from a small
start-up in tel-aviv and our biggest
struggle was getting data for when
you're not like such a large company so
there's a few sources you know the
normal one is virustotal I mean this is
pretty much all I had as a data source
in order to find new apts and new
threats that maybe went undetected by
other vendors there's also virus Bay
which is ran by a colleague of mine IDO
now or it's a community community of
malware researchers that share samples
I'm sure we can arrange some invite
codes after the
there is actually ito and Danny can you
give out some invite codes after this
for virus pay all right cool
I put seen it up here just like maybe
that's we're gonna get some clean clean
files because as I said clean files are
just as important as malicious ones
Microsoft maybe you take like a whole
operating system extract all the files
you know these files are clean and this
could be part of your clean data set and
then Mel pedia is another one that you
can also click now we're off of a bit
similar to virus Bay so you need
something to manage all this data now
before I joined Kaspersky they gave me
access to their system called Clara now
this is a yarra management system you
put up a bunch of collections as I
talked about before and then you're able
to actually search yarra rules over
these collections and it's completely
open-source you can find it on github
and I was using this before I joined
Kaspersky I think it's the best platform
for managing your or your data sets
so this is just an example of what it
looks like when you search a rule via
Clara you see you have the status
finished just that the execution times
this is a rule the collection I tried to
search over with sass and it didn't
match any files but when you'd use this
in your own case you can create like
your own collections like this was the
collection sass now you you can create
those four essential data sets that I
was talking about earlier they're small
clean the large clean the malicious and
the random data so moving into threat
hunting as I said before there's a
difference between hunting for new
threats versus using Yara to detect so
threat hunting you want to make like
what I call loose rules this includes a
lot of wildcards
so if a certain instruction may be the
register is gonna change you want a wild
card the bite responsible for saying
what registers there the thing with this
though is you have more false positives
but you have a higher chance of getting
a new variant I can tell you this from
being at a startup and the only thing I
was able to search our rules over was
virustotal and I managed to find a PT's
named a malware and just by building
these rules the other thing you can use
our for really is detection but these
are these are tight rules these are
rules meant to detect certain variants
and there they're more specific and
that's maybe if you want to scan
computers on your network and detect
like a certain variant of a
now where so where can you use these er
rules as I mentioned before as data
sources virustotal and now pedia both
let you search our rules or you can
upload a rule to virustotal and every
time something gets scanned it scans
with your yard rule now the way I build
rules I almost took virustotal down I
got an email from from Victor the
creator of yarra he wasn't too happy
with me he sent me a photo of a graph of
when it ran against my rules and their
server CPUs is piqued
so try not to wild card things too much
and it's not my fault if you take down
virustotal
so just like a procedure for building
these successful rules first you want to
do an analysis so you take whatever
malware samples you have access to that
you're looking to find maybe new
variants or or other tools from the same
group so you want as many tools from the
same group or the same our family that
you can analyze the second step is to
identify strings code maybe even meted
out of the PE file or your left file
whatever using yarrow 4 and finally the
unique information like the strength the
third step is actually build the rule
using information that you got from the
binary for us to test it on those data
sets that I spoke about before
we're going to go over with this small
clean data set the large clean data set
your malicious data set and your random
data now eww now you want to deploy the
rule
now at this point maybe a passed all
your tests you don't have any false
positives but you know there's a lot of
data out there on the Internet
so maybe you put it up the virustotal
and you start getting a lot of false
positives this used to happen to me a
lot because we didn't have much data so
you want to monitor the results that are
you're getting from if you're searching
you're on virustotal for like false
positives and maybe you have to adjust
something in your rule so this is uh I
want to show you the difference between
string rules that tend to stop working
after a couple generations of the same
malware and rules that are built off
coat the thing about malware is like the
strings might disappear but they're
still using the same code base so this
is just an example binary that I made
and we can see okay you have what can be
a unique string test space STR and we
can build a yard rule off of that so
this yard rule is going to detect if the
binary if a binary has this unique
strength test STR but what happens here
this is often a common case in malware
it they create the string as an array
and now searching test string will no
longer work so what do you do now if you
look at older samples thread actors used
to not do this type of thing so you
could just find the strings as things
have evolved these techniques are to get
around yarra rules AV engines and other
security products
so if we look here on the left we have
the string in plain text and then on the
right we have it initialized as an array
but what stays the same or almost the
same is the code so I like to build my
rules from the code because the code
doesn't change most of the time so I'm
going to show you it's demo time so
something's bound to go wrong
[Music]
sir
to what what ito loves busting my balls
[Music]
I'm his second wife by the way ten great
question moe
okay debate
so here if we look at the code we can
see after the string is initialized by
an array here we have a lot of the same
code compared to the goodbye area on the
right now it's not identical
if you actually look here you see this
one shows movie CX which is going to
give you different optos or the same
output but for the register the second
byte that tells what the register is
it's going to change so on the right you
have movie a X so now I got to build a
rule that's going to work across both
binaries from the code so what we do
here
so in order to build the rule role of
the code we want to we want to be aware
of things that can change from binary to
binary maybe you use maybe the author
use different compilation flags maybe
just a different compiler in general and
it just changed the code slightly and we
want these rules to work throughout
multiple generations so let's start
building a rule over here so I'm going
to start from this code which looks the
same on both sides so I'll go c7 of four
or five see the FC is the EBP plus fair
four so that's gonna change so now we
want a wild-card that anything like that
that can change maybe if they change the
function slightly it would it would be
f8 it could this is something that we
wild-card wildcard I mean putting these
question marks which basically means it
will it will accept any bite to match
when you're matching this rule
now constants are a very good thing to
look for so we have elite leet as the
constant here so we're gonna write that
in the rule we're gonna do the same for
the next line wild-card offset for the
EBP take the constant again wildcard
wild card okay so we covered those those
lines with the constants there now let's
get to the next part you see this is
where it changes you have the movie CX
here and B move EAX here
so it's gonna happen is we're gonna take
the out code for the move
now the it's for D on the left and on
the right we have four or five so we're
gonna wild-card this because this is
saying what register it's being moved
into so wild card next one's an offset
from the EBP so it's wild card that now
we have the same thing with these ads on
the left you have a DC X on the right
you have a Dax so we're going to wild
card what says what registers going into
and the offset and do that for all the
ads okay
so the next one again it's still using
the ECX so we're gonna wild card the 4d
in the f0 same thing with the move in a
wild card here now you see this XOR that
we have this is a tricky one we need
when it's X or EAX it's actually a
different opcode so if you look over
here X or evx
you have the eight one and then the f2
specifying the register and then the
constant if you look down here when it's
exploring the EAX the opcode is 35 so
how do we deal with that that's
different than just wild carding and you
can see that it changes from binary to
binary
the xor EAX isn't down until here the X
or e ax is the second one here so we've
got a we've got to be able to skip
basically these the opcode for this
instruction because it can be different
now the constants are the same but the
opcode is different so if we continue
building the rule we want to do a
bracket and one to two now this one to
two basically specifies that it's gonna
it's gonna skip the next one two bytes
this is because in one instruction the
opcode is two bytes and in the X or ax
it's only one byte so let's do the one
to two now let's fill in the constant
nein nein nein nein nein nein here we go
for the move doing the same thing as
before for the move and now here we're
gonna hit the next x4 so we're gonna do
another one to two and then 1 1 1 1 1 1
1 1 8 9 doing the same thing for the
moves as we did before and then here's
another XOR so we're gonna skip 1 to 2
and then we're gonna put in the
constants bad food in X
keep moving down we have another move
and a wild card the same they have some
pushes with some constants these are
probably gonna stay the same so here we
see we have a push EDX this is another
one that you want to you want to watch
out for you change the calling
convention of a function maybe from fast
call or C deck
the registers might change or just the
compiler you're using so what I do for
pushes is I do five and then a question
marked so basically this means anywhere
in the Oh X 50 and below Oh X 60 it will
accept anything in that range as we can
see on the right it's bush ECX and on
the left it's bush edx and then the last
thing I'm going to add is just the
opcode of the call because it doesn't
matter this can this is a relative call
so the next four bytes can change
because the distance might change from
the call so just instead of just adding
the wild card we'll just take the rule
as is here so let's try and run this
over both files
oops where's the safety
okay now the first few lines is because
I have the files open in Ida and these
are the associated files with Ida so
it's getting an error with those but you
see it caught sample1 and sample2 both
of these binaries one is with the with
the string that was initialized by an
array and the other binary is with the
string in plain text and now this was
built from this rule that came from the
code now the thing is the code usually
doesn't change thread actors they
operate just like software companies and
I'm sure a lot of you program or
something like that I'd sent a copy and
paste code from project to project
I'm not going to rewrite the same
function twice and I'm ceremony you do
the same so this code these little
pieces of code if you find the unique
code are what stands out and this if you
put a rule like this up on on virustotal
for example let's say it was from an
actual apt you might find new variants
undetected variants actual different
malware but from the same thread actor
and from my experience working in and in
desert when virustotal is my only option
this worked and I was able to find new
apts all the time by building my yarra
rules off the code and just a quick
quick demonstration with
if we run it with just the test string
it only found that sample to which had
the non alpha skated string so you can
see that the code by building it off the
code we find both binaries building it
off the string we only found one binary
and this tends to happen any our rules
stop working I noticed a lot of people
online they publish our rules it doesn't
cover the code and when it does they
take a unique function but they don't
wild card things that can change as you
saw like the registers offsets and these
are things you need to take into account
when building these rules and as I said
don't wild card too much unless you want
an email from Victor the creator of
Yarra I heard I'm on a first-name basis
and the virustotal office because of
certain rules that I put up and they had
to disable them multiple times and yeah
I'm not first-name basis not on a good
reason okay so now what actually should
that was just a sample file that I I
compiled myself so I want to show you
with actual real-world sample samples
and I'm going to do that with the apt 15
Mirage Mirage box whatever you want to
call it and their malware tool set so
the way I used to before our joint
Kaspersky I had the visibility that I do
now the way you used to build rules was
I would go on I would go on different
like security threat intelligence blogs
maybe secure list or Palo Alto zone it
42e sets blog checkpoint any of them and
I would take
the IOC s or even information that's in
the post let's say there was a hash that
was posted but I can't find this hash
anywhere you can actually use data from
screenshots or information from
screenshots or other information that's
given out in the post so just going to
show you an example with a with a blog
post that I did while I was that integer
on Roz Fox you see we have like a code
reuse from Raj at the time of finding
this there were only ten detection x' on
VT so here's an example photo of some of
the shared code so what can you do here
let's say you can't find the IOC s from
the hashes on the bottom you can take
this information here and build a yard
well actually from the code just from a
screenshot from a blog post you can you
can start writing from the the up codes
there's actually some unique strings
here and then maybe you can find other
variants or the same malware but with a
different hash just from looking at one
of these blog posts here here's another
example now this was a function for
decrypting the CNC configuration and I
found this code to be in many of the apt
15 and Miraj binaries now this is what I
would consider a unique piece of code
now
the difference in the the code here as
you see it's checking the length 134 on
the left but on the right it's checking
one to see so what does that mean it
means we're gonna have to wild-card this
area of the code in order for it to work
on other samples
so yes this is how I work so many are
the windows open so let's take a mirage
sample
I mean I just know where to find this
function but from from like just a
screen shot you could actually build the
rule if you took the opcodes just a
little more difficult if you don't have
the sample because any just you got to
know the opcodes for each the
instructions so here let's get the D op
codes now let's build a rule from this
rule a PT 15
condition c1 okay since we said that the
only it looks like the only piece of
code that's changing here is the length
of the CNC configuration so we're going
to build the rule from the beginning of
the function three three zero zero zero
eight zero now this is another thing I
can change is the address here you have
maybe in this binary it's one zero zero
one three two six eight and another
binary it's different so again we're
going to wild-card this four bytes in
the ink EAX now we have the 3d and we're
going to wild-card the length of the CNC
configuration 7 - 2 C 3 okay so now we
built the rule from this CNC
configuration decryption as we saw on
the blog post that was unique code now
what happens when I run this across the
samples
so it looks like we got a hit again this
is the errors in the beginning are from
the file being open and Ida so you can
ignore that and it seems we got a hit
with multiple barrage samples actually
every one in the folder and these
different samples vary from can go back
to 2012 to something more recent in 2017
whereas if you did it off the strings
these strings might have been obfuscated
over the years to prevent detection but
still the code hasn't changed and we're
able to build the rule based off this
now something interesting here
this one
now this file that we actually hit this
is not a mirage sample this is another
sample from a PT 15 yet we took the
unique code from a mirage sample and if
we applied this like on virustotal
and we're waiting for for a hit it would
have hit this this file here which is
not me raj at all but it's another
malware from the apt 15 group so you see
you can find using the unique code
instead of the strings you'll actually
find maybe other malware from the same
thread actor because of the code reuse
as I said before they tend to reuse code
just like any software company what I'm
just showing you from the shift f7 this
is not how I reverse engineer if we look
here I mean it's just an easier way to
show that it's not a not the same
malware there they're clearly different
so this is uh we I built one rule from
this unique code and using this rule we
detected a different brand new malware
from the same group this happens all the
time I'm used to having limited
resources like I said I was at a
start-up we didn't exactly have a big
budget or visibility like I do it
Kaspersky so if you don't have large
resources and let's say you just have
virus total this will still allow you to
find new apts or new threats without
having access to so much data so just to
wrap up as I've been saying the thing
you want to look for is code that is
unique to specific samples and you want
a wild card the things that that can
change from sample to sample
not not only this you you want to build
those data collections that I mentioned
before you need a way to manage these
data sets that you have test the rules
out and make sure you're not popping up
with a lot of false positives there are
plenty of times that have put up one of
these rules I thought okay search my
clean collection my small clean
collection search my large clean
collection search my malicious
collection on my random data and then I
put up on virustotal and actually you
know my whole email is getting spammed
with false positive results which means
you need to adjust something so the main
thing is the code it doesn't lie the
strings are easily manipulated so when
building rules that you want them to
last for generations and generations of
different malware and not only the same
malware but now we're from the same
thread actor you should be using the
code any questions
I believe they give out independent
research accounts
[Music]
well what what happens is you put the
rule up there's two ways you can do it
it's in the regular hunting or you can
do a retro hunt a retro hunt lets you
search the past three months of hours
total uploads with your yard rule and
the other regular hunting every time a
file gets uploaded or rescan and
virustotal it sends you an email or you
can check on their website with the
results the match essentially of the our
rule and the sample - - the sample which
then you can go and download the rule
itself yes mm-hmm
that's correct
I mean it it can it can go on none you
wanna like basically basically it's
something you pick up over time of doing
this over and over again and checking
your rules that you've built in the past
like and if you keep practicing this you
start to see like what parts of the code
that you want to build it off of now
right there in this piece of code in the
samples that I showed they were there
were some constants being used now these
constants tend not to change a lot tend
to use the same constant so when there's
a constant this is an area of code that
I'm going to look for and say hey I'm
going to start writing the rule from
here I mean there's other methods for
this you can
I mean yeah you can do that well you
could build something that that
automates it that maybe wildcards of
things that I told you about wild
carding I mean I I prefer to do them by
hand just because like of doing this for
a long time and I can see exactly what I
want and sometimes when you build an
automated tool you know it can add stuff
that maybe it shouldn't have added and I
tend to do these by hands but you can
easily build a tool that takes maybe
give it an address and then address and
then it'll construct the rule itself
using the wild carding yeah the so
actually what I showed you before from
the blog posts on intezaar
I found a low detection variance of
Miraj here's actually the code reuse
can't really see it so there was a 13%
code reuse from from me Raj 74% of it
was actually unique to this specific
variant and this is just one example of
an apt that I was able to find while at
a small startup just by using yar rules
that I was able to put up on virustotal
there's other examples of my old work on
the intent Ezzor blog if you'd like to
see more I can show you later you know
mm-hmm in my room
yes naked
any other questions you may mow yes
anyone else want to watch gaper view
okay that's a good idea let's make some
money off it all right that's it
you can follow me on Twitter here at JJ
dessert and thank you very much for
attending
[Applause]