um
i think it's better it
broward
over 10
i really hate that meet-up feature as
soon as the meeting starts you can't
edit it right
don't be annoying
yeah
i kid you not i'll kid you not search up
does everyone know that do you know why
they close the mind and subs in hialeah
did i win do you know why they closed my
head no i'm so broke is it rashan
cocaine no
porno
they must've saw that
all right just give us five minutes will
and we're gonna start it off all right
oh
[Music]
today
[Applause]
so
it was just unfortunate the other
location
[Music]
yeah i need to talk to you
meet up here
hey uh you guys on uh discord do you
hear me okay and here we'll and see the
presentation
if you take some
a couple of words to make sure that they
could hear you and that the audio is
passing through
um yeah testing testing one two and
three everybody can hear me okay
can you hear me
did you hear that
uh no did you hear will speaking
all right
[Music]
we have a couple people on
discord and a couple of people
all right
so as you can probably see
we're at
climbing subs
here
nice
everyone
doing our presentation cyber pizza cafe
didn't open up
at all today apparently
and uh we had to
ditch that location and find a new place
so we're here now
we're online and uh
any updates we have here's this workflow
oh really we have to find a place
besides having to find a place for our
next meeting in two weeks
we'll keep you guys uh
updated on
a new venue
but uh
today we have will talking about rf
hacking
and uh it's gonna give us a presentation
right now all right
all right thank you
so uh
guys you may know me from doing the uh
adsb uh talk which i did at a hack miami
conference and another one actually at a
previous meeting
um my name is wilnette and i do play a
lot with the rf and rf technologies and
as far as like i've got a bunch of a
couple of tools in front of me one of
which was gonna be a little bit ironic
um it just happened to us spark up today
but uh i do play with a lot of different
tools and toys and there's a lot of
different methods i use for doing
different kinds of rf hacking
so um
one of the things that we had done
earlier also when i did a talk with
claymore was about broadcasting over a
raspberry pi
and you can utilize a raspberry pi just
by installing a single wire on a
raspberry pi in this case i've got a
raspberry pi zero and if you put a wire
on i believe is gpio3
and you can install a wav file and
running i'll put in some hyperlinks to
the applications that you can install on
the raspberry pi that will actually
enable you to broadcast over
multiple different frequencies and the
spectrum that i can actually broadcast
in i believe goes up to approximately
350 megahertz
which actually 350 megahertz includes
pretty much most of like your garage
door openers
your security gates at different uh
apartment complexes things of that
nature
one of the devices that i used i used to
use uh predominantly for locating what
the frequency that was actually being
utilized is a frequency counter and i
will post a link in
our chat about what this device is and
how it works it's relatively simple you
fire it up and you can click on scan and
as long as you're close enough to the
transmitter you can actually locate the
frequency it'll tell you very close it
goes from 27 megahertz up to three
gigahertz uh what the frequency of the
transmitter is actually operating on and
that's a really useful tool
let me see what else do i have here
there's also i know some people were
more concerned or considering doing
about like wi-fi hacking or man on the
middle attacks and stuff like that um
i've gotten some devices like these here
uh i will post a link in those as well
and in the chat for those as well
and those are actually stupid simple
stupid cheap you can get like five for
20 bucks
and they basically run a like a micro
python on there that enables you to
you can run man in the middle of tracks
and just start capturing people's logins
and passwords
um other rf packing techniques that we
use
and this is the one that just came in i
really really wanted to make sure that i
had this
a week or two ago and this is something
that i ordered probably back in october
and it literally arrived today uh about
an hour hour and a half ago i
called respeto about it and this is
called the
flipper zero
i haven't even had a chance to take it
out of the box so you guys are actually
seeing it for the first time
but uh
this is the device
and with this device you can
theoretically
you can
scan you can sniff out rf
uh it has an ir beam meter on there so
we can actually receive ir and broadcast
it out
and the frequency ranges on this is sub
1 gigahertz with this you can
theoretically
sniff copy and then like all things rf
if i can see it if i can hear it i can
reproduce it and if i can reproduce it
boom bob's your uncle it gets you back
in
so for people who want to play with uh
rf
whether it's ham radio or otherwise
there's a lot of different tools out
there that everybody can use
for people who want to check out or just
start beginning to exploring
frequency shifting or getting into rf
one of the big cool websites that i
actually go to is websdr.org
and with that you can actually listen in
on different ham radio frequencies you
can't transmit but you can definitely
listen in on those frequencies
all over the web
so one of the other cool devices that i
use for sniffing out rf is what they
call an sdr or which is a software
defined radio and that's what we've got
over here in this particular screen i've
got an sdr radio plugged in to my screen
right now
let me see i have one that just arrived
a couple of weeks ago
and it is about the size of a usb dongle
this particular sdr radio can actually
listen in on frequencies
up to i believe two gigahertz
they make some other ones that listen to
frequencies up to even higher like if
you uh was the the hack rf1 from great
scott gadgets can actually go up to i
believe six gigahertz
so looking into the screen that i've got
right now this is an example of an sdr
radio that i've got currently plugged in
and i can listen into right now i've got
a setup for just fm radio and i'm going
to go ahead and start that
when gas prices get decided it does make
people think a little more carefully
about so what we have here in this
particular screen
is called a waterfall
and once you've got it dialed in
correctly you can actually
like for a garage door opener you can
actually go on to the fcc's website
which is the
fcc id dot io
and if you happen to come across a
transmission device like the garage door
open or whatnot you typically you'll see
on the back of them an fcc id
and with this particular website
if you plug in the scc id and like right
here it'll bring up the technical
specifications of the transmitter or the
transceiver and tell you what frequency
it actually operates on so most of your
like garage door openers your car key
fobs and whatnot a lot of them typically
operate around
315 megahertz
but if you have if you go to this
website you type in the fcc id you can
typically see what frequency the device
operates on and if you have that and you
have an sdr radio plugged in
and the application i'm using is uh gqrx
with that you can pull up the waterfall
you if you get close enough you can
typically see within the waterfall the
frequency that the device is actually
operating on now one of the things
you'll notice on here also is this
little button in the bottom corner here
which is record with that you can
actually
if you're close enough to the person
that is operating the device you can
click on record you can capture that as
a wav file
you can store that wav file and then
going back to again using something like
a raspberry pi
you can actually using the pi fm radio
application rebroadcast that right back
out may take a little bit of cleanup
work with something like audacity but if
you use something like audacity you can
clean that up and you broadcast that
back out it should actually activate
whatever device it is that you're trying
to operate be it a garage door a an
apartment complex gateway uh things like
things of that nature so that being said
i mean that's the gist of it i really
really wish i had gotten the flipper a
little bit earlier so i could play with
it and give you guys a little bit more
in-depth uh
update on how the how the thing works
uh unfortunately i did not i just got it
today i just got it this afternoon
so with that being said
um
that is the gist of a lot of the
techniques used for rf hacking again
frequency counters help
sdr radios if you build it out and you
use uh gqrx which is which operates on
windows mac and linux
you can actually see a lot of the
spectrum with the stuff that's actually
going on rfys you can record it you can
analyze it
you can tell if it's analog or digital
you can zoom in on these things you can
zoom out let me see if i can
know where is that
um
it's been a while since i've used this
particular one
[Music]
that wants to just shift the frequency
you can also save the waterfall for
later analysis as well
let me see here going back to the web
sdr
this is a great one i use
let's go
[Music]
region united states north america
northern utah
hopefully this is still working
and we want
40 meters
so again here you can see the waterfall
as well
so this is a broader example usage of
the looking at the waterfall which again
gqrx can also do
and so with that like i said that helps
people explore the different rf
frequencies that are available that you
can either see online or locally using
something like a software defined radio
or an sdr the small sdr radio that i
initially showed you guys this little
black one here that i got this retails
on amazon for about 20 bucks
the
frequency counter that i have that can
actually pick up the frequencies that
are currently being transmitted nearby
you this is about fifty dollars online
at amazon uh the only problem i have
with this realistically is if i'm just
out and about i try and use this i tend
to pick up cell phone towers uh so in
some cases you actually have to be
really close to the transmitter to pick
up the actual frequency
so that's the
basic gist of anybody have any questions
now he could hear us do you have any
questions but
yeah did you repeat the waterfall they
want to put something displayed
sorry
i can barely hear you guys
can you hear me all right
yeah we can hear you a lot of clearance
but we had a question about the water
put that sample you saw for us
something about the waterfall
where did you pull the sample the audio
sample from
so there's the audio sample on the
waterfall on the screen that you're
seeing right now this this is actually
live
um and this is actually coming from an
sdr radio very much like this one that i
have here um i've got one currently
plugged into my computer if i pull it
out then it's gonna disconnect and drop
my qrx but
you get the same thing out of this that
you get out of the regular rtl
rtlsdr.com i believe
um that one is a little bit more
expensive because the antennas on that
one are a little bit more versatile
they're
they've got some telescoping antennas
some smaller antennas and that that one
is actually the one that i used uh back
during my hack miami conference talk on
uh adsb
so when you pull up vprx and you tune it
in you actually get the ability you can
look at the actual waterfall itself
so rather than dialing in a very one
specific frequency in this case you only
have to get close and you can actually
see okay
i may be at 315 megahertz as per what
the fcc document says but it's actually
maybe a little bit more or maybe a
little bit less and you can actually see
it much easier looking at the
waterfall hey will i got a question for
you you can hear me all right yes i can
perfect um do you have any experience
with tools like um in spectrum or
universal radio hacker some of these
tools that that
so in my experience you either have
out-of-the-box tools that are built to
decode stuff like adsb or some of these
other protocols or in the case of like
trying to figure out your garage door
opener stuff you're kind of just
trying to reverse engineer um a signal
do you have any experience with any of
those tools
um so like i said mostly using gqrx is
what i've used to actually locate like i
actually have worked this out on my
garage and unfortunately i don't have
that setup anymore
um but yeah i actually was able to sniff
out the frequency that my garage door
was using and was able to play it back
on a previous raspberry pi that i had
this one that i have right now i just
basically like two weeks ago i was able
to get the heads soldered on so this
actually has a usb head on it
i haven't tested this one out yet but i
was able to play it back and yes in many
cases you can actually open a garage
door
the funny thing is actually a lot of
cars are still using
uh no encryption whatsoever so they're
not even rolling codes
yeah yeah not even running codes they
just use the same code over and over
again and if you use gqrx in many cases
you can actually record if you have a
halfway decent sdr radio that signal
that's being broadcast out and play it
right back like i said using a raspberry
pi you don't even have to use
uh was it other device that we used over
at the b sites and i just had my tongue
i was just looking at it earlier
they had it on hack five
uh
yardstick one yes the yardstick that's
it
one so you don't even have to really in
many cases actually use a yardstick a
raspberry pi is a little bit dirty
and when it comes to the rf signal but
if you're close enough typically it
actually can work and there's no special
equipment that's actually required on a
raspberry pi to make it work it's all
software so the only thing you really
have to do is i think it's gpio3
is actually put a wire on there a little
bit of practicing and
getting the right length of the wire so
you can tune it correctly and you should
be able to get in
right because they got a
dax on some of those pins digital analog
converters so you can just you know
that's interesting cool cool we're gonna
try that out
hopefully like i said the next time i
have a talk on the hack rf this uh
the flipper zero will actually come in a
lot more play i'm really excited to
actually look at that and do more stuff
with it but it literally showed up in my
house not even like an hour ago so i
haven't had a chance to play with it at
all yet
a little lower to that
they're actually now showing up at
everybody else's noses as well
all right yeah still waiting online
yeah we i have my as soon as uh
everyone has theirs priority uh
next month
we should probably all bring them in you
know get our tamagotchis to know each
other you know
i don't know if they have
i think there's like a french
other
features on it too to connect to connect
them to each
i just opened the box like a half hour
ago and i haven't had a chance to play
with it yet so i'm only going off of
what i've seen on the website and what
they claim to do
so rfid
um sub 1 gigahertz frequencies supposed
to be wide open and i'm really excited
to play with that
they also supposedly have the capability
of hacking some type of e-tag something
i've never seen in the us i think it's
more popular in like europe and russia
um they look like a little like
tab battery that you use to open certain
doors you can hack them with i've never
seen them or i don't know if it's useful
here
it's probably something similar i mean
it's rfid basically what those things
are and i used to actually use those
when i was working in italy in the
shipyards all the coffee machines have
them
so you go out to the coffee machine
itself when the vendor was there you
spend five euros he gives you this
little dongle that has that tag on it
you load up money on it and then you
could go out and get espressos in the
afternoon while you're working on the
ships
cool
cool man thanks for doing the talk
any uh
you guys have any other questions
i wish i really had more but
i wanted to bring up awesome my work has
been really really really crazy busy
so
uh i currently work at i would smoke
i wish i was a little bit taller
yeah
so if anybody knows any decent limits
is in south florida we're looking
oh yeah you said um
what was the name of your company
uh it's a little-known company it's not
cisco right but
yeah it's cisco
well it's working well got acquired by
cisco and they're looking for some
decent linux engineers so
do you guys know anyone that
is looking to relocate to another
company
and shoot will you can shoot with their
info and
so you can get a referral
i don't even really care about that
honestly we're sports staffed and we
just
well can you post uh some job
description in the job channel and
everyone could read up about it
okay can do
how about we show us the actual uh
right oh let me see
can we see your the
which one do you want to see
oh the ponygacchi right yeah can you
stop showing your screen and show us
your ponigachi i mean uh flipper zero
yeah well you can still see my cam right
one second let me uh
yeah flipper does everything
yeah
yeah this thing is pretty impressive
there's the infrared
it's got a usbc in the back
nfc
right it has uh
you could you could tone your hids
high frequency low frequency you could
clone tags
you could you could uh control tv
monitors
with the rf
you have
and you also have the uh
wi-fi hacking too because it has uh
802.11
yeah you can do diode authentic captures
and and that's what and that's
is like an upgrade to the ponagachi
yes but it also has
plus plus plus plus plus features
this is like a poniganchi on steroids
like you said we should actually have a
meet-up once everybody gets theirs
yeah
i gotta bring
take down my garage door opener
and uh bring it into the
bring it in say here let's clone this so
you guys can see it work and watch the
motor the gears
absolutely
yeah
uh anything you want to do you want to
join the meeting rock
or you
does anyone on uh
have any other questions for will
thank you well
thanks will all right
sorry we had our first and
our first meeting here at
miami subs
we're actually gonna probably rename it
to hack miami subs
all right
but uh
i guess we leave it on for uh for
discord yeah we'll talk about
we're gonna
talk here about some
meeting arrangements for next
our next meeting
and uh
we'll catch you guys on discord
oh i think there's a meeting uh
in chat
oh flipper zero yep
flipper 0.1
yep
all right i'll see you guys later
you wanna stop recording yeah
[Music]