[Music]
and for the next talk i
want to introduce luke stevens also
known as hack luke he
is one of those people that um
phenomenal hacker but loves to talk
about the mental side of bug bounties
that's a that's a flip
um and just really dives into you know
what it takes to be successful beyond
just the technical and i think it's a
very important area to cover
and uh this talk he's going to cover you
know zero to heaven
zero to hero how to cross bounties in
your first 12 months you know what what
are the things you want to know if
you're just starting out
how can i go from where i am now with
zero points zero bugs and no bug bounty
experience
to a successful bug bounty hunter
in 12 months or less that's what i asked
myself when i started doing bug bounties
[Music]
to answer this firstly i needed to
define
exactly what successful meant in this
phrase
so successful is a word that gets thrown
around
around a lot and its exact meaning
is basically totally up to the person
who's saying it or hearing it it's
highly subjective so i decided that
being a successful bug bounty hunter to
me
meant that i would be paid enough to
replace
a full-time salary not necessarily my
full-time salary
just a full-time salary that would cover
my expenses
um and i would do that all while
maintaining a healthy balance
in my life so on my quest to
achieve this i learned loads and i made
a lot of mistakes
but in the end i feel that i succeeded
in my first 12 months of bug bounties
i earned a decent uh average australian
uh probably the same in the us and and
europe and
and most countries i earned a decent
salary
so the goal of this talk is to provide
guidance
on how you can go from total zero
to a successful in that sense bug bounty
hunter
in the shortest time possible while
avoiding the mistakes that i made along
the way
right now if you've recently started
your bug bounty journey or you're
thinking about starting
you will get a lot of value from this
talk i hope and
if you've been doing bug bounties for a
while now
but you're struggling to like push
yourself to that next level
i think that you'll also get a lot of
value from this talk
now before i get into the nitty-gritty
technical details
on how to be a more successful bug
bounty hunter
there's something way more important
that we need to cover
and that is how to overcome the fear of
actually
starting okay because that is really the
first step
to being successful is starting in the
first place and it's
interestingly the step that trips the
most people up it's
it's the step that stops people from
actually
doing it right so fear of starting or we
can call it foss
fos comes in many forms you might know
it as
procrastination that's a that's a fear
of starting
or distraction that's a fear of starting
you might know it as
a fear of judgment from your friends or
family
or you might know it as a feeling of
inadequacy when you compare yourself to
like some other pro bug bounty hackers
out there when you see tweets of them
earning
you know five figures in a day and you
might have said to yourself things like
bug bounties are too hard because all
the bugs have already been found
or um the pro bug bouncy hunters on this
program are so good there's no way i'll
ever find any bugs
um that's all fear of starting as well
you might also just be scared of
investing your precious time and time is
precious
you might be scared of investing that
into by grantees because you fear that
you won't find any bugs
and all of that time that you invested
will be wasted let me tell you this
first and foremost from a bike bounty
hunter perspective
but also now i've seen i work for bug
crowd so i've seen the other side of the
coin as a triager i've seen a lot of the
uh the queues and things i can say to
you without any reservations
that it is absolutely 100
feasible for anyone to start doing bug
bounties
today no matter what level what skill
level you're at
you can start today right now and
succeed in earning decent money
within a year right
so all of this fear that is holding you
back from starting
is all in your head um
now in the past if if you follow me on
on maybe tik tok or youtube or whatever
you you'll know that i've made
some content about starting in the past
because it's something that
i'm really passionate about right and
the content that i make basically says
forget all of those fears and just do it
overcome your fears and just do it
right but i'll admit that sometimes it's
not quite that simple
and the reason is that these types of
fears are
deeply rooted within us and simply
ignoring the fear
it's not that simple right it can be
extremely difficult
now it's important to remember that your
brain
your primary decision maker doesn't care
whether you're successful in bug
bounties at all
your brain is just the result of
millions of years of evolution
and its predominant purpose is to help
you
to survive and the best way that it
knows how to do that
is to keep you within your comfort zone
to keep you safe
that's why naturally humans enjoy the
feeling of safety
and comfort we enjoy waking up in the
same bed every morning
we enjoy spending every day with the
same people
we work the same job for years we um
we're on the same projects for for
months or years
and we keep the same hobbies right
unfortunately
this primal survival instinct to keep us
safe and in our comfort zone
may also hold us back from starting new
things
or taking risks and that's because
to our brain doing this feels like a
risk to our survival doing new things
that we're not certain about
feels like feels like risk to our brain
so
how do we overcome this this primal fear
i think that the first step is awareness
every time that an excuse slips into
your head or you find yourself
procrastinating or something
so basically you're stopping yourself
from starting something that will
clearly benefit your life
like learning something new or
exercising or whatever it is
recognize the excuse for what it is it's
an excuse
and it's bred out of fear and it's not
necessarily rational fear
right and then the second step is to
recognize that
by not starting that thing whether it's
bug bounties or something else
you're only cheating yourself nobody
else cares whether you start or not
nobody else cares whether you succeed or
not even most of the time right
but if you want to go on living how
you're living now
and not bring that thing into your life
whether it's bug bounties or something
else
go ahead don't bring it into your life
keep living how you're living now
nobody's going to stop you from what
you're already doing but if you want to
actually grow you're going to need to
pucker up the courage to start
and then dive right in you need to log
out of youtube and netflix
turn your phone off put yourself in a
space where you can focus
and eliminate all distractions right
because
otherwise you're going to have every
excuse under the sun to procrastinate
like your phone's going to beep or
you'll get a message on slack
or you know you've got this netflix
series that's that's really taking all
your attention
so turn all of that off and then take a
deep breath and then just start
[Music]
that's enough pep talking hopefully by
now you are convinced
to take action to actually start right
but what does that even mean what's the
first thing that we need to do
it's all very well to be fired up and
ready to start but what's the actual
first thing that you're going to do when
you sit down
in front of your computer now i would
recommend that you first focus on
education whether you're a total cyber
security newbie or you're a seasoned pen
tester
you will still need to spend some time
on bug bounty related
education because even if you're coming
from pentesting bug bounties are really
different make no mistake okay
in my opinion hands down the best guide
to starting bug bounties is the bug
bounty hunter methodology by jason
haddocks
he's just released version four there
are actually two
version four uh bug bouncy hunter
methodologies by jason haddix there's
there's the recon one
and the application hacking one so
definitely check out both of them
the recon one you can find on youtube
the application hacking one was
earlier today it was released before
this talk
i haven't seen it yet but i know that
it's absolutely amazing because
jason haddocks did it and everything
that guy does is amazing
but check out both of them they're both
going to be amazing primers
to how to actually find bugs and how to
kind of set up your workflow and
everything for bug bounties
to be successful now a couple of other
really great resources that i would
recommend
education wise the web application
hackers handbook
is basically the bible of web
application testing
but it comes with a caveat right
basically
it's a very long dry book about every
single
well not every but a lot of different
vulnerability types that you can find in
web applications
and if you try to pick it up and read it
from page one to page like 700 or
whatever it is
then you're gonna you're gonna get sick
of it and you're not gonna make it all
the way through the book because it's
quite dry
okay but the way that i think you should
be using the web application hackers
handbook
is as a reference so whenever you kind
of
hear about a new type of vulnerability
say you hear about sql injections
you can look it up in the web
application hacker's handbook and
it will have like a lot of information
there about that particular type of
vulnerability and how to discover it
for a more practical education like
really
hands-on hacking i would recommend pen
tester lab
so pentest lab um they have a lot of
free
stuff like free labs that you can
download and
uh there'll be a bunch of exercises
there that you can kind of
just like hack on in your own time which
will teach you
different types of vulnerabilities like
the obos top 10 but also
um really new cves like typically not
long after
a cve gets released in some popular
framework or something like that
sniff will have uploaded a lab to
pentester lab
but yeah there's free exercises that go
through the basic stuff which are really
good
and if you find that helpful then you
can pay for the pro version which is
for what it is it's really cheap for for
the for the amount of
training and the amount of knowledge you
can get from pentester lab it's a very
good return on investment so i'd
recommend paying for it by the way i'm
not getting sponsored by pentester lab
i just really like it and sniff's a good
guy
and the the last kind of
educational resource i'm going to
recommend there are so many educational
resources out there but i'm trying to
keep it down to a few
because i really i don't want to give
you too much information
i i would rather just give you the few
things and you can focus on all of these
because there's not too many here
and hopefully you won't feel overwhelmed
you can just you know which ones to
focus on
so yeah the last resource would be
following hackers
on all the platforms whether that's
twitter youtube
github twitch um and any other platform
that they might be on so
i'm pretty hesitant to list uh
to list actual hackers to follow because
there are so many great ones
and i cannot list them all or remember
them all
and i'll definitely be leaving a stack
of them out but
but a few that spring to mind are
jason haddocks narmsek sterk
franz rosen um naffy
meals zeddlezed insider phd
albino wax mayonnaise codingo
prodigy sml um zed shawno farah
mr tuxrasa the gentleman space risk goon
sack
um ob sam techno geek ox patrick live
overflow
ed overflow rhino radar today's new
merch two
hours later europa gen sec yours
doggie g fisher tom nom nom the list
goes on right you can see why i didn't
want to list them all but
i ended up listing quite a few just
anyone who is either
very successful at bounties or releasing
good content about bounties or both
if you're looking for a really great
list of people to follow
you can go to my twitter profile which
is twitter.comclick
um which you can see there and um you
can just like go to like who i'm
following and just go follow follow
follow
follow all of those people because
there's a bunch of great people there
um yeah so if you're following these
people you're literally
surrounding yourself with greatness
you're surrounding yourself with
the things that you want to achieve and
not only is this good motivation
it's also good in a very practical sense
because
every time they share something bug
bounty related you have the opportunity
to learn from it
so the next thing that will put you on
the right path
to bug bounty success is consistency
and habits and that's what then that's
the next thing that i want to talk about
so
just for a quick analogy because i love
a good analogy
let's say that there are two identical
twins
who are both extremely unfit
right and they both decide that they're
gonna get fit
so the first one decides that they're
going to do a hundred push-ups
every day and the second one decides
that they're going to do
10 push-ups a day five days a week the
question is
after five years who is more likely to
succeed
in getting fit now think about that
carefully
right it's gonna divide people i think
but i would be putting my money on the
guy who is doing
10 push-ups a day five days a week the
reason is that
i don't think that a hundred push-ups
per day
is a sustainable habit the second twin
chose a much more reasonable 10 push-ups
per day and only five days a
week and this is a habit that is
sustainable
over the extreme long term right
so let's say that the first twin despite
being extremely unfit
managed to do 100 push-ups on monday
on tuesday morning he's going to be
waking up
with a very sore chest and likely won't
do any push-ups on tuesday
by wednesday he might be feeling a bit
better and do another 100
but then the next two days he decides to
take off because his muscles are too
sore
and then saturday he does another 100
and then sunday he takes off so
in total the first twin has done 300
push-ups
in the first week but his fatal flaw is
that
he didn't build any habits because his
push-up schedule was
all over the place because his muscles
were too sore and because he didn't
build a habit
in the following weeks he kept
forgetting to do push-ups on various
days
and eventually gave up on the idea
altogether on the other hand
the second twin woke up every morning
and did 10 push-ups before doing
anything else
straight out of bed did 10 push-ups
after a week or two
doing these push-ups became a habit and
they became part of his lifestyle
so even though the first twin may have
appeared to be the one that would
succeed
and while he may have done more push-ups
in the short term
the second twin continued with his
schedule for five years
because it became part of his lifestyle
overall of course
the second twin did way more push-ups
than the first twin
in the long term right the difference
between the two was that the second twin
knows the power of small
incremental changes that are applied
consistently
so bringing this back to bug bounties
okay because we're getting too far into
the push-up thing
i get a lot of people messaging me
saying i'm gonna spend 10 hours a day
every day doing bug bounties and
learning to hack but what happens is
they don't stick to it and the whole
hustle culture thing is to blame for
this right
people you know like people are just
being like hustle hustle hustle grind
grind grind
and um you know to a point it's true but
you need to know the difference between
um i think like hustling like like
actually doing work and wearing yourself
into the ground
right someone who's who's decided
they're going to do
bug bounties for 10 hours a day or learn
bug bounties for 10 hours a day or
something
they crafted these goals when they were
feeling extremely motivated and i get it
because this happens to me as well when
i'm really motivated i set goals that
are too high
but when the grind sets in i realized
that
i was too ambitious and then you know
you can't help but feel like you've
failed
right and it sets off this whole like
negative spiral and you end up resenting
bug bounties
so just trust me it's better to set
sustainable
realistic habits that can be applied
over long stretches of time
and this is where the magic happens this
is where you really start to amass a
huge trove of knowledge
that you can apply to bounties so when
you're planning out your time
or you're planning out your schedule or
you're planning out like your learning
habits for bug bounties or
whatever you're doing just set a little
bit of time to do it every day don't set
10 hours per day as a goal maybe just
set
one hour or something that you feel that
you can comfortably do
consistently
the next thing that i wanted to talk
about is automation
now i think it's fair to say that there
are two streams of bug bounty hunters
one stream focuses more heavily on
automation and scanning
and the other stream focuses more on
deep diving
and if you look at the the leaderboards
on major bug bouncy platforms you'll see
both types of hackers there so you can
do well either way
but if you're starting now i recommend
that you first build out your automation
and there are a couple of reasons for
that
firstly even if you are more inclined to
be a deep diver
and in other words like you want to go
very deeply into one specific
application and find bugs in that
having excellent automation will allow
you to more quickly
and accurately determine where to focus
your efforts
so it's all very well focusing on the
main application
but maybe you could deep dive on some
other application
that your automation kind of found
through its
reconnaissance and you'll have a lot
more luck doing that
secondly a good automation system can
earn money for you
through bounties passively now as i said
at the start of this video we are
defining success
as being able to earn a full-time salary
without sacrificing our lifestyle
and the perfect way to do this is to
generate passive income
right now if all of your bugs are being
found by you
manually then you are essentially
trading time
for money similar to having a job right
which is fine as long as you enjoy what
you're doing but it does
limit your potential for growth and if
you want the income to be reliable
and consistent then you need to keep
working and keep grinding
every single day to earn those but and
those bounties that you're finding
manually
but if we develop um an automation
system that earns us money passively
then we can take a break whenever we
want and still be finding bugs
although it can take a while to create
an automation system that generates
passive income
once it's set up properly it will
continue to earn you money
for as long as you leave it scanning so
that's super exciting
just to really nail this point home i've
made a spreadsheet
okay and keep in mind that the numbers
on this spreadsheet
are kind of kind of a little bit guessy
like uh they're not necessarily accurate
to you
but uh they've just they're just numbers
that i've chosen to demonstrate the
point
okay so on the left hand column here you
can see
that i've got the month and this is from
january 2020
it goes all the way down to december
2039 this is the hours
spent the column b this is the hours
spent on bounties
every month so this is basically an
average because
every month's different length you have
to kind of average it out so in this
case
what i've done is i've done two hours
after work
so two hours five days a week 52 weeks a
year
okay and that rounds out to be 43 and a
third hours per week
a per month sorry and then in column c
we can see the amount earned now i've
been quite generous here i've said from
day one
from the first month you're going to
earn ten thousand dollars
a month okay been very very generous for
the manual hacking here
and if we go all the way down if we do
that for 20 years we don't take any
breaks
we own ten thousand dollars a month
every single month or on average
we end up earning 2.4 million dollars in
20 years
okay so how does that compare to what we
might earn doing automation
well let's let's find out so we take the
number of hours that we've spent and
let's just assume that
we can spend 10 hours coding something
and that will make us back on average
30 dollars per month so that's pretty
doable i think if you if you think about
it like this
you could spend 10 hours coding
something and then at some point in the
next 10 months
you're going to get a 300 bounty back
from that i think that's pretty
reasonable
so basically what we do um
we've got to figure out the formula so
we want to get
this number the hours spent in that week
and divided by 10. so now we've got
units of 10 hours and we times that by
30 because we're making
30 dollars for every 10 hours okay
so that means that we end up making 130
um per
month yes but when we're doing
automation
uh you have to remember that actually
it's not just 130
for this month that that 40 uh that
43 hours that we spent coding this
automation
will serve us every single month for the
next 20 years
all right so um we've already put in the
work
to earn this to earn this 130 this 130
every single month for the next 20 years
so the following month we can take the
previous month's
efforts and money that we've earned but
we spend the same amount of time coding
more automation which is going to earn
us the same amount of money it'll earn
us another 130 dollars this month
so this month we earn 260 and then
this time for the third month march 2020
we can take again the 260 which is the
previous two months work
and then we add on another 130 because
this month
we spent the same amount of time coding
okay
now as you can see these numbers when
you when you compare them
to the manual hunting are very bad
okay we're earning in the hundreds
instead of the
the thousands okay so earning even after
three months running 390 dollars
instead of 10 000 but the real magic
happens
when you start to pull this down over a
long stretch
so in this case we're doing it over 20
years in total right
scrolling down and there we go
so we end up with a total of 3.7
million dollars instead of 2.4 million
dollars
now it's also important to note that
the longer we spend on our automation
the
the more money that we're going to be
making every month regardless of whether
we work that month
or not so let's say after 20 years we're
like
okay i call it quits i'm sick of coding
automation
i'm sick of doing bug hunting i'm just
gonna coast from now on
well you're in luck because even if you
stop after 20 years
you're still going to be making 31 200
every single month from your automation
that you've spent 20 years
building okay but that goes for any
point at
absolutely any point let's say after a
year
uh so what is it december 2020 or let's
say january 2021 okay
so you've gone from january 2020 and
then it gets to january 2021
and you're like i'm going to have a
break here and i'm not going to do
anything for a few months
well during that time you're still
earning one thousand five hundred and
sixty dollars a month
okay when you're doing nothing whereas
if you do nothing
for a manual the manual hunting method
you're earning zero
because you'd have to just delete this
right and that
is the power of automation
now let me be very clear about those
figures once again
they are flawed in many ways i'll admit
okay for example
you won't get 30 per month for every 10
hours you spend coding
sometimes you might make more than that
though and sometimes you might might
make less so i tried to kind of average
it out
also you're you're unlikely to spend 20
years
on bug dante's okay a lot of things are
going to happen in your life
in 20 years also if you're earning 10 or
20 000
per month from bounties you'd probably
um up the amount of time that you're
spending on bounties
and down the amount of time you're
spending on like maybe your day job or
whatever so
you know the figures would kind of
adjust to spending depending on how
how many hours you're spending um doing
bounties as well
and uh also from the manual hacking side
you're very very unlikely to be earning
ten thousand dollars per month
from the first month okay but as you
gain more experience
it's actually possibly doable on average
to earn ten thousand dollars per month
there are a lot of people that are
actually doing that now
but the point i'm trying to make
basically from a financial standpoint
is that passive income is super super
powerful
and automation in bug bounties gives you
the ability
to bring passive income from bug
bounties
which is just amazing now just to hedge
your bets
and keep you motivated i would recommend
adopting an approach to bug bounties
where you do
both streams i'd recommend splitting
your time
roughly in half and then spending half
the time on
automation coding your bug bouncy
automation and then the other half
on manual hacking that will make you a
very well-rounded hacker
who's taking full advantage of the whole
bug bounty spectrum
and that is what i actually do myself
i hope that now you're convinced about
the power of automation and you
understand
why i spend a lot of time on it but the
next question that i'm sure is in your
head would be
what exactly do i automate so i wanted
to speak about that a bit
so firstly you need to think about data
storage
before you think about anything else
think about data storage
you need an organized scalable way to
store
all of the data that's captured by your
automation now i chose to do this in a
relational database
but some some people find that text
files work for them
right but you have to think about text
files there's no way to do relations or
no easy way
to do relationships so i like to be able
to relate
for example a platform to a program
to a root domain to a subdomain
and all that kind of thing so it doesn't
really matter honestly whether you
choose
uh like what kind of data storage you
that you uh
choose as long as it's organized and
scalable
and easily searchable so
another thing to consider here is what
what kind of data do you actually want
to store do you want to just store
subdomains or do you want to do ip
addresses dns records
http responses maybe or like the html
titles maybe just that or
status codes http
response status codes what about port
numbers
basically the more data that you capture
the more analysis you can do
but also the more storage that you'll
need so it's worth planning this out
before you start
and once you've planned out how to store
that data that you capture
and you've decided on what kind of data
you actually want to keep and what you
want to throw out
you need to think about alerting so how
do you want to be notified when your
automation discovers something
personally i've got my own slack
workspace and i just use the slack api
for alerting
but there are loads of other services
that you could use that might actually
work better for you
alternatively again you can just store
output in a text file and check it
regularly
now when it comes to alerting the other
thing to think about
is what you actually want to be notified
about
so when i first set up my automation
i generated a slack message for every
time a subdomain got discovered but
of course i ended up getting thousands
and thousands of slack messages
every day which leads to notification
fatigue right
and i would just end up ignoring all of
the notifications and and i couldn't be
bothered scrolling back through them to
find anything that was useful so
there are a few ways around this right
to solve this notification fatigue
problem
and the first way is to batch
notifications so for example
maybe once every 24 hours maybe in the
morning
your automation can send you a single
message containing a list of all of the
new subdomains that have been discovered
within that last 24 hours
that way if if on that day you want to
do some deep diving
some deeper hacking you can just do it
on those targets which are more likely
to be fresh
right the second way is to
heavily curate the notifications um
heavily curate what you're actually
notified about
so for example you might want to limit
your notifications to actual
vulnerabilities that have been
discovered
and not not any recon results
and then the last way is to separate
your notifications into different
channels so
if you're using slack you might send
recon results to a recon channel
which is muted probably and then send
your actual vulnerability discoveries
to a dedicated vulnerability channel
with its own notification settings
so you can get notified of
vulnerabilities and then if you want to
check the latest recon results you can
just go to that channel manually
now yeah that's what i do so now you've
sorted out your storage schema
you need to start thinking about
gathering your results
so i would recommend starting this
process by
automating your recon and there are a
few ways to do this
if if you're looking to get your recon
up up and running like
fairly quickly then i'd recommend just
writing wrappers
around existing tools for example you
might write a
python wrapper which simply calls the
amass binary
and then processes and stores the the
results okay
so you could then write a separate
python wrapper for
all the other sub domain enumeration
tools like subfinder
uh asset finder or maybe like calling
some api that produces
similar results and you can say you can
use the same concepts like this wrapper
concept
for gathering other data for example you
might write a wrapper around
tom nomnom's http probe in order to
determine which of your targets are web
servers right or
you might write a wrapper around nmap or
mass scan
to determine open ports now
writing wrappers in this way can be a
bit dodgy because
you have to process the actual text
that's returned from the tool
so if the tool is updated and the output
is like different in the update then
you might break your automation also
some of the tools that you write
wrappers for
might not be totally stable or they
might have some kind of weird quirks
that you don't notice until you start
using them at scale
also the tool might not exactly fit your
purpose so
perhaps the output is in a format that
doesn't really suit your automation or
that
or it's missing some key thing that you
really need in the results
something like that but i still think
that writing wrappers in this way
is a good way to get up and running
quickly okay
the alternative of course is to build
out your own
tools and and script all of your own
stuff instead of writing a wrapper
around
a mass or subfinder or whatever you can
simply code your own
subdomain enumeration scripts now this
can have
a number of advantages firstly you've
got full control over the tool
uh secondly the code that you write can
fit natively within
your framework your automation framework
instead of calling a system process
right which is way more efficient and
depending on
the efficiency of your code this can
have significant speed advantages too
yeah also if your automation breaks
this is a big one if your automation
breaks you know exactly how to fix it
and you won't be relying on the
developer of some third-party tool
to make changes in order to fix your
automation right
the disadvantage to uh writing your own
stuff of course
is that you would need to spend a
significant amount of time
building out these tools so it might
just
not be worth the extra effort for you
so on to the next step once you've got
your recon
automation nailed the next step is and
this is
this is where a lot of people stop a lot
of people just automate their recon okay
but stopping here is in my opinion silly
okay so once you've got your recon
automation nailed the next step is to
start automating
your vulnerability scanning okay and the
more creative you are in this phase
the more bugs you will discover
essentially black box vulnerability
scanning the way that i think of it is
basically like sending probes to a
server
and analyzing the response or responses
for a specific thing now if that
specific thing exists
or um maybe you're looking for something
that doesn't exist
but whatever you're looking for you can
determine from those responses whether
the server is vulnerable
and the best server that uh the best
tool sorry that i've seen
so far that does this is nuclei from
project discovery
i won't go into that in too much depth
here but if you want to learn more about
it you can just google
nuclei project discovery yeah
and you'll find it i'd i'd highly
recommend checking this tool out along
with
the templates that are in the same
github account so there's like a nuclei
templates repository
and then just a standard nuclear
repository um
but you should keep in mind that if
you're only relying on
nuclei templates that are in that in
that repository
then literally you are actually scanning
for the same things
that everyone else is scanning for who
is using nuclei
so vulnerability scanning really comes
into its own when you scan for custom
things
that you designed yourself right and
that's where your personal judgment
and your creativity as a hacker comes
into play
now one of the biggest problems that i
initially faced
when i was um kind of building out my
automation was being able to scale out
to a massive attack surface and still
scan everything within a reasonable
amount of time in other words being able
to scan the entire bugbounty space
frequently so for example let's say that
you need to scan
three and a half million hosts right
which is a situation that
that i've been in right um
so if you scan three and a half million
hosts and
let's say you're doing a check for a
particular vulnerability and it takes
about
five seconds okay maybe you need to make
two or three http requests so
on average it will take five seconds to
come back to you
in this case if you're just using one
scanner and it's single threaded
it will take about 200 days yeah
ideally we don't want it to take that
long we
we don't even really want it to take one
day okay so what options do we have for
speeding that up
well firstly you can add threading
which will dramatically improve your
speed if you're lucky
maybe you can run 20 threads at a time
which might not
that might knock the scan time down to
about 10 or 15 days which is
much much better but it's still not
ideal
so firstly that's just too long to wait
but also it would require a system
with more resources and eventually if
you keep adding threads
you're going to run out of resources and
and it just gets too crazy so if you
tried to do
uh those tasks in one day even if you
had quite a powerful
vps setup or something like that chances
are
you're not going to be able to do it
right so ultimately
to progress further than this you're
going to need to scale out using
multiple systems
and there are loads of options for for
doing something like this
honestly i haven't experimented with
most of them
um i have one that works for me but i
haven't experimented with most of them
so
i won't go into this too much but some
things that you can check out
are kubernetes uh message brokers like
redus and rabbit mq are really good but
also uh there's one that's really up and
coming at the moment
and that is axiom by a
great hacker called pryoc which is p r y
0 c c so if you search axiom
prioc github something like that you'll
definitely find the tool and it's really
coming into its own
and um the stuff that products doing
with that is crazy so i recommend
checking that out
anyway once you've got all this sorted
you've got your recon
you've got your vulnerability scanning
you're scaling out with multiple systems
and and you're able to scan like a very
large amount of hosts in a single day
then you're going to have some great
automation set up and
you can use that to generate passive
bounty income and also to prioritize
which targets
that you want to deep dive okay so even
if you're a deep diving hacker
i'd recommend setting up your automation
so you're able to
prioritize the targets that you're deep
diving
now i wanted to talk about something
that i am super passionate about and
that is collaboration
and community so bug bounties are at
this incredible point
now where there's a really awesome large
supportive community of people who are
willing to share information and
collaborate with one another
and i personally collaborated very
heavily with
codingo and prodigy sml or sml 555
when i was starting out in fact we
developed our automation out together
and it was super beneficial for all of
us we all learnt a lot of stuff
and i would highly recommend
collaboration it's worked very very well
for me
however there is a caveat you need to
make sure that your collaboration
is mutually beneficial and i did very
well here luckily
so i i think it's super important to
agree on the terms of your collaboration
before you start all parties that are
involved with the collaboration
need to be getting equal benefit from
the collaboration and you need to decide
what that looks like from the start
otherwise it's just leeching right
meaning that
it won't be a successful collaboration
and at least one person will feel used
so when you collaborate with someone
make sure that you're very
upfront from the start about the terms
of the collaboration
what will the split be if you make money
who's responsible for doing what
how much information are you sharing
with each other these are all
important things to consider now i don't
want to put a dampener on collaboration
because
it truly is something that's made me
grow as a hacker immensely
but i have been very lucky with the
people that i've collaborated with
and i've seen other people in
collaborations where it's just fallen
apart in a nasty way so
i think it's best to mitigate the risk
of that happening
now as for community i'd recommend
getting involved with a community
as much as humanly possible right the
advantages of doing this are super
obvious
and abundant so join the conversation on
twitter
join the bug bounty slack workspaces
various slack workspaces and discords
share your successes with people share
your failures with people
do write ups share tips and research
that you're doing
everything that you share and all of the
positivity that you spread to others
will come back to you tenfold i promise
so the next thing that i wanted to talk
about is kind of obvious but
many of the people who message me on
twitter are missing some fundamental
knowledge
and it's really holding them back so
that's what i wanted to talk about
time for another analogy so suppose your
bug bouncy knowledge is a big
tree okay and the larger and older that
that tree becomes
the more knowledge you have and each
leaf on that tree is a piece of
knowledge which grows on another piece
of knowledge which is a twig
and each twig grows on a another piece
of knowledge which is a branch
and then each branch grows on some core
hacking knowledge right which is a trunk
okay so you can't have leaves without
twigs
you can't have twigs without branches
you can't have branches without a trunk
but then the absolute fundamentals such
as basic networking
how http works basic back uc bash
usage um and how web applications work
so basically how the internet works
and stuff like that would be the roots
of the tree
now without roots the tree's gonna have
a lot of trouble growing leaves right
can you see where i'm going with this
from what i've seen there are too many
bug bounty hunters out there that are
trying to learn the leaves
without knowing the roots so in order to
give yourself the best chance of success
you need to give yourself a grounding in
the fundamentals
of how the internet actually works
before you start learning to hack
don't try and learn the leaves without
learning the roots
so there is another general rule that i
like to follow when i'm doing bounties
and
i think that this rule following this
rule has allowed me to find
way more bugs than i would have
otherwise and this is the rule it's a
basic one
hack where there is less competition
there are a few
practical ways to do this okay
firstly you can hack on programs as soon
as they open so when a new program opens
up
jump on it straight away and be the
first people to be one of the first
people to hack on it
this sometimes allow allows you to find
really easy
critical bugs if you're quick okay
secondly you can use your automation to
detect new targets
as they pop up and then focus on them
straight away
so it's important to have good
automation for this one using this
method will ensure that you are the
first or if not one of the first hackers
to be looking at it which which is a
huge advantage okay
and think about this what's the
likelihood that someone else has got
automation
which managed to discover this host uh
before you did
and then they've actually decided to act
on that and jump on
and start hacking on it straight away
basically zero so there's a good chance
that you'll be the first person if you
use that method
and thirdly you can detect changes in
your existing
targets using your automation so for
example
if a dns record changes on a subdomain
check
that out because it it might be pointing
to a new website it might be a subdomain
takeover
or it might just like have some like new
admin panel that's not supposed to be
exposed externally something like that
and if an application has a significant
change for example if the http response
size is
significantly different to the last time
you saw it or the html titles changed or
something like that
check it out fourthly you can run a web
crawler such as burp
or hack ruler against an application
regularly with the same settings every
time
and then you'll be able to know if a new
endpoint suddenly
appears and if a new endpoint appears
you've got to check that out right
because you'll definitely be the first
person checking that out there's there's
basically no one doing that as far as i
know
of course there are loads of other ways
that you can find targets with less
competition
but hopefully that gives you some ideas
to start remember
creativity is key if you can think of
more ways implement those into your
automation
and start doing it
and we are almost out of time but i
saved the best thing for last okay so
if you just take one thing from this
whole talk i hope that it's this
in order to be successful in bug
bounties you need to be super switched
on
and creative which requires that you
have a brain
that is well nourished and awake and
this means that it's going to be
way way easier for you to succeed at bug
bounties if you're eating good food
and exercising regularly and sleeping
enough just generally
looking after yourself and i really want
to encourage
everyone to put their health before
anything else and the best thing is
this won't just make it easier to
succeed at bounties it will just help
you in general to live a more
fulfilling life but staying inspired
and excited about life and like being
able to focus and discipline your time
like with
bug bounties it requires more than just
being healthy
okay healthy is a baseline you don't
want to just be healthy
you want to be at your peak and this
requires constant personal growth
now i attribute a lot of my success not
just bounties but
everything to the time and effort that i
invest in improving myself by reading
inspiring books
meditating listening to podcasts and
just generally being
creative and inspired in disciplines
outside of computers right
personal growth is something that all
humans i think naturally desire
but it's also something that many of us
never fully
embrace or bring into our lives
and since i have fully like embraced
personal growth
i feel like my life is just booming
since then right
so i want to encourage everyone to
embrace self-growth and bring that into
their lives
i want to encourage all of you to be the
best people that you can possibly
be and on that note best of luck
being the best human that you can be and
also good luck with all of your bug
bouncy endeavors i know you're going to
do great
and if you ever want to contact me or
you want to hear more from me
you can follow me on uh twitter or
instagram or youtube
and i will be there now it's been an
absolute pleasure speaking at level up
seven
i'm totally honored to be speaking
alongside a bunch of other
amazing people that i really look up to
so
good luck everyone i wish you all the
best and thanks for watching my talk
[Music]
that was awesome yeah
um love the uh love the talk there's
just
so many questions now that we have to
work out where to start so i guess
off the top one of the one of the key
things to kind of cover here
burnout how do you deal with it if
you're going to be doing this
daily as shown is the better way to kind
of approach this
how are you balancing that with burnout
ah yeah so this question gets asked so
much
and um uh to to everyone i i think
like if you watch like nam sex stream
and things like that nonsense
asks it to everyone that comes on the
stream
um for me it's not about uh
recovering from burnout some people ask
a question like this they say
um how do i get over burnout and then
other people say
how do i avoid burnout so i think like
90 of the struggle is avoiding it in the
first place
and um you can do that by not hacking
too much like
it's something that you love and it's
easy to do a lot
at the start but you need to make sure
that you're approaching
hacking and bug bounties from from a
point where like you don't necessarily
need that you don't need to do that
to like survive or whatever so something
that has happened to me in the past is
is i've had
people message me and say hey um you
know
i don't have a job and my family is
relying on me being
um successful in bug bounties or earning
bounties this month
to like um to pay for my family's
living expenses or whatever and i'm like
what
like you can't you can't put yourself in
that position unless you're 100
sure that you're already going to be
able to do that on your ear so like
that's one thing is like trying trying
to like position your life in a way
where
you are not relying on that income or
you're not
absolutely forced to be doing that 100
of the time
um so there's that but you know
if if you are feeling burnt out or you
kind of um you know you have overdone it
which i definitely have in the past
multiple times um you need to just step
back
um i find that you know some people say
i play video games when i feel burnt out
that doesn't work for me because i'm
still sitting in front of a screen like
physically
i'm doing the same thing right i'm
sitting in front of a screen um
but things that work for me are just
getting out of the house
um just like not thinking about hacking
for a while just resetting my brain to a
point where
i'm not constantly thinking about bug
bounties or some like
bug bounty puzzle that i'm solving or
whatever but like getting outside
getting in nature
going to the beach going for a bush walk
um
you know spending time with my family
obviously playing music
uh things like that so that's that's
basically
how i deal with burnout but the other
thing is is the one that i touched on in
the talk
and and that is like it's better to pace
yourself
and to do little and often than it is to
um
do big chunks so if you kind of
if you commit to doing one hour a day
five days a week
you are going to probably end up doing
more hours over a long stretch than
someone who commits to doing
10 hours a day every day right because
if you're doing 10 hours a day every day
how long can you realistically keep that
up
versus if you're doing one hour a day
five days a week you've got two days off
and you're only spending one hour a day
the other five days so
that's like quite an achievable
sustainable thing that you can keep up
for a long time
and i'm about to start reading a book i
haven't started reading it yet but i
think
that's what it's about and it's called
atomic habits so i'll definitely let you
know how
that goes after i've read it
so i guess uh follow up from that so one
thing that i love
like we've known each other for a few
years and one thing that we've often
done
is liken bounties to other communities
so
um i used to play poker for a living so
i'll refer the evolution to that and
used to be a musician so you'll refer it
to that and i think we can both agree
that both of those communities have
established
you don't go doing this for a living
until
so for poker if you didn't have a year's
worth of savings you were crazy to try
and become a professional poker player
you just wouldn't do it and music as
well like you need established gigs and
you don't just jump in and do it
so in the bounty space what would you
say is the definition that we don't
have yet but how would you know when
you're ready to go from being sort of
your side hustle
to a full-time bounty person
well actually michael i remember having
this conversation with you when we were
thinking about it ourselves
because there was a point yeah before
before we worked for bug crowd where we
were
getting pretty successful in the bounty
and we're collaborating a lot on that
and um also with sajeeb shout out to
sml555 he's not here right now but
um shout out to him because we'll
probably see it later but you know
um i remember for me at the time i was
like
um i want to earn i won't say the amount
but i want to earn this much money as my
yearly salary
and if i can earn an amount every month
for six months running
that that would make up that salary
consistently over that whole six months
then i'll quit my job
and that was my goal and um you know
what we
i actually we did achieve that goal but
by then we had
uh we were working we were both working
for pug crowds so now we're like
we noticed you were doing that and
started offering jobs and i think that's
that's a testament to like there's
multiple ways in security to be
successful
you know yeah there's there's you know
we love what we do
and it feels it feels like fun i mean
we enjoy it and and you don't have to be
full-time bounties for that i think
that's a it's a super important like
those there was two bits you know when
you when you busted out the spreadsheet
in that talk look it's like uh what's he
doing but it's
it's really key i think to
you know do the fundamentals in terms of
just understanding like what is what is
your personal burn rate what is what's
what does a budget look like for your
household you know
like actually approaching the whole
thing rationally
there's a lot of excitement there's like
that game mechanic there's the dopamine
hit of getting a bug and like how good
that feels like all that sort of stuff
and like those are all good things but
if they if they cause you to act
irrationally you can end up in a
position where you're under a fair bit
of duress
which is not something that you want to
you know you want to avoid that if you
can
and i will say like personal finances
are super important
and um this is something that like my
wife is meticulous in in our budgeting
like she
she adds up uh everything we know
exactly what we've got to spend in these
different areas we're saving for our car
insurance as soon as we pay it we're
saving for the whole year month or month
like little things like that so when we
take risks
um we know the risk that we're taking
and when we spend money
on something we know exactly what we're
spending and we know that we can or
can't afford it
you know so i'm not saying that we still
make we make good decisions but at least
when we make bad decisions we know
exactly how bad the decision is
and and i think that's important and if
you're thinking about quitting your job
and saying bug bounces full time like
you
better know what you're doing you know
what i mean you you
want to be very sure that you can live
off that salary and i and
i don't want to discourage it because a
lot of people have done it very
successfully
but um yeah you you've got to know
you've got to know what you're doing
basically
yeah definitely i think it's you know
that's the next phase of discussion in
valley like i've watched you
successfully predict a lot of the bounty
space a couple years ago
luke was like oh youtube's the next wave
and he's like oh it'll be streaming and
we're just hitting that phase
and then automation we were all in quite
a lot like that's the next phase
and you know i think we're just hitting
that phase now we're starting the mental
side of things
being that active discussion and it's
still not
quite here yet a lot of people are
taking risks that i think are
probably too far on the on that you know
just jump and hope for the best
or as case would put it yet just go
and it's good yeah like these talks are
great because that that starts to
establish that conversation that needs
to be
reinforced and happening well i think i
mean i'll
i'll just add to that before we go into
another question as well just going off
the uh the last talk like
when um when i stepped out of working
full-time
into full-time entrepreneurship it
wasn't just cut the whole thing off and
jump in
like i'd built up the ability to do
consulting work
to basically backfill my income as i
started to work on the riskier stuff so
it looks from the outside in as this
like
crazy heroic you know not very rational
decision to jump into
trying to do startups but there's a lot
of there's a lot of planning and a lot
of thought that went into it and i think
that's part of why it's been successful
um because the same thing applies to
most people that do that type of thing
including
going into full-time bounty hunting it's
not just like screw it let's just go
and see what happens it's actually
building it up and actually being in a
position where
you know you're not going to completely
like you want to be uncomfortable enough
for it to push you along but you don't
want to be so uncomfortable that you're
so stressed
you just end up burning out like i think
it's it's that kind of balancing act you
want to
want to be able to do the math on yeah
so absolutely
sorry uh so you've also released quite a
number of tools recently for example
hack crawler and
uh there's quite a number that have that
you've released how
what sort of what sort of process would
you use to maybe automate something like
something like that and and how's the
how is the
the community actually um
assisted with the development of those
tools the community part of that
i think is probably one of the more
important things that we probably need
to touch on as well
yeah so um i feel like
the infosec community ha sometimes has a
reputation for being a bit harsh
um but it's really weird it's like
sometimes harsh and it's sometimes the
most loving supportive amazing community
ever
so it just depends on who you run into i
think and
um you know when it comes to releasing
tools
i compared a lot to releasing music from
when i was a musician you feel like
you're really putting yourself
out there and you feel like you are
really putting yourself out there for
judgment right so you release a tool and
then
you're just scared that like you're
gonna get a bunch of negative feedback
from that and destroy your reputation
because you're like you know you coded
something wrong or whatever
but um it's all fair you know that
that's just fear and
i think um overcoming that and releasing
tools um
is super important and it helps the
whole community to grow
so i've kind of gotten into the habit of
um well i realized that i'd written a
lot of stuff for myself
that wasn't necessarily what i
considered to be
release quality and like from working as
a developer previously
and working in um you know application
security at banks and stuff
like i had this kind of um what's the
word
this idea of something being production
ready and release quality as being like
absolute perfection
and um when we're talking about hacking
tools like it's just not the case
like you don't have a development team
you don't have a qa team
you don't have like a full-on devops
life cycle unless you're
unless you know crazy um just for your
hacking tools so i think it's important
to just like
when you feel like you're kind of ready
you know you have tools at like an
okay level it's okay to release stuff
and call it a beta
and ask for community support because
you're open sourcing your tools
and you are giving to the community
and um you know just own it and and
if someone's like oh this tool sucks
then then ignore them
and um just um you know know that you're
doing it for the community and and know
that
it's not just your responsibility like
you're giving away something for free
so if you're asking for people's um
what's you know pull requests and and
you know tool updates and things like
that
people to help you doing that that's
fine like like absolutely do that
and um you know releasing stuff on
github is
is amazing i i really enjoy doing it and
i've got some public repositories up
there that are so not production ready
and even hack crawler when i release
tack crawler it didn't really work very
well
and it's slowly getting more and more
stable and and um
you know i feel like it's kind of stable
now it's but it's definitely more stable
but um there are still some features in
there that i want to implement that's
still on there and i'm kind of hoping
someone else will do it because i'm
sure short on time but you know that's
fine and
um and a lot of people are using how
cooler now and it's it's great you know
so it's the same mentality as your talk
right where you're saying just start
it's just release and i'm i'm terrible
at this i don't take my own advice but
the main mistake people do is over
polish and and worry too much about what
the community thinks before putting it
out there
and once you release and you start
collaborating yeah yeah
yeah that's that's what
i just said that that causes you to
never release because you're waiting for
that perfect
yeah yeah fast fast dns that's where
this is where this is where
collaboration
is is so i think it's so powerful as
well because you can end up in a
position where it's like okay i'm
releasing this thing
look you know it's alpha um
that's being generous but here's some
friends that i've been working
with it on like you know on on it with
um and all of a sudden you're getting
like you're not misrepresenting it super
polished you've got other people that
understand what you're trying to achieve
and know how to like support you and
driving that whole thing forward so all
of a sudden you're not
kind of just sticking your neck out on
your own i think that's a really
important component to it
i mean that's that's where sorry
i like when you look at a lot of the
major like
really kind of popular hacking tools
that have come out recently that
actually
groups that are releasing them and
project discovery is one of those groups
you know
um you know really they they took sub
finder which was
already an existing tool um that
actually kaninga was part of
and they kind of revamped it and
re-released it and it's the same with a
lot of the tools that they're doing but
it's a group
so if you're working as a group i
suppose you have less some fear about
your own reputation and things like that
it's more of a collaborative effort
yeah and i think to click on there too i
mean you don't have to be a security
professional yet
involved like subfinder originally was
iceman and myself and then kent gruber
joined the project
and just brought this professionalism to
it from his development background
that really took it to that ex next
height
and i think that's often the case that
you can put it out there with
you know your intention behind it and
someone will see a better way of
approaching it and if you can work
together it becomes a really powerful
thing
yeah definitely definitely same thing
happened with hack crawler when i
released it
there are like three or four pull
requests that basically like
revamped the whole tool put more
features in um change the code up
and you know people people message me
sometimes and they're like thanks for
hack crawler
and i say don't just thank me there's
like
10 contributors you know that have gone
into that say
it's you know yeah agreed
yeah uh someone asked
is akamy subdomain takeover possible i
don't think it is but
it could be wrong subdomain takeovers
are one of those things where like
even that even that repository that
that's up that's like uh
um what's it called can i take over xyz
together yeah
i'll touch base on like i'm i'm one of
the main contributors with that overflow
the it's reached a stage where like i
can't contribute anymore because i work
in a triage team so it's the wrong thing
for me to do
and ed overflow has broader visions for
the project that means that that one
um doesn't move as much so i think
there's an important lesson there that
if you just use that
as your reference point you're missing
so much and one of the most valuable
things that
luke sajib and i did about a year ago is
we flew
sajeeb up we got into luke's apartment
and we just mapped out every single
service we could and then started
testing in a spreadsheet and
that kind of research is what leads you
to new findings in new areas because if
you're doing that and 90
of people are using the can i take over
list 90 of people are missing things
that you're going to find
or some of them are flat out wrong these
days because the state has changed
yeah so actually there's a tip there's a
tip in that there's a hot hashtag bug
bouncy tip in that
so the way what we actually did was we
got all of our recon data together
and then we got the c names of every yes
in every domain and then we checked all
of those c names to find which ones were
attached to services
and then we got a stack of sub domain
takeovers on really
really obscure services that that like
we didn't know existed so
um instead of starting from like okay
what services exist we actually had that
and then and then we tried to take over
them from from there so
yeah and to kind of touch it like this
was some of these were
spun into entire programming projects
you don't just stop it
oh yes no this move to the next one some
of them we were like i think there's
something there
and there's a project that luke and
sadie did off the back of that for a
service that just took them
way down a rabbit hole to finding
something that just
paid incredible dividends because no one
was looking at it the right way
um and that's you know that's there's so
much of that in the bounty space that
you see like even in in our own discord
some people go oh i just don't feel like
there's
anything to be there to be found i mean
we still see stuff popping up in public
programs because
the state changes all the knowledge
changes what we know today we may not
know tomorrow i mean
there's a point where people didn't
understand sql injection right there's a
point where people didn't understand xss
and there's going to be new stuff that
comes out maybe not whole new
vulnerabilities but new ways of thinking
that allows you to find things that
people haven't seen before
absolutely yeah so i have i have a
question for you luke
how do you avoid forgetting to turn off
your vpss and running up your digital
ocean build to
the point that it announced any earning
that you've made from anything
ever so there's two there's two things
there
um the first thing is my automation
never sleeps so i never have any reason
to turn a vps off
um and uh
that's uh so so earn more is your
your solution to that problem nice okay
you should be paying for your your uh
vps and then some and if it's not then
turn it off
but um there's that and uh
also check out axiom the project by
pryoc where you can start
up digitalocean vpss on a timer so they
just kill themselves
after however long you set so yeah
there's that
nice and also you can just spin them up
and then at the end of the month when
you get the bill you can remember that
and then turn it off
or you can get a whopping big cloud
service because you forgot to turn stuff
off
being there situation's not so bad but
sometimes with aws stuff
i just like even even when i get the
bill i'm like i don't even know what
that is
and then i have to like search through
the console for an hour trying to find
what i left on you know
i think goggle's really good for digital
ocean as well
which i guess bug bounty tip if you can
figure out if a server has been
a kami band and have an image in
digitalocean you could spin up a new
instance and doctor and get a new ip
address
so there's some some useful things
around that that i think a lot of people
aren't doing and their automation gets
hampered because they're not
seeing those pieces and uh a lot of that
still to be explored
yeah you could you could automate around
this um too
like kind of like what you touched on
like aws
and digitalocean both have really
comprehensive apis
so if you did want to learn how if you
did want to remember to turn something
off you could literally
code something up to send your message
every day saying these are the instances
you've got currently got running
yeah are you sure yeah yeah yeah that'd
be cool you know i imagine i mean you
know
i keep on referring to uh to digital
ocean here but it's the same for any
any cloud provider it's the one that i
use most often but yeah
that whole idea of you know management
of all these resources especially
i've seen it i guess the reason i asked
that question is that i've tripped over
that particular problem you know more
than once um
in context to bug crowd and in context
of just doing my own research on the
side but
i don't think i've met anyone who hasn't
been accidentally alarmed by a build
they've gotten from a cloud provider at
some point
so it's sort of like for the for the for
the newest uh amongst this um
you know how to think ahead on that one
yeah i think that's also
when not enterprise like in an
enterprise that's that stuff's planned
for
you know what you're doing from the
outset bounty it's like
vps go and then you realize the impact
uh yeah i i just got i just wanted to
touch on this thing because ah quite or
um andy just recently uh
just put this in the discord and he said
um i'll read it directly
i want to poke that question answer
around bounty earnings and automation
and being able to turn them off
i think there's an element of economic
privilege there that we need to
acknowledge where someone who's short on
resources
and just starting out can't have that
power and i totally agree
i totally agree um when i
started bug bounties i was not saving
any money
and i didn't spend any money on bug
bounties so the only money that i've
ever spent on bug bounties
has been money that i have earned from
bug bounties so initially
my automation was running on my home
internet with um on my
on my laptop and i just had to like
leave it on and change my power settings
to like stay on overnight
and then you know i got a few bounties
and i kind of reinvested that into
um you know digital ocean and everything
um
and then as you kind of start being more
successful finding more bugs you can
keep reinvesting reinvesting
treatment i mean i kind of treat
automation like an investment right
and the day that my automation starts
stops earning as much as i'm paying for
it i would downscale that automation
or just stop it entirely and i totally
totally acknowledge that
um you know economic privilege is
definitely a thing so i don't mean to
come across that way
but yeah it's it's worth calling out
that digitalocean has the 100
100 voucher for your first month i think
i can't remember exactly what it is but
there's definitely a free proof point
there to start out as well
um you can google that and find
affiliate codes everywhere
um essentially they'll give you a
month's worth of credit
you can go nuts on that and use that as
your earning point if you're starting to
to build out
so yeah and andrew mohawk on discord
just pointed out to you that um
aws has a free tier so you can you can
definitely
yeah yeah that's a good point
and azure and gcp i think as well i
think they've all got some sort of
some sort of entry level tier that that
most people can get a bit of a basic
start on
um just don't go don't go crazy on on
some of those because then you will end
up with a bill pretty quickly
yeah yeah um so what how
what sort of so obviously it's your talk
touched on automation and you need to
know some sort of coding
skill to to to start that what what sort
of things should people look at starting
with is it would you
would you think bash is good enough or
maybe go for python or
what's your thoughts around that bash's
is like super powerful for doing
hacky things like that that's basically
how i kind of look at bash
but if you want to build something
that's more scalable um
and you want to build something that's
going to kind of um how do i put it
i know be more
stand the test of time and more
resilient that's what i was looking for
you want something more resilient and
more scalable
you're probably going to want to look at
something else
other than bash bash makes it really
hard to interact with
databases and things like that and and
personally
i put time into learning a framework
um and it's it's a web frame oh it's
django right so it's a python web
framework
and um the reason that i i kind of
learned that
is because it's got a great orm which is
uh the way that
the framework interacts with the
database
so um i was able to do that also it's in
python and i
i knew like a bit of python already um
and like that's that's the way that i
did it but
i didn't want to say that in the talk
because there are just like a billion
different ways to do automation and
every single person that has automation
is going to do it differently
um you know doing it in django and
python had some serious disadvantages
but it had a lot of advantages too
and i think no matter what way you do it
it's gonna have disadvantages like for
example donut the other day
you probably saw his tweet he put up a
tweet that said i actually regret
writing all my stuff in rust because no
one ever collaborates because no one
knows rust and i'm like
that's a good point like rust is amazing
and it's super fast and like the guys
really switched on and can code anything
in rust but he'll never get any uh
well he'll never get a huge amount of
collaborative support from the community
because
it's not a language that's used very
much so you might want to look at stuff
like that to
support and everything um but i think i
know where you're going with this vortex
and that is like
the the classic do i need to code to do
bug bounties
and do it and what language should i
learn that's right yeah essentially that
was the that was the root of the
question
yeah yeah so do you need to code no um
and you know the and the question
do i need to be able to code to do bug
bounties is a binary answer
and you only need one person who can do
bug bounties without coding
uh and then the answer is no so you
don't need to because there are some top
hackers who
at least say that they can't code um but
is it gonna help you hell yeah it's
gonna help you you
you know every time every time you find
a zero day
or or um you find some kind some type of
bug
um if you can't code and you don't have
your automation set up or whatever then
you're gonna find it once if you find a
bug
and it's in some software like like a
wordpress plugin or whatever
and um yeah you find that bug you can
now test that out on all of your hosts
very easily by writing a script right
and if you've already got your
automation set up you can probably get
that scanning in like an hour or two
so i think you know that's how i use
my coding skill and i think it's super
um
super beneficial super helpful but it's
not
a prerequisite to being able to do bad
bounties
it's just um for me it's been very
helpful
so yeah i completely agree so
we know uh kodingo's recently not not so
recently but it's got a got the tool
called interlace which is a really great
tool for for scaling out sideways with a
well you might have a single script but
you can
scale it out with that and run it a lot
faster
yeah so that um i guess if you don't
know how to code but you know what tools
you want to use the goal of that is that
you can build run files so you can say
run nmap then run this then run this and
build out a target list so
um sajeeb lehani and i did that when we
were pen testers
because as a pen tester you land on a
network you'll write a script you want
to run it everywhere
but same applies for um the bounty space
you just in a more external facing
capacity
much more scale needed too yeah so
basically what what i use interlace for
is
like if i if i want to quick if i want
to quickly do something at scale
and i just put together like a crappy
script that just like checks one host
i don't want to have to spend hours and
hours like refining my script to take in
multiple hosts and do multi-threading
and um you know work over cidr ranges
and things like that so
um basically what interlaced allows me
to do is write a crappy script
to do a poc and then um interlace allows
me to scale
quickly with and and you can do that if
you don't have like a proper autumn like
a full-on automation system set up you
can just use interlace
and it will probably do the same thing
you know what i mean
so it's super powerful for that kind of
thing
but i guess um
automation we've kind of covered the
mindset where you begin
um and in terms of language stack and
things like that but
bounties in general you start today
what's your
what's your first action what's the
first thing you would do you sign up and
you want to start
and beyond the just start what's the
first thing that you're doing
so education is number one uh the
resources i mentioned in the talk so
jason haddick's stuff anything from json
addicts um
following a lot of people on twitter
getting involved in the community
um pen tester lab web application
hackers handbook they're like the few
ones that i recommend constantly
i feel like if you start with those then
after that you'll be able to find your
own resources and you'll know the
difference between a good one and a bad
one
um so that's like a that's like
fundamentals for me
um but yeah if if you're coming from a
space where you already know how to hack
um
the next thing would be educating
yourself on how bug bounties work
so you know uh no matter which platform
you're hacking on
there'll be documentation on like the
how many points you get for what um what
you can expect to be paid out on the on
the bouncy profiles what's in scope
what's out of scope what kind of
vulnerabilities we um accept and what
kind of vulnerabilities we don't accept
so that's the side of education as well
so
at the point i'm trying to make is even
if you're a pentester and you start
doing bug bounties you've still got some
education to do
um although nowhere near as much and
then um
once you're educated i'd be focusing on
um bug bounties on sorry on automation
and and um also
i would be but not just automation like
i said in the talk i'd be focusing half
my time on automation
half my time on manual hacking the ideas
that you get from manual hacking you can
apply to automation
and the ideas that you might get while
you're coding on automation you can also
apply to manual hacking so
i think it's important to have both um i
know i pushed the
the automation thing a lot in in my talk
um in terms of like
generating passive income but you really
you really do need to do both i think
and um
you know those big those big bucks those
big bounty payouts
usually uh don't
uh come from automation right so for
automation you tend to be scanning for
things that
are lower risk and there tend to be a
lot of people scanning for them so
it just depends um but i do want to make
another point there too
and that is um that
when we're scanning for stuff at using
automation it's easy to just be like
i want to find vulnerabilities and i
send this probe and i receive this
and is it a vulnerability yes or no like
we're looking for binary stuff
but i think um you know i think a trend
that's happening
at the moment is that people are
realizing that a lot of stuff can't be
automated
but there are ways to hint at things
that
might be vulnerable that you can scan
for in an automated way so
for example um one thing
that i've done in the past is pulled cve
results from showdown
right and each cv has has a um
a cvss score and if you just add those
cvss scores up you can get a
you can get like a decent idea of how
vulnerable that machine might be or how
old it is because it's running old
versions of apache or whatever so you
can kind of prioritize which host to
hack on in that way
so you know automation is not just about
flat out finding vulnerabilities
it's also about being able to
um prioritize the host that you do your
manual hacking with
and it's about being able to um
you know find hints at vulnerabilities
so
i don't know how to put it more
succinctly than that but you there are
not there are not a whole lot of
vulnerabilities that you can just scan
for and get definite results for
so sometimes you need to be looking for
for hints and prioritizing targets to
manually hack on if that makes sense
yeah 100 that is i i
didn't think to put that trick out i'm
kind of sad it's out now but that is
one of the key tricks that uh luke and i
use for identifying where to look
and the other thing since we've given
that up and i'm going to start
the best part of luke's talk i think
there was um
it's not just about monitoring
vulnerabilities it's about monitoring
points of change we put
a lot of time into working out how do
you identify that an asset
has changed so you can look again
because others a lot of people do state
in time recon
they pick up a mass they pick up sub
finder they run all of their recon
and then they come back to it later and
amass
with jeff foley today they've just added
change tracking that's really key but
doing it at a finer level than just new
domains appearing and disappearing
allows you to go test an asset that's
changed and that
you know such an underrated piece of
your talk that i really wanted to kind
of put a
a bit of a bold around because i think
it's really key to
finding things that others are missing
because if you continuously monitor it
and others aren't and they come along
and they just start monitoring it
they're not going to look in the same
place you are
yeah and and here's something here's
here's a tip this is something that i've
been wanting to do for a while but i
just haven't gotten around to it so now
someone's gonna beat me to it but anyway
that's okay so one of the things that i
recommend doing is endpoints on targets
right so if you're
if you've got automation set up that
crawls the target and finds endpoints so
for example if you've got hack crawler
running on on all of your different
subdomains or
some other crawler whatever you'll get a
bunch of endpoints back and
and when those endpoints change it's a
good time to look at that target and and
have a look at the new endpoints right
because if you're finding new endpoints
then
that's new functionality that that you
can explore and and not many people are
monitoring
endpoints at the moment so that means
that you're going to be
one of the few people that's going to
see that change and you're going to be
probably the only person that actually
checks it out right even though there
are loads of bug bounty hunters
these are the kind of niches that you've
got to be looking for when you're bug
bouncing hunting right
and then another thing that hack crawler
does is it dumps javascript files
now if you can get the urls of all
javascript files that are in use for a
particular application
and then you can constantly monitor
those javascript files for
um just changes like particularly like
if if that javascript file changes
size then you're basically
getting back like functionality change
in that application and javascript files
are such a
treasure trove of like money basically
you know they're
they're a treasure trove of information
about that application
that you can use to exploit it so if
you're one of the first people to see
that javascript file after it changes
there's a good chance that if there's a
vulnerability there you're going to be
the first one to report it so
it's little niches like that like that's
just one example and
i'm i'm fine about giving this stuff
away because there are just like a
billion other niches that that you can
that you can target and they need that
you can look at it and that's never
going to stop there's always going to be
more things to look at and more things
that people aren't doing even if they've
thought of it like implementing it as a
whole other thing right so
so yeah i find that the
the times that i've made money like just
trying to kind of generalize
um the whole process and and the times
that i've been successful
it's been when i've found a niche and
i've i've found
this like one thing that i'm the only
one that's doing that
so so i'm the first one that sees that
i'm the first one that's that's
able to like check it out and that's not
necessarily like a type of vulnerability
or a zero day or whatever
it's like finding a particular way to
look at hosts or a particular way to
scan hosts
that nobody else is doing so um this is
like
this is this is like when people say
like um
you know the hacker mentality or they
say um
the hacker mindset things like that that
this is what they're referring to
you're you're finding little different
ways of doing things that that people
haven't thought of and you're looking at
like
um abusing functionality in ways that
other people
wouldn't have thought to do or whatever
and yeah anyway
that's that's that's kind of something
that i wanted to get across
no that's that's that's real that's
really powerful and super underrated too
because i think there's
yeah there's hunters that that go wide
like
almost every hunter starts going wide
across stuff and just looking everywhere
for things because part of what they're
doing is
learning in the process as well but then
as they do that there's like
the particular techniques that allow
depth to plug into their skill set or
their interest and that's
this continuously iterative thing
because you know eventually
you get bored of a particular technique
or a particular kill chain or whatever
else or you get new input from going
wide
um in in such a way that it makes you
you know kind of diversify your skill
set at that point in time like that
whole
kind of relationship between this very
broad
like i just want to hoover up
information and learn stuff
and then you know as we go along it
connects into this new part of interest
i can then engage and be effective with
that's a that's a really important
aspect of personal growth that i think
um doesn't get talked about a lot
it's also we're early in the phase of
recon we're still at the point where
everyone talks about it as if
recon finds stop like we look at github
right
everyone's searching for credentials on
github when one of the key things you
can be doing is actually looking for
endpoints that no one else is touching
and those credentials most of the time
lack and impact and
don't end up being a valid finding but
if you find endpoints you can go and
find things that others have never
actually tested on
and it's it's funny to me particularly
jumping into triage seeing
all of these people doing a lot of work
in github and they're going oh i've
found these credentials they
either have tested and found they're not
valid or they haven't tested and they're
not valid
but not actually going to the point of
looking for domains new assets or
how does that you know credential that i
found tie into a bit broader impact
and that's where the real money is
that's where the most successful people
are putting their effort is to
use recon as a tool a wide coverage tool
but then to go really deep on what
they're finding
yeah absolutely absolutely and like this
this concept i think
applies i mean i'm sure cj you could
you could probably attest to this more
than than i could but i think it works
in business too
like you speak you hear about the niche
niche everybody's gotta find the niche
like when you're talking about like you
know drop shipping bros or like
big or like you know finding the next uh
what is that crypto
currency or whatever that's gonna boom i
think like um
like this is what everyone's trying to
do everyone's trying to find that little
thing that no one else has thought of
yet and
and bug bounties are no different it's
it's really interesting
because bug bounces you're working
across a huge
range of targets the people working on
it are from all different cultures
all different backgrounds all different
educations they've had different mentors
some people are coming at it from binary
or mobile or wherever whatever and like
you've still got to find something
that's unique
it's like it's like it's like hard but
that's that's in my opinion that's where
um that's where like bug bounties that's
where you become successful
being creative and i can i completely
agree like i
i draw so when i talk to entrepreneurs a
lot as
a founder um i draw parallels between
defensive security and and building a
business
all the time because it's like
fundamentally the same thing you start
you start from point a you want to get
to point b you've got
you know a limited set of tools
available at your disposal and a whole
bunch of stuff trying to stop you
and your job is to create a path which
is no different
to hacking a system at the end of the
day in terms of
you know what your brain's doing to kind
of execute all that
um obviously what you're playing with
and all those different things and and
like the
there's a lot of difference to it but
like the fundamentals i think are
very much the same so i think that's
it's
a very transferable skill set really
when you think about it when you can get
into this idea of like okay i'm gonna
you know be like relentlessly focused on
the path but approach it as continuous
learning i think the other bit that's
that's um you know important and just
kind of logical to call out is that like
for someone who's building a system
they're not they're not thinking about
xss or
or you know injection or whatever else
they're thinking about making the system
works with whatever
has gone into that like you think about
a connected car now you've got
you know cunix running on an arm chip
talking
out the tire through a radio sensor to a
thing that you've just driven past
that's got an api with a
mobile app blah blah blah there's all
this convergent attack surface that goes
into these systems
and that's ultimately what we're here to
try to you know find vulnerabilities in
so they can be de-risked
so like there's this incredible breadth
of stuff that you can end up
focusing in on the only way you can you
know pursue new things is if you've got
at least some sort of eye on
how broad that that spectrum actually is
so it's good depth and breadth i think
is
you know the the two have a really tight
relationship and i think being able to
navigate being able to
improve both at the same time if you can
pull that off then then you're winning
i just want to give an example i want to
give an example of that from
my music day so using that that hacker
mindset
um you know basically when streaming
came out when streaming became a thing
when spotify became
a thing a lot of musicians were super
angry because you get paid like
point zero two percent uh cents per
stream or like some ridiculously
tiny amount of money and um musicians
were used to only earning money from cd
sales at the time right
which is like you get at least like 15
20 bucks
for selling an album so um a lot of
people were super angry about that so
there were the people that got angry
about it
and are still angry about it and still
post about it on facebook all the time
because a lot of my friends musicians i
still see a lot of it
and then there are the people who were
like okay
the games changed time it's a new
opportunity for me
to figure out the system and figure out
how it works okay
and i saw two great hacks you could call
them hacks
for this one band was like we need to
raise money for a tour
so what we're going to do is release an
album it had like 10 tracks on it and
the tracks went for three minutes each
and they were just dead silent no music
at all
and they called the album sleepify and
they were like hey if you want us to
come on tour
everyone's got to play this album while
they sleep on repeat so they made it
money because they got so many streams
because
everyone was just playing this album on
repeat even though there was no sound
at all so they made a stack of royalties
off that and then they used that to go
on tour
and then the other way that i saw this
guy who was like
a average musician just bought a baby
name book and was like all right
i'm going to record happy birthday in
every single name
so it'll be like happy birthday to you
birthday to you happy birthday
clarisse uh happy birthday to you i've
been out there do you have an idea
daniel happy birthday to you like
whatever it was
and he just he just released that for
every single every single name
and the guy's a millionaire now right
just from the toilet hey
did he automate that
[Laughter]
um yes like you know even though you
know i'll keep the
the ethical argument of streaming out of
it out of this conversation entirely but
when i but the game changed right
the game changed and some people some
people winched about it and failed
and then some people saw the new system
as an opportunity
to grow and they smashed it so like it's
the same thing with it's the same thing
with bug bounties
um you know you've got to treat it like
a game and
you've got to be like how can i best uh
even though it's very high competition
how can i still find bugs and like
that's how to do it you need to be
creative
so one one thing that was probably uh
probably important to
to mention with regards to success is
success in bug bounties is not
necessarily about the amount of
submissions you make
or the money you earn it's about impact
so yeah impact to the to the customers
you know we've
you might find a you might find an rce
or something on a free program
that's a good impact you know
totally we've there's been examples of
that some we've
some of the recent zero days that have
been out there have actually been
reported through our platform before
they were even
released many many times yeah sometimes
months before right
yeah a hundred percent yeah there's a
key
thing they're almost they're almost
never sorry go ahead michael
there's a key thing here one thing
that's a bit of a
people make this mistake there's bug
bounty tips as a
as a tweet has become a way of people
promoting themselves and it's less about
good bugs these days so let's say dmacc
for example
if you're reporting dmarc on a non-email
based domain the company doesn't use it
what's the impact to them what is that
what is a hacker going to do
it's not like it's not o day and like
they just it's it's one of those things
where it's like
that statement that i mentioned earlier
as an attacker i can
it's as an attacker i can send email on
a domain the company's never sent email
from before and it's got
a subdomain in front of it and it's got
no value right the company
the customer is just not going to
resonate with that and versus you know
looking for things that have
customer impact that's it don't report a
mark
it's a joke
it's probably a dude
next that's our next t-shirt i think
the lesson is if you really are
concerned and you don't want to dupe and
you really want to do things
go to pen test lab sign up do the
essentials badge
learn how to go deep and then use your
really acquired recon skills from like
this talk and bug bounty hunters
methodology
to find somewhere to go deep don't use
it to find something to
run over you know those those categories
that won't impact
or have some sort of tie back use it to
look for xss or to look for
you know csrf in an app that maybe no
one's touched before
there you go all right well look i think
we're gonna would button up on time here
so
thank you so much luke that was that was
baller and um
you know i mean michael mentioned it in
the intro it's something that i've
really enjoyed about having you in the
scene but uh having you as part of bug
crowd as well as just the way that you
unpack the the mentality
and really focus on that and but then
connect that to the technology as well
so it's not just all about the
psychology it's not just all about the
tooling it's about how those things plug
together
that was a fantastic talk um i think a
lot of people are going to get value out
of it for a long time so appreciate it
i hope so that's the dream awesome
awesome
[Music]
you