[Music]
so in this this presentation now
as i mentioned earlier is by matt
birdwell who's also known as nerdwell
um hello on twitter you can find him at
the real nerdwell he's one of our bug
crowd ambassador ambassadors as well
which is just really cool so matt's
passionate about
securing the internet and helping others
achieve their infosec career goals
he has been building and breaking it
systems for 20 years
and has experience in regulated
industries like healthcare and public
utilities
and as the video mentioned this video is
insecurity through obscurity
so over to you
all right thank you let's
let's go back to the beginning okay
so in security through security um
you got a basic idea for me i will
skip that so basically what this talk is
about is uh
code objectification and minification
and how that impacts the security of
android apps
i came across it basically through some
actual
applications that i was working on and
next thing i know i was
going down a rabbit hole and came across
some
interesting stuff and some very
surprising stuff and
next thing i know really uh some
very wide scale potential new attack
factors
however code obfuscation definitely
poses a lot of problems for
bug bounty hunters of course and
developers but
for us it provides some very interesting
opportunities that we're going to talk
about
and we're also going to talk about how
we can put this together
with open source libraries and how we
can still
identify open source libraries even if
there's obfuscation
in play so of course
lots of people have done a lot of
research a lot of what i'm doing today
will touch on like java insecure java
object deserialization that's one of my
favorite bugs
it's a really good way to get code
execution
but there are definitely a lot of
gotchas and
what i came across here was
a way potentially to get by some of
those gotchas
and there's also this is a lot of words
but
basically i didn't find anything that's
actually on point with what
i was looking into the closest i came to
not available
so there is a wide range of
audience experience today i think so it
will probably help to just
lay some real quick foundation
of course we have compiled languages and
interpreted languages
where compile language is compiled at
build time
to executable code and an interpreted
language
is compiled to an intermediate language
which is then
converted to executable code at runtime
and this is especially important in the
android environment because
it is basically running java i'm sure a
lot of people would be like no no no no
it's not it's not i mean there have been
lawsuits over it right
but for our intents and purposes
it's absolutely java and we're going to
take advantage of that to the fullest
extent possible
and object-oriented programming will
play a big role
obviously java is an object-oriented
programming language
and it object-oriented
nature of the language creates some
unique challenges for us
and then also some opportunities another
interesting aspect of java
the java runtime environment and the
android the runtime environment
is that the function name or method name
is especially important when determining
like how to branch to a particular set
of code
so like if you call a function in some
java code it basically
looks up the there's a series of things
that it puts together and it's the codes
decode the method signature like the
return type
the name the parameters and
based on that knows where to go and
that's
actually going to play a very big role
in what we're looking at here today
and then of course java object
deserialization and serialization
i test on that a little bit but just in
case
some people are not that familiar with
it basically
uh what java allows developers to do is
very easily take
an in-memory object and then convert it
to
a fight stream that you can then send
over
the network or write to disk do all
sorts of stuff with it and then once it
arrives at the destination you can
deserialize it into a new
in-memory object and as it turns out
there are a number of quote-unquote
magic methods that get called in that
process
and that is generally where the
insecurities arise
in terms of object deserialization
vulnerabilities
and obfuscation and especially
minimization
actually plays a big role in breaking
this sometimes
which can have some you know security
related
implications and then also
exposing the application potentially to
attack factors
that frankly i don't think
people are looking at right now and i
showed that original slide
with the three pictures in terms of
prior research
one of the big outcomes from
basically the guy who kind of brought
this to light i think it was in
2015 chris rohoff
and he had a partner unfortunately i
could never remember his name but
uh why so serial i'm sure you guys are
familiar with that if not
definitely check it out on github it's
very useful
for for coming up with a quick proof of
concept
however it relies on known gadgets
and in things like the apaches commons
library
there are a few that don't one of my
favorites
is the ur url dns gadget
because it basically works on
native java or android well no not
android it works in
native java and does not require any
third-party libraries
but it does not work in android which is
a bummer
because actually android relies
on deserialization a whole lot
like basically every time you want to
send
data to any significant amount of data
to another application through an intent
one of the most popular ways to do that
is with
parcels and bundles which implement a
special type of serialization
okay so
what got me into this was i was hacking
on
an android app and basically
super duper difficult to get through
so let's but it was not something i had
not seen before
anyone who's done some web hacking has
seen minimize javascript
and i don't know if you've ever tried to
browse it like pretty print it in the
web tools or developer tools
and then actually operate it in the
developer tools but every time i do it
i mean my laptop starts
to take off and uh
chokes on his memory so i mean that just
speaks to
even minimize like it's
huge and gobbling up all the ram on a
you know decent box so there is an
actual legitimate use case for this
and and we see in javascript we also see
an android and
the uh the google
canonical reason for objectification is
to reduce the apk file size which it
does do
somewhere between from my experience 30
to 50
so it's just substantial savings uh
which
not only has benefits for the
publisher the author and then of course
like the app stores in terms of
the customers or users downloading it
and bandwidth and all that
but then also for us users
you know if they tap the size that's all
the more
vulnerable apps we can load up on our
phones
and then i thought i'd throw this in
there malware
is one of the other places that we see
obfuscation the most
and there obviously it's not used for
such
legitimate means and it's also
not used to make it smaller generally
you'd see it like encrypted
and it's actually very interesting the
work that malware
reverse engineers have to do but
we're not quite going to get that today
okay
so how does android
do obfuscation so in the past
it used proguard which was a
is a third-party tool and now it uses r8
it actually operates in much the same
way and
even today when you are
if you want to refine the way that it
behaves you use
proguard rules and basically
the way that it works is it has a
default dictionary which is the english
alphabet
a through z starting at the top working
on the way down
and renames all classes and members
members being variables and functions or
methods
and once it gets to z
then it goes to a a through z z
then the aaa through zzzz
and from you know i've watched a lot of
education material and youtube channels
and and
read a lot of books and one thing that
is pretty consistent across the board
is people say don't even bother
trying to understand that
i mean and they have a point we'll get
to that
but so i had mentioned earlier that
google says
that the reason for obfuscation in
android apps is to minimize the file
size
the developer forms and even some of the
books
actually refer to it as a means of
securing the app
basically thinking if they can make it
more difficult
for hackers to
reverse engineer then all the more
difficult to compromise their machine
of course we know
not only does security through obscurity
not work
what i'm going to show you today is it
actually makes the application
vulnerable
in a place where it was not before which
i think is kind of neat
i don't know about you i'm always
finding myself up against this battle
and it's kind of neat to uh to actually
say well
not only is it not good it's bad
okay and i put these exclamation points
here they basically come straight from
the
android documentation which says
don't let use the proguard rules to tell
it
to not change the name of your
application entry points
which is important because like if you
renamed
certain key functions or classes to aaa
how would anyone know how to call it
okay
so we talked about this a little bit if
you've ever
reversed an application an android app
that's been obfuscated then you'll
recognize
this tree on the left i just took this
from some random application
making sure it didn't have anything i
did check before but yeah
uh so so that's what it looks like and
of course trying to make sense of that
and especially
trying to walk a hierarchical
object-oriented structure is
it's mind-numbing i mean very very
difficult
and it actually even a lot of the
application
like automation tools that we have don't
handle it very well
especially the ones that work on like
things like java object deserialization
they refer
they rely on those magic methods names
and if that magic method has been
either removed from the app or renamed
then then it doesn't know what to do
um so
in addition to renaming there is another
element of what it does and i've
actually found it to be incredibly
annoying
when i'm trying to
like develop a plc for example is if you
have
a member or a even a class
or a method that does not get used or
the android studio doesn't think it gets
used it just
removes it and it's not in the release
build
so imagine for a second
that you have a devops pipeline that you
are
pushing changes through multiple times a
day
and you're using instrumentation to
automate a lot of your testing
and stack traces
comprised of a bunch of nested a dot
v dot one dot or you know all that good
garbage
is not gonna be very helpful for
troubleshooting problems
so generally that's going to be done
on on like a debug build which does not
have minimization
and then right before it hits the door
we do a release build and some final
testing
and then push it out
i'd be interested to see which how
companies are
where companies are doing their
application security checks if they're
doing in the
in that pipeline is it before the
release build or after
because what i've found here is
basically
optimization and minimization and the
removal element of that
as well is fundamentally changing
the structure of the code and so if
you've performed all of your testing and
application security tests against a
debug build
and then obfuscated it or minimized it
without doing further testing that's no
longer the same product
by a long shot and
google acknowledges that this is not a
knock on the technology
it like i said it has a legitimate
purpose and they have addressed
these issues there's a lot of other
things i'm not really going to go into
because they don't apply to bug bounty
hunters but
they do provide tools to help
developers understand like a stack dump
from a release build
that they get through the app store for
example
but basically i mean it's generally
understood that
it makes it difficult if not possible to
understand the code
and and stack dumps and that kind of
stuff
however for us there's a
that's a double-edged sword i i touched
on a few of them right there
but some other ones are and i'm speaking
to these from
from observations i've made in live apps
i have basically a large number
i don't think this is a surprise to
anyone a huge number
most perhaps android apps have a lot of
vanilla third-party java
dependencies and all the stuff that
comes along with that
like my personal favorite bug
deserialization
vulnerabilities and uh so
once you have now let me back up
developers do have the benefits of like
gradle
and some other things to help them
automatically
update those packages so i think that
helps a lot
but somehow i don't know how this is
happening
but somehow there are in these
obfuscated release builds
a lot of old dependencies that
are known vulnerable and we're going to
look at how we can find that
in a minute another very interesting
thing that i found
that sometimes developers will fail to
remove the qa instrumentation tools
that help them automate uh like mojito
and junit uh and they those actually
rely
on some other things under the hood like
bite buddy
ham crest which if you
go look at those it is amazing i didn't
even know that they
had come this far but basically they let
you
create your own classes on the fly
in the class path and some of them
actually will do that
upon deserialization so like if you know
much about these serialization
vulnerabilities one of the biggest
challenges
is having a vulnerable class in the
class pack well if it has
these instrumentation libraries you can
create
a an object to be deserialized and when
that object is deserialized
it creates a vulnerable classroom class
path
at your you know based upon how you
choose it to be
can't beat that and then
i touched a little bit on it does hinder
automated tools a lot
and especially the removal aspect
like read objects is a good example so
when you
have a serializable java object
and you basically hand it off to be
deserialized to the underlying api
it calls this magic method read object
and also like read resolve and read
write
something like that but
that call is nowhere in the code and so
as far as android studio is concerned
that's never used and it will very
gladly
build your package without that method
and
i've seen that help and hurt so
sometimes there will actually be some
like business logic or access log access
control logic in the read resolve
method and
a lot of people think about the read
object method and they'll include that
in the proguard rules
and exclude it but if you don't do the
same thing with read resolve
in some cases it will actually lead to
basically an access control bypass
um and then
so i see this as an opportunity
obviously this is you got to get pretty
deep in the
weeds on this and every single
application is different
so there's no doubt i mean it's
difficult
it's hard to automate and there's a lot
of
risk that you are going to basically
come out the other end empty-handed
however definitely is less competition
which generally means fewer dupes and
the nature of these bugs that you will
find when you do find them
is pretty severe so
you know maybe a quality over quantity
thing
to uh to to juggle there and then again
i put this as an opportunity because
the don't change name of app entry
points because a lot of times
developers are just either going with
the defaults
or it breaks their app like if you
google
uh pro guard broke serialization it's
all over the place and they're like oh
yeah just you know copy paste this one
thing off of uh
stack overflow and it works you know and
uh
it works but
who knows what else it's doing in your
particular app
and then one last thing i'll add on this
is
every time you rebuild the app it
changes
the obfuscated result and so
there are several several opportunities
for the bug bounty hunter
as a result the first is
obviously new bugs but then the second
is
like entirely new code paths that the
developer
did not intend and in fact could not
have
anticipated because they did not exist
at the time
they did their testing they did not
exist until
after it was released and or obfuscated
in a release build
so i mean that's pretty neat okay
so so
a couple novel attacks i say that
because i could not find
any other instances of it so if anyone
is doing it i forgot
i apologize for that uh but basically
we're going to treat the android app as
a java app and in fact
what i generally do is run decks to jar
and and actually convert it to an actual
java app
and what that lets you do is
so if there's a let's say there's a
vulnerable
object class with the deserialization
bug
it actually lets you just run java to
see it at the command line
dash jar with what was an apk but it's
now a jar
and you can instantiate that class and
create your own
instance and it makes it a little bit
easier to
to attack it also helps you
so if you can so like i actually do most
of my android testing on a non-rooted
phone which obviously makes it difficult
it's probably silly of me but it's just
there's several reasons why i did that
anyway what helps
is being able to take that apk convert
it to a jar and then if i want to
exercise a particular code block i can
do that and i can do it in a
environment where i have debug
capabilities
and uh and i don't need group
so i'll touch on this again the method
name
is central to resolution and
invocation of function calls in java
and so what happens is
if uh well i'm going to show you a
better picture here but i'll explain it
now
if you have two classes
and they have the same parent
and one of them let's say they're it's a
person class and you have man and woman
and woman has a function that man does
not have
and man has a function that woman does
and then you
obfuscate those classes
it's just going after numerically so
the uh the function that the woman had
that the man didn't could be
it could become c and then the function
that the man had that the woman didn't
also becomes seen
and you get in this situation where if
you can get
the the application to deserialize
the wrong class and that uh
read object implementation calls
c you've just
expanded the potential range of
of gadgets substantially
and i'll explain that a little bit more
in a second
okay so thinking of this in terms of a
tale
of four classes what we have on the left
is a friendly class writes a vulnerable
class so
not necessarily evil just a third-party
library
that no one realized is vulnerable on
the left
unobfuscated basically
we have i'm going to go down to the read
object method here
we're going to read an object off of
that stream and then call
a function upon that object
this is a very simplified
use case i mean anybody who's written
java is going to know that
that code will not compile but it's it's
for illustrative purposes
when it's obfuscated that class will
become a
a and string becomes a
you know going down the line there what
you end up with
is at the bottom y dot b
and that is very generic and stepping
over to the vulnerable class
we have a similar structure
it doesn't have to have the same names
and in fact
that's where the
the novelty of this comes from
so in this instance also with the read
object we instantiate it and we call
upon
a function upon the instantiated object
and but that one has a different name
it's run command and it's
it runs you know the shell
well when we obfuscate that we get bb
and so on
uh moral of the story being the very
last line
in both cases you end up with y dot b
and so
if you are attacking an an application
and looking for
vulnerable java object deserialization
a key element to that is a class to the
class path that you can deserialize and
that
has a function with the same method
signature
as that which is called in the
vulnerable read object method
and that's a mouthful but
what this does is instead of having to
call
uh my full name upper which is
very unlikely to exist in any other
class now all you have to have is a
class
with the function b which is basically
every class
and now the key there though is being
able to get it to deserialize it but
look into deserialization that we're not
actually worried about it completing
the deserialization process so
kind of neat so we i've illustrated it
here a little bit
basically if i was to take the
unobfuscated vulnerable class from the
first picture
over here and pass it into this read
object method
i would get amongst other things
no such method error if i
take this bb object
serialized and hand it to this read
object method
i get profit
okay so with that let me
switch over here to well i think i need
to change
my window
bear with me up here
okay
okay so
so this is a class that i did that on
and
basically
we have so
and this is where if you look it up or
you know you watch a youtube video or
some education material they're like
yeah i mean it's it's you can't even
make sense of it
and so they have a good point i'm
sitting here trying to think of how best
to explain it to you
uh it's difficult so basically though
what we have
is a is
our parent so okay
somewhere here we have an abstract class
let's go look
f
okay so basically in my source code this
is
just a real basic plc we have a
a like a root level abstract
parent class and it's got just some you
know random function
it's not defined here other than the
fact that it exists
so it has to be declared it's declared
here not defined in the
in the child so d
and e are two
classes basically like man and woman in
the
as i just was describing before uh that
extend that abstract class and implement
some unique
behavior of their own and what you end
up with
is if you look here so
a comes from
well they have their own a and then they
have
a as is defined in the parent abstract
class
and the key here is if you look here
they have the same name same parameters
same return type meaning
they're the same signature and being
from the same parent
you can craft a payload that will get
d to deserialize e
and well
i think it's the other way around that
they're vulnerable i have to look but
that's the basic premise of it and uh
it's actually
all over the place once you start
looking at it once you start
considering proxy classes and
um
interfaces and stuff
it's it's very interesting so if you
look at some of the work
from matthias kaiser in particular he
found
a lot of the proxy gadgets that use
invoker handler
and he illustrates the gadget chain
and it highlights basically
that having a function with the same
name
is essential and that that's one of the
biggest hurdles to overcome
well this basically eliminates that for
you
the difficulty becomes at this point
just getting a class
that you're going to be able to call
that method on and that's where
uh where proxy classes and reflection
especially will help you
which let me switch back
takes us onto our next slide
yeah okay okay so
so the way i came upon this
actually was
i was working on an app and i don't
remember exactly what i saw but i just
saw like a function name or something
that was
odd a lot of times you'll see
a lot of the code is obfuscated but not
all of it and that goes back to those
proguard rules
and so some class was not and there's a
third party library
and it it was one of these qa
instrumentation
classes or tools and
and it was something like you know
create class and i was like wait a
minute
you've got a class that creates classes
in your class path
i want that and uh and sure enough
that's exactly what it was and so i had
a lot of fun with this but
it also became pretty challenging so i
knew that i had
mojito in the class path and i knew
that i could create a mock as they call
it
a serializable mock that will
create a class in the class path of my
choosing upon deserialization
which is like the holy grail of
of deterioration
however it was really goofy some of the
classes were
were obfuscated and some weren't and so
getting that
to work was very very challenging
and what i came down to was looking for
static values in the source that did not
get changed
by objection and actually i failed to
put
i wanted to put another slide there has
been some research on this
and they basically suggested
basically a similar approach uh and it's
the
if you have a serializable class the uid
here will
will be a very clear telltale sign
because that's a theoretically should be
a unique number to that class
and you can go to github put that in
there and find out
what what library is in that application
so it's a really good way like if you
just open up jdx gui
do a search across the entire app for
serial version uid
anything that's not uh 0 or 42l
and there's a big long number like this
that's basically a fingerprint
and you can run from there but even then
even say with maquito not every single
class in that
library is serializable not all of them
are going to have that value
in fact not all of them are going to
have a string
which is another useful tool for
fingerprinting them
so if you have a class that
a third-party library it's been
obfuscated and it writes an
error message to the log or file or
something like that
well that can also be fingerprints if
it's in quotes odds are
it's not going to be touched by proguard
or r8 and then
you can use that where it became very
challenging is when you have a class
kind of like that abstract class that
well not kind of like it's exactly like
a parent abstract class or an interface
that doesn't do a lot and by design
well you still likely will need to know
the entire hierarchical structure to be
able to successfully
exploit and so those are the challenging
ones
and it was very fun the approach i took
was basically established all the ones
that i can
using the static from fingerprint
capabilities and then literally go
through
the remaining classes by hand and say
okay so like
this one imports these libraries
and then it's got these variables of
this type
and then they're all gobbly goop names
but i know the type
and i know how many functions they have
i know how many what they return
so that helped a lot and actually i was
basically able to
fully uh
i'm not sure what the right word is but
basically
document the uh the entire class
structure that i needed to be able to
provide that serializable mock to have
it deserialized
and then that's what i found out
uh it had renamed the read resolve
method which was key
to to instantiating that class
and the whole exploit didn't work and i
had to go a different way
but that was just that one app
and there are definitely others where
that is not the case
and going back to you know the copy
paste from stack overflow
the one i see the most often basically
has like
read object read resolve right object
write resolve so
if they fail to remove instrumentation
libraries
a huge gaping hole
and basically
you know unprecedented opportunity for
rce however it is
difficult and time consuming but
the payoff is pretty big as well thank
you very much that was uh that was
certainly was a real deep dive into
into object deserialization in in
android
um the uh the one thing that stood out
to me that i wanted to ask
was um has do kotlin apps
are they vulnerable to similar to
similar desiralization or it's been a
while since i've
i've authored any android applications
but uh i'm certainly interested to to
find out if kotlin's
vulnerable to the same sort of yeah
actually
that's uh something i want that's my
well not my next but it's on the list i
basically have zero experience with it
but what i did find as i was going
through there is the way that it's
implemented
is using basically these new uh
uses lambdas a whole lot and so
that's that's perfect when you have
something that is using
uh dynamic typing on the fly
yeah super cool yeah i think there's
some opportunity there
yeah absolutely yeah it's a
there's yeah there's certainly a lot of
a lot of research that can be done in in
the kotlin area for
sure
so the you mentioned there was a
um a static id there in in one of your
last
one of your last slides there is there a
good reference for those static values
that are available online as there may
be someone keeping track of them on
github for
for bounty hunters or i'm not sure i
i don't think so but
there could be there was definitely some
research done i wouldn't be surprised if
those people
had done it what i did was actually just
plug it into the search uh at the top
right and
like eight times out of ten it would
tell me
bam there it is and actually what's cool
is a lot of times it would
increment it would change in versions so
it not only can it tell you the class
but in some instances it will actually
tell you a version
and help you fingerprint if it's
vulnerable
yeah are there um is there any tooling
to comparatively fuzz that so you can
take the github
version of a tool and comparatively fuzz
the method
the method and class names
not that i know of but that would be the
cool project there we go yeah someone
someone watching this
is can go and run with that that'd be a
be a good
useful project machine learning on it
yeah very true very true actually as it
might be
seems to be a theme kind of bubbling up
out of this level up
yeah i guess yeah we're starting another
startup right
beyond that as well uh you mentioned not
renaming certain entry points two
questions of that
could you fuzz that which it sounds like
you could and
is there any known reference points for
those entry like beyond entry points
anything else you just shouldn't
rename when you're exploring with this
oh
that's a good question actually uh i
meant to mention
i think developers don't consider read
object actually
is an entry point into your application
and so
yeah it's easy to forget that and uh
and all the other ones and if you're
using you know
jax b or the xml deserializer all of
those
are places where data can become
you know crossed into the control plane
and i would say
yeah yeah that's good
yeah it was interesting talker it um
what are what are the current projects
you're kind of looking at beyond so with
the theory and everything you've kind of
presented there what's the
what's the area of this that you're kind
of diving into most at the moment
um well actually i guess the apartment
was the thing i end up spending the most
time on
uh just because i mean the problem with
this is it is incredibly
tedious and time consuming and next
thing you know you're like
your head's spinning so
don't make a lot of progress on that one
but
it's something i kind of come back to
every once in a while
i have the idea that like you could
basically hit all the
google app store the play or
absent yeah
so these these techniques for
deserialization do they apply at all to
ios
applications or is a completely
different world or is
is there anything we can take away to
for people who to only look at ios
perhaps i'm not sure i mean i've done a
little bit of ios but just because it's
a black box
and uh
i don't know so last time i played with
it like you couldn't really get to the
source code it was like
signed and encrypted and that's
basically when i stopped so
i mean if it's using java absolutely
yeah i mean all of these so all these
apply to java apps as well
and you know proguard is not only an
android thing it's
actually i think it came from the java
world
yeah just on the um you know you're
talking about your
your projects and it being time
consuming it's another question that
we've had come in from discord is there
any parts of your analysis that you you
typically
automate if you if you're giving
automation tips to
to seasoned or even new android hackers
what would they be
so i do uh automate when i can i did not
in this
i i was trying to think of how i could
um
there's probably some some ways but i
basically
did it manually uh but i actually
participated in the um in like the darpa
cyber grand challenge
a while back so like i mean i
you know you didn't see my name i didn't
go to black hair or jeffcon so you know
i obviously didn't do that good
but it just the learning experience was
amazing
and uh so i did kind of work on a bunch
of tools
not really tools but you know i do a lot
of like ida
scripting and uh i guess on that
beyond like android studio and ida what
are your what's your toolkit consist of
because it's the in the public realm
that people could kind of go and have a
look at
yeah so uh so actually
mostly i was using middle proxy
for like all my web application testing
and actually i didn't really switch over
until
to burp so i needed like to produce some
burp logs in a particular format
and i mean i've used burp before but i
like the uh
i was just familiar with with minimum
proxy
um but now i don't ever use it anymore
so i mean nice to have a cool gui
um and then either i mean you know i'm
uh
i guess the pro version of that it's
worth every penny
yeah if you've got the access to it it's
uh yeah have you played have you played
around with guydra at all
i know a little bit i played uh
with that and uh rodari and i
steep learning curve i guess that i was
familiar with yeah with either so i
would definitely like to because i mean
if it's just good and it's free yeah
it's an interest
yeah exactly that's the reason i ask
because obviously you know ida pro and
it's the same with a lot of these
you know static analysis tools you spend
years building out your own particular
workflows on top of them it's not easy
to just kind of rip and replace it off
to something else but
you know for folks that don't have
access to a to a commercial license
provider
or a commercial instance of it and they
don't want to go down the you know
shady um bittorrent route
um geidra is a legit option
that's what i've heard and then you can
do you know like arm i guess
and and x64 and yeah
yeah there's a lot of a lot of um a lot
of pros a lot of architecture
compatibility built into it
this is you know from from what i
haven't frankly played around a time
with it myself but
i think when it was first released there
was that initial
this is an nsa thing and i'm a bit
freaked out kind of reaction that
everyone had and since then you know
it's turned into oh this is actually a
pretty great tool
yeah so they have a resources
yeah true taking it back to to android
for a moment
so if somebody was watching the
presentation and wanted to get a start
with
with looking at deserialization in
android what's a what's a fairly simple
path they could they could follow to do
that
so uh so right now actually
unfortunately there are no
to my knowledge like uh uh
public gadgets that work in android so
like
in in a web app or any other java
environment you would go
get wi-fi serial actually i kind of went
deep on the url dns
gadget to find out why it does not work
at android and it's
it's like this one tiny little
change but it's enough to make it not
work
so the downside is
for deserialization in android is it's
pretty much a one-off
per application thing but that's also
the upside
because that's the kind of thing that
automated tools don't find
developers don't or application security
engineers a lot of times won't find
and uh you know they can generally
be quite impactful
that's good so um i guess the last touch
you know
what you've got and what's out there
beyond the two kind of fuzzing
little startups we quickly spun out
what's uh what's your dream tool in this
space that you'd love to see if someone
was watching this
like i just want to poke and build
something what's the uh
what's the one thing you wish you could
have in your tool kit oh man
i do i think for me it would be
something that can
um reliably emulate
uh like router and iot
firmware that has
nvram you know that you don't auto like
i can always get it to go until it needs
to hit that and then i have to go like
compile my own nvram dot so so
that would be cool that's interesting
are you are you aware of
you're aware of anyone who's so you're
talking about like um
virtualization kind of uh
you know bare metal level virtualization
of android is that is that accurate
uh well yeah actually android and also
like uh
any iot stuff rather you know light
bulbs yeah yeah right
got it so i actually started playing
around with i got a raspberry pi
and a uh beaglebone
black so i was able to
to do some of that and you know actually
just
run the firmware on it but there's still
some use cases where being able to run
it in keemu
would be helpful and still a very manual
process
there's a lot of good things yeah for
sure i i was just i was just checking
them because i know i know of an
organization that's working on that i
don't think they've released it yet but
when they do we'll make a bit of a to do
about that because yeah it's
it's a common thing i mean it's access
to hardware
all the variations of different hardware
that exist out there you know it applies
to
like major iot like automotive hacking
all sorts of other stuff as well so
the idea of simplifying that and making
it available as a platform
is a is a pretty neat thing
yeah and yeah and like being in the
critical infrastructure space there's a
lot of stuff that we can't
uh really probably test
because it's it doesn't get physical
because we'll talk about i imagine
right oh that would be awesome we've got
one more we've got one more question
that came in from discord from fat fred
will you be my sensei
well i think i love fat friends i'll be
yours if you'll be mine
oh there you go mutual mutual sensei
it's it's all happening at level up
now look as we as we wrap up mate i
really appreciate the um
you going through all of that is there
anything any kind of parting party
comments you want to make to the
to the viewers uh just
have fun stay positive you know
hacks for fun and uh i hacked the planet
awesome awesome all right well thank you
so much um
and yeah if you if you want to um if
you're able to jump across into the the
discord as well reminded everyone who's
viewing that we are
on on discord so discord.levelup.sh if
you haven't signed up already or if you
are
we can carry on the q a and and go a
little bit deeper into that stuff as
well there is the qr code
thank you very much amp for uh spotting
us in the control room there
and uh yeah thanks again
[Music]