[Music]
um but yeah without further ado let's
introduce the next speaker katie so for
those of you who don't know
katie is a bug bounty hunter educational
youtuber and
is somehow finding the time to finish
her phd in cyber security and machine
learning
a former data scientist turned cyber
security person who's been in
bug hunting until 2019 that's her bio um
today katie's going to be talking with
us about
an intro to ai for bug bounty hunters
which i'm
super jazzed for this talk i think this
is going to be super
super informative and exciting um not
for the
for the least of the reasons to actually
understand what ai
means and is hopefully by the end of it
so take it away katie
well thank you for having me today i'm
really going to be talking about
several different topics but i hope
you'll come away from this entire
introduction
thinking i kind of understand this a
little bit better
ai and machine learning as a field moves
really quickly
um and sometimes actually quite slowly
and there's a lot of terms so i really
hope by the end of this presentation
you'll maybe understand a little bit
more
um so i should start by introducing
myself again
um my name is katie i call myself an
occasional bug bounty hunter
because i don't always have the time to
do it
part-time um but i'm part-time a cyber
security youtuber i make videos on bug
hunting on youtube
um but that's kind of what i'm well
known for but actually i also have a day
job
i'm a phd student and my phd is in
cyber security machine learning i have a
bachelor's in computer science
when i finished my bachelor's i ended up
working as a data scientist now you
don't really know what data scientist is
it's kind of like the software engineer
for things like machine learning but
also a bunch of other things
my like job in machine learning was not
actually that interesting
um i did kind of got a bunch of sales
data and worked out which sales person
would sell
what day to the best um sounds really
boring
was kind of boring that's why i'm a phd
student now
um so we really want to start with one
key question
which is what is ai and i'm going to
tell you
probably everything you might have ever
wanted to know about ai
um but let's start with the big question
what is ai
and i think this is a really great way
to explain what ai is is this kind of
ever increasing like
circle we start with ai which is this
general concept or a program that can
sense reason act adapt we think about a
machine that can act like a human
then we have machine learning where we
have algorithms that are specifically
designed to improve their performance
when they're exposed to more data
and then we have deep learning which is
about uh neural networks
um but if you're not really familiar
with these terms you probably don't
really understand them
so i've created this in memes now our
big ai
is if statements so this is quite a big
mean that all ai is just if statements
um then we have machine learning which
is just statistics that we rebranded as
machine learning
so statisticians um would get upset
and then we have deep learning which is
really importing
a program called tensorflow into your
code and making it do all the hard work
while you sit back and do machine
learning research
so this is a bit tongue-in-cheek
because it's not always if statements
some of the time so ai is this gigantic
field but it includes a bunch of other
things as well
so we have machine learning which is
kind of separated into supervised and
unsupervised
don't worry we'll cover that um then we
have natural language processing which
is what i do
my phd which is all about kind of
statistical analysis
of text and human language we have
computer vision
that's you know the self-driving cars
that can see if something's a human
or a dog or a stop light whatever
um but also those memes where you see
like why is my machine learning
algorithm recognizing the dog as a cat
that kind of thing and we also have our
if statement so robotics manufacturing
optimization
um which might kind of look like machine
learning that is this statement
most of the time if statements all the
way down
and it's not always a stuffer nightmare
so this is a
neural network um and it's designed to
kind of replicate how your brain works
apart from it doesn't do that
it just gives you nightmares of these
kind of like inner layers which will
have all these neurons that connect
now i'm going to reassure you here
machine learning
is just statistics if you have a ball a
flat a bag of balls
and if i pull out three red balls and
one green ball the probability of the
next ball being red is three out of four
and being green is one out of four
now this doesn't really matter because
it could be that the next
all the other balls that says temples in
the bag the rest of them
are also green so
we really can see that the probability
of it being
green might be one out of four based on
what we've seen but actually
the statistics might not tell us the
full story
um and from this we kind of make a
prediction
that a red bull is most likely it could
be the rest of the balls of green
however a red ball is more likely and
this is primarily what ai
is doing under the hood um it may look
like ai is doing all these
clever things but really under the hood
ai is just
looking at these statistics and kind of
making predictions based on what it's
already seen
unfortunately machine learning is just
statistics
and the field of statistics has moved on
since you did kind of
maybe grade school level stats uh where
we're talking about balls
and bags and no joke this is actually an
algorithm
that i had to look at for my phd and i
had to explain those like i'll just
get off on wikipedia how does it work i
looked at this and thought
okay for further information on this
algorithm please see
paper name yeah because i'm not going to
touch that
uh and often in machine learning the
math kind of looks
much closer to this um we're not math
people this looks confusing there are
like greek letters in there
no um we're not really looking at
improving the algorithms and we really
don't need to know all this
we really only need to know the kind of
what the algorithm does and how it does
it
so what is the core of machine learning
now there's two kind of key concepts
here one is
training a statistical model a bunch of
data and then using that model to make
predictions about new data using what is
previously seen
to make predictions about new data
and that is all machine learning is like
everything you see from computer vision
to
self-driving cars to what might be the
next bug hunting machine learning
uh model it's all going to be data
model prediction it's not going to be
any more complex than that i promise
so i've told you about the statistics um
and i told you that's not really what it
looks like so
let's have a chat about practical
machine
learning um so
i'm kind of skipping over here the other
types of ai i'm focusing on machine
learning because it's one of the easiest
to explain it's where most people start
um and machine learning can kind of be
broken down into how the algorithms work
and that supervised unsupervised
reinforcement that's what i call
semi-supervised
now that doesn't mean that they need a
programmer watching over
the like algorithm at all time what it
means is that the data has labels
associated with it
for certain like supervised machine
learning i'm going to give you a bunch
of data and give you the label so that
might mean
i give you a bunch of photos and i tell
you this is a duck
this is a duck this is a duck this is
not a duck and then i ask you to predict
which one is a duck uh a new a new image
and then unsupervised is where i give
you a bunch of pictures don't give you
any other information and just tell you
sort them out reinforcement learning is
a little bit different
um and it's primarily used in kind of
different
fields but i'll explain that a little
bit more as we get to it
um but it's the idea of rewarding
a algorithm um when a model works really
well
and these are all used to solve
different problems i really like this
graph over
here because i think it does a great job
of kind of highlighting it so we have in
unsupervised learning we have clustering
we have recommender systems so that's
when amazon tells you a bunch of
products you don't want
customer segmentations that's when you
kind of look at a bunch of customers
inside which categories they go into
over in supervised we have image
classification
and over in reinforcement learning we
have game ai
um so they're used to solve different
problems so i want to just go into sort
of
more detail on what these look like so
this is
supervised machine learning now we give
a
bunch of pictures that have labels and
we ask it
new image tell me what it is and this is
one of the simplest forms of machine
learning you tend to see
a lot of kind of complex machine
learning is built from these um
uh statistical like supervised learning
models the problem is is that as you can
imagine you need
a lot of data to make machine learning
work very well
and not just that you need a lot of
label data
and humans have to make those labels you
can't get a machine to make
labels for you really and it won't be
accurate if you do
so not only is there just like
the whole getting all the data you have
to label the data it's
quite labor intensive to do supervised
machine learning
um but it works great for classification
problems so when you have
like what in what is this is this a cat
or a dog is this a duck or a not a duck
so that's the first kind of easy kind of
beginner stuff we then have unsupervised
machine learning
now as for supervised machine learning
where we had a bunch of data
labels associated with each piece of
data with unsupervised machine learning
um we have the opposite we just have
data and we ask the machine to figure it
out for itself
now the way it does this is quite
interesting algorithmically i won't kind
of go into that
but it tries to draw these boundaries
between where the data might be
you tell it how many clusters it needs
so in this case we've asked
the algorithm to take this data and turn
it into three clusters
and it kind of decides where those
boundaries might be between the data
now this is really useful and this is
like what i do during my phd as well
because this
is not very labor intensive
comparatively anyway
you just give it data and you just see
what it figures out on its own
um it's only really can be used to solve
some problems though and
what it's good for is really going to be
dependent on what problems you have
um very very good for clustering data
kind of a good security example might be
um
i have a bunch of bugs tell me which
bugs have some kind of relationship
you know tell me which where sql
injection is related to blind sql
injection for example which is related
to whatever
and then we have reinforcement learning
and this is my favorite example and i
don't know if you've seen this this came
this was quite popular uh
a few months ago and it was on the bbc
um
and what this is is it's got it's a
skeleton that's held some rules
associated with it with how it can move
and it learns to walk and jump and run
in a very strange way
because what happens is the algorithm
gets rewarded the further it can make it
so it just basically hits random buttons
until it makes it further then it tries
to almost mutate that
so that's kind of very similar to what
we might consider as evolution
um but not as we know it like it's very
different
it's kind of like watching it play all
the game
q q up a few years ago where you have
like runner and you have to hit the
buttons and you just end up hitting them
randomly
so we know the algorithms now how do we
actually
train them uh so once we decide an
approach we need to change the algorithm
which seems simple enough you think one
line of code
model.train put your data in sorted
actually the actual stages of going from
data to machine learning model is quite
difficult there's
loads of stages and in each stage you
kind of
it really does impact the performance of
the model later on so it's really
important to make sure you get it right
and how to kind of have this iterative
process
um so some of the stages you typically
see splitting the data into a test and a
train set i'll explain that a sec
selecting which features are the most
important so that means you know
what part of a duck makes something a
duck
um and then evaluating the model does it
work well what's the accuracy like now
accuracy when it comes to machine
learning
i'm going to use it very generally i am
aware that it
it there are measures of accuracy and
there's loads of different types
i'm going to cover that that's fine um
so let's talk about splitting the data
so
when we have developed these machine
learning models
we have our training but we also
have to have some way of seeing if it
works
and then primarily like the way we do
that is we take our big data set
and we just go 80 of data will be used
for the training of the machine learning
and twenty percent will be used for
testing later there's a big advantage of
this
that because say for classification we
know what labels are associated with
we can kind of see you know we can tune
the model a little bit change some
hyper parameters which like hidden
parameters in the model
and then make some small adjustments
does it work well whatever
and then uh for some you might have not
just a training a test set but also a
validation set
so you might be starting with say 100
records
by the time you do this you might be
only looking at 60 records
that you can actually train your machine
learning model on so you end up like
slashing the data continually just to
try and get something that you can test
and you can validate and you can see if
it works
a feature selection is next so feature
selection is all about
what makes that piece of data that class
because we might look at a duck and
compare it to a cow and go
well a duck has feathers but actually
all birds have feathers that's not
really something that's special to ducks
it's just all birds have feathers
you go oh well it has a beak and its
face is green
and then you go well you know do it does
other things have green faces
so when you do this kind of process
you're really trying to pick out what is
the most important features that will
lead to the best
um classification overall because if you
include
everything you go well i'm just going to
trade on everything
what you'll get is something that takes
ages to run and that won't give you any
good results it will just return garbage
so we've got that
we then we've got evaluating the models
and there are so many different
mathematical ways of evaluating models
um there is tables of accuracy there's
for different algorithms there's
different ways of looking at things
there's heuristics there's precision
recall
there's r square there are so many ways
of like
quantifying if something works
and actually this can take a really long
time
because you have to figure out when you
act when you're actually okay with your
model being bad
um because you won't get 100 accuracy
you may not even get 90
when you first start out it's working
out kind of the best
combination best recipe of data plus
hyper parameters plus the test and
training sets
plus whatever that ends up giving you
the best model possible
um and with that comes errors and one of
the biggest errors we see in machine
learning is bias
any machine learning system is going to
be biased towards the data it was
trained on
um and often the data comes in biased so
for example um gpt-3
can't give you a sentence about muslims
without it being about
violence um apple's credit card system
was discriminating against women um tay
tweets which was this famous
kind of experiment set up by microsoft
people tweeted out racist things to the
robot and the robot tweeted out racist
things back it learned from what people
were tweeting at it
um when you give a uh
image classification system pictures of
people cooking
it often assumes they're women because
it's seen more women cooking
on youtube if you post content that's
lgbt
you're likely to get demonetized and
we kind of wave this away as garbage in
garbage out
it's really important to know what the
data is trained on and how that's
actually going to affect the model
because you know these are really
extreme examples that are quite well
publicized
but if you've got a model that's only
slightly biased
you're going to have similar problems
you're going to have errors
and you're not going to be able to
really fix them
not in the same way you can fix code so
it's really important when we think
about errors to also think about
what you've actually fed the model um
and
what data it's got so
that's a very very quick introduction to
uh machine learning um and
kind of some of the relevant issues um
and if you really
if you listen to this part of my talk
and you go
yes that sounds amazing
how do i get into that uh the best place
i find to go is data camp um machine
learning
kind of models and code is often written
either r
or python i'm going to guess and say
most people here
want to use python not r i did a i did a
survey on this and i was very much not
in the majority with liking r
um and datacamp.com is amazing
for this and if you want to have a go at
kind of doing this on real data
kaggle.com
is bug bounties but instead of finding
security vulnerabilities
you make machine learning models same
idea you get paid there are
um people talking and doing write-ups
about how they
built their models so i just kind of
want to take this
and talk about how you build a model a
step-by-step guide
step one your data step
two you've got to understand the data
you can't just take the raw data
and run it through an algorithm because
all that'll give you back is terrible
results you've got to understand you
know is this biased
what issues does it have um what works
really well
what might be a good predictor then you
have
feature selection so you look at every
single value in the data set
and you look at the ones which gonna
provide you the most accurate results
you build a model um in this case this
is a decision tree model
you test the model you test its
precision
its recall sensitivity selectivity
accuracy f measure you do a bunch of
them a bunch of these maths
and you build the model again because
your first model was probably bad
you test the model again and
you use the model on your data so you
build this model you
apply it to new data and then you get
results back
and you know what that gives you it
gives you more data
and this is how you have this iterative
process
of designing machine learning models um
where you kind of end up in this sea of
data
and really your job is to kind of wade
through it and find meaning in that data
and take that meaning and show how
you can use it to really
um build and understand and create these
machine learning models to predict more
so
okay what about bug hunting
um and i'm gonna call this aka why we
won't see ai taking over bug hunting
i hear this a lot a lot of people are
very worried that ai
is about to take the but all of the bugs
um and i really want to reassure you
with this
ai is not going to take all of the bugs
you're going to be fine
so really when we look at machine
learning and cyber security
um apart from vendors who are often
bragging about their
amazing machine learning algorithms a
lot of it
is still far more in academia and
academic spaces and
isn't necessarily being operationalized
because it's actually quite difficult to
operationalize machine learning
especially in something like cyber
security where
one of the big kind of issues is like
regulation
and being certified for things
and especially when we start to consider
okay
could we build machine learning models
to hump bugs the research just isn't
there yet we don't have
like any of the people working on this
so do we need to worry about ai no
why don't we need to worry about ai
statistical models
need data it's so so so important
you cannot build machine learning
without
very large data sets you can do it on
small data sets
it just won't work it won't be accurate
it won't represent reality
it's just not going to work and there is
no
publicly available data set on how
people approach hacking
specifically you know what people need
to do is record what steps they take
so then we could figure out a way to
represent that and then kind of
recreate that as a machine learning
model it doesn't exist
the data isn't there when we think about
the evolution of machine learning and
kind of before we build up a data or
build up the data we have to kind of go
through
these stages we start out with a sea of
data
we then have to figure out you know how
can we
look at it how can we get meaning from
it so if we think about that with the
lego bricks
we have a pile of lego bricks when we
sort the lego bricks we learn more about
them we can see every single color that
is there
when we arrange them we understand more
about what shapes are available
and then when we present them visually
we can really start to understand okay
we have a lot of yellow and red
it's not until we get to that final step
of seeing it visually
that we understand the data we
originally started with which is a lot
of red and yellow bricks
so before you build the model even if
the data existed you have to
understand the data itself and
machine learning cannot represe like
recreate
human creativity um a lot of people
worry about like general ai
it's nowhere near that there's no way an
ai can accurately represent human
creativity
it's slaves to its data it's trained on
it can't think outside the box it can't
produce something new it has to go with
what
humans have already told it so the data
isn't there
even if the data was there we don't
really understand the data
and even if it was there we still
couldn't find unique bugs it'd just be a
slave to the bugs it's seen before
and really one of the big things the
community is missing is expertise
now i hope by listening to this you kind
of realize how much effort
it is to actually make a good machine
learning model
because the actual cycle and i think
this is a great
like like idea of how machine learning
works
when you start to think about it from
like a deployable piece of software
we need to understand the business we
need to understand the data
we need to prepare the data model it
evaluate it
and then we can deploy it the problem is
throughout all of this step
these steps here are a cycle of
and like slightly more and just like
better understood
even if you have all the data even if
it's all labeled
it's really easy to build a bad model
that
doesn't work um so
okay what do we have and what are the
next steps to be able to do
machine learning we have bounty targets
data
now this is a data set available on
uh github which has a list of all the
domains on
hacka1 on bug crowd on i think it has
integrity now it's got all of the
domains and what's in scope
and this is a good place to start if you
want to see
kind of what websites are available
and look at the domains associated with
them we have
bug bounty scans which is just scanning
results of different
domains that are available on bug bounty
programs
we have awesome bug bounty write-ups if
you remember
right to begin the presentation i talked
about natural language processing the
ability to understand text
so something written in human language
like a writer
could we potentially try and retrace the
steps i don't know it hasn't been done
yet
we have the official hacker one
disclosure timeline
again list of disclosed reports written
in human language
that's something we can look at doing
next
so the next steps for ai and
bug bounty one is we've got to
understand the data we have now usually
we do that by conducting an exploratory
data analysis
we look at the data and we just
visualize in different way we give it a
poke and see what comes out
we need to understand what our goals are
when we want ai and bug bounty do we
want to be able to
find bugs do we want to be able to do
recon activities
do we want to um kind of
i don't know look at see what bugs are
going to come next what bugs
are going to be the next big thing we
need to gather
the data the data isn't there for most
of this
we need to find it even if if we want to
automate the finding of bugs we need to
record how people hack
we can't do that part unless we have
the first part of recording people
hacking
and it's only once we go through those
steps we can even think about machine
learning methods and models being
applied generally to this
space in the field um we can't look at
it now
we're still we've got to do all these
other stages at least until it works
properly
and because there's just no way to get
an operationalized machine learning
model
in the space of time that kind of we're
looking at at the moment
but you know what if you can't join them
beat them you can hack machine learning
this cve was issued in 2019
um and this was the piece of research
actually done
um by a member of the ai village at
defcon um
who found it was by looking at email
headers
uh they were able to create a copycat
machine learning classification model
and then extract how their model worked
to try and
craft emails that would get through
filters
um this is from a really great paper um
talking about what the attack surface of
machine learning algorithms might be
um we have kind of issues in feature
extraction prediction
cross cost function minimization model
representation clustering
um and we have a bunch of these kind of
exploitation techniques and impacts
which come to some of the bugs we can
find
even if we're looking at machine
learning models you know what we can
find we can find arbitrary code
executions
we can find denial of surface us service
attacks
we can also um corrupt machine learning
models
um by giving it fake jpeg files we can
cause memory corruption
actually machine learning is becoming
more and more popular
especially with like big big big uh
organizations who are desperate to have
the next shiny new thing but don't
really understand the security issues
around it
this is not something to be afraid of my
friends
this is something that is an opportunity
for us all
so thank you very much for listening if
you want to follow me on any of my
platforms my youtube
is inside a phd and my twitter is inside
a phd
you can google me thank you very much
for listening everybody
that was fantastic it um i
really do encourage people to dig into
your youtube as well i know
um at any part of the journey there's a
lot to get out there i've been
recommending videos and intro you know
for people starting out but i know even
as someone who's done it for a few years
i get a lot out of your content i think
it's brilliant
but um thank you before i'm gonna be a
little bit selfish here before we dig
into
questions from um discord i i have a
personal question i wanted to ask
you were saying about it's very
difficult to operationalize
um because of lack of data do you think
on the inverse of that there's still a
lot of room for defensive team to
take the data that they're receiving
from organic traffic to start to filter
out
um malicious traffic easily or do you
think it's too noisy for that to be a
productive space so there's a lot of
research
on kind of those kind of steps
i don't know if there's anything we can
do about traffic because in general it's
quite difficult to do anomaly
detection on traffic because it is so
noisy
one thing that blue teams could do if
they have a bud bounty program
is actually try and gain insights from
reports that have been submitted
um and then make changes to their
program you know if they're seeing a
certain class of bug
maybe they can do internal testing for
it
i'd be disappointed because that means i
would get less bugs
but things like that are like a total
way that a blue team could
kind of not necessarily exploit their
own systems but use the same data to
solve a different problem
yeah that makes sense for sure and i
guess to to flip to one of the uh
the youtube questions is there a way to
use machine learning with reinforcement
learning to
follow the pattern of hacking to find
exploits so could you
monitor your own traffic and use that
for an exploratory path
that's a great question so i don't know
because the research hasn't been done
and you know what that means that means
that you
can look at it and do that research and
see if it works
we this is really um the first steps
and i'm like i'm doing delivering this
presentation and i'm really giving away
all my ideas here
because there's a lot of
stages that one can take to really
um kind of push the push it forward
when it comes to using reinforcement
learning you still need quite a lot of
data
um and the question would be you know
who how many people are you recording
how diverse
are their hacking techniques if we're
just going to be doing the kind of
traditional reinforcement learning which
is hitting a bunch of buttons
and then rewarding it when it gets that
far
are we testing on ctfs how are we
rewarding it what kind of reward scales
are we looking at
there's so much there and you know what
you can do that research you can find
that out
how much i mean from from your
perspective working on this stuff
you know in context of your your phd and
professionally how much does it rely on
the target
being the same because i would think
that the other thing that would be a
challenge
um you know behind the idea that um
is in the question michael just asked is
that every target is different as well
you're not just talking about
one ctf you know framework or one you
know windows box on the internet or
whatever it's just the whole raft of
different stuff
it'd be really difficult i think
when it comes to what we're really
asking machine learning to do when it
comes to like finding bugs
i don't know if we're there yet i don't
think we have
the openness of how kind of like pros
especially approach targets
um that they would be willing to share
because that's propriet like that's
essentially their job
and they shouldn't be forced to share
that i should say i'm not gonna get
against them
that's totally fair for them um but i
think that represents a real barrier to
getting that type of machine learning
however there's a lot we can do with the
data we already have access to
you know we have hacker one publishes a
ton of disclosed reports
we have people who do write ups we have
bug bounty
uh tips on twitter we can't just think
of
what we might think as like our perfect
ai system as being
something that can hunt for bugs but
something that can do
say automated recon might be a really
nice
first step in doing this kind of task
but in a little bit of a different way
yeah it's interesting and switching
gears to to offense
um just talking about that a little bit
more because i think you know
when i i think was the last um last
stream that you and i are on together
and it's like oh we should talk about
aii
um through this lens of an nml
specifically through the lens of the
fact that like
we've gone and slapped it on just about
everything we can think of
as as you know the collective internet
over the past 10 years
uh and what tends to happen is when you
know that sort of product development
happens
you find out about five years later that
you forgot to do anything meaningful
when it comes to security so
yeah when you're talking about actually
attacking machine learning what what are
some of the things that you're
seeing be effective you know how do you
think about that i mean even as
a hunter so there's a really interesting
question in machine learning
at the moment in general which is what
is a bug
when it comes to machine learning
algorithms because we accept
machine learning algorithms will make
mistakes because they're not
perfect um often times they might
misclassify something
but here's the question what time is a
misclassification something a bug
if we look at say i don't know image
recognition
if we think about our classification
algorithm confusing a dog for a cat
no big deal if we confuse it for not
being able to recognize a person
it's a self-driving car that's obviously
a huge risk
and what part of poisoning that
algorithm can we do and this is kind of
a discussion that happens within
the um community at the moment like what
is a bug what isn't a bug what's a bug
we can actually
explore um one thing that i think is
really interesting is
kind of the combination of machine
learning and business logic
because machine learning plays this
really interesting part
in how applications work nowadays
and if you can kind of break the kind of
flow the same way you can do with most
with other bugs by getting a
misclassification
that's a that can be a security risk
depending on where where it appears
you don't always look for traditional
security bugs sometimes you have to look
something a little bit different because
machine learning works a little bit
differently
yeah i mean the the thing i've always
found fascinating about that
um is the idea of you know it basically
being untrusted input
like anyone who who's working security
for any period of time that the
alarm bells immediately start ringing as
soon as you
you see anything that looks like
untrusted input um
and the quintessential example is the i
think it was israeli research where they
spoofed the gps coordinates of a bunch
of android phones to basically cause
a pseudo traffic jam on the uh on the
peninsula that ended up rerouting
traffic
um and then just a really interesting
type of bug
yeah yeah well another guy did it just
recently um
in europe somewhere i can't remember
exactly where but he got a bunch of
phones put it in the back of a
like a little red wagon trolley thing
yeah i saw that
walked really slowly across the bridge
it's like that's that's technically a
machine learning attack it doesn't
fit into i think the normal paradigm of
computer science that we tend to think
about
in in bug bounty but it is basically
exploitation of a
you know assumption in a model that's
not resilient to that type of
abuse yeah and i think to add to that
not only do we see these kind of new
attacks we still see the same
bugs you know machine learning is not um
impenetrable um if you have uh
kind of dealing with images dealing with
kind of
any kind of pre-processing you're going
to hit like the traditional
exploits of you know xxe
or anything where you're messing with
entities you can define the same books
mess with image you might hear
image magic for example um so really
we both have to think about it as not
being that different
but also not being um like the same
which is a really interesting space to
be in i think
especially as kind of this is being more
operationalized now
in the actual like vendors and stuff
that's very cool
so if we're gonna move down this path of
of of taking advantage of ai what what
sort of data sources would need to be
available or what sort of data would you
look at to
to start training the models oh there's
so much you can do and it's going to
depend on what your expertise is
i am an nlp person i think
language is really cool for machine
learning and i'm going to go off and
lovely rant now
the web how many way we kind of
communicate with each other and we
interact with the world is through
language
we talk to each other we write long
documents
if we want to share our knowledge we use
language
and that means it's a great place to
train machine learning algorithms
because
actually it contains a lot of
information especially technical
information
now i am an nlp person my first instinct
is
let's look at the disclosed reports we
have loads of disclosed reports
um we have a bunch of bug bounty
write-ups what can we learn from those
let's look at doing kind of an
exploratory data analysis on what data
we have
you know how can we graph it what kind
of information do we have access to how
can we use it
that'd be my first kind of step somebody
who has computer vision
background might say something else
completely they might go for another
type
of uh looking at kind of behavioral
seeing if um you could record what
people are doing in some way
um that kind of thing there's a lot of
ways you can do it
yeah i wonder if a computer vision
person might even just take screenshots
and look at the screenshots and
determine what to do in a particular
application just from screenshots
yeah and especially if you look at um
when people tend to have like
include a poc include a screenshot as
well what they did
you know how much can we learn from
those there's so many different ways to
think about this
we really are like infants
we've got so much further we can go and
i would like
if you're listening to this and you
found what i'm saying is really
interesting or something you want to
pursue
go and pursue it because nobody else is
and
there's a lot you can do with what we
already have access to
that's awesome there's a interesting
question that's kind of coming
um from youtube in what you've
experienced with different models and
talk about different exploits have you
seen any
where you can essentially dos the intake
with a large image or a large data flow
like are there many input validation
kind of bugs that you're experiencing or
are they more in manipulating the
outcome of the data themselves
oh input manipulation is one of the
primary bugs you see
on main learning at the moment because
where
a regular application might only have
one stage of processing
um there is so much that happens with a
machine learning
it might go through you know go in
through a web server go into a python
script the python script then gets piped
into
so like go and then the go script gets
piped into r
um and you have so much like trent like
when you hit those kind of boundaries
you have another language of
bugs to look at so i think it's really
important also to consider that
machine learning algorithms tend to be
written in r and python
so if you want to kind of if your
application isn't written in
r or python most aren't um
they you're likely going to be in a
position
where you're having some kind of like
translation between the two
pieces of software great place to look
for bugs in that little gap
that's awesome so yeah so i guess
um kind of taking a step back from
bounties as well
um do you see this do you see like
competitive ctfs do you see
machine learning starting to take a rise
there or do you expect it to start to
take a rise in that space where
data might be a bit more constrained and
available but provides you a reasonable
degree of advantage um
i can see it but maybe only in
particular areas
even the kind of big companies tend to
focus their
like machine learning efforts in
separate areas at the moment we don't
necessarily
like somewhere like google is maybe
going to focus on
nlp because they have google translate
they have a lot of like search
functionality that requires a lot of nlp
experience
you'll have nlp people heading into
um the kind of security areas as kind of
domain experts basically
um so i think it really depends what
in-house talent they have
and you just can't predict what in-house
talent somebody else has
um so i'd say yes but we'll see
because like i said it's in the infancy
we just don't really know
in in terms of you know folks that are
watching this and and wanting to see how
that all evolves because you know i'm
thinking about
like the work that trailer bits have
done like the the cyber grand challenge
and all those sorts of
you know adversarial ai um very kind of
offense defense focused
uh events yeah do you have any any
places that you can point the audience
to to
kind of bone up on that i've got a
follow-up question around your own bug
hunting as well but just
on that part i would say any kind of
machine learning
if you're new at this data camp is the
place to go
it is the best way i think as someone
who's done like a looked at a few things
to learn it because if you pick up on
the academic textbooks
they do not start at the important parts
they start
at the like statistics and they
completely like
only focus on that so it's looking and
finding those places where you can
kind of find the practical uses of ai
i would say data camp is a great place
to start from there
it would be kaggle getting involved
seeing what data sets are available
practicing a lot of practice before you
can
then start to um
like build up models that might be
adversarial
and attacking defense for sure for sure
okay cool
and yeah i mean the following to that is
you know what if anything
have have you um you have you used
uh ml or ml concepts in your own bug
hunting
um if if so that would be great to hear
about if not as
is there you know projects that you're
aware of that you can point people
towards
oh um yeah so i'm working on
i'm working on a few tools at the moment
i'm not sure how much i want to say not
because i want to keep it
correct i don't want to promise anything
um but some of the cool tool like some
of the cool work i'm working on at the
moment
is looking at ways to predict
which vulnerabilities are going to
become
bigger so if we think about how
vulnerabilities work
we kind of get a curve almost right if
we're looking at sql injection as soon
as developers start to
defend against sql injection not just
leave it in there or they update their
software we see it go down
um comparatively and we can probably
plot that curve for other types of
vulnerabilities
so what you could do is you could find
figure out
when something's at the peak of its
curve and when it's
just rising up and it's just becoming
like the next big bug and some of the
other stuff i'm working on is about
recon
and especially the apis that use normal
worse
normal human words and looking at ways
you could for example look at the
marketing text of a website and figure
out
what their api endpoints might be
because they've shown off all of their
features and their lovely paragraphs of
text
with their love or or the inverse of
that and the css is just a little bit
janky and there's a few typos which
kind of suggests support code quality
underneath the hood
that sounds so much stuff you can do but
that's some of the stuff that i'm
working on i'm kind of working on a
suite of tools at the moment to kind of
do a bunch of the
ai stuff um i will release it
if it's operationalizable i'm not
promising anything at the moment to be
clear
for sure but stay tuned stay tuned still
exciting either way even
even putting that thought maybe not
releasing but it refines it for a future
something else i think it's it's awesome
there's um
so yeah we've got one more from discord
which sort of fits into the recent
recent chat um do you think machining
learning
could watch you back at all when you're
conducting in an engagement
um or alert you maybe when the blue team
is is on to you they've seen you your
payloads and
blocking your access is there any do you
think there's anything that
machine learning can help in in that
area
so i have a kind of general answer to a
lot of questions when people say
can machine learning do this if there is
data
and if there is an algorithm that can
match that goal
so if you're asking it to just classify
something like
uh is this likely to get caught or is it
not likely to get caught
or is this a sign that somebody's called
us
for example we're really looking at a
classification problem
um if you can boil it down to having the
data
and knowing which algorithm will solve
it machine learning
will be able to do it the problem is
will it be able to do it
well and i think that's a really
big kind of research question really not
just
for um when we like talk about bug
hunting but like research as in
academic research as well that we don't
necessarily know the question know the
answer to that
it's ongoing it's still something we can
look at
yeah that's uh that's fascinating
thank you very much katie this the whole
presentation was
was amazing um it was i learned learned
a lot and learned that i
i know nothing in this space so it was
it was absolutely fantastic
very much yeah i'll definitely have to
re-watch it probably four or five times
to
to pick up all the stuff i missed um but
no it was was fantastic
thank you uh so thank you man just a
reminder
that we are in the discord uh let's uh
let's make sure we give katie a huge
virtual round of applause
and uh nice nice shirt too by the way
katie thank you so you wrapping the
level up sure though
rock and rolling thank you so much thank
you there we go
you