I didn't think it was gonna work
hello
yeah you're projected here
hello everyone welcome
hmm
if you're coming for this session on sex
work we're starting now
hello
so
nice to meet you all it feels a bit like
a high school you know like some kind of
play or something with the lights and
everything so nice to meet you my name
is Luca Stevenson I'm a director of
programs at the European sex soccer
rights Alliance we are a European
network of around 100 organizations in
35 countries that work to protect the
rights of sex workers
and I will be sharing the the panel
today
we have a session with a really amazing
speakers sex soccer rights activist and
a researcher as well who will join us
online I will present them briefly I
just wanted to set up the scene a bit
before before we get into it
first of all thank you so much to enri
for having us here it's really exciting
it's the first time I think that we have
a whole panel on sex work at privacy
camp and it's a very important issue for
us and hopefully for you as well hmm
so uh as well as I was mentioning is a
sex worker LED Network we have the
various priorities including access to
health access to Justice racial Justice
labor rights decriminalization of sex
work and more recently we started to
focus as well on digital rights so we
know that the digital rise of sex
workers are critical issues which is
which are often overlooked by policy
makers and sometimes by other activists
as well and so when we try to put this
panel together we discuss of a title I
know when you try to put a session
together the title is the worst part and
you just leave it to the last minute and
you can't find it and it's two minutes
before the deadline and you're like okay
let's find something very clever and so
we were like oh in the eye of the storm
critical crisis mythical crisis and then
later we realized the eye of the storm
is usually the most quiet space of the
storm so our metaphor is a little bit
limited but actually if you look at us
and how calm we are maybe it does make
sense
so what we meant by the title is that
you know if you look at uh decades and
Decades of like policies and laws
affecting prostitution or sex work as we
prefer to use it the issue is that sex
work has always been conflated with
another issue which we call trafficking
in human being and so I want to just
before I give the the panel uh panelist
Mike I want to take you back to a
hundred years ago in 1910 where actually
the League of Nations came up with the
first International one of the first
International treaty and I don't know if
you know this but one of the first
International treaty was actually
developed by the United Nations so the
league of nation at the time to tackle
what was the biggest issue at the time
which was
I don't know if you know maybe somebody
know what was the first treaty white
slavery so
the issue was that it was so critical to
address the issue of white slavery that
we had to have all this nation come
together and create internationally
binding treaties in order to address
this problem and by wise slavery what
was actually meant was prostitution and
so when we look at the issue of
trafficking and the way it's been framed
internationally it's always been an
issue about uh you know controlling
prostitution and controlling migration
in particular and it has from the
beginning extremely racist underturned
if not completely overtly racist
overturned so if you look in the U.S in
particular like man Act was also a law
that was developed in 1910 the same year
in order to address prostitution but
this law was mostly used against black
men to arrest them in order to like
under the guise of like protecting white
women from prostitution so from the very
beginning of the development of laws on
trafficking sex workers sex work and
trafficking has been conflated and a
hundred years later 2022 what we see now
whether it's at the Council of Europe
the U.N level the European Parliament
this conflation of prostitution and
traffic can continue to be affecting sex
workers and this is what we're going to
talk about today as well as other issues
affecting sex workers
um I think that's all I had to say as a
setup uh so the three panelists today we
first have uh the amazing uh Kelly sudra
which is who is a sex worker a sex
soccer right activist she's also one of
the board members of eswa and she will
be
she will be speaking about her own
personal experience but also as well
about foster sister which she will
explain in more details and we then have
the you as amazing it adenov who is a
program officer on digital rights
[Music]
and it will uh discuss a bit the the
work we are doing at Israel on digital
right some of the key issues and some of
the successes that we we had and our
final speaker who will be on the the
screen
is Dr Elisa Red Mile uh from the Max
Planck Institute of software system and
I got the name right for once in my life
uh Elisa is a fantastic researcher we've
been collaborating on the research
together I really recommend reading some
of the research Elisa has been developed
with different partners very very
interesting on digital rights of sex
workers so I now give the mic to our
first Speaker Kelly thank you
thanks Luca hey everybody thanks for for
having me here today
um so as Luca said I'm a full service
sex worker so the things that I've
written today
um are from my own firsthand experience
and also the experiences of other
um colleagues in the field
um so I'd specifically sorry I'm gonna
read Because I get really nervous so I'm
gonna I'm gonna read some of the stuff
and I will also look up and and smile at
your lovely faces
um I would specifically like to address
like how digital Technologies are
critical for sex workers and how our
access to these Technologies is
prevented and how this impacts our
health and our safety well-being to
explain this I'm going to use the covid
crisis and how sex worker experience
this Health crisis as an example and
lastly I'm going to talk about certain
situations and the crisis rhetoric can
be used to attack sex workers rights as
we've been experiencing years for years
now
and and if we look at how human
trafficking is used as an excuse to
criminalize sex workers and to cut their
access to critical digital tools
so as many of you know the covet crisis
certainly pushed
um
many companies to accelerate to be
digitalized and it made us realize that
it is crucial to have access to digital
Technologies in this time
I don't think anybody really could have
predicted what was going to happen
but one thing that became clear with the
covet crisis is that the general
population and sex workers both had a
great need for digital Technologies
um it pushed sex workers to limits where
we had to look for new ways of working
because
um it was especially noted where there
was harsh lockdowns where they shut down
brothels and clubs saunas massage
parlors etc etc
so we couldn't leave our houses and we
had to go somewhere else
many sex workers found I mean also does
this work yeah
all right
many of us found that
um
that we had to find another way to find
income so a lot of us turned online so
big platforms like uh many vids and only
fans received a big influx of of new
people trying to find work as well not
just sex workers a lot of people that
lost their jobs during the pandemic also
were able to rely on sex work to help
pay bills because we weren't
um it was a kind of unprecedented times
we didn't know what to do
um and things so thanks to digital
technology sex workers had access to
tools and were able to you know sell a
lot of content or do shows or chat with
their clients and it was such a Lifeline
for most of us
so
um after I mean not after still during
covet we realized a lot of our work
could be digitalized and a lot of sex
workers are now being drawn even more to
digital Technologies than before
um there are some pros to digitally
mediated sex work the first and foremost
being less encounters with the police as
you probably know sex workers have
reported direct violence at the abuse to
the hands of police officers harassment
intimidation humiliation extortion
um just general physical and sexual
violence
and
um further criminalization also of their
jobs arrests or accusations for other
offenses so having
um kind of like a layer the internet
between us and the police I mean they're
still there obviously criminalizing us
but we didn't have to see them in person
was
um helped lower levels of violence
also another Pro about working online is
it was efficient and helped us save time
sex workers could work from our home a
place that we knew a safer environment
one that was familiar to us
um it also helped us have safer sex by
only having digital contact with clients
um helped us connect online with other
communities of sex workers have
conversations about important safety
concerns such as warning other sex
workers about potentially dangerous
johns or time wasters
sorry time wasting time wasters are the
worst
um
any other sex worker will agree with me
um it gave us a space to screen for
clients if you don't know what screening
is it's basically you know just asking
clients a few questions so you can have
like kind of like a digital Trail
um maybe their ID have their phone
number or their address or whatever this
is kind of hard to do in person while
doing street-based sex work it's not
impossible but it's harder to do
um also online it gave us a place where
we can advertise our services and just
put our policies which saves us time
instead of like having to tell everybody
you know it's just there on the internet
um and then working online gives us a
possibility to increase income and then
also allows us to have Community with
other sex workers so having spaces to
connect and then the problems with
digital
um Digital Sex work in my own personal
experience I'm just going to mention two
short ones Financial discrimination
uh we must rely on financial services to
get paid for our work
um so to do that we must abide by the
TOs in terms of service that are always
almost sex worker discriminatory so it
presents a problem if we can't use our
also it presents a problem by giving our
uh really private information out we
have to like you know
um use our real names to open up
accounts
um and it kind of puts us in a in a a
very difficult position
um big platforms like PayPal for example
are super discriminatory against sex
workers and um I'll go a little bit more
into detail that after and then online
censorship my favorite
I I know for those of you know that I
have been censored on all every single
platform even Tinder so
they censored me there too um no but
they censor me everywhere so like um
but censorship was a is a really big
barrier to sex work and it's also kind
of a confusing a confusing barrier
because of the algorithms that I I
personally don't understand how they
work I just know that they're very
racist and that they go after
marginalized identities for our own good
according to Big platforms like Tick
Tock and Facebook that openly admitted
to censoring bypoc
not too long ago the main problem though
being censored uh it seems like a silly
I mean
lots of people when I've complained
about censored being censored people
thought it like kind of gaslit means
like that's not that big of a deal it is
because if I don't if I'm not able to
advertise for my service online my work
I can't get I can't get a job I can't
pay the bills etc etc it also pushes sex
workers to to the very limits and the
margins and so if you can't get work
online where do you go you go to the
street which is
um where lots of sex workers face the
most amount of violence is on the street
um the more so
it is a big deal you know it's not it's
not just like some silly thing like you
know all right they deleted a post that
I made about whatever it's a really big
deal you know some of the recent years
there's been heavier restrictions online
and we might ask why is sex work so
censored on the internet
um it's a highly complicated question
with complicated answers but we could
start to describe the Why by explaining
two bills that were passed in 2018
sounds like a long time ago but they're
still having an effect in the United
States and they had an impact on sex
workers and internet censorship in
general worldwide
so uh you probably have heard of sestan
foster
um they sound good in in principle but
they're not that great
um there's a stop enabling sex
traffickers act which is Zesta and the
fight online sex trafficking act which
is Foster there are package bills that
were passed in April of 2018
um that made it illegal to publish sex
online they are designed initially to
censor online content in order to curb
sex trafficking they are meant to amend
the section 230 of the communications
decency act something that makes online
services immune for liability of their
users
um
and it would make section 239 applying
cases of sex trafficking so before
sister and Foster I'm sure maybe you
know this but I'm going to tell you
anyways
um websites and internet service
providers were not liable for their user
generated content posted on their
platforms including advertisement
comments forms etc etc without this
Clause exempting websites from liability
of their actions of their users most
websites couldn't afford to exist they
would just have to perpetually ward off
potential legal actions based on
inflammatory comments or unpredictable
behavior of their users
by devoting endless resources to
moderating everything the users did by
or by simply bending users activity
altogether by throwing millions of
dollars at litigation costs so now the
owner of any platform
um that pose content involving sexual
activity including consensual sex work
can be sentenced up to 25 years in
prison so foster ancesta amends this two
section the section 230 of the 1996
Communications decency act and
um to allow prosecutors to penalize
internet companies that promote or
facilitate prostitution so as a result
of system Foster major Pages were shut
down one of the biggest ones that was
shut down was uh one that was called
Backpage
I was a website basically where you
could advertise for your services and
get contacted by clients
um it didn't just help us meet resource
needs but also help to stay safer access
and Community being able to organize
those things that I said before about
the pros of doing online sex work so
Backpage was a vital tool for sex
workers and shutting it down could be
compared to that of a massive layoff
affecting providers all around the world
um it didn't just affect people in the
United States
taking away those tools obviously
affected the most marginalized
communities like the bipod community and
the 2s lgbtqi Community who are more
likely to face unemployment and housing
discrimination and more likely to rely
on sex work to survive
um when sex worker responded Mr Smarties
she said it's true that any system can
be abused but the idea that removing
sites that are is going to make someone
who is going to sexually abuse someone
say never mind is ridiculous it's a
child's view of the world
these bills have done so much damage uh
to sex work because they've basically
conflated sex work and trafficking which
are two separate things it pushes us all
into one corner and the more that we use
terms like teen prostitute instead of
using the word trafficked teen the less
we're actually solving the problem that
we claim to be you know concerned about
um
okay so how am I doing for time I'm
running out of time now um because
that's not created this kind of fake
crisis conflating sex work with
trafficking or child trafficking many
websites were sent into a full-blown
panic and they didn't want to be
conflated either or caught up in any you
know legal stuff so their response was
uh well we're gonna kick sex workers out
or anything related to sex so there was
an outcry of anti-sex worker groups
celebrities even jumped on the on the
bandwagon like Amy Schumer uh sorry I
won't get into her comment it was
ridiculous
um and they were like you know this
outcry about like you know what about
the children and you know
um if without these bills a child's
trafficking is going to run rampant you
know there's a lot of actions that took
place to make sure that sex workers were
de-platformed but really little action
to deal like to actually you know deal
with the problem that they were
um supposedly you know concerned about
to date actually this is really
important to date it's resulted in just
one Federal prosecution
according to the new report from the
government accountability offices are
they jail so basically there's been no
like it's not been useful at all and
actually a lot of people that were
pushing for this bill like to be passed
um they they gaslit sex workers saying
this is this isn't gonna with this isn't
meant to harm you but they knew that it
was going to harm us even though we said
we said it and um they haven't really
even been public about this one
prosecution because I think that they
they knew that this bill was just really
going after sex work and not after
trafficking because
um yeah there hasn't been any kind of
like you know any update about how
system first is working Etc et cetera
because it's not working
um another thing is payment processors
have become really strict with anything
that can be screwed construed to sex
work and social media Giants obviously
decided to crack down in any material
that can be interpreted at all could get
you deleted even you know a sexual Emoji
because they really Instagram or meta
said like even emojis in the sexual
nature and I'm like which Emoji is going
to be like the sexual you know what I
mean it was like anything could be
sexual nature like some Emoji smiling I
have no idea the Emoji that there's a
face you know like I have no idea you
know but anyways that could get you
deleted so as I mentioned before the
Digital Sex work really shaped for the
passing of these bills and um what if
says didn't force to have in common
um firstly they put sex workers in
danger cycling they threaten the whole
population in terms of privacy
violations and encryption as we heard in
the um the chat before
um
and then they made it also complicated
for anyone who marginal identity to have
a platform basically you know these
bills destroy destroy our right to
privacy Freedom digital rights
um they want to destroy all forms of
encryption and so nobody gets it
unscathed it's not just a sex worker
issue it's an everybody issue you know
um okay sorry how am I going oh two
minutes oh my God okay
I I don't like this at all
um okay so not far behind system Foster
only fans followed to try to get rid of
sex workers if you don't know only fans
as a platform that provides content for
a subscription service usually mainly
used by sex workers but also other
people can exist on there if you're a
chef and you want to sell your recipes
great good good for you
um no one's going to pay for that but
my only friends can come sue me now
before the pandemic this site generated
lots of income but obviously during the
pandemic everyone's at home with you
know some disposable income and lots of
time on their hands people bought porn
great that's amazing sex workers
um helped build only fans essentially
only fans would not be where it is today
without sex workers having like you know
broke their backs to for them to be
where they are and it was a critical
tool for us you know and then only fans
was triumphing booming in sales
everything seemed really great meanwhile
there was lurking this uh crisis that we
didn't know sex workers didn't know they
came with announcement this past August
19th that they would ban sexually no not
this past one the year before
um that they would ban sexually explicit
content on their main platform super
shocking because like again like I said
like who like what were they thinking
you know like who are they who's going
to keep paying for I mean everybody that
goes the only fans looking for
um specific sexual content and not like
you know recipes from some weird Chef
you know
um so anyways basically they they kicked
they were gonna they threatened to kick
sex workers off their platform
sex workers were outraged as well was
outraged
um and then like a few days later they
completely backtracked their statement
we're like oh we didn't mean it uh we
would never kick sex workers off our
platform they realized it was a big
mistake obviously they were going to
lose billions uh billions of euros and
um it wasn't they weren't really clear
they were kind of shady they said it was
Bank Banks basically
um that was the reason why that they
couldn't process the payments which was
later then they just magically found
another bank to work with they didn't
publicly comment on who they were
working with but yeah basically this
essentially um This Disaster is a very
real crisis for sex workers and can be
tied back to susten Foster
um a lot of companies Idol companies
were feeling the pressure MasterCard
also put on tighter regulations in 2021
around any content that's sexual
um so anyways uh yes only fans okay I'm
gonna read Ezra's statement and then I'm
gonna stop
so Ezra also published a statement after
only fans decided to try to ban us
um Ezra strongly condemns only fans
initial decision on imposing a ban on
explicit content on the platform this
disturbing and unfair decision caused
high levels of stress and uncertainty in
the sex worker Community although the
suspension of explicit content banned
can be considered a step in the right
direction
there's an urgent need to address the
underlying reasons of exclusion of sex
workers from digital platforms and
financial services among other things as
what demands that digital platforms
revoke anti-sex work policies and make
changes I make public apologies to sex
worker communities
um only fans kind of made a half-fast
apology they didn't really really care
that we were really stressed out and so
despite having to deal with a fake
crisis the conflation of sex work and
trafficking amongst the real crisis
covid sex workers wouldn't receive any
money from the government
um we didn't disappear after these bills
instead we've globally mobilized sex
workers and massive numbers we've
created new community-based
organizations based on our needs and
have done lots of research and during
the Copic crisis we received little or
no help from the government we created
Mutual Aid projects across the globe
We've Come Together in president's
situation to support each other and make
sure that we don't get left behind so to
summarize sex Works sex workers greatly
rely on digital tools to have safer
working conditions and the removal of
sex workers from these platforms and
tools only puts us a greater risk of
harm and precarity
we need to be listened to when we're
talking about grave laws being passed
about our work because Bill's accepted
and Foster had years of damage in our
community and continued to harm us they
could have been prevented if sex workers
were centered in these conversations so
going forward we need to make greater
efforts to Make spaces for sex workers
voices and lived experiences of
discrimination
thank you very much Kelly uh
I know it's okay and you will realize
that Kelly is one of these rare sex
workers when you book for 15 minutes you
get 25 minutes so that's really like you
know why we love Kelly is
professionalism and dedication to the
curse let's see if it is the same so now
it who is our program officer at eswa
thank you Kelly
hi everyone thank you so much Kelly for
this
very fun presentation so my name is it
and I am the program officer at asva
responsible for our digital rights
program
and uh this is first time as we're
participating at privacy Camp so I'm
very excited thank you so much adri for
organizing this amazing event and
inviting us
and
um I must say I thought it was very
fitting uh for Edward to set this year's
uh you know team as the constant state
of Crisis and also point out that the
digital is critical
um especially from sex workers point of
view you know because we feel like this
constant state of Crisis is the usual
way of living and just the normal state
of the world
if you're a sex worker
the infrastructures and tools that are
critical to sex workers are constantly
being attacked by actors who do not only
use legitimate crisis as opportunities
to push their agenda of excluding and
criminalizing sex workers but also
construct construct crisis for the same
purpose as Gadi mentioned
and sex workers
always had a very close in it it's very
intimate relationship with technology I
mean you know throughout this story sex
workers were one of the early adopters
of new communication Technologies in
order to you know communicate with their
clients and advertise their services so
sex workers use both print media and you
know other visual media very very fairly
early on which these sex workers then
became one of the first adapters of
Internet so in a sense they helped
develop the you know first versions of
Internet
as we know it but you know
so there has been many benefits of
digital tools for sex workers and today
they are definitely like an Inseparable
part of how sex work is conducted in
Europe and globally actually
however simultaneously sex workers are
being Stripped Away of these very
important tools
because you already mentioned her
experiences as a worker and how
platforms like only fans for example are
critical for sex work and how this
critical tool is being taken away from
sex workers by companies who constantly
undermine sex workers rights and exclude
them from their services even during
actual state of Crisis such as kovid
of course private Act is often you know
base their actions uh that undermine sex
workers rights on the existing legal
Frameworks and this legal Frameworks or
the lack of appropriate appropriate
legal protection for sex workers are the
enablers of companies and platforms
discriminatory and harmful policies
so as mentioned for example foster
sister is a good example of how the
rhetoric on the human trafficking crisis
is utilized and hijacked by
anti-trafficking organizations in
collaboration with right-wing
evangelists in the US
2D platform sex workers leaving sex
workers no space to Breathe No Room for
self-expression and no possibility to
generate income
and
um
so all foster sister did was to put sex
workers livelihoods health and safety in
danger and the conflation of trafficking
and sex work is detrimental to
fundamental human rights of sex workers
and we have seen this repeatedly
happening over the years for example
some politicians keep referring to sex
work advertising platforms where sex
workers put their ad in contact with
their clients so it's their online
workspace of sex workers
we see again again politicians referring
to these websites is essentially
important websites as trafficking
websites
so this is of course you know purposeful
framing of these play workplaces as
something that they are not instead of
acknowledging the importance of an
actual purpose of these platforms they
are framed as trafficking websites to
manipulate public opinion to get these
platforms to shut down so it's an
ideological war on sex work and
pornography that unites certain branches
of famous movements and right-wing
extremists which is mind-blowing
uh we believe that abusive working
conditions can happen in any sector work
can be degrading and workers may find
themselves in exploitative working
conditions
no matter what they do so the difference
here is that workers normally have
rights that they can pursue right
because sex work is not
recognized as work and is heavily
criminalized when this abuse happen
happens in sex industry sex workers have
nowhere to go so the for us the real way
to fight the exploitation in the sex
industry is therefore to Grant rights to
sex workers like New Zealand does and
there isn't the Belgium took a step
towards the conversation of sex work
which we upload
of course sex workers rights are also
attacked by those with no apparent
agenda of criminalizing sex work and in
these cases the harm mostly arises from
actors who might have good intentions
however due to lack of Engagement with
sex workers and other marginalized
populations sex workers end up being
collateral damage in the policy making
process
so a fairly recent example of this was
the Digital Services act
where the European greens proposed an
amendment
with the support of victims rights or
organizations working on the issue of
image-based sexual abuse so
non-non-consensual sharing of images
and Amendment 24b that's what it was
called if except it would have made it
mandatory for platforms that host
user-generated pornographic content to
verify users by collecting their phone
numbers and verified email addresses so
that police could track down the
potential perpetrator based on the data
they provided
so image based abuse is certainly an
important issue to tackle and it is part
of a wider structural problem which is
violence against women
and it is also a fact that many sex
workers are victims of image-based abuse
it can be you know clients downloading
and distributing our images or using
them to Blackmail sex workers and for
extortion it can be other platforms and
websites that collect and create
everything content stealing you know sex
workers as pictures from their own
website to put their own website to
drive traffic basically
so it's a problem that is highly
relevant to sex workers but we fought
against this amendment for several
reasons first of all we advocate for
data minimization especially when
working with marginalized communities
increase data collection and processing
is a threat to privacy and as well as
coming to research on privacy as well as
other many research shows that
protecting privacy and data is crucial
to ensure the safety of sex workers
privacy acts as a protective barrier and
um when privacy is lost sex workers
report that they experience harassment
blackmailing lose their accommodation
and Face-Off face
threat of deportation
secondly there was no reason to believe
such additional data collection measures
would prevent image-based abuse the fact
is that the vast majority of porn
platforms are already collecting
horrifying amounts of sensitive data
like Kelly said you know when sex
workers are registered on these
platforms they have to send their
passport copies they have send their ID
copies they have to send their selfies
in order to you know show the platform
look it's me and they have to sign
consent forms with their real names so
all these horrifying amounts of data
sensitive data is collected and stored
by the platforms so it wasn't clear for
us how collecting even more data of sex
workers would actually you know stop
image-based abuse if collecting the
passport copies didn't stop the image
based abuse
finally as I explained sex workers are
one of the populations to experience
image-based abuse and it is their online
workplace this amendment directly aimed
to regulate so in this case it was clear
for us that sex workers should have been
consulted as priority stakeholder but
that wasn't the case
we also argued that the non-consensual
sharing of images occurs on every
platform online and it is not limited to
porn platforms so this amendment ended
up being discriminatory against sex
workers at that time you were saying
following their logic if it makes sense
it would make more sense to ask every
internet user to disclose their
sensitive data on every platform
but unfortunately you know of course we
didn't want this but now there are
concerning policy proposals at EU level
that threaten the privacy of everyone
and not just sex workers which is you
know one of them is child sexual abuse
regulation
so as I'm sure many of you heard of this
proposal even if you are not directly
working on it European commission
proposed prepared a proposal that would
will allow sales providers to scan
private conversations in order to
supposedly the text child sexual abuse
material and prevent the further
distribution of this material
and through this regulation once again
we see the trend of pitting fundamental
human rights such as right to privacy
against you know important issues like
the protection of minors continues in
addition we against it over Reliance and
trust or trust in technological
solutions to tackle uh you know
structural societal problems as sex
worker rights Network that work on
topics like privacy and data protection
of marginalized communities we are
extremely worried about this regulation
because it is not currently in line with
fundamental human rights and the use of
automated systems to detect such content
we believe is going to create lots of
false positive results which will
increase the chances of sex workers
becoming in contact with police officers
which are the one of the you know
perpetrator of violence against sex
workers
and it is also very damaging to the
human psyche to feel like every move you
take is surveilled by private
corporations and governments alike even
if the part of your identity or the work
you do is not criminalized like sex
workers
what this regulation tells us is that
it's variable leak I think that's
you know we are not able to find ways to
tackle these issues and manage crisis
without treating some portion of the
population as collateral damage so csam
regulations nothing less than Mass
serving's practice for us which doesn't
even do much in terms of protecting
children and we find it find it very
disproportionate and there is no legal
basis for imposing this level of
servings on everyone without reasonable
suspicion
um finally I'm gonna just mention One
National level development that is very
concerning and use that uses this crisis
rhetoric that politicians loves to use
which is Online safety bill in the UK
uh uh so this so-called Online safety
bill in the UK is a prime example of how
legitimate intention of protecting
children from online time is again
utilized to increase online surveillance
to further push online service providers
to discriminate against sex workers so
it is very similar to the foster sister
actually and the effect impact they will
have will be again very similar to
foster sister so it essentially makes
sex work content it defines sexual
content as harmful content and there is
a line in the bill saying that
controlling prostitution for gain is a
criminal activity but controlling
prostitution for gain is interpreted
very widely in the criminal courts Our
member organization in the UK the
English Collective of prostitutes
reports that some women have been
prosecuted under this offense just for
helping a friend for example build a
website or place an advert online so
companies who aim to avoid any potential
liability will make the move to D
platform not only sexual content and sex
workers as you know accounts but
possibly all erotic and sexual content
so the result will be as devastating as
for Success so the recap and finance I
just wanna
make three points first of all is
so there are legitimate crises that we
are facing today and it is crucial uh to
have a you know robust police landscape
that seeks to address these very
important issues however we should be
aware that when there's crisis
uh there are always people who use those
crises to exploit our feelings to push
their own agenda
we should therefore have a very critical
mind when we are facing politicians and
other actors who use overly emotional
and alarming language to push for their
agenda such as you know increasing
surveillance for example
my second point is that tackling techno
solutionism is very important
for us we are aware that technology has
a very important space when we are
trying to come up come up with you know
solutions to our problems however techno
Solutions and we see today is especially
in the voice making is like okay we you
know build this fancy algorithm or you
know we collect lots of more data and
then everything will be fine we don't
have to do anything else obviously it
doesn't work we are therefore advocating
for structural solutions that address
the root cause of societal problems so
technology won't have a meaningful
impact on this we try to tackle racism
poverty talk about borders and lack of
education for sex workers for example
the starting point is the
decriminalization of sex work which
would Grant labor rights to sex workers
and help effectively fight human
trafficking violence and exploitation in
the sex industry finally ethical
inclusive and fact-based policy making
is needed more than ever today there is
a lack of ethical post-making at both
National and EU level where policies are
being drafted amendments are put forward
like DSA
without doing the exercise of matting
mapping out stakeholders and to then
initiating conversations with these
stakeholders only by being truly
inclusive we can lay out effective laws
it is also equally important that the
different stakeholders in an issue uh
talk to one another and actively seek
ways to collaborate to this end as well
has initiated a process that aims to
tackle image-based abuse issues
collaboratively with other stakeholders
for example and as the first step of
this process we partnered up with the
Max Planck Institute in a research
project that's Elisa will discuss I
think next thank you so much for
listening
[Applause]
thank you so much Eid we can talk a bit
more after as well about some of the
program we are doing I'll mention as
well this multi-stakeholder dialogue we
will be developing with adri as well and
Elisa will be part of and I now give the
floor to Elisa thank you
thanks Luca
um thank you I will end up echoing uh in
some ways a number of the things uh that
have been said before me
um so as Luca had introduced on a
faculty member at the Max Planck
Institute and I run a research group
where we have been uh working with sex
working communities and looking at the
role of digital technology in sex work
for the past um five years and I come
out of the field of computer security
and so what brought me to this work was
feeling like the tools that we were
building as technologists and the
research we were doing as computer
scientists particularly in security I
was not necessarily addressing the needs
of sex working communities and other
marginalized communities for a number of
reasons that have already been raised on
this panel
so a lot of our work has involved doing
hundreds of paid interviews uh with
different types of sex workers all
around the world uh to understand sex
workers safety goals the risks they're
facing their strategies for coping with
those risks and the goal of our work is
really to try to understand how
technology can start stop hurting and
start helping
um people achieve their their labor
goals
um and so some of our our initial work
uh started out with in-person workers in
Germany Switzerland and the UK
um and then has progressed to look at
folks who are doing either in person or
digital only work uh in the U.S and in
other regions around the world in
addition to looking at kind of folks
labor practices and the role of
Technology and Safety technology and in
that we have also done a bit of work on
understanding kind of the the harms and
measuring the efficacy of some of the
anti-trafficking solutions that are out
there um so to offer one example
and the United States in particular as
well as in other regions and there was
sort of this idea that oh if we you know
do these unsolicited text messages uh so
if we scrape sex worker advertisements
we put that data in a database and then
we text people and by we I don't mean us
but we being some some organization uh
we text people and we ask hey are you
being trafficked
um that maybe this would be a good way
of stopping trafficking
um and as might be intuitive this is not
a good way to stop trafficking and the
organizations that do this themselves
say that they get less than a five
percent response rate to these texts
um and also of course the scraping is a
privacy violation and it can be quite
dangerous for folks right so folks are
not always sole owners of their phones
and the person they share a device with
may or may not know that they're doing
um sex work and so getting one of these
texts links that information the texts
are often also very stigmatizing and
harassing and might have religious uh
information in them all of which can be
triggering and uncomfortable and
emotionally harmful so there are a lot
of harms that can come from this kind of
Outreach and also very little benefit
even
um partly organizations themselves and a
lot of times the the data that gets
scraped is actually sold to non-profits
so people are kind of profiting off of
this uh scraping of sex workers
information
um so that's sort of an example of work
that we do where we'll
um work with the impacted Community to
kind of understand you know how is this
harming you and then try to convince
technologists not to do uh these kinds
of things on the positive side we also
partner with organizations
um like eswa on topics like intimate
image abuse as eat
um was introducing so before we get to
talking about our current work on
intimate image abuse I wanted to touch
on a couple of findings from kind of the
hundreds of interviews that we've done
with sex workers over the years
um the first is sort of largely echoing
um what kalyani have mentioned
um sex workers right are forced to use
Technologies and platforms that don't
take into account their business or
privacy needs
um and as someone who came out of the
the US originally I sometimes got
pushback that was like oh well the work
people is are doing you know isn't legal
here and and so you know maybe it's okay
that platforms don't support it right
but a lot of the workers that that we
work with right and this won't be a
surprise in the European context are
working legally are paying taxes are
registered to work where they are and
yet they still can't use digital payment
Technologies or they still get kicked
off of Airbnb even if they're using
three different phones where one of them
is dedicated for Airbnb to try not to
get kicked off
and that's really kind of an imposition
of one particular kind of framework
um which certainly I disagree with but
still it's an imposition of one
country's framework on other countries
and other workers in those countries
um and so it's really kind of not the
case that at least as far as I can see
there's a justification for not taking
into account people's business needs let
alone at safety and privacy needs um
for their work and so examples of issues
that we've seen facing workers as
mentioned are de-platforming from all
different kinds of platforms regardless
of the legal status of the work being
performed
um folks being outed or doxxed uh being
harassed which can spill into real life
right so it's not the case that just
because something happens online it
never makes it into kind of real world
context it absolutely does
um Financial harm particularly from the
platforming from Financial platforms
content theft as we've mentioned and
then also burnout right and this is
something that has been touched on a
little bit in this panel but of course
the pandemic made a huge change in how
people were doing labor both for folks
who are already doing sex work as well
as for folks who came into the industry
during the pandemic and while kind of
echoing a Cali's notes
um you know folks were safer from
distance from police
and distance from kind of physical
interaction and we also see that it
changed people's digital portfolios so
they were telling us well you know
compared to when I was doing
say only in person work I'm finding that
I have to be online on more platforms I
have to be sharing kind of more content
people are wanting to have like a richer
online persona for me
um and I might be having to be like a
little bit more explicit or more visible
online like maybe I used to be able to
not show my face but now there's so much
competition in this online only space
and a little bit of difference in
um sort of what folks are looking for
that that's a much harder thing to make
viable business-wise so people are kind
of finding themselves more online in
more places putting more content being
more explicit and that raises some of
the the digital concerns that you might
have particularly around like content
theft right finding your content
um places that you don't want it to be
and so a couple of quotes
um we've had from participants that
maybe give a little bit of color uh to
these experiences are in one of our
studies a participant said you know I
took a selfie in a public restroom and I
uploaded that to a social media site and
there was a guy that went to the same
bathroom and posted a selfie of him in
that bathroom directly undermine like I
know where you are and so that kind of
stalker things are the ones that make me
more scared
uh another participant said you know the
platforms or Platforms in general are
the this thin ice that I'm walking on
and at one point it's going to break and
everything is just gonna go you know to
Hell uh and I'm gonna fall through and
this is sort of a common
um sentiment among hundreds of people
that we've talked to is these platforms
are thin ice and they also sometimes are
facilitating harms like the first one
right they're they're really showing
your content to everyone which in some
ways is good
and in other ways is not so good because
people uh don't always behave in the way
that we wish toward other people
so our goal is to change how technology
is built in order to try to improve
safety and we do this through a number
of different Partnerships uh but the one
that I'll touch on today is the work
they eat and Luca mentioned which is a
set of research and design projects to
try to develop features for preventing
intimate image abuse
um so intimate image abuse uh has
probably what I'd say like three
different components
um and what we are focused on is folks
who are consensually producing images
whether for recreation uh so like
sexters or for labor
um like digital sex workers and so
they're consensually creating the image
we're not focused on
um kind of non-consensual whether it's
like secret recording Etc
um consensually creating the image
they're sharing it somewhere posting it
somewhere but then it's finding they're
finding that image uh being spread
outside of wherever they initially
posted it right and I think there's
sometimes this misconception that's like
oh if you've posted your image on only
fans you must be okay with it appearing
anywhere else on the internet and that's
not true right both because you
consented to have it typically behind a
paywall for your subscribers on only
fans or in the case of recreational
folks on a particular
platform one-on-one chat group chat
whatever it was and two in the case of
content
um for commercial purposes it's theft
right if someone takes your content and
posts it somewhere else you're losing
money because they're getting the money
from people buying your content or from
the clicks or the ads or what have you
so you both have the emotional and
privacy violation uh with potential kind
of physical harm stemming from that and
you have Financial harm because this is
tough
um and so in this work what we have done
is thus far we've connected uh conducted
57 interviews
um with different groups of folks so
we've done interviews with sex workers
and with sexters and about half of each
of our interviews with those groups have
been with folks who are victim survivors
of intimate image abuse and then we've
also spoken with organizations that
support victim survivors so these are
organizations that people might turn to
after they've had images stolen from
them and the organizations will work
with them to help support them in
reporting the content trying to get it
taken down and they may also provide a
kind of mental health and other Support
Services
and our goal in these interviews is to
understand
um very much the technological aspects
so sort of like what technologies are
people using to create store and share
their images
um what are their kind of current
defense strategies if they have any
um for these kinds of attacks and then
what are their dream kind of design
features how would they like the
Technologies to work in order to better
protect their content and that's
something that folks sometimes have
really clear ideas about and other times
they have really clear concerns but not
necessarily clear design ideas and
that's sort of where our role as
researchers is is to come in and try to
figure out how might we prototype things
that might work for folks and then we
come back to the community to do what's
called participatory design where we
kind of co-design and co-create tools
that may be useful and then eventually
bring in
um you know technology platforms or
technology designers to really figure
out like how do we get this into the
technology
and so our results in this project are
sort of still emerging we're still
actively doing work
um but I'll share out uh some of the
highlights that we have so far
uh the first thing we learned from from
the 57 interviews we've done is that
really any technology that you can use
to send and store images or videos is
being used for intimate content
um so this could be anything at all from
like Dropbox to local storage on a
device to Discord to kick to very
specific
messaging Platforms in a particular
country to Reddit like anything that you
can use for image and video capture
storage and sharing
um folks are using and people are scared
about
um you know their fears around having
intimate image abuse happen are around
you know embarrassment from things
coming out being blackmailed being outed
this could be outed as a sex worker or
outed in terms of your sexuality or your
gender
um people are afraid of or have been
doxed and then also of course Financial
loss for folks who are selling their
images
and videos
um and at a high level one of the things
we see from a technology side is image
and video data is really treated with
insufficient sensitivity right so a lot
of times the protections for image and
video data are basically the same as
Text data but image and video shares a
lot more personal information and has a
lot more sensitivity particularly given
um that people aren't kind of using you
know one of three platforms for for
intimate content they're using every
platform and so that means the image and
video content on every platform is
sensitive and the re-sharing of that
content is sensitive
um and there's this theoretical idea in
Academia of contextual Integrity which
is basically that people's kind of
privacy concerns are very much focused
on who I shared it with why I shared it
and
um what I who I expect to be able to
receive it outside of who I shared it
with and so this is sort of a perfect
case study where people are intending to
share content you know even non-internet
content with a particular audience and
then finding it in a completely
different audience being used
potentially for a different purpose than
whatever their intent was originally and
that's very violating
so how are people trying to defend
themselves
um they are removing identifying
features from their images so this might
be face tattoo
Etc
um they're also doing screening and
vetting right colleague kind of
mentioned screening and betting
um for in-person work people are doing
the same thing for sharing images
they're also kind of creating like
hierarchies of trust based on how well
they know someone
um or know a particular a client or a
friend or whoever it is or a particular
group
um to figure out what they're willing to
share kind of at different levels of
that trust
um one of the things that's come up is
how do I handle kind of expiration right
sometimes I trust you and then you
violate my trust there's currently no
way to really get my content back from
you right or to kind of continually be
checking in on on whether I still feel
the same way about this particular
sharing
space or interaction as I did you know
three months ago uh the other thing that
that people are doing is is they're
resigned right they're telling us well I
just assume that my content is public
and I just sort of operate with that
assumption and I'd say there's a lot of
sort of internalized victim blaming that
that folks
um are sort of exhibiting where they're
like oh well I guess it's my fault you
know if I choose to share content or I
choose to to do this kind of Labor
um and that and that sort of victim
living is also in a way encoded in the
technology right by this sort of
assumption that like well we're not
going to do anything to sort of protect
your content it's just gonna go wherever
and you know it's your fault if you
shared it instead of putting the the
responsibility on the platform for
saying no you know it's your
responsibility to make sure my my
content stays where I shared it which is
on your platform and not somewhere else
or in this particular conversation on
your platform and not somewhere else
Elisa uh so to that end okay we just
have a couple minutes more for your
presentation so then we have 15 minutes
for the Q a okay thank you perfect yes
we're on the last slide
um so the dream designs
um that folks had focused around being
able to automate metadata removal right
so folks didn't necessarily want people
to be able to look in the metadata for
an image uh or video which you can do
and see kind of the the location where
it was taken the time stamp Etc
um people want this both for privacy and
also because if you are doing commercial
work you may want uh clients to think
that an image was just taken when you
might have done it as part of a photo
shoot you know a few days ago
um people also want flexibility in how
they are able to control their data
depending on different levels of trust
um they would like content tracking as
well as detection of content appearing
elsewhere and notification education
about that so really trying to kind of
automate this flow and they would like
safer storage there really has not been
a lot of emphasis on tools or platforms
really to support this use case at all
but particularly to support storage
um and so I'll close with a quote from
from one of our participants in this
work who said I would like to have full
control on what I'm posting on these
apps when the elements for controlling
data appear how uh on a general page or
a private one uh to I would like to
protect metadata and ensure that my
account is safe I would like you know
one of those options when people can't
right click on our pictures all of these
are reasonable and relative many of them
are relatively simple technical requests
right and so you know what can we do on
this problem what we can do on this
problem is view sex workers and um
everyone who who creates and shares
intimate images as stakeholders users
and creators who have digital rights who
have privacy needs who have intellectual
property rights not as you know
criminals or victims or spam right these
are stakeholders who are core users of
your platform and folks who ought to be
uh supported in their rights as users
and content creators and with that I'll
hand it back to Luca thank you so much
Elisa
and Elisa slides will be available I
think on the Privacy Camp website they
were really good slides but we couldn't
show them so we have a little bit of
time for a few we do we
10 minutes
okay so we have around 20 minutes for
like either questions to the audience
and uh to the speakers or comments maybe
I don't know if there are more mics so I
give this one
please raise your hand
um
hi
yeah my name is international I have one
question that I would like to know how
much you see the growing uh religious
integrism that is in the U.S now with
your tax against abortion that's a core
of a lot of things because it seems that
a lot of them come from the US and if
that change depending on the platform
especially where the platform is from
oh sorry
um yeah how much the growing like
religious integrism that there is now in
the US and we see the attack against
abortion how much that is at the core of
the first time sister lows and how much
does that affect platforms differently
based on where they are from
hello yeah okay yeah completely I mean
obviously
um a lot of the the people that were
anti-sex work also happen to be
um super pro-family and what about the
children so I mean yeah we did
um we did see that as a big impact and
and obviously whatever is in the states
people think like oh yeah it's only it's
only American it's only going to affect
Americans but it did have a worldwide
impact because I mean uh people were
allowed to use Backpage all around the
world and actually it was used a lot in
Europe as well so yeah I would say that
I mean
um we did see that big connection and a
lot of those anti-sex work people also
happen to be like um anti-abortion it
kind of seems like all mixed in together
there also happen to be anti-trends I
mean like I always I always say that
it's really impossible to be sex work
exclusionary radical feminists what they
call themselves
um they think they're radical feminists
and it's impossible to be like a sex
worker exclusion a radical feminist and
not be transphobic so then you're also
kind of a trans exclusionary radical
feminine or whatever they call
themselves so yeah swerves and turfs
kind of go hand in hand and the same
thing with like people that are um
anti-abortion also happen to be you know
I mean they're you're against any of uh
like a person having
um uh full
um capacity over their bodies and
deciding what they can do so obviously
it makes sense that those things are
tied I think or Luca you want to say
something yeah a feeling is like a
growing amount of evidence about the
like impact of religious groups and like
Reproductive Rights in particular you
know uh right to abortion Etc and
there's less information about like the
relation with sexual but we have like
lots of evidence for example in the UK
you got an organization called care
Christian action research and education
which is like a million pound-funded
religious organization who's doing
direct lobbying to the UK government and
for example they were supporting bills
to criminalize the clients of sex
workers but also pushing for like you
know repeal of like gay rights or trans
rights and Reproductive Rights Etc as
well like Kelly Kelly was saying is that
it's really shocking for often we put
the blame on like feminist part of the
feminist movement when it comes to
criminalization of sex work in Europe
and we know that feminist organizations
have a big impact on in particular the
Swedish model like the Swedish model is
the model where clients are criminalized
in order to abolish prostitution but
actually we know that these laws
wouldn't be passed if they were not
supported by a big part of like
religious groups and right-wing and
left-wing uh parties so if you look at
Ireland for example in Ireland the main
organization that is providing services
to sex workers currently is called
ruhama rouhama is a religious
organization who has the same nuns on
the board than the Magdalene laundries
so we don't have time to go into
Magdalene laundries now I don't know if
you know anything about it Magdalene
laundries where a religious Institution
for foreign women during like the
beginning of the century until the like
the late 60s I think and they were
responsible for like lots of traumatic
like I don't know if you Lawrence you
want to speak about it like there is
really like still a very clear link
between religious institutions such as
ruhama in Ireland or movement in France
and many others and other organizations
that push for criminalization and then
directly benefit from it because then
the government makes funding available I
know in France where we are like so loud
about secularism and basically so
islamophobic so essentially there's no
problem to work with the Catholic
organization in order to like
criminalize sex work and I feel like the
main one if you want to look into it in
the U.S if you look at Exodus Cry Exodus
Cry is unbelievable is this like extreme
religious organization who does things
such as purging against trafficking
where they organize Global prayer
against trafficking where we also ask
for donation and then use this money and
Exodus Cry is one of the actors
responsible for the whole campaign
against PornHub and what Kelly was
thinking about only fans like the whole
push to have MasterCard stopped working
with only fund for example is by Exodus
Cry and other actors like Ashton or
whatever his name is Ross
I have been identified already
you're the processor in this case uh uh
hi I'm lohos from dff and my question is
because uh Luca you mentioned in the at
the beginning the the racist uh origins
of the Abolitionist Movement as well
um how the question of like access to
digital rights is also uh to be
differentiated in relation to race but
then also to to access to uh legal
documents because a lot of the things
you said also Cali is how people need to
identify and give their passport and
things like that and I just wanted to
hear more about like how that might also
be exclusionary to people who can't do
that for obvious reasons
yeah I mean collection of uh you know ID
copies and passport it's a real problem
that we are actually quite against this
kind of this way of age verification age
verification is important yes so we all
agree on that definitely so we want our
workspaces including online workspaces
to be as safe as possible
however there are no different
ways to verify age at the moment that
platforms use and you know the easiest
option to go for is of course let's just
collect all the data we can and then you
know we can then store this data however
we want and then we can use this data
however we want we have no idea how they
do that
um but it does end up excluding actually
mostly migrants and uh you know
individuals who are in the you know
migration process they may have lost
their passport you know or they don't
have the right work permit for example
some platforms even go beyond asking for
ID copies they ask for work permits like
they want to see your work permit
especially if you are a person of color
so if your photo is you know not white
enough they you know have the intense
incentive to ask more questions like
this and it is a real problem that
excludes migrants from basically
generating income which makes them more
vulnerable than to violence and you know
then they have to go to pimps you know
or third parties who you know facilitate
the sex work for them because they can't
do it by themselves so yeah
oh yeah so and also again like you said
that this um like different
differentiated access also to the
internet one of the things I I didn't
have enough time because I was being
pressured um to say during the during
the crisis is that
um also there's a lot of sex workers
that couldn't access the internet I mean
because maybe they should or maybe they
showed a flat where they had you know a
lot of you know other
um people they were sharing the fight
with or people that just didn't have
access or the funds to to have these
platforms but again like you said the
platforms do require that you be legal
that whatever that means you
know
um to be able to access a platform so
even if we even if we were like for
example in a country like
um like Switzerland or Switzerland and
Brussels Brussels Belgium oh my God
Brussels is a country
um Belgium or New Zealand where sex
workers decriminalized you still have to
be legal to like migration is still
criminalized so you still have to be
legal to like able to access those
platform platforms as sex workers so we
see decriminalization still has it's not
I mean it's not all that glamorous
because again it still leaves out the
most marginalized people which are
migrants so yeah even in countries
um like
um like Belgium or New Zealand still
have this problem again you know like
even if you have only fans or many vids
you can't have it unless you have a um a
passport that's uh in Vigor or a work
permit
we're having like this in some of the
reports like so mentioning here we have
a couple of reports on a privacy and
censorship uh written by eswa and I feel
like there was some specific example of
undocumented migrants who want to be
able to advertise in a country like the
UK for example so in the UK you have a
main platform called adult work where
tens of thousands of sex talkers are
advertising and it's the main way to
make an income if you work in the sex
industry in the UK at least like on
digital platform and undocumented
migrants need to find a way to advertise
there so what they would do some of them
would find a third party and say like
you know what I'll do it for you I'll
find a way to hack the system to use a
fake ID Etc but I'm going to take 30 of
your income and I will decide this
information on your platform your rates
for example when you work etc and we are
talking with sex okay we're saying like
we're not able to get out of this
because I only wanted to sell sex for a
few months and now my advertisement is
still there and I'm still receiving fun
Etc from clients Etc so I think there's
a real issue where all these laws even
the laws that are like defined as like
trafficking or in Germany the price
Institute prostitution protection act
all these law are designed to protect
sex workers but I've never developed
with sex workers and in particular with
marginalized migrant racialized lgbtqi
sex workers were more at risk and often
this law that are meant to protect us
without talking to us in the first place
actually making us more vulnerable and
more at risk of exploitation by Third
parties in particular and there's a lot
of similarity with like many of the
discussions we have around like
undocumented migrants in general if you
want undocumented migrants to be safe
just make it easier for migrants to come
here there is no other way for migrants
to be safe making it more difficult by
you know creating like more like less
Pathways to come to Europe in particular
will make it like more risky for
migrants and it's exactly the same for
sex workers and platforms
[Applause]
there's a few more questions just one
more one more
please identify yourself too much yeah
okay hi I'm Ali sibai from uh
uh I just want to ask if since like
during the covert pandemic
again since sex workers have adapted or
adopted a
online tools more often so did this
actually
facilitated law enforcement Crackdown on
sex workers through using tracking them
through iptu location or like did this
happen like help law enforcement or
facilitated for law enforcement to do
Crackdown on sex workers as a deputants
of sex anti-sex trafficking and so on
follow-up question new advice like
sexual workers to use like vpns to
protect their geolocation and so on
thank you
if it's the last question we can take
and then we try to respond so
hello my name is vitaria I'm an activist
from Brazil and my question is also to
collect maybe perspectives on how we
could create financial instruments to
not fill in these lives of these persons
but also filling out movements
sorry I'm not sure I understood the
question
it's a way how you could create
financial instruments to make the money
flows to these persons but also filling
our movements like discriminalize
abortion sexual worker and so on
by creating financial instruments that
don't rely you want to answer the police
Elisa did you hear the question as well
okay yes so I give you basically uh you
can all say a few words either directly
responding to the question or final word
that you might have wanted to say on the
dance and then we can close the
financial instruments yeah I'll just
quickly respond to that I mean it's
really hard because the terms of
services are super anti-sex work so if
there's somebody with a lot of money
that wants to create an app that's sex
worker friendly or if not I mean one of
the things that I've been doing as a
survival based sex work is just finding
somebody a third person a very good
friend who would be able to accept
payments for me and use their ID and
their like PayPal account or whatever
although I have got my friend's PayPal
account shut down by accident even
though I didn't say anything about sex
work I just said English lessons and
still got shut down so finding third
third parties I mean isn't the isn't the
kind of solution but that's what I've
been doing because I haven't been able
to find an app that's actually
um that I don't violate the terms of
service so you're always kind of like
you know
um trying to jump from app to app and
not try to keep too much money in any of
the apps if you doing Digital Sex work
but yeah I don't know if there's anybody
here that has a better a better solution
but that's what I'm doing for now
um I can answer if we are suggesting sex
Works to use VPN and stuff like this so
digital security is of course the
important part of uh you know it's one
of the ways I think to uh try to fight
back uh and I do personally find them
important but uh you know there are lots
of things to consider so are these tools
are accessible enough for example are
they cheap enough are they uh you know
do they have multiple languages are they
you know easy to navigate
so these are all important uh and it
does leave some sex workers out of these
systems basically
but also I feel like technology changes
really passed and you know uh
you know technological artifacts are
always you know reimagined and you know
people find ways around Technologies you
know to overcome the barriers they
basically present so I don't think it's
a absolute solution to just rely on
digital security because you know these
technologies will change people will
find other ways to you know interfere
with your Communications and stuff like
this so I personally think policy is
should be really you know
really really the fundamental thing to
do for us so we should base all our
policies on fundamental protecting
fundamental human rights and then just
let the technology evolve around these
policies
thank you and
yes I'll address
um the the technical security tools so
um in a survey of about a hundred
workers in in Europe
um what we saw was the the primary
security tool that people were using not
always necessarily for security purposes
but sometimes for that reason uh with
encrypted chat so about a third of
people were using encrypted chat tools
only about 15 of people were using
um vpns and then about five percent
reusing cryptocurrency
um and I think we have kind of uh
there's sort of two reasons for that so
one reason that folks are not always
using sort of these technical security
tools and is well put by one of our
participants who said I would gladly do
all of the above but that really only
works when the customers participate and
they said you know threema signal pgp
encryption cryptocurrency right I could
know more sort of demand that the max
Punk Society pay me in cryptocurrency uh
than many workers can can demand that
their clients do so and clients may not
want to do so for a variety of reasons
that doesn't necessarily mean that
cryptocurrencies can't be useful in some
way but at least in the current way that
they are built right a you're opting
into a different currency system it has
interoperability payment issues as well
as just usability issues and it has to
be cooperative with clients and then for
things like vpns while this can be
useful as a privacy protection certainly
there is this kind of usability
trade-off of like using a VPN doesn't
change the fact uh to Kelly's point that
the terms of service are very
um you know kind of to the first
question in the panel american-centric
and sort of with these particular set of
moral values
um that prevent people from using them
right and so I can use a VPN but that
doesn't really change what can I can do
with tools and so I think for a lot of
people that kind of utility uh cost
trade-off of using some of these tools
just isn't high enough and they're not
addressing people's like core needs and
concerns
thank you so much Elisa and uh I wanted
to say like a few words to conclude uh
like many things were said just on the
point of like banking sex workers uh
I've often organized in relation to this
crisis for many years if you look at
India for example sex workers were not
able to access financial institution the
bank would say we don't take your money
your sex worker is probably coming from
trafficking we don't want it so sex talk
has created their own bank which now has
tens of thousands of members and able to
like save money and do micro credits to
support one another and this is
something that sex talkers have always
done creating Mutual Aid support so that
we have we are protecting each other I
want you to say a couple of things we
have resources here we also have these
t-shirts that's why I always wear these
T-shirts if you want to buy one of them
it's helping us sex workers and our
organization like work in very
precarious environment is very difficult
for us to access spaces political spaces
but also resources so we really
encourage you if you are able to support
sex local rights organization at the
local or european level or International
level please do so you know reach out to
us and I wanted to finish with one thing
that we are working on we are very
excited about with different partners
including edree and freedom
collaborative and hopefully Elisa and
Max Planck Institute as well I think
lots of the things that we said is often
that
foreign
debates had been based on this idea that
on one hand you got victims of
trafficking or other victims and on the
other hand you got sex workers and
somehow it's not possible to get rights
for these two communities but we know
this is not true because many of us are
victims whether we are victims of
gender-based violence we are victim of
intimate image based abuse as we discuss
victim of exploitation or trafficking
there is no such thing as like two
different communities many sex workers
are victims have been victims or will be
victims at some point and what we want
to create is more dialogue between
different organizations that might not
have the same priorities or the same
strategies but should have more
conversation about how we create in
particular digital landscape digital
environment that both protect the rights
of sex workers to sales sex to advertise
to express themselves but also protect
the rights of victims including children
including victims of intimate major
abuse and sexual exploitation so to do
this we are creating this
multi-stakeholder dialogue which will
bring together different actors Civil
Society policy makers sex workers take
imagining some organization that never
come together in the same room to
discuss on how we can create this and as
that's the thing that I've heard
throughout the day is that it is
possible to imagine new structure new
design but also new realities we already
talk about prison abolition you know
abolitional border or new structure that
allows sex workers to exist freely
without fear of repression so thank you
for your support and have a great day
bye
foreign