your colleagues there
Somewhere In The Ether so they should
place I'll double check when I
okay if you could please take your seats
are you is that working
hello yeah that works okay we are about
to kick off with solidarity not
solutionism
I don't know why that was funny
are you laughing at me
okay I'm not sure I believe you
um okay welcome back everyone thank you
so much for being here
um we're gonna kick off now with
solidarity not solutionism and I am
going to pass over to Becky kazansky to
introduce this panel
thank you so much
um
so my name is Becky kazanski and I am
here today as part of a really great
group of people who um are mostly
joining us from all sorts of different
geographic regions of the world hello
I'm going to be awkwardly looking up at
them in this uh hybrid
format experiment so please bear with us
as we make our a playful time of this
um this really great way to actually
hear from voices from all over today
um this panel is kind of a follow-on to
a workshop that just happened which
began to explore environmental and
climate Justice as a digital rights
issue
this panel now is going to be focusing
on the idea of false solutions for
climate and false Tech Solutions in
particular
just a word about myself
I am here on behalf of an organization
called the engine room today it's a
international non-profit organization
focused on the responsible and strategic
use of data and Technology
uh and joining me as a co-moderator is
um uh Shauna Finnegan from the
association of progressive
Communications uh uh and
um we're also excited to welcome four
panelists based in Chile Bulgaria
Germany and here in Brussels with me on
stage
um
first uh we have POS Pena
independent activist and researcher and
with the Latin American Institute for
terraforming
uh Lily fur is joining us from from the
center for international environmental
law
Plum and pave of Blue Link Bulgaria is
also here with us and narmeen Abu bakari
from the EU greens
they will introduce their work and how
they've come to this discussion of uh
environmental justice uh very briefly
but first we just want to thank adri and
privacy camp for hosting this
conversation
um because uh it's part of an effort to
think about how we can Center climate
and environmental issues in digital
rights discussions
so um in terms of uh this Workshop that
I just came out of
what we saw there is
um that environmental justice and
climate Justice intersect with digital
rights issues in a number of different
ways one key point is on surveillance
and security of movements and lands
rights Defenders
who are put into Harm's Way and are
dealing with safety concerns as they
arise through digital means
there's also a concern with information
and disinformation which connects
digital rights and climate Justice
concerns and there's also a common
shared concern around the extractive
nature of corporate technology practices
and in Europe we see this clear
interlinking happening with the
discourse around the twin transition
which is the idea that sustainability
can be supported through digitization
and digital Innovation something which
which narmine also touched on just
before our panel
um the question is is it always true
that sustainability and digitization are
mutually supporting
there is a lot to unpack there uh with
this idea
and it's a question that seems fit for
the digital rights uh communities around
the world to take stock of
the digital rights Community is of
course very familiar with the need to be
critical about what kind of innovation
gets supported and invested into but
um Shawna and I and the rest of the
panelists here today believe there's a
lot we can also learn from the climate
Justice movement on how to resist
solutionism as a common concern
so on this panel we're calling out
techno solutionism at the intersection
of these different issues
and we're taking inspiration from a
framing that the Justice climate Justice
movement uses which is false climate
Solutions Technologies and narratives
that can distract from the problem we're
trying to solve and potentially even
make it worse
we're asking what are the false
solutions that the digital rights sphere
needs to be aware of
and we're also asking what are some of
the just Pathways that already exist and
which can be which we can way fine
together in order to solve climate and
environmental crises
um so just a little note on the hybrid
format today
um uh we encourage the audience here as
well as online to use the hashtag
privacycamp23 uh to uh share uh
Reflections and uh questions with us
throughout the panel there will be a
time to discuss those at the end
and you can also join Shauna
online uh through uh their Twitter
handle Shawna can you uh hold that up
for us
sorry Becky I forgot to make the sign
but I'm gonna uh do it right now
um okay the Twitter handle is Shauna
Finnegan
um and uh Shawna will momentarily share
it with us so Sean is uh gonna create a
Twitter thread that people can respond
to if you're interested
um so now I want to hand it over to uh
give proper uh self introductions from
all of our panelists
and uh let's see the first person I will
ask
um is uh Shauna if that's okay with you
Shauna how did you come to this
discussion of digital rights and
environmental and climate Justice
thanks Becky I made the design very
quickly for anyone who can possibly read
this this terrible writing here
uh yeah that's absolutely and I'm gonna
just put a Twitter thread in the one
that um Andrea has just created
um because yeah I'm really excited to
hear what's bringing everyone in the
audience and participating online to
this conversation
um as as Becky said this has been a
conversation that's been happening for
some time and we really wanted to be
something that continues well beyond
just this moment that we're having today
at privacy Camp
um as Becky said I work with the
association for Progressive
Communications which is an international
network of Civil Society organizations
that are really dedicated to supporting
individuals and groups to use technology
for care for ourselves each other and
the planet and environmental justice and
sustainability really is at the heart of
ABC since APC was founded in 1990
however there's been really A Renewed
focus on environmental justice in the
last few years including a publication
called the Global Information Society
watch gizwatch published an addition in
2021 really focusing on this issue and I
know for myself it was incredibly
valuable to see just these really
grounded perspectives of what was
happening with ABC members and allies
and communities that that ABC network is
working with in terms of the real
impacts of the climate crises and the
ways that digital Technologies are are
very much intersecting with these crises
so
as part of that work APC has also been
looking at ways in which we can support
environmental justice movements and land
Defenders and this conversation around
false Solutions has come up time and
again and I think we're really looking
to how can we resist those false
Solutions and what are the opportunities
to as Becky side said we find those
those just Pathways so that's part of
what brings me to this conversation and
I'm really excited to hear from the
other the other speakers so I'll pass
back to you first Becky in kisses
anything else you want to add
no thank you so much Shawna
um in that case uh narmeen if I can pass
it to you nermeen how did you come to
the this intersection of issues and tell
us a little bit about what you work on
so um I work for the greens at the
European Parliament so for um elected
representative I was First Data
protection legal council before so I
really focused on basically I did that
protection
um and then after that I worked for a
consultation consultancy agency really
focusing on sustainability in Tech as
much as data protection and I've
realized that the question of
sustainability was mainly taken into
account by companies but because the
climate movement was influencing the
discussion so they were extremely scared
of the legislative steps that was taking
place in Brussels
and then I changed job and worked for
the greens where I was the digital
rights campaigner and I work on digital
rights as much as climate issues and
this is where my work really focused on
writer repair circular economy but also
environmental impact of different type
of Technologies and this is where also
it was more of an activism
role that I had because as a campaigner
obviously I can be on behalf of the
Queens for a better solution for our
attack infrastructures and products
um what up thank you Becky thank you
uh next I'd love to hear from Paz
Paz can you hear me hi everyone yes I
can hear you
um hello everyone my name is past Pena
and I live in Santiago of Chile I work
as a freelance consultant and for the
last I would say five years I have been
researching the intersections between
digital technology and the climate and
environmental crisis and I'm
particularly interested in the social
environmental conflicts of digitization
and it's your political effects
especially in Latin America
in this sense I work on the you know on
the exploitation of nature by
digitization as well as the displacement
and social environmental impacts
experienced by indigenous populations
and of course the working class so my
special interest in the issue of false
solution has to do not only with the
size systemic effects of digitization in
the increase of consumption and energy
use but also with how this supposed
Solutions are built at the cost of the
lives of human and non-humans in a
particular situation of vulnerability no
so in other words what are the
communities paying the price of the GT
session as a solution for the climate
and environmental crisis thank you very
much
thank you so much pause
um Plum and tell us about your work
please
and I'm working for the
boring Foundation Bulgaria but as we are
Global Foundation you know in many
aspects in terms of our interest mostly
I'm based in Estonia and I'm
Environmental Lawyer for more than 20
years and we have been working with APC
and also
with other organizations on the network
internet
governance but also networking with
environmental and social uh social
rights and other human rights activists
so that we could bring together all the
perspectives where it comes to the point
when we need to move forward with the
Technical Solutions and then also the
impacts of these Solutions
across various Fields
my my perspective has been in a way
limited to the environmental field for
many years but since we have been
working with the APC on different issues
especially on the taxation between
digital and environmental rights and the
possible potential for exploring the
potential for their Mutual reinforcement
that brought me a bit further out of
this style of
Environmental Protection work in terms
of law policies and also people behind
and to see how we could
mutually support with with the tools
with experience with the stories we have
been through in our work so there's a
lot of to learn from each other
and there's a lot we don't know about
each other so it has been really maybe
at the beginning of the journey is for
me because
in the in the past years I had one
not much but I'm trying to learn much
more so that we could help each other
and find ways because there are many
challenges uh even with with the good
Solutions related to the
climate change with the for example of
European green deal and just
transitional there are many social and
other issues technological mostly also
which should be considered so there is a
a lot of debate and a lot of uh
playing field in this regard so to be a
part of this thank you
thank you plumbing and what we'll hear
more about uh specifically what kinds of
Frameworks and just Pathways you're
looking at and very last but very not
least uh Lily please tell us about your
work
hello everyone
um yeah I'm Lily four I'm Journey from
Berlin Germany and I work with the
center for international environmental
law an international NGO that works at
the intersection of the environment and
human rights I'm not a lawyer I should
say many people expect that I'm a lawyer
we have many lawyers I'm not one of them
um I've only been with Ciel for the last
half year and and and I think a lot of
what I've done before then also brings
me to this conversation
um today for um 16 years I worked for
the German green Henry's bow foundation
on International environmental policies
um focusing very much at the
intersection of the environment and new
and emerging disruptive Technologies and
I've also been sitting on the board of
an NGO that is very instrumental in the
social movement space on this topic uh
the ETC group or Etc group that monitors
new and emerging Technologies in this
space
and and I you know I can that the
streams that you've already mentioned
Becky that came out of your Workshop
very much resonate with
um sort of the the way that I've been
looking at this topic and where I'm
coming from the surveillance the
extractive nature of corporate practices
um but in addition so I've always been
interested at this intersection of or
we're basically powerful corporate
interests on the side of big polluters
fossil fuel Industries big agriculture
on the one hand and then big Tech and
Big Data where they where they um
polite or you know where they come
together and and intersect and maybe the
other few things just to mention
um where where you know that that
concern might work whether it's
happening is really where big um tech
companies and entrepreneurs with that
Tech solutionist mindset
um begin to implement so-called uh
solutions to The Climate crisis
um for example geoengineering which I
hope we can speak more about later
um and yeah also very much the impact of
the environmental impact of these
Technologies as passes mentioned their
massive energy consumption I think leads
to a big uh colliding of interest and um
then
one other thing that I just wanted to to
flag
because I think that's something that
I've worked on for a long time but
that's not very much the Forefront of
this discussion is where um big
companies in the agriculture space
um are beginning to really go for a big
data grab to grab what is now called
digital sequence information so
digitalized information about genetics
of plants and species to really exploit
them for their private profits it's a
huge topic that is also being discussed
at the UN level I think it's something
to explore much more from a digital
rights perspective and a question of how
we deal with big data so um yeah very
happy to be here and and there's lots to
discuss
thank you very much Lily and we
appreciate your perspective on Climate
Technologies because the folks in this
room and in the digital rights space
were accustomed to focusing on digital
Technologies and now thinking about
their intersections with climate and
environment there's also of course
a lot of a long history of climate
technology
there's a un mechanism for a transfer of
technology and exploration of carbon
capture and geoengineering so we're
really eager to hear more about that
history and your perspective on how this
these discussions and Investments have
changed over the years
um so with those uh introductions I now
want to move us to the first part of
this discussion the first part of the
discussion uh that we're going to have
together is around calling out false
climate Solutions and thinking about
what these actually are in relation to
digital rights concerns and then after
that um Shauna is going to take us
through thinking about these just
Pathways so
um just to come back to what what do we
mean by false solution and why is this
relevant for digital rights folks one
example that has come up a lot in our
discussions so far is around carbon
offsetting
so carbon offsetting is a practice that
first or Rose in 1988 as part of What's
called the voluntary carbon market and
it's a way to
um
for institutions companies and also
individuals to think about their carbon
consumption and try to compensate for it
either by through a forestation efforts
such as planting trees or restoring
ecosystems and over the decades it's
become a less popular idea and a more
popular idea also tool and Technology we
can think of it as a climate technology
as well
um what's interesting is at the moment
there's a lot of renewed interest in
carbon offsetting and when it comes to
the digital rights space
um this is this is where I would like to
tie it back to some research that we at
the engine room worked on for the last
year and a half uh what we did uh
together uh in in our organization was a
research project exploring intersections
between climate Justice and digital
rights and as part of this we looked at
corporate Tech practices for both big
Tech corporations and smaller players
also in the commercial space and what we
saw often is that there are very
expansive pledges made by companies
around climate and sustainability
targets but not a lot of information
about what's actually happening Behind
These pledges
what we do know is that one of the most
common tools that is used to kind of
achieve Net Zero so to speak is a carbon
offsetting
uh there are other tools include
renewable energy credits and also
discussions of infrastructural
efficiency
Etc but carbon offsets this is um what
we think is a false solution it's been
called out by the climate Justice
movement for decades more recently we
also have increased empirical evidence
for example a study came out last week
or an investigation rather which
collected a number of studies and also
pulled in New Evidence which showed that
at least 95 percent of carbon offsets in
the end do nothing to offset carbon
emissions
these projects often fail
and Beyond the failure of individual
projects there's also the larger problem
of this idea that it's okay to do harm
in one side of the or one part of the
world
if you compensate for it in another part
it turns out that ecology and the
ecosystem doesn't work that way it's not
a balance sheet where you can just you
know balance the budget and everything
will be okay
that really calls a lot into question
about big Tech and it makes us ask as a
group of people practitioners exploring
intersections of climate and digital
rights what does that mean for digital
rights advocacy and efforts to already
try to hold companies accountable
is this concern with climate pledges
something that should be integrated with
concern around other kinds of digital
rights Harms
so with that provocation I now want to
move to
um
uh to Lily
and to ask Lily to reflect a bit about
this history of climate technology and
what it brings us to today what should
digital rights folks be aware of as the
space becomes increasingly involved on
sustainability and climate issues Lily
thank you and thank you for that
provocation
um that was already great and so I
thought what I could offer is
um looking back at when I was 30 years
basically of international climate
policy making looking a little bit back
at the different turns that we've taken
along the way that have led us down a
lot of wrong past
um and that is that have increasingly
narrowed down our sinking to just a few
options
um basically ruling out other
alternative options and Pathways that we
could have taken because I do think they
want really want everyone to keep that
in mind that when we talk about
Solutions the key question is really
what is the problem we're trying to
address right depending on how we Define
a problem the kinds of solutions that
we're going to look for are going to
look different you know people you know
with a techno fixed mindset usually come
with a solution and then they look for a
problem to solve let's do it the other
way around let's look for what is the
problem and then
um you know what's the solution and
looking back really two of the driving
forces along the entire
pathway of four Solutions in the last 30
years have been the believe in Endless
economic growth on a finite planet
um you know followed by neoliberal
capitalism basically and then
um also this uh techno optimism and the
belief that Technologies can fix
anything and Innovation will be the
solution and
um so along along just just outlining a
few of those terms where we have maybe
taken the wrong turn when in 1992 the
world agreed on the U.N framework
convention on climate change right the
UNF Triple C
we decided you know collectively people
in that convention back then that the
climate problem was going to be framed
as one about emissions in the atmosphere
something very abstract not to do with
people's life it's somewhere up there
you know a thing you cannot touch its
emissions
and the solution was going to be
emission reductions
well we could have decided the problem
was the fossil fuels in the ground that
we were burning you know and the forests
that we were cutting down
that's not what we decided the problem
was emission reductions and then and
then came the Kyoto Protocol which you
know decided on some first concrete very
small but targeted measures to actually
reduce emissions for a few countries the
rich countries
and what we decided then was gonna was
that one ton of carbon that that is
emitted when you burn
coal for example or oil or gas is
equivalent to one ton of carbon that is
sequestered in a tree or an ecosystem or
you know soil
that is actually very flawed because
they're very different carbon Cycles you
can ask in ecologist the biologists they
will explain because those Cycles have
different timelines and um so it does
matter a lot also the the geographical
location matters the question whether
you're locking in a coal mine or cutting
out an entire Forest matters so one ton
of carbon is not it does not equal one
ton of carbon but that is the very basis
of carbon trading which was then created
as a mechanism under the protocol and I
think what resonates with a sort of big
tax mindset is
that we need to quantify and measure
everything
and that is something that very strongly
resonated with the climate conversation
back then and still today and the next
big step I think came sort of Turning
Point and we're still in the middle of
that that curve um came with the Paris
climate agreement after 2015. where we
now are talking not just about emission
reductions we're talking about Net Zero
we're talking about negative emissions
we're talking about the idea that we can
actually pull carbon out of the
atmosphere by some magical Technologies
um that you're going to do carbon
removal for us
um that is something that by the way big
tech companies like Microsoft are
heavily investing in and they're
counting on offsetting their big
footprint of emissions by investing in
um in in so-called removal Technologies
which are highly problematic
Technologies and by the way the European
commission has just proposed a new
framework to certify so-called carbon
removals from the land sector but also
from so-called carbon caption storage
and other big Technologies
to actually build a voluntary carbon
Market
around these removals at the EU level
just highly problematic
um so that's the next big turn that
we're taking and then there is another
one looming on the horizon that we're
very concerned about and that has to do
with a technology called solo
geoengineering it's actually a sweep of
Technologies it's not one but the idea
is that maybe you know the whole thing
about dealing with carbon is too
complicated there's a you know easier
cheap way that we can fix the climate
Problem by addressing some of the
symptoms of climate change by turning
down a temperature by taking control of
the global thermostat and basically
turning it down to whatever we want 1.5
degree you know who wants less let's see
so managing so-called radiative forcing
managing the level of sunlight that
reaches Earth and there are a number of
Technologies being researched and
increasingly they're moving into outdoor
experiments big Tech is very interested
this field is full of Silicon Valley
startup sort of idealists or optimists
who want to go for it and actually just
a few weeks ago a Silicon Valley startup
firm can't make sunsets announced that
they did the first Rogue so unauthorized
solo geo-engineering experiments in
Mexico
um just in April last year
um it just was announced that they did
it at the end of last year the Mexican
Government now announced to ban it but
um
um which is the right decision I think
but anyway so the idea that we should
get rid of it or in addition to the
carbon metric that is really dominating
climate policy actually introduce a new
metric of radiative forcing is something
that resonates strongly with the big
Tech sector you know make sunsets it was
already beginning to sell so-called
cooling credits instead of carbon
offsets you can have Cooling offsets
so that opens up like the door widely to
a whole sweep of not just false
Solutions but sort of
risky technologies that have the
potential to destroy entire you know
clamp climate systems including things
like the monsoon which millions of
people depend on for their livelihoods
and their lives
all of that is quite scary
um and I do hope that we can form and
create new alliances between the digital
Rights Movement under climate Justice
movement so I'm very glad we're
beginning to have this conversation
today today here and in many other
spaces
thank you so much Lily I think I I noted
some reactions from the audience this
idea that the main metric around climate
change would now be how much sunlight
hits the Earth
um it's kind of where do you go from
there if that becomes the main solution
that we're banking on and is it even
possible to or feasible for the kind of
global cooperation required to make uh
geoengineering have this desired effect
and if that does get put into place
is there kind of a lock-in then for you
know the mid to long-term future and a
Reliance on on just having less sunlight
going forward so that that feels quite
fundamental thank you so much
um now we want to ask uh pause uh to
reflect on techno capitalism and
um kind of challenging this idea of the
twin transition that um I introduced as
being an important part of uh approaches
to Innovation at the moment in the EU
and Beyond pause
thank you Becky uh yes I want to
introduce the idea of technocational
capitalism instead of talking only about
big tax in the understanding uh that
although big Tech is a great example of
protagonal capitalism I believe that it
is the techno-capitalist ideology also
adopted as a demonic logic by most
digital developments including the
developments made by the states that
must be fought as a solution to the
climate and the ecological crisis
basically because as Mel Hogan says
techno capitalism implies Big Data
ecologies no so for example the creation
of an infrastructure generally placed in
foreign territories specially
conditioned to infinite growth with
intensive exploitation of Natural
Resources to operate if everything is
subject of datification digital
infrastructures become more intensive in
their consumption of of course natural
resources and that intensive
infrastructure
um
in all its life cycle affects human and
non-human communities which tend to be
of course the bodies that matter the
least to capitalism
so this is why the false solution of the
so-called twin transition is dangerous
primarily as understood by the European
commission where the competitiveness of
Europe is in the global economy is by
far the first priority and where the
complementary transitions are more near
of a geopolitical idea than an actual
scientific truth one because due to the
indirect effects of techno-capitalist
digitization we will likely have a
digital rebound effect in many
Industries so it is at least this is
strange to seriously believe that they
are complementary transitions when
conclusive evidence is still lacking you
know but more importantly to say that
they are twin transitions is to accept
that both green energies and digital
Technologies are the industries where
the control of the world economy is
being played out between China the
United States and the European Union
thus the twin transition concept is an
economical concept more than a Green
Solution Green Solution you know to to
the crisis
but I want to return to the issue of
technocational capitalism as the logic
to be suspected as an approach to The
Climate crisis not only looking at how
big Tech is portraying itself as a
friend of the environment but also
um at initiatives that have much better
press in terms of green text but that
continues with techno-capitalist logics
and here you know taking advance to the
fact that I am in a European Forum I
want to bring fairphone into the
discussion
um in their last book
um
do a fascinating analysis of the images
of the first one website where magically
the white bodies are the ones that
repair
and the color red bodies are the ones
working in minds but of course not any
Minds socially responsible Minds
according to the company
by the way first one
is holding a series of conversations
conversations here in Chile to see
sustainable lithium extraction methods
this green tech company instead of first
you know coordinated a conversation for
example with the indigenous communities
affected by this abstraction choose to
Ally with large German companies of
electric vehicles that is you know the
big Capital to the today is part of a
severe social environmental crisis here
at the salar of Atacama in the north of
Chile
so if you think it it's like teaming up
with Google to see a sustainable way to
exploit personal data
so Eddie Clements
State and I strongly agree that we
cannot produce a social justice problem
to a feel-good consumption practice of
European customers
I think might give us a clue where we
need to go in alternatives to techno
capitalism as a response to the climate
and the ecological crisis I don't want
to extend any further but I leave the
conversation open for for that
Collective reflection thank you very
much
thank you so much pause for calling our
attention to the contradictions of what
we might consider to be even agreeing or
responsible technology I think it shows
that there's always a way to go and that
part of that is acknowledging the
continued extractivism uh that comes
into play even with the devices that we
might feel better about
um and uh not to end it on a depressing
note we are going to also explore just
Pathways now but before I hand it over
to uh to Shauna I just want to invite
the online audience if you want to
engage with us on this question of what
is a false Solution please feel free to
tweet the hashtag no false Solutions
and now I want to hand it over to Shauna
thanks so much and uh yeah thanks so
much for those interventions Lily and
pause I think it's really useful to to
Really frame
um our understanding as well in terms of
just Pathways when we can identify what
are false Solutions I think we have a
much clearer idea of where where there
are real opportunities and really
learning from from communities and
people who have been doing this work for
centuries for Millennia
um I I live in the Prairies of so-called
Canada and um here in Canada and in the
U.S indigenous peoples and traditional
communities have been on the front lines
of Defending ecosystems defending the
rights of nature
um you know Recent research suggests
that 80 of the world's remaining
biodiversity is located on lands and
inhabited by indigenous peoples although
that only makes up 20 of the world's
territories it's it's very indicative of
the fact that indigenous peoples and
traditional communities have been doing
this work for so long and actually over
the past decade there's research to show
that indigenous communities specifically
in U.S and Canada who are resisting
fossil fuel projects have stopped or
delayed greenhouse gas pollution
equivalent to at least 25 percent of the
annual U.S and Canadian emissions which
is huge and there is a growing
recognition and I think we do need to
really be pushing our representatives in
different government spaces to be moving
this forward here in Canada the
government has just started to develop a
Guardians project there's more work to
support indigenous nations in setting up
for protected and conservation areas but
unfortunately that relationship doesn't
often come as a kind of nation to Nation
partnership it's often still a very um
you know Legacy of colonialism in terms
of the ways in which the the Canadian
government is approaching the
relationship with indigenous Nations so
I think it's important to think about
how we any as digital rights actors can
really be supporting and acting in
solidarity with these movements with
land and territory Defenders who really
understand the ecosystems far better
than any anyone who's just swooping in
and hoping to you know set up a carbon
offset scheme
um and so just with that very brief
framing I want to really now turn the
mic to to Plumbing to reflect on some of
the ways in which environmental and
internet governance have started to
really find these intersections and some
of the opportunities for collaboration
problem number two
thank you thank you Sean
first of all I want to just come back to
this uh
reference point that I was making when I
presented myself and my background that
the environmental rights and the
environmental justice and now Primal
Justice if we could take more broadly
it's she has been around for many years
more than 50 years and have been
developing as a
has a true Democratic tool of
influencing the the development of the
society development of industrial
Solutions
and this history and the lessons and the
collected knowledge but also experience
in the in the field of Environmental
Protection by the environmental
activists it's really very important
because there is obviously New Era new
stage of this
struggle between between the the
economic industry interests and also the
the interests of people to live in
health environment we live in in their
places where they could have a clear in
air water soil have reached biodiversity
so in a way uh environmental rights have
been really enabling people to defend
their uh the land their livelihood and
in a way it was a powerful tool in the
hands of the of the week week part of
the society because otherwise industry
itself you know wouldn't be a
will then be self-regulate I think
itself in a way that it will really
produce a positive change taking into
account of the public interest so coming
back to the public interest I think it's
a good reference across a reference
point about uh to understand how how the
digital and the environmental rights
could in the sector and I won't just
present you the example of an office
conversion which has been has become
recently also Global uh uh legal
instrument otherwise was covering the
countries of Europe and the Central
Asia but now it's not every country
could be part of to the convention so
this uh or whose convention has enabled
to its uh three pillars access to
information uh public participation and
access to Justice and environmental
matters I enabled
all the
Angels activists and uh not just the
general public in the country's
participle convention uh to have a
stronger and uh
and more powerful way to uh
to control to monitor or to resist in a
way to the over exploitation of
financial resources to to
be part of of the discussion and also
decision making process where the
governmental governmental authorities
decide whether one one or another
another project will be
approved or not so this convention has
become really a very strong
safeguard for for nature and also a
benchmark for for environmental
democracy because it also links the
environmental and human rights and also
acknowledges that the the fact that we
owe an obligation to the Future
generations and also establishes
establishes the sustainable development
should be achieved only through the
involvement of the all stakeholders it
has influenced really the policy making
and also the thinking in a way of the
decision-making process also a business
level in many counties because for
example Bulgaria is a practical
convention European Union as a union is
a part of the convention although not
perfect member I should say but so in a
way
this international law uh over imposing
this new uh new rules for uh procedural
rights she has been changing the
landscape of the Democracy uh a national
level so this is a really powerful
instrument which could be in the lessons
for more than 20 years of uh
history of implementing of this
convention he has been could be really
important reference point for any
conversation related to how we could uh
how could approach and understand and in
a way be involved into the
decision-making processes related also
to the
to the Improvement on the introduction
of new technologies which might be
digital or other Technologies which I
have hasn't been haven't been regulated
yet but anyway the environmental law is
uh protecting and ensuring
decision-making processes to be uh to be
a democratic and an inclusive so that we
could really regulate and and be
involved into the decision making for
the development of different
infrastructure projects it was in the
life of everyone so the same way uh I
think all the new infrastructure digital
and other infrastructure of new new
generation would be also I would need
also this really uh all-inclusive
element of decision making process and
openness really full access to
information probably participation and
eventually as much as possible under the
different
Nation Nation Frameworks even the
Frameworks access to Justice and also
the challenging different decisions and
also challenging in the best case also
the business in the car thank you very
much
thanks so much Clement I I really
appreciate also your your reflection on
the ways in which the arhus convention
has really sort of shifted thinking
around
um these issues and I think that's
really valuable to think about how we
resist false narratives and again as you
said the opportunities to really use
this mechanism to really address that
Gap as we see there's clearly a concern
among you know the majority of people
living on this planet about the climate
crises and it's really the people who
are in power who are refusing to act so
thanks so much Clement I think that's a
really valuable example
so I want to now uh turn back to the
um on ground in Brussels uh to hear from
narmeen to reflect a little bit on
what's happening at the EU level now I
mean the floor is yours thank you very
much and I would I would like to set a
bit of light on how actually companies
publish on their website their
environmental impact you would see on
Google for instance they will tell you
how the data center in climate neutral
and this is actually an environmental
claims
um and 57 of EU consumers are receptive
to these environmental claims when they
buy or use any services or buy a product
and in certain countries there are even
more receptive for instance Sweden or
Denmark
what does it mean it means that we have
companies using a marketing strategy to
showcasing how well they are well the
environmental footprint is regardless on
of how reliable that information could
be
and because it's self-awarded by the the
manufacturers or the person providing
the service or the projects we have a
lack of trusting for from consumers
because you can have a label or a claim
that is actually real and has been
Justified and others which are
unreliable super vague
um and or even wrong sometimes and
because consumers like that type of
information they are being confused and
Spanish consumer organization have even
shown that
uh more than 43 percent of people do not
stress anymore the environmental claims
on products so we have a situation where
people do care about how they consume
how they they about what they buy and
the the response that companies are
providing to us consumers
and this screen washing is also
misleading other economical actors so
it's not even giving the advantage due
to the to the people making the effort
to Green the product and their
activities and ultimately that leads
obviously to a less green economy
I'm talking about this because I think
it's a really good example on how we can
create a better environment for our
infrastructures and our products the
European Union I mean the European
legislation is
um exists on this matter but it's mainly
on the information that a company is
supposed to give to the consumer and
there are two legislative texts that
provide
um I mean that gives a legal basis to
this one of them is the consumer rights
directive and the other one is the
inferior commercial practice directive
and both of them oblige the
manufacturers actually give the
information but also for bits any
misleading omission of information now
we still have a problem because a
product can still enter the market and
we without being justified and that
would mean that you would have to bring
a complaint to the table and I would
take ages and the project will still be
on the market while it's misleading us
so we we end finally we know that there
is no obligation
to to provide any information on the
environmental aspect of it so you can't
really ban a green claim and that is
really the problem and this is why
you're doing I mean we believe as greens
that it's really important to regulate
those claims and ensure that
um you don't have companies claiming but
they are not claiming things that they
were actually not doing
um recently in December 2019 at the very
beginning of the Mandate the European
commission but for the European winter
and this is a strategy that
that aims at Greening pretty much a lot
of topics like Mobility food housing and
even the finance
financing Factory but they decided early
in 2020 to finally tackle the problem on
greenwashing they first published in no
in 2022 sorry that published a proposal
on on empowering the consumers in the
green transition and the aim was really
to create an environment where you could
publish trustworthy information on how
eco-friendly a product is and give a
consumer a better role or a bigger role
so little disclaimer I shouldn't I mean
I don't believe that the burden should
be put on the consumer this is not how
the ecological transition should be done
but creates and trustworthy
informational oblige the manufacturers
to stop reducing products infrastructure
that goes against ecological transition
and this is
an economic way and that is this I mean
you can discuss whether we should use
this this way
um but that that brings actually a way
to find company for providing
information that is wrong
um
now what is interesting into that text
is that it will pre pre-approve any
claims
um that the company will put into the
market and that would have to be done by
a national body
um and
I think it would enable to avoid like
purita to come to the market and
actually have no impact on our side I
mean positive impacts on our society the
second thing is that it will provide
more information on the durability the
repairability of of a product
um and it would also ban and that I
found super interesting the
environmental claims so every claim like
you know sustainability eco-friendly
climate neutral all those words would
have to be proven by
um by um by that would have to be
actually backed up by a scientists and
performance and indicator developed by
the commission so then the question is
will that indicator could be good enough
and that I I actually don't know but
it's better that at least we have an
institutionalized way of looking into
what companies will be able to claim or
put on their website or put on their
products or what type of Labor they
would be using
um in a natural I think this um the this
new proposal would really help us
European consumers
um have a better impact on the on the
planet but also that would blight
manufacturers to really respect what
they are actually saying and this could
be really inspiring not from not only
from a consumer perspective but for more
General services that we have and apply
to digital platform a digital platform
Digital Services that you would have to
use because this is really linked to
products that you're buying not Services
um so we could extend potentially this
legislation to other ways
um
and finally have more better information
for consumers for manufacturers and for
any economic players that is going to
enter the market and not undermine the
green transition thank you
thank you so much narmine that's really
valuable to hear about these
developments and as you were speaking I
was thinking about some of the
reflections that really you shared about
changing metrics and thinking about some
of the metrics that that you mentioned
are being for example durability and
repairability and you know one of the
questions I thought was is this
something because of some of the you
know right to repair campaigns that have
happened in Europe that that these
metrics have gotten more prominent and
just thinking again about those
performance indicators and your note and
I mean about their effectiveness it
seems like there's really a lot more
conversation needed to be have around
around indicators and metrics and how we
really understand this movement towards
um you know it just transition thinking
about the ways in which the pathways
have really narrowed over the last
decade So yeah thank you so much narmeen
and before I pass back to
um to start asking some questions I do
want to just also invite anyone who's on
Twitter if you want to share some
examples that you know of of
um you know actions that are really
contributing to just Pathways for
climate Justice and sustainability it'd
be great to hear from you
back to you back to you
thanks so much Shawna and Elsa nermeen
for your intervention
um this actually brings us to
um uh to opening the floor to questions
both from the audience here and online
so
um yes does anyone have a question
they'd like to pose to the panelists and
maybe we can pass the microphone over uh
then I see um one hand up uh over here
hi I'm Jonas from the Ohio University of
Brussels a communication researcher
working on data protection impact
assessments so actually it reminded me
quite a bit I've been learning a lot
from environmental impact assessments
when we were conceptualizing
um especially the involvement of
citizens in these impact assessments so
I'm very interested in the links between
the digital rights and the and and more
environmental rights but my question
um
where I really thought what you were
talking about links to the digital
Rights Movement was um enforcement so um
some of the ideas that you've been just
presenting um about like green washing
or forthcoming green washing how um well
seeing for example the gdpr how
difficult it can be to enforce um these
rules how isn't it extremely wouldn't it
it sounds extremely complicated to
enforce
um for example what companies write on
their products to
um
to inform the consumer so how realistic
is that in practice uh that these rules
are actually being enforced followed and
enforced
um nurmeen would you like to answer this
and yes sorry I think just like for the
pr it would be National Authority then
you would have to the question of would
you really like to have consumer
authority to organize this or do we
prefer to have competitive Authority I
mean I think that was the same question
the Hub that took place for the DPR
um frankly it's um I found really
difficult to to know if a consumer
organization will be better than a
competitive competition organization but
since it's a consumer directive I mean
both of them are it would make more
sense than they are the one following
this topic I mean precisely on on the on
the
um and very practice directive that
that's the case
um then then remains another question
what is the financial mean that would
you would like as a member states to
provide to these authorities this is a
political will question it's each
National member states
taking I mean taking it seriously and
putting um the the money into the
national authorities
um
so I would really frankly answer that
the consumer organization should be in
charge of this and we will see if if
that will take in place but then the
methodology should be one that is made
by the European commission so that you
have a normalized methodology beforehand
that could be used by every National
authorities later
I hope it really answers your question
uh I see another hand up
yeah thanks a lot my name is Maximilian
I'm a part of figure of Belgium and
thanks a lot for for all of your
interventions my question would go to
Lily and pass we heard you sketching uh
problems but I would also like for you
to have the opportunity to sketch just
pathway and the way out of techno
capitalism so how do we change and how
do we challenge it and what paths should
International climate policy take
um you spoke about perhaps not being
taken Lily maybe maybe you have a an
idea of which one to follow thanks a lot
do you want me to check this immediately
um yeah okay
um so I do not have a grant master plan
to offer um to make a clue because I'm
skeptical about what we need is a big
master plan um but that's maybe not what
you're asking and
I think like there's so many things we
could and should be doing
um but if I just name a few it's really
phasing out fossil fuels as fast and as
completely as possible starting
yesterday
um and that is not what we're doing at
this point and we're doing so many
things that are counterproductive to
that urgent and necessary phasing out of
fossil fuels including
um you know brainwashing in the form of
you know calling
new investments in fossil gas
infrastructure clean
um so phasing out fossil fuels um and
then also stopping the destruction of of
ecosystems that are still standing and
and allowing those already destroyed
um to to be restored
um it's a key one Transforming Our
industrial agriculture system into
something that's more just and
sustainable and based on around
agri-ecology for example and diverse
models so there are many many different
things I I was just listening to the
conversation reflecting myself on what
are the parts where I see you know the
solution pass or ways forward where the
digital rights movement and the climate
Justice movement intersect and could
really be working together just want to
name two
um that really come to the Forefront for
me one is really
that the climate Justice movement knows
how to tackle the fossil fuel industry
and Lobby right that's what the climate
Justice movement is good at
that part of the movement does not
really get the mindsets of big Tech and
Silicon Valley and how these companies
operate
and how we can tackle them and I think
that is what many of you I can't see you
in the audience but I believe you know
much better or that part of the movement
is much better so I'm inviting all of
you to join the fight against
geoengineering and a big techno fixes
because we need that knowledge and we
need those synergies the other thing um
connecting it back to the issue of
surveillance and shrinking spaces that
apparently was discussed in a workshop
we're extremely concerned about the next
climate conference happening um in a UAE
a country where digital surveillance is
very very strong
human rights
um are not protected at all and we
already saw what happened at the last
Conference of parties um in Egypt
the good news was the climate and the
human rights movement were beginning to
work together and actually have Joint
Communications at that last Conference
of parties not sure how that's going to
play out at the cop in UAE but I do
think that the climate Justice movement
at the cup needs much more support from
digital rights activists both in terms
of concrete analysis of you know apps
that are being offered to participants
of the conference whether they're safe
or not ways of communicating safely
while on the ground Etc but also
actually understanding the political
context of the country that this
movement is going to come to for that
big un conference so those are two
concrete things that I'm hoping
um spark some interest in your movement
um well I have
three ideas you know the first one
um you know especially thinking about
what we have said before here in the
with with panelists is
um to understand that this is a
planetary issue no so whatever is
happening in Europe for example any
measure that you take in Europe is going
to affect the rest of the world and in
this regard I really you know my my core
lists actually to think about what are
the measures that Europe is taking
around this especially around this
screen washing thing Etc and how that is
going to impact the rest of the world
because this is capitalism and
capitalism is gonna look for other place
to extract
resources data Etc I know and I think
that is something that we need today uh
ultimately address to understand that
this is a planetary issue and I think
that the European Union has a very
important role here to think not only
about Europe but open and its Vision to
the rest of the world that is one thing
especially you know for Europe the
second thing is probably something that
you have discussed a lot as privacy
Specialists no the idea that we need to
limit technical capitalism especially
when we talk about big tax you know big
tax are not a solution for the climate
crisis no because this idea of growth
and growth and growth of extractivism of
data that means
um use of a lot of Natural Resources Etc
I know we need to limit techno
capitalism and I know that is a super
complex problem but we need to move to
that direction and the second thing is
that we not only need to reduce the
power of techno-capitalism but also to
um push public policies to have
technodiversity you know and
technodiversity understood as the
Chinese philosopher yukui understands
technodiversity now this idea that there
are different technologies that can be
tied to communities to their territories
and to their customer Visions you know
we are facing today this
totalizing idea of technocapitalism no
where you know every little
um technology is tied to that
growth Logic No and we need public
policies that can fertilize uh you know
the the the
scenario for different Logics of
technology to appear you know because
this is and I I want to end up with this
no technology will accompany us
in this problem no if you want to have
Solutions technology will you know
have a very important role but not any
technology not technoc capitalism so we
need to to to to urge you know our uh
public policies uh to to to to them
police the
decision makers no to take public
policies that can be actually
um directed to have a more
technodiversity field in in our
realities thank you
thank you so much for for these last
Reflections and for the uh wonderful
questions from the audience we are kind
of coming on to the end of this
discussion today
but
um we don't want this to be the end of
the discussion and so that being said I
know there there might have still been a
couple hands up please feel free to
reach out to us afterwards and I'm going
to pass it over to Shawna now for some
clues about next steps and ways to
continue to to have this talk yeah
thanks so much Becky and for anyone who
does use Twitter we are collecting some
resources in that Twitter thread that
we've got going
um and if you want to
um you know feel free to to direct
message me at my full name Twitter
handle
um and so Becky's as Becky said and I
think as we keep trying to bring up
throughout this conversation we really
want this to be an opening for
conversations for people who maybe this
is really new as well as really
continuing the work that we're doing
um with each other and and with our
wider networks to really address these
issues and so we are working with a
coalition that will be hosting some
discussions at mozfest at the end of
March which is I believe the 20th to the
24th of March
um we'll be having a few conversations
there and we're really hoping that this
will be part of building coalitions um
really connecting climate Justice and
digital rights there has been a lot of
work happening that around really uh
having digital rights funders um really
engaging in work towards climate Justice
and supporting really intersectional
research and we really hope that if
you're interested in getting involved
that you'll reach out to to those of us
who are in the in the panel and the
organizers to really think about
um how we can continue working together
um so I do just want to make sure that
if everyone has if you want to see any
final words the speakers and and then
pass back to thank you
thank you so much Shawna and I also want
to express my deep thanks to all of the
panelists today who engaged in this
hybrid experiment with us
I hope it's been an enriching discussion
for you all and I look forward to
continuing it with you with that we
reach the conclusion so thank you so
much
[Applause]