once again
hello can you hear me well
thanks so welcome to this uh this
session on data retention you might
wonder why are we talking still now
today about the day retention again well
this is something we're gonna
get it into it's the title of the panel
is not really
um
it's a bit alarming but it's also
optimistic as you can see
um I'll be your mother the moderator
today I'm as a disclaimer I'm the
assistant of one of the panelists who's
late
so while he's away I can still see what
I want
um so I'm similar assistant to MLP
Patrick
with me I have plixabra
sorry
clicks
um I have sorry who is at the center for
it and epilo in in leuven as a doctoral
researcher
um we have jespers from Eustis lawyers
who's representing
the Belgian NGO and La Liga finish
and we'll have if he manages to find a
parking spot
a med battery power representing the
Pirates
and he he works for the greens IFA group
more generally
you may have noticed that data retention
is a topic that comes and goes we talk
about it as PDP actually I'm not here at
Price Camp it's been many years there's
been multiple panels but also multiple
court of justice cases
each with a slightly modified question
to the courts
um
so why are we here today what what has
changed since the last time
you might wonder maybe you know that
there's not that much new compared to a
year ago well there's been at least one
new law that has been passed and there's
a couple that have been stricken down
we'll get into this
um
Patrick just arrived so we it's perfect
we're going to start
um let me start with you
you presented a couple months ago your
research at the Luis conference in Italy
it goes
um it's about how the security objective
in
correspond to the
sorry how the seriousness of the
security objectives pursued by the data
intention compared to in corresponding
compared to the seriousness of the
interference to from the fundamental
rights can you tell us more about this
research of yours and I'll give you my
thank you very much also for the
organizers for having me and for Simeon
for the introduction indeed you can also
find a lot of this informational
discussing today in on a presentation I
get on the caregiver 11 website
so I would like to discuss today the
judicial regulation of mass and data
retention and some challenges that arise
I imagine as experts you probably have
heard some of the things before but I
hope that we can engage into more
discussion in relation to three specific
challenges as mentioned by Simeon how
the court of justice has developed this
hierarchy whereby the more important the
policy interest objective is it must be
proportionate to the seriousness of the
interference in Gert by fundamental
rights to privacy and to data protection
so according to the court
and the most important security
objective it is capable of justifying
the more serious interferences and the
more processing operations are allowed
and on the top we have the safeguarding
of National Security
which is the most important security
objective in the middle we have the
protection of public security and the
fight against serious crime and on the
bottom we have the fight against Crime
which is allows for at least intrusive
and the non-serious interferences with
privacy and data protection
so what the court considers on the top
National Security allows it is capable
of justifying what the core refers to as
the more serious interferences and those
are for instance the preventive Mass
retention of
metadata electronic communications
metadata but also the real-time
collection and automated analysis of
metadata
in the middle the fight against serious
crime and protection of public security
for that purpose only serious
interferences may be justified and those
can be incurred by for example Mass
rotation of IP addresses and targeted
data metadata retention
and the fight against Crime can only
justify non-serious interferences such
as the mass retention of civil identity
data
so we already know that the EU the the
European Court the European judge has
allowed Mass data surveillance and I
would like to focus on three challenges
in relation to First the security
objective then or first the seriousness
of the interference then the security
objective and then the distinction
between mass and targeted
so first how can we
um
distinguish what the type of
interference whether it's serious or
non-series
to start with data retention in itself
regardless of any harm or sensitive data
being included constitutes an
interference and that conclusion is even
more Justified vis-a-vis privacy when
sensitive information is included
then the court has found that the
processing of data which do not allow
precise conclusions to be drawn about
individuals leads to a non-serious
interference and that was for example in
Ministry of skull the same conclusion is
here worth it is not worthy to to say
that the same conclusions was drawn with
regards to the processing of Passenger
Name Records data in the context of the
EU Canada International agreement
whereby the court had said at the time
that the processing of this large
amounts of data despite the fact that
they can reveal a lot of sensitive
information and are subject automated
processing does not constitute a serious
interference
the exact opposite was now recently
concluded with regards to passenger Name
Records data processing in the context
of the EU and as regards the PNR
directive and in there the court said
that the PNR data processing because it
is continuous systematic and untargeted
it undoubtedly entails a serious
interference
and a similar reasoning was also used in
the digital rights Ireland ruling
whereby the court mention of how this
wide-ranging data retention creates this
feeling of constant surveillance so we
can see that perhaps this um
element of constant and continuous
surveillance is important for assessing
seriousness of interferences
and finally what the court consider as
the more serious interference on the top
of the hierarchy is to my knowledge only
being discussed in the context of
National Security
so the most decisive Factor seems to be
whether there is sensitive information
and whether that information allows to
draw specific conclusions about
individuals lives private lives the
court is quite focused on privacy and
often assess this seriousness of
interference in a quite
conjoined assessment and here it is
perhaps interesting to to ask whether
assessing the right to data protection
alone and interferences with the right
to data protection could be assessed
independently not only as a means to
safeguard privacy but also pursuing
goals of safeguarding fundamental rights
more broadly as well as empowering
individuals against Power and
informational asymmetries so in this
case an interference should be a serious
and even more serious simply by the fact
that this vast amounts of data being
collected amplify quite significantly
the power and informational symmetries
between the citizen and the government
now the Second Challenge I would like to
discuss is how to distinguish between
this first objective or the more serious
objective of National Security and the
objective of protecting public security
um the court considers that these two
types of threats are distinguishable by
their nature seriousness and the
specific nature of circumstances and
mass data retention is allowed when
there is a present or at least
foreseeable threat against National
Security which is distinguishable by
their threats to public security which
are according to the court general and
permanent
however if we see how in EU law and case
law these two concepts are defined very
often a lot of the same terminologies
used and while National Security is not
defined in the law as such the Accord of
justice has given a sort of definition
and public security it was initially
kind of defined in case law regarding
the fundamental freedoms of movement
and now you also can find definitions on
public security within the law
enforcement data protection directive
and the regulation on the free flow of
data and in those definitions we see
that both National and public security
are defined by making references to the
protection of fundamental interests of
society protecting Assessment Services
the survival of the population
Interstate relations and even military
interests
an area which is traditionally appointed
National Security is now also used to
describe public security
so nothing to that of course is the
thorny topic of terrorism which is
falling under both and that has been
explicitly recognized for example in
Lakota Nets and while terrorism is part
of National Security on the other hand
in for example the PNR directive ruling
that I mentioned earlier there the court
was more reluctant to accept that actual
intelligence services will have access
to this data because they also pursue
this same objective
so the guidance from the court on how to
differentiate these two
types of threads might be a little bit
limited and neglecting that definitional
confusion as well as how in practice
security agencies are increasingly and
more closely collaborating further
blaring the lines ultimately the most
decisive Factor seems to be a temporal
one between present and foreseeable and
general impairment and in in such a
dynamic environment such as security it
might not be as clear and as easy to to
draw the lines there either
so as invoking a different security
purpose allows for mass or Target the
data retention the question inevitably
arises whether member states will try to
label more operations as protecting
against foreseeable threats to National
Security in order to impose Mass data
retention
and finally the third challenge I would
like to uh bring forward relates to the
issue on how to delineate between what
constitutes massive Mass data retention
and targeted retention according to the
courts mass is general and
indiscriminate while targeted is a debt
retention measure that is targeted in
relation to a specific time period a
geographic location
a person is likely to be involved in any
way to crime or persons who could for
other reasons contribute to the fight
against Crime
so insofar as restricting rotation to
geographical area is concerned there the
court has heard they're clarified that
this can happen for example by
restricting data retention to all the
people within a location that is
um
chosen because for instance of its
vulnerability or high risk of crime such
as airports or Maritime ports
so these criteria seem to neglect first
of all how targeted from a criminal
procedural perspective should be should
be more linked or related to a
reasonable suspicion and should be more
specific
um in relation to a specific threat or
crime and they also seem to neglect the
reality of advanced algorithmic tools
increasingly being used
the court has made a caveat that the
effectiveness of modern investigation
techniques should not lead to mass
surveillance
so this seems to imply that we should
find a balance between ensuring
effectiveness of new tools and not
leading to collection of data being Mass
however it might be difficult to draw
lines on what is considered an objective
link between the data to be collected as
targeted and the fight against Crime
when we have automated iron Predictive
Analytics employed which are notoriously
known as objective as initially thought
and they are inherently looking for
previously unknown threats and their
effectiveness actually depends on having
more rather than less data
so that could potentially make the link
between the threads and the broad
amounts of data to be collected more
easily established
and after all data contributing to the
fight against Crime maybe all the data
that helped to create an update
assessment criteria as is the case with
the aforementioned PNR directive whereby
one of the purposes of processing all
the passenger Name Records data of all
passengers within Europe is exactly to
create and update the pre-established
models on the basis of which we can make
risk assessments of passengers
so in this way even if member states
limit their practices on targeted data
retention that might still be not as
targeted as the court might think and to
wrap this up I would bring all this
regulation that the court has built is
built on the premise that data retention
is has a legal basis in a way in the
Privacy directive
and with the draft privacy regulation
further questions arise first of all
because the current draft for instance
exclude National Security from its
applicability
bringing conflict potentially with the
case law and second because actually
retention the references to retentions
have been deleted and there is only a
general restriction clause
so to conclude do we want to have the
regulation of mass and targeted data
retention by the courts or by the EU and
if it's so by the legislator should that
happen through
um secondary law like the Privacy that
concerns the confidence health of
communications or should we have a more
specified
framework and in that regard I think
that perhaps a new dedicated instrument
with a proper impact assessment having
sufficient empirical evidence on what
are exactly the security needs between
linking specific data to specific types
of crimes and the harms incurred not
only on privacy but also vis-a-vis data
protection as an empowering tool and
also taking into account of course
otherwise right Fair trial and
discrimination then we could perhaps
have a more clear regulation
yeah thank you very much
I think a couple of things that you've
said will be touched upon the next
speakers as well both about the
targeting of the retention and about the
new possible tools for for the EU as
well as about the effectiveness
um uh empirical evidence about the
effectiveness and needs for these tools
to begin with
um before I continue let me just I
started this panel very quick because we
were getting slightly late but I forgot
therefore to remind you that this is
live streamed
and that if there are
questions also from the online audience
these can be asked through the
intermediary of
Twitter or Mastodon but since I'm
sitting here and moderating this panel I
need someone from the audience to look I
need a volunteer thank you to look for
um
any questions with the hashtag hashtag
privacycam 2223 and hashtag data
retention so those of us who those of
you who are watching this online know
that you can still interact with us and
ask questions through
um through Twitter unless and with these
um hashtags
the audience is also uh invited even
though also those who are in person in
the event to ask questions I will give
the floor both at the end but also in
between speakers so if you have
questions please note them down or keep
them somewhere because otherwise you
might forget them happy to take them in
between different speakers
um
is there any question on what has been
said right now before we move to the
next was anything unclear or does any
specific point needs to get a bit more
in depth
if not we'll move on but think of your
questions uh ahead for the next ones
please amazing
um so
um you represent the Liga and the league
yes
um I assume you you're going to speak
about the Belgian data retention model
was adopted last August and specifically
about the topics of what is targeted in
a general indiscriminate manner in the
sorry when does a data retention law
that does something that is both
targeted and uh indiscriminate find the
balance
um
the floor is just
okay good afternoon
I hope that you understand what I want
to say because my English
is not so good
okay I am the lawyer from the league for
human rights the Flemish and French
league of human rights in Belgium we
have two legally human rights leaks
and I in Belgium there are at this
moment three
data retention lows
the first was from 2000 I give you a
short history to follow the discussion
the first low Belgian low data retention
low was from 2013.
and the Belgian constitutional Court
annulate this this low in 2016. first
law second low was from 2015
and the Constitutional Court annulates
this law in 2021
they annulate the second law after an
interruption by the European Court of
human rights to put so-called
presidential questions preliminary
questions
we were two days in the
The Fairly beautiful Hall of the
European court of justice in Luxembourg
you must go there when you want to see
the real work of the European court of
justice
we were there two days
to discuss the questions not only from
the Belgian constitutional court but
also France and the United Kingdom but
in the same procedure also prejudicial
questions to the European Court
it's remarkable that in this procedure
in Luxembourg 15 European countries do
an intervention normally when you go to
the European Court of human of Justice
the road to e45 European countries who
come in but in this case there are 15
countries present and also the European
Commission that underline the importance
of the the discussion that was happened
in September 2019 by the European court
of justice
the European court of justice maker that
Norm at that moment the so-called
judgment like
it's because it was the French party it
was the first party but it was also a
party of Great Britain and from Belgium
we were there with the leak for human
rights with the Barrow from the the
lawyers maybe some other persons
I come back on like quadrature because
it's a very important decision
then in 20 July of this year
20 July of this year the Belgian
Parliament vote a new the third new uh
anti-date data retention I say antibiot
data retention low
and we have time just at 6 February to
make appeal by the Belgian
constitutional court and we are at this
moment not I alone but also
to other lawyers we are preparing the
appeal by the Virgin constitutional
court for the third time we go there
we hope to win it but I will give you
some
continue about the third Persian law
that's the first part of the history the
Belgian situation
the second part of the history that's
what's happened by the European court of
justice because it's very important
because my opinion is that the European
court of justice
always take a good position
in this question also when the pressure
of all of many European countries was
fairly High
in the discussion when we were in
Luxembourg the representative of Ireland
say when you don't follow our position
you will have problems with your court
literally say that literally the the
pleasure the intimidation of the Court
was very very high
the court make the first decision about
the data retention was in
the basic law
for the the a privacy
Direction directive
is from 2000 to 2002 then because at
that moment the the European uh
Parliament and other realized them that
they have to do something about the
communication the e-communication
because it was coming up it was happened
more and more that people did
communication by uh
digital elements
first decision of the European Court
digital rights
2014 second judgment
from 2016 and then we have the
quadrature the net
from 2020 and it's very important also
after like regardless there were two
other procedures by the European Court
about the same discussion also the
discussion about the German law
because there was a similar German
low-light the Belgian although but they
waited to take a decision about the
German law after that they take a
decision about the Belgian French and
law of the United Kingdom
there was a
important decision with the name
Commissioner of Anne Garda I think it's
from Ireland
in April 5 April 2022 last year fairly
recent and the most recent decision
Judgment of the European court of
justice was from 20 September of three
four months ago about the the German law
the name of that decision is space net
there's a Korean name to to speak about
this decision 20 September
2023 22.
that means that
in in this decision of space net the
European Court bring all their
statements together it's the basic to
discuss at this moment for instance the
third version
data retention law
and also later in the decision of space
net
uh
you have to know that the central
discussion
is about article
15.1 of the e-privacy directive
and this article was also Central in the
discussion in Luxembourg and this
article say that European elective that
there can be restriction
from privacy when it's necessary
appropriate and proportionate measure
within a democratic Democratic Society
to safeguard National Security defense
public security and the prevention
investigation detection
and prosecution of criminal offenses or
of an authority authorized use of the
electronic communication system
what's important
is the the word in a Democratic Society
many people forget it but they think
yeah it's about discussion
proportionality and and necessarily also
that but the fundamental political
discussion is what how far can we go in
a Democratic Society to to stop and to
to survive the the communication of the
people that's the fundamental discussion
that people say yeah but look to China
look to Russia look to the United States
no that's not the discussion in Europe
the discussion is how far will Europe go
and Belgium go to to stay a Democratic
Society and how far will we go
okay what did uh
uh there's a the chart the the the
directive article 15.1
and the European Charter fundamental
Rights Article seven and eight seven
privacy eight privacy on communication
and from the the chart of the European
human rights the oppose General and
undifferentiated on differentiated
retention on a preventive base of
traffic or and location of data does the
central
point of view of the European court of
justice
the Lord
just with a few of time since the
background might be already known by
some or perhaps most of the the audience
could you go a bit into the Belgian
analysis
that might be I know you're giving the
the framework for for understanding
what's happening in Belgium but just
with a view of time okay but the
question is when you discuss the Belgian
love you have to know about what was the
position of the European Court of just
that okay
you can find my uh
my exposure on the website of the
of this Camp privacy camp
I will be very sorry
in order to explain this very
complicated uh question okay the Belgian
law
uh what did say what did they do know
with the new Belgian law
in Belgium there is a
some men say when when men do something
again and again and again and Hazel
study Hendrick and trache and deserved
the stain I it's not a translation in
English it seems to be in English Fox is
not caught twice in the same snail
and when I see to the third Belgian low
but also to the second one the second
one is worse than the first one and the
third one is still worse than the second
one
they in the in they do the opposite of
what the law the Belgian constitutional
court and the European court of justice
what they say
what is word sir
you have to make distinction between
Sterling of data
retaining of data on one side and the
access to that are two different
elements
about the stalling of data Belgium
in the new Belgian law say make a
difference between Sterling in
geographical zones and
the European Court
say you can do that storing in
geographical zones but under many
important conditions not not like that
Belgium low third version low
say that there must be starting in five
different geographical zones
first are the judicial judicial
districts and police districts with a
certain number of crimes per thousand
inhabitants
on average over the past three years
that means that when there are three
crimes
on Thousand persons in certain judicial
statistics of ballistic six
the they can order the operators to
collect the data from the people
that's
three
it's very low
they were controlled by the general Data
Bank from the police but in this data
Bank everything comes in this data bank
that's not make for this purpose and in
my opinion is that they never can do it
on on a good way second geographical
Zone or the zones or entire territory
determinated by the coordinating body
for treats analyze in Belgium is the
name Oak cuts
in case of tweet level three
level three and then they can do a
general and undifferentiated detention
I repeat your P the Luxembourg accepted
but also on the very strict conditions
and these conditions are not uh not in
in the Belgian though level three from
the Tweets in Belgium is the not the
highest level
the highest level is level four and
there is a important difference between
the third level and the fourth level I
think that maybe only in the fourth
level they can maybe applicate do an
application of this question
third Zone the areas particularly
exposed to treats to National Security
and serious crime
what are these areas
the 19 different
locations or areas
for instance all the Metros all the
prisons of the Armed dealers and
shooting Rangers the
municipalities with critical Network
Central and provisional Data Center
building and so on 19 different places
who also called a treat can be a treat
to National Security and serious
94 Ford Zone
the zone you can may post serious treats
to vital interests of the country or
essential population needs
what all these
Jonas
all the neutral zones and the Parliament
and all what's in in
in that position all the motorways all
the motorways and the packing of the
motorists you know Belgium is a very
small country you have everywhere motor
race
all the town halls all the townhouse the
Royal Palace okay
the Royal domains the Constitutional
court and so on and also the Border
municipalities it's all the board
municipalities from this small country
can be see as a Zone to collect the data
the last synonym
or the potential potentially seriously
threatening the interest of
international institutions
established on national territory or
disease the European Union the
parliament of the Zona Schumann plan
Schumann place and so on the NATO the
European economic area the U.N
institutions in Belgium and so on
important is that this is in the law but
the law also said for the five zones
that the the government by Royal Decree
can make them broader
there are still very very broad when
when you look to the second important
point is that they say it depends also
from the pyramid how long will you go
with this Zone there is no perimeter in
the low
the law of say it's a Royal Decree who
can this can decide how long the
perimeter will be that can be one
kilometer that can be 20 kilometer
that's that makes a great difference
that is in the low not a minimum or a
maximum from the perimeter that they
have to uh to to develop
then that's
all the
the geographic zones then very short
second Point what kind of data Master
operators collect
when you in the discussion can you can
give me an example to see if this is in
the in the data I think that everything
you can think about what operator can
collect is in this data it's more than
40 more than 40 different data that they
have to collect
traffic data General data data about
individual persons in the low the
European law of European court of
justice say you can collect
storage do from
IP addresses and
identification addresses but not not in
fact not fairly much more than that
and when you do this you can do it on
the on the spatial conditions for
instance then that can be a problem to
for the treats against children the
pornography against children and things
like that they are very
exact conditions in the decisions of the
European Court
and then the third point the first
second what the operators have to
collect
third point is the access
which authorities can have access to the
data from The Operators
I've
I follow I know the first law I know the
secret law and I know the third low in
the first low there were four
authorities who can have access in the
second law there are six authorities who
can have access
I ask you how many
authorities or no in the in the third
law
then
different authorities who can have
access on certain conditions okay but
who can potentially have access to
this data uh what's a little bit normal
that are the intelligence and Security
Services
that or the competent
authorities for software
for yeah
to to follow at least that even of our
judicial authorities competed to prevent
investigative detect prosecute serious
crime
okay you can discuss about it
but also
administrative or judicial authorities
competent prevention investigation
detection prosecution criminal offense
not serious crime it's so in the law an
infected the discussion is serious crime
that's the only possibility to to to
collect data to have access to data it's
literally in in the the new Belgian law
that also administrative and judicial
authorities can have access for criminal
offense not serious crime
in some other seven others also
well I can can stop here I will finished
with
uh one citation
of the Belgian
protection authority the Privacy
commission uh
they look to this low and they give an
advice about the project of the law but
between the real law and the project
there was not so many uh
difference
what did the Belgian Authority say
however
and also the Belgian constitutional
Court say that however it should be
noted that the preliminary drafts low
does not really
entail the change of perspective as
acquired by the judicial Dance of the
European court of justice and the
Constitutional Court in its opinion
The Authority notes that the preliminary
draft law intends to impose new measures
for retention of traffic and location
data which could lead to de facto
de facto reintroduction of generalized
and indiscriminate data retention
obligations while at the same time
increasing the possibilities for Access
until search data is further expanded
that I normally when you look at that
you stop it you stop it is slow
and to finished
the same Authority it is therefore
crucial to ensure that the draft law
does not reintroduce the uni or de facto
generalized obligation to retain the
traffic or location data of all or to
many of the users of electronic
communications in Belgium I finished
with that because it it gives a very
good summary of what of the problem
who's happened at this moment with the
third law in Belgium thank you
thank you very much this was very good
to hear so we have very clear issues
that we need answers to in terms of what
is serious crime what is the data that
you need to come from can it be targeted
while de facto reinstating Mass
surveillance all these would like to
have the audience ask more specific or
in-depth question about so if you have
any feel free to ask them now
um otherwise keep them for later but
happy to have them now
um
you touched also on a couple points that
Patrick I believe will will go into for
example what the the Dynamics are in
terms of of pressure what the direction
taken is
um you mentioned IP addresses being been
retained
Etc
um Patrick I believe you're going to
speak about uh
situation in Germany in the space net
case but also uh the Alternatives so I
want to ask you why are we still here
today given there have been so many
cases at the court of justice and other
other courts as well
um has not has everything not been said
why
um is there so much pressure from a
legal but also political point of view
since you are both an MEP and a judge
um for this Mass surveillance
in can we say all member states
not quite all but nearly all I'm first
of all happy to be having this panel on
on data retention and that so many of
you are interested in the topic because
it's an old topic but also one where
Civil Society has been really successful
in pushing back against this the court
of justice and null the European um
directive on data retention and really
set red lines to this type of mass
surveillance so
um it is so important that we keep
fighting and defending it and thank you
for all your your work in in doing so
also in Belgium now as to the situation
in Germany
um we also have a history of a First
Data retention law 2009 that was
annulled by the Constitutional Court in
2015 another data retention law came
into Force but administrative courts
decided soon after this is in plain
violation of the case law of the
European court of justice and they
suspended this law and that's basically
the legal situation we are at in
September of last year as we've heard
the court of justice annulled or
basically declared the German
legislation in violation of fundamental
rights of the EU karda and the main
reason it gave was that this data could
reveal habits of everyday life a
permanent or permanent temporary places
of residence daily or other movements
the activities carried out the social
relationship of those persons and the
social environment frequented by them so
the court understands very well just how
sensitive this data is is but as has
been said previously it no longer
applied these principles to the
indiscriminate and general retention of
IP addresses which is a huge problem
because these IP addresses allow for
tracing your activity on the Internet
it's like a fingerprints that you are
leaving on whichever websites you visit
they usually keep exact logs of your
activity even if you're not signed in
they will retain logs of your IP address
and what exactly you were reading or
posting online and the fact that this is
being treated differently by the court
is a huge problem
the court also allowed for a so-called
quick freeze procedure which would then
be used to
preserve data on a case-by-case basis
that could be needed to prosecute
serious crime
in Germany then in ensured a fierce
debate within the government which
consists of liberals and greens that
have always opposed General data
retention but also social Democrats that
have actually enacted the law that was
subject to the judicial review
and so in October of last year the
German Minister of Justice a liberal
proposed a law that would replace the
current data retention regime altogether
by a quick freeze regime and notably not
using the opportunity for a general and
indiscriminate IP retention
and the quick freeze regime that they
propose would mean that at the first
step it would generally require a court
order or in Urgent cases an order by a
Judicial Authority the prosecutor to um
preserve a certain data of specific data
and in the second phase there would
another order would be required to
actually access
the retained data if needed for a
specific investigation
and um so um this quick freeze procedure
which is targeted it is certainly a much
better alternative because it's a
case-by-case basis it doesn't uh place a
general suspicion on the entire
population so
um this is the right way to go but I
think the scope is too wide because the
proposal doesn't provide clearly
um how restricted these freeze orders
would be so it's worded so vaguely that
you could basically
um have them very a general and say in
order to investigate a certain uh
a suspect we basically need to preserve
every data because everything could be
relevant and that is a great risk in the
current wording of The Proposal but
anyway
um there is a deadlock in in government
because
the other side the minister of the
Interior who is a Social Democrat keeps
calling for a general retention of Ip
records of the entire population and
will not agree to anything less
and what they are mostly arguing with is
child protection
however I don't see that a general IP
data retention would actually improve
the situation when it comes to
Prosecuting a child sexual exploitation
and I will provide you with some
arguments
first of all we know because of a
parliamentary question that Germany
fails to trace only three percent of
Nike make reports of alleged child
pornography even so there is no a
general IP data retention in place at
current only three percent of reports
cannot be retraced they are just very
fast and usually they can retrace IP
addresses within the few days that the
providers will keep them for business
purposes anyway
furthermore
um
Germany anyway is able to prosecute more
than 90 percent of all
CSM investigations without IPA blanket
IP data retention being in in force and
also a research by the European
parliament's research service that I
commissioned found that throughout the
European Union there is no statistically
significant impact on crime or crime
clearance rates When comparing those
countries with IP data retention in
place to those countries that do not
have as such a regime
and also we can see that in in EU
countries that have IP data retention in
place the crime clearance rate is also
at present no no higher than in other
countries so that's why I think that
there is a lack of evidence that
um this actually significantly
contributes to uh Prosecuting this these
types of crime
um governments still tend to to push for
it and we can see at EU level where
there is indeed a discussion on
reintroducing a a new European
instrument on data retention that the
greatest consensus among National
governments is on mandating IEP data
retention which is a great risk because
basically even in those countries where
the Constitutional courts or the
parliaments have decided against it they
would be forced by Union law to
reintroduce it and that would in the end
make every online activity traceable
it would not affect a criminals because
they can easily hide between
um anonymization Services
data retention is ineffective for um
the
covert investigations that are needed
for example to um
prosecute a child porn rings that
usually use self-hosted forums and
encrypted archives data retention cannot
be used in that area but it takes very
targeted investigations
so what we need to talk about and what
is what I think is the greatest threat
to fundamental rights is the lack of
discussion on real solutions and and
Alternatives that are not as easy as a
piece of legislation that Parliament can
simply decide
so um what kind of alternatives are
there if we want to protect children and
we all want to do that
um let me just name a few that I've
noted down here what about an emergency
number for children or um if somebody
has knows that some children is in
danger what about well-equipped
counseling centers they keep complaining
that
um they are suffering from a lack of
funding what about Anonymous content
contact points also for perpetrators who
seek help there is therapy on offer but
not enough places for
pedophiles who want to receive therapy
what about public education campaigns
mandatory child protection programs in
schools sport clubs churches all these
are places where child sexual abuse
often typically it takes place
trained Child Protection officers
police units that are specialized and
and trained in in processing this uh
these crimes if you distribute the
prosecution to local police offices they
often don't know how to deal with it
professionally they don't know how to
identify victims they don't know what to
prioritize
that is a problem we are seeing with law
enforcement at present
what about online police patrols or
login traps that will be able to
um
preserve the IP address of a suspect the
next time they log in that usually works
for services that require a login
without IP data retention in place so
there are so many Alternatives that need
to be thought of and that would be so
much more effective but not as easy to
to put in place so we certainly need
more dialogue between Child Protection
experts and fundamental rights experts
and um
we need to learn from
experiences such as the horrific case in
Germany in ludica where children
suffered 20 years of abuse and the
report on this actually concluded that
this was due to a failure of authorities
and a lack of Investigations and the
same is the case often when it comes to
abuse within Church authorities no more
surveillance is needed for that
so let me get close with um two uh
remarks the first is a very recent and
pending case on daily retention we still
have with the European code of justice
is the hadoopy case which is about what
are the conditions for accessing IP data
retention the code of justice said you
couldn't retain it indiscriminately but
you can use it only for prosecuting
serious crime and now The Advocate
General in this Adobe case actually
proposes to drop this requirement and
allow to access your generally retained
IP addresses even for prosecuting any
crime including copyright
a law which is of course a huge
expansion of of purposes and would
result in many more accesses to to
retrace your internet activity
and finally a remark on what Ralph
described and how the governments deal
with this case law and Belgium is just
one example of many a similar ones we
really have a crisis of the rule of law
in the EU if you see how they deal with
this case law on data retention how they
show contempt for it and how they try to
circumvent it to to use all sorts of
Tricks but sometimes openly disregarded
or even make laws that are worse than
the ones that have been annulled and the
governments even put pressure on the
courts as as you described it to some
effect actually the court starts to
introduce exceptions
but the EU commission is completely
standing idly by it would be their job
to enforce the case law on the Privacy
directive and not a single enforcement
procedure has been brought forward
because the response of a commissioner
interior commissioner Johansson is
herself in favor of data retention and
so this is really a crisis of the the
rule of law the EU keeps
saying that Hungary and Poland have
problems there but in fact when it comes
to data retention this is a crisis
nearly throughout the EU where
governments are not willing to to follow
the rulings and to protect our
fundamental rights and that's why it's
important that we stand up for our
fundamental rights that we reject any
kind of of General data retention which
would affect
450 million EU citizens place them under
a generous suspicion massive violence is
the opposite of what European values
embody and you already mentioned the
Democratic Society what does it take to
have a Democratic Society and the the
threat we are seeing is the ignorance
for finding real solutions we need to
work on Alternatives and we need to
engage experts in in doing that and
that's the positive outlook that I have
that it is possible and we have an
opportunity to convince the policy
makers of of better approaches
thank you Patrick thank you very much
this is at the same time Bleak and also
optimistic
um I mean hopeful looking
um
what's really good is that you provide
Alternatives I I think in that you don't
come with just we don't want this
therefore it's out and we don't want
discussion even
um
does the urgents have ideas about other
Alternatives that have not been
mentioned for example or before we move
on to specific questions other than this
is anyone aware of Alternatives that
have that exist and have not been put on
the table
um
if not we'll move on to the questions
I think this is there was a question
from online
just from Twitter uh Nicholas
um was if
um panelists can address what is the
role of aeropol to gather and process
personal or like a communication data
that's the question
can you keep the microphone and give it
to anyone who has questions following
this in the meantime while we answer
this question you may think of your own
questions if you have any doubts or any
Clarity who wants to take this question
on the role of oral Paul in gathering
data
yes um maybe just a quick information
for the first part europol stores all
the data that they receive from member
states so it turns out and there is a
procedure with pending with the European
data protection supervisor that they are
storing masses of data and also bulk
data on millions of citizens
um
um uh which the European data protection
supervisor says is illegal but europol
refuses to um to delete and they have
now gone to court against the revised
europol regulation and mandate which
seeks to legalize this bulk storage of
data on on citizens some have said that
what your poly stirring goes beyond what
the NSA is storing and this is really
worrying and for the other part with the
new europele reform europol has received
the power to directly request data from
private companies so they can ask for
data however the companies are not
required to hand it over and maybe data
Privacy Law May prevent them from
serving those requests we don't know at
this time how often they use these new
powers we don't know whether companies
will agree to handing over data but
there is a mandate
thank you Patrick
is there any other question right now
otherwise
we I may have questions for the pendants
myself or I may allow them to go into
greater depths about things that have
been mentioned in that would benefit
from having more details I'll give you
30 seconds without saying anything so
that the
those of you who are brave enough can
raise their hand
oh
hi Patrick Williams
um from Manchester United University
um everyone on the panels made reference
to the problem of crime definitions of
crime and I think the final point you
were making Patrick around the fact that
the vast majority of child abuse will
take place in the home and in the family
means that any response to it is not
really going to get to those issues so
I'm wanting to what extent that could be
a valuable lens strategy through which
the transist worked
um Arguments for Mass potential given
that crime in and of itself is really
problematic and vague and it's an
absolute an objective fact of reality
I think this question was directed to
all of you equally but
if I'm not wrong so if anyone wants to
take it
interesting lands and we do have a
problem of definitions because for
instance serious crime is not actually
defined in the EU when we have a lot of
different instruments
um having their own definitions which
might depend on how many years of
imprisonment is at risk and I have also
seen an Empirical research on what
actually the citizens consider to be
serious crimes might not correspond to
what they you thinks it's serious crime
so uh for sure I I completely agree with
you that the lens of looking into the
causes of crime the social and
socioeconomical causes of crime and how
can we address them in the roots rather
than this Mass data surveillance
instruments but we can see that this is
not happening also with new technologies
which are being developed or under
development and whereby it's more about
looking for patterns of suspicious
behavior that actual doesn't have any
causal link to the the sources of crime
but only looks into correlations between
types of behaviors and criminal acts
um so yes I think we should refocus
precisely as you mentioned what what are
we looking for exactly and what do we
want to solve
thank you
I understand your question
this question about what scribe about
serious crime and and what can you do
against that and what's the
um what can you do with this kind of
flows again serious crime
in the Belgian in low also in the third
low they
give a reference to what so is so-called
as serious crime that or
43 crimes for who the the the
not the prosecuted
okay the special person who can do these
kind of interventions
is competence but that's a list of 43
crimes in who are not really serious
crimes serious crimes what is that the
terrorism
and things like that that can be that or
things about against children and and
things that that means my opposite my
position is that when you make these
kind of laws you have to give your own
definition of
serious crimes they don't do that they
make reference to
General position in the Belgian criminal
law
second point
in in Patrick knows it better than me
they make a report to see if this kind
of laws have any influence in the
solution of crimes you you can give
better the answer but
mostly it's not any proof about that and
in Belgium there was the the president
of the the high court in Antwerp Antwerp
who make his Mercurial that is the
speech he gave by the beginning of the
year the geological year and he speak
also about these kind of laws and you
say what's the experience in Belgium
about the payload that there was a law
and there was not a law because the
first law was working
annulated period of Nolo Second Law
working period of no law and so on he
said what did you have any proof that in
this period the the it was a element to
give solutions to the crimes
and his conclusion is there is not any
statistic not any statistic in Belgium
they don't know it and that that's the
that's not serious when you have these
discussions in the Parliament that are
things that you have to know you you
know you must know objective elements to
uh to to make this kind of uh
definitions third and last point
that is a problem
you you may be in Belgium of the sky
question maybe I don't know if you know
the sky
uh question but in in France they
they find the description of the sky
telephones
and uh
where at this moment I think based on
the description what's in the sky sky
telephones were used by
criminals in the direct traffic scene
and at this moment there are in the
prison in Antwerp about 150 people who
were imprisoned based on that kind of
description
okay it's a discussion
because
the lawyers who have to defend these
Case by the tribunals they say yeah but
there is a problem with the Belgium data
Belgian uh with the a privacy uh
directive and so on but the Belgian
courts reject this opposition but okay
in this kind of uh files you see that it
can bring some
elements to the to solution of the
crimes that's all what I say about it
Patrick do you want to add something on
this question of serious crime perhaps
on the question of should we have an EU
wide notion of the EU crime
um
perhaps because I I hear that in the I
think media Freedom actors there might
be a mention in the council documents of
what a serious crime is
regardless of where whether there is or
not is it something that we should look
into
I'm afraid that if we had an EU
definition they would use that as an
opportunity to introduce data retention
and also every member state would add
their crimes to it and we would end up
with a catalog that's even larger than
43 types of crime so I can't say I
support that but I fully agree with what
Ralph said on
um if the the court says you can do data
retention for National Security you can
do data retention to to target areas of
of you know specific risks then I wonder
what about any evidence that data
retention specifically is strictly
necessary to prevent threats to National
Security to prevent terrorist attacks to
protect the court buildings and the
European Parliament has retained data
ever been needed for these purposes so
they just set out purposes but they they
don't specifically
request
evidence that this is strictly necessary
to attain those aims and I can only say
that when it comes to France they have a
general data retention regime just in
Belgium based on a permanent threat to
National Security but they had data
retention in place when any of the
terrorist attacks that happened in
France had happened and I've not heard a
single case where this would have helped
to prevent these attacks so I don't see
the evidence that data retention is
actually a useful tool to counter these
threats and that's something which I
think the case law and the court needs
to look into more because a general
requirement of proportionality is always
is something strictly necessary to
attain the the aim that you aim for
that was always a discussion is it
necessary in a Democratic Society
the the European court of justice
also was confronted with this discussion
and they say in
the space net judgment
article
96.
because that was also an argument in
Belgium the the prosecutors and so on
they say yeah we need it for a criminal
to to to to fight against the serious
crime
the court say in the European culture in
that regard it must be observed in the
first place that the effectiveness
effectiveness of criminal proceedings
generally depends not on a single means
not on a single means of Investigation
but on all means of Investigation
available to the competent National
authorities for those purpose that means
they have also in Belgium at all in all
the countries they have other means to
to to do the persecution of crime but
okay it it's a discussion
thank you very much we are reaching the
end of the panel so if anyone has a
question pending ask it now otherwise
we'll move on with concluding remarks
I'll give you 10 seconds
we move on therefore closing remarks
um I think the message that this this
panel gives is that uh
it's intended for for civil study but
also for commission and governments is
that we are critical of what's being
made of the steps that are being taken
we are aware of what is being made and
taken
um and that we are not tired we're not
we're going to fight this fight I I hear
that you were going to appeal the
Belgian proposal
um
therefore I want you to conclude and
reflect on perhaps what
um
what is uh worse
the the impacts of crime when we don't
have data retention if it were effective
or the impact of having an old again and
again the data region sorry the data
retention loss so what is worse having
crime that is not tackled through data
retention or having crime that
was supposed to be tackled but because
we I know the data retention laws over
and over they are not able to be pursued
in court if we have to cancel these uh
these Skype cases for example
um and what is the most important
threats also in the forthcoming years in
terms of data retention
thank you
um I agree with everything already said
that we don't really have any
information as to whether crime is
actually not being solved when we don't
have data retention or it's more solved
when we do have data retention schemes
and let's not forget the data are
retained for business purposes in any
case for a few for a period of time so
it's not like data are immediately gone
forever
um so with regards to the to the first
part I think we have already established
we definitely need a lot more uh
empirical information on what types of
data are actually necessary and
effective in contributing to specific
types of crimes
um with regards to the Future looking
ahead
um yes as I mentioned I think that this
should be more specifically regulated
because the court of justice is also
Bound by the preliminary questions every
time it keeps on repeating it's a case
law it keeps on
um
being restricted in specific areas and
I'm not sure we can go much further only
with case law and knowing that the data
retention directive was annulled perhaps
a new legislative initiative would be a
lot more careful in the impact
assessment that it it's mandated to have
in order to pass so that would be my
suggestion or thought for the future
yep
when they invite us for this
discussion they say can you prepare what
challenges you see for the future
I have two challenges first
that we've in the case against the third
Belgian law
because
you can discuss many things but it's a
Concrete question to to stop these kind
of flows and it's not an even not
evident to win it but that's the first
point we will do everything for that but
it's not along the lodge who have to to
to
do their work but I think the everyone
who is interested in privacy and
democracy must support these kind of
procedures because we know that also a
little bit of pressure of outside on the
on the courts can be a little help
for this kind of procedures that's the
first point in
also what we need for the league for
human rights is money we have not so
much money to do this kind of of
procedures that it should be very good
when there is a European funds for that
in which we can collect money and I
think they're all in in Belgium but also
in Europe many people who want to give
100 euro for for this kind of of
procedures and this kind of fight
that's my first wish
and a second wish is that
I write my book book big broadly in
Europe in 2010
and then I say uh at that moment climate
change was coming up
but I also and it's very important
but I also say private change is coming
up but you don't see it you don't feel
it you don't you feel it only when there
are accidents and and things like that
that and it's not easy to make to make a
popular item from privacy I know it it's
a it's not like climate you feel it when
the rain is coming to Merchant so on but
for privacy it's it's another uh it's
like Atomic that you don't feel it's
it's that problem that means that I it
should be good when they're on on
European level
there's some coordination collaboration
between all the people who are
involved in this kind of of discussions
and this kind of struggle we I think we
must need a kind of European there are
many uh different uh Society ngos who
who make these kind of things
in France and and others that
and maybe that's that stood to you that
I I
do this demand to try to coordinate on
the European level the struggle to
defend privacy because there is climate
change but there is also private change
and we have to do with all the the
people who who are concerned about that
we have to do something it's really what
you say it's linked also with the the
time period the
the rule of flow is not only in this
question that the rule of law is under
pressure it's in many other discussions
that we applied not only not only on the
Belgian level but also on the European
level also the the court in uh sales
board the the order on the pressure and
we from from police politicians who say
we reject the judgments of the of the
higher courts okay that's my second wish
to to the European uh struggle for the
Privacy I think you have I can give your
microphone to Patrick sorry this is the
fourth one even if you want to raise
funds rough I'm happy to support and
also redistribute the call for funding
um as for the how does it affect crime
I'm not I don't have a bad conscience in
fighting data retention because I know
that the crime clearance rate is not
influenced by whether there is a data
regime in place or not we can witness it
in Germany that there was no effect
whatsoever when the law was no longer
applied and so I'm not worried at all
certainly there will be one case or the
other that investigators can
specifically point to here it would have
helped us here it may have prevented an
investigation but there are also a
counterproductive effects of data
retention for example many more people
use anonymization service if there is a
data retention scheme in place that is
what polls have found in Germany and so
it can actually be harmful to criminal
investigations and basically push crime
to places that cannot be investigated
even in a in a targeted manner and
finally when it comes to the Future and
the Outlook I just want to say that if
ever the EU commission considers to
propose legislation to bring back data
retention at EU level they can meet the
fierce fiercest resistance of the
European Parliament as can already be
witnessed in the current discussions on
the Privacy regulation where council is
trying to bring in data retention we are
totally refusing that and would rather
give up the entire legislation than
agree to that and so I can only warn the
commission not to to try to bring this
instrument back be it with regard to IP
addresses or otherwise they've totally
failed in court with the data retention
directive and we should find
alternatives
thank you all these powerful words let's
close the panel thank you very much for
your attention