[Music]
hi
my name is martin i'm the head of
research at mnemonic
i'm here to talk about adversary
emulation more specifically
on how to generate sequences of
techniques
from microplex first a little bit of
background
on adversariation
we defend against real adversaries
and in order to test our defenses we
should test them against
real world adversary behaviors
and we can do that by using adversary
emulation in order to do that
we need a plan an adversary emulation
plan
this is an example of the first
adversary emulation plan
published by mitre on apk3
and the figure shows the different
phases
of the attack and the activities that
the adversary performs within each phase
now adversary emulation plans
have developed further since this plan
was published
and the current state of the art is that
an adversary emulation plan
consists of three main components the
first
is the intelligence summary which gives
a general overview of the adversary
with references the second component
is the operational flow where
the techniques used by the adversary are
chained together
into a logical flow to show the progress
of an attack
and the final component is the emulation
plan itself
step-by-step instructions showing
each command executed by the adversary
of that step
making adversary emulation plans require
a substantial amount of time
expertise and effort and it's largely a
manual task
so one of our goals was to see
whether or not we could automate parts
of this process
to speed up the creation of adversary
emulation plans
now adversary emulation plans are
based on my choice adversarial tactics
techniques and common knowledge
also known as attack an attack is
security and knowledge base and model
for adversary behavior
mitre attack consists of the following
core components tactics that are
tactical adversary goals during
intrusion
examples include initial access
persistence
natural movement collection exfiltration
then the second component is techniques
and techniques
describe how an adversary
achieve these tactical goals so one
tactic can have multiple techniques
some techniques are in principle the
same
as techniques they just have a more
detailed description
and finally mitre attack contains
information about adversary usage of
techniques
what kind of software they use
descriptions of their procedures and
other kinds of metadata
microattack has an object relationship
model
which is shown here so in the top left
you have an adversary group
this adversary group uses techniques and
some techniques
and they also use software
and that software implements techniques
and some techniques
a type contains mitigations that prevent
techniques
and finally techniques and some
techniques accomplish
tactics as you might notice
there are no relations between
techniques and sub techniques
so mitre attack does not contain any
kind of information
on what relations or dependencies you
have
between techniques and that's
an issue if you want to change
techniques together
so our problem statement what we try to
solve was
to generate the operational flow of an
adversary group
or a campaign or an incident
that means you can spend the time
expertise and effort once
and then reuse that every time you want
to generate a new operation as well
there is some previous work on this
topic
mitra caldera is a tool for automated
red tv and caldera has a concept of
preconditions and post conditions for
attack steps that are mapped to
techniques
and the apple bone from my crew took the
instant step further at the first
conference in 2019
where he presented how to
use caldera to change
techniques together in microattack now
the limitations on this previous work is
that
it doesn't cover all of microattack it
only covers the techniques and some
techniques that are defined in magical
era
and second it's tool centric to
micrometrical there
because the preconditions and post
conditions in
caldera are very closely tied to the
toolbox
that caldera provides so we want a
general way
to describe dependencies between
techniques
in order to generate chains and
uh from a threat actor incidental
campaign
and to achieve that we applied promise
theory
i will not go into the details on
promised promise theory here if you're
interested there's a link at the bottom
to the paper that introduced it
but i'll give a very very simplified
explanation of how we use it so promise
theory consists of autonomous agents
and promises and a promise is a
statement of intent
basically an autonomous agent saying i
can provide this
and as opposed to the classical way of
thinking where
one agent would call another agent and
ask it for something so give me this
like a function call or a web request
in promise theory each autonomous agent
says
i can provide this and then the
agent that needs that promise will
look for other agents that provide it
that can give it to it and then this
agent might again
provide promises that are required by
other agents so the advantage of
benefits of using from a theory is that
it's capable
there's no explicit coordination between
these autonomous agents so they can
self-organize
and it's distributed so that
you can view each autonomous agent
without
considering all of the other autonomous
agents
so the way we use it in a general model
is that
we view techniques and sub techniques as
autonomous agents
and then each technique or some
technique
has a set of preconditions or requires
there are promises that are needed to
execute
the technique furthermore
it also has a set of post conditions or
provides
which is a set of promises that are
provided after executing a technique
and since every technique and sub
technique is autonomous
analysts can review them separately and
they don't need to
consider anything else than one specific
technique they're
assessing here now but
one example just to illustrate this this
is a technique
remote services from the lateral
movement tactic
uh it has a required section with
four promises access network credentials
users
info network hosts and info network
services
access network means that it has access
to
the internal network of the target
infrastructure
credentials users means that it has
access to valid credentials for
multiple users in the infrastructure
info network hosts means that it knows
about
posts and addresses of other systems
in the infrastructure and finally info
network services
means that it knows what kind of
services
that are running and listening on that
reports
in the infrastructure finally
there's a provide section and it
provides the promise moved laterally
moved laterally means that the adversary
is now no longer constrained
to the single system where they gain
initial access they have moved and they
have access to
several different systems in the target
infrastructure
another a little bit more elaborate
example
with two techniques so here we have the
phishing technique and
the user execution techniques
the first promise i'll show is info
email address
this promise represents the knowledge of
a valid email address
in the target organization and you see
an incoming error to phishing that means
that
phishing requires info email address
in order to execute once executed
phishing provides
to deliver tool delivery means that you
have the
capability to upload or deliver
an arbitrary payload to a target system
tool delivery is required by user
execution but user execution
also requires another promise called to
available
tool available represents the fact that
an adversary has
access to a tube or malware
and that's different from having the
capability of delivering
a payload to a target system so user
execution requires both
and as you might see in this picture we
have no techniques that provide
info email address or two available
which means that by themselves these
two techniques cannot be executed
because they require promises that are
not
provided by any of the teachers
finally user execution provides
four promises privileges use local
access file system
access memory and code execute
so the approach to we wanted to
be able to generate these
sequences or chains of techniques
and we started out by developing a
vocabulary of promises
the first thing we did was to
investigate sticks and mic
vocabularies but we couldn't find any
that were at the right abstraction level
to fit
techniques and some techniques in
microattack
so we started developing our own
vocabulary
and then we reviewed all techniques and
sub techniques in microattack
and we defined which promises
are required by and which promises are
provided by
every one of those techniques of
techniques
we also developed a tool that could
generate attack stages
based on this information that tool is
open source it's on github
on the link on the bottom of this slide
and i'll
give a demo of that tool a little bit
later
and this was an iterative process so we
did one pass at least then we went back
expanded and refined the vocabulary
reviewed the techniques again
improved the tool and cycled through
like that for several iterations
so we're not done with this work but
we've gotten to the point where
it starts to become useful and we hope
that this tool can be useful to other
people as well
so to give a very brief overview of that
tool
the tool takes three inputs the first
input is a list of techniques and
subtechnics
it supports uh attack navigator layers
uh but it also supports a very simple
json format which
is just a list of json list of
technique and subtechnique ids from
microattack
the second input is the definitions of
the requires and provides for each
technique in microattack we have a big
json file with all those definitions on
github
as part of the data for this tool
and the final input is the end condition
or objective
and that could be exfiltration
destruction
extortion denial of service
representing what the adversary
tries to achieve by this intuition
some techniques provide this
unconditional so in order
to reach it you need to execute one of
those techniques
when executed the tool initializes by
creating an empty queue
and then for each attack stage it
executes all techniques and sub
techniques
where all promises
in the requires section of that
technique are present in the queue
that also means that for the first stage
only techniques with no requirements can
be executed
next it adds all of the promises
in the provide section of the executive
techniques to the queue
and then it advances to the next stage
and thus this all over again
and it keeps doing this until it is
unable to
execute any more new techniques of
techniques
the output the main output is
a table with the stages of the attack
and the corresponding techniques and sub
techniques but it can also display
the tactics that those techniques belong
to and
the promises that were provided during
that stage
and finally it outputs a verdict and
that verbatim is whether or not
in the uncondition that was given as
input was
achieved given the techniques
that were available
so i want to give a quick demonstration
on what
this tool looks like and how it works
the tool on github is
command line but we have a prototype web
interface
which is shown here
and in order to run the tool you first
have to select
a threat actor or incident so
for this example i'll use the master
screen
[Music]
then you need to select an end condition
so i will
choose objective exfiltration
which means they want to find the
information they're after and exfoliate
i want the tool to show the promises
that were obtained or provided during
its stage
and then run it
so when i do this
the first thing that happens is that the
tool says it failed incomplete attack
chain
and the only thing that happened was
that at stage one it executed
brute force password spray which
provided credentials usually local and
then nothing more happened
and the reason for that is that
the techniques associated with lazarus
group in microattack are not
sufficient to be able to carry out an
intrusion
so in order to see what would happen
if they had other techniques i can give
them the technique
gather victim identity information which
is
we'll provide them with with a valid
email address
in the target organization the technique
id is
1589 so just
add that and then
run it again
so now this is the technique that i
gave them gather victim identity
information
and what happened is that they are now
able
to launch a phishing attack as you saw
in the previous
example with phishing and user execution
you might remember from that example
that user execution
also required to available
and that's actually what's missing you
because
from the fishing spearfishing attachment
you get tool delivery so you now have
the capability to deliver a piece of
malware
but you might not have that malware in
the first place
so the next step is that i grant lazarus
group access to
develop capabilities which is 1587.
and i run it again so now they have
access to malware and then
a whole lot more happens at stage 3
we get user execution of a malicious
file
then they move on to
internal discovery on the target system
they obtain persistence they do
privilege escalation
and they reach some of the other
objectives like the amount of service
destruction
computational resources but they do not
reach objective acceleration
one of the missing pieces for reaching
that
is they don't have a command control
channel
so
what they're missing to get the command
control channel is command and control
infrastructure they don't have any
technique that gives them
command and control infrastructure there
is a technique called acquire
infrastructure
which i can give them assuming that
laster is group has
access to economic control
infrastructure and that technique is
1583.
we run it again so
the main difference here that this is
not that much more exciting than the
previous execution but
uh at this point
they're able to establish command
control which gives them the promise
adversary control communication job
so okay they're still not able to
complete their objective which is
acceleration
the last missing piece here is that
they're not able to do lateral movement
because they do not know
about other hosts and services in the
infrastructure
which is a requirement for moving and
laterally
so i will give them the technique
network service scanning
which is number 1046
and run it again
and at this point the tool says success
because what happened now is that at
stage seven
they move laterally using remote desktop
protocol
at stage eight they collect data from
local system
which gives them the target information
and at stage nine
they archive stage and exfiltrate that
data
which reaches objective exfiltration
so just a quick this was a threat factor
we also have
incidents here so just a quick example
of a solar winds incident
without giving them any pre-seated
techniques i just run it with the
attack navigator layer that describes
the solarwinds incident
they're actually able to do quite a lot
because they start off with
supply chain compromise
they obtain execution defense elevation
persistence
command control channel privilege
escalation
but they are missing some techniques to
get
all the way to exfiltration so there are
some missing parts here but
uh at least the first four stages of the
attack or intrusion are pretty complete
compared to
that
so back to the presentation
that was a demo um then i want to talk a
little bit about some issues that we
have
these are not necessarily issues with
attack
that there is something wrong with it
but it's an issue for how we use attack
so the first issue we have that is that
the tactics defense salvation
and persistence they don't really drive
an attack chain any further they might
be necessary for an adversary
to avoid detection and to be able to
come back at a later time
but they don't give you they don't let
you progress to the next stage
of the intrusion so for those techniques
we basically just say that
okay you achieve persistence you achieve
the translation
but those promises are not used by
or required by any other techniques
the main issue we have with attack is
that an attack basically consists of two
different types of techniques
the first one is we call how it's done
techniques
like exploit public facing application
those techniques describes what an
adversary does
and they map pretty well to what we've
been doing because you can identify
what the prerequisites or requirements
are and you can identify what you get
when you do it
so those techniques are fine the main
issue
is that attack also contains what we
call what you get techniques
like valid accounts that don't really
describe
adversary behavior they describe
what the adversary gets which more or
less maps to our
provides promises so we had issues with
that we've tried to get around it but
ideally we would
[Music]
hope that all techniques should be how
it's done
describing how the adversary behaves
rather than what they did
so an interesting side effect of what we
did was that
we pretty quickly started identifying
missing techniques and subjects
and from the demo
you could see that iteratively
you could you can identify candidates
for missing techniques
which takes the generation of the attack
stage one
a step further we also have some
functionality in the tool that i didn't
show to help
identify or pinpoint exactly which
promises
are missing and which techniques that
might provide those promises
so we've already had one submission to
my chair
of missing techniques and we hope to
have more in the future
so the tool also can help as a quality
assurance tool
there's a bunch of caveats um
the first one is that i used last year's
group as an example but
it actually is quite a bad example
because
adversary groups and mitral attacks
are linked to techniques that have been
observed over a very long period of time
so in some cases you might have
aggregated techniques that have been
observed
over a period of more than 10 years and
if we keep doing this
in the future we might have adversary
groups
with a long list of techniques that are
being observed over the time span of
decades
so those techniques don't really tell
you what that adversary
has been doing recently so the best
source of
techniques to be used with this tool is
actually from
incidents or campaigns so you have a
clear
time frame in which you have observed
these techniques
that being said there are not that many
good sources of techniques
except for micro attack so
i don't really see any good alternatives
at the moment but ideally
techniques should be linked to incidents
and campaigns
in addition to threat factors um
also keep in mind that what we've been
doing here
we're not considering any specific
infrastructure we're not
simulating attack or an attack
on a specific infrastructure what the
tool tells you
is these are all the options that the
adversary has
at each stage of the intrusion but those
are options
those are not necessarily what they
would choose to do
but they if you just look at
one path through these options that
might be an attack
so to visualize this as a graph you
would have
edges going out to lots and lots of
nodes further down but
one path through that graph would be
attached
so you don't get that one path from the
tool but you get all the possibilities
then our vocabulary
our vocabulary doesn't cover everything
it's not finished
and we're still working on it and we're
probably going to change this and
change it in the future and finally uh
there's probably mapping bias at play as
well we're humans
we do mistakes um and when we
assign promises to the requires and
provides that's
a little bit subjective it depends on
the experience and the expertise of the
analyst
which kind of brings me to future work
because
we're not able to finish this on our own
if but what we want to achieve is to
develop a standard vocabulary of
promises for us
that's accepted across the industry and
that's not something we can do on our
own
so we're hoping that others will
see the value of this and see that this
might be a useful
way to ultimate generation of
attack stages and then we can
collaborate
on bringing this photo and maybe even
bring it into a standardization body at
some points
so if you're interested in that then
please
uh interact with us on github or contact
us
i will be happy to collaborate the next
step would be attack integration
so whenever you add the new technique to
attack
in addition to what's done today you
also
define the promises provided by
and required by that technique
because once you've done a job of
mapping all the existing techniques
the extra effort of
mapping new techniques is negligible
compared to the big job of doing it to
the
techniques currently in attack and it
has
it is very useful
we also want to integrate this in the
socrates platform i'll get
back to that in the next slide and
finally
more ambitious is that sometime in the
future we would hope
to develop structured procedure
definitions to address the actual
emulation plan part of this so that you
can
take even further steps to automatically
generate
a full adversary emulation
so finally on the socrates project
the socrates project is an innovation
project that
builds a security automation and
decision support platform for socks and
c-serves
it has a web page webpage at
soccertest.eu and
the project is also looking for new
members of the stakeholder group so
if you're interested i think this uh
sounds interesting
please consider signing up for the
stakeholder
that's all from me and thank you very
much