hello everyone and welcome to our
breaking drydex mower talk
at the first conference 2021. my name is
gustavo i'm a security researcher and
manager at
immunity which is part of appgates and
we also have felipe in the call
hello everyone i'm felipe dominguez
security researcher at community
in this presentation we have two
different goals first
showing how our analysis can be used to
identify a threat capabilities
extract iocs and automate detection and
second
showing how a full knowledge on a threat
can help us building tools to fight
against it
for that we'll analyze tridex one of the
most popular malware families currently
active
and then develop a vaccine that can be
deployed on systems to protect against
it
all right thank you very much let me go
over really quick over the presentations
agenda
we will start by a brief introduction
about drydex showing its anatomy and how
it usually works
then we will demonstrate how the payload
could be obtained
when you have the packet file and once
we have the payload we will then cover
some of the main features about this
malware such as the encrypted strings
the c2 communication
and also what we did to automate the
actionable data extraction with a python
script
later we will demonstrate how drydex
works when it comes to the windows api
resolution
and how we exploited that to create the
vaccine
all right so first things first uh
drydex is
one of the most relevant banking trojans
in the wild
it has first appeared about 10 years ago
as
crydex sharing a lot of features with
the game over zeus
which was another major threat across
the years
drydex has launched a few versions
with many specific features some of
which we will show
in this presentation all right so let's
take a look in the infection chain
uh drydex is usually delivered through
an infected microsoft office
file which downloads or drops the dridex
loader
the loader is responsible for contacting
the c2 server
and to download additional files such as
the main bots and other modules
so the bot contains most of the drydex
functionalities
such as the keylogger and the web
injections and as just mentioned
drydex is modular which means that it
can download
and execute additional payloads such as
a vnc
file which allows remote access and a
socks prox module
this research is mainly focused on the
dridex loader
and that's because we wanted to make
sure that we can extract the situ server
addresses which are stored in the loader
also we believe that the loader is the
best layer to implement the vaccine
as the downloader can vary a lot and
many of the features implemented by the
loader is also present in the other
layers so we can use most of our
research
in the bots and the modules as well so
the first thing we need to do
when we have a drydex loader is to
unpack the file
almost every loader we have analyzer
contained a custom packer
and the payload is never written into
disk which means that we have to unpack
the file
and dump it so we can analyze the
process is pretty straightforward
once the file is running it decrypts and
executes
a small dll in memory which is
responsible for
unpacking the payload so here we can see
the same process in the immunity
debugger so first the encrypted dll
is copied to a recently allocated memory
then after the printing the bytes the
dll is
executed and the payload isn't packaged
to another memory location
which is eventually executed the dridex
loader could be easily unpacked by
monitoring the calls to virtual lock and
virtual protect
or by using a tool such as a hollows
hunter
once we have the unpacked loader we can
start the analysis on the real file
one of the most important things is that
all the drydex strings are encrypted in
the binary
probably to evade detection and make the
analysis more difficult
fortunately is not a complicated process
all these strings are located in the r
data section of the pe file
and you could identify them by checking
the either cross reference to the
location or using another
disassembly of your preference so here
we have an example showing the reference
to these
our data offsets and we can see that it
is some nonsense bytes
not showing any clear text the structure
is pretty simple the algorithm used by
drydex is rc4
and the first 40 bytes is the key
meaning that the rest of the blob is
just encrypted data
by using a small python script as
demonstrated in the second image we
could easily decrypt those bytes and
review the real stream
so another very important parts is the
c2 communication
as mentioned before the drydex loader is
the one
responsible for contacting the c2
servers to download the bots and the
additional files
the first thing is how the c2 commands
are stored in the file
so drydex uses a very simple process it
calculates the crc32 hash
of the string that represents the commas
so
in this example the string bots which is
the command to download the drydex
magnifier
is represented with this extra decimal
number
which is the crc32 hash of the string
and the mower does that for all the
other strings slash commands
so the way the situ server address is
stored in the binary
depends on the dridex version in the
latest which is the one that we are
showing in this presentation
all the addresses are stored as bytes in
dpe
data section as demonstrated in the
first image
uh we have first two bytes that
represents the botnet id
then one bytes that contains the amount
of ip addresses
that this loader can connect and finally
we have the ap addresses that
are for in this case here on the right
we can see in
immune debugger the exact function that
loads the data on the left
by parsing those bytes and building dip
string
so after parsing the addresses the
loader sends an initial request to the
c2 server with a few information about
the infected machine
so in the left we can see that the data
is properly encrypted
since we can't understand what was
submitted so after reversing a couple of
samples
we saw that this information is
encrypted with rc4
and the key is among tridex encrypted
strings
which we already demonstrated how to
extract so by decrypting the data
we can see some of the information that
is being uploaded to the server
such as the computer name the botnet id
the command strings
as well as the list of the installed
software in the machine
all right so once you know how all of
this works uh what we can do
to make our life easier when it comes to
the analysis
so at this point using python or another
language of a preference
we can automate the extraction of the
botnet id and the c2 server list
which could be very useful for socks or
any black list you may need to feed
we can also decrypt these strings which
contains many useful data such as the
key to decrypt the c2 server
communication
that we can also automate one point that
we need to make clear is that the
automation will not work in 100 of the
cases
since you can have different versions or
variants of the malware
but according to our experience a lot of
code is shared across modern versions
so you could easily track the changes
and update your scripts to keep them
working normally
thinking about that we have compiled
everything we could in what we call it
the drydex analysis toolkit
it was everything done with python and
the script can do pretty much what we
just described it without the need of
analyzing the file manually or
executing it in the github page you can
find all the options provided by the
script
as demonstrated in the second image
so here is an example uh we have
unpacked a drydexloader and then
executed the script with the verbos
and the dash c option which extracts the
situ server list
first the script outputs the binary
information
such as the hashes and the compiled
dates that we read from the pe header
and then in case the file was dumped
from memory and the de file was not
unmapped to disk
the script can do this automatically for
you just save you some time
then it will try to locate the c2 server
list inside the binary
any case it founds it will parse the
data and displays
all the addresses in the screen for you
also if you use
a dash a or the dash s option the two
will decrypt
all the strings it can find also
printing on the screen
the possible rc4 keys use it to encrypt
and decrypt the network communication
and finally all the results are written
into disk so you can have
a full report
alright so what next i will now give the
floor to felipe which will show the main
discovery we did about drydex
after understanding drydex we would like
to cover one more drydex feature
dynamic api call resolution
but first to understand it let's
consider the default way programs make
api calls let's say in the program you
are developing you want to generate
a message box in this case you would
import the windows library and call the
messagebox function
in the compiled program this translates
to an entry on the pe
imports directory table referencing the
dynamic library
and a lookup table containing all the
functions available when the execution
starts
the operation system will allocate to
the library in the memory
if it's not already there and will
provide the address so the binary can
execute the api calls
in a similar way one can build dlls with
functions it would like to contribute as
a library
or equipped outside the main executable
in that case the binary will contain an
export table
addressing the function names and its
addresses inside the binary
let's get a little more deep into that i
promise this will be important
in the windows nt operational system
family we have what is called a process
environment
block this is a structure heavily used
by the so
we can find references into the pad in
the windows internals documentation
but a lot of the fields are not
documented at all
as they should only be manipulated by
this operational system during the
binary load and execution
every process has its own process
environment block
and in one of its fields we have a
pointer to the ldr data structure
which holds the list used to store all
the dialogs loaded in the process
it contains among other things the dll
name and the basic address pointing
to where it's stored in the memory so
when you code an api call in your
program
that's what happens as one can imagine
analyzing a binary import stable can
provide a lot of information on its
usage
and can even use it to identify
potential malicious behavior
that's why as an nt analysis technique
somehower employs strategies to hide
their imports
some uses windows functions like load
library
to load dll inside the code but for
those
that use this feature alone we can find
the loaded dlls and the executed
function
just by extracting the malware strings
in the left here we can see the imports
table of a malware that loads the hd api
to retrieve the allow
this contains functions regarding
registry manipulation
so as an analyst i know i need to
monitor the registries to see
if the malware is loading or reading or
storing anything there
on the right we have a couple of samples
from the drydex loader
the top one being the m packet sample
and the bottom one being the packet
sample
we can see that it doesn't reveal
anything relevant on the malware
capabilities
if drydex api calls are not available in
the binary and extracting the mower
strings we can't find
any references to them either how does
it call them
reverse engineering the binary we found
that the malware executes windows api
calls just like that instead of calling
a function imported from a library it
calls
this function that we name it the
malware ati resolver
this function receives a couple
arguments both crc32 hashes
now the malware access the process
environment block table
and run these functions on each dll name
generating a crc32
if the crc32 matches the one passet as
an argument
it repeats the same with the library
functions and voila
it resolved the api call it just returns
the function address to the program so
the execution can continue
now what happens when a dll is not found
in the process environment block
in other words what happens when the
operational system haven't loaded that
dll in the process yet
well the malware loads it itself it will
search the system directory
and make the same process with the dll
names until it find one that matches the
crc32
and it will load it into the memory
using the
ntdll ldr load dll method
for analysts interested in analyzing
dridex in our github we also
uploaded a 9d script you just need to
add the malware api resolver offset
and it will comment in the decompiler
every code with the real dll
and function the mower is trying to
execute summarizing
that's how drydex hides its api calls
it will first check on a table that
builds in memory
for the api hash passed it as an
argument if not found it will check the
process environment block for the loaded
dll to populate the same table
if it's still not found it will search
the system directory for the dll
by the file name should then load it on
the same table and populate it
now let's go to the interesting part we
left this functionality to present
last as this is the one that we will
exploit to create a vaccine for drydex
as some of you may have noticed it the
malware does not have a way to validate
exactly what dll is loaded on its memory
the only verification it have is the
calculated hash
from the previous diagram we can see how
the malware behaves
loading a dll from the disk simplifying
it will call the malware api resolve
search the dll in the csvo64 directory
in our case
loads the dll that matches the condition
and executes the exported function
crc32 is a very small hash using only 32
bits
it's very prone to hash collisions so
what we're going to do is to create
another dll with a different name
with the same hash so when the mower
tries to load the system dll it will
load hours instead
and when it tries to execute any
function on it our vaccine code will be
triggered
we can use that to sabotage drudex
stopping the process or
generating an alert adding a breakpoint
to the function that loads dll from the
disk
we can see that the first one loaded in
this sample is the sheltery two dialogue
now that we have a candidate for our
collision we can just brute force a
bunch of strings to generate compatible
names
let's just not forget it will be a dll
so it needs to end on dot dll
and that the brute force name is
compared in upper case
we won't show how to build a brute force
script for this as you can just
iterate through hex decimal characters
and test one by one
it's that easy to create a crc32
collision
now with the name of our candidates we
will build a simple dll to generate an
alert
pausing the thread and then it will exit
the process
effectively stopping the malware our dll
needs to have the same export as shelter
e2dl
so let's add the same api names to the
exports.dev
file now with the compiled dll we just
need to edit on the same directory
dradex will look for the dlls
in our case the cisvo 64 directory
as we can see in the same step as before
when we detected sheltery2.tll being
loaded
now the malware is loading our
custom-made dll
let's execute dradex on a vaccinated
environment to see what happens
so here we have our custom-made dll and
the drydex loader
we will open the sysvol 64 directory
drop the dll there and execute the
malware to see how it behaves
so right after its execution it will
show or
alert and after clicking ok the process
will exit effectively stopping the
drydex infection
and voila we are protected against
drydex at least from the sample
we showed here a very simple vaccine
implant that only exits the process
but one might modify our hook stub to
add more functionality
you can create a memory dump of the
process before stopping it
or even signaling the company endpoint
alerting that the system might be
compromised
now let's keep in mind that this is not
a silver bullet against rydex
new versions can employ different dlls
or a shelter into the allow might be a
reading memory
but this process can be replicated for
any dll drydex loads
so if the technique remains the same you
just need to map new candidates and
build your own vaccine
it seems a bit odd to build a vaccine
for one strain of malware
but let's consider a scenario where one
of your clients was infected and you
found the druidic sample in one of the
machines
you could then deploy the vaccine as
part of your incident response
helping in the containment phase
stopping the infection from spreading to
others
and in the remediation phase avoiding
ring faction of the machine you just
found
you can also use that to detect other
machines infected with the mower
as the next time the mower will load it
will load the vaccine instead
building the vaccines is not a
replacement for any security solution
but it can be very useful on
investigating or protecting against a
specific threat
all right thank you very much felipe
here are some of the references and the
resources that we use it across our
research in case anyone needs
further details and that was pretty much
it thank you very much for attending the
talk
and this is the end at least until
drydex updates your new version right so
thank you very much
thank you very much everyone