hi everyone
thanks for again for joining us today
i'm chris with the first events team
and i'll be helping with host
responsibilities on the webinar today
before we get started i would like to
remind everyone that speaker q
a will take place in our conference work
adventure platform
if you are just joining the stream and
are not pre-registered
please send an email to events at
first.org to get set up on the system
work adventure is hosting all of our
conference networking activities as well
as the conference exhibit hall
and with that let's go ahead and get
started and i'll pass the mic over to
our session moderator
marguerita ram
thank you um hi everybody
um so i'm margo and i'll be moderating
this
session today um i strongly
um recommend to join the q a
and the social spaces in work adventure
that was a lot of fun yesterday um
and now i'd like to introduce
kuniko yoshimura he is a cyber security
researcher from
fujitsu system integration laboratories
and he has many years of experience as a
security analyst and researcher
he spoke at first the first conference
in 2018
about multi-dimensional malware
similarities
s4 and in this talk how to apply
machine learning the appropriate way for
our security operation
he will present the best practice on how
machine learning should be applied
using this sample similarity scoring
system improvements
as an example um and apply those methods
in in your environment
to improve operations so this should be
very interesting
uh so go ahead thank you yeah
thank you margaret hi there
i am a kunichiko yoshimura from 52
system integration laboratories
i'm happy to be speaking at this
conference
today i will be giving a talk titled
how to apply machine learning
appropriate way for security operation
this page is about me i have been
working
in the security field for 10 years
i have been doing security operations
for four
years and security research for
six years so i have a good understanding
of both the operations and the research
cultures
as a result of my research i gave a talk
at the first settings annual conference
three years ago i'll talk about it later
based on my experience in
in security operation
uh under knowledge from research
institute
i would like to introduce a recommended
method
that also can be easily used in your
field
okay number one is uh introduction
in the security operation field security
operations
center suck has some missions
for defending organization one of them
is to monitor errors and events
and to alert the incident for ir
team or customers
another one is manage security operation
seats
like firewalls suck
is the front line in the security
defense
and like a star player in managed
security services
soc also has implemented
important tasks to complete
these missions one of them
is to maintain signature rules
of sensors or seams
purposes are to ignore false positive
removable order vulnerability rules that
didn't
exist in the period and
at the signature route that are
appropriate for operations
sock team is always busy
with monitoring and managing
however they should spend more time for
maintaining
maintaining the rules otherwise
unanimous cannot response alerts
effectively
as a result he will not be able to keep
up with it
this diagram is a structural system
in my presentation at three years ago
i developed sample similarity scoring
system
s4 which determine most
similar known malware pieces for new
malware
this tool divides the 17 similarity
truth into three categories
surface dynamic and geometric
integrates the similarity square using
square transformation in each category
and output a result
in a ranking format
i talked about the effectiveness of a
multi-dimensional evaluation by
integrating mario similarity through
scrolls
s4 succeeded clustering pieces of
mario as mario permeates effectively
and support mario analyst by reducing
analysis time
the expo is a useful too but
had the different difficult uh
difficult to tune problem
it is necessary to spend a time for
maintenance tuning
parameter that used in the
square transformation when i
integrated 17 two
squares for three dimensions
i set parameter of piecewise linear
transformation
plt for all of the tools
prt is flexible for human thinking
but it is complex
it needs much time for setting the
appropriate
parameter in short this tool gave
an analyst time reduction
but also time increase
that is a fatal program
in this chapter i'll talk my approach
that i try to apply machine learning for
maintaining
automatically tuning parameters in
each step i will talk about basic stance
for
applying machine learning and examples
i experienced in s4 case
first step also most
important step we should pick a set
of goods for machine learning
in other words it is a planning for
machine learning
at first we decide type of machine
learning
in general there are three types that
be known well supervised running
unsupervised running and reinforced
riding
there are three important points
first it's the defining
a cost function for machine learning
of course the status that cannot be
judged by human being it's
neither by a machine
secondly what is the data you can
prepare
in the learning
you must prepare the data you refer
in the operation and
to discriminate the types of
the data that is
explained next slide
okay sadly is of explain
explanation recently
advanced algorithms like deep learning
is coming in the world
however in the secret operation i don't
recommend that techniques is too
advanced to control by a human
because it often looks at critical
responsibility
in our operation so you should choose
simpler algorithm like regression
analysis
there are two main categories of data
quantitative is a data that changes in
a gradient such as days
or event counts
qualitative is digital such as
on and off
or one and zero
it is important to be aware of which
category the data to be trained
will be
in the expo case squads from several
tours can be prepared
to create an integrated school
this are quantitative data
yes however without pld
we should not prepare integrated scores
for learning in advance
we need to change our thinking
what could i use to prepare the data for
running
the answer is as two pieces of
malware that scores that
same family or different
this is qualitative data because there
are two
are only two ports same and different
in the supervised learning we choose
predicting in a single variable
from module multiple variables
in called multivariable analysis
select the appropriate algorithm by
applying
it to the type of the data
we have just organized
yes this is a case of ether
i chose to use logistic regression
i identified the tools that score
high only for the same family
and then finds a coefficient
that minimizes the distance between them
and the logistic function i mean
i changed square transformation logic
from plt to logistic function
the logistical regression feature is
that the data that was qualitative
at training will be between
1 and 0 in the prediction phase
that is quantitative data
this algorithm is highly recommended
because of
its personality this is because
in the field of secret operation
situations sometimes occur such as
the past data is clearly malicious
and benign however in the projection
stage
we want to predict the priority metric
for responding first
okay step three uh let's code it
i chose to use python uh
because of uh it's versatility
but i think you can use any language
that suits your environment
the code in python is very simple to put
together
just do a fit and predict
two lines of coding under you are done
congratulations
however merely implementing
machine learning is not the goal
rather this is just a starting point
i will explain the actual hurdles
i encountered when applying it
and how i jumped over then
okay chapter three is trial
and errors these huddles
huddle number one is a low winning rate
first i used data from
a test i did three years ago to see if
i could successfully group them
as a result uh while maria farmi didn't
did not recognize many samples correctly
uh we will look at the output data
to find the codes
that the red text on the screen shows
that
the coefficient of one source
is a negative number
uh this means that
the higher the score the more different
the family we examine
the correlation value between the target
variable
and the explanatory variables of the two
correlation bar is an indicator of
how much these two variables are related
and the correlation value is 0.49
a positive number uh which means that
as the one increases that the
other also tends to increase
why is this when
we look at other explanatory variables
we found that there was a very strong
correlation with another explanatory
variable
this problem is called marginal
linearity
and it is one of the problems that must
be avoided
in various machine learning
there are several countermeasures a
simple solution
is to disable one of the correct data
created data but in this case
it could be extreme data so
we try to solve this problem by
dimensional compression
in pca principle of component
analysis a theory of
efficient dimensional remake
there is a metric called the explanation
ratio mainly try to
represent three uh just three
tools in three dimensions and
put those demand dimensions together
efficient
effect efficiently in pca
we are able to represent 97
of the original data in the
two-dimensional states
we thought that if we could truncate
the remaining percentage and perform
regulation
analysis to restore the original
dimensions
we would be able to obtain results
that you are not affected by multiple
linearity
okay huddle number three in further
testing
i increased the number of families to be
trained
to 10. this seems
to work fine but
then i run the calculation with
these parameters i only got
42 points even if i got a perfect
score with all the tools
assuming that there are two samples in
each of the 10 families
the number of combinations with
different family
is 4500
and the same families is 450.
if the data you want to train is
extremely skewed
the results will have to
be skewed to that side
this is called imbalanced data
the solution is simple adjust the amount
of correct rate
increasing the amount of correct data is
all called over sampling and
decreasing the amount of incorrect
data is called under sampling
python already has a variety of
logic modules like saktra available
for this purpose you can choose the
appropriate logic based on the nature
of your data and sometimes by
benchmarking
each of them
next hurdle on the left side of the
screen
is the ranking result of the one of the
three trick box
samples normally we would like to
see trick board at the top of the list
but there are many different types of
mario in the mix in case like
this we examine the
squares of each tool on the sample
visual visualization is useful
for examining the characteristic
of data we if we examine the
distribution of squares
output by one of the tools
on the right side of the screen
we can see that squares for different
combinations have a single mountain
saturn
at 40 percent and the squares
for the same combination have two
mountains
uh one saturn at 80 percent
and the other at the 20 percent
uh if we focus on this 80 percent
mountain
we can do machine learning that clearly
captures
the futures but
machine learning evaluates both mountain
equally
and judges them as
features this problem
is not a general hub
general name i called this program
data overlap
as other countermeasure processing
is performed define something
like what data should be ignored
and in this case ignore the same
combination of
data that is less than
the average of a different combination
of data
this way each of them will become one
mountain
and the two will identify them as a
feature group
now we'll verify that that
the machine learning system we've worked
so hard
to create work properly
first step is the select target tomorrow
families and
retrieve sample randomly we identified
some valuable families
that were popular at that
at the time from the monthly reports
prepared by
the center for internet security
and security uh cis
obtained malware has value from the
information provided by
the cti vendor and downloaded
the samples from virustotal
next compare samples between different
monsters average them arrange
them in chronological order learn
from the past malware and predict
from the future malware finally
evaluation outputs verify uh
that clustering is working uh
by the correct rate and another node
graph
to determine the target marijuana
families i referred to
the monthly reports published by cgis
i chose mario families that
had up appeared in the rankings at
least five times in the seven months
reports
at that time
we randomly selected from a hash risk
based on the
cti of seven selected
mario families and downloaded the
samples
pre present in bios total
this page shows the correct thread from
each mario
which is a quantitative evaluation
result
for reference at the correct rate of a
commercial mario similarity
service is also shown
this service uh has not only
the sim uh similarity between samples
but also the master data of malware
families
and uh benign software like microsoft
binaries
so the value of the service cannot be
measured
by just this
the extra total correct rate is
76 percent which means
that the accuracy of escrow shimmy id
is compatible to that
of commercial services
uh this is a qualitative evaluation
with an autograph showing a relationship
of 19 19 plus
points or more f4 uh connected samples
of the same family successfully in the
most of
cases overall
we can say that the s4 tuning automation
was
a success
okay chapter five conclusion
as for uh which i have just introduced
has a pork ready to be provided
we are discussing the possibility of
making it open source carefully
because of the risk of uh
it's falling into the hands of malware
developers
if you are interested in s4
i can make it available to you
via github after signing on dna
please contact it
okay conclusion uh my takeaway
message is the procedures in
this talk uh should should
help you improve your security
oppression with
machine learning in the social
cooperation
and i need to spend a long time for
tasks like maintaining signature rules
otherwise you must respond to many
others including many unnecessary ones
i served s4 issues in the same
way as mentioned above
with machine learning
ok thank you for listening
right thank you very much that was uh
that was very interesting
um and to all of you
attending uh i'd like to remind you that
there will be a q a
immediately following this presentation
in work adventure
so there's a there's a
separate room where you can enter with
your avatar and
join and i hope to see many of you there
thank you so much for the presentation
again
yeah thank you everyone
right
right um we are
ready for the next session um
i would like to uh welcome you
back here uh i'm margo and i'll moderate
this session
uh there will be a q a immediately
following this presentation in work
adventure
uh the virtual social platform where you
also find the exhibitors
and social activities
um and it's my pleasure to
introduce simon cannon he is a
independent security researcher and
well-known in the security community
he has a broad experience in
vulnerability analysis malorial
analysis forensics analysis and
developing detection
logic as well as keeping track of the
exploit market and the work
world of web exploitation
um today we will learn
uh about what a carrier-grade nut is
what the risks and dangers are of being
part of such a nuts
especially during a pandemic
so um over to you simon
thank you um
just let me share my screen first
it's kind of hard with multiple screens
okay so hello everyone
i hope you are doing well during those
essential times
thank you for joining me today for my
talk about cgn
will not carry great problems
this is my main agenda for the talk i'll
start with some introduction
about some basic concepts of the
internet then i will explain what is cgm
later i will tell you why it is dead and
what we can do to minimize the problems
or even fix them
this is agenda for the introduction this
is not a very technical talk
but i do cover sorry but i do cover
many topics in order to get to my point
so i hope you will keep up and learn
some new things today
as mentioned my name is simon i am 34
years old
i do my lauren equity research for clear
skyber for clear sky cyber security in
israel
and this presentation has nothing to do
with this kind of work
i've been hacking and passionate about
information security since the age of
13.
i had a pv6 on my windows xp with 46
426 tunnel in 2007
and i allegedly did some interesting
things over the years
in this talk we are going way back to
the 80s when the pb4 became standard
we slowly progressed until today to see
what happened
and where we went wrong
the internet was built on the end-to-end
principle
which is simple data between two devices
should be sent as is without any
manipulation on the way
otherwise our connection is not private
and we can't rely on the data to be
secure and authentic
this is a diagram of how end-to-end
should look like
according to the principle the network
is only responsible for providing the
terminals with connections
any kind of intelligence should be
located at the terminals
an example for such intelligence is
modifying a packet area
like destination or source back in the
80s
computers were big and expensive and not
a common commodity like today
even at a later point each house didn't
have more than one computer
this computer wasn't necessarily
connected to the internet
and if it was it wasn't 24 7.
at some point people had more than one
computer at the house
but they had only one telephone or cable
line
there was the need to connect multiple
computers to the same external line
in order to do so natto is created
it maps multiple addresses to a single
point by modifying the headers of the
packets
this behavior breaks the end-to-end
principle
because it plays intelligence but we
control the nut device
so it should be okay as long as we
control it
in this diagram we can see a home
computer which is part of a local
network
trying to communicate with the server on
the public internet
the nut changes the addresses
accordingly so the router
could draw the packets back and forth to
the right destination
inside the local network
at some point the internet becomes so
popular
there was a fear it will be
overpopulated by subscribers
this is because each subscriber should
have a unique ipv for others
and the ipv4 pool size wasn't big enough
in the days of the dialogue moderns
those did the funky noises on dialing
isps started to give dynamic ids to
subscribers
this allowed isps to have more
subscribers than it is
because not everyone were connected at
the same time
but if there was no free ip address you
simply could dial in
and use the internet and then someone
will disconnect
or the sp would purchase more ap
addresses
the depletion was anticipated since the
80s
today there are great markets to buy or
release ipv4 addresses
because all ipv4 space has been
allocated and issued already
let's go back to our timer in 94
nut was proposed and we all use not
nowadays one way or another
only two years later in 96 ipv6 was
proposed
in order to overcome the issues with
ipv4 and to eliminate the need for not
so we could restore the android
principle of the internet
unfortunately we are now in 2021
and we didn't fully adopt ipv6 instead
cgn was created and it is widely adopted
today
cgn is basically a large scale knot
that's a sp control
ejp in this line belong to a subscriber
which also might have their own
controlled knot
cgi was created because at some point
people not only had personal computers
they had to connect to the internet they
had mobile phones with data plans
those phones will dial in when internet
was needed
but later on we started to have
smartphones
that are 24 7 connected all those
devices
need ap addresses which mobile carriers
couldn't provide
if you didn't know 95 percent of mobile
traffic in the world
is behind cgm if you have a smartphone
congratulations you most likely cgn
in this diagram of cgn we can see the
subscribers
have full control over the private
employee space
until it leaves their home equipment and
goes to the private ep space of the asp
we don't control the carrier not at all
therefore
this might be risky you can compare
isp to a bank all customers
hope the bank will keep their money safe
their rules and regulations for the
most of the countries but this is not
the case with cgn
so what do we do is there are no ipv4
addresses left
and cgn doesn't seem like a good
solution
if you've forgotten already in 96 ipv6
was proposed
in 98 it became a draft standard it was
meant to fix all this nonsense
ipv6 can provide a unique external ipv6
address
to all your internet connected devices
and restore
the android principle of the internet
four years ago
in 2017 ipv6
finally becomes standard official
standard by the internet engineering
task force
if ipv6 is so great you would expect it
to be widely adapted after four years
unfortunately we are in 2021
we have no internet connected cars yet
ipv6 adaptation
is still low according to google
only third of google users have ipv6
assigned a site named ynoipv6.com
shows that less than half of alexa top
1000 sites
supported dv6 and that less than third
of alexa top 1 million
sites support ipv6
i will quote the site author and will
say that
this is a huge change i would like
to personally ask you at the end of this
presentation
to check whether your home network
support ipv6
and if it is actually enabled
cgn adaptation on the other hand is only
growing
and will continue to grow if you won't
switch to ipv6
except the obvious fact that it breaks
the end-to-end principle
there are different other issues in
different aspects since cgn introduced
i will elaborate on those new issues in
the next slides
now you can see how cgn deployment
should look like
in theory
it is meant to be deployed in dual stack
each subscriber has a cgn ipv4 address
and also a public external ipv6 address
enjoying both legacy support for a and
ipv6
sounds good but in reality
cgns are the wild west since we don't
have control
over the sp in that device we don't know
how it is configured
they can do whatever they want without
regulation
apparently some sps give only not ipv4
address
without any option for ipv6
it's a logical solution would be the
opposite
i haven't heard of ipv6 only sp yet
but there are some ipv6 on hosting
services
there are many posts on the internet of
people complaining they have issues with
running some services
most of these people either find out for
the first time
they are behind the cgn and people tell
them to enable ipv6
to solve all their problems small
portion
already knows that they are behind cgn
they also mentioned
that the isp doesn't have ipv6 support
and ask for advice how to overcome this
issue
but i have found this one particular
interesting post
one year ago a user on reddit
asked how cgn deployment impacts the
users
as we saw earlier it does
this user claims he works in isp and
they are currently planning to deploy
cgn without ipv6
this shows that also the cgn rfc clearly
mentioned
the deployment should be dual stack mode
with transition mechanisms to ipv6
this is not necessarily how it is done
in practice
on the other hand myasp does support
doorstep
but you need to explicitly ask for it
they will tell you they don't officially
support it
and the connection with the ipv6 enabled
for some reason
is not optimal and you get better
results with a physics disabled
unfortunately some people think that nut
is a security technique
you expose only the ports you need in
the land addresses you want
no no no no not is not a firewall
this is only a by-product from the
workaround for the brokenness of the
end-to-end principle
that nothing produced if you run
legacy os inside the knot ipv6
can open up a doorbox if you don't
configure your
gateway firewall correctly
sorry one passion zero can infect a
whole sp
with a worm we might see worms
returning big time inside cgi networks
because that breaks the end-to-end
principle some applications stop
working different techniques are
introduced
in order to overcome these issues
upnp is one of those
akamai has published a research in 2018
about a campaign that exposes mb ports
on machines
behind the nut to exploit the eternal
blue vulnerability
a subscriber inside the cgn can do the
same
except it won't expose the ports to the
public internet
he will expose them to the cgn private
ipv4 outdoor space
this kind of attacks are also called
hole punching attacks
cgn deployments might be vulnerable to
similar attacks
and with double punching the sports it
might be possible to expose those
machines
to the public internet adventure
as i mentioned cgn was supposed to be
deployed with dual stack
to enable smooth transition to ipv6
in practice cgn is deployed without any
regulation
and sometimes without ipv6
instead of adopting the real solution we
give life support
to ipv4 although it was doomed a long
time ago
on top of that we add new internet
connected devices
every day iot smart watches
even cars some of these new devices
most likely don't even support ipv6
ask yourself do you really want your car
to be connected to a pb4cgn
if you're not sure about your answer to
my previous question
take a look at this
europol already identified legal
problems with cgn
in 2017. before cgm
everything was simple if a security
agency would give an ip address and a
date
to the isp the asp would provide records
of the subscriber and their internet
activity
with cgn multiple subscribers share the
same ip
does the sp records or what's happening
inside the cgn if there is no regulation
the quick answer is no
here are some examples the europol gate
for cases being closed
because of missing records for cgn
activity
in one case with partial records 49
innocent people were questioned
the privacy was violated because of one
criminal
to share the same ip address with them
on cgn
what would happen if the cgn ip was
shared by 1 000 subscribers
would 999 people will be questioned
without doing anything if you think
about it
cyber criminal doesn't need a vpn he
just needs a cgn
to cover his tracks if he can combine
both
he can be bulletproof
as we saw in the previous slide your
privacy can be violated indirectly
because of the actions of a subscriber
sharing the same external p
address with other innocent subscribers
but your privacy can also be violated
directly by another subscriber
because all the subscribers are inside
the huge line
what stop someone from doing a port scan
and perform reconnaissance on other
subscribers
in some cases it is even possible to
determine the approximate geolocation of
another subscriber
as mentioned much earlier the end-to-end
principle is broken
the cgn is a black box controlled by the
sp
but what do they do actually with our
packets
and finally for the conspiracy lovers
here's one for you
what if the nsa had backdoors in the cgn
equipment
to spawn on people think about it
the following text is taken from a
research
that was done in 2016. it says
there isn't sufficient guidelines and
regulations on cgn deployments
and call it a black art which leaves a
subscriber
with no other choice rather than to
believe that his isp
knows how to do it
now we approach the juicy part security
issues
some cgn equipment ships with default
passwords
that's the companies that sell these
devices do proper security checks for
these devices
as mentioned other subscribers can
actively or passively hack us
because we are on the same line actively
by port scanning and exposing some
vulnerability
or positively by a war
black hackers would want to gather a
foothold
inside the cgn those networks must
contain
easy targets some network
might be even full of specific
vulnerable devices
that are given by the sp to all of the
subscribers
massive jackpots
services that use ap address as
additional
security measure can be easily bypassed
if a hacker managed to get credentials
to such servers
and the credentials belong to a cgn
resident
the hacker simply needs to be connected
to the same cgn
as a resident and easily bypasses
additional security check
because both will have the same external
ap address
in theory to cause the ddos to cgn
from outside of cgn should be easy
with some effort it might be possible
from inside as well
you simply need to overload the nut
table with open sessions
myasp resets the subscriber connection
each day at midnight probably to flash
all the open sessions
the ddos impact in both scenarios is
ddos for all the cgn subscribers
as they can't initiate new connections
because the nut table is full
from gluten perspective blocking a cgn
ip
will lead to a massive user block
because of the actions of a single
offender
i mentioned default passwords on cgn
devices i didn't make this
up
this is an a10 device exposed to the
public internet
we default password this is only the
load balancer
but this might happen with cgi equipment
as well
this device is ranked like that for over
a year
this might be still a huge problem as an
issue with the load balancer
most likely will affect the subscribers
as well
okay now let's see some real life
examples of what actually happens inside
the cgm
we can see the same subscriber receives
a different cjnip address
and is connected to different gateways
this happens
each time he reconnects once again the
legal issue
comes to mind does it speed up
everything or it's just random
assignment
the same thing happens with ipv6 a
dynamic appear location is made
once more the issue of logging user
activity is being questioned
most likely ipv6 logging is insufficient
at the sp
level and needs to be regulated
as i mentioned a subscriber can scan the
cgn subscribers
but he also can scan the cgn equipment
to potentially hack it
there is no network oscillation
this is a potential that only cgn
resident have
as those devices are not accessible
directly from the public ipv4 space
you might think how bad this can be
obviously there will be devices with
different passwords and security
vulnerabilities
but this can happen on public ipv4 as
well
however cgn exposes some old risks
probably because someone thought that
nat is a security technique
we can find externally open file shares
it's like we're back to the early days
of this millennium
when computers were connected directly
without nut
with the file shells exposed
today if a hacker will find such a
he will most likely leverage into some
sort of ransomware attack
now we can see an interesting case i
will call it
a voodoo we see a printer that has
internal landmarking
an external ipv6 address as well
but it is also somehow exposed to the
private ipv4 space of the cgn
although this ap is not listed anywhere
on this page
this is most likely due to some sort of
sort of misconfiguration but you can
find
similar cases in cgn networks in high
numbers
at this point i hope you understand that
cgn can be problematic
but the solution is actually very simple
upgrade to ipv6 restore entwine
principle
upgrade to ipv6 solved by pv4 exhaustion
upgrade to ipv6 solve crime attribution
upgrade to ipv6 install full control
over your network
great pb6 experience the full power of
the internet
upgrade to ipv6 it's 2021 it's time to
upgrade
and yes i wrote upgrade to ipv6 six
times
on purpose
okay we have learned that you all use
cgn
in one way or another unfortunately
some of the cgn deployments are broken
cgn is basically the insider threat
for residential networks
due to coffee 19 many people work from
home
some of you might have a cjn at home
as i showed earlier there are security
issues with cgn
this should be considered as an
additional risk factor to working from
home
there is no real benefit from cgn to a
subscriber
maybe to the asp but remember
ccgm is not a permanent solution it was
intended
as to be a transitional technology until
we fully switch to ipv6
so let's embrace the tv6
uh thank you for your time and
you're welcome to ask question work
adventure or find me on twitter
hope you enjoyed my talk thank you
wow um thank you it was very interesting
to hear about the
wild west of cgn and
for instance how criminals may just hide
in the crowd
uh again i'd really like to thank you
although you paint a bleak picture
um to all of you listening there will be
i'd like to remind you about the q a
immediately
following this presentation
uh in work adventure and
we also have some extra time now because
we have a 15 minute break
until a quarter after so i guess 20
minutes
um i'd like here to invite you all to
join us
in session one for the featured panel
life and security practitioners
in the wild will with uh nazir
khalash jeffrey carpner and
katie masuris and caroline wong
so um see you all there
you