hello everyone welcome to day two of the
33rd annual first conference
i'm josh crandall from the first events
team and i'll be helping out with host
responsibilities on the webinar today
before we get started i'd like to remind
everyone that speaker q
a will take place in our conference work
adventure platform
if you are just joining the stream and
are not pre-registered please send an
email to events
at first.org again it's events at
first.org
to get set up on the system work event
work adventure is hosting all of our
conference networking activities as well
as the conference exhibit hall
and with that let's go ahead and get
started i'll pass the mic over to adley
our session moderator
thank you josh welcome everyone welcome
back
to the 33rd first annual conference
virtual edition
uh this is day number two and i'm sure
all of you are excited to
be part of this event just as i am
now um the next session
or this session that we're having now we
have two presentations
the first one will be on root cause
analysis in dell's pcert
and to do that we have david spencer
senior manager
p search engineering who'll be
delivering the presentation so dave
whenever you're ready
the floor is yours all right thank you
very much
my name is david spencer uh i lead the
pcert engineering function within dell
technologies
and i want to thank you for taking some
time out of your day today to listen in
this presentation about how we within
dell's
pcert group handle root cause analysis
uh just a little bit of background about
myself i won't spend much time
here uh i've been in this role leading
the p
engineering team for about two and a
half years and prior to that
i was doing software development for a
variety of product teams within dell and
emc
most of those product development roles
had some amount of
security embedded in them and then i
made the jump over to the product
security organization
within the last few years
so i don't think i need to explain to
people that are attending this
conference
how important root cause analysis is in
a secure development life cycle uh it's
built into
all the frameworks that we follow
whether it's ssdf
or iso 27001 even
first's own pcert maturity model all
require the use of root cause analysis
to learn from the incidents that happen
to our products and applications
but i will just spend a moment on this
slide just to refresh
for everybody why it's so important so
obviously
when you're developing software in a
secure way you do have various security
controls that you're hoping that your
development teams
are utilizing when they write their
software you have security education
programs which you're hoping they will
attend and learn from and then you're
hoping that those security
things take hold and when the product
teams do their development and testing
they're doing it in a secure fashion
but no matter what happens you know
there's always going to be
vulnerabilities that somehow escape this
process
and if you can learn from those
vulnerabilities and take those learnings
back
in to your security controls back into
security education back into how
the teams are doing their development
and testing hopefully that process
improves your stance overall and so
every vulnerability that
escapes your development environment is
a chance to learn
something about something that went
wrong and prevent that specific thing
from happening again
maybe prevent things like it from
happening again to other
product teams throughout your company
so before we dig into how we are
approaching root cause analysis
currently i think it's important just to
give a little bit of background
of how the security stakeholders work
within dell technologies
this model is certainly not unique and
i've vastly simplified it for this slide
but of course we have a product security
organization here in the middle
and that product security organization
has a number of teams in it the two that
i've shown here are the ones that are of
interest to this conversation
we have a team that's responsible for
our secure development life cycle which
we term sdl
and we have a team that's responsible
for vulnerability response specifically
we'll be talking about pcert product
security incident response
teams so these two teams
handle all the security incidents in a
centralized
fashion right all the security practices
and incidents within the
product security organization but within
a company like dell there are
hundreds of different product and
application teams scattered throughout
many different business units in the
company
each of which having people of varying
skill when it comes to security and
varying
uh expertise and knowledge about
security practices
and so we have a program like many of
you do
where we have security champions
embedded in those teams
and the security champions are
developers or
testers or product managers or all of
the above
who have some level of security
expertise and are
considered in their team the subject
matter experts on security
and they are the ones who interact most
closely with us whether it's during
development when they are looking
through
the sdl practices that they're supposed
to be enforcing on their teams or
whether it's during the vulnerability
response
cycle when they are helping make sure
that the process is handled
properly and that the issues are
remediated properly
so that's sort of the picture just as a
background
the conversation that we're going to
have assumes that that
is in place so when we look at
root cause analysis in a company like
dell
the immediate concern you have is around
scalability
um every you know root cause analysis
was always a part of our
secure development life cycle whether it
was done in a centralized fashion or in
a distributed fashion
it was always there but over the last
few years we decided to take
a look at it and try to make a process
which was going to be driven through our
pcert organization to formalize it a
little bit and we'll talk
throughout this presentation about why
that is and how we did it
but when you try to do that you
immediately run into a little bit of a
scalability issue
you have the vulnerabilities that are
coming into our organization discovered
by
in many cases external finders outside
the company whether it's researchers
or customers or folks that are signing
up for a bug bounty program
you've got hundreds of different
products and applications all of them in
varying stages
of maturity in their security journey
and you have a pcert team which is
lean and sometimes maybe you might
talk to some of the engineers they might
tell you that they're a little over
subscribed that the work
they were already busy before we decided
that we wanted to
to sort of centralize this root cause
analysis procedure
so given that scenario we have a lot of
interesting questions to ask about how
are we going to approach
the problem of root cause analysis what
sort of quality
information do we want to get about this
uh
certainly one approach to root cause
analysis would be to say let's pick
a small number of very interesting
security issues and dive
deep into them sit down with the product
teams and dig into it
another one might be to say let's get a
little bit of information about every
single issue we have
there's there's trade-offs on both
approaches you want to be able to come
up with a solution that we can automate
and fits into our existing automation
capabilities so that as the product
problem scales
our solution scales and we sort of have
to make decisions about what types of
work we're going to prioritize when it
comes to root cause analysis
so we had a lot of questions to ask and
in the end we decided to focus
on kind of the primary question about
root cause analysis which is answering
what happened what was it that happened
in this situation
that led to us
needing to have the this vulnerability
sorry
so some of the things that could have
happened there could have been gaps in
how
the sdl procedures applied across the
company
we call that a gap in the sel coverage
different organizations are at different
levels of maturity and gaps in how those
those procedures are applied to those
organizations might have led to an issue
there could be a situation where the sdl
procedures didn't focus on a particular
issue or that that team didn't focus on
a particular sdl procedure
it could be that there was uh an error
quite common right where a team is
trying to do the right thing but fall
short
there's this interesting scenario here
which is a team might have acknowledged
that there was a risk here
didn't think that it was going to
actually result in a vulnerability but
it did result in a vulnerability
and then there's this last scenario
which would be a truly
novel vulnerability something new that
has happened that we were totally
unprepared for
and this is a chance to learn from that
so
with that in mind that was our initial
focus these you know we want to be able
to take every issue and sort of
categorize it into one of these
buckets the question became how do we
approach the problem in a way that lets
us answer
those questions for the highest number
of
vulnerabilities possible and so that
sort of drove us to focus
more on the quantity side of the
equation as opposed to doing a deep
analysis
on the quality side of the equation
what that gives us a chance to do is to
turn our scalability problem
into a solution into a feature so
instead of being a problem it now
becomes a selling point to say we have a
lot of data
coming out of this root cause analysis
because we've decided specifically to
gather it about so many issues
so with that approach we really faced
some early struggles and i wanted to
document some of them here for you and
every single one of these bullet points
could be a hallway conversation or a
whole slide on its own
but i just want to run through them and
give you a chance to see a little bit
into how
how this decision to do root cause
analysis in this way
led to led to some interesting
conversations so the first one that i
want to call out is
messaging you use the word root cause
analysis
and people who have engineering
backgrounds immediately think of
a bunch of engineers huddled in a room
with a door closed for a few days
until they come back with a specific
recommendation of exactly what procedure
needs to change so that this
never happens again and while that's
certainly appropriate for some types of
root cause analysis
we were deliberately not targeting that
type of situation here
and so one of the things we did was
start modifying the vocabulary when we
talked about this we sort of drew this
picture for people of multiple levels of
root cause analysis where
at you know the very top level is this
level zero that gives you enough
information
to do to make some changes without
needing to do that deep dive that we're
talking about
and once we started using that messaging
it started becoming a little more clear
what problem we're trying to solve
another problem that we faced
specifically at dell had to do with our
asset categorization
so when we started talking to different
stakeholders
it became immediately clear that there
was different groups that cared about
different types of assets when it came
to doing root cause analysis
so our initial focus as engineers was
proprietary code we want to know what
you know here's a chance where you guys
were writing code and something went
wrong and we want to help you fix it
but it turns out though a lot of our
application teams are doing some level
of customization
of off-the-shelf applications and
there's just as many opportunities for
things to go wrong there
and those teams really want to learn
from from the vulnerabilities that they
face as well
and so figuring out how to make that
mixture and how to prioritize those
issues is pretty important to us
another problem we ran into once we
started to scale this up
was in normalizing the outcomes that
come out of it so the initial impression
to sort of get this
process off the ground quickly was to
sort of do this in a free-form way
and let the engineers provide as much
data as they wanted to but it became
pretty important
early on to sort of force people to put
their answers into very specific buckets
it was the only way we could deal with
the scale that was going to come up
one example of that would be we made a
decision to sort of
map every vulnerability as we already
did for for normal procedures
into a cwe and then once you have that
cwe
we can do some further automation and
mapping based on that so take the cwe
and map that to the specific security
control that should have in theory
prevented
that common weakness enumeration that
that error
so if you say this particular
vulnerability could have been prevented
by
these three different security practices
and could have been tested for with this
specific type of security testing that
gives us a great place to start
in having a deeper conversation with
that product team even if we don't know
for sure
that that particular vulnerability could
have been prevented by
in that specific instance that specific
sdl control
another challenge that we had to face
early on was building a starting point
you take a procedure like this and
describe it and people can start to
understand what you're talking about
but it doesn't give you data on day one
this is a process that's going to take
some time to build up over time
and is interested in sort of historical
trends and large scale
you know what you're seeing on a larger
scale and it's a little harder to sell
that to somebody and explain that you're
starting this up and that they might see
some interesting data in three months
so what we had to do was sort of go back
in time and sort of do a what if what if
we had been doing this procedure for the
last six months
what sort of data would we have gathered
so we started collecting that data and
you know took the engineers off offline
a little bit and said go pretend that
you're doing this root cause analysis
you know
go do it for these last six months worth
of data so that we have some place to
start when we have these conversations
then once we actually had this rolling
we started running into some different
types of problems
right so formalizing the handoff of of
the data
became immediately important so now we
had all this data and immediately we had
stakeholders lining up to ask for it
and we had to figure out all kinds of
interesting questions about who's going
to consume
this data and how this is where it
becomes really important to sort of
understand
your own organization and where
information
how information flows through the
organization who influences whom
to figure out if i give this data to the
governance organization
are they going to make sure that it gets
to the
product teams in the right way if i give
it to the
sdl team that we talked about earlier
are they going to share it
with the team that handles education on
the sdl practices or do we need to
directly share it with that organization
figuring all that out and coming up with
good ways to formalize those handoffs is
uh
it's a continuing challenge to make sure
that we we properly navigate the
organization
a good problem to have is everybody
wants more so once we started providing
this data
people immediately started asking for
more things so our initial focus was on
externally found issues that arised from
proprietary code and immediately people
said well what about third-party
components what about
issues that are found internally and
what about issues that are very
interesting and deserve a deeper
analysis how are you going to make sure
that that happens
so right away we had to start balancing
expectations for how do you
scale this operation up while we were
still sort of
getting it off the ground formalizing
the handoff all the things that we just
talked about
and the last example which is a little
amusing everybody wants
examples of root cause analysis and
i ran into that even while putting this
presentation together
so it's easy to sort of describe this
process and then
sort of explain that this is something
that's meant to to show results over
a large scale of data but immediately
someone says well give me an example of
an issue that you did a root cause
analysis on and what you learned
and sometimes it's hard to do that
because the the
pitch here is really about giving you a
large set of data about all the issues
that you faced over the last three
months
not about one specific issue that
happened to be interesting
so i apologize this is not my favorite
slide
but it does get the point across about
how we sort of decided to add root cause
analysis
into our pcert workflow
so anyone who's involved in pcr sort of
recognizes this overall workflow i've
described at the top here
where you you take the issue in there's
some triage and analysis
the engineering team the product team
does some remediation on the issue
uh you have to release and disclose and
then if there's some post remediation
activities that have to take place
what we wanted to do here with root
cause analysis was instead of adding
a whole new procedure into our world we
wanted to sort of
take some existing and some new
stakeholders and sort of add some new
actions
into this process all along so that we
could
show value just by adding a little bit
of incremental cost onto an existing
workflow that was already pretty
complicated
so during the triage analysis phase for
example we ask our pcert team
to gather a little more information and
provide a little more information do
some digging
what's the real world impact what are
the weakness details those things they
were already getting but now we're
specifically
asking to make sure that they have
enough data to really feed the root
cause analysis process
we also ask for a little bit of
historical data do a little bit of
research
based on what you know from this product
team have they run into this type of
problem before
that might change how we think about the
rest of the
root cause analysis
once the problem has been triaged once
the development team is remediating it
there's a whole bunch of new things that
might happen
we start pulling in and working more
closely with our counterparts
inside the sdl organization we start
asking them
questions about their engagements with
this team
what's happened in the past how this
team is complying with the sdl controls
they might have this information because
they've worked with them as individuals
they might have it because they have
automated tools that track these things
however they're doing it they have some
level of information
that they're willing to share with us
and we work with them to try and figure
that out
we asked the development team earlier on
how are you planning to fix this because
that gives us a chance to provide
feedback
earlier we try to dig a little bit into
based on all the things we've just
learned what we think the technical root
cause of the issue is
and sort of confirm that with the dev
team
what this gives us a chance to do is
sort of provide some just-in-time
education
we get a suggestion fixed perhaps we
might offer that to the dev team
but we also might be able to provide
some just-in-time education to others in
in there as well um they may be saying i
plan to fix this by
adding this filter or you know doing
this deny list
and we turn around and explain why it
might be safer to use an allow list
or to to not rely on on something or to
build in some defense in depth whatever
the example happens to be
based on all that we then into the post
remediation phase add a little more data
gathering so we pull the actual details
of what the fix was we're not talking
about lines of code here but
what did you actually do and then we
make an assessment based on our
expert knowledge of what we think this
was supposed to do
and that may give us some additional
actions it may be that the team did
something that we didn't recommend but
they had their own business reasons for
doing it
in which case we may need to open up new
vulnerabilities we may need to track
things with the sdl team and explain
that there are some changes that this
team might need to make in the future
because they made a decision
that led to some residual risk
so i know i mentioned examples as a
problem earlier
but i couldn't let this presentation go
by without providing one example
so here's an example of the sort of work
that we might do with a specific
vulnerability and this is a real
real world example there was a
specific storage product that we
ran into an issue that was disclosed to
us by researcher or customer
actually don't remember which one it was
that there was a port
on that storage product that didn't
require authentication
and turns out it was uh it was meant to
be on a management land and it was on
a front-end land or something something
similar to that
and uh that was reported to us
externally and we had to fix that issue
and then disclose it via cve
um so as we talked about sort of we have
to bucketize that issue what did we
what did we actually do wrong here and
here
as an effort to do that we looked at the
cwe so we assigned it a common weakness
enumeration
668 exposure of resource to the wrong
sphere
and from that we could look up in our
mapping table and say hey
this team there was a design objective
in our sdl
standards that says you're supposed to
be applying least privilege
and then there are some verification
activities that we recommend you do
some tests that we recommend you run to
verify that you have actually applied
least privilege
and some of those things might be manual
or external security testing
there might be some network scanning
that you could do
threat modeling is almost always an
example of something you could do
to detect that sort of problem so we
want to
did that assign those know that's in an
automated
fashion that just happens because once
you know the cwe you can apply those
those specific boxes so then we worked
with our sdl team
and asked them to take a look at the
artifacts of their prior engagements
with this organization and found that
there was a threat model produced for
this storage product
but in this particular release that port
somehow didn't make it into the threat
model and it didn't show up during the
review of the threat model and so
looks like it was a manual error of some
kind
so once we got the fixed details
provided and reviewed them and said yep
that sounds like the right fix
it seemed like then at that point we
could make our conclusion
so our root cause analysis conclusion we
take that issue and put it in one of
those
sort of what happened buckets we talked
about at the beginning
and in this situation the team basically
did the right
things but there was a mistake made so
there was an activity that was supposed
to detect this threat modeling
and there was an error made during the
threat modeling exercise
that led to this so this was a port that
was
missed and then we made a recommendation
back to the dev team and to the
the sdl organization that in the future
with this team let you know double check
and make sure when you're doing a threat
model review
make sure that there's a current network
scan involved to make sure that nothing
was missed
and maybe that recommendation would also
apply to other organizations
and other times that you're doing threat
model reviews
so this is a bit of an eye chart but uh
basically
trying to sort of explain here now that
we have all this data
who's consuming it and who are the
different stakeholders that we involve
and what data do they need from us and
what value are we trying to add
to the security posture of dell by doing
this root cause analysis
so whether it's you know the team that
does the secure development life cycle
standards
whether it's the team that manages
educating teams on our security
practices
we also have the governance organization
that interacts directly with the product
teams
at sort of a senior stakeholder level
and executive level to say
hey these these product teams aren't
doing x y or z
uh and you need to to sort of apply that
pressure and of course our own pcert
organization
is a stakeholder as well we want data
out of this process
uh as well we want to learn from it and
get some value from it
so just going through some of the things
that come out of it
right we we know that there's some
correlation to the different assessments
that teams do
with our sdl process we know that there
might be novel vulnerabilities those are
things the sdl team cares about
quite a bit those are things that they
would want to learn from and we share
that information with them on a regular
basis
our folks who are responsible for our
education want to know about gaps in our
training
is there things that we should be
teaching people about better or things
that we're just not teaching them about
at all uh our product teams
our governance teams and our peace
organization they care a lot about risk
right so whether these are risks that
were
acknowledged in the past that
materialized and turned into a
vulnerability that's an important piece
of information for them
it might be meaningful to go back to an
executive who previously signed off on a
risk
and explained to them this risk that you
acknowledged in the past
actually materialized turned into a
vulnerability was reported to us by a
researcher
was blogged about you know in the
security blog
and and gave us a black eye for a couple
weeks in the press and you maybe could
have prevented that by making a
different decision
now maybe that executive made the right
decision maybe
acknowledging that risk was the right
chance to get that product out the door
and that's you know that's their
decision to make
but i think there's some value to
demonstrating what happened
afterwards and giving them a chance to
look back at it those
same stakeholders obviously also care
about new risks
that are residual after making a fix so
if part of our root cause analysis
determines
that this fix that was implemented
wasn't complete
we want to make sure that the right
people are aware of that
everybody follows this next piece of
data right so we want to track what are
the most common
cwes that we run into the most common
weaknesses that we we might see in the
field
and we make sure that we we track that
information of what we run into
from the sdl and education side also we
want to keep track of which
sdl controls and which activities
fell short so in mass this data gives
our sdl team and our education team a
lot of places to poke and prod
and make fine-tuned adjustments to what
they're doing with our security
education
and with our secure development
lifecycle standards it gives them a
chance to
to decide if there's some shifts that
they want to make in how we're focusing
those activities
meanwhile along the same lines our
product teams and our peace organization
probably care a lot about similar
vulnerabilities that our analysis might
find by product line
so if a particular product line a
particular group of related products and
applications is running into the same
problem
repeatedly that's something interesting
that might drive a future conversation
with that team
this uh next item is something again
everybody cares about
right so we take all of the data that
comes out of this process and pump it
into a business intelligence application
and then we can present
sort of live sliced and diced data
across a variety of
axes so whether it's by date
or by business unit by criticality by
what type of reporter it was
by cwe whatever it is we can sort of
present that data
and do custom dashboards for different
stakeholders
and everybody really is excited about
the ability to sort of see that data and
see it live
being able to go into a business review
with a product team and show them
you know what's happened over the last
six months with the vulnerabilities that
have come in on the different products
that they're responsible for
it's a pretty compelling story and the
last one is the one that i'm the most
excited about
is the ability to sort of provide
just-in-time information based on the
outcomes of these analyses so uh
there's obviously in any group that you
know the size of dell there's sort of a
procedure for making sure how do we
update our education how do we update
our secure development lifecycle
standards
but there's also a chance to produce
these you know bursts of information
that are highly targeted and have to do
with real world vulnerabilities that are
coming in
and we always had this capability before
right if an engineer came to
us and said hey i noticed this problem
came up three times in the last year
it would be nice to educate people about
it but here
it's more formalized we can hopefully
see these things by
finding patterns in the data and then we
can look each quarter and say maybe it's
a good time for us to
to put together a short webinar about
cross-site scripting because we're
seeing it grow
in these particular business units or
maybe it's a good chance for us to put
together a blog post
about code signing and how important it
is or about least privilege or
whatever that the problem that we're
seeing crop up more frequently happens
to be
so that is one of uh and the fact that
that decision is not
just based on one piece or an engineer
catching something
but rather by the relationship between
our peacert organization
and our sdl organization and the other
stakeholders that we've talked about in
this process
i think it adds a lot of value
so where are we and where are we going
with this with this process as i
mentioned
this process is something we've been
maturing over the last couple of years
and uh it's it's really starting to uh
to show some promise and people are
really paying attention and interested
in it
so we are maturing this process as i
mentioned we're getting it incorporated
into
every aspect of our piece workflow we're
producing these live
yeah we just have two okay
thank you very much we're putting
together these dashboards that i talked
about in our business intelligence tools
and we're really starting to evangelize
that data and get it out to the
different stakeholders who might care
about it
and part of that process is accepting
feedback on on the data
and uh learning from what different
people need like i mentioned
in even some of our earliest
conversations we figured out that we
were targeting some information that
wasn't helpful to some business units
and that we needed to sort of widen what
we're looking for
so that leads to the next step really
sort of working with our stakeholders
we have regular reviews set up to make
sure that we're talking with our sdl
team
with our education folks with the
governance organization
we're making sure that the data is
getting shared during regular business
reviews
and then what's next well we do know
that we want to
do these sort of deep dives that i
talked about we want to identify
candidates for really interesting
problems and do those deeper dives
so we've got to figure out how to modify
the process to enable that and make sure
that happens
we want to widen the net and figure out
what sort of problems we might want to
try
and attack that we're not looking at
right now
and we want to build up experts within
our development teams who are capable of
doing this sort of analysis on their own
and driving it themselves so that we are
not the only ones responsible for
driving the process
so maybe we do this top-level process
and we help our dev teams sort of do
those deeper level
analyses and then work out some way to
share the information back and forth
because
the data really has to be both within
the dev team and within the security
organization for us to really amplify
its value
throughout the whole company so
last slide really quickly what is the
data telling us so far there's not a lot
here that should be surprising
this sort of information that we're
seeing and stuff that the teams are
already pretty aware of
we know that the critical issues that
we're facing tend to come from
application
teams that don't have as formal
engagements with our sdl procedures as
some others do
we know that for teams that are already
pretty mature and and
following all the right practices they
probably are at a point where they need
to optimize that and do more security
testing and more fuzz testing
we know that researchers are pretty good
at finding issues that relate to
authentication and authorization again
no big surprise there
the sorts of environments that
researchers are attacking are slightly
different than the ones that developers
are testing
in and we have found a very small number
of issues that have
some newly residual risks so something
new that was discovered during root
cause analysis that we need to document
going forward
very small number but they are there so
it's good to see
but i think the real message is you know
ask us again in a year
we'll be maturing this process and
hopefully i'll have a chance to speak
again about this another time
thank you very much and i will be in the
work adventure platform answering
questions
after the session sounds good thank you
very much dave for sharing with us and
how the pc
at dell technologies does root cause
analysis i'm sure
our audience truly appreciates the
insights and
have learned a thing or two tonight so
or today um
and for the audience who is interested
to engage with today with david uh
please head to work adventure he'll be
there
to answer questions or have a discussion
with all of you
so thank you once again let's give him a
virtual round of applause thank you
david
thank you very much all right everybody
the program uh will continue uh with the
next presentation
uh we have um uh
now uh cleberson silva and nicole
rickman and they are both
um will be speaking on the
uh case rnp
experience in brazilian general data
protection law
uh lgpd compliance so
without further ado i would like to
invite
both of them to share their presentation
and and and start
sharing with us
we're seeing your your notes
hello hello everyone
hello yup we can hear you okay and
can you can you see my presentation here
i can see your presentation but we can
also see your notes maybe you can
share a different screen okay let me try
okay can you hear my presentation huh
yeah you know can you yeah
is that your slides yes
it's okay i think we're seeing something
as i'm not sure exactly but it's not i
don't think it's your slides that we're
seeing
[Music]
all these slides
perfect go ahead
sauce
hmm
he can see the slides but he cannot see
the comments so he cannot
present all the slides
without his comments
um
[Music]
just a second everyone we're just
adjusting here some
screens will start in
nagorno
hotel
foreign see
okay
so let's start okay
sorry for then hello everyone
good morning and first it's a pleasure
to
to be here in my first
my first time on first conference i hope
you are
doing well and staying safe my name is
cleverson
i'm a information security analyst uh
on kaiser from rnp
and here today with me is my colleague
nicole hi nicole
hello everyone i'm a cyber security
analyst
at kaiser rnp brazil
and i'm sorry for the delay but we hope
you enjoy
our presentation
well together we are going to talk about
brazilian gdpr law
or lgbt as pronounced in brazil
and the the experience of kais and rnp
okay so
rnp or enep is the brazilian national
research and education network
and is the organization that plans
designs deploys and operates
the academic backbone that provides
access to federal and public university
universities and federal research
instituted
some private universities totalizing
almost 20 2500 units
as academic campus in the entire country
our backbone reaches all the 27
states of brazilian federation some with
more capacity than others
but always in constant expansion
as part of our backbone already has
traffic at 100 gbps
i'll tell you about kais kais is the
incident his boss team
of brazil his certain educational
network
we are on the road for 25 years
and we manage the information security
incidents
and also offer technical support
security awareness to users and
security vulnerability handling
then i invite you to visit our page and
learn more about guys okay
the eligibility is inspired
by the european regulation
and gdpr as already we told you
the lgbt was approved in august 2018
it applies to any business organization
that
processes personal data data in brazil
in other words it regulates the
the activities of personal data
treatment in brazil
so if the company has any customers
or clients in brazil or offers services
or have
operations involving data it should
begin preparing for
lgbt
lgpd lgpd defines
authorized legal basis principle of
personal data processing
activities rights of personal data
subjects and guarantee of risk handling
and security controls in personal data
processing
what is the punishment applied by the
the law companies that violate the
elisha pda
will be subjected to the applications of
warnings
fines suspensions and partial
total bans to perform their activities
findings can reach a picture
of the organization's heavenly with a
limit
of 50 million per violation
uh the academic network
every enep
or rnp handles personal data in internal
processes and provides advanced i.t
services
to brazilian academic community that
handles some personal data
and the academic institutions can handle
students teachers researchers and
employees
personal data in its administrative
groups administrative processes
and can collect and handle personal data
of research
activities or public health context
we address the challenge of support
challenges
the compliance actions through foreign
fronts
rmp internal adequacy
rnp consulting as a services
this front has specialists on the topic
to support research and education
organizations
and the work of the adequacy
privacy training and the last one
development of lgbt implementation
method
for customers use this front helps
to share knowledge and provide inputs
workshops study groups and training
about
privacy and data protection to prepare
the institutions to adequate to
themselves
beginning the data map
the data mapping is very important to
to view and identify how the personal
data flows
inside the rnp works the company works
once you have this understanding you can
make a strategic plan
to answer some questions like
how much effort do you need to adequate
your environment how many resources
do you need to elicit the adequacy
how to begin living adequacy
well here in this illustration
uh shows we did some steps
to perform the data mapping
here we have the first step uh
identify the focal points inside the
company
and answer some questions about the
workflow
second step
sending sending the the data mapping
spreadsheet
show them third
stepping schedule an interview to
validate the understanding
and consolidate the data map
and perform and the last one perform the
risk analysis
so as you can see in this
illustration here of data map
can show you the method the methodology
used
according to the the label
in the right side here we have the blue
circles
representing the software yellow cycles
representing the hardware
light orange representing the area
or departments so
you can also see the small in small
green circles here
the d1 d2 d3
and representing the type of data
as d1 and for
as d1 represents employees d2
for partners d3 for external users
in this example we have three internal
systems
uh inside the the data center system
system a system b system
b and the corporate email
starring in the public cloud corporation
may here
is starring in the public cloud and also
on a external agent
and here you have it obsolete
we also can see you can see the
arrows pointing the data flows
directions
the area point uh using the
system system b
the area using the
corporate email and receiving the mail
to for another areas
or external urgencies
so after the data mapping consolidated
the risk analysis
the risk analysis was performed
considering
the probability to
possible data leak of personal data
this this possible data leak of personal
data
includes all all circles
all points here
in the data mapping number of
iq systems not approved used
to data choice or data
data leak points in a external
environment
here in this example we have the office
law
and data leak points outside the
vulnerability
management process and the
percentage of lgpd adequacy planned rom
the impact impact consists
in personal sensitive data
where sensitive data values
10 and no sensitive data valued
one quantity of personal data
number of different types of personal
data
in this example we have a three employee
partners and external agents
and as you as hazut the probability
verse versus impact gave us the
understanding to putting harding
supporting order and classify the most
critical areas and the most critical
systems
to prioritize its adequacy
until now uh all data mapping was done
inside the rnp along six
months and we got some some
numbers inside uh some numbers inside
rnp
76 spreadsheets fulfilled
36 interviewed areas
processing of five types of personal
data identified
processing of three types of sensitivity
personal data identified
86 iq systems mapped
58 ic systems that process
that process a personal dating identify
it
and the as the result we got
10 um 10 mos
10 most critical areas and 10 most
critical
systems to prioritize to prioritize
to eligibility adequates also i'll tell
you
i'll tell you some benefits obtained
with data mapping good understanding
uh of how data moves in
and out inside the company view
and documentation of data life cycle
from collection use it
starting and the
understanding of relationships
of our companies processes
systems and areas
beside all that we
have the training the network academic
school
esr as a unit from rnp
provides to academic community training
about
privacy and data protection for managers
data protection officers or dpos
and other public or private stakeholders
more than 150 professionals were trained
until now
um our goal support brazilian academic
community to be
compliance with lgbt and more
help create a privacy future
in their entire activities
sure sure uh practical experience
acquired in the adequacy process
and work work together with the other
organizations to
improve the privacy governance
and that's all thank you very much
[Music]
everybody have any questions
thank you claberson and nicole um
for sharing um yeah for sharing uh some
insights on how
um you guys are dealing with the uh the
laws there
for qna if people would like to ask
questions
all the q a is done in work adventure or
social
engagement platform so if you can all
head there
i guess the participants will be there
to ask questions
uh once again we'd like to thank you uh
for your
um your time and um and spending
the time to prepare and give um give the
presentation to
the first audience tonight thank you
once again
thank you thank you very much all right
over to you josh
all right we're going to take about a 20
minute break and then we have our
panel session that will start in
breakout room one
and that's going to be the only one
that's going to happen over the next
hour
we'll see you there thank you thank you
everyone
you