welcome on our talk
about our research into security
advisories and vulnerability
privatization
in the wild which is a research we
conducted
for national cyber security center for
the netherlands and ccnl
and we are stephanie the smaller and
great van dyke were both researchers at
ncc and we conducted this research in
collaboration with
michelle van eter from delft university
of technology
so over this research we looked into
what happens when organizations
receive information about possible
vulnerabilities
and given that these organizations have
a finite capacity to conduct security
updates
we asked how do they prioritize the vast
amount
of vulnerability information and
advisories which is published every day
to start at the yearly
number of cves we see a strong increase
every year
as a graph shows here from cve details
we started
with around
more than four thousand in 2010 and 10
years later
we see there are almost nineteen
thousand uh cves published
every year every year which isn't
um even the total amount of
vulnerabilities
found in hardware and software every
year
but this indicates the growing stream of
information and the
growing need for organizations asserts
to analyze and assess and communicate
about these vulnerabilities which takes
a growing
capacity for organizations and
ourselves so
our main question was how do
organizations process vulnerability
information
and prioritize vulnerabilities to start
off
one of the tasks of the ncc is to inform
our target groups on
current vulnerabilities and
analyze and assess them and communicate
our assessments
to them we do that in the form of
security advisories
so the ncc now has a risk score
matrix not not unlike the cvs escort
to assess the vulnerability on basis of
one likelihood
and be possible damage and
we published this these security
advisories about recent vulnerabilities
or threats in specific
software or hardware we publish around
a thousand security advisors each year
and here you see as well the steady
increase
from 2012 when there was 650
published so um here's you see the
growth
in security advisories and the
information
we uh put out each year
and approximately every year hour in
approximately 40 advisories
are categorized as high high these are
relatable to
critical advisories critical
vulnerabilities and
we communicate these both through our
security advisories and also
through calls indicating that they're
both they receive special attention from
both
us as wealth or as well as of our target
audiences so looking at the
vulnerability management field
we see that early research has found
that users do not
interpret it to see these escort
consistently and that the formula
has been used not always just is
sufficiently justified
or validated um adding to that is that
prescriptive prescriptive models
that exist for organizations to organize
vulnerability management and capacity
for
for example suns or gardner do not
always have
a much empirical grounding
moreover they present a clear-cut
path from immature to a mature posture
for vulnerability management based on
the use of tools
thresholds and policies while
these current maturity models assume
a perfect capacity and a perfect
information position
of these organizations which is not
always the case
as seen by research from
frankly is that decisions are mostly
influenced by organizational factors and
processes
for example as he has shown us that the
staggered deployment of updates
implicitly trades on security for
reliability
so for our research we did 22
semi-structured interviews
our goal or our population
target population was the constitution's
constituencies
of ncc now which is a mix
of small and large organizations mix of
central government organizations
critical infrastructure and the common
denominators
all these respondents receive ncc
security advisories
so looking at the organization's size of
our respondents
we interviewed both very large
organizations with more than
10 000 employees smaller ones with
less than 50 employees and you see also
that there is a large diversity between
the size of the instant respawn teams or
teams
some some are very small some have
multiple instant response incident
response teams
interestingly is that the size of the
organization not all
always correlates one-on-one with the
size of the incident response team
so when we talk about large organization
in this context
we don't necessarily mean the total size
of employees but we mean
that these organizations have either a
large security team or a large incident
response team
and we see a lot of small organizations
with a big it
focus a more complex it
infrastructure and a larger security
team than
large organizations with a less i.t
focused
organization
who were the recipients of affordability
information that we interviewed
the largest group we interviewed were
security analysts
followed by csos
and interestingly is that some of the
small organizations we interviewed
is that they combine both the role
security officer
and system admin which means that these
organizations have
people that both look at the inflow of
organizations and assessment
but also are responsible for the
remediation of
these vulnerabilities whereas large
organizations with for example
security operations centers have
dedicated analysts
who only analyze and assess the
information then pass it on
through to the people responsible for
remediations my colleague will talk a
little bit more about
our research into that
so one more interview topics
we looked at the inflow of security
advisories and other forms of
vulnerability information we looked at
how this information
is processed by organizations how they
assess the information
and how to prioritize the received
information
and vulnerabilities we also looked at
the remediation process
of vulnerabilities so now my colleague
stephanie will dive into our research
results
okay so i will take it from here and
provide more details about the results
of our study
uh so back to the main question how do
organizations
uh process and prioritize vulnerability
information
we've created a simplified workflow as
you see here and this is
by no means a management model so what
we intended to do is
look at how vulnerability
information is processed in practice so
in real
life in organizations because
there is no perfect information uh
there's limited capacity so how do
organizations deal with these
uh limitations so what are the coping
mechanism
mechanisms and bringing back
the uh the workflow into
four categories so the inflow how
information is received
where it is received who see who
receives the information has
looked upon uh how is the information
assessed
and by whom uh what is the uh house
urgency and relevance
of a specific uh vulnerability
determined
then how is a potential uh
vulnerability remediated how is it
prioritized and
mitigated and the last
step uh how is a vulnerability
media remediated vulnerability evaluated
and
is feedback provided if a reporting
process
is in place
so what are the key observations
of of the study we will go
into detail in the next slide so i will
dissect them
one by one but the key observations are
that the majority of respondents
learn about vulnerabilities
reactively whilst a minority
proactively searches for vulnerabilities
and i will go back into these uh
remarks in more detail in the next
slides the second the formalization of
vulnerability assessment depends on the
triage capacity of the organization
third the security advisories sent by
authorities aid in creating urgency and
necessity for mitigation
and lastly vulnerability reporting
depends on organization
uh the organization of uh
triage and the specific type of
vulnerability
now looking uh diving into the first key
observation
reactive learning versus proactive
searching we found that the mailbox
unsurprisingly is a central note for the
inflow
of vulnerability information
it is where individuals receive
newsletters and also secure security
advisories about
uh vulnerabilities also but also mail
from vendors
about specific um relevant
vulnerabilities but it's
it's also a form of a reactive
a reactive form of receiving information
and the majority of these for all
organizations
the the mailbox was the central node
another form of
how individuals reactively learn about
vulnerabilities is that
the majority of respondents relied on
trusted third parties to provide
information on relevant vulnerabilities
and this is one
form of a coping mechanism where
if there is limited capacity to to
look for vulnerabilities to to make
sense of the high
of the amount of vulnerabilities then
organizations
tend to rely on those organizations that
provide that filtering
process for uh them
is is one of them but others uh
specifically
uh the example used here i see assert
if uh or uh organizations
with ot security tend to rely on third
parties such as ics
cert to filter relevant vulnerabilities
for them so
and if we look at sources used by
organizations to look for
vulnerabilities then we see that
vendors are
our source used most frequently and
what i forgot to mention here is that
ncsc is
left out in this graph but it's it's a
given that ncsc is the source used
because all the uh we all the
respondents
already receive security advisories by
the ncc that's why we left it out in the
graph
other sources often used are security
websites so a variety of
of national and international websites
are
used but also vulnerability scanners
and so what we see is that
as opposed to other sources which are
more based on the personal interest of
specific
uh security analysts there are um
scanners have a special place in that
that they're more of a proactive form of
seeking out vulnerability information
which brings us to the the last
point is that specifically medium to
large organizations are more inclined to
use
vulnerability scanners to actively
search for vulnerabilities
and are regarded as an important source
in asking respondents the question which
type of information is most important
for you
then we see that scanners are as
important
as information received
by trusted third parties and
such as the national cyber security
center
or vendors
going into the second category
assessment
we see that the risk assessment in
security advisories
plays an important role in the
prioritization and assessment
of the organization and particularly
this is not exclusively for small
organizations but it is a coping
mechanism that
um uh
that smaller organizations tend to rely
more on
the risk assessment done by um
authorities
and vendors because they don't often
have the capacity
to to do all the assessments themselves
and secondly the small organizations
the assessment is done by the receiver
of information
uh and also
the remediation is done by the receiver
of the information and that's because
many of the respondents have had a dual
role so they were both
system admin and a security officer
so it would make sense that
this individual runs through the entire
process workflow of uh from the inflow
to the assessment to the remediation as
opposed to
large organizations which have different
roles different teams for each part of
the workflow
uh and there you see that
the the rules are much more
spread out and far apart from each other
and lastly the received
information is checked against public
social sources
and here we see a difference
in again between smaller and larger
organizations
that larger organizations have automated
and formalized these
checks checks on third parties and again
this is a capacity issue
um if you have a large incident response
team
and if you have a
devops capacity in your in your team
then it's much more easy to automate
these things than if you have
if you are operating solo which
makes it uh harder
to to proactively
formalize these uh
[Music]
these checks
going into third category security
advisories
uh uh what we saw
organizations uh appoint roles or teams
to track and lead remediation
processes effectively and this here
there's a difference between
organizations that have highly
formalized processes
and organizations that have more um
ad hoc processes so we saw on one hand
organization with formalized processes
have
will have
a crisis manual which say
in event of this and this vulnerability
will scale up
and we have this specific team as
opposed to
an ad hoc organization that much more
takes a case-by-case
view and looks at the specific
vulnerability and then
assembles a team
and a second point is that security
advisories
are used um as by the majority of resist
recipients to advocate um
mitigating measures and there was this
was an interesting find
that advisories sent by the ncsc
had a higher author have authority in
higher management
actually actually uh were used as a
measure for persuading management to
to mitigate specific vulnerabilities
and lastly what we saw here
in in the remediation process that
internal socks
were much more involved in the whole
process than external
so what we saw is that
if you look at the whole cycle from
inflow to assessment
to remediation to reporting external
socks were only were very active in the
inflow
and sending information to the
organizations but
not much involved in the whole
assessment and
remediation processes as opposed to
internal socks
who took a more active stance were part
of the
crisis structure and involved in
also the remediation and reporting
process
so lastly if we look at the reporting
phase
this was highly dependent on the type of
organization
however in in
in case of a critical vulnerability the
reporting phase became
particular became important in all
organizations so
uh all organizations wanted to know
what were the measures uh when was it uh
when when was it patched and is the
vulnerability remediated yes or no
and here there's a difference between
ad-hoc
organizations who have
where reporting is less of a structured
less structural and for highly
formalized organizations which have
a reporting phase built into their whole
cycle
secondly uh here we saw yeah smaller
organizations
have less formalized reporting processes
this makes sense because
uh as i mentioned earlier as
particularly
those that have individuals
which have a dual role um
have um less
less use of a reporting process because
the
the groups are so small
and uh what we
what we saw in uh an interesting
way to formalize these processes is that
ticketing systems play
a central role in reporting and tracking
the vulnerability to the ash process
because they can be they can be
assigned and tracked and
around the ticketing system uh a process
is
is formalized
so what are the key takeaways from these
these insights is that organizations
have coping mechanisms to process
vulnerability information
think for instance of
about using trusted third parties to
filter information
secondly risk assessments of trusted
third parties
uh kickstarts uh own vulnerability
triage processes
uh what we saw particularly
relevant here is the risk assessment
done by the ncsc which you
which was used in this third security
advisory sent by authorities aid in
creating
urgency and necessity for mitigation
so using advisories
for higher management and lastly the
reporting evaluation phase particu
is particularly relevant for critical
vulnerabilities
and here we see a uh
difference between organizations which
have
uh adult processes and organizations
which
have highly formalized processes in how
important this reporting and evaluation
phase
is so here are
some of the works that we cited and
this was our presentation and this was a
pilot study and we're looking to
collaborate
to conduct a comparative study
affordability triage and other
search so if you are interested please
contact
us you can email us at research at
ncsc.inl
and we're we're starting we've just
started up this research so if you're
interested in joining us please let us
know
um so this was our presentation my
colleague
rick and i are very uh happy to take
your questions so
i will end it here and i hope everybody
has
fun at the remaining conference so thank
you everybody and
we'll see each other soon bye