please say hello to Martin
[Applause]
right hello everybody I am ecstatic to
be speaking at an event I used to live
in Bristol and drive down for the
evening to come to the chapter meetups
here and I was has taught me a great
deal over my life in Korea so ecstatic
to be here hello I am Andy a bit of
everything maybe a technical milliner by
the stage but I'm certainly a build
fanatic and an advocate of continuous
everything I'm a founder of control
plane which is continuous delivery for
container security essentially and I
want to talk today about the kubernetes
attack surface ecosystem tooling that's
available to deal with building
pipelines to assert our state's and
obviously continuous security compliance
and assertions why does this matter
because we need to know the state of our
systems performance veracity load why
not security of course I'm preaching to
the choir here but if we don't know the
state of our systems we can never know
if they've been compromised or our
burning lesson everything is fine when
nothing bad is going on but how do we
harden a kubernetes cluster to be
resistant to an attacker that has
already broken in everything public
facing in kubernetes is in a container
so we want to make our containers as
difficult to break out of or pivot from
as possible we also need to lock down
our API is data stores network security
so even a compromised system does not
give up decrees and crown jewels easily
giving us more time to detect the attack
and shut it down
so we're going to go crazy deep you
don't know Cuban actors already then I
hope this will be an enlightening
experience if you do I hope that there
is something for you as well
so how secure is Cuban assets is it safe
to run multi-talented in a public cloud
on
beep I locked in a safe in a box
suspended above the Thames can we really
run Google style multi-talented
infrastructure safely and how do we make
sure that what is safe today is also
safe tomorrow so we will talk about
common pones of kubernetes and look at
how it's been broken how to harden how
to deal with our workloads because there
are two different networks in kubernetes
warmth of control playing and one for
the containers hard and soft
multi-tenancy patterns and how to build
this in very high compliance super
paranoid environments and finally tying
it all together with continuous security
so back in the day the cubelets was
insecure security fails to keep up with
the pace of feature delivery as I'm sure
we all know one thing to note here is
the kubernetes feels really insecure by
default which is not a good look but of
course it has proliferated aggressively
it is the most popular projects in terms
of new contributors and it is an open
source success story let's say and it's
been deployed into everywhere you could
possibly imagine so historically there
was an a back model that would mount a
service account token into every pod
that service count had essentially route
permission on the API server so up until
our back was shipped in 1.6 then RTE in
a pod
meant you could then route the cluster
from one RC workload security this is
about running set comp in communities
again the set comp extension while
available and docker was not available
in the cumulated proxy layer essentially
up until I lose the version numbers but
anyway this talk from Jesse Frisell
demonstrates how to defeat a dirty cow
attack of course containers are sharing
the same kernel so a kernel breakout is
container to hosts very quickly coupons
or another great talk from Brad Guzman
on the misconfigurations and
Kuras is in a cluster that he saw in
vendor-supplied distributions he worked
with the vendors responsibly disclosed
then delivered this talk it really did a
great deal of good for the ecosystem at
large
helm which is the deployment
configuration tool had an open to you uh
PC interface until kind of recently it
didn't have TLS until bit less recently
which meant again if you could make a G
RPC call for an unprivileged container
in your cluster you could spin up a
privileged container which of course
breaks out of all namespaces in the
sense is essentially running a process
on the host and game over
so the unsecured s dashboard from Tesla
again this dashboard had service account
tokens that gave it elevated permissions
to the API server so compromise at the
dashboard leads to a compromise a full
routing of the cluster in this case they
actually did all sorts of things to get
this dashboard on the public Internet it
was intentional but sadly mistaken way
of doing things
we've had a recent subpath volume mount
that symlink traversal issue of course
amount points is it's from the host
mount points process namespaces memory
and approaches communication they're all
namespaces that you can share with the
host violating your security boundary as
with privileged mode it is foot gun
central and we will look at how to
mitigate those sort of things
of course kubernetes is a very
fast-moving
and very broad and wide attack surface
and because it's on there's so much
active development of course new code is
somewhere folks to hide this was
probably latent in kubernetes for a good
couple of years and again allowed
container breakouts well host breakout
via pass traversal on a mounted volume
so ultimately the first thing we have to
do in a cube nest cluster is create a
cluster see a sign our root certs and
our lease and run mutual TLS across the
control plane absolutely vital
otherwise we are leaking traffic that
can lead to cluster compromised city
security again I realize that the choir
is here and I'm preaching to them
but of course we want to do these things
because we know it's impossible to
secure anything without automation on
almost everything and a continuous
delivery content security sharer a
beautifully recursive loopy future
marvelous so let's look at the control
plane this is what kubernetes looks like
at a high level we have in this case
this is a single master you'll always
want to run this with high availability
on the master nodes there they're built
to run in that manner and importantly
what we have here is a lot of networking
communication so the API server is the
single point of truth it is the only
place that data should ever be accessed
LCD should be for whatever we go into
this but firewalled
and firewalled exclusively to the api
server if one is running cops then the
Calico plugin that you are using talks
directly to an unencrypted SCD an
unencrypted that CD is its again routes
straight into the cluster more or less
so there is no provision for keys here
we'll go through this as well but but
ultimately we have a single point of
truth in the API server and we'll scale
that API servers then we have the
cheddar and controller manager which do
similar but slightly distinct jobs in
terms of actually assigning a workload
to a node versus assigning the
horizontal scalability and and various
other startup functions the controller
management deals with then on the
individual nodes themselves we have the
operating system which my preference
would be something very lightweight
immutable lockdown chorus was very good
at this and who's the kind of poster
child this revolution there are now a
few others that do it if you go on gke
the image that you the operating system
image that you run there it's beautiful
there's no exact permissions on a lot of
things and it's constricted so even if
you break out onto the host you still
have a lot more work to do there is also
a minimal attack surface of course
because these distributions do not come
with package managers the pattern is if
you want to debug something you pull
down the container with those debug
tools
and you run it that way so lockdown OS
contain a runtime is typically docker
although that is now changing with Red
Hat release of cryo potato runtime
interface plugin there is Intel's quatre
containers which integrates with
hardware VTX extensions to run
virtualized virtual machines as
containers and that is now full circle
that obviously is probably a trade-off
and balance between whether one requires
fast startup or the extra guarantees the
virtualization gives the containers
don't so yeah of course and then onto
the cube look which is the agent for the
API server and a networking which is a
container network interface plug-in the
important thing to note here is that
this is just a bunch of abstractions and
indirection debugging stuff in here is a
nightmare we will look at this further
so minimal viable security tell us
everywhere as you've said we now have
provision to bootstrap TLS nodes so
historically you'd have to bake your
keys into your golden image that you use
to horizontally scale your nodes now
there is a TLS bootstrap that initiates
trusts using the public key of the
certificate on the API server uses that
for temporary exemption essentially for
he bullet passed the CSR receives a
certificate mutual TLS an authentication
therefore and and then we have joined a
cluster from a golden image without
baking secrets into the image super nice
turning up that is what it looks like
for those of you to care Oh
Semin 8ly slides afterwards there's a
lot of information in them I won't go
too deep into everything our back role
based access control is the way to slice
and dice to cluster permissions so
instead of that nebulous ploud one has
this abstraction they're super difficult
to audit one of my Powell's is recently
enticer one of my powers has recently
written a load of bats tests for these
work yeah so you can literally use the Q
control off while achieving a certain
user and then a certain state of yeah
and so that's really nice that again
leads toward continual assertions of
identity enrolled in the cluster and
that is certainly the message that I'm
trying to convey today that auditing our
back is super difficult because ideally
the access our back in a Cuban asset
should be federated and we should push
identity out to a third party system so
that on-boarding and off-boarding is an
organizational concern and not a
snowflake concern for cluster a B or C
that doesn't mean that auditing these
roles is difficult because all we have
is a claim or a group coming in from our
federated identity so making sure that
these group these are back roles are
locked down super important and an easy
thing to get wrong without static
analysis or testing on them there are
lots of ways to connect to vanassa's to
an identity service there are also many
ways to authenticate ultimately you can
just call out to your own binary and
have that do whatever side-channel
authentication you require and then
bring back your authentication into the
cluster legacy authorization is
old-school on gke you need to manually
disable it I hope this flag will become
deprecated and default soon GK is the
google kubernetes engine which is their
opinionated distribution I love it
personally I think it's a fabulous tool
it's essentially a distributed system on
a blocking API called which is a CLI
one-liner
really quite magical the port name I
mean the flag name says it all really
they ship within secure port because at
one stage it was a way to monitor the
applications of bootstrap they've worked
around it now they should always be set
to zero otherwise your 88-key port gives
you read-only access to the API as you
can see there it is locked down to local
which is a theoretical security boundary
but I mean I'm privileged user can get
on and still have access to that
loopback adapter so that should be
disabled otherwise you can do things
like this
this is leaking secrets for a service
account token system anonymous if we
allowed this so unless we disable this
we leak our version information on the
API server the API server under is zero
trust model is sitting publicly on some
network with this mutual TLS
authentication that I've bang on about
however if you are just driving by and
you have anonymous or thon then you can
scrape this from six four four three
ports that hang around the internet this
is the HDD model that is recommended at
C D is V plus the state when you submit
a pod to the cluster it is validated in
various different ways mutated and
finally validated again and then
persisted to xcd nothing else happens
the controller and the scheduler then
scan at CD for configuration blocks
let's say without certain annotations
and then as they share do it on two
nodes then those annotations re added so
it's it's a really nice pattern actually
because it fully decoupled everything
but at CD is absolutely required to not
only be available but also secured
because everything everything everything
is persisted to XE d super important get
it as far away from all the rest of your
infrastructure as possible and of course
certificate rotation sto is network
security for the application tier that
now stands up its own CA runs a reverse
property called envoy for a matt leinart
lift which is a modern c++ code base
they exist and what that does is pull
the new certificate every hour for this
mutual authentication it's actually
backed by something called spiffy which
is secure production infrastructure for
everybody which is workload identity so
by signing an identity to a workload
that we trust we can a code that on a
csr we can request a TLS certificate and
we can mutually encrypt our
communication and do that with ok
and these things need rotating in
classes itself however because EDD was
not encrypted by default and in fact
still is not so even getting on to one
of those xcd nodes I'm forcing a core
dump you can get everything out and read
it or you can read it if you can get
access to the client the API so now has
provision to do this and yes there is
more detail available so workloads we
know about containers bless him
so containers form the basis of the cube
letter security model so while these
mechanisms are good for layering defense
in depth and have mitigated a number of
kernel vulnerabilities on top of app sec
it only takes a single bad kernel bug of
which historically there have been a few
to bypass all these mechanisms and
escape the container now that is a
generalization of course because
layering will increase our resilience to
various different forms of bug now
notably there are still multiple
resources that are not namespace in the
kernel system time the kernel keyring
the kernel audit log dns resolution
devices bits of proc so we still leak
things and we still have good enough
security as it's viewed by the kernel
developers but not if we bust out of
these namespaces so the pod the lowest
addressable component in cuba neces and
here's an insecure one with privileged
enabled this is running its route it is
privileged we we have no set comp here
this is never something we should
knowingly submit to a pod of course we
wrote a tool cube Seck it's static
analysis cube nested resources and it
comes with a load of human readable
responses to why you're receiving these
particular judgments against the pod and
secondarily it's just an API call and it
will return you not only a risk risk
score which is basically if it's below
zero you probably shouldn't deploy this
pot at all and you should probably set
that well above 15 or 20 because that
requires a lot of positive security
enhancing flags to be added to get you
to that risk score and then
try and vindicate its decisions and also
give you some advisories on what you can
do to increase your score so table
security policies are the API servers
static analysis for pod gamal if you
have in this case host network if you
try and mount if you try and bind to
your host network adapter so breaking
out of your the the network namespace so
if you're trying to share that with the
host then this pod security policy will
deny it as with sharing interpersonal
communication in the process namespace
this forces you to run as a non root
user there is a dirty secrets which is
the username space has never quite been
finished you may notice that docker runs
without the user name space enabled by
default
Kuban athis does the same this is
because discretionary access control and
the fundament of the Linux security
model is all based on the identity of a
user making that work through multiple
namespaces is difficult and nobody
really wants to hang the synthetic
benchmark penalty on their layer of the
stack so the kernel doesn't want it the
block devices drivers it wants it the
file system drivers they want it and
what lenhardt pottering has suggested is
that what we really need there is a
shift file system so the request goes to
the file system the ID is looked up in a
map held in memory by the file system
and then mapped to the equivalent user
on the host of course this then becomes
complex if your binds mounted to
multiple places at the same time and we
start to understand why no one's
actually fixed this so that's probably
five years away the long and short of
this is that running is roofs and cider
container is running as root on the host
because there are no user name spaces
that can have very serious implications
in some situations and if you run an
open shift cluster the admission
controller will prevent you from running
anything as routes and it also rebind to
a user to an arbitrary plus 30k random
ID so the even multiple pods starting
with multiple containers sorry
starting somewhat aeneas they're given
different user IDs to try and work
around this problem slightly a lot of
people find sorry a lot of people sign
that to user 1,000
probably exists on your host so you'll
just then inheriting the permissions of
that user so strongly recommended to go
high and high in random so resource
linting Gareth odd gasps rush Rhodes
cube test is it's kind of the other
angle it exposes cube nation's resources
and allows you to run a Python desk
dialect called Skylark which is the
anyway against your your kubernetes
resources so deployments as this brave
individual is performing right so
deployments contain a few extra things
notably these luminaries if you don't
recognize the names our core original
kubernetes either some founders or early
engineers it's all based on the Borg
system from Google which is aggressive
multi-talented with containers all moved
to a mega which was Borg b2 they learnt
things they were all the changes back
and they've reintegrated them into Borg
and most notably labels so of course
these other things as well but labels
are our secret sauce and kubernetes now
it sounds super boring they're just
metadata annotations like why would you
give two hoots they are a fundamental
security primitive in kubernetes
everything everything is addressed by
label selectors a lot of things that are
addressed by label selectors that are
used to reconcile a pod or a resources
defined behavior with its targets these
are not validated ever ever at all full
stop triple golden bags there's no
returns they are such a frequent point
of debugging pain and security
vulnerabilities you make a typo in a
label so by extension static analysis on
the actual resources that are submitted
to the pod absolutely paramount there
are other patterns like get ops which is
emerging which is essentially committing
your cluster state to a git repository
we actually layer multiple levels of
controls on top of that for source code
safety and
rusty for eyes on every pull request and
static analysis on everything there and
then the cluster reaches out to that git
repo to pull its configuration back in
so no one actually has bright access to
the cluster and then it asserts its
state and unifies the state with that
desired state in the git repo that's a
good place to check for labels going
wrong services also use labels to
address the pods behind them and they're
quite an oculist it's not a lot going on
there they're essentially just a virtual
IP that will redirect traffic to where
needs to go but the one benefit they
have we don't want to run as roots in
our containers if we run a web server
we're probably used to binding through
ATM for four three if you look at Apache
nginx they will start this route and
then drop privileges for their Forks
children so they're not running the
actual web server process at sorry
anything but the web server process only
the workers are running its routes that
is not a nice pattern in containers so
what we can do here is remap ports from
say 8 4 4 3 so we've built a container
we would run it as non routes have it
bind to those very high ports which
don't require a capped net by in the
admin and then we use a service to
essentially act as a shim as a
translation layer to the service receive
requests from 443 because that's a
command to the key proxy the API server
which is configuring to keep proxy which
is already running his routes and has
these network mutation privileges but in
the container we can run as non-root
user and avoid a layer of insecurity
that would result in the event of an RTE
service accounts spoke about these
briefly by default they were mounted
into all containers as as privileged and
as such should be audited and yeah
double checked let's say excuse me
I love admission controllers these
things are awesome this is again it's
very simple the way you get a pod into
xcd where it can then be looked at by
the controller manager in the scheduler
is through the API server single point
of entry
for all that information and we
authenticate and authorize our user we
mutate the resource itself which might
include something like adding a default
service account or making sure that
specific labels are added or maybe
putting the time of the deployment
actually is one of them and then then we
validate the schema to make sure we
haven't booked anything in our mutation
step and then finally we validate the
admission controller that where that is
where for example the pod security
policy comes in and says well you've
tried to submit something which is
running as a root user or you've tried
to break out of network you first set
the boolean to true for the network
namespace with the host I'm afraid I
can't do that and and you'll be denied
at that stage all those past and we
persist at CD admission controllers are
the root of the staff analysis that
kubernetes does we have a new extensible
web hook admission controller so we can
put arbitrary functions on the end of
those they include things like twist
lock an acro which will perform image
vulnerability scanning from CDE feeds
from repository package maintainer z'
and we submit the pod manifest to them
they validate whether the image that
we've passed is compliant by whatever we
have configured in those systems and
then permit or deny that pod into the
cluster supercool loads of things that
we can do in there the web bugs are
actually a bit difficult to write
because they're very opinionated and
require you to encode the public portion
of a SAN sorry of the the key that
you're using TLS exchange into the web
manifest as you deploy it but I think
super paranoid it's a good thing so
cubelet config these are not cuba config
these are more api server admission
controllers
order really matters here if you change
the order you will change what cascades
from one to the other
they're run sequentially there's lots of
information here that I will not go into
in any depth due to the time but image
policy as I've spoken about denying
escalating execution means that if
you're running pod is privileged you do
not want the user to attach to it
remotely because of course they have
that is a privileged pod and you're
essentially routing the hosts just with
opening a WebSocket
to that to that pod limit Ranger is the
way that we permits namespaces to have a
certain number of resources so it's C
group based CPU and memory allocation
and resource accounting super useful to
apply to namespaces which name spaces
are the the logical mapping for our
applications people leave them in a lot
of different ways I've seen deployments
where namespaces are around single
single scaling entities I think has been
insane frankly and for a logical
grouping of similar concerns namespaces
are also where we hang our network
policies which are cloud native dynamic
firewalls essentially and there's always
quota it's same at the previous node
restriction is super cool but an example
of how complex this whole fluster clock
is this prevents pods from requesting
secrets for sorry it prevents cubelets
from requesting secrets for pods that
they do not have running locally so by
induction of course we can you can see
that a cubelet can request to anything
it can request any secret so access to a
cubelet which is an agent on a node
means that you can request secrets from
the cluster and those secrets in a lot
of cases actually cryptograph jacking in
cases contain
AWS keys that contain the the root CAS
for the cluster they contain joining
tokens for dynamic scaling systems like
cube ADM this is very useful to run
these are the default permissions that a
node has and as you can see it can do a
lot of things and no restriction finally
has to run in tandem with the previous
mission controller to actually have to
make any sense I hope you're starting to
understand why I'm such a strong
advocate of continuous assertions and
pipeline driven deployments and security
for this stuff because it is very
Brod I'd say so
the pod security policy as I said it's
also just an admission controller it's
static and static analysis on on this
pods and one should absolutely always be
running a pod security policy you can
hang them on a namespace so you can run
different levels for different workloads
service accounts are mounted and by
default you may not want that more
information is available and of course
we have the validating admission
webhooks which means that we can apply
our own arbitrary security gates to the
hosted and managed kubernetes
distributions which generally pretty
awesome eks is very new so I would not
apply the same awesomeness to it just
yet more stuff there about how to writes
these things okay this is about
encryption on at CD you need to enable
this experimental encryption provider
config on the API server and then
provide it a symmetric key in order for
it to transparently encrypt the keys and
values for what it's writing into xcd
now this means that ultimately without
this what goes into XE d is plain text
these are also in he's rotating manually
at this point in time this only landed
what every 120 1708 recently before that
secrets well in fact they still are but
before that secrets for base64 encoded
and pushed into XE d so again not a good
story on security features but of course
the project has vindicated itself with
an insane level of adoption plenty more
stuff there all good sealed secrets at
the bottom is notable that runs its own
it runs a pod inside a namespace so you
can use the key that you share with that
sealed secrets instance to encrypt your
secrets you can write just the values
encrypted into a gift ops repo so
maintaining this full everything is
codes when that hits the cluster then
the sealed secret is a special custom
resource definition that is watched for
by sealed secrets decrypted in cluster
and written back as an actual secret so
that ensures that we not only have
secure transports of those secrets enter
the cluster
it means again that we don't have right
access to the cluster and it means that
in case of disaster or maliciousness we
can rebuild the entire application like
that of course depending on what it is
you may want to rotate your keys anyway
token request API again super awesome
basically this is the problem with jobs
as we know is not a rotation on every
request otherwise we are subject to
replays token requests is how not to be
subject to replay attacks and compliant
scanning there's lots of stuff here if
we want our clusters again to be if you
always want to know the state of these
clusters then strongly recommend running
these cos benchmarks that have run them
are always very difficult to get a
hundred percent on but well worth it and
yeah lots of good stuff that every
scanning some of this is open-source in
fact all of this is open source the the
plow integration is a hundred percent
recommended in order to use Clare
because Clara quasi to post each image
of your each layer of the docket image
to the HTTP server hang around for a bit
post the next one so cloud just wraps
that all up super nice and gives you the
same CVE vulnerability analysis feed is
used as it's used by the most products
and the docker hub notably his
deprecated its use of this in fact it's
now removed so at this stage we want to
secure some networking this is broadly
what the life of a packet looks like
between two nodes my strongest
recommendation if you're thinking of
running cuban that is is to choose
container network interface plugin that
you are ok with already because we have
everything from VLAN through like pure
ethernet bgp implementations got a
calculation layers 4 and 7 various other
jiggery-pokery and everything that we do
is dependent upon the inter pod
communication the deployment model of
kubernetes is flat it's meant to mimic
VMs and be easy to migrate VMs onto so
all note all pods must be able to
address all other pods on a network
point here is it is
but we have never a policy to save us
you must be running one of the plugins
that supports network policy in order to
use network policy this is interesting
this so missing a slide yeah anyway so
we've net very strongly recommended team
in London who built the original
encrypted overlay for docker they are
now ultimately going to replace the Lib
Network as well so that will be built
into all docker networking
implementations and yeah hi talented
local team so this is a network policy
one of the poor decisions that I slander
them for but of course I don't
necessarily know any better is that this
is this pod selector here without a
visible selector is actually a wild card
so that is a default
failed closed policy which I understand
makes sense but surely that should be an
invalid resource format and you should
get an error because I don't think
that's very obvious anyway so that is a
default deny for every every pods
network communication in the namespace
this is what you would then layer on top
which are exemptions for in this case 53
UDP and TCP as you can see again we've
got a pod selector with match labels the
only way that this is actually providing
this these network exemptions is if
those match labels are exactly correct
on the deployments again there's no
validation here if someone wants to
build the tool to analyze and tell you
where you've got matches for labels that
you do not have I would deploy it if you
don't mind so of course in this case
we've got a fail-safe because we've
denied all egress in the namespace
anyway and we're not relying on that
particular project err to keep us safe
that actually enables networking and
connectivity dns is a non deterministic
resolution so there is no dns in network
policies that is illegal of course that
could be because we've got geo IPS or
round robin low bouncing or whatever
that is so that's all very nice can we
do any better of course we can 2018 is
the year of the service mesh I'm sure
you've heard of sto and various other
flavors
everybody is deploying
something or in this ecosystem are
working towards it
it's really awesome come along to sto
London if you want to learn more but
suffice to say it is still on its way to
a 1.0 release there have been issues
with the Envoy integration they've taken
the v1 API which would Paul the central
infrastructure at a certain scale that
would take down the sto infrastructure
that's all self hosted in the same few
Banesto they changed that API from v1
rest v2 GRP see much nicer no longer
battle testers and yes there is work to
do and all contributions of course are
welcome I don't have a lot of time but
these are here for starett II the
service mesh is ultimately an encrypted
web of HD 52 connections in envoys case
we have mutual to your left on all of
those individually because we've got
spiffy that mutual TLS is actually the
workload identity so compromise the
single pod only affects the
communication from that pod to the thing
that's allowed to talk to we also have
our back and kubernetes we have granular
HTTP verbage our back as well so we can
overlay it still on to an existing
system it also extends nicely onto VMs I
feel like I'm pitching for it it's great
but of course baby steps gently gently
that's kind of what it looks like really
good workshop from Chris and pasta Red
Hat guru there and and yeah this is what
gives you the moon on stick more or less
really excited about the deployment
strategies these enable dark traffic
routing or like dark Canaries as I like
to say and yes there's all sorts there
this is a route rule for SEO and it's
actually performing routing based upon
the regex of the cookie header why can
it do that because in this model envoy
is terminating the TLS a kubernetes pod
is a singular network namespace so envoy
is able to fire up iced tea tables all
cumulated networking is IP tables for
which I apologize fire up IT IP tables
redirect all traffic back to port one
devil 37 and as a result all outbound
and inbound communication to the
downstream service here
is proxied by envoy again no exceptions
envoy is also the place that takes the
workload identity request the
certificate and so terminates at Els so
it's able to see these requests in plain
text while maintaining security because
it's essentially running is sidecar so
that's how we get the plain text cookie
headed there and we were able to route
on it we've written more tooling because
this again was very difficult to deploy
Vanessa is aggressively parallelized
nmap with some namespace invasion and
remote access capability that you
basically describe what you think the
network topology should look like and
this is the the cube Metis version so
it's plain old instance and kubernetes
aware and what it will do is ssh onto
the node that is running one of these
pods it will attach to the same network
namespace which means that outbound
requests appear to be coming from the
same network adapter as the existing pod
and then it will run and map in the most
aggressively parallelized way that the
host will manage it can also run
slightly differently where it uses the
labels of the services but of course
we're then subjecting ourselves to
possible bugs there and by spinning up a
pod in a cluster we're also impacting
what cuban SSC's so this is a
transparent way of testing things
without impacting the kubernetes
deployments nice tap outputs lots of
interesting stuff there ok let's recap
we don't have very much time left for
securing our hosts we've spoken about
these minimal APR minimal operating
systems of course we want our set comm
apparmor selinux etc enabled and a
mutable infrastructure just prevents
configuration drift containers are
running immutably and you could even
prevent you can run them with an
immutable filesystem flag so they don't
they don't write to any where apart from
maybe camp why not extend that the
infrastructure we're already there so
you'd be useful and of course grouping
nodes by type is really useful as well
we don't want network access to anything
at all from our pods
this is such a common source of
escalation as is of course the cloud
provide a metadata API it's the attack
service unfortunately again is one broad
because
of the way this thing's been developed
there are ways to property to the
metadata API it's a solve problem make
sure you're running something like this
oh we're missing a picture of kittens
devastating
all right well ah thank you this is this
is what I think human s actually is
bless them all okay soft multiple C we
want to isolate things by namespace
default network positing pod security
policies on those namespaces limits and
I mean despite the promise of running
this heavily multi-talented
infrastructure do not run similar
concerns
sorry different concerns like Devon
production on same things scan
everything run policy we've been through
a lot of this hard multi-tenancy only
catalog your existing security
boundaries this is not a panacea there's
no magic bullet here we really must
separate things in the way that we would
traditionally we can annotate on nodes
with labels we have advanced edge
willing features such as pod anti
affinity that prevents things from being
Co deployed and we can also once we
don't that run a layer of analysis on
our running workloads to make sure that
we're never actually crossing these
boundaries ultimately if your security
concerns are high enough run multiple
clusters there is no other way of saying
it there are lots of container runtimes
we've spoken about some of these the
virtual Kuebler is so cool it basically
acts as a shim to any other system so
you could put you could put a mainframe
behind a Kuebler and have cuban asses
addressing that mainframe and scheduling
things on it via vacuum s itself yeah so
hard multi-tenancy with a shared control
plane that is the compromise that one is
making I'm still whizzing tweak at the
end of these good stuff from our friend
Dan Walsh and of course intrusion
detection is important because despite
all these layers of Defense
defense-in-depth is the mantra that we
always repeat to ourselves lots of
useful stuff here the auto-generating of
our back from order exemptions is super
cool we get all it logs from gke to
everything everything is audited
various different levels of request
logging so you would never log the
request body of a secret post or a
secret gate for example that is what all
did to our back looks like but I went
going for any detail loads of stuff
about privilege container builds when
you build a container you're doing it as
routes Alexis all right who is a genius
from Australia has shipped loads of
features into run C and a go Lang and
the Kerbal to get rootless container
build closer to reality Lord so far well
recommended to follow and of course
there's no point doing this unless we
continually assert it not only in the
pipeline but also at runtime thank you
for the cat metaphor internets yes so
the system continually self validates we
become more robust and the Advanta
Federation testers are not left with
automated scanning grabbable fruits so
don't get caught out be proactive and
preempt what it's coming there we go to
brave new world of cuba Nettie's gives
us so much but it also dramatically
increases the attack surface there are
lots of interesting new and varied ways
to defend things but ultimately we need
oversight and centralized control from
pipelines
yeah security testing keeps you young
I'm sure you're all aware thank you very
much
[Applause]
hi um I really liked your talk and I
feel that you had the exact right amount
of cat memes that was very good and I
would like to know when your slides will
be available so that puts you every
single thing in them let's see so I will
publish them on Twitter where they will
probably get picked up by yes yeah hi hi
I have two questions many of the
security concerns you mentioned it
during your presentation is out there
yeah can hear me can you hear me now
yeah yeah so many of the security
concerns you mentioned in your
presentation it's already addressed in
the OpenShift so why not I mean if
somebody's worried about security and a
multi-tenancy cluster why not use
OpenShift cluster and they - shift is
great yeah it's very pinyin Isis the
only reason not to use open shift
frankly is vendor lock-in apart from
that I mean it's I mean end of the day
opener shift origin is open source I
mean you don't need to worry about yeah
it's true for the post enterprises
tomorrow they demand the heads to roll
when something breaks frankly and they
require that enterprises port licensing
but i OpenShift actually contribute
loads of security features back to Cuba
NASA's like are back and various other
things so if we ship this awesome
basically since you mentioned core is
looping like one slide like third or
fourth so why is that for loop for eyes
always cross yeah yeah poor West is now
obviously the Red Hat team Red Hat bots
core OS they are folding tectonic into
the the Red Hat okay open shift
application itself which is super cool
and they're also folding the core OS
container Linux into the Dora and taking
excuse me the Omaha
update mechanism which they got from
Chrome OS which is active built on Gen 2
whole layer in that direction there it's
awesome yeah though it's been
walked by kim bulk so we can run flat
car linux which is the