today two speakers from slack that we
all love and use Max and JA they both
are on the red team Prada security team
and they're gonna share their knowledge
about how to gamify security programs
we're CDF's take it away guys cool so
welcome everyone quick intros I'm Max
Feldman I'm on the product security team
at slack I run our bug bounty so if
you've submitted to that you may have
interacted with me work on some of our
future reviews and reviews of
applications on our app directory and
I'm John son and shine I run our
infrastructure red team at slack and
everything that entails and so today
we're gonna talk a little bit about set
some context with the SDL process that
we use at slack a bit about security
education CTFs capture the flags in
general and then how we integrated CTFs
into our security education so then the
planning the CTF we actually ran the
flags we used the execution of that what
went well what didn't go quite so well
and the lessons learned and some future
plans of of what we have for our
security education so a bit about our
security development lifecycle so we
have a CI CD pipeline it's very easy to
develop and deploy we have people coding
on day one it takes about 10 minutes to
push something to production and new
hires push to production within the
first week so we have a very fast
approach and like kind of hit the ground
running type of setup for our new hires
and the employees that we bring in and
we have about a hundred deploys to
production per day and so if you happen
to catch Clint's talk yesterday he
mentioned our SDL process a little bit
in the tool that we open-source but we
have thing that we called go STL and
that's a tool that we use as kind of a
self-service checklist so that our
developers and people working on our
features can can work through security
can engage the security team and think
about security can
Sterns for their features and help us
scale our team so it offers self-service
checklists that allow people to think
through step-by-step like what is this
feature going to affect what security
concerns may be present how do we need
to deal with that and that integrates
into our whole culture of trusting our
developments our developers so at SLAC
we have big culture of limited blockers
to to developing like being able to work
quickly but also a high degree of trust
in our developers in the people that are
building our products and building our
features we want to have a good
relationship not an adversarial
relationship but something where we both
help each other and so that brings me to
security education so for a lot of we
have a lot of passionate developers and
people in general in the company so in
our marketing sales all of our
non-technical people ops everything
people care about security they care
about what they're working on they're
very passionate but people aren't always
security experts the security team has
the security experts and everyone else
has varying levels of experience with
security and slideshows text books etc
can be informative but doing a security
training for people that doesn't have an
engaging aspect is by its nature not
very exciting it's if you sit through an
hour of security slides it's not super
exciting even if you work in security
not not the most fun thing to look at
ten slides of what is XSS ten slides of
what is sea surf here's what it is in
theory to try not to do it
we have front-end we have back-end
employs a lot of different people from
different backgrounds we have people on
the team who've worked on security teams
before and then transition to
development there are people who are
developers but dabble in security or
they maybe they've been to blackhat or
maybe they've been to Def Con and we
also have a goal with our education of
getting people in the company to work
together so not having so many silos of
the company or having people work in
isolation but whenever
we do training and education we want to
bring people in the company together so
have people who work in development
interact with people in sales for
example or customer support or have
different teams and different people
interact in and grow together so
additionally training classes etc can be
kind of overkill so is it worth spending
several thousand dollars to send a
developer to like blackhat trainings
yeah maybe maybe not security
conferences may not be relevant to the
area their areas of interest or what
they're working on they're also full of
degenerates so the big question is can
we improve our education techniques the
answer is yes and John is going to talk
a little bit about CTFs right so CTFs I
enjoy them some history of the seat of
CTS they were started at DEFCON 4
in a sort of formalized way and they
kind of grow in popularity from there
there was there was not super formalized
the challenges were just kind of made up
by goons of varying levels of scoring
just whatever the goons kind of felt
like and over time they started to get
more and more formalized to the point
where they are now where there's you
know different categories and different
scoring rubrics that you can use more
automated platforms that use that that
are used to present them and I don't
know if anybody in here plays cts
regularly but there's there's two main
sort of general types is the Jeopardy
style and then the attack defense style
so the Jeopardy style is there's a bunch
of questions there's a bunch of
challenges you solve them you get a flag
you put it in you get points the attack
defense is you also are running the
challenges on your own machines and you
have to find the vulnerability patch
them so that other members there so that
other teams can't come in and take your
flags they are super super common almost
every
security conference has one these days
there's a bunch that just run online so
we're at the point now where there's
almost never a weekend where you can't
just go do a CTF so if you want to do a
CTF you go to CTF time like if you have
some extra time you want to do with CTF
you got CTF times see what's running and
just pick one so yeah so DEFCON four was
the first formal CTF it was a first like
official challenge contestants provided
and then has really provided machines
hacked other's points were judged based
on the coolest hacks it was sort of
there wasn't us like a scoring rubric
for it there was just that was cool so
you get a hundred points kind of deal
these days they're organized by various
groups usually they end up being the
teams that kind of one previous CTF so
plaid the legit business that syndicate
are all very large CTF teams that will
get together and and compete for you
know DEFCON qualify for the official
DEFCON CTF and they will in turn go and
create challenges for other CTF players
to do and you know they're there at
every conference including some that are
specifically for training such as the
sands net Wars which is a CTF
specifically designed to train you to do
things some cool stuff that just to show
the sort of evolution of where we've
come to and CTF so that than just being
like random things that you hack some
recent stuff the DEFCON 24 had a cyber
Grand Challenge which was a completely
automated AI CTF so rather than you are
presented with a problem and then must
come up with a solution you had to write
a AI solver that could deal with this
with the problems that came up with it
last year's Def Con know sort of the
years before that Def Con had the most
just batshit crazy
CTF machine to run on it was a middle
Indian nine byte machine so all of the
previous tools that people had come up
with for receipt for playing CTS before
didn't work anymore because no other
machine is middle-end Ian
other machine has 9 bytes but sorry 9
bit bytes and interestingly as soon as
that was announced that was announced 24
hours before that CTF was rung by the
time the CTF started all the tools that
are been ported so all of that all of
the really good teams managed to modify
the tools to deal with this just bonkers
machine that has never existed in
history would never exist in history
because it's like why would you ever use
that so what are the some of the pros
and cons of running a CTF for education
they're great puzzles they're just fun
to play
they're very engaging if you are at the
least bit technically interested they
just you know no other time in your
career will you get to solve middle
endian 9 bit by a buffer overflows they
offer great rewards and incentives again
they're fun at the end there's prizes
usually you can use a lot of memes in
the names of the challenges and a lot of
the platforms for running CTS have
evolved so C T FD is like is a common
one Facebook CTF is pretty cool you get
like a map and there's you know
animations that you can click through
some of the cons are of running CTF or
like inviting your co-workers to come
play a CTF they're not always work
appropriate
there's Blaze CTF which is a weed themed
CTF which I don't think that you can get
away with in most corporate environments
and they're often tailored to a
different level of security skills so if
you play CTFs a lot and you go on see if
you have time and pick a random one you
can have a good time the challenges will
be challenging if you have never played
one before and you go to go play like
plaid CTF it will you will not even know
where to start so we ran a CTF and we
needed to planet so we started by
thinking about what was our goal why do
we wanna run the CTF other than just the
fact that it's fun we wanted to raise
the security and where's awareness of
skills of all of our developers so
understanding that they are developers
maybe our front-end developers have
never
even thought about a buffer overflow for
instance we wanted to just sort of raise
their awareness of the different kinds
of ways that security vulnerabilities
present themselves we also wanted to
engage a broad audience so again most of
our employees are not hackers and
especially the employees that aren't in
our development team so we were we
wanted to to engage our marketing teams
our sales teams our customer support
teams we wanted them to just think about
security a little bit to the degree that
they can and we needed to measure our
impact so when we came to the end of it
we wanted to know like that we weren't
just playing a game and wasting company
time so we started with thinking about
our communication so how we're gonna
communicate this with the company so we
started planning in October October is a
thing in many companies certain become a
bigger thing and kind of the industry as
a whole so we decided Harbor was a good
time so we started planning for it in
August which gave us a few months of
lead time to come up with challenges
come up with our communications plan we
engaged our internal events group so we
have a group that they organized like
any kind of internal event that we're
doing Sony company announcement kind of
things we engaged our communications
department to give us like the right way
to phrase things and where we should put
things which slack channels we should go
in should we put up posters that kind of
thing we organized a live lock-picking
Village because we have a few Lock sport
enthusiasts that work both on and off
the security team so we put together
that just to give people something they
could come in and you know talk to the
security team play with lockpicks it's
always fun we organize we put together
channels because we're slack for CTF
organizers CTF participants office hours
so you know if you were struggling with
a challenge you could come in and talk
to us and we could give you hints and we
also wanted to avoid disruption so we
thought about the length of time for the
challenges to run and most CTS will run
for a weekend thinking that
you know we don't want to bring drag
people in their off hours we want we
didn't want to run it on a weekend they
also have other work to do so we didn't
want to run it in the middle of the work
day so we we gave it a week and then we
certain thing about prizes like what are
we going to give so we had issues with
for instance lockpicks we have we remote
that we're an international company some
of the rules and some jurisdictions are
kind of fuzzy we don't really want to
ship lockpicks across international
lines where they may be prohibited so we
have to think about what we're gonna do
for prizes so when we came up with our
challenges we thought about what's in a
regular CTF and it's usually crypto
challenges forensics challenges etc and
web app challenges etc but we also
wanted to engage the non security people
so we brought in some security trivia we
brought in some OS int challenges and
some slack specific challenges us being
slack we wanted people to think about
what is it like to administer a slack
team securely so when we came up when we
started to put together the
infrastructure we chose Facebook CTF we
did that because of the visual effects
we thought it would just be a really
stunning way for a company to come in
and start clicking around on things and
get cool animations and etc CTF D is a
wonderful platform it's not very
visually stunning we have many developer
we have many designers and front-end
engineers that you know we wanted to
give them something of like this is
actually an interesting platform to use
we bought a domain fidgets spinning life
because memes I don't know we're a bunch
of Millennials and we offer we also have
some accessibility concerns so we have
several developers that have hearing and
visual impairments so we put together a
spreadsheet that had the challenges on
it so that I was more useful for screen
readers and stuff we put it on
digitalocean we used slack for
collaboration because we're slack and we
came up with a slogan that is a play on
the company slogan which is
slack is where CDF's happen and I'll
hand it over to max to talk about our
flags
also a quick poll how many people are
doing the CTF here this this these days
okay how many people have done a CTF
ever okay cool yeah so so you're at a
security conference you've probably done
one but yeah we wanted flags that
catered to all sorts of people people
who had never done a CTF people who'd
never heard of a CTF and also people who
maybe had dabbled or who had experience
that we had to have a broad range of
flags to offer to our employees so when
we were setting up we split the work
between a handful of our teams so we had
prod sack working on the webapp
challenges so we worked with John on
some of the crypto challenges and we
made harder challenges as well we had
our incident response team work on
forensics challenges and we had everyone
kind of collaborate on the miscellaneous
challenges or trivia we wanted security
trivia questions that would inform or
educate people even if you could just
google the answer well everything you
could google the answer for trivia but
it was designed to get people thinking
about security topics or pop culture so
our flag names we tried to keep the meme
based appeal to avocado toast eating
demographics we had a lot of puns and
yes we split the work between the
relevant teams
so our first handful of questions were
in kind of we called them trivia and
sleuthing so we had if you want to cry
my lover was one of them and this
referred to Marcus Hutchins being
indicted under this Computer Fraud and
Abuse Act if you didn't work in security
maybe you hadn't heard about that or
want to cry so we wanted people to get a
feel for what goes on in the security
world all your base are belong to us was
an intro to base 64 encoding so not not
a super-dense security but things that
you could google for and start to see
like we wanted to show a path as we went
through the harder challenges so start
with
stuff that was simple and and show
people bit by bit like how they could
reach harder security topics also yeah
so through insecurity pop culture we had
OS int and slack specific challenges so
these were also meant to be able to be
googled so we had a flag on LinkedIn we
had a flag on Instagram just to kind of
show people if you're not thinking about
it has social media how the Internet can
have this information sitting around
there and how easy it is to actually
find we had a few challenges within
slack within like slash command
configurations and other things to get
people poking around and seeing like oh
this is this is what you work on where
can things be hidden here how do you
administer it securely and this we
highly recommend this if you're if
you're building your own if you're
working on one at your own company like
the things you're working on people know
very well and it's a good way for them
to engage in puzzles but puzzles of the
product that they know or just show to
give people who maybe aren't actually
building it but the people who work in
it a chance to shine so another one was
it's all Latin to me this was a simple
rot13 and kind of then an intro to
Caesar ciphers Hashmi outside how about
that which was more topical at the time
if anyone remembers that was about md5
this was to show the ease of of breaking
md5 we had a couple md5 hashes and you
could use hash killer to get them back
to the flag which was a dr. Phil oh I
think we also had forensics challenges
so our incident response team put
together a peak app of of an attack
scenario so of an insider threat who was
sending information outside of slack and
the goals was the goals were to see what
information was sent out and also to
dabble in Wireshark or whatever tool you
wanted we recommended Wireshark but to
get people who maybe maybe are technical
but haven't done traffic analysis before
to start looking at that or to get
people looking at these traffic captures
to do some like unzipping of files
traffic analysis dot doc properties EXIF
so if you haven't seen jpg with location
data
before then this was a time for you to
be able to find that out we had some
puns and hints in there as well
it's worth noting so if you've done a
CTF that has forensics challenges before
those you think the ones I've seen
usually start with strings or looking
through the raw files as the easiest
part and then they get significantly
harder we wanted to have a much less
technically demanding way of showing
like critical thinking through a
scenario without needing to know
necessarily the tools or file types and
formats or how you would break passwords
or vulnerable versions of whatever
software so we then had a range of web
application flags so this is not
forensics this is web app so the project
team and red team worked on web
application flags ranging from HTML
comments at the the easiest so go to a
page and in the comment is a flag to PHP
deserialization vulnerabilities that was
much harder we tried to cover the Oh
awesome top ten and we had an X X XSS
exploitation where we ran phantom J s to
actually require people to exploit this
to receive the flag so they had to they
had to steal like document cookie and
then send it to a site and we would
actually send off the we had phantom J's
running so that we would send the cookie
over to whatever site they chose and
that had the flag in it
so in addition to so it was beyond just
doing an alert box it was actual
exploitation of XSS we also had sequel
injection RCE via OS command injection
PHP D serialization as I mentioned and
lfi which we added during the
competition so we'll talk a little bit
about the execution and the on the fly
or just-in-time nature of some of the
flags that we made so as John mentioned
to start this off we had company-wide
announcements preparation we coordinated
with our internal events team we've
launched early for the Melbourne office
because they are in the future from
Francisco so on Sunday we set things up
to so that Melbourne could start doing
it from the get-go by the end of day one
one team of five people had done most of
the challenges and so we were happy to
see that people were working on it
people were forming teams and working
together with people in their office
people on their team but not just their
immediate coworkers and then we ran out
of challenges so a couple of our
stronger teams which is our our CTO
co-founder and a guy who used to work in
used to be a hacker and then moved to
ops
they both did everything and then we had
two people who are twins in Vancouver
who work in front end but also crushed
all of these so then we were scrambling
to make slash borrow more challenges so
that PHP deserialization for example and
some harder crypto challenges a padding
Oracle challenge that we made those were
all done the week of once people
finished all the challenges we realized
we need to need to make this harder so
what worked people participated we had
teams four in Melbourne in Vancouver and
San Francisco a couple people in New
York we had people in Dublin so all over
the company people participated of
across diverse departments not just
engineering there were we
the security team had a more
interactions with these teams more
conversations with people outside of
what we would normally have where maybe
it's just a security question we now had
people saying hey how do we do this
Challenger hey can you give us hints
this was I think it was the most we've
talked with our CTO before yeah I had
never spoken to our CTO before the CTF
when he came up to ask me about one of
the challenges that I stole from plaid
yeah so so we had we had we boosted our
security interaction and kind of
presence within the company and people
complemented some of the challenges we
saw teams formed the majority of people
who did this were on the team out of our
top ten teams about half or sorry top
ten ranked groups which could have been
an
half of them are teams so the top four
people were individuals and then after
that it was mostly teams so we were
pretty happy with that to see people
engaging and working together we also
got security cookies at the end so we
gave these out at the closing event
other things that worked for the most
part the service data we had about five
eighths and so that's a b-plus
Facebook CTF is flashy and fun it's if
you haven't oh who has used c TF d
before who has used Facebook CTF before
so C T FD is pretty straightforward
Facebook CTF you click through like
various countries of the world and it
looks very hackery and matrix
esque so it was a it was a pretty fun
way to do it we had four individuals who
completed all of our challenges
including the last-minute ones that we
made we had unfurl link in slack so if
he shared the link to any of the fidgets
spinning got life domains it would
unfurl with that cool hacker we had
trophies and prizes so we gave
certificates and trophies to the top ten
finishers and for a handful of people we
gave raspberry PI's and a couple other
bits of hardware so yeah we had a with
not a huge budget we were able to give
out pretty neat prizes and have people
engaged and having fun couple things
that didn't work
Facebook CTF sometimes had some hip hop
DM caching issues that made like
changing the code very difficult to
figure out how to actually get the
changes to show up and also the
interface of that makes it kind of hard
to pull challenges in a list and go from
easier to hardest because you're
clicking through countries but there's
not an obvious like oh this is 25 points
this is 50 points this is a hundred
points so it's at the expense of a
little bit of usability it looks cooler
I am NOT a sysadmin there was a lot of
copying and pasting scripts and then I
think every time server messed up I
would just burn it down and start it
over
because we didn't do any cheffing or
anything so there are occasional flubs
of challenges in the haste to make the
new ones so the padding Oracle one for
example forgot that you can't get the
first block of ciphertext but the second
half was Google Apple so people were
still able to get it
digitalocean probably has more features
that we could utilize there were a lot
of manual fixes manually adding SSH keys
so there are a couple a couple things
that like in the haste to make new
challenges or in the lack of us doing
infrastructure management we're a little
more difficult pleasant surprises so we
had a higher than expected level of
participation good engagement good
discussions we had a slack channel for
the discussions as we said attention
from higher levels we had engagement
from ICS to execs we had security
enthusiasm from the top down and that
was great
less pleasant we had really smart people
doing it so we ran out of challenges
it's probably like a teeny bit of lost
productivity from the people who were
doing this and from us who yeah so we
lost we lost a week of work but slack
stayed secure in the meantime don't
don't worry about that and so I'm gonna
hand it back over to John to talk about
some of the lessons learned so we at the
end of the CTF we asked for feedback so
we put together Poli we use polio we put
together a survey on on the CTF that we
handed out afterwards to get some
engagement some more like answers some
of the questions were what were people's
favorite challenges what were their
least favorite challenge is people
really like the sequel injection one a
couple of a couple of the top finishers
that finished everything really enjoyed
this one challenge that I stole from
plaid it was a Python rebel sir it was a
server you connect to you get a Python
Red Bull but you don't get the standard
library or alphanumeric characters so
that that one was interesting
people's least favorite challenges where
the cross site scripting ones the
padding Oracle question because again
you couldn't get the first block and the
XSS one died every so often so that was
why it the rest of it people like when
it works yeah some of the positive
aspects that we got as not just from our
team but from the feedback itself people
really liked the collaboration of it
they enjoy being able to form teams they
type they liked coming into a security
office hours talking to us about them
getting hints they also enjoy the
education challenges so there's there's
a sort of rush that you get when you
solve when you hack something for the
first time and and for most of our
developers they've never actually
written a buffer overflow or as a sequel
injection before and and getting things
that you're not supposed to be able to
get from them gives you a rush so people
really enjoyed that from the education
aspects of now they know what cross-site
scripting looks like more than just
don't write it some areas that we got
that we could improve as better
sandboxing they were all kind of running
on one server there was no you know
there wasn't any separation between
others if you managed to mess it up
which happened with one of our stored
cross-site scripting yeah one of our
stored challenges you can mess it up for
basically everyone and then the security
team had to pull it down and bring it
back up again so you know probably
segregated more and the other thing that
we could have improved is is more PR and
more build up so we had an announcement
in our in our announcement was like a
global announcements channel that we're
running the CTF I think was like a week
beforehand and then the start of so a
lot of people had projects that they
were working on like actual work
projects that they were working on and
would have loved to compete in the CTF
but they had all of the all of their
actual like okay ours for work to do
instead that week had we announced it
beforehand people could have planned
around it so had we announced it more
around it so some of the lessons we
learned is have a cool domain name
because it's fun
we were thinking Tide Pods
life next but that might be a little bit
dated next October and again market had
better a heading ahead of time and the
other thing to note is don't
underestimate people we assumed that had
not being hackers and not being CTF
players most of our developers would
have a really hard time with the
challenges but again like by day one we
had to start coming up with more and
more difficult challenges because as it
turns out they do actually know how to
do this they're smart people that's why
they work there and it would be good to
incorporate even more teams so we had
some of the we had some of the
challenges that were accessible to
everyone so the trivia and sleuthing
type challenges it would be nice to have
both more of those more diverse
challenges that were not technical and
and maybe score them separately in some
scheme that we haven't figured out yet
just so that the the you know I'm not
trying to pick on marketing here just so
that the marketing person for instance
that's playing the CTF can win a prize
they can actually win the CTF by doing
those challenges and not have to worry
too much about that like super hard you
need to know how to write code
challenges some future work we're
running on we're already planning the
one to run next October August to
October turned out to be a very short
amount of time when you have other work
to do so we're starting to plan it now
one of our members of our compliance
team is really interested in in in
helping so she's going to help us with a
lot of the legwork on that one
so we can focus more on the challenges
more more participation would be nice
like I mentioned earlier we didn't we
didn't announce it with enough run up
for people to be able to like plan their
quarterly projects around you know there
will be a week where you do less work
more communication again same reason and
and again like I mentioned tiers and
prizes for different levels so have your
non-technical staff scored differently
from your technical staff maybe do it by
Department haven't figured out exactly
how we want to do that but it would be
good to recognize that
the smart people that are in your
non-technical positions should have a
shot of winning and I think that's all
we've got we have some time for Q&A oh
[Applause]
yes we did we did publish the solutions
afterwards we had a there was a wrap-up
meeting which was unfortunately not
recorded yeah so yeah we had a we had a
the question if you didn't hear was did
you publish the solutions after we did
publish them and we did a like hour-long
rundown for the company going through
each challenge and how to do it
including different ways that you could
have done it based on some people solved
the challenges in ways that we didn't
originally intend so we tried to cover
every way that you could have come to
the conclusion how many people have been
involved in the preparation so in the
first one the number okay people
involved in the preparation so making
the challenges was you me Eric Michel
Vickery so like five I think people made
the challenges and then we had more
people involved from different teams
doing promotion and so like Ali the head
of our incident response team was super
involved in getting like the prizes and
helping set up like prizes cookies all
this other stuff we had facilities team
we had some other people doing Locke
pickings but the main challenges and
running of the infrastructure was about
five of us thank you yeah and also going
forward we are now going to have more
people our team has grown a lot and
we're planning a bit farther ahead so
we're gonna have more involvement from
more teams and also yeah like John said
we've been more teams get more diverse
challenges also hopefully yeah we have
it's a big company with a broad set of
skills so we have people who can help us
like run things more
smoothly and also judge the level of
difficulty so yeah we can actually
engage the operations team to do our
operations because that's not our job
and we're bad yeah yeah not not that we
yeah
not that it's their job I guess but I've
definitely felt out of my element and
running some of those things and there
are there are people on the team who
excel at that and their advice would get
us to like five nines maybe like an a a
plus yeah okay so beside the besides the
general security knowledge in the
company and integration and so on have
you found it useful for developers you
see now less security bugs so we are
getting better at tracking our security
bugs that there are a lot of different
factors going into it that unfortunately
makes it a bit hard to track if like our
bugs have gone down so anecdotally I
think we've had more conversations and
engaged with more people or more people
now reach out and DM and say like hey I
have a security question and maybe it
was a person that I had first interacted
with during the CTF but now we've had
more conversations with them after the
fact as far as fewer vulnerabilities
it's it's hard to say because our
company has also I don't know if we've
doubled in the last year but we've added
like several hundred people so like we
have we have more and more features so I
think the people who participated know a
little bit more about the security
aspects but we also have more features
so more bugs but then the security team
has gotten bigger too so we're doing
more like to prevent stuff so it's um
we're trying to get better at like
granular tracking of it I couldn't say
for sure that we have fewer bugs I could
say for sure that we've had more
conversations and more people who have
like referenced the CTF or brought it up
after the fact so it's at the very least
it has stayed in some people's minds so
I would say it's a strict improvement
but I don't know how much do you plan to
do this on a more regular basis not only
onion
that's a good question I think if we had
the resources we would run this we had a
lot of good feedback and people who
really liked it I think it was we were
such a small team putting it together
that the prospect of doing it more than
once a year seemed hard but our team has
grown a lot now so I think we would like
to get to a point where we do it more
than once a year or maybe we have like
some other challenges to get people kind
of involved and like excited having fun
as a way to bolster our current security
training and also what would be cool
like sort of longer-term goal would be
to run one publicly so have people
outside of slack who can participate
have had that as a means of like
boosting our interaction with the
security community probably also
recruiting but also like giving out
prizes and just interacting more and
getting better at running CTF for our
own training but also giving back more
to the community so yes
bar I plan is to do this more when we
will I'm not totally sure yet but doing
it again in October and doing it bigger
is our first first step on the process
to doing it more frequently internally
and then hopefully externally or like
open sourcing some challenges etc do you
guys plan challenges so yes sort of so
some of the challenges are are hiring
challenges so we use them as a as like
part of the coding interview for for
product security at least there are
things some of our challenges say like
hack this vulnerable website and provide
a write-up so we don't want to give
those literal challenges out in case it
completely removes the effectiveness so
far of our hiring but there are
challenges in there that war just for
fun and there are some things that are
more slack specific so yes with the
caveat that we need to balance it with
like how to keep hiring or interviewing
people without everyone being able to
copy and paste the answers and and to be
clear some of them are
and source because I stole them that's
it yeah so there are a few of these that
were already on the internet but so yes
and that's um as we as we get more
mature we're hoping to and that would
also go along well with running a public
one so if we could run a public CTF and
then after the fact open source the the
challenges and let people use it that is
one of our like big bigger goals yeah
any other questions well thank you
everyone and thank you again John and
Max from slack thanks everyone
[Applause]