okay cool oh yeah thank you so much for
coming and thank you very much to the
organizers for having me my name is
Clint and today we're going to be
talking about a number of specific tools
techniques and processes that about 10
to 20 different bay area companies are
using to scale their security so before
we get into it a little bit about me
some would consider a security
consultant and research director at NCC
group we do penetration testing for web
apps mobile network hardware review
crypto pretty much anything I am from
the Midwest originally and then moving
to San Francisco I realized that in
order for anyone to take me seriously I
needed to start dressing like this
before that I was a security engineer
and before that I was a PhD student at
the University of California Davis where
I dressed like this so just to make sure
we're all on the same page let's talk a
little bit about some of the agile and
DevOps changes we've seen over the past
few years so there's been this big push
to release say daily not quarterly
there's this idea of infrastructure as
code using config management tools and
generally there's a lot of benefits to
this right it allows developers to move
more quickly iterate based on user
feedback and has a bunch of nice
features but at the same time this can
be challenging for the security team
right so the ratio in most companies is
50 to 1 or greater of developers to
security people
you can't possibly review all the code
but at the same time you can't be a
gatekeeper right you can't say you can't
release this until I've looked at
everything in most companies and code
goes from development to production very
quickly so at high level this talk is
essentially a collection of specific
tools processes and automation Pro tips
for scaling your company's Apps efforts
again this is taking lessons learned and
some best ideas from talking with a
number of different companies largely in
the Bay Area but not entirely so we'll
talk about some things that work some
things that don't work and really one of
my motivations for giving this talk is
I'm sure many of you work at companies
that do all sorts of cool stuff that
I've never heard or thought about and I
would love for you to come up after or
email me or tweet at me or whatever and
I'd love to talk about this with you
more so I've included this quote because
I think it sums up a lot of companies
challenges very well which is this
essentially you
we're building so many services so much
stuff is going on you know how do we
keep up we really need to scale our
efforts better than linearly with AB
psych engineer time so really in one
sentence this talk is you know how do
you scale security so a few disclaimers
I'm gonna mention a number of different
things some of these work in your
company some of them might not so you
know if they don't work ignore them
that's fine really it's the mindset and
the methodology that I think is more
important here I'm gonna reference
several tools and products this isn't an
endorsement and also this is a confined
amount of time so it's not everything
important in Dev psych ops so I'm going
to talk about some specific technical
measures but ultimately at the end of
the day no matter how many good ideas
you have you need buy-in from the people
involved right so just some ideas for
getting security management onboard you
know you can say oh this is gonna be
some nice cost savings we can do more
with the same headcount we can scale our
security team along with the dev team
and things like that for security
engineers you can pitch them on hey
let's automate the boring things right
let's spend time on high leveraged high
ROI tasks and then for developers there
are perhaps the most important people to
get on board
ideally any new security processes need
to be no low to no additional friction
for developers if you have alerts or
tool output that you're trying to push
the developers directly without vetting
them ideally this is about zero percent
false positives or as low as possible
otherwise they sort of build some
resentment and ideally when you're
developing new standards and processes
you want to make it as easy to adopt as
possible essentially a drop in a
replacement so if you're writing a
secure wrapper for something ideally it
has the same you know arguments and type
so you can just change the class name to
the secure version
ideally in addition to saying hey do
this it's more secure you also provide
some benefits outside just security
maybe like hey if you use our library
also we'll give you a some nice
performance sort of telemetry
information as well and then one thing
that we found in practice is that
developers care about security but also
if you show them the fixing bugs hey
we're improving the robustness and the
code quality of this thing you've loved
and we built as well can also be a good
selling point okay so we've talked about
who I am some agile stuff some important
memes who's involved and but the
majority of this talk is
going to be about the how I really
expected that to go over better here
alright so here the quarry areas we're
gonna be talking about so first we're
gonna be talking about some specific
tools that companies have built
internally to gain visibility into what
engineering teams are working on we're
gonna talk about some high ROI libraries
that the security engineering team built
and then there's a bunch of different
areas in the SDLC where you can
implement some sort of security touch
points so specifically we're going to be
talking about doing some lightweight
static analysis on developer machines as
well as on code as it goes in code
hosting we'll talk about doing some
dynamic analysis and fuzzing in the
tests and QA environment and then
finally in production we'll talk about
some monitoring and remediation okay so
let's get to it so one challenge a
number of apps tech teams have is you
know what all is the engineering team
working on at a given point in time so
you you can't really feasibly attend
every dev team stand up and at the same
time you can't expect every dev team
lead to know everything that security
cares about so basically we want a a
low-friction automated way to get an
idea about you know what are people
working on and where should I focus my
limited time as an app psych engineer so
here's a couple of examples
so you could say scrape slack all the
public channels the dev team channels
for security relevant keywords such as
crypto security hash et cetera and maybe
you pop in and say oh what do you what
are you chatting about like can I offer
any guidance or assistance one company
has some automated tooling in place that
will auto scrape Trello and JIRA boards
so essentially the development team will
tag issues that our security relevant
with security and the tool basically
continuously polls to say you know what
is currently being worked on what's
going to be worked on that's relevant to
security and then they reach out to the
teams as appropriate so along the same
lines a number of companies have built
some internal web apps that are
essentially self-service threat modeling
security checklist type things
so slack gave a talk at app sec USA last
year and then recently they wrote a blog
post and released a tool that I'm going
to show you a couple of screenshots for
but basically the idea is you know there
are dozens to hundreds of internal
services where can I add the most value
as an app psych engineering you can't
always threat model everything so what
matters the most so the first thing that
developers are presented with is you
know provide you know who are you
what JIRA ticket are you working on
where's the code stuff like that then
there's a couple of high-level questions
to try to get an idea of you know what
how risky is this how much should the
security team be involved like do one
security involved are you changing new
authentication or security controls
things like that and then it brings you
to sort of a more detailed checklist
where like okay what language are you
using whatever you select it will give
you some language specific advice like
this is how to do things securely in
Python or make sure to avoid this and
then here are some things that tend to
be potentially dangerous for example
parsing XML or URL parsing or some
common web issues and basically the
developer fills out all these things and
then it will auto create to JIRA tickets
one assigned to the development team and
then one assigned to the app SEC team so
for the developer team they get this
nice little checklist that says here's
all the things based on what I filled
out these are probably the things I
should think about so as they're
developing the future they can go back
to this and say okay I've made sure to
check that I'm parsing XML securely I'm
doing all these other things right and
then this JIRA ticket for the security
team puts everything in a nice place
that makes it very easy for them to vet
all the things that you would care about
so it has links to the technical and
design specs you know who on the dev
team should I reach out to where are
they talking about it which slack
channels and things like that so both of
these things so far have been
essentially I am only so much time what
should I care about and how can I find
out those things quickly another way to
do that is a different company has sort
of this live dashboard that displays
risk by service based on various factors
so some of these could be you know how
important is the service to the business
how many known vulnerabilities does it
have however we found them is it facing
the internet or is it just internal and
things like that and also there are
various AWS config metrics such as you
know what Adri us account what sort of
security groups is in what is it have
permission to do how many instance of
the instances of it out there etc so
basically this allows them to say okay
this there are a bunch of these services
running it's facing the Internet I
probably
to focus my time here okay let's talk
about some libraries so really the in
many respects I think the highest ROI
security engineering things you can do
as a knapsack engineer is build
libraries that are secure by default if
we look back say 10-15 years for many
web frameworks such as rails you had to
add this additional call in order to do
output encoding securely so back in
those days you had to do something right
to be secure unsurprisingly a cross-site
scripting was much more prevalent what
once it became a default you had to
change something in order to be insecure
that happened much less frequently so
when you're thinking about what do you
want to spend time building some areas
you should perhaps consider our managing
secrets things related to crypto often
allsey sequel file system access shell
exec things like that one interesting
example is a company has banned the use
of md5 and instead they require
developers to use this function called
non cryptographically secure md5 so you
can md5 that's basically a wrapper
around it but you have to explicitly
acknowledge I know that I'm not relying
on the randomness properties of calling
this here's some other cool examples
we've seen this first one is probably
one of my favorites which is this one
company has a test case that will
programmatically iterate through every
route that is every exposed endpoint
introspect on the code in each of those
and because they have a specific method
that is performing access control checks
it looks to see if any endpoint is not
calling that method just whenever anyone
wants the test suite so they found that
this actually found a couple of times a
new developer joins the team and they
don't know how they do things so they
add a new endpoint but they forgot to
add an honest and authentication check
and this actually just immediately
founded on check-in or I guess as soon
as they ran the test we'd rather so I
thought that was super neat other
companies have built say a view library
or a data model wrapper library that
essentially eliminated classes of
vulnerabilities and really the core
takeaway here is if something is hard to
do securely if you have to be aware of
different things basically just build a
secure by default implementation and
then make it very easy for everyone to
use one company that I think does this
really well is Netflix so hasta and
Patrick gave a talk at oxide Kali about
this and they had this slide that I
included
their permission because I really like
it so on the left side this is where
they started as a company a number of
years ago a lot of these are very
manually driven and you're sort of
limited to how much person time you have
but over time they've really invested in
security engineering efforts and they've
moved as far to the right as possible
where everything they do is ideally is
highly leveraged as possible so I've
I've linked there to the talk I
encourage you to check it out but the
idea the paved road they call out is
essentially let's make it as easy for
developers as possible to do the secure
thing and get up and running so you're
improving developer productivity but
also making it more secure at the same
time ok so let's talk about some student
static and dynamic analysis but before
we do that I want to do a brief
diversion to make sure we're all on the
same page so at a high level static
analysis is reasoning about code based
on looking at it while a dynamic
analysis is you run the code and observe
how it behaves so there are some
fundamental trade-offs here based on the
analysis type technique that is sort of
not dependent on a tool these just
fundamental sort of computer science
limitation type things so static
analysis is high coverage and that you
see all the code but it tends to be
imprecise that is there are false
positives
conversely dynamic analysis generally
code coverage is a challenge it's
difficult to exercise all of an
applications functionality but it tends
to be more precise in that when it finds
issues they're usually true issues
because you just saw it happen this
isn't always true but that's the general
idea and both of these rays and
complexity from simple to more advanced
so I talked with a number of engineers
at various companies and said hey do you
use static analysis what do you think
and ninety-nine point eight percent of
the time this is what they said which
makes me sad because I think static
analysis is awesome but I think what
happened for many of them is that they
got very excited about it there whoa
we're good we're gonna use it it's gonna
find a bunch of bugs it's gonna be
awesome but then they ran it for the
first time and then this happens right
so they so they get this report that has
a thousand findings they start triaging
them and there's like one or two they
care about but most of them they
generally don't so I get asked this a
lot you know should I buy this should I
use it so I just wanted to sort of give
you some high-level tips on this we've
actually got brought in by a number of
companies to help them integrate
martial sass tools into their sdlc and
here are some things we found
so some considerations you should
probably make do we have large legacy
code bases that haven't been thoroughly
vetted this may be useful
are you using Java or other statically
typed language languages it's generally
hard for static analysis in general to
deal with dynamic canal dynamic
languages such as Python Ruby JavaScript
and so forth do you have a mature
security program does your org use
custom frameworks with non-standard
control flow if so that's fine but
essentially you're gonna have to write
custom rules that teach the tool how
data flows through your program so just
to know that you're gonna have to do
this if you don't use a standard
framework that it already supports and
also are you willing to invest weeks two
months of security engineer time during
the rollout so we've done this a number
of times for different companies I would
say it always takes at least weeks
oftentimes months in most companies so
just just be aware of that it's not you
buy it you plug it in and you're done
usually there's a fair amount of work so
regardless of what you decide to do I
would encourage you to calculate the ROI
here so how much security engineer time
is required to come through the results
versus how many bugs of what severity do
we find so let's say you spend a month
triaging bugs from a commercial assess
tool and you find say one or two mediums
well in that case depending on your
codebase you may just say hey just do a
month of pen testing instead because
given that amount of time you're
probably gonna find better bugs than
that but again it depends on your
codebase is it going to be an initial
upfront time investment with a low
recurring time cost or is it going to be
continuously a lot of time many
companies have found that you might find
a bunch of good bugs when you initially
start using it but over time as your
maturity as a program improves things
get a bit better and a number of
companies have started rolling their own
or writing custom rules and we'll talk a
bit about that soon okay cool
so here are some things if you're
writing safe and lightweight static
analysis check some developers machines
here's what you should consider these
can be done as get hooked or as part of
the test suite and generally it needs to
be fast with low to no false positives
so some examples we've seen at different
companies reject all database accesses
that don't use sort of this known
approved API or if it seems like it's
concatenating sequel strings just ban it
you could been known dangerous functions
such as shell exec one company uses es
Lin in their nodejs applications to
check for the use of eval or a new
function so essentially they've wiped
out certain RCE code injection type
attacks you can also try to reject
commits that seem like they're adding
secrets
so this first link is a tool that by AWS
labs that aims to do that and I've also
linked a couple of tools that find
secrets and sources that are already
there so one thing to note here is these
are essentially grips but they have nice
security wins even though they're very
simple but at the same time you want to
make sure you don't do this too
aggressively that developers keep trying
to commit and then you block them and
then they'll find ways around you and
they'll hate you so don't do that
okay so code hosting this is when codes
already been pushed into github gitlab
or in C ICD tool like Jenkins you can do
on receive hook store on new branch
creation things like that and we'll talk
about four different core areas so the
first one is essentially doing the same
type of checks that you do in developers
machines you probably want to do that in
a CI CD pipeline as well so the
developers laptop maybe not set up and
just for sort of a defense-in-depth you
probably want to check here as well but
one neat thing you can do here that I
want to point out is you can use this
idea to improve code quality over time
by blocking new editions of
anti-patterns while allowing existing
ones so if you just say one and two fix
everything in the codebase developers
are adding bad stuff perhaps faster than
you can fix them if there are many of
them in a few of you right so the idea
here is for example if you're trying to
migrate to a strict content security
policy but your inline JavaScript
everywhere so what you can do is you can
block new inline JavaScript so if you
stem the bleeding things aren't getting
worse which gives you time then to allow
you to gradually refractor existing code
so keep it from getting worse and then
you can start making it better instead
of just blocking sometimes you might
just want to get a heads up so is maybe
someone is doing some file system
interactions or crypto related things
and as a security engineer you may just
want to know hey let me know if anyone's
doing anything like this
so essentially rather than blocking it
here you are sending an alert maybe a
slack message or an email or whatever
platform you use to say hey the
user and this branch of this repo is
adding something that you probably care
about here's a link to it so this gives
you some context automatically without
asking people you know how applications
are evolving and where you may want to
pay attention to this also lets you
correct common area errors early so
maybe someone is using hashing say
sha-256 when they mean to be encrypting
so you can have those conversations
earlier rather than later a related idea
is in most code bases there are files or
directory structures that are you know
probably shouldn't change very much
maybe things related to authorization or
authentication the login flow session
management encryption wrappers stuff
like that stuff that basically as a
security person you probably want to
know if this ever changes because if in
most cases should not change very often
so this you can either look at the
commits to see which files are changed
or hash them and look for those hashes
changing and things like that so if you
wanted to you could perhaps also take
this further to say you know only let
the security team or specific senior
developers modify these critical files
you could build models of who tends to
edit what with the intuition of if
someone is editing code they tend not to
work on they may have less context and
may be more likely to introduce bugs and
then finally another example is square
in the blog post i linked earlier said
that they leverage code turn and code
quality metrics about where they should
focus their time so last one for this as
an organization you should determine a
policy based on four out of date
dependencies of what severity how
quickly should we try to patch it one
company does something pretty cool which
is whenever a developer adds a new
dependency they have some automated
processes that essentially try to
determine what is the trustworthiness of
this newly added dependency so it'll
query say for example for NPM it'll
query the NPM registry and say you know
how many downloads has this had in the
past say month or six months what about
all time does this use any dangerous
functions that I should know about you
know is it shell exacting or using eval
or things like that so basically
whenever there's a new dependency they
have immediate insight into at least a
high level of gauge of should I use this
or not so there's a lot of tools to do
this some open source such as language
specific ones or hospital pendency check
and then there are infinity commercial
ones so in a number of these the
idea has been you know given new code
run some arbitrary checks on it to check
our various properties so scum blur from
Netflix and a couple of others feel free
to give it a those a look there's
probably a bunch of others I'm not
linking here and then there's some other
tools that are more focused on wrapping
other tools rather than specifically
hooking into the CI CD but just for your
reference in case it's useful I include
a couple of those alright so let's talk
about the testing QA environment so
despite what marketing for most
companies will tell you it's
fundamentally difficult for SAS dynamic
analysis tools to be well on modern
JavaScript heavy applications it's
difficult to understand how they work if
there is a sort of complicated
multi-step flows if it's very JavaScript
heavy these are just fundamentally hard
and about two-thirds of the way into the
talk for this app sec us a talk from
last year he calls out specifically some
issues that are challenging but let's
talk about some ways that tend to be
useful in practice so one thing is just
ensuring that a nice security baseline
is being enforced so whenever we release
a new service let's make sure it's only
talking over TLS and it's using strong
ciphers we can also check headers you
know are you using a strong CSP are you
using the right cookie flags and things
like that
so one thing that I think is
particularly cool is what's there on the
bottom which is oftentimes these desk
tools you need to do a lot of upfront
config to say here's how you log in
here's how all these different flow is
work and that configuration can be very
time intensive so the idea here is you
probably already have integration tests
that exercise most of the application so
rather than having to teach the tool
essentially configure your integration
test to use the tools such as burp suite
or SAP as a proxy and then when you run
the integration tests it's exercising
all the different end points with
arguments realistic that what you expect
so the tool knows all the different
things and then essentially condition
run active scanner from there to sort of
fuzz so if you get bugs reported by a
pen test or bug money or however I would
encourage you to add unit tests that
test that exact same issue so say in
this end point in this parameter there
was cross-site scripting just add a unit
test that makes sure that that never
happens again
because occasionally based on how
different systems change or various
coder factors issues could reoccur so
this make sure that doesn't happen this
was called out by Zane Lackey in his
black cat talk last year and overall I
would very much encourage you to check
that one out
it's of all the dev suck up talks I've
seen that's probably one of my favorite
so I would I would HIGHLY highly
recommend that one and it's on YouTube
so a quick case study we were brought in
by a company to integrate fuzzing into
their es s DLC and I just wanted to talk
a bit about that process so the
situation is they had a number of
services written in C that was parsing
traffic from the internet WebSocket
Jason etc they needed very high uptime
they were processing billions of
messages a day and this is what we did
so some of the challenges where the code
was very tightly coupled so it was hard
to write some good test harnesses by
test harness I mean essentially it's
sort of a unit test that tells the
fuzzer you know start here and then this
is one functional area and then you
write another test harness or another
functional area and the idea is by
having a set of test harnesses you can
have the fuzzer get good coverage of all
of a complex application and also they
wanted us to sort of scale this across a
cluster of machines so the first thing
we did was sort of understand the code
right separate harnesses for different
functional areas to make sure we were
getting good coverage we set up a
fuzzing cluster that continuously fuzzed
new builds as soon as they were released
based on various priority metrics so is
this internet facing how important is
this service things like that and then
we made a table for the development team
that was essentially if you change this
part of the code run this test harness
so they can make sure that they're
focusing their fuzzing efforts on where
it's most impactful so some things they
added after we left that we didn't have
time to get to during the scope of the
engagement is they set up some process
such that every time a crash was
detected it would automatically create a
JIRA ticket with the test input that
caused it in the stack trace and then
assign it to the project owner so they
could say you know run this on this
specific build and it'll cause a crash
and here's what we saw and also you want
to do some work and deduplicating
identical crashes to make it more
actionable so some lessons learned this
isn't surprising ideally there's a
constant dialogue between the security
and the development team this can make
things a lot easier for example if you
work with them to establish a clean API
it makes it much easier to fuzz and
again I mentioned this earlier
but the dev team really appreciated the
bugs not just for the security but
because we were helping them make their
code better and more robust I think in
the first two or three days we found 12
or 13 unique crashes which was not found
by internal testing or unit tests and
things like that so they they were
really happy about that some open
problems this is not specific just to
this but just in fuzzing in general like
how long do you fuzz
is it possible to automatically
programmatically only fuzz newly
modified code these are some interesting
problems for future work and I'm the one
talking about it but really the people
who deserve credit are ryan Sullivan and
Gabe pike okay so a lot of people are
not happy with existing tools and they
want to write some of their own so
here's some here's some best practices I
would encourage you rather than building
or using or building one tool that tries
to find everything instead focus on
solving one class of vulnerability very
well and you may want to say oh let's
just find the most severe first that's a
good place to start but I would
encourage you instead to think you know
yes how severe is it but also how
precisely can we find this like can we
find a tool that finds this bug class
with few to no false positives such that
we can essentially report results
directly to developers without the
security team vetting so even if this is
a low severity issue if you can find it
100% of the time all the time and never
be wrong then essentially you can wipe
this across a bug off and not have to
worry about it and then redouble all
those other efforts on solving the
remaining and then choose another bug
class and repeat and ideally whenever
you send something to the development
team it's very high signal right so
again the large company did this they
have tens hundreds of thousands of
services they attack one class of bugs
at a time and one thing that was
interesting is they allow anyone to add
new rules to be checked but if a rule
has been flagged too many times is
having too many false positives it will
automatically turn itself off and like
stop bothering other people so I thought
that was nice okay we're reaching the
homestretch so some infrastructure best
practices many organizations are using
config management tools like puppet chef
etc which makes the configuration of
servers declarative and reproducible and
in version control so you can check so
this makes it easy for example if a
server reaches an
clean state for example someone SS HSN
it makes it very easy to wipe in a
reprovision
ideally you're also providing some sort
of secret management service that
developers can use so that they don't
have to roll their own which is hard in
as an additional hardening step you can
roll out mutual TLS using certs between
internal services not just externally
facing so a couple of cool tools both
from Netflix so the first is repo kid so
when a developer releases a new service
at Netflix it's granted a base set of
eight abuse permissions just by default
and then what repo kit does is it
watches how this app behaves over time
and then gradually starts removing AWS
permissions that it doesn't think it
needs based on the API calls and what
it's doing and essentially if removing a
permission causes it to crash it then
rolls that back and gives it back so
what's incredibly cool about this is
that applications eventually reach a
steady state of least privilege with
minimal security team interaction right
so there's no meeting up front before
you did the work saying like I hey what
do you need to do okay based on what
you've described I think that you need
these permissions and at the same time
the developers don't need extensive
understanding of AWS permissions which
is pretty complex right so essentially
by doing nothing but having good
infrastructure they can over time have
all their services reach this nice at
least privileged state and I think there
is some new stuff in this area to come
the other tools chaos monkey so many
people have heard of this but the idea
is they force developers to build robust
apps by programmatically just shutting
down instances of a service and may
forcing them to be very robust in the
face of random failures so what I like
about this is rather than say having the
developer build something and then
afterwards you come to them and say hey
you need to do this - essentially you're
making your assumptions and requirements
explicit upfront specified in code and
then making them test that from the
beginning rather than sort of ex post
facto making them do more work
okay so let's talk a bit about detecting
attacks at run time so one idea is
having canary is either on servers or
laptops something that looks juicy for
example and AWS access token credit
cards things like that a couple of
companies are doing this which i think
is pretty neat on their website and the
login page or in the company logos they
have some JavaScript that essentially if
an attacker were to mirror that page for
example for a phishing attack if they
hosted somewhere else the JavaScript and
the page will send some telemetry back
to the app psych team that says hey did
you know your login page is hosted on an
attacker comm you probably didn't mean
that you should check it out so you sort
of get this a live feedback on if people
are naively copying your assets this one
is also pretty cool overriding runtime
environment to detect code injection so
the idea here is this one company looked
across all of their front-end code and
found do we ever legitimately use alert
and the answer was no so essentially
what they did is in JavaScript they
programmatically overrode it such that
in JavaScript when alert has ever called
it first sends some innocuous telemetry
back to the app site team and says hey
you know this user on this page and this
other meta information just triggered an
alert and then it triggers an alert so
the user sees it so basically what
happened was they were doing a business
deal with another company and that
company without telling them engaged
this third party pentest firm to test
their site and as the person was doing
it he ended up finding he or she ended
up finding a cross-site scripting
vulnerability and essentially the app
sect team knew about it immediately as
soon as it happens
and they actually fixed it and rolled it
out to production you know in like an
hour after it was found so by the time
the other party was like hey by the way
you have this vulnerability if they were
like what vulnerability it's fine and
yeah and Zane lackeys talk at blackhat
he was one of the early people doing
this at Etsy back there back in the day
so conceptually I think this also could
be done with other server-side languages
such as Ruby and Python so say for
example you have a service that never
rests the file system or never shell
execs in theory you could
programmatically at runtime overwrite
those methods such that any time someone
tries to open a file or write a file or
things like that via some sort of code
Injection attack however they get it
instead of doing it instead you've said
and telemetry back to the app site team
and you raise an exception or fail or
something like that another example a
company wrote an XML parsing wrapper
library that mitigates xxe so
essentially when everywhere whenever
anyone tries to provide some input that
causes them to reach out to some
external party they log that and send
telemetry back so again key lesson here
they got the developers to buy into this
very easily because they said hey we're
gonna give you a bunch of nice telemetry
oh by the way it's more secure so the
developers wanted performance
information and telemetry and they got
that in addition to security so
something to keep in mind also a bunch
of security tools have user agent tells
unless you configure it so this is sort
of a trivial thing to look for it ok so
one of the last things you can have
systems that detect when security
policies are violated and essentially
auto remediate so for example if you
think you know our AWS cloud trailer
should always be enabled so for example
an attacker who's gotten in who wants to
disable this to avoid detection
this company has an AWS lambda which
will auto re-enable it immediately and
also alert the security team or you
might have a policy that says AWS
instances should not be accessible on
all ports of the internet if this
happens it's probably an accident we
never want this to happen so basically
this company whenever an AWS instance is
spun up with this insecure network
configuration and AWS lambda will
immediately shut it down so the the
window even if a developer accidentally
does something it shuts it down
immediately
so data dog has a blog post or they
talked about this area a bit more which
is also cool to check out some sort of
the core takeaway here is are there some
things about your environment which
essentially should always be true such
that if it's not true really we should
fix it automatically as soon as possible
there's never a case where there should
not be true think if there's a way where
you can you know first detect when this
ever changes and then second can you
programmatically change it back again
you have to make sure that this can't
legitimately be that way all right so
this is pretty clustered but I tried to
put sort of like a tldr of everything as
much as possible on one page
I missed a lot of stuff obviously but
yeah in case you want everything in one
place perhaps this is useful yeah so
this is largely what I have
I blew through things extra quick
because I knew we are tied on timing so
I'm building a best practices they're
sort of a dev SEC ops pro tips playbook
I would love to chat with you more if
you want to share how your company does
things or if you want me to let you know
when I write blog posts or white papers
on this please let me know I would love
to chef I'm also available to chat now
and then you can go there for these
slides that I'm currently presenting
right now and yeah I think we have some
time for some questions so I would love
to hear from you
thank you thank you all right do we have
any questions
what would be your advice to a brand new
app SEC team so let's say they've hired
their first app SEC person at a company
and the company is doing DevOps like
what would be the first one or two
things you would suggest that they do
right away for big wins okay high ROI
immediate big wins for a new app site
program mm-hmm
I think the first thing that might be
useful is just really gauging where you
are so one thing that I can I think it'd
be useful is saying like aggregating
what vulnerabilities you're finding out
about and learning about from all the
different sources so figure out you know
if we're getting pen test or doing bug
bounty or different things like that
what are all the different bugs we're
seeing where are they and sort of what
are their classes and then trying to
figure out basically where am I gonna
get the most value for my time so a lot
of the things I talk about they can get
you huge long term wins are these big
security engineering efforts that take
even very good companies with senior
developers like Netflix like five years
to build yeah I guess I would say
opening a bug bounty program can be
useful for getting some continuous
coverage initially have a private
program with a small number of people so
you don't get a deluge but that can be
useful yeah I guess first I would find
out how are things currently and
understand just for my company what are
sort of the the quick wins and and some
of the developer machine quick grep type
things those are very easy to implement
as well and they can be very high signal
so yeah thank you any other questions
and hello you speak a lot about what
would I call technical security testing
static analysis dynamic analysis have
you ever seen also things like
developing methodology tooling which has
BDD security or these kind of things
within your experiences you know
development type things where right like
cucumber ask tests that are like it
should not do this or it should do this
and things like that in fact I think
that BDD security scripts lots of
security scenarios and test it and drive
the development to the developer is
riven by the test when is developing its
application and BDD secretly provides a
lot of these scenarios and you just have
to it seems plug into into your
application so it can be run
automatically using as the ICD like
Jenkins to drive this and this is a very
interesting promises but I'm wondering
if it's a dream or so have you ever
experienced that or not yeah okay
conceptually I think that that's a good
idea honestly I haven't seen that in
many companies that doesn't mean it's
not a good idea I just haven't seen it
but the the Mozilla talk I referenced
earlier does sort of automatically run
zap with sort of baseline settings on
every newly newly deployed service so in
some ways the checks they've implemented
are sort of BDDs tests yeah I think
creating some automated tests that
assume certain security properties like
you can't access without off or things
like that I think that could be useful
but it's not just a concept you have a -
which is called BDD security and which
is based on Columba with a framework
which is a lot like okay you got some
security stories driven and you have
just to plug in into your application so
I was wondering on my contact if it's
interesting to just spend time on that
and see if it's really really usable or
not but yeah there's some tools I linked
earlier like gauntlet and things like
that
it seems - next - comes in I guess yeah
robot framework and gauntlet are
specifically to do that yeah let's try
two more about that after I'd like to
think about that more I haven't seen it
used much but that doesn't mean it's not
necessarily useful just my experiences
do you have any tips for large
enterprise companies where you've got a
lot of varying levels of maturity and
development practices like you've got
some teams are absolutely top level
agile and some teams are still using
stuff from the practices from the 90s
and waterfall at all just scaling your
security to cover those different levels
okay yeah so the question is how do you
work in a large enterprise with
companies or development groups some
agile some waterfall like very different
type styles yeah I guess a lot of this
these ideas assume certain sort of
development practices and certain
methodologies I would say in that case
it could be useful to sort of do an
asset invert inventory experience type
thing where you know what are all the
things we're building which of these are
most critical to the business what would
be the worst if they got compromised and
also say we have some front-facing like
new web apps but generally they use
modern frameworks and they're fine but
we have one or two web apps that are
still important but they're written in
super old Java spring and they have like
20 known criticals in them yeah I guess
inventory everything figuring out what
is the most important and how many how
much time we should spend on them and
focus there and sort of gradually try to
increase the bar everywhere but sort of
first figure out what's the most
important where should I focus my at
least initial efforts because again
these ideas some of them can be sort of
generically rolled out such as just like
whenever say Jenkins deploy something
let's throw zap or burp at it but a lot
of things are sort of code base or
language specific see I would figure out
what do you care about most and where
should you initially try to reduce risk
the fastest basically where can you get
the quickest wins the fastest is really
what most of this is yeah thank you
[Applause]
thank you I have another question
it's about logging monitoring and the
run time medication side protection you
talked about lot about telemetry we we
are we improved a lot in the last two or
three years on detecting logging and
transmitting all security warnings and
abnormal use cases and I heard quite a
bunch about run time medications air
protection in the past month whether on
a technical point of view to detect a
pattern and to detect flows in the
business logic like this user never
accessed this kind of transaction and
now he is so I should I should write a
warning and did you did you in your
experience found out about implementing
this this kind of product like a runtime
application side protection so is your
question what are sort of the challenges
or what are the so we're people focused
in implementing the runtime is it
detection so it's it's like is it a
dream or is it something that that is
really implemented in production
environments on some critical
applications there are some companies
that do implement it in production
environments there is one pretty
forward-thinking company that can
actually so far as say like oh this
currently this current user has done
things that seem to be pretty malicious
and they can sort of flip some
environment flags at runtime that say
let's start messing with this user a bit
maybe we respond a little bit slower
maybe we don't let then hit certain
critical paths or things like that so I
will say it's it takes a lot of work and
is advanced and I can't speak to any
commercial products in this space most
of the people I've talked with have
implemented their own so I'm not
recommending like oh this is something
you should buy so we have to code it the
people who I've talked with have
implemented themselves I just don't have
enough experience with existing
solutions to recommend or refute them
but yeah I think adding telemetry and
things like that is very important and
very useful because you see what
actually happens not
what you think might be happening sounds
like you're going the right direction we
have time for one last question
so in companies with limited resources
when you're doing these consulting and
you go to the handoff
we tend to deal with the fact should we
develop this security feature in-house
first doing a consultant like what are
the risks of running through a
consultant and then not being able to
manage that specific like what would you
suggest working on internally with
limited resources versus putting off to
a consulting firm okay yeah so so the
question is if you have a small team and
you want to engage consultants to help
with this type of stuff how do you do
that effectively rather than bringing
them in and then you have trouble
maintaining it and sort of like you know
we've wasted our money yeah I would say
a lot of these efforts are a non-trivial
amount of work so you're not usually
gonna be able to bring in a consulting
firm for like one week or two weeks and
like get one of these type of things
done I would say in this capacity would
it might make sense to bring in
consultants for a certain amount of time
to say like hey help help advise us help
figure out like what are we gonna do
based on our organization look at what
we already have implemented look at our
Deb processes and how everything works
together and let's come up with like a
plan together and maybe start
implementing it which then is sort of
carried out and finished by your team I
think ultimately the abside team needs
to own this right because they're gonna
be the people working with it the whole
time so I think consultants can be a
nice advisory and sort of help and maybe
you bring them in periodically
throughout the process but depending on
your budget it might not make sense to
have them actually implement it
ultimately the app team needs to know
how this works but the consultants may
have seen this at a bunch of companies
and they can advise Oh for you I know
this is gonna be hard or something like
that and sort of save you some time and
get you in the right direction so I
don't it's some high-level thoughts so
thank you all right thank you Clint
please thank you
[Applause]