team I'm a part
PhD student at UCL my previous role
before PwC was leading an R&D team in a
law enforcement agency and previous
poking at DEFCON brew corn 44 corn and
so on so what I'm going to cover today
is the concept of delayed execution
particularly in malware
thomna puzzles themselves what they are
and how they work attack defense
countermeasures and then some up with
the conclusion I will kind of caveat
this whole talk by saying that I'm not a
cryptographer or a mathematician at all
my first degree was in English language
and literature so definitely not an
expert on this stuff I'm just kind of
interested in in unconventional attack
vectors and kind of manipulating the
properties of things to have an effect
so delayed execution is as the name
suggests deferring the execution of an
application of a binary until a
predetermined time has passed that can
either be kind of normal time minutes
seconds hours or it can be CPU cycles or
a certain amount of things that have
happened and the idea behind it in
malware is to wait out the analysis
period of sandboxes and emulators they
can only dedicate a finite amount of
time to analyzing a particular unknown
application after which time they have
to return execution to the user or to
allow that file through an endpoint
filter or to just move on to the next
file that there has to be analyzed and
that period can differ it can be
anything from a few seconds to a few
minutes and there are other applications
for delayed execution why you want to do
it as well so time bombs or good example
logic bombs that kind of thing
and crucially as I'll cover later it's
not just about evading security
mechanisms there also be known uses for
it good uses for it
so hantai DDoS is one and I'll kind of
cover how that works a bit later on
so this is a really simple method of
delaying execution there's no
cryptography involved this is how I
developers did it for a long time and
some of them are still using this you
literally just call the sleep windows
API function and pass in an argument
which is a number of milliseconds and
then you have your evil codex
you after that you can also have a
conditional statements you can compare
the system timestamp to a hard-coded
timestamp in the malware and if those
don't match or the the target timestamp
hasn't happened yet then don't do
anything just continue sleeping and then
check again in 3 seconds or whatever it
is
so sandbox developers and antivirus
developers and other people responsible
for creating security mechanisms kind of
got wise to some of these techniques and
they started doing things like
manipulating the system time that was
returned to applications querying it so
for instance accelerating it so this
pseudocode here simulates a check for
that kind of manipulation so what we're
doing here is getting a timestamp
sleeping for an amount of time and then
getting another timestamp and then
comparing the difference between the two
and if the difference is less than what
we expected then we're probably in some
kind of sandbox or emulate environment
so the code will then not execute it's
originally intended methods it will do
something else this is an example with
just wasting time in assembly so again
this is very simple no cryptography this
would happen before the kind of main
method of your malware and in this case
you just zero out the X register and you
increment it by one and just loop around
continuously until it reaches some kind
of predetermined amount and similarly a
very simple example here we just load a
library multiple times so these are all
kind of really simple methods a little
bit more advanced is the concept of
remote lookups for time stamps so rather
than relying on system time in this case
the malware will get a timestamp from
the HTTP headers of a server and compare
that to a hard-coded
timestamp in the code and if that
matches then it will continue to execute
evil code and if not it will sleep and
then check again the issue with this is
that you are relying firstly on having
internet
access at a sandboxed environment which
isn't always the case the internet
access might be simulated so sound boxes
do that the wanna cry malware for
instance relied on that as a check so
that non-existent domain that Marcus
Hutchins registered was a check by the
malware to see if internet access was
being simulated so here's a really brief
example of this so what we're doing here
is getting date information from an HTTP
server and we're checking it as
hard-coded one sleeping for a certain
amount of seconds getting another
timestamp comparing the two and seeing
if it's being manipulated and then the
second example is an NTP server so just
an alternative to doing our over HTTP
now normally you do this for more than
15 seconds but otherwise we just be kind
of staring a video for kind of 2 or 3
minutes now where I've kind of
introduced some new techniques that I
haven't seen before in the wild but that
could be used is looking up external
data rather than time so what this
pseudocode does is it fetches a response
from the Australian Government's website
on the current population of Australia
and it compares the population count to
some target population count which is
hard-coded in the malware obviously
there's an assumption that the
population of Australia is going to
increase but the crucial thing here is
that you don't know how much it's going
to increase by it's not a kind of
predictable increase at least not the
exact person but the the statistics on
that Australian government website are
updated on a regular basis so the
malware can check every three seconds it
knows it's going to get a new value and
it can that compare that the other
example I've got in this demo as well as
the Australian government is checking
the block count of Bitcoin so check how
many blocks of Bitcoin have in mind that
is something it does happen on a
predictable regular basis like there
should be a new block around every ten
minutes so this is the Australia example
and you can see very simple again in
this case the the actual value is below
our target again just to kind of save
time we don't want to wait for so many
people to be born in Australia before
the demo works okay so I briefly kind of
covered this earlier soundbox
capabilities what sandboxes can do is
they can manipulate system time they can
manipulate values from external sources
and crucially they can do something
called multipath execution that's where
you have a conditional statement in
malware and the sandbox can take both
branches or more than one branch of that
conditional statement to see what would
happen regardless of whether the
condition is true or not so it's hard
not puzzles
thomna puzzles are a cryptographic
construct it's quite an obscure sub
branch of cryptography brief show of
hands has anyone heard of Tom not
puzzles before one two people I think
okay so the idea behind atomic puzzle is
that it's a cryptographic puzzle and the
solution to it is generated over time
sometimes it can be a kind of variation
of a brute-force attack so it's
essentially brute forcing itself Timothy
may of the cypherpunks in 1992 kind of
first suggested the concepts and then
reversed than others in 1999 implemented
at a practical peripheral concept and
the initial intention behind sonic
puzzles was for them to be benign
essentially a kind of digital time
capsule and the ideal atomic puzzle as
suggested by Rivest and others would be
resistant to parallelization to
distributed attempts and that kind of
thing
other uses included are sealed auction
bids so your bid for a lot that an
auction wouldn't be available until
everyone had put their bids in releasing
classified information
after a certain period of time and
escrow for contracts so this is a brief
excerpt from the implementation MIT and
by Rivest
and others in 1999 so they have a kind
of digital time capsule running at the
MIT computer science department which
should decrypt roughly 2033 so it
started in 1999 should take about 35
years to solve so Tom not puzzles for
attack so the kind of concept here is
that you can achieve the late execution
but without having to use conditional
statements without having to rely on
timestamps or anything like that so an
example attack here would be you have
some malicious payload you encrypt it
with a key which has been generated with
a torn-up puzzle you don't hard-code
that key into your decryption stub
instead your stub has to generate that
key by performing the same time lock
puzzle and that key will then be
generated after X number of cycles or
loops or minutes if you're looking for
minutes it depends on kind of what
algorithm you're using or what kind of
constructor using once you've got the
key you decrypt the payload and then you
can either run that payload in memory or
write it to disk or whatever and the
benefits of this for attackers for pen
testers and red teamers and so on would
be that you negate multi-part execution
you negate that kind of system
manipulation of timestamps obviously
negate signature detection because we're
talking about encrypted content you
don't have to rely on any hard coded
keys in the malware for decryption and
you will so wait out that analysis
period of sandboxes as well the
disadvantages of using it depending
again on what kind of tomat possibly
using it can take as long to generate
the key as it would eventually to to
generate it from the decryption stub so
you might be kind of sitting there for
two or three hours or whatever waiting
for that key to be generated there are
heuristic markers photonic puzzles and
I'll talk about that a bit later and
some of them will also be vulnerable
to parallelization and distributed
computing so I'm going to show you some
proof of concepts the proof of concepts
are predominantly string text-based but
right at the end I've got some actual
weaponized versions in macros and
executables as well so I'll jump
straight into it with a future timestamp
so in this case this isn't encrypted
it's using a timestamp in the future to
encrypt the malicious payload and what
the malware will then do is get a
timestamp or the system based or from a
server it will then try and use that as
a decryption key if it doesn't work it
will sleep for a certain amount of time
and then try again
you'll notice my really GUI skills here
as well so here we're just taking some
string which is testing one two three
we're putting in some timestamp from the
future encrypting the data and then this
malware will just try once a minute to
fetch a timestamp from a server and try
and use that as the decryption key so I
will skip forward for this rather than
making you sit through it okay and then
it then decruz the issue with this of
course is that you're still relying on
data from a remote source which the
sandbox could could speak for whatever
but this is less susceptible to things
like multipath execution chained hashing
so this is one of my favorite ones with
this one we take some seed text it's
just an arbitrary string or value and
then we hash it and then we hash the
result and then we hash the result of
that hash and we keep going for in this
case 10,000 iterations and said
eventually we end up with a final hash
value and we use that as the encryption
key encrypt the malicious payload with
that and starting from the same seed the
only way to get that eventual hash value
would be to repeat the entire chain
again
so in this case where we're going with
10,000 iterations again that's the
length of the chain we just start with a
random seed value and a string and that
eventually gives us some encrypted text
and then to decrypt the text we need to
repeat that chain so we pass in the the
number of iterations the seed value and
the encrypted text and that returns us
to the plaintext
there are ways this could be could be
defeated so if you have kind of
accelerated Hardware for instance like a
world like a Bitcoin mining rig or
something like that that could be
probably configured and to do this a lot
quicker brute-forcing weak keys so this
works on the principle of layered
encryption so you have some text that
you encrypt with maybe three or four
very weak keys in layers and then for
decryption what will run on the the
victim's computer would be a brute-force
algorithm to brute-force all of those
layers of encryption so in this instance
we just need to pass in a string to
encrypt and then just some weak keys in
this case there they're three character
keys three of them that gives us some
encrypted text and then the decryption
process will just brute-force all of
those weak keys in sequence
until we then retrieve the plaintext so
this technique has been used in some
proof of concepts before it's using
something called our crypto a kind of
similar version to it is used in
Hyperion as well repeated squaring so
this is the technique that's used for
the MIT implementation by Rivas than
others so this is essentially trying to
do RSA factorization so what we do with
this one is we specify two Prime's a
difficulty value and the test string and
the string to encrypt
that then outputs the modulus of those
two prime numbers we already know the
difficulty value which we have to use on
the decryption side and a kind of secret
value our encrypted text so we pass in
those three things the the modulus the
difficulty and the secret value and then
repeated squaring is then performed on
those and so eventually we end up with
the plaintext again client/server so
again this is potentially subject to the
weakness that you're relying on on some
remote source but this one's slightly
different so in this case you initially
encrypt your malware with a a timestamp
concatenated with some secret value
which is stored on a server and you hash
those together you use the hash key to
encrypt your malware and then what the
client does every X minutes is what
we'll reach out to that server and it
will retrieve a hash of the server's
current timestamp concatenated with that
secret value to determine if the the
decryption key is correct
so in this case again in the interest of
saving time the time stamp has already
occurred so it will decrypt instantly so
this is the encryption key so it's just
a matter of passing that to the
application and encrypting the plaintext
and then this is what the server will
return to the malware when it updates so
it's a again the current timestamp
concatenate it with some secret value
and hash together
okay so that decrypts instantly in that
case but you could obviously set your
timestamp to be a day or a week or a
month in the future chain pseudo-random
number generators this is very similar
to the serial hashing concept so again
you start off with some seed in this
case it's a number you specify a number
of iterations and then you run through a
PRNG I'm starting with that value as the
seed and then repeat that and then
eventually do something with that number
at the end so you could either
concatenate them all together for the
number of iterations you've got or you
can hash them or whatever and then use
that as the encryption in the encryption
key so in this case we have a seed of
one two three four five we're going to
do it five times five lots of 10,000
iterations and this is our test string
to encrypt this will then run through
five lots of 10,000 iterations until we
get a final value and then use that as
the encryption key for the plaintext and
then to decrypt that you perform the
same thing again so all you need to know
is the initial seed value the number of
iterations and the encrypted text and it
will then just repeat the sequence until
you can decrypt the plaintext okay this
is definitely my favorite one so this is
proof of work this is based on the same
algorithm that's used in Bitcoin mining
so if you're not familiar with how it
works it is pretty simple so you have
some target hash value and you select a
certain substring of the hash value and
that the length of that substring
determines how long it's going to take
because what you're looking for is a
partial hash collision for that
substring so in this case it's three
it's the first three characters which in
this case is ABC and then you will hash
some data plus a nonce value and if the
substring of the hash of the result
matches the substring of the target hash
then you've won
and you know bitcoins of mind if not
increment the months by one and then try
again and keep going and keep going and
keep going and if you still can't get it
after you've exhausted that the amount
of non C's that are available then you
change something in the data so the time
stamp for instance and then start again
so in Bitcoin this takes about ten
minutes to find a solution here we're
doing something slightly different we
still have a target hash we still have a
substring we're still attempting our
attempts are a hash of some day so plus
an Lance value what we're using is the
encryption key is the eventual hash
value the whole thing so all we're doing
here is we're specifying some plain text
that we're going to encrypt and the
length of the substring which will
determine roughly how long this will
take or how difficult is going to be
that thing gives us some encrypted text
and then to decrypt it we just need to
pass in the the ciphertext and the
difficulty again and it would just
repeat the function so the really nice
thing about this is that there are
multiple results multiple hash values
and non C's which will satisfy that
substring condition but there's only one
hash value which is going to work as a
decryption key so if you're starting you
could start at like a nonce of five
hundred thousand or five million or five
billion or something like that and you
could very well easily get a successful
result but it doesn't mean it's going to
be the same hash value that you've used
to encrypt because Bitcoin mining and
proof-of-work isn't it's more of a
lottery so every nonsuit wire has got an
equal chance of winning okay so some
practical applications so what I'm going
to show you now is proof of work as an
executable stub so actually bypassing
antivirus product then proof of work as
a couple of VBA macros and then sewer
hash training is VBA macro as well okay
so this is as an exit stub so in this
case our malicious payload is calc and
msfn and payload which is obviously
going to trigger antivirus straightaway
we're going to encrypt that so this
would be on the attacker side this takes
about a minute I will skip forward
and once this encryption process has
finished what we end up with is a blob
with encrypted data which is the
encrypted form of that MSF nm payload so
just to demonstrate if you try and run
that as an X E it's obviously not going
to work so what actually is going to be
opened by the victim in this case is the
decryption stub and what we're going to
do is add in that encrypted resource
sorry that encrypted blob of data as a
resource to the decryption stuff so the
decryption stub is going to run exactly
the same process but once it
successfully mines as a problem it's
then going to decrypt the encrypted
resource and run it in memory ok so this
is our decryption stub our new
executable so if we copy both of these
over to a virtual machine that's just
got a standard consumer antivirus
product running on it you can see MSF
finem gets blocked straight away and
deleted as you'd expect other critical
stuff hasn't if we scan it with the
antivirus product it's not going to find
anything obviously because it's still
encrypted at this point if we run it you
can see it's going to do exactly the
same process
so this is looking for a partial hash
collision of four characters in this
case it finds it and then runs the
payload in memory okay and this is VBA
macros so this is a serial hash training
and the proof-of-work thing so here
you'll be able to see it's the same
payload msfn and power calc it's just
been customized for VBA so this is the
array of encrypted bytes the encryption
has already happened
and you can see in the the console
window here we're now doing the hash
training in this case then pops up calc
and this is the proof-of-work demo so
again we have an array of encrypted bias
that's already been encrypted
and again if you look at the console
window you can see it's then
brute-forcing house hashes the one issue
with this obviously is it from the users
perspective if the the program seems to
freeze when it's running so I don't know
if there's a way around that possibly
but that's kind of that the one drawback
of using it as a macro okay and here are
some holy and practical applications
that I haven't tried much as I wanted to
I wasn't allowed to so you could use
lasers so you could shine a laser at the
moon or something and time the amount of
time that the reflected laser beam takes
to come back you could wait for planets
to align in a certain certain way you
could measure the time of orbit for an
arbitrary object around a planet you
could measure bacterial growth which
will kind of vary obviously depending on
conditions and that kind of thing the
one I really wanted to do and really
wasn't allowed to do was to look at the
half-life of different radioactive
materials combined together and wait for
the ratio of them to reach a certain
point but there there are some massively
impractical and dangerous ways that you
could do Tonto puzzles as well okay so
countermeasures photonic puzzles if an
attacker is using a ton of puzzle in a
piece of malware what can be done about
it so I mentioned earlier heuristic
markers and there are some now I'm not
an anti-virus developer a sandbox
developer I don't know kind of even in
practice how difficult these would be to
implement but some markers that
definitely give things away as tile no
puzzles would be obviously encrypted
contents or some kind of blob of
encrypted content dynamic key generation
so there's no hard-coded key and the
keys not fetched from some remote
resource it's generated on the fly
multiple failed decryption attempts so
most time at puzzles will attempt to as
you've seen kind of try and brute-force
themselves and they're finally not
specific to thomna puzzles but but
generally kind of process injection and
process hollowing because obviously if
you just write and
just payload out to disk that's still
going to trigger a signature based
antivirus in some cases there are
cryptography attacks that you could
deploy against Hamlet puzzles as well
from an analysis I did so
parallelization is obviously one
distributed computing as well
one potential technique you could use
from a sandbox perspective here starting
your analysis period after something is
decrypted which then kind of notifies
the whole point of someone trying to
wait out an analysis period
okay so toilet puzzles for defense so
this has been kind of suggested in a lot
of literature over the last kind of ten
or fifteen years and it's a really
interesting potential applications on
your puzzles predominantly to do with
DDoS mitigation so the idea would be
that you have a server let's say it's a
web server that obviously accepts
incoming requests and gives clients
access to resources
if the server becomes aware for some
reason that it's experiencing malicious
traffic or if it's experiencing an
overload of traffic it can then almost
kind of switch on torn up puzzle mode so
with time that puzzle mode what and the
server would do would be to give every
client requesting a resource a time a
puzzle to solve it wouldn't be anywhere
near as long as the ones I've shown you
here today
it might take on a three or four seconds
something like that the client has to
solve that and submit a solution to the
server the server then verifies it and
if it's correct it will then allow the
client access to those resources if the
solution is incorrect then it won't and
you could kind of adjust the difficulty
of those Tomica puzzles depending on you
know the client profile what type of
request it is how many clients you have
requesting resources that kind of thing
and crucially you don't necessarily need
to use it just for kind of HTTP HTTP
DDoS attacks you could use it for things
like spam as well so one of the first
implementations of proof-of-work with
something called hash
anyone heard of hashcash before the show
hands wonder one person rather back okay
are two people okay so hashcash is
really interesting and it contributed a
lot to the development of Bitcoin
hashcash was written by a guy called
Adam back in 1997 excuse me and the idea
behind
hashcash was to disrupt the whole
business model of spammers so the idea
was everyone would have some kind of
add-on plugin to their email client and
if you wanted to send someone an email
your client would have to compute a very
very short time what puzzle a
proof-of-work
again it might take kind of four or five
six seconds something like that once
that solution had been generated it
would be attached to the email or it
would be inserted into the email headers
when that email was then received by the
recipient their email client would check
the email headers for the presence of
that solution verify at their end and if
it was correct it would move it to the
Inbox
if it was incorrect or just wasn't there
it would put it into the spam folder so
the idea the concept behind it was that
for a legitimate sender waiting four or
five seconds to send an email is no big
deal but if you're a spammer that throws
out your whole approach if you have to
spend five seconds for every single
email you're sending you could also use
this technique for API requests as well
so it's something that we're starting to
see as an attack vector for DDoS is
abusing complex
API requests particularly at the back
end and kind of mid tier API requests so
where as kind of from the the client
side it doesn't look like anything
necessarily you know too intensive is
happening within the infrastructure
because of the amount of kind of
interconnected requests that certain
api's have to make it can cause denial
of service conditions on the backend so
again this is something that could be
applied to that so I mention hash cash
and buy them back some other work that's
been done around this
I've cited here one particularly
interesting one is McNiven
and others in 2004 so they suggested or
they actually did is a kind of proof of
concept making changes to the the Linux
kernel to the tcp/ip stack to actually
implement this so when a device for the
operating system tried to make an
outgoing request it would have to solve
a tamil puzzle so I've got a really
brief brief proof of concept for a
defense tolerant puzzle it's really
simple it only works at kind of a
browser level so clients requesting a
particular page have to solve a
JavaScript puzzle and send that to the
server the server then has to verify
that so this is all recorded from the
client side so you're not gonna see a
lot but just to take you through it the
client here is requesting a particular
page you can see the browser is hanging
for you know five six seconds and then
eventually it's granted access and you
can see the result of the timer puzzle
in the URL bar in this particular
instance that's not reusable so if you
then request the same page again you
have to complete the time not puzzle
again and that's the idea behind that is
to kind of stop an attacker then just
sending that link round to everyone so
they can all use the link and bypass the
time puzzle so benefits of using it for
defense good for layer seven attacks and
kind of application layer attacks so
things like kind of exhausting web
application resources if it's done at
that level it doesn't hugely in
convinced inconvenience legitimate users
and shouldn't you know regardless of
whatever level of supply that if you're
a legitimate user you know you shouldn't
mind waiting kind of four or five
seconds depending on what your use case
is of course you can't always mate it
and here at least relatively simple to
actually implement some drawbacks of
this approach is that the verification
process itself can be a new deal
attack vector so an attacker can submit
multiple incorrect solutions
deliberately to cause denial of service
conditions on the server trying to
verify the time that puzzles themselves
there are ways that you could bypass it
potentially it gets pretty impractical
at lower layers so you either kind of
would have to revise tcp/ip or kind of
revise kernels or get everyone to agree
to use a particular client and that kind
of thing
one interesting possibility which is
purely hypothetical and purely
theoretical would be to attach a defense
Tom a puzzle construct to something like
brick a bot so brick a bot is an IOT was
an IOT worm that exploited many of the
same vulnerabilities as Mirai and Reaper
and those kind of things the purported
developer of brick brick a bot claimed
in a statement in January that the
reason he launched it and the reason he
or she had launched it and attacked all
those devices was to prevent vulnerable
devices subsequently being used by
Mariah and Reaper and so on because
brick a bot would permanently brick
vulnerable devices it would try and
upgrade the firmware to some kind of bad
image or something similar and those
devices would then be permanently
unusable and therefore not available for
Mirai and Reaper and so on to to
actually attack and that that some kind
of concept is really interesting and
there's kind of lots of ethical debates
you can have about whether that's ever
the right thing to do obviously it's
still legal but but you know compared to
those devices subsequently being used
for mirror on Reaper is that preferable
it's it's really gray area but it kind
of feeds into a concept called nematodes
or anti worms which is something else
I've been looking at recently which is
the concept of building worms which
exploit the same vulnerabilities as
malicious worms but then will patch them
or prevent them being infected so in
terms of time apostles
and again purely hypothetical purely
theoretical something like brick about
instead of permantly breaking devices
could implement some kind of thomna
puzzle in those devices that would
massively hinder their usability for
subsequent DDoS attacks if they were
infected it's purely kind of completely
blue sky thinking that I'm sure there's
all sorts of problems with it I just
thought it was an interesting idea okay
so in conclusion Tonglet puzzles are
relatively obscure area of cryptography
and historically going all the way back
to 1992 and they were first first
suggested it's all been about the benign
uses of them in offensive security
research they've been very much
underexposed there have been some people
looking at it I mentioned our crypto
there was a paper on a Python framework
that you could use for anti emulation in
my opinion I think it's really important
that the vendors and defenders start to
look at
thomna puzzles and how they could be
kind of misused a problem is that they
are very difficult to identify and
detect to my knowledge they haven't
really been seen in the wild yet other
than malware is created with the likes
of Hyperion our crypto that kind of
thing the literature goes into a lot
more detail about their possible
applications for defense albeit those
aren't always practical but there are
some really interesting applications for
defense and for deterrence particularly
when combined with other measures but
still a very underexplored area of
research and I've when I was kind of
researching this project yet to kind of
see a really practical way that this
could be applied for defense so some
future research that I'd like to do and
I'd like to invite you to think about as
well if you're interested is comment
with more variants of atomic puzzles so
some of the ones that I showed you
earlier were novel some of them were
based on you know the work of others so
Rivest and others for instance the
repeated squaring one but I think it'll
be really interesting to see if we can
have some more variants at on our
puzzles
I think it
be awesome to get some more realistic
applications for defense and some more
realistic proof of concepts and I'm sure
that people in this audience and in the
community who would be kind of far
better suited at doing that than I am
prevention and detection is a crucial
thing so if you have kind of ideas for
how tamo puzzles could be prevented and
detected and that would be really
interesting and I think just from a kind
of societal point of view other uses for
Tommo puzzles would be really
interesting so I went through some
earlier you know time capsules solution
beards release of classified information
that kind of thing but it would be
really cool to see if there are other
ways that this could be used
beneficially for for society as well so
thank you very much if you'd like to get
in touch that's my twitter handle and my
email address feel free to drop me a
line and the feedback or comments if
you're interested in doing some stuff on
tom at puzzles I think I have about five
minutes for questions
I'm so happy to take any thank you very
much yeah
so yeah that's a really interesting
question so so we have used this
technique before for some of our red
teaming stuff and we typically set it
for kind of twenty minutes plus one
actually on that subject one really
interesting possible method of detection
is looking at the amount of CPU cycles
for a certain period of time and that's
obviously something that's also being
looked at for crypto jackin malware so
you could certainly look at CPU usage
but typically yeah we've set it for kind
of 20 minutes and above we don't try and
set it for anything kind of more than 30
minutes just in case something overheats
or something like that but yeah
whether you got one at the back hey good
talk
so not really question but now here for
a time lock puzzle invalid JavaScript
syntax so create a puzzle based on you
basically mutate at the card so it
produces in bad syntax and then the the
server knows the answer and then the
client side you brute force the
JavaScript cold and so it contains valid
send syntax which will return the the
correct password court whatever you
wanna call it yeah that's awesome yeah
that that's really cool so that that
would work yeah that's really cool
who done all right thanks very much
[Applause]