start streaming
yeah here's the agenda three exciting
bullet points one two three we're gonna
talk about chapters we're gonna put that
what projects were operational stuff
okay who doesn't know me my name is dawn
Aiken I'm a community manager I've taken
over tractors what is it you spelled my
name right so basically a lot of people
noticed lately who have been wanting to
open chapters with trying to restructure
everything some chapters head away quite
a bit I'm still waiting to open new ones
we have really worked in the United
States region has really cleaned up I'm
working on Europe so there are some
delays in opening new chapters because
we're really trying to focus on the
regions and there is some game plan
about trying to see how Adam eight
chapters have members and how to help
promote them everyone who wants to open
a chapter any guidelines have a
conference hold me we request obviously
they can read the chapter handbook I we
will send out some updates in the next
few months because we will be updating
things and also JIRA you want to get
paid you need to know JIRA also so
everyone needs to look on that
reimbursements get paid twice a month
mid month the end of the month the board
has to approve just sign off the quicker
your co-leader approves your JIRA
requests the reimbursement requests the
quicker you get paid just the process is
you submit your thing
co-leader approves it goes to accounting
the counting right to be paid and then
on the 15th and the 30th they batch all
those up would have been a report for
the board the board goes yay
we go forth and conquer and then they
get paid and they will get paid not the
next day they usually get paid it takes
cause a banking a few days a couple of
days so lately we really caught up
everyone's around and you know we're
good on that obviously smaller chapters
the basics right now are in order any
new chapter in order to receive $500 see
fun you must have two chapter leaders
good one no one no one can spend money
that they don't have without approval
common statement not really so basically
if you want to have an event and your
budget doesn't have money you need to
have to look pretty approval just cause
you asked doesn't guarantee it's going
to be approval so don't spend a book a
venue that hasn't been approved by the
foundation a lot of times now I will get
help from other chapters to help but
Raptor we'd like to do a lot of things
with students we like to start doing
stuff for the women in app set so we're
trying to give towards that also
chapters we have a look we are up to
last I checked 220 chapters in 220
chapters we do have a virtual chapter as
ever anyone's interested in doing
completely so right now we've really
cleaned up the United States working on
your the other regions are starting to
clean up some of not active so standard
procedure is the wiki page must be
up-to-date at all times if you choose
that you don't want to use the wiki to
up today you have to have a meetup page
which it we can Harold will set up you
but that link must be on the wiki page
so some people can check to see where
your meeting to listen
like when I I have access to another
page but when I go ahead and accept the
organizer progressed it asked me to
paint but then my choppa leader has
reached out to other people so that I
can get access to it and I can set up
the meetups so is your meetup to adapt
the foundation or is your your own
chapter leader foundation so we can add
how many administrators per is there a
limit so email me it don't expect a
response to Monday Tuesday will you get
back and we'll check email me with a
list of who needs to be administrators
also chapters are now three chapter
leaders is the limit if you want a name
other people treasure certain things but
we only acknowledge three chapter
leaders any more on them no a lot of
people to join army up because you the
chapter doesn't have to pay the monthly
fee Herald is the one who sets up for
the meetups for the chapters so it's
three chapter leaders we set up the
meetings the jira trying to go Oh
awesome a lot of people setting up
meetings that you need insurance for
some of the venues request insurance you
would crest that to me I need at least
45 days depending on the insurance how
quickly together it's a little harder to
get an ongoing certificate of insurance
so I would it's easier to tell me in the
basics if you're serving alcohol what
the date is and what the time and the
quest about approximately how many
people are going to be at the meeting
on the merchandise as last week I got a
whole bunch more photos I will be
putting that all up within the next
three weeks all the other merchandise we
have stopped we need about a week just
to know depending when you can send if
it's Friday I can't ship it out to
Monday we're going to start working on
putting some merchandise that you can
with a vendor in Europe because the
shipping cost for some stuff there's so
much money for use when I shipped from
the United States so that we're working
all the tables are out there now we're
talking to a vendor currently and their
pans that we'll have one in Europe so we
couldn't not have to ship stuff across
the Atlantic to this side of it if the
chapter is new and they need help and
wanting just to squat off meetings more
than willing to help send flyers and
stuff we will not be sending swags for
your first meeting we're not gonna send
backpacks we're not gonna send t-shirts
we'll send Flyers we'll bring it to the
wiki page for the branding now we have
stickers up there well what will promote
it on Twitter counter you will promote
it on Facebook well we'll send you the
links to we could do LinkedIn group and
page me up we could do that apparently
what perils about 10,000 yep okay to say
proximately plus or minus 10,000
so the goal is to make the chapter
successful the best way we can
communication if you let me know we can
post blobs about an upcoming event you
have we can tweet about it people help
you promote the goal is to make all
traps is successful and I'm blanking on
so sorry so we have so many regions to
reach out to leaders
self-sufficient we want the challenges
to be so I'm now trying to clean things
up and like we said we're going to put
the merchandise on we're gonna find
stickers and different things that you
can get locally so you don't have to
waste expense to bring to the meeting
Flyers are always available oh one thing
we should say is if you have like if you
know somebody in pull in wants to start
a chapter that's awesome let us know
about it but we were gonna reach out to
that person like you know send Donnie
Melissa say Don there's this guy named
so-and-so and pull in didn't he and
somebody else are when I sorta chapter
and Don can we talk to have been handled
so this or someone you know that you
know who's interested let Don know and
we'll reach out to them and yeah I
usually do is set up oh I always set up
a conference call with the attending
chapter leaders and go to the whole
process for the record right now it has
been months as we're starting from
scratch cleaning things up now I
completed the United States and working
on Europe then I had abscess so it
wasn't fan starts when I get back from
the next weakest out I have call
scheduled again okay also we're going to
go review and when we start to fit
figure the different regions we have to
also say everything is not guaranteed
just cuz you requested because I might
have something very close I know at one
point we had a local chat that for
different people requested to sorta
chapter and that along water to work
with each other oh really
so it's the first email I opened kind of
tonight of the corwin we'll all have the
different people so we are backed up a
little because I just taken it over but
we're working away any other questions
[Music]
I think what we bracket maybe I'm
jumping ahead of you side due to
whatever kind of yeah we're pretty
laid-back here man I think that what
we've recognized is that you know the
community is hugely important and that
chapters are the foundational elements
that forced the community out towards
the foundation and there's probably a
gap in our engagement levels and how
would we as your team support you but
yet maintain the guidelines of the
foundation and ensure equitable support
and distribution amongst all community
members and chapters and that's been a
little bit of a challenge and I think
Matt will show you some charts about
what it looks like so words were very
fluid with the chapter process we want
the community to be a part of it we want
to understand more at least I know I do
and Matt does what what do the chapters
look like how do they function there's a
huge you know variation amongst
different levels of activity amongst
chapters and so what Dawn did was the
basics first we had to clean it up there
were so many variations on how we
treated chapters and funded chapters and
managed chapters and now we want to
start back to the basics with the
understanding that you guys are
everything
this foundation and if it weren't for
you having your meetings and putting
these people and we wouldn't all be
sitting here together today so bear with
us be patient because you know we don't
know so Matt will share with you a
little bit more we're trying to
understand who you are and then find out
the best way to I did some survey sorry
we did like we started to realize I
think we were like anywhere from 23 to
25 percent of our chapter leaders
amendments that's it we started to
realize certain chapters have less than
10 members they might have a list of
twenty twelve hundred people only ten
members of us members so that kind of
stuff week you're in towards to start
research and figure out you know
interesting some of the chapters I've
seen have a problem where someone is the
leader or Thursday group of people
they're leaders and they don't want to
vote meetings unless it has to do with
their company or product or they just
like aren't active anymore but they
won't let someone else anyone it doesn't
have an active chapter this issue they
need to bring it to us and then we go
from there and there's stages then we
contact them because I'm also looking at
their work wines with so many meetings a
year and if you see well ninety United
States in Europe there are a lot of
chapters who's become inactive yeah and
I've gotten a lot of emails from chapter
leaders because if if you're a chapter
leader you're not a member you lose your
wife's email address you're taking off
the calendar taking off so I'm less then
they're like oh no we're active love
it's not on here so then you know then
the communication starts again so we go
from there so I have a few people said
okay I'll fix everything
so some testers that's the case and they
won't let anyone else feel like this is
my perfect use for the Governance
Committee which they're going to talk
about the board meeting or maybe our
chapters really happy but I know let me
know in general they won't ask but do
when you say we have people like
claiming a chapter I have been not
active or whatever they do and then just
hold on to this position or saying you
allowed to do my chapter each do this
it's a different understanding even in
the globalization of what is not
appropriate for the spenders not and how
do we and feels both concepts chapter
president or whatever
vice president we have chapter leaders
and you are supposed to do stuff to pay
there's not an go away can have benefits
since I see it but yet responsibilities
and if you don't to responsibilities and
somebody else will step in
we have no form of process for that and
luckily very few cases see the size
acuity but we have to support them or
think about the guidelines as it's
something but I always said I was taught
responsibility is to help you to create
the rules so everybody can play if
there's promise that and a cabinet is
broken or not sufficient we have to
update
it's not that we are holding this we are
trying to create for you the driver so
he kept a together but this is happening
over the years now they want two cases I
think in two or three years the question
would be to be required and option C
Jupiter if somebody says I don't so
people from baby they check their emails
so we have a time I think a month yeah
they have it for something the chapter
has not been active in let's say five
months when I do the audits in the or
it'll end up being twice a year I sent
around a red flag now when I started
this some of these chapters have not
been updated on the pages for two years
a lot of them shut down and then I send
in the email that you or was you know
the whole bit the whole you know it's
gonna be deactivated but also if it
comes at like you were just saying they
can reach out to me and if they weren't
really involved we can reach out to
those chapters to see and they can also
help a project is so much you can
volunteer for if you're finding there's
a personality situation because there's
so much to do
I know in the past we had a nice tip
Dementors right long time church leaders
having new church leaders how to get
speaker funding how do I operate how do
whatever and I think that was a great
initiative course not
long what do you say that because I've
already talked to a couple chapter
leaders and I know we're good and active
and said hey after you is done and I can
breathe again but why do I have to read
out to them and get like a lessons
learned what worked for you and get sort
of an ala carte menu of like these are
things that work for chapters because
the other thing that's really
interesting about chapters is you have
chapters that are like three people in
Omaha and that's like the three people
that are security people in that
community period right and then you have
like you know New York or London that
has a large body of people right so it's
also I don't want to just say the only
way to do it is like a New York London
model when you're a small group or a big
chapter or little chapters different we
do with the US and Germany is kind of a
different thing with the stumped ish if
I'm saying it right which I'm probably
not
that's why I like the idea of gathering
like these things worked and you can
pick from them what makes sense for your
chapter I don't want to say you must do
a or for your seed but he was like a big
menu and I did receive Sam sent me today
because he has a video that he uses in
this area that I got for us to go over
next week oh cool oh you know within the
next week too and then we're gonna
discuss and maybe set up for the meeting
with him we did talk about I don't know
what month we're gonna start with it
they're back to having at least monthly
chapter leader meetings like different
time zones obviously so I can get
feedback but he needs to clean up a
little more so I know what I'm working
with and then a math back so we can on
that one yes escalations well we really
need like getting our stuff in order
yeah is a good thing and very important
because it's hard for us to serve you
when we're stumbling over systems that
aren't working for us internally if I
may say this for you guys I know lot of
types of deism Portuguese are frustrated
I sent a email then I pain
nobody invites me today or next week
understanding everything if your email
doesn't get reply the next day it
doesn't mean it's not in weeks so we are
active in their workshops big job for
new conference so when a team is a
synchronous communication so we said Eva
you get a reply but maybe not the next
day these people fit through that they
have a lot of people to handle for and I
think doing so but it is a little harder
right yeah because we I just started to
clean up and I did get to regions but I
can't really open chapters in regions
that I haven't researched and done that
way we're not even sure if that chapter
that is there that we're telling you you
can't have because there is one it's
actually is one yeah we'd like to be
able to answer your accurately which
would be good let me add on Martina said
nobody's questioning the hard work you
put into this I think it's just
extremely challenging to like supervise
200 chapters I mean I really see how it
could possibly work smoothly I can tell
you anything about their chapter
somewhere in the world and you need to
believe them and yet well what happens
now I find that things are running
smoothly is that when we follow the
guidelines so now I have like us I know
on these chapters everyone is posted on
the wiki a meeting within so much time I
know that if they didn't they no longer
have a no Wasi email address before if
you are not a member your email address
it's gone things that you've had I know
you're not supposed to have if you don't
do a are now really being taken back and
then people saying okay I want that I
want you owe us email address I want
that and then like Harold we have the
meet up more people involved so yeah it
is a lot but once we get everyone on the
same page then it's red flags when it's
not happening and the other thing to
mention here too is that things like
meetup the meetup row in particular has
an API and we can do some interesting
stuff that I'll talk about in a couple
slides but we can also once we get
things settled and we have sort of
audited and cleaned up the books we can
go and say look whatever if we could
pull the API and say for this chapter
has it had a meeting in X period of time
it hasn't flag it and we're not manually
clicky clicky
the API tell us right and those kind of
automation things can happen once we
have clean data we do it now because we
look at now like we're trying to add
insurance someone needs a certificate
insurance because they wonder venue
there's gonna be now setup said this is
for you contact this is how many days
before and if I could get you know the
chat deletes and different people to
follow those guidelines things can be I
can't get you a certificate of insurance
from tomorrow it just does it's not
going to happen even buy more I got a
request I do all the time how they will
come back to and say these guidelines
don't function well with who we are
today what do you guys think about a
change and and you'll hear some
complaints because we're going to start
you know structuring the way chapters
operate again and stick to the
guidelines so you will hear some people
probably say things that are not so
positive because they're not used to
having some guidelines but it's only
fair and equitable right that everybody
adhere to the same rules
I think it's available with people who
know stork startups being the edgehog
small company moment you in the past
have called the other guys here to dance
I'll do that and now we need a so big
that we need a process three point three
point earlier I was curious when I was
doing in the deck last night and I did
the math and so if dawn only worked on
chapters and she does way more than
chapters and divided her time equally
amongst those chapters block in my
transition I worked hours on this eleven
minutes per week she'd have for your
chapter so we lay just that it's just it
was I was wondering so yeah we're trying
to we're trying to make things with the
least amount of variation so we can
handle them quickly and promptly an
automated module the canvas snow
flakiness and then not so awesome data
right now it's hard to get there but we
are we're we the us were mostly through
Europe and then we knocked the rest on
yes and we are moving like for me two
weeks ago three weeks ago I was under
200 emails a day I was doing doing the
happy dance
beautiful beautiful thing and you're
about three slides ahead yeah but that's
exactly what yes because there are some
of these things that we don't have to
answer in a more public forum well but
if they are in this course and it's
called by Google Google can at least
index it yeah and I felt like a lost
chapter how do I and most of my
questions or activities I have to be
done opening chapters insurance
different a lot of stuff getting
reimbursed for money a check
things like that that the community
doesn't really have your job as much
yeah a lot of stuff like Ohashi mail
addresses have been passed on to someone
else and the IT staff Harold's been
doing some glitches on that that he's
working through but a lot of the
questions I'm doing I'm putting out
fires and the more I streamline things
the less fighters I have to put out
because it's standard procedure and some
of these things I thought would work
don't work some of the things that
people suggested I have some community
under said why don't we try this and
working great so I can't like I said we
can't make a judgement until I clean up
the rest and I do have some I talked to
Martin and I think was Owen and I said
there were some regions I really don't
know anything about and I don't know
like I know New York like everyone say
Brooklyn technically is what ate mozz
way well it's still a totally different
community so I don't know in India in
certain regions how for anyone is
different things so I can't make a
judgment call so I take Martin this can
help me and other people gonna help me
so we need to like and once we figure
all that out we can also gear towards
getting these communities to work
together it's close that time Brooklyn
works with New York City Long Island
doesn't have been together so if we have
these little groups I can pair them off
with a bigger group but I'm not I'll be
honest I'm not there yet I don't have
that knowledge yet in certain regions
and I'm not gonna say that I do it's a
long process but I really do feel very
strongly about this that we are moving
forward as crazy is for everyone in the
way period isn't the greatest we've
cleaned up so much in the last three
months and the change with this venue
and everything and to get out everything
I think we're doing pretty good my
personal good but that was it for your
stuff any questions for me I didn't
wanna hold you from registration for too
long you from you
yes you've already been assigned it I
send it once you I get to secondly I
send a memo to accounting and say I sent
a June 5th it will be put in the July
budget I have the donation scorecard and
scoreboard numbers I'll get posted for
the morning because they just sent it to
me and I was like all numbers on the
chapters section on the donation
scoreboard list in the bottom of 30 days
behind because accounting needs 30 days
to close their books once I clean up the
rest of the regions we'll go back to the
individual chapter transaction reports
but I don't want to post something - I
have surveyed that region that the
numbers are actually correct so yours
was done two weeks ago so you if you
didn't hit you have $500 in your budget
the chapter handbook there's a list of
sort of pre-approved or known expenses
any of those good you can do you can get
a local vendor for yourself yes if you
commit a lot talk to the London chef
Kaimana they would hold your stuff for a
little bit right over right here and if
you have up someone buy you like I had a
chapter recently some chapters make
their own chapter logo but it has to be
approved by Karen so if you want to make
a look someone did it it's orange
someone recently did it that has to be
proved by cam but yes you can get a
vendor by you if it's cheaper because it
is gonna cost me I can't get around up
because a lot of people been trying to
order the cornucopia cause there's 750
box shipping to them is $45 for three
there's nothing I can do about that so
yes you can do that say you going 100
t-shirts you get the receipt submitted
through JIRA I get a second chapter
later approve it you get paid within the
next pay one any of that exists but I've
never run a chapter look for it
probably not but ping me afterwards a
nothing else we can shake some big
chapters and that exists your 20
yeah because the REITs PayPal does not
take certain regions yeah talk to me
email me I'm gonna have to ask the
county on that one
[Music]
that's already set up yeah there are
certain registered SP what region you
are once the asia-pacific there's
another one that is only $20
we also have to you can't totally
eliminate everyone down to a certain
point either because you have to we have
to be realistic too cuz we holiday is we
only have 2,500 paid members I had a
thousands and thousands of people come
to our meetings so that's something that
we have to look at why what don't we
have paid members lawyers people not
joining our organization because we can
have it just a nose
it'll be a thousand people and that and
then I told members but on membership is
only twenty five hundred and that's a
big difference because what chapter
could have a hundred people having a
member and that's very common and that's
something usual because they don't get
absolutely anything whatsoever for
becoming a member
except for a high five from every one of
the chapter leaders but we also because
open we also give like like you look
here chapter Li can come to the meeting
for free gets to get to all this
different stuff that other organizations
might not do for you so that's something
above me yeah but that's something the
board and diamond would decide on that
we're trying to find ways to do both a
find more incentives and value for being
a member right so that we can the top
leaders can circulate among the team and
we can have some fliers when we have
monthly meetings yeah we yeah yeah we
have the membership flyer it's on the
wiki if you don't want to have them
shipped you can do that locally Chevy
I'm sorry did I cut you off
for example if it's by region you still
have for example a country like Cambodia
versus a country like Singapore and
their GDP the membership in the US and
the GDP of the US and then get that
ratio and then you just basically figure
out what three tools regulate that
what's a year and then the registration
system is oh yeah before you head out as
a project calling what is really
difficult with people and there was a
lot of movements especially left felt
more contacts oh she's no longer here
yeah and it's hard to really understand
what is the right person to approach for
a given project I mean once you
stabilize I think things will sort
itself out but right now it's all yeah
and I'm sure I'm always at the wrong
person so basically what we find now is
any of the cases put in 90 members
shifts still goes to Kelly everything
else I get pings every time an IT goes
to power projects but basically putting
a case and address it to me putting it
on general and it'll come to me and I'll
find the person so pretty much Kelly can
tell you any person Kelly knows more
than I do anything but me or Kelly can
tell you who the right person is you
can't but if you don't know who that
right person is ready yeah follow-up
question who's in charge of Twitter
account so for account is Karen
technically one yeah that's mostly me
and Karen you and Kevin - no thank you
yep but I do want to say going forward
once we get that all the chapters
cleaned up I'm going to have chapters
send me directly and I will post for
them on the Twitter account Facebook and
so on yes so then it's one person yeah
we've not told anybody
absolutely and then another thing to
what you were saying is the other thing
we're trying to do and we haven't
because we were small and scrappy in it
like you just knew you maybe build K for
anything or alsa for accounting but
they're both gone and what do you do
we're trying to start also putting sort
of like subject area mail addresses to
things so if there is a reimbursements
we make every umber sment at a loss and
then we can set as a Google group who
that goes you don't need to know under
the covers that's why you know we do
that for the treasurer of the board that
is a good response to my question yeah
yep
and the other thing is we're looking at
the cases because I've never liked how
the Salesforce cases work because once
you submit that unless we email you back
there's nowhere you four know what's
going on with that like I have to push
to you any kind of notification you
can't go back and look at the queue so
Harold and I are have been investigating
ways to replace that with the system
that gives the submitters much better
visibility because that staff I could
see everything but you guys can yeah and
you would know oh crap dawn has 400
things in our chapter queue I just
submitted 401 gonna be a while yeah
right but you don't know that right now
cuz you're the only one as far as you
know needs a bit than the normal case
short out yeah so that's that kind of
feedback we're trying to get in place
anyone else last chance
I'm gonna chat for a wee little bit then
we gotta hand it over to Harold and then
if we have time I may chat for a wee
little bit more oh so yeah my point is
if you haven't figured out the
foundation staff is pretty thin there's
all of six of us FTEs so what we've
really asked view is just a little bit
of patience we're really working hard to
get the systems nailed down and
straightened out and audited and cleaned
up because like I mentioned there's been
a little bit of chaos and we just have
to clean up from the cast and we'll be
good so please give us a bit of patience
and number two like allow us to simplify
things right now when I was paying
invoices last fall I would get an email
that says hey I need you to pay this
invoice and it could be in meetup Pro
any one of the individual chapter
meetups it might be an event right
Eventbrite or Eventbrite and that's not
a typo I know of for different
Eventbrite accounts and I might have to
go login and pay and then there's
doorkeeper two for the chapters in Japan
so like when I have to go pay an invoice
I have to go figure out which of these
things it is sometimes so we're trying
to like Whittle these things down to
systems that solve 80 to 95 percent of
the problems and then use them all over
the place so that I don't have to fish
through ten different things to find
what it is and like see FPS could be an
easy-chair or submit alluro fancy a fee
or pay per call that I owe and if I need
to help you with that like I only know
one or two of those a bit I don't know
the other one at all and so I'm gonna
log into it so we're trying to like
figure out systems where we can have
like the thing that you do is here
and it's gonna solve your problems and
if we need to talk and figure out an
exception that's fine but I'd rather 90%
of the people use the norm and if we
have exceptions we'll figure out how to
handle this right maybe the system isn't
right who knows as we start to make
these choices I'm gonna be very vocal
about this is what I'm thinking tell me
if this won't work for you otherwise
we're going forward because this was
nuts like when Kate left and I started
paying the bills it was insane
find another event well that says pay
too so yeah so this just has to be
cleaned up so that's what we need a
little bit of patience for Oh other
things we're looking to do is revive the
chapters and projects committees that
used to exist and then died and I think
need to come back because I think we
lost a really good feedback loop from
the members that are out there doing
things for OWASP
right the projects committee and the
chapters committee in particular those
are our active people in their
membership we need to have a debate for
them to tell us things that's more
effective right so get a committee going
as a chapter you have a problem you can
ask talk to the chapter committee and if
they need to have the foundation do
something they can talk to us right it's
a wave and if they've already handled
then they can just tell the chapter oh
by the way this is what you do there's a
bunch of people that are in that
chapters committee probably no chapters
much better than me
so I don't have that committee kind of
handle those things provide feedback and
all that and then this is very early
days for me but I'm trying to figure out
ways to handle maturity levels and
incentives for chapters and I had this
as very soft and squishy in my head I
have no hard and fast rules I'm thinking
about this but there's really no
distinction between chapters like I was
saying earlier I'm picking on Omaha I
don't know if that was it a small rural
part in the u.s. that I can't remember
it came to talk to me and they said we
literally have seven people that meet
once a month and is it okay if we're
also a wasp and Issa and aisaka because
like were the seven people in the small
area that care about security and I'm
like you know what if you meet the
minimum rules for chapters I don't
really care that's fine right we got
minimum rules you do that you want to
co-mingle with other groups like
whatever we're friendly but that's no
different than New York or London there
are big chapters do lots of stuff and
have tons of members so we need to
figure out a way to understand the
measurements and the metrics around
chapters and I don't know that we
collect or have that now but I want to
start collecting and having that so we
can make distinctions between what types
of chapters and this isn't good or bad
this is like big small maybe or
you know the active or inactive or
something like that it's not necessarily
a judgment it's more of a understandable
kind of chapter you are we're trying to
figure out ways to provide incentives so
you can mature like hey maybe if you get
10% of your people are actual members
that attend maybe we give you you know a
slip you a little bit extra more on your
budget or send you rounder t-shirts or
who knows one right something like that
some kind of incentives like okay if you
can help us we can help you and figure
out a way to help great chapters get
recognized and take that information
this is kind of something about later or
earlier about talking to active chapters
that are successful and say what are you
guys doing that works so we can put that
in a sort of some sort of consumable
format for new chapters so they can go
and say hey this is the menu of things
that chapters have tried and they worked
or these are things we try to didn't
work and let them have a little bit of
sort of shared knowledge of the
community before they particularly for
new chapter to have just got a wide idea
and headlight what do I do
right well when I talk a little bit
about this meetup pro so the OWASP
foundation hasn't been a pro we handle
billing I would love it if everybody was
just there and we just paid one bill
we're not there yet but we'll get there
were closest Harold has done a lot of
migration which is fantastic we also had
somebody created a MediaWiki extension
that if you had a simple tag in your
wiki it will take your stuff an army to
probe and boost it automatically to your
wiki page got it right here Ottawa
chapter does that if you let me see so
here's the auto chapter
you scroll down a bit what part is
auto-generated and this is so these are
the kind of things we were looking to do
where we can if we have consistency we
can automate I can't automate a hundred
thousand snowflakes but I can automate
200 of the same thing real easy so
that's it that's an awesome cool hwhip
and I don't think a lot of people know
about that that's one of the reasons why
I wanted to talk about it thank you
volunteer
oh yes this is very early days where
Harold and I are trying to work on
figuring out a way that chapters can
work with projects and projects with
chapters so if you have some students in
their area that could help
we're trying to find a way to
might be trial and error this is a fluid
next 12 months as we find our way
together experts it's very clear that
the professors in the colleges
[Music]
actually I'm doing one of the systems
we're looking at that did make the deck
is a volunteer management system that we
tie into our CRM and those are the
things you can playing in there like
this project has these kind of things
and then you can put a dynamic board
that says I know this and it looks like
well these seven projects need CSS or
whatever the reverse is true and I know
how I was working on classifying
projects in certain categories so if you
want to use a project you know where he
goes
[Music]
we can link it to a chapter so here in a
certain region yeah yeah dude here
playing nice I'm gonna give it to arrow
is this is project time before we start
with me I don't know how many of you
actually know Karen that Karen is our
executive director of Oh boss so let's
start with inferred most of this already
challenges for projects early go long
probably late last year we were
migrating to a new version of our CRM
and that migration didn't quite go as
expected
it wasn't even complete at the end of
that time and so with all the time that
we spent this year is getting that
cleaned up and moving forward so that we
can get the new projects into our system
we still have ongoing gender fix gender
fixes
that's costing us money it's taking
their time and also last year we had
lots of churn and the foundation itself
so we do have about a backlog of project
issues cases hundreds of them so some of
the plan to fix some of this one is to
use JIRA to handle new project requests
the project promotion request and what
this will do by taking it out of the
Salesforce allow us and that was
something about tracking chapter type
things this will allow us to track where
is this that we don't have to you have
to come to us to know where your project
is that most particular steps it will be
in zero
we also want to connect the information
what that has to do with is providing
API is using the api's that are
available to us to connect say our
financial information to our wiki in the
project area so that if you need your
project funds like how much money do I
have you don't have to wait on me
they'll be listed one of the issues we
have right now is that the funds are at
least 30 days behind at least sometimes
it's 60 you may need your funds pretty
quickly
I'm waiting then you're going to get I'm
going to do more project Town Hall's I
don't know how many of you knew about
the previous Town Hall we had in June I
think it was well thanks Steve he showed
up we had two of them and it was a
little bit late so some of that's on me
right I think I told fuel about it maybe
to Ocean City bands so for August we're
going to have another I will send that
out well here are two weeks in advance
and we'll have more than two times at
two times said that one was for our time
as far as lunch time and then the other
time was around
six hour time as well so that would
allow our people to come in at 6 p.m.
and people in the UK would be at 6 p.m.
on our project leaders so I send it out
to the host leaders listen project
members go as well with absolutely so
one of the things we want to do moving
forward is also a reintroduction of the
project summits I think Martin was
actually talking and doing this we want
to take them separate from the big
global conferences make it so that
there's more regional and focused on the
handful of projects and that this huge
spattering we think that this would
provide a breeding ground for new ideas
new projects how to use a project
differently maybe integrate the projects
a little bit better like this project in
this project earth we find that hey they
can use each other and bring in our own
project forward we want to provide a
place where you can get project services
you want you need a tech writer
what's available this goes to what you
were talking about that we'd have a
listing of hey I need translation
services
we do have great projects that continue
to come in the amass project that Sharif
brought us from Jeff Foley it is it
basically looks at the network and does
the reverse and ends up turning it into
something that looks like this it's a
network map yeah so it gives you what
it's actually where so he can do it both
ways you can give it a bunch of domains
that you own and it will just tell you
where they are
but you can also do it the other way
around which is you say okay this is my
data center or these are my external IP
ranges what is running there and it will
go give it give it to you but it'll also
put it in this Quran this is neo4j which
is a graph database so you can actually
query that and say Rackspace I don't
know I had anything in Rackspace just
tell me all the domains that are
actually resolving to Rackspace or
something like that and it will show it
to you so you just run this this isn't
just a pretty visualization this is
actually a graph database you can see
the relationships and you can ask some
interesting questions because now if you
know that there are certain sites that
you're covering from a security
perspective you can say well those I
know
and those I'm actually you know trying
to protect what else is out there that I
don't know
it's thorough because it found cheese
monkey that was got work yes this is
what I was using to test by ansible to
deploy let's encrypt search and I
figured that's a crazy freakin name who
would guess that and it still failed DNS
record but it fell yes
it also found one that I am absolutely
love which is did you guys know that
there's a short fling stock loss all
stored yes so I sound that loss not work
if you want to put on Twitter or
something a short link so you said that
it would provide translation so our
project is planning videos where we're
going to do things in the project and
release them and I'm just going to pay
to caption them if someone could help
with translation it'd be really cool to
have it be available in multiple
languages that's part of what we're
going to are interested in but if they
charge or provide their services for
free I personally have had
a handful of requests from people who do
translation services specifically
translation services services that are
either the foundation rounds or services
that we don't necessarily run but we
know other projects chapters have used
and they're useful like maybe we don't
necessarily have a login account but you
know this other product and this thing
they needed done and they use the
service that was actually useful for
them so if you do find a service or
something that's neat and usable let us
know
yeah at least like isn't I know the
translation and you've already been
through this video payment that Johnny's
we can actually sort of give the vendors
they in the meantime if you need
something like that you can send me
I think some thing we don't know what we
just thought we want to have more of
them and we're not exactly sure that's
another that's another sign up yeah
[Music]
because maybe some companies would be
okay with just giving us like one big
room for a few days right especially if
there's like an employee that works
there that can like sign the forms and
be like I'll make sure no one wrecks the
place sort of thing right right if you
want to get that connected to the OAuth
stuff that's probably
speaking of the project one of the more
recent ones was the precluded a lost
book project with Cherie gay Becky put
together they produced an eBook version
of OAuth Sam and correct me if any of
this seems to be a little wrong it's so
it's basically you take mark down you
use various tools that eventually
produces an e-book as the output what
the end goal is the defined process to
produce ebooks through this thing you
have github you put down your part down
and get how you put on a web book and
get out there to run a tool to create
your evil yeah so that's exactly it so
I'll give you an idea just really quick
Sam when I showed up and I asked them
can I see the artifact so we can update
it they basically said here's a PDF but
says no no what's the where it doesn't
matter if it's a weird awkward text or a
month down so no no it's PDF and they
actually had to use Acrobat writer to do
Sam 1.5 that's why as an update problem
so we've got turn it into markdown so
it's easy to be edited you can turn it
into whatever what we well then we'll be
able to create that process so it's easy
to automate if it's in markdown then we
can take it and so on what's the one
challenge that we have right now to get
it to
sorry the bookstores and so on that's
what we want to get to is that markdown
on its own doesn't have like a nice
design to it but the good news is you
can put in CSS into it so one of the
things that some of the books have asked
is that we have a CSS template not
mandatory but if someone chooses to use
it that it's available so that the
tables look nice and the diagrams look
neater so if we have that template then
we'll just introduce it and then
basically hand it over to the foundation
so that it just becomes a service in a
box
hey we've just updated a document we
also now want to have it published
visible and that will be just
streamlined yep can anyone write a book
on something yeah all I could find was
PDFs of the freaking bylaws so I turned
him in to mark them and there now I'm
kip-up
and when I do updates I actually do a
board meeting and that's a change then I
take the markdown and convert it to PDF
and also convert it to MediaWiki tags
and one last nice little thing about
markdown is that even someone who isn't
technical like a writer can their music
so Becky was the writer that actually
took it from PDF and so on hmm didn't
know that much about it and was it
necessarily the most technically
proficient person like when she showed
up she was like what's going on here and
then sat down here is markdown here's
WYSIWYG editor for it and she did well
took about a year of planning in a day
and a half to get it done so Katy and
look forward tree is looking for
somebody who might know CSS CSS so yeah
designer that doesn't mind working with
books so that we can finally publish Sam
the top ten as well which we got Andrews
back singing this week and then package
it up and then anyone who wants to use
that process can do that
so yeah anyone who wants to play with
style sheets to create like a template
for other books please reach out to me
and it's a priest
absolutely anybody who wants to write a
website look absolutely go ahead and do
so and you know this would allow us to
start selling books that aren't ok
various things is left there's project
wikispace updates donation processes we
want to start doing an automated thank
you that basically sends it out to the
person who donate to a particular
project or chapter where they get a
thank you
and then you're notified as the leaders
of the project or chapters that these
people gave you a donation that allows
you to go out say hey thank you
personally and this recent donation
thing would be something that the vision
is that under wiki page or project page
you would have a list I would actually
list here the recent donations for your
project
project release and update information
we want to get more involved with
getting out your project releases right
now the way to do that is not very well
it's not step in the way it's currently
done typically somebody in slack around
Twitter will make statement this we
unfortunately aren't able to monitor
everything all the time so from our
perspective we don't know we don't know
until finally somebody lets us know so
we wanted to come up with a process by
which when you do a release that
automatically you don't have to do it
[Music]
some of the other things is one of the
things that we've been bouncing around I
know that there's currently a project
that is aiming to provide a little to
cloud services that are out there too
but perhaps some oh uh sponsored
low-cost no-cost cloud services
depending on say like your project level
flagship like a no-cost cloud service
and something that Steve mentioned was
having a defect record protocol where
the project lives and one of the things
he brought up you would like to see
something better than this but say
issues we actually have opened up JIRA
for them to start using that to start
tracking things as an experiment so it's
possible that we can use our own
well they actually have lips I haven't
forgotten this it may have been possible
I wasn't around and things were chaotic
oh my god really attack there's oh I've
been forgotten this this has have been a
thorn in my side for ages my daughter
was like no your Wikipedia
yeah no Harold is been doing so good and
I this is why I haven't done it because
if you've seen any kind of stylistic
thing I've done you're looking at it
like it ain't pretty
Harold is much better at uija graphics
to me and he has patients for tonight
don't he's been peeing a lot of
different changes to make the the style
side of the wiki much better I have a
meeting next week with a consultant or a
contractor that we were considering
hiring who understands media wiki
content organization side of things like
categories and how to actually make
sanity in the organization of the
insanity that is our spaghetti wiki
[Music]
yeah well then we're all Sami one of the
I'm looking at a bunch of different
things and there's a there's some
possibility of switching out our CRM
system and that CRM system has a way to
front it with a like a public much more
public general website so maybe we front
the wiki with the more public website II
thing I don't really know but all
options are open because what we have
now doesn't I mean it works because it
answers on port 443 and 80 but that's
not where the segment ends so we will
make this better it we know it's not
awesome
let's go I was going to show you one
example of this as I was playing around
now I didn't so I was playing around
last night for your June of 2017 before
things went crazy before Payton Allison
left in my life went sideways I was
playing around with actually using
categories properly in choking the
information in the wiki based on a usage
case so if you're interested in a lost
project spheres things if you're
interested in contributing here's things
if you want to actually if you're a
leader here's things because right now
we have this gigantic tab Tampa 5ms
that's the project page but I can't find
crap in it and I've been doing project
since 2008 god helps somebody who's just
new to auspi trying to find something so
this is like conceptually what we wanted
to do and if you if you look at him do
categories correctly you can do
interesting things like have Auto drop
downs if like all the flagships this
isn't actually accurate I only have two
but like this is you can actually do
these Auto generated lists of projects
on places because they're categorized
correctly right now though there's
projects project most project a los
projects categories we actually have
over 500 categories in the wiki right
now it's it's insane and so the other
nice thing is if we can get the
structure saying we can do automation
like if a new category gets created and
we don't know about it like what the
heck let's go look did something get
creative when they made a wiki page do
we need to go fix that do we need to do
a little maybe education of a new
chapter leader who added a weird tagging
it didn't work like they thought like we
can't do that now because it's just
spaghetti isn't it so we can get here we
can actually start moving forward and
the other one that was brought up
earlier discourse
I love mailman no it's awful I mean it's
awful to admin it's awful in terms of
features its way the heck out of date it
just needs to go away and I want that to
be discourse I wanted that to be this
course before I just never got to it and
now we'll do it but for no other reason
we're trying to migrate off of the host
on which this lives and it has to go
somewhere so my my plan is to take a
sort of static snapshot of all of the
archives of all this we'll put that on a
static web server and it can just sit
there so that we still have Google foo
and otherwise everything - yeah so man
one has to go while it's still there if
you have problems actually I would put
in a contact us because here older I can
do it and that way dong can get two
rivers free that's a better way to get
it because either one of us can do that
everywhere they get caught because guess
what like sometimes people are talking
about like attacking Web Apps categories
this hacking it's really weird this guy
he's a leader he's talking about this
weird exploit thingy and you know
Barracuda lost its mind and said it was
awful which it would be if it was a
corporate network but it isn't so fine
let it go and by the way bliss is gotta
send how would you the the plan is to
ask the owners of the mail list well and
we have nine hundred and some-odd mail
lists I think it was I don't remember
it's been about a year since that the
numbers but I think it was roughly 15%
of those actually had had a post within
a year so we have loads of cruft but
those that are actually active and my
definition of activists you
a post within a year which is a pretty
loose definition of active I will ask
the owners is this thing worth keeping
and if they say yes we'll take the list
of people that are on mailman and email
them and say hey this thing is going
away if you want to we here's a link go
add yourself to this place because I
don't want to force subscribe them to
disperse but I want to give them the
option members it's for everybody the
another thing that I like slack I think
slack is pretty cool but the other thing
that's really unfortunate about slack is
that it's not NX funky and so if you
answer a really cool thing about how to
fix something in Java on a mail list at
least that was indexed by Google but
that's not in slack so like almost has a
lot of good advice that gets hidden in
slack so let's unhide it by putting it
on disk that's kind of one of the my
main thrusts it'll be this fall of the
earliest because I have this and I have
a whole bunch of hoo-hah that has to
happen between now and August and then
in August on me and my two kids are in
an international tournament in London
yeah and then the other nice thing with
honestly from a just a functional
operational point of view is I can SAS
discourse the discourse people X dollars
and they just run the thing I love the
fact that like operationally I don't
have to go unpatched OS and though
there's an updated I know we just give
you some money and this thing stays
current before but we never went real
with it we tested it and I had thrown up
a couple docker first
of it to play around and make sure it
was cool
because I've got my I guess my point was
talking about docker was like out to the
point where I realized I tried it and
this will work and then I never got
beyond the like hey let's talk to them
and see do you see what I'm saying
that was one of my next steps too
because yeah I loved playing the charity
card hey we're a charity like give us
free stuff I mean if they say no we're
nowhere soften if they say yes like
awesome yeah I'm trying to give
everything as that as much as I can not
run by people in the foundation because
I'm not sure they help you guys which is
a much more unique skill set than just
paying somebody some money since we're
going to be using and they don't use
mailing list because mailman is rubbish
so anyway to kind of integrate with
because you mentioned a cool automation
with the meter Pro to actually get the
mailing list from meetup somehow
integrate with this course so we don't
have to be post yeah I don't know of an
existing thing that does that they both
have api's that are fairly same so it
may exist as a either an add-on a pay or
a community thing or we could write it
but I don't know if it is explicitly
existing today and I put a nor did I
research
yeah we have to see but that could be uh
you know get some students to knock up a
POC we give them a docker image and some
meetup account that's bogus and try to
migrate it if it works then we do it for
reals at you on the real server we did
with our thing I just like yeah there's
a load of integrations with this course
having a monthly chapter leaders meeting
my go-to meeting I think I think we
probably need two different timezones
outcomes to publish any chapters any
cool idea that needs to be shared and
there's some operational things oh I'm
in the middle of migrating this is the
thing that's going to happen when this
is done before I start karate-chopping
people migrating off a higher cost used
to be donated but isn't anymore host to
in less expensive folks because we're
spending i'm also retiring a bunch of
past wordpress sites that were used for
conferences and i'm static to find them
and shooting them in the head and then
leaving them on a static site because we
actually have EPSA qsa going all the way
back to 2005 like we have all those
sites like 2005 all of them only used
like all of those like still answer on
domains and I've been moving them all to
static and so I kind of hate it to just
turn them off so they all I found a nice
way to turn WordPress into static and
they're all being static for fire and
then for the stuff I'm doing I have
written some ansible that both handle
these migrations and also redirects so
like for this conference app psyche you
if you just type in FC key you write it
redirects you to app state 2018 app
psyche right next year will be 2019
that's an ansible script that I wrote
that just goes and answers for 43 and 80
and 80 redirects to 443 and 443 is
covered by a let's encrypt CERN so it
cost us nothing that we get a less
forwarding to the right place like all
that's automated now we're using
HootSuite to better handle social
management we just restarted using
HootSuite so now we can currently it has
Facebook groups pages us Twitter and
then just staff upgrades issues in some
kind of inside ball but just so if you
see this you understand what's happening
I set up a domain ojas foundation.org
and we're gonna migrate all staff on to
that email address so that you can tell
the difference between a staff person
and just a wasp member right yes and
when you leave we just turn this off any
kind of weirdness because that's also
your community address right like for me
that would be a problem so a lot of
people complain when they become a wasp
members they don't can we please
automate that process so when someone
becomes a paid member there's some
there's some CRM things we have to get
lined up first but yes that's definitely
on the
it's kind of honestly like selfishly
from a staff perspective that's a dumb
thing that I could automate why would I
want dawn to have to answer an email and
automated that's right so yeah but we
have to like we say clean house and that
stuff and then finally we're rolling out
LastPass across the staff so we have
password there is actually actually the
discount code is going to die in San
Jose because we have wired in the CRM to
the registration so it knows that you're
a leader and that's one nice thing too
we we had done some POC work on
connecting the sort of tags for lack of
a better word we give you like
leader-member and whatever in CRM like
these kind of things and see around to
discourse so when you're in discourse
and you create a profile we can say hey
member badge leader badge you know
whatever we can actually attach those to
you yeah I wanted to you back oh I meant
well this is I'm using discourse speak
discourse bead calls bad just like
achievements oh and so you can when you
log in your profile would say here's you
and by the way you're a leader and
you're also a Tucker member and you're
in the we org or whatever these kind of
things that are in our C and we can
actually surface in discourse which is
another really cool reason because then
like being a member it's very public
about it like this guy you answered my
question he's not just some random Joe
as a discourse account he's actually
always a project leader and he's a
member of Olas yes and I think no more
ops oh that's boring and I was on
business against the foundation staff
hours kept getting locked when you buy a
whole bunch of different than nominated
European
currency Amazon gift certificates from
America you get locked out of Amazon
it's the weirdest thing
true
and by the way speaking of Amazon smiled
at amazon.com we're a charity I'm hooked
up with my smile to OWASP books yes
merchandise yet merchandise is still a
bit of a mess honestly we need to get
providers and regions I'm playing with
step here is that what's up how you say
that whatever for a playground that's up
yours up for process automation which is
really pretty cool we're like I get an
email and I give it a tag in Gmail and
automatically drops it into a card in
Trello whoo and yeah yeah yeah like done
I'm reviewing GoToMeeting
I'm not going to switch it do you have a
question before I go to meetings okay
I'm looking at alternatives to go to
meeting just because we haven't like
looked at that in years and I know
there's a lot of options and I'm not
even sure if those options are better
worse different or or lesser and more
expensive but I want to kind of look at
that and see if there's something better
we can use yeah that's a problem we have
the GoToWebinar thing an account but
it's kind of a mess that's one of the
things that's motivating the other pro
30 years yeah because they're that kind
of issues hit assume is on my short list
not about Skype Skype could be a rush or
at least
they were like a team that's all across
the world and there's 60 of us and we
have team meetings and we use super sky
yeah yeah I've used in my past employers
and it was fantastic yeah
so that's one of them on my short list
looking at a platform and then I don't
I've looked at several platforms I try
to find a platform to handle non global
app sites so if you're doing a regional
event and you need a calendar and
registration and a web page and see call
for papers I've looked at a couple of
platforms that handle kind of all of the
junk around holding a regional event in
one place you could put it on Austin org
domain and you can go there in all of
the events will happen in that place so
that we don't have like 50,000 different
event systems and it's just DC if you
want to have a little bit like it's just
right here the ones I've looked at I can
actually delegate your event to the
event team but it's still sort of
foundation you know globally control
that we end up building in the Oval
India our current event insurance
provider is less than stellar and we're
trying to find a new one so for slow
getting you venture event insurance
that's why they're particularly
responsive to any plans to replace the
payment system and I would consider the
payment system not what you see but what
shuttles the money around but yes the
front end yes we're looking at one we'll
use a totally different one for Jose
because reg online yeah I agree it
wasn't fantastic he was like I've been
doing events at oh lost forever and I
was like yeah so yeah I know that was
some optimal UI but that was the best
the time frame and definitely looking at
replacements and it doesn't read online
doesn't understand our Sierra Mitch is
one of the other problems we don't know
you're a leader Donna's going in quite
honestly and double-checking people who
put it a leader go to make sure they're
really leader which is both like I want
her doing much more high-value work than
cool I think that's all I got yep I
don't know if it was staying at the very
beginning it's great to be back I yeah I
told I told the I've told a lot of
people this I'll tell you this like I
think if Karen had showed up a couple
weeks before she did I probably wouldn't
have because basically what happened was
almost anywhere mm-hmm I'm kind of
grumpy right now I'm doing a lot of crap
that I don't want to and it seems
chaotic and yeah that sounds better but
I was very very happy to come back
because I'm up 10 to Karen at snow frog
where I was speaking and talked to her
and really was super excited about what
she wants to do with the work so I'm
very very happy and we don't forget
[Applause]