so my name is Amit Ashville I work for
checkmarks shimmie Ashkenazi he also
works for check marks his research team
we're gonna talk a little bit about
serverless injections today serverless
is a big thing now it's growing
significantly and we thought it's
important to look at the security aspect
of that how many of you by the way are
using already server lists ok nice like
10% 5% maybe so we'll quickly talk about
an introduction to server less which
I'll run through very quickly because
most of you probably are familiar with
it
we'll look at a few server security
assumptions and then Jimmy will have the
hard work of doing the demos and
explaining the technical details of what
we did in terms of understanding where
the security is limited what needs to be
improved changed or what's good also and
then we'll have an example of what you
can do in order to test your security or
your code security even in a service
environment so starting off in the past
we had data centers Hardware was the
unit the abstract material was actually
the physical hosting environment so you
had a computer a server in a hosting
environment and that was your server
later on we moved to infrastructure as a
service where the operating system
became the unit of scale and the
hardware was no longer relevant for the
let's call the users for us and then we
had platform as a service where the
application was the unit of scale and
the OS was no longer relevant you just
launch your application it runs there
you don't care where it really or what
OS is really running it you don't have
to set up an OS or anything like that
and today we're it's serverless we're
function is the unit of scale and the
language rent runtime is the abstract
there are a few different types
of service environments today there are
more than these we'll talk about them
all so later
AWS is probably the main one at the
moment we then have ashore IBM cloud
functions and Google cloud platform
we'll be talking specifically about AWS
today so again looking back data centers
we used to deploy in months so you had
to set up your server implement it make
all the security checks and so on so
forth and then they used to live there
for years later on we moved to deploying
in minutes on virtualized clouds and the
systems used to live for weeks they
still do and when contort containers
were introduced we deploy and second and
we'll live for hours so you drop the
container you start a new container and
with AWS lambda you actually deploy in
milliseconds and you live for seconds
actually 60 seconds after these 60
seconds the functions that you've
deployed just disappear off the server
so again the classic approach you had
the back end which was stateful very
accessible for hackers where today you
actually don't really have a back-end
it's not stateful at least you do have a
back-end but it's not stateful and it
moves all over the place so one of your
functions could be running on thousands
of servers it's multiple time and
disappearing or running on a bunch of
different servers and replacing every
time that's the process you develop you
push you trigger and you clean so
nothing is left over that's the
assumption that nothing is left over
after you finished deploying your
functions or triggering your functions
actually the advantages of server less
infrastructure are one that they are
scalable you can run as many functions
as you want on as much CPU that you want
there's no operations behind the
it's very easy to implement and the cost
is lower because you're only running
what you need really you're not buying a
server you're not buying a cloud server
you're actually running exactly what you
need or leveraging the CPU and the
resources that you need exactly the
disadvantages first of all it's a new
paradigm like every new paradigm that
has to be learned understood better it
might be a bit slower in some cases
because you have to trigger or or start
the function every time that might take
a few milliseconds monitoring is
difficult again because you're not
really sure where your functions are
gonna run at any given time and it's not
platform dependent so you have as we
said earlier you have the different
vendors who provide the different
platforms so a little bit about the
different platforms we mentioned the
commercial ones there are also some open
source solutions quite a bunch of them
actually there are names of some of them
and this is an overview of the top three
AWS lamda it's probably the most common
and matured as I mentioned earlier it's
been around since 2014
it has a wide language support or wider
language coverage and will focus our
demo on that specific platform and then
you have the coop the Google cloud
function which was introduced about two
years ago in alpha it's still considered
in beta and it supports only JavaScript
nodejs runtime at this stage microsoft
azure also introduced two years ago
supports a bunch of languages in
experimental stage
very well integrated obviously with
visual studios and Microsoft
environments a bit more about Amazon as
we said introduced 2014 supports nodejs
Python Java go net core Linux containers
can be triggered using all of Amazon's
different services so whether it's s3 or
the any of the the services that we use
on Amazon's AWS obviously you also have
an api gateway that you can leverage
well this slide talks about the
different use cases for server less
environments but I think that the most
relevant ones would be the file and
image processing and any heavy CPU
utilization so imagine you want to do
image processing today you need a lot of
CPU power if you want to do image
processing with server less you just
need a lot of servers running the same
functions or the different functions so
it's very useful when we're talking
about high CPU or CPU intensive
functionality which includes a lot of
these specific cases some assumptions
based on a research done by rich Jones
awhile ago so the fact that the
functions are running in their own
environment reduces the potential damage
and the fact that nothing is stored so
the function is removed deleted disposed
after run also prevents stored
injections because if you inject
something it's deleted later the
function is new and clean should be much
more secure with that I will pass it on
to shimmy will show you why these
assumptions are not necessarily accurate
thanks to meat so as we mentioned the
the common assumption is that the server
is more secure than others drones and
other security visual search including
checkboxes of stream I want to eliminate
this assumption so in the research
stream of check marks we wrote a demo
app that's as a simple UI and in the its
back-end it's run free service function
in the iaws lambda there it is example
of two Fox
the main factions is invoked once this
page is loaded and it's returning the
results they state the data of the main
box including the widows visitors Kanto
and inside it in the invoke in another
lambda functions called cars according
to the marked input in the URL cows and
it's get a parameter and number in milk
parameter 1 and in this case you can see
therefore the front end of the
application including data from 3 to
lambda functions another function in
this demo app is the users and you can
use can see an image of the user at
internal data they taken form a cloud
database and there is a really thin
client it's only invoked serverless
functions and let's see it's running
just to let me shoot snots a screenshot
yes you can see while clothing the Rizk
invocation of the lambda function the in
this stage the male is triggered Nick
created and in milliseconds disappeared
it's they use aside it like any other
application so this code that I wrote
secret it's include code injection after
our code is code it's every code if it's
routine correctly and on purpose or not
a purpose could be vulnerable what is
the code injection there is a very basic
definition of of ASP I pretty sure you
already know in case you have an input
that it's sourced by the user it's not
been sanitized and it's get tree and of
that flow to an invocation a command
like even in JavaScript then it can be
answered
so if it's the code that I wrote and I
on purpose internet congestion inside it
you can see an evil of the JavaScript
that's running the code and the code is
built of the event trigger the event
trigger is the input of the lambda in a
function as we said event it trigger is
not always the textbox so regular input
it could be iota vol 10 it could be API
service and in this case we could clue
to parameters that we saw in the URL the
resource names it will create the
invocation to the internal lambda
function
anomalous parameter so okay and this is
the function code we start the in this
market call injection do you concede in
this I admit
I will code another vulnerability its
marked away in the first line there is
some sensitive data exposing the code
not related to server less but just may
we'll get back into its later if you're
writing your code don't do it you it
will have a serious impact in the next
stage of the demo you can see the
database core included API key expose
it's not scripted in the code okay so
assuming we have the code injection and
will try to attack it with further and
until we find the malicious inputs
deaths will do is arm what can what can
be what can they actually do which
infidel is in this know several
container okay so I read the Amazon
documentation and I thought this
container contains some environment
viable one of them is very interesting
is the path of the lambda called
function called itself so assuming we
know there is a call instruction in the
function and the soon we found after
both Falls the malicious inputs that can
invoke this eval and we try to get this
in football to form the invalid viable
and especially we want to be focused and
get the RAM to test route let's see is
in demo this malicious code on the same
make URL and we can see the result is
virtus it's not surprising it's the
default location of path of the code in
lambda containers so we have our demo
application and we know its own demand
it's create a container that's contained
the functions code and we know where it
stores in this container in the specific
folder and there's an actual outside of
this environment I have my several of my
own using this code attention I want to
check can I copy this code to my
location as Annika or not there will be
I assume there will be some block of
limitation in the network that prevent
me from doing this but I was surprised
and was not here is the malicious code
that road we am using guess the classic
library is available for nodejs I'm
zipping the source code today nobody
stays in the virtus and I'm sending it
to my actual server URL using a non
common pot it's also an Indian ink jet
we'll get back and compared to artists
solution it is my server of the archive
country it's empty
running this malicious code and let's
see what happens to our server right now
we can see a copy of this zipped a
source code and let's see what it's
contains it contains the code itself
including the sensitive data that was
exposed the code and another thing even
if it was the end not in the code and
was in the configuration is beside it we
would could get it is part of the zip
but it would be a bit harder it's
obvious in the code you can see the out
code it will be PI key that this K could
be used by the this cloud DB but you can
be no worries we already replace it
since then so we used within done a
simple code injection but we don't want
to do some more company complex a and
invest actions not just copying the code
what tools to Amazon give us so I was on
Evan SDK that can do some cool stuff
with lambda it could get a list of all
the functions of your account deployed
and invoked it's it's usually useful in
the development environment and when
you're doing it in your development
environment you are authenticated by
your AWS profile and you can do only
what you are permitted to do but what if
we were doing this using the same SDK
that it's already built in in the lambda
function and you'll do is it calling
it's within the lambda function itself
in this case there is no authentication
amazon counts on the setting that was
set in the predefined lambda function
including their description role and
only what the cook is the crucial role
that was pretty fun for the lambda you
can can do the same action will be
permitted by you the
decay so I don't know what permission do
I have so I tried to write this bit more
complex code including and using name
dead at the Bruce decay and using an
update function code object function
code will create a stored injection it
will rewrite a regional function and
will edit some malicious in in malicious
code so if we see the original layer is
a output of the both functions it's
clean as we saw its before visitors and
details and in its original code nothing
with suspicious now I'm running this
malicious code including the AWS SDK
usage in the and including the update
function code in the end of the of this
URL and once it's done we come back to
the application with consented our
result of the output contains some
strange output main act by six what is
written there let's go to the main
function what's happened
chuckle gave us a hint he mocked is the
function is act like a good hacker and
is as to edit this malicious output in
the result of the function and/or just
using the NWS decay of the within the
memory simple so this was a stoic
injection not a regular we use the
permissions that's given to the
execution of the function but again it
was a one-time may damage we can reset
the function and this will go back to
the original code the code diction at
the code attraction path will stay since
we did fix the problem but we can
control on the damage let's see in this
case both functions were infected both
the cars in the main and you can restore
the cast the original code assuming the
DevOps doing that in this case the cars
must clean the main was not cleaned but
there was no impact since the main only
was injected and was not viral it does
not affect another function the solution
of wlw lambda was useful in this case
but what if we want to do some more
damage that is order to fix in this case
and every stored code injection will not
just the ED some may output in the end
of JSON but also in fact all others it
has access to it is case you are going
to get a cost contamination that is in
an endless loop will inject all others
access function is killed a useful and
you get out of control in this our case
we have three functions in the beginning
they are clean when you will inject only
the users we run the cars in the main
and we'll see they're both clean we load
the queues of functions we will see the
contamination in all the older systems
got infected will clean the main in the
users will see they're both clean but
when we load the cars that was forgot to
clean the Earth system will be damaged
again
and the only way to get out of this
situation to be traced all the functions
to the original source but all of them
without forgetting anyone
it was the scenario in the beginning
it's all okay
in this is never consistent much smaller
leg because the function code is being
changed every time and the caching
mechanism arrival of Amazon which needs
to read trigger ready no other that
cannot restore the code from its
previous version and especially all the
infection and nutria cost contamination
it takes some time but as you see as
described in the scenario the cows was
injected it is now contaminating at the
other functions both thousand men
infected but I'm cleaning the main
function
and cleaning the users the DevOps do it
this think is the control of the
situation
everything is there ok but when it will
call back some other user will render a
class function it will infect the count
function and in the second one we can
see that you main end user got infected
as well ok so how can we prevent some
such attacks
there are two main layers of projection
debris lambda to prevent it the first
one is the execution roll the lambda
function can only do what it was the
sets meant to be done by the execution
or permissions and luckily the default
is the basic limited permissions given
as set by Amazon in this case in this
demo I on purpose change the layer role
to a full access control and you could
say it will be mistake we are show in
the next slides was this mistake is
there not so surprising another layer of
protection is the BBC that should
isolates the container that they prevent
out both the connection but unfortunate
the d40 was you know using the PC so we
talked about the execution role and
there is a long complex term creation or
Amazon that's if you read it very well
you will know do it but assuming you are
lazy and you want man let's do some open
source tool that's better life easier
deploy no J's is lift one the lambda
founded Google and very common open
source web walk let's see what it's says
instrumentation oh it's will require AWS
number full access not so good once you
have such a troll in your system you can
get easily confused and use there as
blatant a privilege but you say it's
such just one tool not already using it
but I'm sure that Amazon are responsible
and not have in such cases so again you
can be a good developer and in all the
documentation
oh you're lazy to just Google for ready
code example
and while you're looking for ready code
example but official one of AWS labs not
someone they wrote in the top row bleats
so the official code example of a SS l
WS labs include the following commit to
a sign if n WS time the full axis not
good so this is all about how we can get
confused and get creative function LW
stand the full access permissions to
your execution role and there again
proved that the whip is zoomed out the
rain it's more easy to get confused
because the default is no V PC the first
option so these two layers of protection
that's meant to prevent protect us one
was the easily a cabal with no V PC by
therefore and what was easily to get
confused by using external tools or
using your own
obsoleted so simple but what is the
lesson of all of this research yes there
is no such Fingal cloud or server list
there is always someone else ever yes
you should be worried about and
protected there were these two servers
the servers of the objects containing
temp container and the services
containing the source code in Amazon
it's probably as free and code is code
and if you not write a sensitive latin
your code in the server the same way you
should not write sensitive data in the
in the service code since this could be
a accelerated and attacked by a torrent
to the occur server you should be aware
in case this case of Amazon that the
iaws SDK is built-in and a lambda
container and you should be aware that
the way pcs must be defined otherwise
the default is open there's a good
reason test there is no pcfo is there a
common use cases of getting data from
the internet but sometimes you should
get control of this isolation and beside
the fact of del WS SDK is built-in
should be available about its execution
world effect at not and most in most
cases the basic limited permissions are
good enough if not you should control
and read very well
what about the permission you are going
to do a function since if it's by any
case contain the cont dejection then you
enter you are not monitoring it you can
get reproduced such scenarios of attacks
and as we there is a common st. with
great power comes great responsibility
so you have no power armors to
accounting on Amazon Google Microsoft
the day of the power of silver but still
you have the responsibility you have the
responsibility to keep your code this
were secured and the monitor is deployed
version and how you do it is you like
code this code as I said you should scan
it and use a living any other sqt tools
to make sure there are no variability
delete why way to use the one tool is
the SAS tool
that's as I said you can download the
code automatically with integration from
data from the AWS and scattering scan it
with every SAS tool in this case of
checkmarks and here we say a project it
is was predefined to be integrated with
the lambda project the code it was is
downloaded with the current version you
can trigger events that's only on update
version there will be such scan the scan
was finished and code injection is a
call injections of the same queries and
rules that are valid for regular code
will be valid for this JavaScript code
the only difference this the input is
not a common input another function it's
as an event Regal and even check mocks
the resort you can see how the event
trigger a goal in the data flow till the
code that's been run by an invalid and
if you would scan the code you can see
this vulnerability fixed it and approve
the fixed version to the server and so
the main research was of AWS lambda I
are produced all the following scenarios
under some limitations and the
assumptions there are two others
commercial solution I did some small
research about them as well and the code
injection scenario assuming the code is
as the new valid in North sanitation can
be reproduce in every other solution
after all code is code
the Outland connection and the default
depends between windows in Amazon the
default was no we PC in google GCP there
is a firewall by default but it's walk a
block only uncommon part like this the
50 Potter use it was being blocked by a
qu 2 switches and it was not blocking IP
in a shoe there is some more advanced
settings of the edge resources and I
would indicate with other tools of
Microsoft so again there is some
protection but you should take the
responsibility of setting it the modify
function code was not indeed agree to do
list it in GC Peter since there was no
SDK pre-installed but maybe they will do
it in one stage of another and in a Joe
it was not best to much decay it was
based on some common resources of the
agile that was accessible but again
depends on the settings of continual and
the stole injection modify other
function code was reproduced under the
certain permissions in Amazon but not to
produced not in a jewel and not in
Google again yet the all using still in
beta and alpha version Amazon is the
most common and most stable solution and
the viral injection was reproduced again
under the same assumption in lambda but
it's not worry about comparing AWS
Google issue it's about keeping in mind
it's the fact that is using someone else
solution that will provide you the
server even your Delta probably they
some damage could be done it should be
you should believe it's possible of your
code and that's it
any questions
do any questions does anyone have any
questions they would like to ask and
quick questions you saw that you were
basically evil or some some arbitrary
stuff do you know some other kind of
vulnerability so it could be actually
exploited yes you know you can reproduce
SQL congestion was the most easy to
produce but if the original code was the
containing the SQL injection and there
is a path data flow from the input to
the database call and in this case which
usually will be a several database with
a cloud resources and if it will access
to a malicious import it will be
reproduced as well after all code is
code and the same for the protection of
course the same rules that are valid for
the scanning layer involving judgments
of tools scan tools that scan and find
vulnerabilities in regular code are
still relevant in the several support
more questions okay thank you very much
[Applause]