and rewind the stock is gonna talk to us
those of you who don't know Andrew how
many of you know always top 10 so this
guy was behind over stop 10 this year he
compiled it all and we owe him a lot and
actually I can talk a lot about Andrew
but I'll actually gonna hand over the
honor of introducing Andrew to another
amazing Oh Oscar - Jim Anika Jim Oh hold
your applause for Andrew
I've known Andrew for over a decade and
before he talks I wanna I want you to
understand who Andrew is and what he is
to the ojas foundation so Andrew is a
unique person number one he's been doing
ab SEC for well over a decade one of the
most knowledgeable people by app taste
carry that I know number two he's a very
ethical person he's always trying to do
the right thing for the foundation
that's called our fiduciary duty as a
board member number three
unlike myself and some others he's not a
drama queen
right I'm a drama queen but Andrew is
always about trying to find a peaceful
resolution to these conflicts he's
always looking for the right path where
everybody wins and last he's a very
gentle person but he's also sharp as a
razor don't mess with him he's always a
couple steps behind me and a lot of
other people I know of just an
all-around great person from an ethical
from a how he treats people its
technical competency and his leadership
capacity all of us in this room are
lucky to have Andrews uh volunteerism
here at the yo Haas foundation I present
to you Andrew Vander stock
I'll find out what B really likes later
unfortunately as noted Ross can't be
with us today and it's really terrible I
actually wanted to meet him I missed out
and coming to the cambridge ab ii you
and i wanted to actually meet him at
that point and i was really looking
forward to his keynote today so now I'm
obviously not Ross I'm also not this
person I am a lot smaller than I used to
be I think the other two have motioned
the other parts I'm a senior director
I'm a a director of the OS Foundation
and we've just opened up the nominations
for the Board of Directors this year
please if you want to you've got
something for the community you've got
something for a project you want to get
done do run for the board it's been very
valuable to me it's not easy but it's
really rewarding in terms of experience
I'm also a senior principal consultant
at synopsis I look after the managed
services area which means that we do
lots of pen tests which when you come to
hear the talk it's gonna be fun
obviously done a few things my favorite
right now is the application security
verification standard it's close to my
heart and you'll see why so I think
we've got to define what is winning
because if we don't have a definition of
winning we're not going to win because
it's just you know it's it's the task of
on their end and it probably will never
end so I personally believe based upon
my experience of being doing this since
like 1998 you know I really think we
haven't progressed as much as we could
to my mind the definition that I want
you to think about is building secure
software that uses trust and protects
their lives their privacy and digital
self and I personally believe we have
failed miserably and that is terrible we
could have done something different but
we didn't and so we're going to look
into the reasons why it might have
happened that way but also then let's
look forward to the future so I called
it a future spective in agile we do
retrospectives to see what went well in
the last spring
well I was going to look backwards 20
years we're gonna look forwards 20 years
I want to start thinking about these are
some very very big issues that need to
be dealt with we're not going to do it
tomorrow and some of you haven't even
thought about doing it yet and so I want
you to actually be challenged I want you
to actually think about what it is that
I'm actually asking you to do which is
to stop doing what you're doing okay
so let's go back in the early days of
information security how many people
here have got a CS CI SSP okay I've got
a CSS LP I mistakenly believed I needed
another CSS LP to sign me up and get me
a through I'd never met another one I
mean my bad back in the early days you
probably have heard of Bell in the padua
and all of those information security
you know early giants but we really
haven't had any true Giants we've had
plenty of people who have done
extraordinary things the IDI Felton's
the Ross Anderson's and you know the
folks have been doing a lot of the
on-the-ground industrial information
security don't talk to the academics and
I think that's a fail but there's one
person that I think all of you need to
know and it's dis gentleman he actually
this is the first nist special
publication if you are following the
OWASP top 10 2017 you know that we've
picked up 863 863 is just the
continuation of 30 40 years worth of
special publications this is the first
one literally the first one it was done
in April of 1976 let's have a look at
what they cared about in 1976 I was 6
years old it is the I was top 10
literally it is the OS top 10
we have incomplete parameter validation
heard anywhere
inconsistent parameter validation I
would actually add missing parameter
validation is still a problem implicit
sharing a privileged and confidential
but that is a - that's the I was top ten
2017 a - and act asynchronous validation
and inadequate serialization you know
what that is a eight this is 1976 I just
want to draw your attention to the fact
that they were already thinking about
threat based models they were actually
thinking about floors classes of users
because they were thinking about the
insider threat they're also thinking
about methods and exploitation and if
you look at the way that these guys
thought about it you can see the
beginnings of buffer overflows you can
see the beginnings of business logic
floors and what did what happened does
anyone know what happened straight after
this was published it was classified it
was so top secret they couldn't possibly
share because you'd hacked the United
States so instead of fixing the problem
and sharing this knowledge amongst all
computer science know will classify it
no that's ridiculous okay so it was
classified for a while
and it got unclassified a little while
later but it was already too late
because we'd already started thinking
about security in terms of adversaries
and that is the wrong approach we were
thinking about ourselves as being
different all the way back in 1976 does
anyone know exactly where password
rotation came from I'm going to give you
a hint it's in this table here and yes
the date is correct 1979 if you divide
760 hours by 8:00 anyone want to hazard
guess at how many days that is yep
that's 31 days so originally they had 30
day password changes because if two
graduate students working at night time
on a single user pdp-8 could crack it in
30 days surely you could just then go
ahead and change it if sorry in 31 days
you just changed it every 30 days
problem solved
the other parts of this paper are great
it actually talks about salting it
actually talks about how to make it
slower and actually more difficult to do
it talks about password complexity which
by itself is crap but anyway we cannot
change our passwords fast enough today
to keep up with the scaling that's in
this table so you would have to change
your password at least several thousand
times every second to match the control
that was visible in 1979 on a single
user pdp-8
working only at night times and on the
weekends the attackers have never
thought like that they're going I want a
GPU cluster I will steal someone's
credit card and hire Amazon's you know
GPU clusters and crack away but even now
we don't even need to do that we
actually have people's real passwords we
are missing the academic foundation of
our field it's because we're industry
practices we want to provide feedback
for our clients straight away and we're
trying to provide recommendations that
we believe to be true but a lot of its
built on this you know mountain of lies
we haven't got the academic foundations
to correctly say what is the actual best
answer as I said before I started in
information security in 1998 back then
the entire thing was all about five arul
configurations we were looking at doing
hardening we were doing things like for
example we were doing configuration
reviews of Active Directory to make sure
it was hardened for everyone it was it
wasn't good realistically 1998 in web
app terms whereas do it through a
firewall and make sure you use TLS or
SSL v1 and we're still thinking in those
terms today many of you aren't I'm glad
that's happening but the reality is here
is oh was this is the first recorded
mirror by the wayback machine of the OS
website if you look carefully on the
left hand side at the what became the
developer guide we are still doing that
every single pentose checklist and into
a certain degree in the ASVs
actually is built exactly like that list
which is just like the resource list
from 1976 in fact they actually
mentioned race conditions which is still
another part of our of the OS top 10 or
even or the ISPs we need to fix that
it is an important element I mean the
resource Fox in 1976 we're dealing with
mainframes that did batch literally
batch one thing at a time it was non
interactive they were already thinking
about race conditions at that point they
didn't have multiprocessing they
literally were thinking ahead of their
time we still don't think about that
even though things like nodejs is
implicitly multi-threaded okay so one of
the major frameworks that we deal with
pretends to be single threaded to the
programmer but it's really not in single
threaded at all it's very much
multi-threaded we are being passed by
the reality is if we don't change our
industry will die think about for
example what happened to Yahoo when they
got hacked all those times think about
for example how Alex de Moz went there
and left within a couple of months we
still don't know the exact reasons why
that might have been but I hazard a
guess that he figured out that they were
ignoring the information security team
who by the way we call themselves even
to this day the paranoid so if anyone
from here is from oath I'm gonna throw
you under a bus and I mean it you need
to stop calling yourself the paranoids
you need to actually work with the
developers and I hope this is actually
changing we don't add any value by
sitting to the side one of the things
that I'm actually pointing here is is
that the way that we worked 20 or 30
years ago is very different to the way
we work today
developers are very collaborative if
they work with small teams they talk
together all the time they use pair
programming sometimes they do a lot of
work to make sure their software is
actually good but for some values of
good so we need to start thinking about
how to do that too but we've got a huge
impediment in the
and it's us we are Gordon Ramsay telling
people they are an idiot sandwich our
reports are written in such a way that
it implies you did a bad job your babies
very ugly and by the way you can't code
yourself out of a wet paper bag even if
your lives depended upon it how do you
reckon it makes developers feel when
they if but I should say not when if
they get the report because what the
executive summary says is that your
developers are terrible you should sack
them all you can never ever build a
bridge by reviewing it we need to build
a bridge and that means we need to
actually stop victim blaming victim
blaming means we have to stop victim
blaming developers we must stop blaming
victims we must stop blaming cue Ayers
the business people who take risks it's
their risk to take we need to inform
them of what that risk is but it's
nervous to take we also need to actually
identify why are we blaming users for
password failure we know better we all
know better if we say you know and I see
it on Twitter all the time that's one of
the reasons I don't use Twitter very
much because I'm on drama queens I choke
each other that's the wrong and very
sexist thing drama Lamas drama Lamas are
really annoying and they're killing our
industry if you participate in
[Music]
Australians we swear a lot I'm going to
avoid swearing but you can actually go s
dot posting if you're doing that please
stop it doesn't help anyone we've got to
stop victim blaming if people have had
their credentials stolen it's not
because they chose a bad credential my
credentials had been stolen on many
occasions the fact that they're 25 or 32
or 64 character random passwords doesn't
make it any nicer for me it's not my
fault
I used to factor absolutely everywhere I
have literally hundreds of unique
passwords I do it all right and yet I am
still in have I been pawned around eight
or nine times we don't victim blame if
we're victim blaming we are doing it
wrong okay
humans people is security
it is not tools it is not process it is
you know anything like that we need to
actually understand these are real
people on the other side and they're not
on the other side at all they are us
stop using Fudd immediately if you're
fern markets fear uncertainty and doubt
you are part of the problem and why we
will never solve this you must build
solutions we must build bridges policies
policies have utterly failed us yes it
gives someone I rocked to punish someone
else in the future it's supposed to set
the tone and standard but if you go into
almost any large organization and try to
apply each and every one of the things
that is in a policy I would have to find
out where it is it probably is down in
the basement in a locked cupboard in an
abandoned toilet with a broken light
with a beware of the leopard sign on the
front because no one looks at them not
even the people who wrote them if you
really think about how do we actually
create policies its institutional
mistakes that we want to correct for the
future the reality is policies are
useless what do we need instead is
guidelines that are you know
aspirational statements we should be
secure we our users to trust us from
every single decision it's made in those
like you can't comply with every single
policy I was just outside trying to get
a photo for this particular presentation
and my work laptop was blocking me get
to getting to iCloud I know a number of
other places it won't let me get to but
I can get to other cloud providers if
the idea was to prevent exfiltration
it's not an appropriate control all it
did is slow me down we work around these
things human nature is such that if we
have to do it the hard way we will do it
the easy way if we can and that goes
through it the way we code apps so back
in the 1980s and in the 1990s to a
certain degree it was the Golden Age of
big design up front Waterfall desk
checks these are things that have a part
of the bygone age there are benefits to
that approach however we
do them anymore but our industry is
stuck in that age we are the dinosaur
okay we need to start working on why is
it that we're not being involved in this
diagram there is no security you can
deploy an application and then keep on
working around and around and around
even though waterfall is supposedly
linear and not do security because if no
one knows to put secure requirements and
if no one actually architects it with
secure design and if no one codes that
for example as a user I should only be
able to access my own profile which is a
constraint that's not going to get built
in and if we're the people who say no
they're not going to come ask so
enterprise architecture is a lost art
how many people still have an enterprise
architecture function in there in either
the clients or within themselves yeah it
used to be very close to 100% and the
reason why it was got rid of is it
didn't provide value because they
couldn't demonstrate value they have
immense value being able to say that
this is the enterprise SSO function and
they're validated and improved that and
then made it easy to work with and cheap
if they done that value proposition
enterprise architecture would still be
with us we didn't let the architects of
this world basically thought about
themselves in terms of ivory tower and
they're no longer with us many of us
have been some steamed into other duties
and we don't have the responsibility or
the authority anymore to make the sort
of changes that are necessary so what
happens is we don't have secure
requirements we don't have secure
architecture so we have design flaws and
these are where basically access control
and business loss can occur those two
areas alone represent the vast majority
of the breaches over the last couple of
years when you take out passwords almost
all the decent breaches have been in
those two phases there is no secure
design we often do it at the beginning
of every sprint and unless a security
person is there helping and building
secure software with the team there
won't happen sometimes we do code
reviews sometimes will do configuration
or years
but generally no so developers have just
got down to code deploy code deploy
DevOps
we need to divide process which is agile
development and DevOps which is culture
many of our information security
policies say you should have segregation
of duties you shouldn't be allowed to
publish if you're the developer you
should not be in production if you're a
developer you should not be able to
deploy code that's absolute rubbish
it's absolutely terrible and in fact
DevOps ignores that entire policy so are
we better off with the DevOps approach
well we're no longer at the table we
don't have a voice anymore so if we want
to change the DevOps culture it's a
cultural thing it's a people thing and
we're never going to get it back so we
have to demonstrate value you ain't
gonna need it if you haven't been there
so here we are we're the information
security team we're sitting by ourselves
in a different building or a different
country and we're pen testing away or
laughing to ourselves how bad are our
customers bla bla bla bla bla bla I've
been there it's not good you know we've
got to stop doing this and I mean that
in the nicest possible way
we need to be there with our clients
building the secure software with them
the attack the test patch test patch get
hurt test patch don't fix hamster wheel
of pain has to stop and you would think
after when was the Fred books book come
out the mythical man-month came out at
least 40 years ago and it introduced the
concept of desk checks we do desk checks
okay don't lie to yourselves we are
external auditors we do desk checks the
reality is that that process is utterly
broken
it's Totoro this horrible we've got to
stop doing it that way it does not work
we've had 40 years of failure and it's
time to try something very different
don't be on the hamster wheel of pain
talking about not being auditors we are
not auditors how many people here
actually have an accounting degree in
and have specialized in internal audit
anyone like literally anyone in an
audience of at least 300 not a one of
you we aren't or it is
stop calling ourselves what it is it's
not okay the order process is to
actually ensure that the accountants are
doing the internal controls that they do
every single day they are doing
reconciliation every single day they are
doing month-end every single month
external audit just simply comes through
and says in my professional opinion
these controls are effective or these
are the problems they do it like once
every three years
I can guarantee you some of our clients
some of the people that we worked for
published the internet many times a day
what does it actually mean to do a pen
test when the application changes from
under you before you even finish doing
the initial scan our techniques our
tools our processes are utterly broken
and it starts with we're not part of the
team we're this other thing over there
which were not even then we shouldn't
call ourselves auditors because we are
not auditors and just in the same way
that I can do in a large multinationals
tax return I shouldn't be doing a large
multinationals tax return and they
shouldn't be doing security but
developers on us we should have a
symbiotic relationship we need to help
doing it so the other part of the
problem is everybody thinks that someone
else is responsible for security there
was one particular JavaScript
presentation library that I throw into
the bus almost every single time that I
do it some training that's because they
won't fix Dominic's success in their
product and I can guarantee the reason
why you've never heard of it is it
cannot pass a penetration test because
that team who builds that product
doesn't believe that presentation is
responsible for security they're utterly
wrong anyone who's here is done react a
couple of you react is awesome it only
has one way to shoot yourself in the
foot and it's called dangerously set in
HTML that's the only function unless you
go to JavaScript and hurt yourself that
can cause you problems we have to make
sure everybody
things that security is their problem in
the same way that performance is a
problem for everyone you know we can't
just simply keep on passing the buck but
we can't do that unless we're there I
have been in this industry now for 20
years come November and I have seen all
of the fads and some of them would come
around a couple of times and the current
one of fatalistic you're going to get
hacked we may as well just accept that
well the only thing I know for truth is
that all software has bugs okay all the
software it does have bugs but you're
not going to get hacked I don't think
that's actually true
and it's so fatalistic that people
actually think oh there's no point in
investing anything in other than in like
detection but our software can't help
with detection because there are no body
they're saying the requirement is if
there is a problem like someone is busy
doing something unusual the input
validation or failed logins that we need
to log and escalate well your
application is silent so intrusion
detection is only as good as application
security we need to work on the
left-hand side of the equation I
personally believe there is necessary
balance we need to have all parts of the
application process needs to be defined
there is a place for intrusion detection
there is a place for having incident
management and practicing incident
management there is a place for things
like security groups in cloud providers
there is a place for TLS we need those
things those controls need to be in
place but the fatalistic feds that we've
got you know back in 2000 it was PKI
everything was going to be secure
because we had PKI you know how many
people have actually got a client-side
certificate that's got their own
identity on it today you know it's a
huge thing in 2000 it was unusable the
usability of client-side certificates is
still terrible lastly the thing I'm
going to hassle you about is tools tools
help right we've got the equivalence of
tools baked into some of the standards
like PCI DSS says that a Web Application
Firewall and a source code review are
the same they are not the same they're
two very different things
tools are getting better if I had the
tools that I have today and had them in
2001 I would be considered a wizard you
know but the reality is is that tools
need to help us they're not there as the
sole solution I think Jim mentioned in
his talk that you need at least a couple
of tools I'm not sure the exact phrasing
but essentially we needed multiple tools
to get to a secure solution but what
tools I think we need to understand what
the tools actually provide us not every
tool is useful not every tool is going
to work for us but if we're getting and
detecting things earlier that's great
but if we have a tool that is not like
the other thing we should stop doing it
so we have to stop with the excuses I
dislike intensely anybody who goes the
world is falling the sky is coming down
but has no solution other than by my
product by my service we must be done
with excuses and part of this is
building us up from basic research into
our field all the way through to the way
that we address ourselves and the way
that we work so we need solutions we've
done with excuses no more excuses we
have to dispose off the computer says no
if you're a part of the security team
that says no you're not going in
production they will stop coming to you
to ask whether or not they're going into
production they just will we need to be
thinking about security as a people
problem
how do we come to them and say how can
we securely build this together back in
2005 I was doing internet security
architecture of a corporate internet
banking that platform if you had two
billion dollars in the bank and needed
to do 40,000 transactions to do payroll
we had to work out how do we do 40,000
transactions with a two billion dollar
bank balance safely on the Internet
previously clients gave us nine track
tapes which then we loaded on our
mainframe and did a batch that got
transferred into secure FTP the security
was that it was on a leased line it
wasn't because it was SFTP it was
because you couldn't get to it unless
you're another bank
but yeah if you dump this transaction
and process it we need to work with them
to actually how do we securely build
this together that is a different
mindset than what we have today it's got
to just work a wrassle this on Twitter
the last night when I was asking for
more memes I just had to put it in this
day
I love memes I've been using memes for
about since 2007 Mike my iPhotos is
literally chock-a-block with cat memes I
make no apologies security has to be
transparent we must make it the easiest
possible route if we are helping
frameworks to build secure solutions for
example react does not have cross-site
scripting you know unless you choose to
use a very dangerous function or go to
JavaScript directly then anybody who
uses react does not have Pro site
scripting that's an incredibly powerful
message if you actually say if you're
using entity framework and you're paying
attention to the way that you search for
records you just don't have super
injection that's a very powerful message
and it saves time it means we don't have
to test for those things anymore we can
actually move on and actually test for
the more valuable things
let's build secure software and that I
think means for I was is we need to work
with frameworks we need to help to the
spring MVC s we need to help the
Microsoft's and others of this world
need the Apache Cordova's we must help
frameworks that other developers build
upon to be secure by default and not
repeat the mistakes of isapi I if you
don't know worked on a snappy for PHP
until I realized that PHP is never
getting Unicode and it cannot pass
Unicode unit tests and therefore it's
useless as an input validation mechanism
why were we working on ourselves we
needed to work with PHP the first stage
would be for PHP to get unicode but then
we would work with them to actually help
their terrible security story which is
that they don't have a security story
now I'm not throwing them under the bus
for any particular reason there because
some of the PHP frameworks actually have
decent security but it's in spite of not
because of PHP
we've gotta work with frameworks we are
not special in any way we have only the
same voice as anyone else who's assigned
the exact same employment contract as
anyone else the fact that we think that
we have more of a say than other people
is wrong we should be basically saying
I'm going to spend my story points on
this and if you move into other people
to come along for the ride you will get
secure software but if you're just
saying I'm not gonna let you go into
production until you do it I'm gonna
hold your program hostage until you do
exactly what I say that's not okay
that's not for you to decide okay the
risk is for the business to accept and
at the end of the day they can't
outsource that risk to you we need to
make sure that when we're making
decisions for a piece of software it's
because it's early enough in the process
it can be just fixed then and there this
picture by the way is one of the very
few pictures in here that's not common
like freely licensed it actually comes
from code like a girl which is one of
the charities that I would hardly an
employer to follow on Twitter it's one
of the things that's close to my heart
PDF reports we have to do a dumpster
fire we have to provide sufficient
detail in there for developers to fix it
the audience is senior executives it's
just a dumpster fire if you'd make it
readable by a senior executive or the
developers are going I don't even know
what language you're writing in here but
I can't figure it out what are you
saying now we have to work with the
developers tools we have to use what
they use we have to deliver them into
vulnerability management platforms for
those of you who do look at Twitter I
said this is going to give you the feels
because you're going I agree with all of
you said but you haven't given many
solutions defect dojo is one of the most
important projects we have here at OU us
today I would encourage each and every
one of you to help it get into if it's
not already flagship then to get into
flagship status I hope it is a flagship
project I must admit I should have
looked at that before defect dojo is a
vulnerability management platform there
are others there's Brinker there's
thread fix and there is an open-source
version of thread fix we need to build
our solutions our reporting into those
platforms but even better is if we could
actually deliver them directly into the
issue registers into like for example
JIRA or github or whatever they're using
bugzilla we need to make sure that the
developers can see what we think is a
problem as early as possible I know from
personal experience people are loath to
give up their report until it's perfect
its polished but in the meantime you've
got this critical sequel injection which
is not being fixed for days if not weeks
because you know about it but the
developers do not there is no harm in
fixing that straight up we should be
basically saying to people hey you've
got a sequel injection how about fixing
it I'll give you a hand okay what we do
need though to replace PDF reports is an
executive friendly reporting mechanism
and I don't believe that to be PDF I
don't believe it to be paper I believe
it to be dashboards allows people to see
vulnerability trends over time the
reason for that is is that essentially
if there's a development team that has
actually got a much worse posture than
someone else they need help if you get
an isolated PDF report you're not going
to know that they need help unless of
course in the executive summary you've
managed to somehow slam it into the
first few paragraphs this development
team needs help but if they had a
vulnerability trend over time they will
be in a much better shape so we need to
provide the value the context and the
value of the executive audience and it
is not PDF reports there are dumpster
fire we should stop doing it this is the
future of pen testing this is do shops
automatic integration suite that tests
every single one of the vulnerabilities
and juice shop if you have the spoiler
alert you're about to see some of the
solutions for G Shops things so if
you're working through G shop and I
heartily really recommend you do this is
about to do more penetration test in
around 30 seconds than most pen testers
can do in
a day and it does it every single build
this is the future of penetration
testing we should be basically producing
test cases that our developers can build
into a CI CD job if you don't believe me
then you are going to get replaced by a
small shell script with another pen
tester who can write unit an integration
tests because this can run hundreds of
times a day at a speed you just cannot
work out and it gives immediate feedback
to the developers whether or not they
have resolved a problem this is the
future and if you haven't quite got it
yet please come back watch the YouTube
video in a few months time and
understand where I'm coming from if we
don't start thinking about helping
developers build secure software within
five years our clients can get the sort
of tools that can do the sort of job
you're doing today okay at that point
your job is replaceable by a tool and if
Garris or anyone from ports figure is in
town good work at a certain point in the
same way that we don't do a lot of
network pentose now because our clients
can actually do network penetration
tests to the level that they are
satisfied with using any number of
commercial tools and some open source
ones where that tools will get there -
this does access control floors this
does designed floors this does business
logic floors tools will never do that we
still need to use our brains you've got
a code it we are not auditors we are
helping build secure stuff if you don't
know how to code how many people here
actually code that's also oh thank you
well that wasn't expecting that hi you
guys are well placed because you can
actually code the thing that you just
saw end of story
but if you don't know how to code you
need to learn how to code now even
though it might feel basic to you right
now go to code.org go to all of the
other resources sign up for udemy sign
up for thorough site sign up for
whatever
years attend these conferences take our
training classes and learn how to code
pick a language learn any language once
you've learnt one there are usually
fairly similar if you had to pick one
today I would either choose Python or
JavaScript mainly because most pen
testing tools are written in Python and
most of our customers and clients use
javascript you can still learn Java
there's good reasons to do that but if
you can code unit tests you're going to
find bugs early in the development cycle
if you can code integration tests and
automate them you've got a job for life
it is really that simple
we need for you to upskill we need to
change our industry completely from
being this external auditor dealing
lightning from the mountaintop to
actually applying our skills to building
secure software we have to work with
developers we have to learn from the
business we must work with the business
but most of all my advice to you is
learn from your developers I love going
in dealing with my clients and sitting
with the development teams because I
love learning I've been doing this for
20 years I still get surprised by the
things I don't know any day that I don't
learn something is a sad day looking
forward to the next 20 years he who
thinks cross-site scripting will be
solved by 2038
there are some people there's a couple
of people who think that maybe CSP is
the answer but realistically unless
everyone adopts frameworks that have no
cross-site scripting we are never
getting ahead to me that's sad buffer
overflows have been going down there
have been working like people have
actually thought about the bug class and
done decent work at an academic level to
address the bug class the marios and the
goth phase of this world we need more of
them to actually understand how did that
happen and what do we need to do to make
sure that it doesn't happen for
everybody just because we need to change
it so that we have basic academic
research into what constitutes a good
authentication platform NIST have done
that if you haven't yet adopted NIST 863
please go ahead and do it it really does
address all of the problems that exist
with passwords we must build a secure
future together I am absolutely certain
we can but we have to do it with our
developer friends and they are friends
they are not our enemies if you sit in a
different place in a different building
or even a different country than your
developers you are doing your job wrong
they aren't doing their job wrong you
are doing your job wrong it may not be
possible for you to sit together but you
can do it virtually and remotely the
future is remote work the reality is is
that if you can be replaced by a remote
worker you can be really replaced by
automation and at that point you don't
have a job you need to evolve everyone
needs to evolve please let's stop doing
the things that we're doing 2001 it
wasn't great then and the evidence shows
that it has not worked and continues not
to work let's stop doing the things that
don't work and start doing the things in
a fast fair way maybe unit testing with
security test doesn't work I don't know
but let's try it out it's got to be
better than pen testing anyway with that
thank you go change the world
and for a presentation that had zero
attempts to actually do it before I did
it we have time for one or two questions
everyone if you have a question please
raise your hand before we start with
questions can I just say that to
security researchers that andreas
mentioned is in stock you stockyard
Hayes and Mario Heydrich are here and
they will be presenting tomorrow mario
has opening keynote so please be here
before 9 o'clock because Mario is
opening tomorrow and Gareth Hayes is
speaking I think at 1 o'clock tomorrow
so they both here any questions for
Andrew but where we going we're going to
be replaced by robots soon yeah thank
you very much for this talk and you
touch I mean very important thing about
changing the mentality of abject people
instead of just blaming the developers
and that's that's very important but
also the other thing you mentioned
regarding I mean working on securing the
frameworks themselves and building more
secure for more how do you think how can
we I mean move ahead of that so with
that approach how can we work with with
I don't know companies or software
companies for building new frameworks to
to make sure that they are building this
framework securely that is actually a
really difficult question I don't know
we've solved it yet but I think we need
to reach out to the really large
frameworks which are struggling and if
we can work as a board member with my
board member hat on for a tech if we can
help you or anyone who wants to help a
framework get better at security if we
can lend our priority or at least
introduce you to other people that we
might know I'd love to be able to help
it's not going to work in every
situation some folks just don't want
help
but if you look at Drupal for example
they didn't have a security team before
version 6 and now they have one and
they're doing a great job so it's
entirely possible to help projects with
security but yes
any more questions
yep there's one here hey I had one so
you talked about having a positive
relationship with developers and
non-security folk how would you deal
with those who are always resistant you
give them the information you give them
the advice and then they still try argue
against those points a pull request
really works wonders at the end of the
day if they can see that you've actually
got some solutions that you want to try
out I've never met a developer who
hasn't wanted to at least have a
solution being worked on I worked on a
really gnarly CSP problem with a client
a few years ago and we just sat down
together for a day and bashed it out and
yes we spent an entire day working on a
CSP bug but once we actually worked out
what was the issue we understood the
issue and then we were able to apply it
to some other apps that they had issues
with it's actually is showing them that
you're dedicated to not just telling
them what to do but actually finding a
solution I think that's where it comes
in - because before they've always had
an adversarial approach with security
folks and often some clients that I've
worked with have actually got KPIs on
project managers and application owners
that if you have a severe security bug
that's a that's a bad thing for your
Christmas bonus and that's a negative
KPI because it means they're going to
argue with you until the cows come home
is this actually a security problem yeah
so it's on us to actually help our
clients understand and you know our
partners to understand whether or not
these KPIs are appropriate because if
they're arguing against our advice and
we can't provide them a solution because
they won't listen yeah it's a real big
problem but I think sitting down with
them and helping them come up with a
solution is really good
I am going to the dinner tonight so feel
free to hassle me about board and this
dinner ok sometimes well you have
developers that want to do the right
thing they want to write the best
applications you have DevOps that want
to do the right thing they want to
deploy the most secure applications you
have security consultants and
specialists that want to do the right
thing but then you have management which
wants to get the product out as soon as
fast and spending the less amount of
money possible so my question to you is
do you have any hints dealing with
management with that resists spending
more time or more money in a project
because it needs to go now and oh it's
just a security bug it's not gonna stop
our deployed so we're in a transition
period and it will be a transition
period where we go from the external
view but we're brought in right at the
end to actually working throughout to my
mind it's about budgeting if we're
actually there from the very beginning
and helping them build secure software
we won't have that conversation because
it went and be necessary however right
now we are brought in right at the end
and that's a very negative experience
for management in 2004 I was involved in
a project where marketing basically spun
up an external team they literally built
an online application for credit card
but when we demonstrated that we
couldn't secure it because well and by
the way we found out the day before TV
commercials our doodles go live that we
could actually see everyone's details we
could see and improve the credit card
process so we could actually apply as
you know Ronald McDonald or Hamburglar
and get a $10,000 credit card we could
approve that too they hadn't thought
about access control they haven't
thought about actually data privacy or
any of those things that project got
cancelled you know there is a penalty
for doing it so late by introducing it
earlier we shouldn't have so many of
those conversations I'll be ever going
to get away from them all the time no
we're going to have them from time to
time but if we're part of the project
budget and we're there from the
beginning yeah
a minute okay Andrew so one of the talks
today was Charles MIT from mitre and one
of the things that he talked about was
sort of NIST and they're using ASCAP for
configuration monitor management as you
know in the OS 10 there's a lot of
issues with misconfigured systems so one
of the things is you would like
community feedback but also if we can
take some of the specifications and also
build projects that make it easier for
people to adopt them even build them
into the middleware systems as well
should we reach out to them and have a
conversation see how he as a board and
also as a community could help
absolutely and in fact if there's anyone
a very important thing they're needed in
my heart it's projects os is about
projects if you search I was the front
pages full of projects so if you are
interested in helping out with these
things and I think in Australia we would
call that a Dorothea Dix er which is a
very friendly question that doesn't
challenge me yeah we need to work with
these standards bodies such as NIST in
fact cwe if anyone feels like they need
to do some editing that's an area that
cwe needs a lot of help there's lots of
things that are missing I'm not even
terribly sure they have da mixes s yet
and so we need to understand what
additional things we could help external
bodies such as PCI such as the NIST and
others so if you are interested in that
maybe just what do you reckon connect up
do it in yours connector
maybe we'll have a chat with NIST and
see what we can do and put it into the
connector ok thank you and that was
pretty much my time thank you
[Applause]