we are very privileged to have Peter
Goodman from New Zealand here today for
our technical keynote he is a researcher
in the department of computer science at
the University of Auckland working on
crypto he helped write the popular PGP
encryption package as well and here he's
going to talk today about bomb fuses and
bomb disposal so let's welcome Peter
Goodman to the stage thanks
ok so the thinking process behind
bombing is you want to cause disruption
and bombing basically causes disruption
also blowing stuff up is fun the general
process behind it is you load the bombs
and the source if rated over to
destination you drop it on your
destination in profit so that's the
general theory however you can revise
that because you really want to cause
disruption in blowing stuff up ok that's
one way of causing disruption but
unexploded bombs - were you expedient
also cause disruption because if you've
got a thousand-pound unexploded bomb
under some critical installation no one
can go near that and all the things been
defused
one example was an unexploded bomb that
went under the NPL national physics lab
and headington which in the UK was a
critical war research establishment took
9800 man-hours to defuse this was
Imperial measurements so he had yards
and pounds and feet and man-hours so the
fact that this thing didn't explode was
at least as disruptive as if it had
exploded and during World War two and
also during the Vietnam War both the
Germans in the Vietnamese became very
very good at repairing bomb damage very
quickly so you'd bomb someplace like a
runway and within 24 hours that have it
patched up they paint fake bomb craters
over the patches so it looked like it
was still destroyed and they'd have
planes taking off over the same runway
so simply having bombs that detonator
immediately isn't necessarily as
disruptive as having bombs that sit
there and don't detonate so you've got
additional considerations with
unexploded bombs the defenders can take
as long as they want to disarm the thing
so they can sit there and take whatever
time they want use whatever machinery
they want to try and disarm this thing
say take two approaches to combat this
the first one is you make the bomb very
hard to disarm and the second one is you
rigged the things so it kills the people
trying to disarm it
traditional bomb fuses were came in all
mechanical and these things go back to
at least the 1890s you had these
incredibly complicated mechanical
contraptions and then if you look at the
function of a fuse there's basically two
functions the secondary purpose is you
want to make the thing detonate when
it's supposed to that's the secondary
purpose the primary purpose is you want
to make sure it doesn't feel innate when
it's not supposed to you don't want the
thing detonating when you're handling it
when you're loading up when it's fired
or whatever you only want it to detonate
once it reaches its target so during
World War 2 the Japanese actually had
the lowest percentage of duds because
they didn't bother with safety
mechanisms if you've got something that
just blows up in your face then
yeah it's relatively reliable and
blowing up in your face whether you'd
rather HIPPA blow up in someone else's
face and this is great quotes if you
read sort of military history books and
things like that this one that's up on
the screen at the moment it's not a holy
sound mechanisms in some instances it
was quite dangerous for the operator
this is US Army Field Manual on Japanese
military equipment and so they're two
main models of hand grenades the model
91 in the model 97 and in both cases
have seen the italics are in the
original throw immediately since action
of fuses sometimes erratic so the way
the Japanese fuses work if you're
familiar with these basically two
general types of grenades are people
familiar with from films these the
standard style you pull the pin out you
release the spring-loaded catch you
throw it and then you've got the German
stick grenade you unscrew the camp and
you pull this lanyard and then you
throught the Japanese ones you pulled
out some sort of safety pin you didn't
smash the fuse down on a rock and you
throw it so one or two at one of three
things would happen with these because
they had really unreliable fuses you
smash it down on a rock and it blows up
before you can throw it killing you and
if you run around you or you smash it
down on a rock and you throw it and it
blows up once it reaches the enemy and
the third option is yeah you throw it
and it doesn't blow up and the other
side picks it up and throws it back at
you and then it blows up killing you so
one out of three isn't that bad for a
for you know for a weapon like that
and then they had this guy Kaduna number
who's he's been called the Japanese John
Browning although I think that's a
completely wrong designation because
john browning designed his stuff about a
hundred years ago and a lot of it's
still in use today
whereas nothing the sky designed was
used after about august 1945 when one
military historian said the sky design
comically bad weapons so one of his
first designs was an Ambu type 14 pistol
this thing has no safety cache so what
actually happened was in the late 19th
century he went on a tour of Europe and
looked at some of the weapons they were
doing there and backed me in the state
of the art was the mauser c96 pistol
also known as the broom-handle Mauser so
they this was pretty much the state of
the art for that time they were a bunch
of experimental pistols or two-team the
automatic pistols done about that time
but the Mauser was the first sort of
mainstream production model that was
really for general use and the Chinese
just built about a bazillion unlicensed
copy to this thing and then probably saw
the manali Express has guaranteed 100%
original pistols whereas the Japanese
got the sky to design his own version of
it as far as I know this is the only
production semi-automatic pistol ever
that's been produced without a safety
catch he decided he just wasn't any use
for one so you could actually fire this
thing without pulling the trigger for
example while carrying one of the
frequent James it was also a horribly
unreliable pistol so in response to this
thing the principal complaint with the
IJA the Imperial Japanese army was that
there's no safety catch and our guys are
shooting themselves trying to clear the
jams and this thing you'd think that
would also be a problem but apparently
the main thing was a safety catch so
instead of you know giving this guy a
short sword and telling him to nip
around the back and you know what to do
with us they see designed more weapons
for us based on this amazing pistol so
designed us for type 94 Nambu pistol us
was the main Japanese officers pistol
during World War two
it is generally acknowledged as the
worst production handgun ever produced
that was the main Japanese side and
during World War two
so you know that's it's kind of an
impressive feat because no two people
can agree on what the beast Hank and
there's no one person can agree on what
the beast Hank I knows but the consensus
is this is the worst handgun ever
produced so the the feature that gives
it that prize is its look at some of the
other stuff first of all it is horribly
ugly it looks like it was made by some
guy with a grinder and a file and this
was a you know a newly
model which was a mess production when
towards the end of the war they probably
were made with a grinder and a file
it's chambered for this underpowered 8
millimeter de round also designed by
Nambu so he was an incompetent weapons
designer and an incompetent ammunition
designer I had a six round clip so it
was the same as a revolver
it was mechanically clunky it was
unreliable it was badly engineered it
was just an awful weapon but the thing
that the gives it the prize of the worst
handgun ever designed is actually I go
back a bit if you look above the monitor
obvious it is above the pistol is that
body which isn't exposed see a bar so if
you press down on that the pistol fires
without pulling the trigger there's lots
of demos of this people love to
demonstrate this because it you know you
should have make fun of this thing so
that's someone firing the pistol will
this finger no be near the trigger
so if you've got this thing and it's
loaded and you holster it or will you
put it down on your table on the table
or you're cleaning it already about you
can fire it this is a persistent but as
far as going to a completely unfounded
rumor that calls it a suicide pistol
because Japanese officers when they were
surrendering they would hand it over to
Americans like vests and the American
would then pick it up and press down on
the sear and shoot someone similar
examples of stuff this Takai design i'll
get back when to bomb fuses in a minute
but just this is this is something else
he designed it's a type of leave in
machine gun it looks like a cross
between like a combine have a stone a
sewing machine it's just it's an
unbelievable weapon if you interested in
this either talk to me afterwards we'll
go and look at it on youtube it's it's
no one's ever designed anything like
this before since but the main point is
you really do want safety features on
your weapon do you do not want you know
someone we can shoot yourself in the
foot some people put by putting it down
on the table or holstering a pistol some
mechanical fuse designs are really
really difficult to make both reliable
and safe you want something that
detonates once it reaches its target but
not when it's being fired or when it's
being handled and in the case of this
for example this is a gym and when I can
infuse a 30 millimeter fuse so this is
going to be used in air to air combat
typically over Germany so you want
something that doesn't detonate when
it's fired it detonates if it hits its
target but if the thing then falls onto
the ground over one your cities you
don't want all these 30 millimeter
shells detonating all over your city and
so what this one does it's got this
incredible series of mechanical safety
features I'm not sure how obvious it is
from their diagram how have
as on that but the two things are right
at the top is the ring of six ball
bearings so as the shell is fired it
starts spinning and the force that
they're spinning then forces these six
ball bearings outwards and so they've
free the path for the firing pin and
down below there that sort of dark those
two dark bands that's a collar that's
also forced open by the force of the
spinning
so once the things in flight at spinning
at high speed these two sets of
mechanical interlocks are moved out of
the way the firing pin can then be
pushed down when it hits the target if
it misses the target the force back down
to earth that stops spinning there's
mechanical interlocks locked back into
place and once it hits the ground it
can't detonate anymore it's a pretty
ingenious design you know it's a purely
mechanical fuse which makes sure that
that will the thing will detonate on
impact with a target by point D tonight
when it hits the ground
however this thing is being fired out of
a cannon and it's been accelerated at
hundreds of G's so you've got all these
very fine mechanical devices which may
or may not function reliably with that
kind of shot that's a larger more modern
for use used in an artillery shell again
entirely mechanical that's got a bunch
of safety features so first of all it's
got a cap over the top so before you
actually fire the thing you remove the
cap so if you accidentally hit the fuse
if a firing pin or anything like that
there's no problem
and this is because it's largely you've
got more safety features in it so in
again I don't sure how obvious it is on
the diagram but let's fire this is
frangible link in the top that share
that breaks away from the firing shock
such chatters and that frees the firing
pin so I can travel down and it's got a
second to meet you down at the base
these two cams also activated by the
shell spinning and the cannon rotates
the primer into place beneath the firing
pin so if it's not fired if you simply
drop it the primer is no way near the
firing pin even if the firing pin
somehow gets to push down it's not gonna
hit the primer once that's spinning
becames rotating to place in the primers
then underneath the firing pin when it
impacts on the target at D tomates but
again you've got all these very fine
mechanical components that have to deal
with a massive amount of shock when they
fired and also being spun at an insanely
high speed and not fall apart or shatter
or break so it is very very difficult to
rely but to build both reliable shells
and ones that are safe in World War one
America Sheltie american-supplied under
lend-lease about one third of all
and she'll supply to the British were
duds because they couldn't actually just
build them safely
so generally carried an extensive
electronic our trials on fuses in 1931
and 32 by the Treaty of Versailles
though forbidden from developing a whole
bunch of different weapons including
this kind of stuff so starters on secret
in 1926 and they did the testing in
secret in Russia so Russia was at that
time was Bolshevik Russia and they had
no friends anywhere because they were
Bolsheviks and they wouldn't like them
and so it the Treaty of Rapallo with
Russia and because Germany was basically
a pariah and Russia was a pariah they
collaborated in doing this weapons
testing so the one place where Germany
could safely keep weapons was in Soviet
Russia and that he stood 250 mechanical
fuses and 250 electronic fuses and they
found the electronic fuses were vastly
superior and they also had the advantage
that they had their Spanish Civil War
where they assisted assisted Franco and
they're basically stages of testing
ground for diffusers so they had a few
school the type 15 fuse which was the
precursor to the one they used during
World War two
and got to test it extensively and it
was a relatively benign war because they
weren't fighting anyone with significant
military capabilities and they'd say EF
yields and I could go in and retrieve
diffusers and see what happened so
basically the life testing if he fuses
during the Spanish Civil War so
traditional bomb fuse is in the nose of
the bomb with an electric fuse you don't
need to do that anymore there's no
mechanical connection even you don't
rely on the fuse actually impacting the
ground you can have at the side of the
bomb and so what they did there is they
have huge fuse pockets in the side of
the bomb the fuses went into that the
other thing is because it's now now
electronic fuse you haven't got the
single point of contact with the bomb
hits the ground so you can put in
multiple fuses so a lot of the bombs had
to fuse pockets for two different types
of users and you can mix and match
different fuses so the general form of a
bomb fuse it's about the size of a fuse
to give you a scale for that sort of
thing so when the witness was inserted
in the fuse pocket so you hit a pocket
on the side of the bomb was about that
thickness so the armorer would take the
fuse this is a effectively turn in a
fuse this is purely the electronic side
of things so the way the detonation
chain worked the bomb itself would swell
with amytal which is the standard
military explosive it's a mixture of
ammonium nitrate and TNT and it's a
perfect military explosive it's in sense
that if it doesn't degrade it doesn't
absorb moisture
it's very shock immune so you can for
example fire a bullet into it and it
shouldn't be donated you can see it fire
to it you can do all sorts of stuff and
it's very very safe to handle but
because it was so hard to detonate you
need a very strong explosive pledge to
actually detonate the thing so the way
the fuse works you've got the basic fuse
that's the electronic component
you've even got something called a
primary explosive which is a very
sensitive explosive which is why you
don't generally use this in your main
bombs and that screws into the base of
the standard fuse so that's detonated by
the fuse that's about the same explosive
charges a hand grenade so the fuse fires
the primary explosive the primary
explosive is easy to see it off but
relatively weak so around there you've
got a second or booster explosive which
amplifies the shock of the primary
enough to actually detonate the TNT
which is relatively immune to shock so
you've got these three stages of the
explosive train so what the armorer
would do is they would this is called
the gain so that would it which
amplifies the explosive charge so they
would take this drop in the attract acid
which is the booster explosive drop this
into the fuse pocket and screw down a
locking ring and at that point the bomb
is armed so we've got two parts of the
arming mechanism the top part is the
bomb wreck in the aircraft and the lower
part is the actual fuse which goes into
the bomb and the it's electrically armed
so the you've got on it you've got two
selector switch in the cockpit where
they can select the fuse delay and a
bunch of other things so the thing but
this is the army context are only
engaged once the Bombers leave the bomb
wreck what that diagram shows it zigzag
thing at the top is these arming
contacts which are held in place like
this and once the bomb drops down out of
a few Zurich and it's lift that so it
once has dropped the bomb rack it makes
momentary contact and puts a pulse of
electrical energy into the bomb so the
feature with this is with a standard
bomb you can get an armed bomb sitting
in your feet and your bomb rack and it's
stuck one of the lugs hasn't attached
and saving his plane your aircraft with
an armed bomb in the aircraft and that
has happened and aircraft have been
destroyed by particularly Japanese
aircraft were notorious for this again
because they had no safety mechanisms
you basically ended up with a kamikaze
aircraft because you couldn't safely
land this thing so
you've pretty much had to crash it into
something in order to D to get rid of
the bomb so again that was an impressive
safety feature if you compete us with
mechanical fuses you were guaranteed
that this thing was only armed once it
had already dropped out of the bomb
racks so you we were pretty much we're
not going to hear the case we've got an
armed bomb sitting in a bomb wreck and
the last section of the mechanism is
diffusing the bomb so this is a
two-stage thing initially when you get
this passive current before going into
the spawn it goes into storage
capacitors so they absorb the initial
current post you've then got resistors
that it leaks through into arming
capacitors and there's a certain delay
while it leaks through those resistors
which is the arming time of the bomb
again you don't want this bomb to be
live the manner that leaves the bomb
wreck you want to have a couple of stick
in to delay slightly it's well clear of
the plane before it goes live they
didn't go into the firing capacitors in
the firing capacitors these trembler
switches in there so when it hits the
ground the chamber switches courses are
short and then it fires the actual fuse
yes so the time for the charge to leak
from the initial storage capacitors into
the army capacitors is the arming time
and the igniters themselves is three
different igniter switch can speak by
the armored us so there's is a screw in
here where when the Bombers actually
initially said you can set the screw to
allow it to detonate immediately or have
a delayed detonation because you don't
necessarily want to do tonight
immediately on this if it deviates as
soon as it hits the surface here's a
huge amount of blast but not much damage
he wanted to do tonight once it's
penetrated under the ground
and destroy the structure that it says
so most of the circuitry in this thing
is actually to prevent accidental
detonation not to ensure detonation
these fuses are incredibly safe the
bombs could actually be transported in
the armed state that's a nice T 250
which is a 250 kilogram bomb and the
theatric on the side means it's armed so
that's a fully armed bomb being tripped
in its case because the fuse is safe
enough you can a transported in that
state but the mechanical fuse there's no
way you could ever do then this is the
standard fuse used throughout the war
it's about 225 B so that's that's the
mainstream fuse used everywhere
this is a development of the type 15
fuse so the 15 was the one that they
Morley's tested during the Spanish Civil
War on the twenty five PT was his
standard fuse
so the selector fuse and the switch
which was set by the armory enables or
delays a short delay circuits so you've
got these detonation delay options
there's an instantaneous which typically
isn't used this short one second so
basically penetrates some distance into
the structure and then is a relatively
long when seventeen seconds so it's it's
the unit comes to rest and then a
theater nights and some of these things
you can also do things for example if
you're doing low-level bombing you don't
want instantaneous detonation because
you're going to knock out the aircraft
so in that case you'll see at the 17
second delay so the aircraft has got
time to get clear before the bomb
detonates and again this is the the
flexibility of these electronic fuses
and you could set them to do all sorts
of interesting things but what wasn't so
easy with mechanical fuses the physical
layout was you've got trembler switches
which actually activate the thing and
I've already mentioned things like this
so that's the gain which contains a
nitro Penta it's still used today in
primacord ellic which is a fuse cord and
I mentioned the explosive treinta
triggers the purgation HED generates of
tnt and the electronics are pitted and
Benjamin so in a tall pace of components
so there's no transistors there's no
valves there's nothing like that in the
purely passive components and the
extremely shocked and sensitive because
the whole thing's potted and bitumen
there were half a century later that was
kind of a state-of-the-art infusers the
mark 376th electronic fuse the thing
about this is this is basically a Markku
the first one developed was the type 15
they hit a few teething problems they
developed the type 25 B and that was you
know the second development of the fuse
this one the Mac
370 sixties 376 revisions that they went
through of this fuse to get into that
state the problem with that it basically
does exactly the same thing as a 25 B
but they use transistors and all sorts
of other fancy components and the
problem is you've now got these you know
sensitive components and you've had
safety circuitry to deal with the fact
that these transistors can't deal with
over-voltage and under-voltage
and you know electrical shorts and other
things then you have to add even more
circuitry to add redundancy in case one
of the transistors fails and so on so
you've got this huge amount of
complexity that exists solely because
you've added more complexity and it just
breeds even more complex
so I can't really see anything in there
that isn't already in the 25 B which has
purely passive components and was 50
years but before then as an aside how do
you mail a bond fuse so this came to me
as I was an intellectual component well
the thing is you know you don't really
want to label seeing something and label
a bomb fuse because if everyone knows
that a bomb fuses like some sticks of
TNT with wires and the clock attached to
it and this isn't that so you just label
is in the literal mind and it is
completely inert in passive it's not
like I'm seeing something dangerous you
know you could shut these things fully
armed because there was nothing in the
air that well it's just a bunch of
capacitors and resistors alternatively
you can get it seen from someone like
the Ukraine where you can just post
anything and they don't really care what
you post him anyway how did he fuse
these things so I've mentioned that
these things were charged electrically
and they then go into the Army
capacitors so in the same way that you
can charge them and equally ignore so he
doesn't charge them so there's something
called a Crabtree discharger it just
goes into these two brass contacts
pushes down on them completes the
circuit the charge leaks back out of the
arming capacitors and at that point the
thing is completely safe and completely
inert so this isn't this is in the cases
of bombs that don't detonate so some of
these things didn't detonate because
again it's affecting the ground there's
this enormous mechanical shock and so in
some cases they you know they didn't do
tonight and again this isn't necessarily
a bad thing because an unexploded bomb
was at least as bad as one that exploded
so basically wait for the charge to leak
back out of the arming context and been
the thing is safe at that point the
theory is if you read the manuals it
sees your toy landed around the fuse and
you stand well back can you pull the
fuse out the problem is the bomb has
impacted the ground with a massive
amount of force in typically the fuse
pocket is deformed the fuse is now stuck
in the fuse pocket inside you basically
attack it with the chisel and a hammer a
device that here's trembler context on
it that detonated teeny shock and this
only worked on the type 15 fuses so they
had a whole bunch of type 15s leftover
from the Spanish Civil War and they used
those initially
and then what they did is because the
civilians were worried about these bombs
being dropped on when they published all
these feel-good stories and newspapers
saying you know so the problems we can
defuse these things if you've got a bomb
in your bed yeah don't worry about it
we'll come in and we'll defuse it for
you and the idea was to raise morale the
problem is the Germans are also reading
these papers and they said okay you know
they know how to defuse these things
well we designed the fuses so they can't
do this anymore the extreme example of a
supposed type 50 fuse which I'll get
onto a bit later so once they had the
type 25 which you couldn't use the
Crabtree on anymore they had the brass
liquid discharge so what you do in that
case is you put the screw this brass
container over the top of this this has
got all these amazing screw lugs on it
so you can just screw on this discharger
it's filled with meats with salt in it
so it's a conductive liquid the in force
event force it into the fuse under
pressure so you've got a bicycle pump
and you pump this thing up it forces
this liquid in there because it's
conductive it shorts out the capacitors
the thing discharges and then you're
fine again and it required about a
thirty minute wait so you're sitting the
on top he's sitting it with a spawn you
pump you look put into it you retire to
a safe distance after thirty minutes you
come back and you take it with a cold
chisel and a hammer and hope that it's
not gonna see it up we see it off
there's another fuse called the type 17
clockwork fuse so this is the sort of
the detonate on impact or don't detonate
and kill the diffusor fuse in
combination with that there's a type 17
clock worth of use so this is a standard
electronic impact fused in the upper
portion so it's basically the same as
the 25 billion what that does is it
being triggers a clockwork mechanism
which counts down so rather than firing
the igniter immediately it starts as
clockwork mechanism and there's a delay
of between 2 hours and 80 hours after
being armed and at that point it
detonates so this is kind of the
canonical ticking bomb and this was
often used as a secondary fuse alongside
the primary fuse so the problem with
this is you can take you tell what delay
has been set it's a 2 to 80 hours you
have no idea how long that thing's going
to keep ticking before it detonates
so a standard approach was you wait 96
hours before you start messing with the
bomb however the type 17 fuse head to
particularly nasty failure modes the
first one and again remember you've got
this mechanical this very sensitive
mechanical clockwork device that's being
subject to a mess of shock as it impacts
the ground so one of them is it stops on
impact with the ground it counts down to
zero
and stops and then as soon as you
disturb the thing at detonates and the
second one is it stops on impact with
the ground and then it restarts so these
things aren't necessarily you know
sitting on the ground with the bomb with
a fuse pocket face upwards it might be
face down and mud so you've got to
rotate the thing you rotate the thing
and suddenly the bomb starts ticking you
have no idea how long it's going to take
before it kills you there were bombs
detonated more than a year after they
were they fell so that when these bombs
fell they had signed the various
priorities but fell into some very high
priority area like under a Gas Works or
a railway line or the example of the NPL
and Teddington there are priority one
that he fused them immediately and then
they were lower in lower priority one so
some of the really low priority ones
it's you know at the farm somewhere they
they've didn't bother defusing them
because it just wasn't worth doing it
because they had more agent bombs to
defuse is there some of these
degenerated more than a year later they
hit some sort of mechanical shock or
something the timer would suddenly start
countdown again and the bomb would
detonate
so the thing was the type 17 is it
contains metal components so it's bronze
and steel so the way you stop you defuse
this thing is user making it a collar
that goes around the bomb in lots of
steel components in place so what you do
is you turn down to where the bombers
and that's an actual photo of a bomb
being diffused so you tunnel down to
where the Bombers you clamp on this
gigantic meat metal collar you activate
the magnets and you certainly with a
stethoscope and hope the ticking stops
so this is think what the clock stock
also known as the Q coil and it was this
90 kilogram thing feed from hundred and
forty volt DC batteries he lowered this
gigantic a heavy thing around the bomb
tape that over we the fuse was a mere
listen to it with the stethoscope and
it's all the ticking stopped at that
point the type 17 fuse has been wounded
inert and you can then take the bomb
away and move it to a safe location and
work on it there either to detonate or
to this various other way other way to
defusing this thing we don't forget on
to in a minute another fuse after the
original blitz so he was the main blitz
1942 41 and there's something with the
baby blitz in 1943 and at that point
they'd improved the techniques so they
injected a urea formaldehyde resin which
was a primitive type of plastic and
other things so they drilled into it
injected plastic reason it solidified
and stopped the thing from moving
so that was that was in the main fuse
this was the 17 and 25 and then they
were being diffused so the Germans came
up with us count activist so 1940 a bomb
penetrated under an oil storage tank in
a picture refinery in Swansea this was a
this is a priority-one bomb it's a
petrol refinery you've got to stop these
bombs detonating because the fuel is
kind of precious they finally extracted
the bomb there were other bombs going
off so the guy who did this was in the
middle of piles of burning petrol with
bombs going off around them and somehow
got this thing out and the bomb had
split open
and it was something else under the
under the underneath of the game that
wasn't normally there and was called a
240 and so what the stud is it was under
here and there was a firing pin the
spring-loaded firing pin that was held
in place by the game when you pulled
this out the firing pin shot across and
detonated the bomb so they've gone to a
strategy to of this bombing which was
you rigged things to kill the defenders
you can't withdraw the main fuse the
minute you put door the main fuse when
you defusing it it detonates the bomb so
any fuses not just the type 17 the type
25 any other fuse that was used could
potentially have one of these things
inserted underneath it so as soon as you
do as soon as you remove the fuse to
defuse the bomb detonates and kills the
crystal diffuser so the counter heck
with us was she'd rely upon the case of
the bomb and I've mission that aim at
all is it's a really good military
explosive it's been used since before
World War one it's still used today
because it has these amazing properties
that it's really insensitive it's really
safe
so you drill open the case of the bomb
and you remove the aim at all and the
standard way of doing this is use high
pressure steam because it's so intense
if it's perfectly fine to do that it
melts the amytal Union get the sludge of
amytal and water that pours out on the
side of the bomb and at that point you
still have again left in there but
that's about the Paley explosive charge
of a hand grenade so it's not that much
damage if it does detonate and some of
these bombs the biggest bomb was a bomb
called the satan which was over a ton of
explosives and that could take quite a
while to actually sit there next to this
bomb with a few still on it's steaming
out a ton of explosive and it was also
used for discharging fuse capacitors so
you for steam under the thing
capacitors then malfunction and don't
still recharge anymore and then you can
pull the fuse out a slightly more
alarming method is you can set fire to
the amytal
and again it's perfectly safe to do that
it will burn so you thermite to burn
open the case of the bomb and you set
fire to the M at all and you simply burn
the whole lot and because M at all as I
mentioned it's extremely insensitive you
can burn happily at Point D tonight so
you can you can take a block of TNT and
set fire to it and use it to brew tea if
you're out in the field now virtually it
detonates once the burning reaches the
fuse it will detonate but by then most
of the amytal is gone so again you get a
very small explosion rather than a
gigantic explosion of all the ammeter
all going up so the response to this was
to type 50 fuse this is really nasty so
the Germans apparently had despised
within the bomb defuser community and
knew all the tricks that they were using
so they come up with the type 50 fuse
this had a split plunger so with a
Crabtree discharger you push this thing
in any discharge up I said a split
plunger so once you remake contact if
it's really been armed you push the
plunger and the bomb will detonate
immediately it also had circuitry where
if you use the mistress alternate method
matures out and also D tonight's
immediately and then they added some
extra features it had an extremely long
arming delay so instead of arming
instead of arming you know while it was
still in the air it armed after the
bomber came to come to reached and have
been at least for quite some time
it wasn't the DITA they don't impact
right bomb that was because the trigger
was an extremely sensitive spring
contact it was so sensitive that tapping
the case of the bomb with the pencil was
enough to set it off that's why you had
to have this long arming delay to make
sure it was totally at rest so if anyone
tried to dig down to this bomb or sneeze
near it or harsh words or anything the
bomb will detonate the sole purpose of
the type 50 fuse was to kill bomb
diffusers and it was typically paired
with a type 17 fuse so you've got a fuse
that detonates if you sneeze near it
next to a timed fuse that detonates
after certain amount of time with an
optional tools 40 next to it which
detonates if you try and pull the fuse
out the other thing was that because
this thing had these really sensitive
chamber switches if you use the clock
stopper on the type 17 fuse it's like 50
fuse next to it will be detonated by
their magnetic field so every single
defusing mechanism
had at that point apart from steaming
out the explosive was rendered void they
also had naval mines which was just a
scary they had this thing called the
beam 1000 which was a one ton naval mine
so they have magnetic fuse to detonate
it making it extends this to detonate it
when a ship went nearby it also hit the
standard ealerts which is the the the
standard 25 impact view so if it dropped
on land instead of going into the water
it would didn't anyone impact it also
had a hydrostatic valve to detonate it
so because these things were dropped
into the ocean and they were under the
surface if you pulled it to the surface
to defuse it
it would detonate and 20 had a
photoelectric sensor inside it so if you
drilled open the case and shun the light
inside always post it to any kind of
light it would also detonation so the
thing with this was I mentioned earlier
the type 376 fuse was overly complex you
had all this extra compensating
circuitry to deal with the fact that
this initially complex circuitry would
fail and that's exactly what happened
with the beam 1000 it was intended for
the Clyde which which was that we have a
scholarship yards were in an overshot
and came down near Dumbarton the first
guy the first bomb defuser that
encountered this I'd never seen one of
these things before so I cut the side
open and Seana torchin on to the
photoelectric cells however because of
all this extra complexity the wires are
come loose because of the shock of the
impact and start never actually
detonated and it saved his life yeah
because the more complex the thing is
the more things there are to go wrong so
basically that the the only approach it
was left while still steaming out the
explosive because all the other
diffusing mechanisms had been bypassed
so then the Jim has introduced something
even nastier called the type 50 B or the
Y fuse so this wasn't in the main bullet
sisters and the baby boots in 1943 and
again they had that same problem that
it's you know because it's electronic
you can add all these cool features but
it's now very complicated and so there's
a lot more things to go wrong so it's
again it's sustained a type 20 few 550
fuse which is already a horrible enough
used to deal with anyway
but underneath that were batteries and
Mercury killed switches in the XY and z
direction so I've already mentioned that
year the bomb could have come caressed
face down or fuse pocket down in some
mud so if you rotate this thing the tilt
switches are activated in the bomb
detonates and kills you it's also got an
eighty withdraw collar on the base so
these things
it's a completely smooth thing so you
drop it into the fuse pocket you can
pull it straight back out again
afterwards this head and Auntie was draw
like in Kalos so once this thing was in
the fuse pocket there's no way you can
get it back out again
there was a fuse captured the winner
under the Bakerloo line which was a main
railway line in London again it's a type
1 priority so that had top priority to
be defused the secondary circuit was
inactive because by this time they were
using effectively slave labor to make
these things and these guys weren't
terribly motivated to help the German
war effort site they often sabotage the
stuff that they were manufacturing the
secondary circuit on this was completely
inactive so presumably due to sabotage
by the by the guys he was supposed to be
sealing it and actually saved he defused
his life because he used he assumed it
was a standard pipe fitters charger on
it and that would have killed him but
because it had been sabotage it doesn't
work so in this case what you do is you
target the batteries and the thing about
the thing about these fuses is you know
if you look at this is a black box it's
it's kind of an interesting black box
you know you charge to fling a minifiers
but what you do is you look at the
individual components that make this up
so you've already targeted the
capacitors the capacitor has certain
physical characteristics so you move
outside the physical operating range
that it's designed for the same thing
with the batteries you don't just assume
it's a black box with with tilt switches
it's got batteries and those batteries
have certain characteristics so you
target those and what you do is you
freeze them to the point where they no
longer function as batteries assuming
that mucking around with the bomb and
that manner hasn't already caused it to
do tonight so what you do is you build a
clay or pasta scene dam around the fuse
pocket and then you pour liquid oxygen
into it until this is purely rule of
thumb until you've got a 1 1 foot dam at
a frost ring all the way around the
outside of the bomb and that tells you
that the batteries have been
hopefully been frozen solid sufficiently
that they're not working anymore and at
that point you can you sustain the
techniques of getting rid of a fuse so
typically it takes about 2 hours so
you're sitting there next to this bomb
for 2 hours pouring liquid oxygen out of
a deep earth flask onto the thing until
you've got your frost ring around the
outside of it and then you crowbar out
the fuse so the locking thing you know
makes it more difficult to to
get out but you know it's a standard
thing with brute force of brute force
doesn't work you're not using enough of
it so you just apply a crowbar and
eventually your leverage outputs of the
fuse so the problem with us was liquid
oxygen wasn't very portable again this
was the initial response to the stuck on
the while to figure this out they used
liquid oxygen so later they use dry ice
which you can make on-site and right at
the end of the war there was what was
left of the Luftwaffe used an improved
wife used which had been a low
temperature batteries again because they
had spies inside the bomb defusing
section they knew what they were doing
so they used beater low temperature
batteries and so dry ice wasn't
sufficient to call them that went back
to liquid oxygen but however that didn't
half the amount of time they had so with
liquid oxygen at about 20 minutes before
the battery started functioning again
would these be debate you said about 10
minutes to get the fuse out with a
crowbar naval mine fusing was slightly
different but they had the same kind of
arms race with that so these didn't use
contact mines it's they called Hertz
horns these are really World War one
meet used a lot more sophisticated
fusing so one of the things they used
was I've already mentioned the beam 1000
here the magnetic mine so it detected
iron objects passing nearby so it wasn't
based on the ship bumping into it it's
simply a ship going close to it was
enough to detonate it
so the heck for this was you had these
towed electromagnetic emitters these
when they fitted to an aircraft so you
flew this aircraft at low altitude
across the ocean emitting this very
strong magnetic field because an iron
boat has a relatively weak magnetic
field so you can be donate these things
remotely just by projecting a strong we
need may need a clear let them or you
can dig out stirrups so they're not
magnetic the counter Hector that was
you've got a counter on it so it
requires multiple activations so we're
plane flying flying over at once women
in it field isn't enough to activate it
you need a ship that's moving towards it
and you get multiple activations of the
ship moving slowly towards the fuse
before it will detonate counter heck to
that one was the plane it's to make
multiple passes and again that was kind
of effective for the Germans because
instead of just flying a plane over
ceiling once to clear it you had to fly
the thing back and forth 15 times before
you assumed that it was safe for boats
to go through another one was it to take
the chips the engines so not just you
know any random noise but specifically
the sound of a diesel engine in a shop
the heck the standard heck with this was
she just did
the sea lanes ahead of you and hope that
the shock wave detonates them all you
project out some kind of noise the
counter heck with this was that you
require a slowly increasing volume
because again a sudden pulse of noise is
not a ship a ship slowly increases in
volume as it gets towards the mine once
it reaches peak intensity using DNA to
casino the ship's right next to you so
the counter head - that was your project
noise out in front of these ships so
what they used was Kengo hammers which
was basically pneumatic drills in this
metal box welded onto the front of the
ship and they hit this thing bouncing
around in front of the ship
so basically project had roughly the
same sound as the engine and shut but at
very high volume out in front of it and
so the mind detonated long before the
shop keeper hit it so the stats for this
were about ten thousand unexploded bombs
about eight thousand would be used about
1,000 detonated in about a thousand odd
probably still down there again they're
out in the middle of nowhere in some
farms time we're near twenty meters
underground so it just wasn't worth the
effort of digging them up these things
are incredibly reliable and long-lived
some of these things are still fully
functional after 60 years there's an
extra news story from the evening
stained and of a bomb that was unearthed
in a construction site
and you know they sort of dug it up with
a digger in and you know rotated it and
suddenly it started ticking because I
had one of these type 17 fuses that have
been stopped by the impact it started
ticking and they used if you read the
rest of the story they used classic
World War 2 defusing techniques straight
out of you know World War 2 to defuse
this bomb so there's various things to
help the defenders and again this is
kind of interesting from a computer
point of view it's you know the sort of
the black box versus white box so all
the fuses were very carefully labeled
it's a German military manual going into
excruciating detail on how these fuses
had to be labeled so the bomb was
labeled in minut detailed with
everything it told the diffusers exactly
what type of fuse was in there and there
are very specific instructions this is
you know it's it's like you have to draw
the letters in in a particular height in
a particular font and here is the German
standard for the font that defines what
you know how you have to paint these
leaders are on and it's like a I can
actually read this thing you know 16
millimeter diameter circle with a 5
millimeter thickness and so on
on a bomb that was gonna be flown over
to the enemy and dropped on them
the theory is no one really knows why
they did this it could have been just
because they were German or it could
have been so that you know if a plane
came back and couldn't drop its bombs
then the guy the armor would know what
sort of cues was in there I don't know
how that method but anyway it made it
very easy for the defenders because they
knew exactly what they were dealing with
the numbering was you know according to
one military history it was inflexibly
methodical you knew that if he had a
fuse and it had a zero suffix it was an
80 disturbance fuse so the 50 and 50 B
it was a 5 suffix the 15 and 25 was an
impact fuse the 17 was a delayed fuse
and so on and so forth so the 50 B was
actually marked as a 25 B T disguise it
but then I had this why after it which
basically said this is markers are 25 B
but it's not it's actually a 50 B fuse
again why did they do this marker type
17 is a type 25 just confuse them to be
really nasty so that was a not a very
good idea other requirements again if
you either that's kind of neat so it
sees things like you know the Dean's
have to be smoothed out if there's any
rust on the bomb you have to scrape it
off if the paint's damaged you have to
repair the damaged paint because what
would the english think if we dropped
they a a bomb would scratch paint on
them i mean there'd be mortified would
be mortified other things to help the
defenders so yeah if the hidden actually
carefully labeled these fuses they would
have had to x-ray every fuse in the
fields next she did this with the anti
disturbance fuses with the wife use
because they weren't quite sure what was
in there so they used radon which is a
radioactive radium derived radioactive
gas and in basically x-ray these fuses
and developed these developed photos on
site
so they've knew what sort of fuse was in
there and again that gives an example of
how high values some of these targets
were and how critical it was to defuse
these bombs they were running portable
x-ray apparatus and developing films of
these bombs just to figure out what the
fuse was so they could disarm it and
that became a saint of practice for wife
users because they were just too
dangerous you had to know what it was
you were dealing with yes so they had
the inner pieces by the diffusers they
were publicized this helped the other
side so they stopped publishing any
information about what they were doing
it that didn't help that much
because the Germans apparently had spies
among the defuser's so they knew what
they were doing but still have slowed
them down to some extent and then it was
just sheer blind like they discovered
that there's a discovery of the two's
forty was pure like the discovery of the
type fifty be fused was pure like other
things with side-channel attacks from
nineteen forty instead of treating the
fuser as a black box treated as
individual physical components and you
attack the individual components rather
than the black box you know heat the
components you freeze them you basically
move them outside the standard operating
range and suddenly the thing doesn't
work anymore in the way it's supposed to
in the case of the attackers the
decision to use electronic fuses was
absolutely amazing the Allies used like
chemical fuses so a time delays with a
tacit eating into something enough to
eventually if they donated these were
relatively unreliable fuses and not very
versatile the fact that he had
electronic fuses and fuse pockets on the
side it a lot of versatility you could
well relatively easily change the
designs of the fuses to keep track in
this with this arms race with the people
trying to do the defusing and you hit
the things like the impact changed the
operating characteristics of the fuses
the type seventeen was particularly bad
in this so that made them sufficiently
unpredictable that it was dangerous for
the diffusers yeah they took advantage
of the fact that the news release was
publicized and they redesigned the fuses
to get around that so the thing about
the thing with the bomb diffusers the
average lifespan of a bomb defused was
about ten weeks so if you were the
person who actually did the defusing
rather than the guy who dug down to the
bomb you were made officer grade because
he had to have the ability to order
around the guys who were doing the other
work however you were never put through
Officer Training School because you
would be dead before we could actually
use your officer training and you know
think about that for a second that's
kind of a scary thing we will appoint
you as an officer but we're not going to
bother training you as an officer
because you won't live to be able to use
that capability if you want some reading
material on this stuff is an annual fuse
conference which is now in its 56th year
and it's everything you never wanted to
know about fuses the recent highlights
is use of lead-free solder and fuses
because you've got to apparently be RoHS
compliant so you know that you know if
you're talking about being maimed by
trasto munitions and stuff at least you
know that it's lead-free shrapnel rather
than lead at retinal
and finally your chances are meaning up
on watchlists due to my research
activity for this talk is probably close
to 100% okay we've got a couple of
minutes for questions do we have any
questions when I be here you didn't show
the ticking down red letters when did
they get added the red letter is ticking
down ten nine eight when did that get
added yeah only movie bombs this is what
they actually look like not dynamite in
red letters just a question here your
marked on the regulations about dealing
with paint scratches and scratches to
the to the metal in the bomb casing that
kind of thing that seems likely to be
more than purely cosmetic I would have
expected that that regulation would
exist due to increased risk for
corrosion of the mild steel casing do
you think that's possible or is that
actually purely cosmetic cosmetic I'm
actually getting almost 100% a car up on
the stage we'll just try that question
one more time all right one more time
sorry yeah do you actually think that
the the regulations about paint
scratches and scratches on the steel of
the bomb casing was for cosmetic reasons
or do you think it might be to prevent
accelerated corrosion and possibly
premature detonation well so that the
paint wasn't the bombs were painted and
it was fine but it was the lettering
wasn't for protection it was purely for
labeling the bomb and the instructions
specifically said that you know you hit
your correct the lettering and even for
rust you'd only noticed the rust as
you're loading the bomb out of the plane
and it's gonna be you know it's they got
a half-life of a couple of hours before
it gets dropped so I don't understand
and you know I've read military history
books where they also say we don't know
why they did this I think they were just
being German
I caught a question around the users
that use transistors can you use EMP to
defuse those so that the Mac 376 was one
of the last of the transistorized fuses
they now all use integrated circuits
which makes them even more flaky because
they're more you know there's even more
complexity and things to go wrong
one would assume you could however to
generate the amount of EMP you need to
deal with a shell and flight towards you
it's not really practical to do that in
the field there's a really interesting
history I've still got a couple minutes
on this here's an interesting history if
you read the history of the development
of proximity fuses during World War two
they basically sent out a what would now
be called radar but it was a lot of
frequency pulse and if it was reflected
back into the fuse they knew that they
were close to an object and would
detonate and the way they were worried
that the Germans would capture these
things and reverse-engineer them and
build their own so developed a way of
jamming them which broadcasts a radio
pulse back at the fuse so that's not
necessarily EMP but there was a way of
dealing with the very early proximity
fuses which had no you know sit pattern
they just if they got a radio pulse back
they would do tonight so early procs
fuses could be detonated that by later
procs fuses they know that they've seen
out the specific waveform the specific
series of pulses and they can't be
fooled that easily so yes straight EMP
it's not really practical and for
effectively jamming the fuses they're
designed with anti jamming capabilities
so you can't really do that either
I'll take your question over here hi and
you mentioned that an unexploded bomb is
almost as dangerous as one that has
actually detonated presumably it's much
cheaper to manufacture something that
looks like a bomb but doesn't well it's
never gonna detonate and do you think
that's a reasonable strategy for an out
force to do - nope one in five or one in
ten they are just things that look like
bombs so that you cut down your
operating costs so most of most of the
cost of the bomb was sort of machining
the casing in the fins and all the other
stuff so you've still got you know the
amytal is relatively
cheap and they produce thousands of tons
of this stuff and having something
that's completely inert you still want
to fill up with explosive so it possibly
detonates at some point I don't really
know if it's if it's worth the effort
because it might be that cheap and you
still want some explosive in it to do
some damage at some point and another
question here so they took a few
examples I suppose of each of these
bombs to to figure out how to diffuse
them how many examples did it take them
to figure out those procedures and how
reliable were they once they figured
that out
did they improve over time repeated
showings or did they still have repeated
failures that's kind of a long a chance
that they had it's probably best if I do
it later because that would be a small
token itself how they figured this out
they had a bunch of people like he was a
guy called the other Suffolk who was the
stadia for bomb defuser he was it was
like the canonical mad scientist he hit
this big stately home and he get these
bombs wheel into the middle of his
almost palace and start mucking around
with him in the basement figure out
these techniques so some of it was you
know rigorous research and some were
what was just these eccentric geniuses
who figured out some of the stuff he
mean she got killed defusing some new
type of bomb that he had encountered
before so it was it was a very British
way of doing things they just got
anybody they could think of anyone who
could coup could come in and say don't
have a go out looking at this got thrown
at it and yes some of it was like some
of was expertise like the other sufferer
got better and better over time he went
from the simple fuses to the more
complicated ones and that's like
computer hacking you know if people
hacking 20 years ago you had relatively
simple attacks in SDS the defense's got
me to the attackers adapted their
techniques and got better and better so
with the simple fuses the lis diffusers
got trained up on this and once they the
experience were the easy fuses that
could work onto how diffusers that were
deployed later but that that's a very
short version of a much longer answer
there anymore are there any more
questions well let's thank Peter Goodman
for is such a great keynote
you