our next speaker which is Adrian from a
CSD and he's going to be speaking about
introduction to change that you don't
like so I'm going to be talking today
about how to get started with analyzing
Cisco IOS for images and memory dumps in
the hope of sort of lowering the entry
bar and starting to finally do a form L
where they decided to come out the finds
a major injustice of maintenance members
wondering with the Australian
cybersecurity centers in 2015 and the
last year ago Phil to need to separate
in doing his normal Idaho work and start
doing some research into how we can
potentially do for anything else devices
so what appeals is something started
doing this school that we thought we
thought that route to metal there was a
theoretical thing I mean historic units
are reasonable human mental issues car
drumming arm but there was a study
accomplished and like such a high entry
mob stop developing their self that
changed in 2015 when in Cisco on borrow
I cannot announce that simply not debate
about so simple enough was a full iOS
need replacement which essentially is
the other one is replacing like
it works affected those provided for
back door functionality admin access
also essentially a rat so saying that
this was now being figured it's only a
matter of time before everyone starts to
get more into this sort of no way
element I mean if you can comprehend
corporations or rather you've got access
to their everything you can breathe
those use more containers they can see
you can redirect webpages it's good for
any taco that really know they're going
to be covering what iOS looks like both
on disk and in memory how to acquire
memory comic diversity and continued
analysis a bit of how the mangled iOS
images to make them sort of a bit more
friendly to the standard analysis tools
and we'll finally go through some
current attack centuries the just so
runs up to the day we're talking Cisco
IOS like original one here not the Apple
imitation we came out years later so
first off when I'm talking about an iOS
image I'm talking either the file you
download Francisco if you're an official
been there on a license I offer all the
one you rip off your dodgy ground you
got a second hand on the event all of
this research on this is the thing that
is stored on the internal storage OCR
target and extracted into make actually
that's all but the down boil required by
various names is a fairly standard Linux
help looking thing that might run on
normal winnings but I still have the
same feel so you got an old elf hit this
hole decompression program a bit of
elevation information to verify that the
chicks on an aside with what you've
acquired and finally that impressed
party of iowa's this is a normal
structure I can okay - no I'm not really
going to miss the one thing of interest
is the machine ID feel which is
typically used to confirm the person to
talk that is fineries being too powerful
but whatever is in the Cisco don't use
the right value that useful Oh use the
person types of turn exist so this can
have some issues when you start trying
to analyze the compression code is not
used wonders for verifying sort of the
integrity of what you've actually done
so if you took for the magic string of
feed face you've got the size both I'm
compressing impressed of the data the
checksum of the compressed and I prefer
Stella which can be calculated using
that Python function off the top there
and finally the action is this data
which is highlighted in blue at the
bottom of it didn't come out - it's set
to its top standards in better behaved
was the very end of the disk there's
this mate that couple numbers with an
empty five after it I cannot work out
this is an md5 hole and according to
this coders website it is a md5 hash of
some sections of the file and I'm
probably tell you which ones he can
actually verify this yourself the only
way you can't verify that I've found is
to use the inbuilt iOS verify command
which is great because you have to
verify the integrity of a compromised
system on the compromise system yeah so
if anyone does know what this is happy
to find out those are these CW strengths
with kind of a bit of an informational
sort of thing if you just make even a
random image to analyze so they contain
information such as the feature set on
the device like what would encryption it
has the bottle it has whether it has IP
because you know that's functional one
grabbers the mobile number at the device
the version number that you're dealing
with and various other things it's there
all the strings sitting there's the nice
ability to extract the filter for down
the bottom they are in green move on to
what this looks like once it's in memory
because I mean if you're dealing with a
bit of nowhere they take that kind of
where's it more interesting just bit of
a full disclosure so that's in here this
is being pieced together by reading like
sixteen year old exploitation white
papers and like reading through people's
really poorly documented code it's also
it should be known as I'm talking about
my OST north in your iOS XP lalala
ranges which tend to be running under a
more winning solar system which I walked
into this that theoretically sort of
standard Linux memory forensic
techniques against the Welcome process
memory a delicated has this struct
wrapped around it and there's a lot of
stuff here so I'm not gonna go through
it always quite frankly folks that's
pretty boring that I would not recommend
putting the magic string of a be one two
three four CA into a hex editor because
there is hundreds of thousands of these
things across the memory doll
things have interests about the process
ID because you can use this dot to piece
together all you
sections of memory that allocate are
allocated to a specific persist but keep
the kind of boring but I can't want to
see the names you can use the allocation
name field which is just a pointer to a
section of memory that contains a null
ten-minute string for that process this
whole structure is a doubly linked list
so you're also able to walk up and down
every three the process allocation and
start to build your own tree up and we
books like ie cup the size of the doctor
the doctor itself and this written value
at the end which is best I can tell is
sort of like a sort of the equivalent of
stack cookie heels that sort of thing so
if you go to another module memory
allocation you overwrite this value the
next time the integrity checking comes
through it sees that the freaks out when
iOS freaks out it total panic sent the
whole grounded previews which is kind of
good from a defense point because if
someone screws up their exploit and so
by the whole intelligence no response so
if I control into a network misspoke
command history of all someone's down on
the ground that's awesome these things
are ridiculously easy to extract out of
memory you can which we just drop
strings and grip the CMD and you'll get
the full time part of the command that
was running everything unfortunately
this isn't persistent so as soon as you
log out of the costs and what the memory
is free so it's not zeros and don't
stick around for they have minimal to be
depending on how how I typically use the
router is but it still plays push this
afterwards this folks that if you have
access to this stuff this is a rough
example what you can pull out of a
device so you're able to see of running
like the Chevron command I configured it
some exception don't we dumping stuff I
talked about the copy run command
throughout trying to connect to
something wrong start for some reason
why we actually managed to
so you can also extract the device's
configuration from memory so little bit
off-topic but you can change interfere
with what get outputs that Cisco
command-line there's like filters you
can built into it to sort of use regex
queries to determine what the user
actually sees so it is possible to write
things become B and then filter out them
actually then print it back to the
screen
so if you suspect someone screwed with
you won't be it might be useful to
extract it or Ana memory it's sitting in
memory in the same format that you would
normally get from running the show by
the start command so you can just
actually run fancy you can just search
the last configuration change string and
you'll see the entire thing just sitting
there so enough about what you can do
with iOS memory or how do we actually
get a copy over to stop playing we're
gonna go through some of the more
official ways and since we've got to be
more of a technical work I'll go through
some of my more experimental ways it
sort of your eyes even haven't had a
chance to test out yet so the official
way is Walt on on that Cisco's website
if you want to configure one of these
you can figure the the exception handler
you tell it to dump it out to a TFTP
server and you just go in the right role
in command support compression
relatively straightforward to do if you
just want to start playing with this
stuff this is pretty good way to start
it also is the official way so anyone
that's actually trying to do some
forward and forensics with a Binny mill
there is gonna know about this command
it's gonna do something to screw this or
give you false results or just kind of
pack the router they are they going out
of memory as well so you can also call
the individual segments of memory this
sort of like a pseudo small point is
exposed to the individual regions of
memory that you're able to use to copy
up no one that is relatively well-known
though so I don't these processes
filtered out and so the woods kept
secret in iOS is the last 15 years
whatever it's had a GD base of it built
into it so you can only access it
through the front console hole which
means you're now running everything out
of cereal at the
speed of 9600 board once you do this
you've got full read/write access to
memory so it is possible to dump the
entire contents of memory on my 2800
rather that has 256 Meg of RAM it was
going to take two or three days the dark
memory if you walk into an actual
organization with a job like I ran
aground on a decent half rack sort of
switch and you say I need to take that a
hyper mom or do a dump of my cereal good
luck see it burns really good memory
access cons really freaking slaughter
it's also being disabled in the newer
versions of iOS although it can be
relabeled through a pompom which is
products according to the fact but what
are the models but doing that does
require rebooting the router so you lose
and I think that's potentially sitting
in memory
it also don't skip the whole graph while
I'm doing this yeah so when you cut some
of these older devices open they using a
fairly standard PC hardware there's got
a nice because saying it the times gonna
apply it so my old 2800 series reality
uses old a dram theoretically there's no
protection against a tollbooth attacking
the big protection is that's really
freaking hard to find an old Pentium
holy and Chuck this stop injury to test
it on but we don't want my TV around and
thankfully I've managed for the because
I'm you know I'm still wage actually
receive in those so I can't play around
with this I don't want that
good luck convincing someone to let them
do this for their sorrows like an active
investigation because you're cracking up
in the wrong crowd and spring for a
spray inch lip and then yanking the ran
out while still running - then I also to
be careful that the toddler you putting
this into dumb support VCC as low as
grant does and zeroing the RAM that you
think has stuff in it when you boot it
up is not a good thing go to the other
side if you exploit they'd rather
they're sitting there running everything
is a single process so any running
process on it has direct memory access
what starting to see more and more
Seabees coming out for routers and
switches and quite a few of these
devices in a demagogy package again my
2800 was ended locked in 2016 and
there's still tools coming out forever
there's a reason why my key is an MP
server and stuff like that so give it a
sufficient amount of effort if you could
easily write your own so that meaty
graphs or implant that can dump memory
out over the network there's a slight
issue that all these devices have quite
a broad range of hardware that they run
also you sit there and write your
shellcode to do a memory dump for the
Calla PC model then you've got a
thousand different bits models and stuff
like that so not really a scalable
solution more of a it's almost you get a
PhD out there and write this then that
asleep so you want like for we are
protected on these classes there are a
decent dollar in protections that are
asked a decent number of bypasses for
the protections as well so there is
depth built into these routers so the
stack of the router as well as like the
IR memory where your packets are stored
is protected and I can't send a packet
that has executable shell code if you
don't haven't been just jump to it
unfortunately it is quite by possible so
there's well-known rob gadgets out there
so if you can get in some form toward
execution you can disable it's also
current integrity checking that it
doesn't basic checksum over there the
various segments of the current memory
to make sure that you haven't like
overwritten any older it is a fairly
basic checks on those that's directly
possible just to brute force your
shellcode so that it matches that you
check something
or you just wipe off debt and don't
overwrite the correlation what some time
is not really intended as a security
mechanism is for the stuff work and we
don't want to like take the rabbit down
so any process on the ground that
doesn't return control back to iOS
periodically will be killed by the
watchdog time it just means if you scrub
the shellcode and aren't returned thanks
to the controller then your shelter gets
killed as well ok again it's really
about that way
I'd like to hold the sleep function it's
fairly straightforward there is actual
ASLR but only on newer browsers with
newer updates my for 2800 is going to be
horrible forever and there's a thing
that I found in an old console by FX
about the fake day or so on so every
version violists
of every individual device subversion
hardware that configuration is an
individual compilation which means the
as these are giant statically linked
binary everything played out in memory
is called like different offsets every
time that means there's about well back
in 2009 there was 300 thousand different
iOS images out there probably a few more
in the last 10 years of people doing
this that's well over three hundred
thousand different memory layouts it
actually provides a better protection
than actually is along so the olds of
you may have brought something on your
router using a fixed offset that you
jump to and then throw against my router
mark pretty dates not you're just going
to crash my router not actually gain
control so I always to be weird I don't
know
Cisco is trying to stop you analyzing it
or if this is just like parts of the
image that they don't use for like they
have for control the systems they don't
need to worry none but idea the course
bit punky and does make some tools freak
out
so first up if you want to analyze this
stuff you've got it actually extracted
as I mentioned before it is just a stop
standard zip file at the end of it so
thankfully the winning sunset command
yeah it will strip the whole bit I'll
hit a crap up a song to speed up an
octave in computer otherwise so if you
do want to stop poking around inside is
probably what you cannot want to work
this into this is where they come back
to that machine ID field I mentioned in
the old head of the throne so when you
load this into either it's gonna read it
say it's an old feather jump to the
machine ID field to work out what sort
of what sort of instructions that you
use to disassemble this and freak out
what's doing research what this class
actually uses of rice I go on patch pile
and everything would be good to go but
what a visit they can learn any is
either properly and just like the
drop-down menu si is designed for our PC
I didn't see that drop down making the
first time so when you deal with the
convoluted way here's what you can get I
said write an exit to live in the
original one you can see the bottom
field pitstop CPU type of unknown off
the patching it it's now caliphate see
and pilot Hathaway sees it so I have a
moment go to the drive there's something
every tool you want to use for this so
there's other random stuff that tends to
pre guys well I've had picked at it is
to try to order pop up what I won't feel
hit or miss that and not be infinite
loops because they don't understand what
the ND it is and well maybe this is not
an iOS specific problem it's a I'm
analyzing anything that's not x86 and
little-endian
there's a lot of tools that just assume
that you're analyzing an x86 binary and
while they will work with a little bit
of tweaking it's not nice so the best
i've come up with a short of rewriting
that also actually a baby nurse flag in
the old header is to read all of the
bellies out within this right the old
feather back
obviously this breaks the binary but at
least you can analyze the property then
section head is quite a useful one so it
defeats out of all the different
conditions and names of the sections
within the file that you're analyzing
again for whatever is that cisco didn't
label one of the regions right and the
region the label right is the offset of
the string table that contains the names
of all the sections
fairly intensive to fix this one you
need to go and track down the correct
stream table using that overhead screens
you'll be able to see them again you
know that a sh
SDR going down there once you find out
you have demand
after the section pity or second table
yourself and find which entry points to
that and finally you can patch the other
the type of that thing to say this is
actually a string table which goes from
the belly looks on the left where
everything is just no names or the right
we can see here the text section well at
the very long the number 12 is the
actual string table States having a
value of str tab rather than going to be
on the web the all all stuff we did
financial nowhere that sort of actually
happening out there on the internet it's
all just on a basic start point of using
things that are baked into these devices
so twelve months ago the big thing with
SNMP confidential traction so this is
just you brute force the right the right
community stringing these devices use
that degree configure that can the TFTP
server of the device and finally by SNMP
you say hey right you're currently
running config out for TFTP server
because you know that's a thing you can
go over to FTP fairly straightforward
about to fix this up like a SNMP is just
essentially like a community strength
either password but it's also at you
only have to type in wants to a device
make this thing really freakin strong
and no one's going to be brute forcing
it over the Internet well then you don't
need right access to the Internet don't
expose right access to the Internet it
feels basic but still happens there's
not a bonus you can also overwrite the
current configuration or the current
running an image of the device using
this so if someone's out there doing
since we're not sockets type stuff again
they can overwrite your or drops in for
not on your device so the newest thing
is disco smart install so we have wait
last year at one of the our Russian
security conferences they sort of
dropped that you can use Cisco smartest
or to exfiltrate device configurations
slow again it's not a bug it's a feature
this being support that supports zero
touch configuration poverty rate much as
you can't type in credit so that no
case you built into this thing either by
default its intended so that you can
just close the switch off to the other
side of the world open up to some form
of IP connection and you can send it a
config and that's going to work it up it
will power zero indication here the
governor who is requesting this so a
very learned they call the secure
filament director so you are you doing
director that can both center the new
configuration as well as teletoon send
it back its current configuration so
that's not one get how much you're gonna
play with it please don't I'm just
showing rather so I don't want have to
clean it off so turn it off the pics
it'll just good as a parent thing is
it's on by default because it will use
it
no no timetable use the please tentacle
so that was a regionally gonna be the
end of this presentation and then last
Saturday someone do this so there's
someone did work after that same key
public school can go in the other
direction and overwrite the car
configuration of the device again no
authentication they use that to go home
wiped out whole switches in Iran and
replace it with a dark mess with our
elections and there's lovely ask us why
they will see in the screenshot there's
just someone putty section they're
actually running the sheriff stop in
command no way this was showed an actual
Iowa's like commands to convey the
device but they just replace the whole
thing a text file because there's also
no validation all the configuration file
you've got to this thing so this thing
literally just boots off saying both
which is it's no confit again just it
tries to actually execute each line of
DST off live which is a lot of fun
then it freaks out what is the default
concierge and all of a sudden Iran's
knocked off the internet for a while
also someone reports or because a
motherboard saying that they also
targeted by the US and the UK but in
that one they just went into turned off
smart install and all devices so they're
sort of calling them vigilante hackers
now as well so yeah really easy to do
script kitty level assault buzzes
emphasis on github at which we
point-and-click and my life completely
off it you've got it
it's also a big person to be there
[Laughter]
[Applause]