okay our next speaker is James head -
otherwise known as ec0 and he'll be
talking about its UNIX system Intel ma
de tag and open source biases so let's
welcome James to the stage
thank you okay I want to start right
over the gate by saying that I feel the
Jurassic Park is the best hack and maybe
that's ever been made and I know that's
an unpopular opinion yes so my name's
James and backgrounds not that important
but I'm right into hardware security
hardware hacking you can find me up at
the hardware village for the next couple
days I'm right into open source
liberation and all that kind of stuff so
what I'm going to be talking about today
is very near and dear to my heart I've
spent a lot of my own time coming to
understand all this sort of stuff and
the format of the talk is kind of less
dropping mad zero days and more of a
public service announcement about all
the weird that your computer does
that you probably don't know about okay
so I wanted to start by just giving a
brief overview of actually what happens
when you turn on a computer a mobile
phone anything with the processor in it
basically the CPU die has built-in logic
that will essentially hold the processor
in a certain state until all the
voltages stabilize at which point of
resets at that at that point the CPU
starts looking for code and the place in
which it looks is called the reset
vector it's a technical term for
basically a fixed memory address that
gets assigned when they just line a
processor 4 Intel and AMD processors
it's just hard coded and the chips it's
the same because they use the same
architecture for it's it's another
address but basically once the voltage
is settled your processor resets start
executing executing code
you can see the addresses here these
have been the same for decades and
decades and decades and decades nothing
has really changed in processes from
this perspective for a super long time
there's actually some pretty cool tricks
that go on in a processor to start
loading code and start getting a
computer ready to be a useful computer
to humans and that all starts after the
processor jumps to the reset vector and
starts loading code an example here is
the Intel series of processors when you
have a CPU a CPU is not smart enough and
doesn't have enough logic in it to
actually bring itself to life you need
supporting circuitry typically these are
called North bridges South bridges these
are just extra chips on the motherboard
that basically give the process of what
it needs to start up and start executing
instructions in sort of more recent
Intel chipsets we're talking about the
North Bridge doing things like loading
code from a flash chip and poking it
into these addresses so basically CPU
fires up voltages settle resets at the
reset vector the Northbridge has already
come in and it done some weird stuff to
load the contents of the flash ROM on
the system board into these addresses in
l2 cache on the cpu so it's kind of
tricks it into thinking like hey you've
got this stuff in memory you should
start executing it does a similar thing
it's typically more implementation
specific and it's typically baked into
the CPU design example being on the
Raspberry Pi basically you've got like a
stage 0 bootloader that gets loaded from
an SD card and the logic to do that is
actually baked into the CPU and it will
basically take that boot 0 again poke it
into the CPU cache and away you go start
running your very very basic bootloader
[Music]
all this is absolutely invisible to the
user which is kind of the important
thing here it's normally binary it's
norm normally source code you normally
can't change it out it's usually not
free and open-source implementations of
this stuff at this level but it is very
important to actually bringing up the
processor and bring up the processor to
a state we can start addressing
peripherals and essentially once you've
been through this state the processor is
in a sort of situation where it's able
to maybe start looking in SPI flashes or
in the case of parm on an SD card for
the next stage bootloader which I'll
refer to generally has boot code but
we're talking about BIOS as UEFI
implementations and in the case of arm
systems it's usually a closed source
system just a general bootloader so the
other thing that happens and this is
becoming more and more prevalent and
it's spooky
hence the flight your computer's also
going to start up and it's gonna start
up a series of support processors this
is less common on arm systems Intel and
AMD systems have their own
implementations of this technically
they're basically gonna fire up as soon
as everything has power so they're not
actually involved in the process we just
talked about AMD has a processor in
their CPUs that does this sort of weird
handshake with the hardware we'll talk
about that but essentially your computer
is going to also in tandem to the main
CPU be spinning up a whole bunch of
other processes whether they're on our
Bluetooth chipsets network cards
external bare-metal control cards and
also the security processor in modern
processors is going to spin up at the
same time so you cook all of this stuff
going on none of it is visible to you
you have no control over the code that
runs on it it
a bit scary once all of that's happened
and you sort of staged the Euro boot
loader has gotten the system in a stage
where it might actually start thinking
about loading an operating system that's
when you actually load a boot loader and
that's always something like you know
grub with Linux gnu/linux NT loader
which Windows NT boot loader launch D on
OS X I bid on iOS H boot is the really
common boot loader on Android systems
dusty goo built on most routers these
are a little more common a little less
implementation-specific and these 'm
there's a tendency for these to be open
source so for example the co boot is
open source I boot is despite apples
intentions now open source not licensed
grub that is obviously the grand unified
boot loader it is a new project and it's
totally open source so this is where you
probably as a user have the first
opportunity to start controlling what's
actually happening on your computer
obviously if you run our sex you've said
I don't care and if you run Windows
you've said I don't care
I trust you Apple I trust you Microsoft
interestingly enough obviously these
things being open source doesn't make
them secure because often the version of
you boot that you're running the version
of grub you're running it's not
necessarily up to date like that's
that's on you to keep that up to date
basically these are these pieces of
software they're their sole role in life
their whole reason for existing is to
take your computer and start looking at
storage devices where they might be able
to load a more complicated operating
system the examples are here of course
OS X Linux iOS Android these are all way
too big and complement complicated to
actually fit in the seat that you died
or fit in like a small boot flash so you
have these stages
buuut and a lot of code running that you
never see so we talked a little bit
about coprocessors before and some more
examples of things that might be
happening when your machine starts up
things like firmware you know we've got
Bluetooth chipsets in laptops and phones
these days super convenient those
typically have a small service processor
in them that run a binary only firmware
to actually do the Bluetooth bits you
know those have essentially got
potential attack surface on them because
you know they're RF devices they can be
interacted with from outside of the
machine these are almost always required
to run the chip and they're almost
always close source you're essentially
by having bluetooth enabled trusting the
vendor of that device that they're being
proactive about security and that
they're bringing your new firmware
whenever they find an issue and that
they even think that issues are a real
thing you've got things like add-on
cards PCI boot roms for example when you
boot a computer over the network to
deploy it say you're going to be running
like a PCI add-on ROM that's called and
it's essentially something that gets
loaded into the BIOS gets executed from
a flash chip on the PCI card network
card and it extends the functionality of
the BIOS there's not a lot of security
or signing around these usually you can
load alternate free open-source boot
roms on a lot of cards a lot of Intel
cards have the ability to load things
like IP x e and g p XE to replace the
vendor maintained chip contents and
people don't do that stuff that really
so you're typically running potentially
the firmware for these devices that the
system came with firmware boot roms by
officers typically don't get updated too
often because you typically also have to
reboot the machine right and that's
that's very disruptive when you take
that out so like the enterprise scale
you take that out to production servers
this stuff's just not happening it's
just not on people's radar it's sort of
like a third real class of systems here
in Co processes that are starting up a
light out and BMC management cards
examples of these like the dell idrac or
HP ILO IBM i think they still call it I
think it's got a flash new name but
they're basically all ARM processors
sitting on a PCI daughterboard
with a full OS like full embedded OS
running on them and network access and
they typically got access if not to the
host OS via drivers that are installed
in the host OS also if I you can just
reboot service with them typically week
off indication on the most people use
the default passwords and typically you
can get into like a show mode on them so
again you'd sort of know you had one of
these cards this wouldn't sneak up on
you but they're not something that
necessarily gets updated very often and
can also prevent present a bit more
attack surface on a system there's been
stacks of CVS for these cards if you go
to any CDE database just search dell
idrac its eye watering authentication
bar bypasses code execution and people
don't update them so they're off in a
really good place to start if you're
trying to cause some havoc on a
enterprise network
I really just want to use this gift
that's why this slide exists but yeah
look I mean in in summary boot code is
there to bring the system up on system
on chips it's typically referred to as
like a stage zero all of these things
essentially perform the same function
which is to make a computer usable the
main sort of key thing with the boot
code which is you know BIOS UEFI it's
it's it's almost always closed source
we'll find out with the firmware as we
find out with the stage zero boot
loaders boot code is typically only
generated by a few companies in the
world american megatrends are an example
inside by us intel's got a reference
UEFI implementation they call Tiano now
and they've got this really great catch
all-around licensing which means that
they don't have to release the source
code the trend away from open sourcing
the code for these is often speculated
to be related to government backdoors
is a really common theory licensing is
usually the defense but due to the
system wide access the UEFI firmwares
and by us have it's pretty common for
people to want to in especially in the
hardware liberation kind of community
want to replace the boot code with
something a little more little bit more
palatable a little bit more open source
and something they can sort of inspect
and sort of know is secure and also just
add additional features to old old
hardware new code is something that
often limits the usability of older
hardware
in recent years we've sort of seen
technology head towards the direction of
locking users out of choice kind of
similar to what has happened over the
years with our gaming consoles as an
example we're now in a situation where
essentially if you buy a gaming console
you are essentially buying a license to
use that machinery but if you modify it
you're a breaching your EULA
[Music]
Technologies like a UEFI secure boot
they sort of come with these cool words
like secure in the name and they can't
improve the security of a process
there's there's a real potential for
someone to load I don't know like a
malicious kernel modification then you
know could cook your real way into a
system you if you have kernel level
access to a system you're essentially
route or administrator and there's
nothing stopping you doing what you need
to do so locking down using encryption
and key signing the actual kernel
modules themselves and the actual kernel
is like a really good way to stop that
from happening and to keep a system
secure the only problem with UEFI secure
boot is most people turn it off and you
have to actually have your binary signed
by Microsoft thereby implementation the
only people who are allowed to sign
things are you can install your own key
routes like a lot of system firmwares
have that capability but most people
aren't gonna go down that path like if
you want to say like hey you want to run
Mac you want to run with it eggs you've
got a go install your own key root to
have this secure boot feature enabled
people they're not going to do it so it
relies on Microsoft actually ordaining
an operating system to run on a system
it's kind of a flawed implementation for
that for that reason
in even more recent processors like our
skylake onwards I think it is om systems
have the capability of essentially
burning into the CPU die a series of
keys those keys are then used to
authenticate the boot code so the actual
system bios UEFI intel have an
implementation of this called boot guard
it basically relies on the processor and
the system board me being manufactured
by the same person and when they install
the CPU into the board
they set a bunch of CPU fuses that
contain the CPUs and once they've been
said you can't unset them or anything
like they're burned in this obviously
stops people from putting alternate
biases on these systems it also
potentially mitigates the risk of things
like like bad by us like malicious BIOS
modifications designed to maintain
persistence on a system there's not a
lot of evidence that this sort of stuff
actually goes on it's more of a
theoretical attack but you know it's
possible so into a boot guard designed
to sort of keep the BIOS locked to what
the vendor wants you to run what's
what's a bit awful about that is it sort
of prevents you from modifying a BIOS
and we've started to see things like
digital rights management technology
built into system firmwares
and essentially into the Intel
management engine there is built-in
system there for enforcing digital
rights management again limiting user
choice so it's another one of those
technologies that sort of looks like it
it improves system security and it it
does by all accounts but it relies on
Intel ordaining things and the vendor
ordaining things and the problem then is
you know if you're not running like an
open source bios or something like that
you have absolutely no say in what gets
fixed or the functionality that gets
added to your system
by us to suffer from bit rot I challenge
you to find a BIOS that got a meltdown
on spec to fix that was more than like
four years old and you actually mind
that's kinda here or there
it's basically putting control from a
security perspective of system firmware
back in the hands of the manufacturers
rather than back in the hands of the
users in the security community in
general it's it's designed to minimize
the attack surface but yeah it limits
user choice on the topic of sort of
out-of-band management cards like bare
metal controllers which we talked about
earlier so these are these are kind of
interesting because they're essentially
deliberate backdoors you don't want
someone to log into your system and have
access to your screen keyboard and mouse
and be able to turn your computer on and
off but a lot of enterprise systems come
with these cards installed a lot of
people don't change the default
passwords on them it's super common to
find these systems on corporate networks
with Fadel our route as the username and
Calvin whoever Calvin is as the password
but it's kind of like an easy way into a
system really there's also like a tack
surface there because you can just wait
out an administrator needing to log into
the console and people are not super
diligent about logging out of the actual
video card on servers once they've done
what they needed to do bring the server
back up from like a power malfunction or
whatever they typically just close their
remote management console either leaving
a root console or an administrator
logged in console on the system so if
you can find one of those through there
the out-of-band management console you
basically in I mentioned before these
systems are kind of very closed doors
they're actually like entire computers
running on a chip so security updates on
these are super important like I can't
stress that enough and people don't do
them enough so if you actually work in
an enterprise that has lights-out
Management cards please update them
there's a very very easy way for people
to get into systems that's if your
vendor is still actually issuing updates
for in line with this like this is a
feature that used to just be relegated
to Enterprise land and like really
expensive servers like several thousand
dollar chassis systems sit in data
centers as recently as like it's less
than ten years ago so it's recent in CPU
land Intel introduced a functionality
called a MT V Pro you might have seen
labeled on your new Dell workstation
this is essentially in its earliest
incarnation an ARCA processor sitting
inside the CPU die running its own
operating system with access to the
network card OB system designed to
provide lights-out management on
workstation class systems I mean like
those those words should be pretty scary
but they scare me and it's it's another
one of those situations where a a lot of
people buy hardware with these
functionality enabled they don't
configure it they don't change the
passwords and again back to the point
about vendors potentially not really
giving a about updating these
things and taking security seriously
there's been you know a couple of really
notable CVS against AM T and V Pro that
have allowed unauthenticated access to
the AMT web interface because it runs a
web server of course it does
and actually the the attack vector was
just not supplying a HT digest when you
authenticate it and that's latinas
administrator so pretty cool stuff
pretty pretty like security 101 kind of
stuff and one of my favorite things is
like this idea that someone
design this feature and would have been
super excited about it and would have
been like oh wow you know we can do this
amazing stuff in the CPU we can control
it from anywhere in the world we can
turn the machine on and off we can give
access to the console never at any point
in the process did they go actually
that's a really bad idea that's a really
huge security issue why do I want that
but sure enough Intel baked it into the
processes in doing so a lot of hardware
liberation community and like hardware
security community raised an eyebrow
okay this maybe isn't the best idea have
you guys thought about the security
implications or someone breaching this
processor typical vendor response it's
we've had the CVS there to show that it
is important to consider this systems
one of the main reasons that this was
implemented anyway despite the security
implications is when you're managing
thousands and thousands of workstations
in an enterprise network and you get a
call from you know you've got your
helpdesk centralized somewhere somewhere
cost-effective and you know your cost
effective help Help Center is having
trouble walking
the user who's calling through the
process of rebuilding their machine
because that fixes all problems being
able to actually just log into the vPro
interface and kick off a reboot it's
super helpful and saves a lot of time
saves a lot of unnecessary Hardware
replacement so you know this is this is
enterprise driven it's not as common in
home systems but all of the bits and
pieces are there right like the CPU
support said most of the system boards
supported it is focused on fleet
management in enterprise environments
and even so even though it's an
enterprise environment I've worked in
enough places that don't actually
configure it to be secure that I have
opinions about it being there
you're talking about processes that are
embedded inside processes AMD's got
their own thing which is called the
platform service processor platform
security processor it's right there on
the slide James its present in 16h and
higher AMD processors so like the much
older or they're like torrents and
things like that they didn't have this
essentially Hardware initialization on
AMD processors is currently and was
previously handled by an open source
library called a GSA AG ESA and that was
a totally totally open source so the
sources that had been provided to like a
bunch of open source firmware vendors
and vendors projects and basically it
meant that you could write a firmware
for an AMD processor and all of the
hardware bring up was handled for you by
this library when they introduced the
security processor they moved all of
that responsibility into this it's
actually an ARM processor so it's an ARM
processor inside an x86 processor that
provides all of the security features
like TPM and it also is heavily heavily
linked to Hardware initialization so you
actually can't turn an AMD x86 processor
on without the tiny little ARM processor
inside saying it's okay and setting up
all the memory timings and everything so
it's super embedded yeah it's like an a5
so it's reasonably powerful like it's
not what the arc caused in the early
Intel processors were really really
underpowered like 100 megahertz or less
this is a cortex a5 it runs a full
real-time operating system inside
I mentioned it implements things like
that at the TPM so what that means is
the inside the flash regions which are
allocated to the platform security
processor you've got user credentials
you've got encryption keys that people
have stored in the TPM because the TPM
on these processes is a software device
it's not a hardware device you know it'd
be really really sad if there was a CV
that allowed code execution on these
processes they also have access to the
host memory which is pretty cool so if
you see erratically got into one of
these machines and had code execution
you would essentially have readwrite
memory access to the host I have a
diagram here it's kind of small
unfortunately it's meant to show you all
of the stuff going on inside the little
ARM processor and how it's just part of
the arm like the AMD processor talked
about the TPM there have been
vulnerabilities so you can absolutely
achieve code execution inside the TPM on
these processes there's also been a lot
of the recent security announcements AMD
flaws the former was a very legitimate
security issue like it basically meant
you could dump credentials if you had
access to the TPM
AMD floors is a little less it's more of
a persistence being at best it was
really played up as like you know the
next big security issue but it really
looks like it was probably just a stock
manipulation you need like local admin
on the machine to exploit this at best
you using it to like inject code into
the platform security processor to stay
a resident but it's not actually giving
you any sort of extra privilege that
having local admin whom the Machine
wouldn't give you so arm processors also
implement a similar thing just whilst
we're talking about AMD's I mentioned
was an ARM processor um trust zone is
security implementation forearm is the
security implementation for AMD AMD runs
an ARM processor for security and that
ARM processor also has its own secret
processors inside it under trust zone so
you know yo dawg i heard you like
coprocessors basically arm trust zone is
actually not so much individual CPU dies
it allows you to partition an ARM
processor into multiple worlds and
they're called so they're just like
memory regions certain memory allocated
to what's called the secure world or SW
d can't
it's totally invisible and it's also
inaccessible to the normal world which
is where your code runs a little blinky
light demo that's running on your
Raspberry Pi actually can't see the
secure world at all and on ARM
processors things like you typically
only see these in really expensive arm
systems like server systems but they
have TP M's and all that sort of stuff
built into them to make them competitive
as server systems but they're actually
again just software running inside the
secure world on these processes
it's a little bit of a diagram so orange
being the normal world blue being the
secure world the important thing to
remember about ARM processors is they're
actually extremely variable between
vendors so arm only really sort of gives
out generic reference implementations
for ARM processors and then it's up to
the individual vendors to do something
with that and do it securely which
always goes great the secure world has
this thing called the monitor running
which is actually what gates access in
and out of things running in secure
world so you've got a TPM running in
secure world you you do need to expose
that to the normal world somehow so you
can actually implement an API to access
securely the secrets and that's that's
the monitors job so there's basically
special registers that get set when
you're running code that are
authenticated by this code that is
running in this secure world they're
kind of like interrupts that you can
fire and you can pass parameters so what
actually happens is the execution of
those instructions then has access to
the secure world really briefly in like
a certain way that the secure world has
to respond to so it's essentially kind
of like a REST API in a in a processor
it's it's pretty heavy-duty stuff but
essentially it means that you can have
specific calls running to access the
secure world to retrieve data and
basically that's available to the normal
world and like most API is it has
security vulnerabilities which is
exactly how the the TPM code execution
was achieved there was I think it was
actually a simple buffer overflow in one
of the api's and once you've got code
exec in secure world you've actually got
access to the entire host memory
whatever you're running in there can't
be seen by normal world so it's a super
nasty
I also mentioned the implementations are
extremely vendor specific so for example
Volcom their their implementation of
trustzone is called Q SEC q SE e and
Qualcomm secure execution environment
off the top of my head and they also had
a CVO that was a codec in secure world
and it was an API that they had
implemented in the secure world to allow
access to like media files or something
and it basically allowed code exact
because it's just an API and they didn't
write it well so the main the main thing
I think that is probably the most
interesting about this world of
coprocessors and like secret code and
all that sort of stuff is Intel
management engine there's been a lot of
focus on the Intel management engine I
think white quite rightly it's been
around for a while so sort of post Core
2 Duo were the very early
implementations it is the hardware side
of AMT and vPro so it's actually the
hardware implementation that is
basically allowing AMT which is a
software product to dial into your
process and to dial into your system and
do things like reboot the machine or
yeah like mount virtual media all this
stuff that it can do it's integrated
into what's called the platform
controller hub and that's essentially
the majority of the functionality of the
Northbridge chip Northbridge chip on the
system board which has access to like
all of your i/o controllers all of your
memory it actually uses the host memory
to run
priest skylight that looks something
like this so you have like your main CPU
any like operating system agents that
are communicating with the management
engine AMT for example you've got your
operating system running on the main CPU
and then inside the platform controller
hub inside the Northbridge you had a
dedicated ARCA core which was running a
real-time operating system anything in
orange on this is essentially dedicated
to the management engine but what's
problematic here is that the management
engine is inside the piece of the PCH so
actually has access to everything that
PCH does which means Hardware sensors
the Ethernet MAC just super cool and all
of the i/o devices that basically hang
off the Southbridge which it also has
access to it also takes up a small
amount of the slot 0 DDR Ram it was
actually pretty cool YouTube talk with
the guy who invented this he's like
super pumped about it you know this is a
great feature and he accidentally sort
of mentioned that yeah it runs in the
slot zero RAM so if you just like didn't
have that bad in the ma wouldn't run and
you could literally just take your first
stick around Mountain EMA would be
neutralised the actual operating system
for the entire management engine runs in
a partition inside the BIOS flash so for
it to actually work it requires the
system bios to have a functional
environment for it to load up and run as
its operating system if that doesn't
happen your machine will reboot within
30 minutes because it has like a
triggers or watchdog timer inside the
CPU so you can't really easily remove it
[Music]
inside that same flash you've got the
system bios you've got the gigabyte
gigabit ethernet firmware etc and so I
mentioned it has access to the network
card it's able to basically coexist on
the Ethernet
physical interface on the system board
and send and receive packets on the
ethernet network and respond to those
and that's how a MT is implemented this
this essentially wasn't as scary because
it was in the Northbridge it wasn't
sitting in the CPU die if you if you
disabled it there were basically ways to
disable it by setting flags in the SPI
flash and it was not that big a deal
post skylake though they actually
removed the intel management engine into
the CPU die so it's actually sitting
there it's in Intel Atom systems it was
actually a spark system which i think is
kind of cool it's like an old hardware
nerd that if you had one of these atom
systems you also had a spark
so really the good old days you are in
the newer systems though it's actually
an x86 core so you've got x86 on x86
it's it's it's way harder to disable so
the tricks around just sort of setting
the spi flash flags that don't work
anymore we'll talk we'll talk about the
methods for disabling this but
essentially being integrated into the
process it makes it much much harder to
neutralize it's much more crucial to the
running of the processor and being in
the CPU die it has everything that the
CPU can access it can access
recent research into the Emmy to try and
sort of get an idea of like what it's
capable of and what code it's running
because really if this is running inside
the Emmy it's running on your computer
all the time and you can't observe it at
all recent research shows that basically
the processor has multiple unlock modes
and these unlock modes are controlled by
specific encrypted flash partitions
if these partitions contain Intel Keys
the processor will enter what's called
read unlock mode and there is
essentially an Intel technology called
DCI which is debug bus that they use
when manufacturing and debugging Intel
processors and if the processor is in
read unlock mode you actually have a
functional JTAG interface into the Intel
ME processor basically what's required
there is not foreign basically you need
the Intel Keys to get that mode because
read unlock code mode needs the Intel
Keys there were some recent CBS against
this though which allowed code execution
inside the Intel ME one cool thing is
like if you if you're familiar with
memory access there's multiple rings in
an Intel processor ring 0 traditionally
being the highest you know that's like
the the operational mode of the kernel
and the until Emmy actually runs in ring
minus 3 so it not only has access to
everything that ring 0 can't see it so
it's totally visible but basically there
were Seavey's that allowed code
execution in ring minus 3 in the Intel
ME core which is an x86 core that
allowed positive positive security did a
lot of really great research on it
there's been some awesome talks coming
over blackhat in a year and this code
executional they are dumping of the
firmware it allowed also for these guys
to work out that there was a like secret
undocumented unlock mode that didn't
need the Intel keys and would get you
into read unlock mode which they did
JTAG was had firmware was dumped and
yeah basically they found out it runs
MINIX which is an educational UNIX
operating system this kinda correspond
with a bunch of emails back and forth
from Android Tannenbaum who's the guy
who wrote MINIX from Intel without
asking like loads of questions about
meanings and he's like this is weird but
okay and yeah they basically wrote their
own extended version of MINIX for this
they haven't released any of the source
code again there's more speculation that
that's due to government backdoors but
it's it's probably just because they
don't want a AMD to steal this and
basically they're emmys a UNIX system
running inside your processor no matter
like what host OS you run you're running
MINIX which is cool cuz meaning it's
kind of like the most commonly run
operating system in the world now so
from all of this like there's a few
takeaways general coprocessor security
to long didn't read security processes
running closed source code beyond user
control which are hard to update without
significant impact to the system they
don't necessarily improve the security
posture in the long term of a system
closed source processors which control
the initialization of hardware and which
payloads they will pass execution to
outside of user control are bad for use
of freedom so not being able to run what
you need to running hardware that you've
paid money for is it's not only like
being unfair it's actually kind of
preventing you from keeping that
hardware for longer it forces you to buy
new hardware and maybe the hobby of god
is totally fine there's like
environmental implications for that and
also he the computer probably has a
backdoor in it that you don't know about
and there's not heaps you can do about
that
from a hardware liberation perspective
there's those options though so you can
basically replace the boot code on your
system with something like Linux boot
coreboot Libre boot you can disable
security management processes like the
Intel ME through various means and
there's also alternate firmwares being
developed for bare metal management
cards like open BNC Linux boot is
actually a kind of interesting project
because it essentially means to replace
the system bios with Linux it's got
essentially just enough to bring up the
system to the point where Linux can
bootstrap and most drivers in Linux
actually are capable of bringing up
Hardware without assistance from the
BIOS mostly because BIOS is are very
unreliable for bringing up Hardware
unless you've got the secret
documentation that they give to
Microsoft but yo Linux boot is is
essentially more of a server orientated
project for end user systems and I run
it on this laptop core boot is a
becoming more of a common option it's an
open source by us basically replaces
your vendor BIOS and it's enough to
bring up your system more like unlike
Linux boot you can actually you know
press f12 boot off the USB it's quite
quite usable
UEFI actually there is a free and
open-source implementation of UEFI
called Tiano court and that's actually
part of the Intel UEFI implementation
that they have open sourced it's often
used as a payload for core boot if you
need to boot UEFI only operating systems
and then you've got projects like heads
which is basically meant to coexist with
tails and it's essentially like a
verified boot option so all stages of
the boot process essentially verified
with a public key cryptography
so as far as if you've got a coprocessor
in you know pro if you've got a
coprocessor in your process of what can
you do about it until they me there's
some kind of crap options MD PSP us or
out of like it can't be disabled at all
trusts own you can get lucky based on
the vendor BMC's you can get lucky based
on the vendor by age there are different
means for disabling me until ma the very
early ones we talked about the ones
embedded in the platform controller hub
you can set some flags in the flash
descriptor and it will just not boot up
it's fine it's gone the hilum onward you
can run it as an open source project
called ami cleaner and essentially what
that does is it removes as many modules
as it can from any firmware leaving only
the barest minimum modules that they've
found a needed to send that watchdog
pulse to the processor to keep it
running
so the nasty stuff is more than likely
in those other modules there's
absolutely nothing to say that the core
modules don't also have nasty stuff in
them there is as a result of the the CVS
that have come out in telling me the
research that has been done by positive
security there's been another method
found very recently using the JTAG
interface which is called old emmy
disabled and it is similar to the early
methods of disabling me where you can
set a couple of flags in the spi flash
and the Emmy sort of goes to sleep don't
really like this isn't documented
anywhere but it seems to work 2013 Plus
Intel have actually implemented a high
assurance platform support which is not
a public feature it's been designed
essentially at the NSA's behest because
probably enough they don't want secret
processes running in their environment
an Emmy cleaner now has support for
setting that bit on the newer processors
and you can essentially disable the ma
that way as well you obviously can't do
this on systems with Intel boot guard
because you'll be changing the contents
of the system bios it'll no longer
verify it won't boot so om systems sorry
systems that you've built yourself for
example by buying a motherboard buying a
processor there's no way the bootcut
bootcut can be enabled on that
combination so you can absolutely
disable the MA using that and there's
also vendors like our purism and
system76 that are basically they are
hardware manufacturers and they choose
not to enable this when they set the CPU
die they set the fuses on the CPU they
don't leave they don't put keys in so
boot doesn't work so you can still
enable Emme because you can modify your
bios and you can also run coreboot on
some of these systems as well talked
about that bar arm you can't run
anything but PSP that's your life i'm
trustzone so certain vendors allow their
processes to you can't disable trustzone
because it's kind of an inherent cpu
feature that allows you to partition
areas of memory but some of the vendors
will allow you to run code in it so you
kind of have access to that you can sort
of inspect it you can see what's going
on there it's still not or some
situation for BMC's you've got open BMC
I mentioned earlier or you can actually
just often D solder the modules or pull
out the BMC cards if you don't use them
but open the BMC funnily enough is
actually a Facebook initiative because
they weren't happy with the stability of
their bare metal controllers but also
they didn't like the idea of trusting a
vendor to have access to their data
which
10 out of 10 for self-awareness and I
figured a now just sort of go through
demo of a laptop I've disassembled
dumping the firmware disabling the MA
flashing Corbett showing what that looks
like which is going to involve me
playing a video on the external screen
of course not
right so this is a motherboard out of a
Lenovo x2 20 that I've pulled you can do
a lot of this stuff inside the machine
like you don't necessarily need to pull
the motherboard a lot of systems just
have the flash chip underneath the palm
rest let's say that's model hands that I
hired showing where the SPI flash is one
of the worst and stupidest things you
can try and do is this because it
doesn't work basically I have it in this
video to demonstrate how futile it is
unless you really dial up the
temperature on a heat gun it's very hard
to remove an SPI flash for flashing
because they sold them on to the ground
plane of the board you've kind of got to
warm up the entire board so what you
want to use is something like a test
clip and this is just a soak a test clip
you can clip it onto the board you can
see I've got the power supply connected
to the board that can that can be a
really good way to supply enough power
to the entire board in the flash chip
often when you plug these things in
sweet that's cool that's what I wanted
to happen
oh no that that's intended basically the
the power from the SPI flasher is not
going to be enough to power up the whole
motherboard and because the chip still
soldered that's essentially what it's
going to be trying to do that's probably
not is that readable ok cool it's not
readable for me
so with a sope chip connected there's a
piece of software called flash rom which
is just really common open-source piece
of software it's used for interacting
with SPI flashes you can see this
command over on here it's just a shell
script that I'm using a BeagleBone black
to do the flashing because it's got a
pretty decent 3.3 volt supply which is
important it's also very fast because it
does native SPI so I'm just dumping out
the firmware from that chip and you can
see it dumped just fine
so this is me powering up the laptop
before I have made any changes system
vital data not that interesting you will
be able to see though on the config tab
when I switch to it okay fine
I'll catch it this time
I prepared this whole video with a piece
of software called open shot and it was
my anyway probably saw it flash up there
the Intel AMT is showing us enabled in
there I got some pretty decent effects
transitions and stuff so I was pretty
impressed with myself but I didn't
manage to pause it long enough on the
AMT bit yeah essentially you can see
that it's enabled its the vendor BIOS
like you've probably all seen anything
paid boot up
what we'll do now is we'll go through
the process of running an Intel ME
cleaner on the flash that I dumped
earlier so basically taking the vendor
BIOS running ma cleaner over it which I
run it with the dash S flag which also
sets the high assurance platform bid in
the flash
and then yeah we basically write the
flash back to the chip
which is always way faster than reading
the whole thing because basically if
there are any zeros in your flash file
it'll just skip over them rather than
rewriting them
I promise I spit this up
so this is just doing a walk of the
original flash showing just the amount
of staff these are all flash partitions
is raw mostly containing code and
modules that are running inside the
management engine just to give you an
idea of the scope of it so any cleaner
will reduce this down to about 2 or 3
modules depending on the edition the
rest of it is things like video drivers
and things like that because it
interacts with the video card and all
sorts of stuff that seems really
unnecessary for a security processor
there's a lot
yeah this is basically any cleaner
running over it she's removed a bunch of
stuff
so now we booted up with the newly
flashed cleaned by us
so it firstly does boot after reflashing
the modified bios which is kind of cool
if we get into the system menu on the
wireless
see the EMT options gone so it's
essentially disabled it
this is essentially a compilation of
coreboot being a free and open source
project you sort of have to select your
board it supports a whole bunch of
different hardware I've selected the x2
20 it supports a number of payloads so
when you run Corbitt on your machine you
are not just running for boot so you can
basically configure coreboot to load
what's called C BIOS which is an open
source traditional BIOS you can
configure it to actually load grub
directly in the SPI flash so you can
direct boot you kernel or your OS you
can even load a Linux kernel in as a
payload so you actually really cut down
the amount of code running on your
machine I've gone with grub here one
downside from filming this demo was that
I learned about halfway through actually
it made me super glad I wasn't doing
this live is that you actually can't get
an external monitor working in coreboot
apparently compilation
I'm just flashing in and then running em
a cleaner over the coreboot binary
because Corbett needs the Emmy firmware
as well as keep the processor up and
running
and it's following up on the laptop
screen now because their boots straight
into grub so no vendor bios anymore and
me disabled and you can embed a config
file so at boot you kernel and
everything like that for the purposes of
the demo I didn't but that's essentially
it
any questions
thank you very much change let's give
James a round of applause
we might have time for one question
before us that before the start of the
next talk if there's any person people
out there that want to ask okay great we
have one question over here
so how many systems have signed by OSA
so you can't run any cleaner on them so
I actually actually missed the last half
of the question so how many biases are
signs that you can't just run any
cleaner and modify them pretty much any
OAM system so the Novo dell they they
all enable good card it's all all signed
pretty much the only one newer systems
is to go with a vendor who specifically
doesn't sign their BIOS is like system
77 purism don't paying me any money to
say that or build your own systems using
sort of standalone parts but they they
all enable it because it's a security
feature
[Music]
thank you very much just one more round
of applause for James
[Applause]
and by the way James mentioned this
earlier he is part of the hardware
people which stuff is Paul Louise coming
up next so go see those guys tomorrow at
the hardware hacking village and they'll
show you a thing or two