we actually have a really great talk now
by Igor coos talking about self force
which is the formally verified
microkernel and he'll be talking about
self Loren family fast trustworthy sheep
deployed so let's welcome a hall with a
round of applause all right thanks
everyone so yeah I me whore and I'm
gonna talk to you about SEL for and the
work were do well I'll introduce what it
is in case people aren't aware of what
it is and then I'll talk about the work
we're doing in order to make it more
widely used basically so there's this
common common knowledge that if you want
to build a system or you want to get a
service then you want it to be fast you
want it to be good and you want it to be
cheap but you can usually only pick two
so we've got SEO for and family which is
the platform around it and other tools
related to it and what we want is all
three of those so I'm gonna talk to you
about why I see SEO for is fast and good
and then I'm gonna talk to you about
what we're doing to make building
systems with it cheap so SEO for maybe
show of hands who knows what it is who's
never heard of it a couple of people all
right cool
so SEO for is a small fast capability
based operating systems microkernel so
what does that mean it's small so think
about the order of 10,000 lines of code
of see and assembly what that means is
that it has a small attack surface so
there's not that much code to attack and
more importantly it's amenable to
verification to formal verification so
you can actually do proofs about the
whole code base it's not too big it's
fast what does that mean it's the
world's fastest operating systems kernel
and that's designed for security and
safety so what does that mean
it means that it's suitable for use in
the real world so our goal with
developing a seal for was to build
something that was
pure that could be formally verified but
that could be used for real-world
systems we didn't want a toy system we
didn't want an academic system we wanted
something that we could build real
systems on top of it's capability-based
so what does that mean it's built with
the capability based security model and
that means that unprivileged code needs
permission to access resources and to do
communication so by default you can't do
anything unless you're given explicit
permission to do something and so what
that means is that the kernel can
confine damage from attacks in
unprivileged code and then finally it's
an operating systems microkernel so what
that means is code that runs in the up
in the sorry it's the operating system
kernel which means that it is the code
that runs in the privileged mode of
hardware and that means it's the most
critical part of the software because
anything that the operating system
kernel can do anything that's running in
privileged mode can do whatever it wants
in the whole system so there's a little
picture of what SEO for is it's that
middle layer between the hardware and
the user level applications it's the
part that runs in privileged mode and
basically does virtual memory management
does inter process communication
dust read management and provides access
control and then everything else in the
system is written on top of the kernel
runs in unprivileged mode and basically
runs as components that can be isolated
from each other so this is kind of an
overview of what SEO for is bring
everyone up to speed ok so I mentioned
it's fast so what does that mean well
some numbers to just look at the goal of
making a sale for fast is to make the
IPC which is inter process communication
performance fast so that when you need
to switch from component process to
process and use the level or when you
need to do communication between the
processes you can do that very quickly
and that's important for a microkernel
because it relies on this switching and
this
communication so it's the fastest
microkernel out there has the fastest
IPC interesting thing I was when we
started developing a steel floor with
this goal of formally verifying it and
so on that we wanted to make sure that
it wouldn't be less than or more than
10% slower than the current version than
the existing versions in the end it
ended up being the fastest version ended
up being faster than the existing
versions so that was a good win so it's
fast it's good what do we mean by SEO
for is good well in this case we mean
that the code is good the code is
trustworthy and it's the world's most
verified kernel so we have a lot of
different ways of saying this but
basically it means that we've formally
verified that kernel so what does that
mean we've got a mathematical proof that
it's code is correct with respect to its
specification we have a mathematical
proof that enforces strong security
properties and we've proved safe from
upper bounds on the worst case execution
time of the kernel so let me explain
this picture here if you look at the
middle there's a green box that says
specification so what we did was we
started with the specification of the
specification basically tells you what
the API does so for every API function
we specify exactly what it does what the
preconditions are what the post
conditions are how the state changes
after you run that function so this is
all formally specified in in Isabel
which is a formal logic what we then do
is go to the box underneath that and
write code that implements that
specification we take that code and we
translate it into the same kind of
formal logic Isabel in Isabel in
higher-order logic so we have this
formal specification so then we've got
this visa specification and this API
specification and then we do a formal
proof so a mathematical proof that the
C's specification that the C code
implements exactly the API specification
why is that important well obviously
it's important because you want to know
your code is implementing the API
correctly it's gonna do what you think
it's going to do but more importantly it
means that the C code implements exactly
these the API specification so it
doesn't do anything more and it doesn't
do anything less and this is important
because that also means that your C code
doesn't do things like buffer overflows
access the wrong memory it doesn't do
things like null pointer dereferences
and so on so that takes away a whole
category of potential problems in your
code so you know that your code does the
right thing and you know it doesn't do
all the bad things that it could do so
anyone who's paying attention will have
a bunch of objections here at least two
so one of them is well how do you know
that the specification is right how do
you know that you got the specification
right and the answer to that is well you
look at it really hard and you make sure
that it says what you think it says but
we went a step further and so we said
well we want to use this code to build
secure systems so what kind of
properties of secure systems need well
there's the standard CIA properties
confidentiality integrity and
availability and so what we did was we
made proofs on top of the specification
that say that if you set up your system
correctly that you will have
confidentiality between different
processes as long as they're not allowed
to share any data or have any
communication you will have integrity
between these processes that you won't
they won't be able to modify each
other's data and so in this way we have
proved that the specification gives us
the properties that we want so the other
objection people have is well okay
you've proved the C code but that's not
what runs on your hardware you still
have a compiler in the mix you need to
compile the C code into binary code and
that's what actually runs so that's true
we didn't take the route of using a
verified compiler but what we did
instead was we verified that the binary
code that the compiler spits out does
the same thing as the C code and so we
took a bind the binary code we took a
model of the hardware that runs on so
this was arm in this case
we read in the binary code we create a
formal model of what the binary code
does and then we extract control flow
graphs from the binary code from the C
code and we show that they do the same
thing and so what that gives us is a
proof that the binary code that's
running as long as it's configured
correctly gives us the desired security
properties and so this was a big deal
this happened over the over the last
almost 10 years and and so these proofs
are mathematical proofs and they're done
in in Isabel which uses higher-order
logic so it's so SEO for is fast and
it's good which is awesome but it's not
magic security fairy dust so just
sprinkling some SEL 4 on your systems
won't make them secure so what's the
catch why why not we have a bunch of
assumptions in the proof so one of the
big assumptions in the proof is that the
hardware is correct and it does the
right thing and that's not always the
case and particularly we've seen
recently with meltdown inspector that
the hardware does really bad things
sometimes not all of the code is is
verified yet so there's some part of the
kernel initialization there's a little
bit of assembly code that isn't fully
verified yet SEO for currently runs on a
single core it's verified for a single
core so a lot of systems want to use
multi core we're still working on that
and then SEO for again is the
microkernel that runs in privilege level
there's a lot of code that needs to run
at user level so we need to verify
libraries and user level code and stuff
like that so there's still more proof to
be done
it's a microkernel not a full operating
system so most people aren't used to
working with the microkernel you need to
provide your own drivers you need to
provide your own network stack your own
storage stack it doesn't give you POSIX
so if you want POSIX you need to
implement POSIX support on top of that
so kind of difficult to work with and
that leads to a higher development
effort and cost for people using it you
need to port it to potentially port it
to a hardware that you're interested in
it doesn't run on everything under the
Sun you need to develop those OS
services you may need to redesign your
systems if you want to run them on top
of
co4 and it doesn't support every
language under the Sun so we support see
we have some C++ support we support rust
pass well there's some other languages
we support but you know if you come with
your favorite language of the day
probably you will need to develop
support for that and then finally the
verification effort and cost are still
reasonably high in particular if if the
kernel changes if we make changes to
that if we add things like to fix
meltdown inspector or if we add features
or if we change the API around then
those need to be verified likewise if we
port to a new platform and add platform
features then those need to be verified
as well so it's not perfect but we want
to make it perfect and so this is a
little bit of a story about how to do
that before I talk about that a little
overview of building systems with SEO
for so if you want to build a system to
run on SEO for this is approximately
what it should look like so you've got
your hardware your processor running
you've got the little microkernel
running on top of that and then
everything else runs on top of that in
user mode so in unprivileged mode and so
if you need to access file system you
need to provide a process that deals
with file system access if you need to
access the network you need to have a
process that gives you network access
you need your device drivers so to
access hardware you need to have device
drivers process management and memory
management and so on so you need to
provide all of those some of those are
already available some of them you need
to write yourself and then you write
your application so you need to take
your application you need to structure
it in such a way to make it take
advantage of the confidentiality
integrity properties that SCF or it
gives you and build your system in that
way it needs to communicate with all of
those other components on the left so
the file system and so on to do things
and then eventually you get tired of
doing that and so the rest of the stuff
you just run on Linux running in a
virtual machine you don't care that much
about that the main thing is that SEO
for is a context switching engine so it
allows all of those processes to run and
switch between them it gives you this
strong
isolation between the processes so if
one of those processes goes goes crazy
maybe one of your device drivers is
buggy and it goes crazy it can't affect
the other processes and then finally it
gives you controlled communication
between the processes so only if you
explicitly allow communication between
processes can you do that so that's
awesome we want to use SEO for to build
trustworthy systems this is I'm from the
trustworthy Systems Group at data 61 our
goal is to build trustworthy systems but
what's a trustworthy system so let's
start with software every system that
needs that has some kind of critical
functionality or needs secure
functionality will have some trusted
software and trusted software is the
software that must work correctly to
ensure that security requires our men or
another way of looking at that is it's
the software that's able to break
security of the system so if the
software that if it misbehaves it can
basically break the system and do
whatever it wants so we take the
collection of all the trusted software
on the system and we define the trusted
computing base and so this is just all
this trusted software on the system next
we look at trustworthy software
trustworthy software is the trusted
software that is worthy of the trust
that it gets so we put all this trust in
this software but should we do we know
that it's bug free do do we know that it
doesn't have exploits in it do you know
that it's not gonna do something
malicious we don't know but when it's
trustworthy we've done something to make
sure that it is actually worthy of being
trusted so there's high assurance and we
can do that by doing good coding
practice by doing a lot of testing by
using awesome languages like rust and so
on by doing formal methods so finally
the a trustworthy system is a system
whose trust works trusted computing base
is trustworthy so we've actually looked
at the trust word trusted computing base
and made sure that it is worthy of the
trust that it has so how do we build
trustworthy systems with SEO for how do
we use it to actually build trustworthy
systems like I said it's not magic
security fairy dust so you can't just
put something on SEO for and it'll be
secur so there are a couple of ideals in
in building a trustworthy system the
first one is a minimal TCB so minimal
trusted computing base you want to
minimize the amount of code that needs
to be trusted because the more code
there is to be trusted the more likely
it is that something will go wrong and
it the bigger the attack surfaces and
then you'd like to verify that TCB so
make sure that the tcp is trusted apply
formal methods or apply good coding or
use good languages etc all right so
these are the two kind of drivers of
building trustworthy systems and then in
doing that they're a bunch of well-known
principles for building secure systems
to follow us or things like lease
privilege make sure that a component or
a process doesn't have any more
privileged than it actually needs to do
its work separation of privileged make
sure that components don't do too much
and have too much privilege to separate
out tasks so that the amount of
privilege a component has is reduced
least common mechanism so make sure that
you don't have all the components using
a single component as a single other
service to get something done spread
that out as well so that there's no kind
of one point of compromise and then
defense-in-depth have a bunch of
different mechanisms to catch attacks or
to stop attacks from happening and so we
use the SI four mechanisms to do that so
we use the fact that we have a
microkernel we start with a really small
trusted computing base compared SEL for
size of ten thousand lines of code to
something like Linux which is which is
millions of lines of code and the
starting TCB is a lot smaller already
then we need to apply isolation so we
need to apply the fact that SEO port
does isolation really good or really
well and apply that so that gives us
things like separation ship privilege
again applying isolation helps us to
reduce the TCB so we can take the
trusted functionality out and isolate it
from the untrusted functionality we use
controlled communication so control who
gets to communicate with who and of
course verification to make the TCB
trustworthy so have preferably formal
verification to
so here's an example we call this the
security retrofit and this is an analogy
this is basically taking existing
systems and retrofitting them to run on
SEO for to take advantage of SEO for its
property to make them more secure and
the name security retrofit is an analogy
to a seismic retrofit when you take an
existing building and you modify it so
that it's better better resistant to
earthquakes so this is what we're doing
with with Software Systems so we start
with a regular system the example here
is a UAV on the mission board on a UAV
this is based on a project that we've
done in practice we start with a regular
system and the first step is to take
that it runs on Linux so we take the
whole system and run it on a virtual
machine on top of SCL for now this
doesn't give us any security but it's
the engineering work needed for the next
steps next we take that virtual machine
or take that Linux instance and we split
it up so we take some of the
functionality and we run it in a
separate virtual machine or a separate
instance of Linux that starts with the
isolation already we have some isolation
between different functionalities then
we also take some of that functionality
and we move it outside of Linux and
outside of the virtual machine and
implement it natively so in this example
we've taken the network stack up and
implemented it natively and we reiterate
that process and take more and more
identified the trusted components in the
system and remove those outside of Linux
into native components and so what that
does is removes for example this huge
Linux from the trusted computing base so
you no longer have to rely on Lync it's
being correct or no one attacking Linux
and so on and so you get this set of
trusted components running preferably
natively that you can then apply
verification techniques to and make sure
that they work correctly so in the
project we did we stopped at moving the
components out natively we didn't
necessarily verify all of them although
we
use some good product good programming
languages that give us a lot of
properties already to implement those
we've done a bunch of projects with SEO
for so mostly on autonomous vehicles and
it's it's open source so it's usable by
by people outside so we're building up a
community around that and we've seen
people coming up to us and using this
and so people are using SEO for
independent of us to build products to
do research and so on so that's really
good we're getting more and more
interest from people doing IOT people
doing automotive from defense etc etc so
this is really good but you know when I
asked who knew SEO for there were a
couple of hands who here has actually
looked at SEO for or done anything with
SEO for okay one person so I expect most
people have it right and why so I mean
it's awesome it's great there's all
these awesome things to do people are
using it but it's not in the mainstream
and so we've done a lot of work on SEO
for the next step is to make it
mainstream and what do we need to do in
order to make that happen
well there's three main things we need
to make it cheaper so it's expensive and
development effort but it's also
expensive to do the verification it's
also expensive to make sure that that
trusted computing base is actually
trustworthy to make sure that we can
verify these components and so on so
what we would like is to get proofs for
free we'd like to be able to write
software and just have proofs that it's
correct that it's good we need to make
it more relevant so whenever we talk to
anyone about using SEO for they've got
all these requirements that we don't
mean we want to run it on this platform
we want to run it on multi-core we want
to use you know Ruby or something crazy
so we need to make it more relevant we
need to add more features to it and then
finally we need to make it scale so the
effort it took to verify SEO for
huge pretty large especially for a group
our size and we're constantly reeve arif
eyeing things so as we modify a sale for
as it evolves as it grows the the proof
needs to evolve as well it wasn't a
one-shot thing that we did and throw
away we need to keep that active and so
I'll talk about a proof engineering what
it takes to actually do that so let me
start with making it cheaper when we
developed a feel for we estimated that
the cost of developing and verifying the
kernel was about $400 per line of code
so multiply that by lines of code and
you get the total cost compare that to
other software development so if you
take low assurance software development
basically using a traditional embedded
kernel and developing a traditional
embedded kernel you're looking at about
one hundred two hundred dollars per line
of code and if you look at high
assurance software development so
something that needs to meet Common
Criteria requirements l6 plus is the
stuff that you know you need to run you
need to have to do top-secret work and
so on that goes up to a thousand lines
of code so SEO for is not the cheapest
but it's also not the more expensive and
we argue that it gives you more than the
Common Criteria el6 plus level of
assurance so it's still pretty good but
it's still expensive in particular if we
need to verify all of the user level
stuff that makes up the trusted
computing base as well that's a lot of
verification work that still needs to be
done and so what we want to do is
automate proof generation so get proofs
for free so we've got two main
approaches for doing that right now both
of them involve programming languages we
have a project called cogent which is
developing a high-level language for
developing system services in so we're
developing services like drivers we're
developing services like network stacks
like file systems and so on in this
language and the idea with this language
is that you take the language you
compile it and that generates your
executable code so your binary that you
run but it also executes SAP roof of
that code as well so you get your
executable code and your proof at the
same time which is really good this is
work in progress you
really take budget and do stuff with it
yet we've got some examples the other
approach is is based on K Kamel which is
a verified optimizing compiler and the
idea there is that you write your
theorem in a theorem proving language so
for example in a higher-order logic and
it and from that generates code that
implements what you want so you actually
don't write your program in a regular
programming language you do that in
logic and you get good code out of that
and because the compiler is verified as
well you know that the code matches your
theorems both of those can be used to
then hook into sd4 and systems running
on top of that to verify your trusted
computing bases so these are two things
that we're doing to make it cheaper to
make it possible for people who aren't
us weren't in our group to actually do
this kind of stuff and build systems on
top of SEO for we also need to make it
more relevant so I mentioned a bunch of
things before about why people probably
aren't using SEO poor so things like
multi-core we need to have multi-core
everyone wants to run things on lots of
cores people apparently have a lot of
computation that they need to do so we
do have an implementation of SEO for
that works on multi-core so an SMP
implementation the interesting thing is
we use a big log for that which you
shouldn't ever do except it's a
microkernel and it actually is okay so
that's good
the hard part there is doing the
verification of a multi-core kernel so
there's a lot of work that a lot of
research work going into that right now
figuring out how to verify concurrent
systems that run on multiple processors
it's it's a tough task we're doing it
and hopefully we'll get there we want to
run it on embedded systems we want to
run it on real-time systems these are
systems that have timing requirements
they have strict deadlines that need to
be meet met otherwise the quadcopter the
helicopter falls out of the sky and we
don't
to happen so we've done a lot of work on
that we've got a version of SEO poor
that's and this is going to become the
main version of SEO for that's for mixed
criticality systems for real-time
systems so that exists and we're
currently working on proofs of that
system and we also need Prevert for
real-time systems we need to have worst
case execution time analysis so we need
to know how long does it take when you
invoke a system call because you that's
part of meaning your timing deadlines
and so we've done a full worst case
execution time analysis on the kernel
and it's one of the only kernels that's
ever actually had that done so that's
really good so we're doing really well
on the real-time systems aspect timing
channels so we've talked about SEO for
providing isolation provides
confidentiality but that doesn't include
timing channels right so those are
explicit channels and so as we've seen
time and channels are tough right Jen
gave this talk about all these timing
channels that are possible we have some
approach that's also challenge work of
dealing with timing channels in SEO for
by doing cache coloring so making sure
that things that are actually isolated
don't share any cache which is awesome
that works except that the hardware is
broken and we can't rely on the hardware
necessarily so we're doing work on that
we're trying to change the hardware as
well we're trying to get influenced to
actually make the hardware work
I guess one way of that doing that is
finding things like meltdown inspector
and embarrassing hardware met vendors
into changing it and then we need
platform support so we want it to run on
a lot a lot of hardware currently runs
on a lot of ARM processors it runs on
x86 we're we're doing verification for
64-bit x86 and we're doing support for
64-bit arm as well we need to expand
that as people have more requirements
and so on but also on the user level
when you move to new hardware platforms
you need to provide disk drive I'm sorry
device drivers and so on and we're
looking at using cogent and KML to do
these kind of things to provide verified
drivers and so
and then finally we need to make it
scale so currently the proof is about
half a million lines of proof code this
is one of the largest mathematical
formal proofs in the world nope which
means nobody's really done this before
and we're adding more features we're
adding support for virtualization
hardware we're doing this multi
criticality kernel
where´s we're adding support for multi
core we're adding support for more
platform 64-bit and alongside the 32-bit
and so on and it's tough right now it
resembles the early days of software
development where people had no
experience building large systems and so
they didn't know what to do to actually
make building designing and writing
these systems maintainable and so this
is what we're doing so we've invented a
new field called proof engineering which
is analogous to software engineering so
it's two proofs what software
engineering is to software how do we
improve the proof tools how do we
improve automation how do we actually
structure proofs such that they're
expandable such that they can grow and
not become unwieldy and unmaintainable
so we need to learn how to you reuse
proofs more we need to have more
abstraction in our proofs we need to do
all of these things to make it scale and
once we do that we can start really kind
of ramping up and verifying with a
bigger and bigger systems more and more
systems so these are the three things
that we need to work on to make this
usable and hopefully when we've done
this in a couple of years it can come
back here and say who's building systems
on SCO 4 and you know a lot of a lot
more people will raise their hands so in
summary takeaway message is that we
produced verified technology that's high
performance and has been deployed in
systems around the world so people are
actually using this to build things but
our goal now is to radically change the
way the world build systems so we want
to get to a point where there will be no
excuse for bad software in systems there
will be no excuse for software that has
vulnerabilities that has security bugs
in it and we want the future to be
verified thank you
we've got time for a couple of questions
if people want to ask any other one over
here I get a tow got CA technologies
I've worked with embedded software for a
long time and most of you probably don't
know that we built the face where I
write us for the intake triggers in
Australia so my question is are you
planning on putting this to PC
architecture the question is whether
we're planning to port this to the
PowerPC architecture and I laugh and I
say that's an awesome question because
we get that question a lot
automotive people like PowerPC as well
we resist maybe someday it'll happen but
currently we're resisting we're hoping
that eventually people stop using
PowerPC we won't have to do it I don't
know if that will happen or not if it
doesn't happen we probably will in the
end any more questions in this
presentation
[Music]
so the question is whether the risk 5
offers opportunities to do the hardware
right and avoid a lot of these timing
channels that exist in the commodity
Intel and ARM processors yes we we're
very interested in risk 5 and we're very
interested in working together with the
community to make sure that they do
things right and to influence how they
do things to influence that the hardware
is written in such a way or is designed
in such a way that the microarchitecture
doesn't have all of the state that that
leaks information and it provides the
right functionalities for closing the
channels so yes risk 5 awesome actually
thinks elf horns one of the crowning
achievements of Australia so let's let's
thank people for his presentation
[Applause]
[Music]