but shower here who will be presenting
on that's not how this works
so anyway that interesting I'm doing
UNIX system administration for 15 years
now first thing to be any fun to a
little bit we had a little bit of
Solaris
going on seven related joins to heaven
conventions on the ground something
generally more interesting about how a
routine would operate and so what I've
been trying to do recently is bring with
that and all those back the way we
operate there's a blue team so this is a
generic system and here's something like
this once you become aware in your
environment you are aware of how I'm
sorry but not actually sorry enough to
know the atrocious it is your loving
tail and absolutely uncatchable the
stuff that you can't get rid of it
actually reasonable not to any point of
time I went for an accompanying that I
will
[Music]
they have also kept illogical early
adopters so it's not like they think
orchestration promotes a coal I think
puppets go and then they think as well
as just slow down a little bit
great I mean also bring your own device
we hopefully every so often back in the
day you used to get our internal network
taken down someone would bring an apple
in and the Apple device would just say
that it was going to DHCP everything
because they know wouldn't you that kind
of thing and then you're like oh these
things are really terrible I know
they're terrible because I go to hacking
conventions and I do that a lot because
I recognize my environment in them and
it's like well maybe you guys could just
burn them and that way I would get some
recognition and I can fix them except
you don't um so it's fine we can totally
do this ourselves like we don't need you
none of us even lift really so I just
didn't play the pudding in the rain but
then you get high on the on call which
is I think most people here will be
familiar with it's in response to Aurora
Google started rolling out is there a
trust network solution and then you may
have devices that have a little of past
users it had a level of trust but that
is to me every day when it gets hostile
and it's really awesome that documents
on the net
come about it's it's really awesome and
then you rate things like you consider
your actual resources and the stuff you
have to actually do for your date that
did a job without actually get to unify
a new way to do perimeter access much
less ignoring and then you consider this
bet which is a Google even Google
required a very public owning by a
nation-state it was China trying to go
all the way into Google's desktops
before they did this and it took them
years and the documents say that it was
very complicated and then you realize
that you actually made the internet some
interesting twist it up you a throne
taken from my quick is a loss then oh
maybe I though there this is more of us
so this toy is stuff that we can
actually achieve most of the stuff that
I'm only mentioning here is not stuff
that requires much buy-in from
management stakeholders it's stuff that
you can do
SSS admin on the down low if you need to
but even Google needing to end up by a
nation-state before if they were willing
to do this and it needed by and you may
not get that but you can definitely do
some things that will help your
environment because even though phishing
is a really good way to get credentials
and own stuff I'm not going to be
mentioning it in this talk because it is
a thing that I would feel immensely
uncomfortable to inflict on the rest of
my company without getting going here
[Music]
right so this thing it would be yes
right just always vent I find out what
information your company is leaking on
the internet what is publicly available
I mean we started doing it because we
like what the are you putting on
github this is this is an internal
project like how would the PN's tearing
documentation with the clients and it
was like the answer was a Google Doc and
you just like please don't do that
so there are yeah the real number of
different ways to do that we were just
great paste burns for a bunch of
keywords and our network basis as well
just lets
my PA range is that I'm turning up one
tune in we've got a few things that way
and you just sort of like with the elbow
and you're like well what were you even
thinking could you don't do that we have
an eternal ice but you could use that
it's imprinted the also we look over you
is this is not your perimeter your
perimeter is basically
undefinable your perimeter is somebody
plugging in their foreign to charge it
in a conference room you cannot control
it you don't know what it is it's kind
of it's a lot more permeable than a
traditional source and under like to
ignite so the number one thing that I'd
like you to take away from this to it is
you know you've set up this you know
your environment and if you don't you're
really shitty subscribe manage to go
back to Java
you know we a weak point so and you know
where the weak points are that you can't
easily fix like there might be you might
be able to just upgrade a box in place
the application on that will actually
work with the latest version and there
might be stuff that it's
business-critical that you've actually
found to the touch but you know where it
is you can sandbox it you can segregate
it off and the other thing is so if
someone is attacking those things how do
you make that more visible to you as
it's a seven be the change you want to
see on your network most of what a gecko
will try and do is get create some own
stuff so the crews might be attained
right fishing they might be bad password
management
we use they could get possibly Active
Directory and crack that and what still
kept those local trying and riff around
and start to network or use the creates
break out of this break out of the
sandbox I would like to think you can
stop it completely but I don't have that
much sustain then that and our ability
to see that complex things in a way that
is pretty foolproof so what I would like
to do is slow them down and then once
it's slowed down hopefully they'll have
to take risks and then you've got more
time to detect a breach and there's more
chance both in making a screw-up it'll
become visible to you so we're actually
getting kind of good at this better
hardening targets there's a lot of like
appliance level things that you can put
it in some lots of concepts like please
privilege defense-in-depth we've got the
CIA triad confidentially confidentiality
integrity availability authorization
verses of education is well known
context but it's the thing that we're
not actually that good at yet and that I
think we need to get a lot better at is
you need to harden your targets but you
also need to look for evidence that
someone is trying to hack them and
that's not a thing that I think we good
at that yeah I mean we've got some
scenes but most scenes I've had occasion
to look at and not actually tuned that
well there's just too much information
going into them a lot of it but not
enough of it is useful it's a way of
increasing the situational awareness
in your environment when it comes to
discovery this will take it from the
Verizon report it still takes people
about a month to notice the average
breach and there you can see like at
least nearly a third of all breaches are
sorta taken by third parties probably
noticing there's a problem with the
citizens you know that's not right you
should have one of three breaches
shouldn't be detected by somebody else
using new stuff you should be able to
figure that out yourself it in New
Zealand now that we - should we go on
it's pretty great instead of putting the
information on New Zealand specific
reaches which is very cold by a
quarterly report you should be reading
it I believe like horizon has been doing
this ages and yeah you should be reading
therefore every year it's really good
but it would be nice to have so much fun
with anything but particularly
susceptible check so the whole evidence
of absence it's not
the corollary to that is even if you've
got the locks nobody reads the lungs
it's I think it might piss my opinions
an engine that comes in through an
automated email is it's more that's
useless unless you have like that one
guy but actually says seven goes through
my check every day if you actually have
that guy raised until they can leave so
their way is as much as you can I don't
really care how you do it you can get
someone if you want just by an officer
or by an options a shell thing there's a
bunch of foster things free and open
source things to do as well I'm gonna be
mentioning a fair amount of products
here that I feel the agnostic I don't
really care what you use as long as he
uses something so agree log to you can
customize your an elk stack we we have
managed to get extreme for our sock and
then sometimes you put a kid in live
stream on it
it's not what it's for but it's pretty
great visualize as much as you can't
that's how it's a lot easier for humans
to just looking too much of any other
information like that I you have a
thousand ban logs for instance which is
a really handy thing that if someone's
trying to very foolish nice association
they don't just bounce them
automatically so you hit that or you
have that one of those is a lot easier
for us to pass which is why visualize
your logs as much as you can
it's very I think it's a waste of your
time just to go through every single
email every day so one of the things
that you should be looking for is like
abnormal behavior on your network this
is the sorts of dos if you put a single
site just put on that plate that's fine
I hear or any kind of testing
environment and you need to take care of
something before it takes out malicious
at the sites on your network and your
network itself yeah you should
I mean this is really really obvious
when you make it a visual representation
of inbound outbound national and
international it's yeah it was really
the sort of thing I have on a dashboard
sort of like takes over and you media
spike you like wait what I mean we've
got what have made it so simple as
follow it up say what kind of traffic it
is is it like a syn flood or whatever
and it's us tracked it down as fast as
we can without having to TCP dump on
particular interfaces at 3:00 in the
morning which makes you really proud
shape
there and I think there are other things
you can do too much in it websites it's
broke ideas is pretty good it's
open-source unix-based it's just best
betting port with packet capture but
everything will help if you know that
you have an incident and you turn it
twice a baby there's even things
services that will monitor your BGP
products for you and send you an alert
on your big TV break exchanges like in
my experience is mostly because I'm
unscrewed it up on our front end but
it's still pretty handy to know where
and so you can just miss fix it as fast
as possible I don't identifying the
weakest number of your targets we have
my speaker notes not tuning up anymore I
just gonna be making up from now
hey
just keeping your my running Indian
terrain oh you have one thing that does
that it's really useful that we're
trying to integrate wait we're doing
things as they make a distinction
between the device which is like the
physical hardware and the host which is
the operating system and the software
that runs on it so they might know that
this is my laptop but there was her care
in a separate students whether the last
meaning the last time also I patched
this laptop which so we try to put that
out into two different kinds of
inventories
one of the other things but it really
usually that is we get metrics on how
fast we catch things like we put a list
of service and absolutely critical only
front element puts it on the engineer
and we do them as fast as possible every
game but we can track how fast we're
getting at them and make sure that maybe
you can also attract your longtail
problem clients that don't like to
schedule an outage one day because they
really super important and also they
never tested the idea so they kind of
fell over to make sure that they have
continuous up time there is something
like that it just relentlessly had to
patch through some that fall through the
cracks
this is he stuff we use at work that
grab stuff fire always query which is
pretty cool but just get it started as
well which is the sort of thing that I
was talking about with the difference
between person and device I noticed that
you personally have got devices pretty
handy but it assumes that uses it's sort
of user directed and it seems that they
will be catching this stuff which is not
actually an assumption that I feel safe
tonight remember and the requires that I
kick around out there what kept them and
still got running Gingerbread Oh
something like I wish I was
- Chet ops is really really good at
making server events personal to you
we're using matrix because it's over
token sorts of federated if you don't
want to use regular you just you can use
swag or HipChat or whatever there are
lots out there them through the most
everything and they're really easy to
program but you also have some political
diets that will be like IRC until I
die but I see it easy to write
botsko and anyway they can suck it chat
ups with me and I like it so again
there's also this which is why I
personally don't like slack
and why we're using my tricks with
federated servers distributed
geographically so if you can't think to
one what we want me to start with it at
all
but using something that's better than
nothing to give it'll quite the same
thing they can be really really simple
like Def Con has got a personal event
scripting thing where you can just you
can hook anything this will just tell
you will store the thing the last IP
that you came in from and if you come in
from so many different I don't tell
administrator you can just push them to
a channel when your light won't that
that's such monies I pay I don't
understand why you would be coming in
from there it's a push notification
start with wait for yourself to read the
logs because you'd like that's a month
the average rate protection takes you
need to know as soon as possible if you
want to limit their access to your
network make more complicated and
another third-party thing there's your
which will again do you IP locking if
you know expecting someone to be logging
in from some other thing they don't get
to look in I mean it's actually very
relatively and relatively easy to sit up
but it can make a big difference to how
complicated it can be
to gain access multi-factor
authentication I mean most people I know
have it somewhere but it's kind of it's
pretty hard to use and therefore had to
roll out to an entire environment we but
wait sorry
at work we ended at home there's no
myself like shooting argument about
whether or not you could use one on trt
paid was good enough or whether you
should go fully beekeeping anything but
like Google indicate on your phone it's
better than nothing it's free just use
it it will send to almost everything
right now
and if you can't
multi-vector or everything something
something is better than nothing if you
know if you can't forget if we want on a
service they make sure that any most
privileged users are forced to do it so
this is a this is about honey touch
mints I just thought this was the
perfect slide for it and we honey tokens
things that you put on in your
environment that when they use they set
up an alert so the belly doesn't use my
and they use but they're in their abuse
their own like a canary value or a
honeypot but they can be something like
[Music]
putting a file in the root if you ship
one directory this is database passwords
or something so it opens it tries one of
those you get an alert because no one
gentleman would bother do that
[Laughter]
does anyone want to argue with the slide
yeah it is anybody but anybody like to
argue whether and actually can't yeah so
yeah a tech is like to get creates
annoying stuff so you can use this
against them
I knew this cloud trail is a really cool
thing that you don't like compliance
auditing of your AWS account than when
you can monitor and retain the
accounting activity for it
and spacecrafts lets you I don't know
paste AWS tokens into IRC and then see
which one of your friends was an asshole
enough to try them example may be taken
from the place use their own tools
against them which is another pretty
nice excuse to go to a hacker convention
because you're learning new things that
you can use to secure in their wigs
although I'm actually an open-source
person I don't really want to talk about
seven active directory because it's
horrible so we're just gonna talk about
active directory space you also did but
bloodhound is a really cool thing that
you can use to users graph theory to men
about the relationship between an
account that they might have access to
and to get into my net worth and
that begin graphically you can use this
on your Active Directory there's nothing
stopping you there figuring out what an
attack you might do and they just be
like it never sucks to be different one
of those accounts could invite be a
canary or something that says let's just
the waited to make this as would be the
shortest possible to maintain Minh
someone tries to actually access
something using that account it alert
you and you have visibility of somebody
doing something dodgy on their network
so a big idea if you know what they
might be doing and you should have a
pretty good idea by now could you tell
if they were doing it can you make it as
it is easy to tell if someone is doing
something dodgy in your environment Plus
this means you can keep going to hectic
conventions so how to do these things to
scan as real fish your eye is entering
an alert like assuming it's only it's
like grass the grass might be look nice
but if they don't just buy anything as
useful for you it's worse than useless
is taking out space that you could have
dedicated to something that you actually
need to care about on your environment I
guess they would if you just use it to
like have a nice dashboard that's not
there when management comes through
that's different but like you could have
oh I don't know external sign up I'm
just like sorry sign up to see your
external get lab something taken from
the news that might be the thing that
you really really care about like who
actually has access to the repos and
have your dense lockdown with every part
well enough that kind of thing and a
little not push the alerts
don't rely on yourself to email
there are files because you weren't I
daren't their feet that's pretty boring
the other thing about this is when
you're tuning it is I found that false
positives are actually really really
useful
most of the weird stuff on your network
will be gifts because that's what they
do well most of the activity on your
environment will be idea of doing
something or a subset meandering
something there's like just statistics
but if you find it positive you could
treat it it's real and go into ends like
if this was an actual intrusion would I
be able to trace it back to the source
what information is missing what extra
logs do I need to hand then or visualize
what was being a nice choke point I mean
it would stop them so you can figure to
use them to figure out the limitations I
guess system before it gets real the
other thing is using yourself as a test
case we do that at work all the time
partly because as a systems
administrator I'd agree on about 3000
boxes give or take a survey would be a
high-value target and seeing me because
if I want to and I really do want to
roll this out there is different company
I need to have I need to make it as
seamless as possible to as many people
as possible so if I start doing it just
to myself I can then make it easier for
myself because I would like that and
they make it easier for them to use as
well when I can get that little bit
forward like most of those 2/7
indicates that we thought ourselves but
people are now interested and not
affected all that's thing now we have
horse way the people that don't actually
need to so again access to the systems
that have just installed Google on their
phone and a unit every single time so
you lower the barrier to entry for
people that aren't as technically
literate as you so they would just
disrupt the productivity of the company
as little as possible when you do get to
push out the barriers a little bit
further I wish there's other stuff as
well I would seek regard ourselves
opportunity for appeal and all this sort
of stuff that just makes it harder for
somebody else to gain access to us to
other than easier for us to tell if they
are in fact I checked they use the tools
against them it can be like just in men
the bloodhound you know anything like
that you know what they would be using
so use it first and then fix it like
this yeah the other concept as it
appears to be for people that I ran that
was talk against other things no I said
many things
there's a kind of thing that I was kind
of hoping people would laugh at I'm kind
of hoping that you wouldn't think I
didn't want it to be normal but yeah it
works it works okay that is pretty much
it thanks to some people and yes very
middle stone was my conflict of
interests which brings me to my actual
ending slide like dirt dissing
[Applause]
yeah I gotta say I like that enough
slide I did he write with quietly first
just to catch on that no I don't do any
questions from the audience
okay so we asked at the beginning I said
conversations with management like this
is the sort of thing you need this is
the kind of thing you need to enforce
with him that it was a lot easier to go
to the inland had already used those
houses case cases saying well this is
the things that we could because the
miserable things that they did and we've
already tried it but a present for
thinking teams and they found that it
was very useful to them but not very
hard to use so you see ourselves as
guinea pigs as much as possible there
was the way you say you can be
physically present with them after you
up a walk as saying if you look a
lot better
okay thank you very much
you