hello everyone
welcome to cactus con this is my first
time here
i'm really excited to be here in person
um
thank you for joining me for this
session of some api security api is
great it's nice we all like it we all
use it
but it has its pitfalls and we're going
to discuss that today
so
let's start with the quiz
what do all these logos have in common
i'm sure there are several answers but
um the one that i'm aiming at is that
all of those had
some sort of breach or vulnerability
exposed around apis
and this is only in the last year
maybe even less so
probably next year if i'm giving the
same lecture i will need smaller logos
who am i my name is erez i'm the head of
security research at checkmarks
i'm fascinated by information security
and application security in general
application security started as
something that is
very limited to code but these days
application security is much wider than
that we move from uh the code you write
to the code you use to dependencies open
source apis
uh containers everything that is cloud
and even supply chains so we need to
move forward and this is to me it's
fascinating
i'm a software developer
um
originally
but
i realized that i'm better at breaking
things than actually building them so i
did this transition
i'm a strong believer in spreading
security awareness this is one of the
reasons i'm here i lead os projects
including the api security project that
we're going to talk in depth about
during this talk
and i'm also the founder of the apsec
village in defcon
on top of all that i have a superpower
and this super power is the fact that i
see a lot of mistakes out there
through the projects and through
our customers
i see many many mistakes and the
mistakes giving us the
the secret power of
predicting the future
because the technology moves forward we
know that
security sometimes stay behind and then
we start to see the mistakes and the
problems accumulate
and we are definitely in a point where
a lot of problems and lack of
information comes around api and api
security
so what is an api
i'm not going to read you the entire
wikipedia
paragraph about that
but basically api we all know that it's
an interface or communication protocol
between a client and a server
and a client as a server can be
basically anything and if we look at the
simple graphic here
in the bottom of the slide we can see
that the apis are the glue or the
connections or the pipes between
different components
so we have component one talking to
component two and component four talking
to component one
and this
talking is done by apis
[Music]
so what is api security what are we
going to talk about
to understand what api security is i
want to discuss the question what uses
apis
so
basically everything really um
microservices and mobile and iot
um
cannot really survive without talking to
some sort of server
every b2b these days is using an
extensive uh list of apis um everything
that is serverless everything that is
cloud and also the very popular these
days single page applications
really everything uses apis and we
really love apis apis are great we love
them and they're very useful
and
every modern application basically uses
them so when i talk about api security
what i'm actually saying is the security
of api based apps
and
actually this is the modern application
security this is
where we are now there is no application
security without looking at api security
this is not something we can do anymore
we cannot ignore that part
of security
so i mentioned modern so let's let's
mention the differences between modern
and traditional applications
so
let's start with what is similar in
traditional applications
and in modern applications we have
a user
contacting some sort of client in the
past it used to be only
a web browser
these days it can be
iot mobile
smart toaster
bot whatever we don't really care and
the user doesn't really care how do you
interpret that
all the user want is the same in both
ways to get back the information they
are looking for
or
to do the activity they are expecting
this is similar
another similarity is the server that is
talking to a database
in the past we had an actual server
maybe even a server room
talking to a database these days the
server can be
an aggregation of
of microservices or whatever
also the database hopefully is no longer
the dreaded sql server but some sort of
elastic or i don't know sql but again
the similarity is the same the the
result is the same you get some sort of
information from the database to the
server
and here starts the the interesting part
the difference
in traditional application the client
would set a get request
the server would
do the logic part the understanding of
what's happening and
reply with a completely rendered html
page
these days it's not the same anymore
currently our client sends a series of
api get requests
and gets back
raw and sells with
parameters and information
the logic part
happens on the client
and this is
an interesting part of the difference so
we see less abstraction layers also and
we see that the client and server and
also database many times speak the same
json language we see that json is
what connects everything obviously we
can use something else but this is the
most popular one
so the differences we see are that the
server is used more as a proxy for data
the rendering component is the client
not the server
and the user state is usually maintained
and monitored by the client these are
all interesting things that we will
touch
a bit later
also we need to remember that clients
consume raw data this is the data that
comes directly from the server
more parameters are sent in each http
request we see
different parameters object ids and
values and filters
and everything is just sent raw
on
sometimes json sometimes something else
but
just flying through deal
and the last point is that apis expose
the underlying implementation of the
application and we will discuss that
also so what makes an api so vulnerable
why are we talking specifically about
the vulnerabilities of apis
first of all there's a lot of them every
endpoint of an api is an entrance point
everything makes
endpoints attack surface bigger
and if in the past we had users
that they have just one doorway in
component a here for example and they
had to do some sort of authentication
authorization and then move to component
bc
and to the data or assets
um now we have
maybe malicious users that are not going
through the the right order maybe they
find the component h that talks directly
to b
maybe they can talk directly to b
o to c
um they don't necessarily have to go
through the same
the same
process that happened in the past
another reason that apis are vulnerable
clients consume raw data and we discuss
that
more parameters are sent and
you don't always know where you send
your stuff to
to be more exact
you know where you send it to you don't
know what happened to that afterwards so
for example if we see here that
component one two and four are part of
some sort of
safe let's call it perimeter
um component one sends some information
to component two but what they don't
know is that component two will then
send it to component three
the other way is also relevant
component one is getting component two's
information and believes it's secure and
safe but what they don't know is that
component two got it from component
three actually
so this is a problem
and the last thing that makes apis
vulnerable is the flexibility of ci cd
yeah the flexibility is great it's
amazing
it's effortless
but
it really it takes just a few clicks to
spin up new apis you see hosts
and and completely
new sets of apis with just a click of a
button
and
it's almost too easy really we see that
all the time people are just
waking up in the morning deciding to
have a completely completely new set of
apis in the past you had to to work
through some problems now in 10 minutes
you can have that running and working
for you or against you
the rate of updates and changes in apis
it may be too fast to handle
and we see that apis become how to track
we see more and more shadow or orphan
it's the same thing
apis out there
and we find a lot of exposed apis that
no one really remembers what they are
who they are who actually spun them up
this is a problem
so let's stop for a second
i'm not trying to depress everyone this
is not all bad news in general
we see that traditional vulnerabilities
are becoming less common in api-based
applications
we see less sql injections due to
increasing use of frameworks or orms so
this is becoming
less and less of a problem i'm not
saying it's not a problem but it's less
common
um c surf again we see other other ways
of doing that instead of cookies so due
to authorization headers instead of
cookies this is getting better
path manipulations
cloud-based storage
is trying to solve that
there is path manipulation in cloud as
well we see that and we see abuse of
that but again this is less common and
less severe
and in general many other classic
security issues are being solved by
software as a service
so how do we bridge the gap how do we
bridge the gap between the security
knowledge that we had as let's call it
traditional application security
staff or engineers
and the new modern world
ruled by apis that we have around us
so
usually what i do when i have
some missing information i go to osp if
any of you don't know owasp
this is a good time to write it down and
look it up later consider it your
mandatory homework
osp is a great organization
that is
working very very hard on making
information accessible to everyone
the closest thing
i could i could see is the the os top 10
or stop 10 is something that um many
people know the only thing people know
about us
as many other projects as well
um
so we took a look at that this is the
one from 2017 when we had a discussion
um
so there is now a new one but basically
we took a look and said no this is not
this does not fit the model or the api
based
applications
so we decided to actually create
a new project
and by way i mean myself and
in onge
he now works at traceable
and we decided to bridge the gap with
this
new security project and this is where
we created the osp api security top 10
and
i'm going to
[Music]
explain to you each of every category
with some examples
so we can understand a little bit
how does the the ecosystem of api
security looks like
so um let's start with the one we just
shamelessly stole from the os top 10
injection and it's insufficient logging
and monitoring these are api eight and
ten
um
many asked us why we dropped it from a1
to a8 in our uh in our session in our um
in our model of api security
um first of all again this was 2017
um osp since then dropped it for two to
eight three four from the top ten itself
but
this is something that i already
mentioned
uh injection is number one because of
sql injections they are less common
because of olms and increasing use of
nosql
and
again i want to say that no sql
injections are a thing but usually not
as common or severe so we decided we
definitely want to keep it in the top 10
but
drop it down to number eight
regarding insufficient logging and
monitoring there is nothing special i
can say regarding
from from the api perspective
really attack attackers rely on lack of
monitoring and timely response
to achieve the goals so
this is something that
every application must have
some sort of logging and monitoring
again not related to apis whatsoever
this brings us to the most interesting
and problematic
category
which is access control access control
is by far
the biggest issue in api security and
the issue is so big that it actually got
its own slide
please remember that access control is
api securities biggest challenge
and
let me show you why
three of the top five
out of the top 10
are actually about access control we can
see
two items here api one and api 5 about
broken
authorization and one about broken
authentication
let's start going one by one
so we will start with a broken
authentication here
boken authentication can happen
because of two different uh
similarly different
reasons one of them is lack of
protection the other one is
misimplementation of that protection
so
for example here is a set of different
api endpoints
uh we can see login and login from from
mobile or forward password also we can
see an
api endpoint to update your location or
edit the photo
and we have
some general protection for that entire
set of apis
but what we need to remember that
everything that is around logging
must have its own
extra protection and by extra protection
i mean
capture
or
2fa or account lockout mechanism
basically anything that will avoid
brute force or credential stuffing or
password spraying
must be in them because if not you will
have broken authentication
the misimplementation part is
sometimes harder to catch because you do
have
a security mechanism
but sometimes you misimplement it for
example
we see a lot of engineers using
jwt for the security but then
readability support and algorithm
um that it called none basically you're
using jwt without any encryption
sometimes there is no validation of
authentication provider so we see
applications that are checking that they
got
an authenticated
user but they did not check where this
authentication came from
and sometimes we see passwords stored
without salts which is
yes you do store a password and you do
have a password mechanism but it's weak
so
many many many different uh different
ways to shoot your own foot
but
this is
something that is very very common
the reason it's common is that
authentication endpoints are exposed to
anyone by design we want them to be
exposed to user this is the purpose of
them
and we know that software and security
engineers have misconceptions
um we see all the time that api keys are
used for authentication and people are
confusing authorization and
authentication
this is a problem
not to mention the multiple ways you can
authenticate these days obviously the
authentication on an iot device would
not be the same as an authentication on
mobile it would definitely be different
than some legacy web
and god forbid the the infamous
deep links with credentials that goes
directly into assets of applications
moving on to the uh
to authorization so we have
a broken object level authorization
it also got the nickname uh ebola
when
your when your object level
authorization is okay
what you will see is a user
is asking for a specific asset their
asset
and then they get a response yeah okay
sure that's yours
if they ask for an asset of another user
they will get no that's not yours you're
not authorized to get that
if it's not if it's not working like
that it's very simple you have a
situation of broken object level
authorization
why is that common
you remember that that part
the attack surface is much wider
we can try and get these assets from
anywhere without being authorized
also there is no security solution that
exists that solves the problem there's
no
silver bullet it needs to be baked into
the logic
of creating the creation of the
application
and this is always something that is
unless
addressed from the beginning might be a
problem
um usually at that point some people are
moving in comfortably in their seats and
saying why are you calling ebola and not
idle
why did you have to change the name so i
will explain
we believe that um it's not really
accurate to use idol and the reason is
that the d in idol is means direct idol
is insecure direct object reference
we don't think the problem is the direct
part the directness
so idol implies that the object
reference should be indirect like a
salted hash map or random string for
every id
we don't think this is this should be
the mechanism we believe that the
problem is not the object reference but
it is the lack of authorization
theoretically
there is a situation where every user
will try to access any object
they need to be to go through some sort
of utilization
and not just hope that they will not
guess the name
of a specific asset
also what would happen if you ask your
developer to implement indirect
mechanism in every place that receives
id
i have
news for you it will not happen
hopefully not that violent but it will
not happen
so that was broken object level
authorization let's go to broken
function level authorization
while broken object level authorization
was what kind of object or asset you are
allowed
to touch
or access
broken function level authorization
is talking about what you are allowed to
do with that
so
um
in a in a way um when we look at
different apis they have
different levels of access
we can see a public api here for example
both an admin and regular user
can get a profile of a user this is
something that is public and it's okay
and they are both supposed to get an
okay with that
but when an admin goes to the admin api
and asked to delete a user now delete is
a different function it's not like
getting it
they should get an ok but when a regular
user uses the delete function
they're supposed to be told that they're
not
authorized to do that
if this mechanism does not work what you
have is broken function level
authorization
or buffalo in short if you want
why is it so common in apis so function
level authorization can be implemented
in different ways it can be implemented
in code configuration api gateways
infrastructure
really every place
in the chain can have that
implementation
we all know what happens when many
people are in charge of one specific
thing
who is doing that in the end
no one
and that happens a lot where everyone
thinks that someone else will make sure
that
this is done but
eventually it does not
also it's easier to detect and exploit
when we're talking about apis the
endpoints are predictable and i want to
show you how predictable they are
so in traditional
in the traditional days let's call it
uh to get a user's profile you would use
some sort of get request
and
through some sort of user's view with
the user id
the deletion of a user would probably be
through
um
some sort of cumbersome admin panel or
user management
page
every everyone had their own way of
doing that and this is how it looked
like these days with apis
this is how it looks like
you want to get the profile of a user or
you want to delete it this is really the
same you just change the function
so
in the in the past harder to predict
and now very very easy to predict you
just it's so easy that it's it's
completely automatic these days when
you're having uh penetration tools um
they're just switching the function and
you get everything
let's see how it looks like in real life
access control in real life so this is
something
from several months ago um
my my team in in checkmarks we found api
vulnerabilities disclosed by researchers
this is us
you can see the
you can find it
online also
we basically managed to take over
coursera api
because of access control issues and to
and to hijack the accounts
um
when i say hijack an account or get
access to assets it can be
files or private things but it can be
everything or anything
for example
this one another thing that our group
did more than a year ago
um
we found an api issue with a smart
vacuum cleaner that also had a camera on
the smart vacuum cleaner
basically the assets that we managed to
get there are
that
we managed to get video streams
from the camera of the vacuum cleaner
and location
basically everything the name and
address of the users
you need to remember access control is
everything if you don't have access
control this is pretty much game over
for your application
moving on
you still have still have the strength
needed for for a few more
okay moving on to excess data
access data
has two different categories in it
excessive data exposure and mass
assignment
these are actually
um one of one in the opposite
of
i mean they're the opposite of each
other and let's see how
so this is bob bob is using uh the super
safe app
and the reason he's using it is because
he's sure that
his information is safe
and
the users can only see his name role in
hobby
and this is the only thing that bob does
want to share and
um
he believes that this is the situation
but when someone
is actually looking at what happens
behind the scenes there's the mobile
phone
run by api you see the mobile phone
sends a get for to get bob's profile and
they get this they get this json
and in the json you can see that
not only the picture and the name and
the role and the hobbies are here but
also the address
so the fact that you don't see it on the
application does not mean it was not
sent
to the application
and what we see is many applications
that are filtering sensitive data on the
client
and this is always a bad idea always
there is
zero reasons to use that
why is it so common again so rest
standards encourage developers to
implement apis in a generic way
we see all the time
generic functions like to json yeah just
take the entire user object
make to json and send it somewhere
this is very very easy to json to string
all these functions
um
sometimes we do that without thinking
who is the consumer of that specific
information or who is the consumer in
the next step
if we send it to someone that's supposed
to get it that's fine but maybe the next
step is not fine anymore this is
something that is very very hard to
follow
and this is bob's case in real life how
many here are uh using three fun
okay i don't expect anyone to admit
if you don't know what refund is is
basically a matchmaking
tinder style application for people who
believe that
two is not enough
this is probably the best way i can say
that
and
a researcher called alex lomas
from pentest partners
it's an old one but i i like to show
that every time so
um he found exactly that he saw that
information that is coming from uh from
the servers to the application
does not only have
um
you know the loud photos and the name
and the and and all the public
information but also
um sensitive information like phone
numbers
uh exact location
um
pictures that are not public etc so this
is exactly how it looks like in real
life
obviously alex lomas did the responsible
thing and mapped it around the white
house
[Music]
that made a lot of noise back then
but yeah this is exactly how it looks
like when you filter things on the
client side and believe that things are
safe
api six is the other way around is the
mass assignment when you get information
that is not completely
vetted
so modern frameworks encourage
developers to use mass assignment
functions
very very similar to the way they
encourage us to
to spill and leak our information they
also encourage us to get them for
example this is how it's how simple it
is to to create a new user
in ojs or rail you just take
the entire body from the request
throw it into a new object and that it
you have a user congratulations
the problem is that this thing might
contain sensitive parameters that a user
should not have access to
an example again by bob
may look like that
so if bob sends a post request for a new
user well his username is bob and the
password is one two three four five six
um this is legit this is okay
but what if bob is not using the client
but using some other tool to send the
post
and it has not only his username and
password maybe you can try something
else how about adding a role admin for
example
that might work if there is well it will
work if there is no mechanism checking
that checking what you're getting if
you're using the code on the left bob is
now an admin on your system
and we see that much more than we want
to
so this is the access data part
the last part
the last category is the category that
we did not find a name for so we called
it devops or devsecops or
general things
lack of resources and rate limiting
security misconfigurations and improper
assets management
lack of resources and rate limiting i
think it's quite self-explanatory when a
resource and it can be anything
really anything that we're using
files and memory and cpu
access to database whatever
when it is exposed to the web
there should be a defined use limit
um
if it's a request then a numbered
frequency and of course in files it's
the size or string it's the length of
them
but we must remember that and not only
because of the reason
of denial of service the nerve service
is something that we all talk about with
rate limiting
but we should not
forget again
the access control the brute force
attacks brute force attacks if there is
no lack of resources
um
there's no rate limiting
um boot force can happen very easily
with credential stuffing and password
spam spraying and whatever
security misconfigurations this is uh
this is where things got wild and we
actually cheated we just took a big
bucket of bad things
and put it under one security
misconfiguration the funny part is that
um the os top 10 the original one not
the api one actually added
misconfiguration also as a category so
uh we really like our bucket of bad
things now
um it includes everything it includes
weak encryption it includes unnecessary
exposed http methods it
includes everything that should be false
but is true or should be true but is
false
csrf protections
detailed errors calls
you name it there are so many things
like that
um
and checklists out there that we need to
keep an eye on
these are very very relevant in our
modern api
environment
and the last one the last one is my
my favorite and least favorite together
i don't know how it happened but
this is improper assets management
important asset management
is a housekeeping issue sometimes it's
not a vulnerability by itself
but some but most of the times if you
have an improper asset management this
is the source of all evil
in your api security it can be one of
two different
but similar again housekeeping issues
either lack of documentation
this is an example from from real life
just the name of the
the name of the target is is
is different we found a payment api of a
company
everyone could easily say what does
version 2 download transactions as pdf
is
they have a very good documentation of
that another one was version 2 transfer
money
and then we found version 0 legacy b2b
export all users
no one knew what it is no one knew what
it's about
export from where to whom
no idea
this is a bad thing to have open in your
system
another side is the exposed
risky apis when you not only forget them
but you
forget to cover them one can be
the reason of the other so this is
another
true target
again not the right name
and they were very happy because they
used
api gateway
it worked very very well
for the payments api and for the mobile
api
but it worked well only on those they
remembered to cover because someone
forgot somewhere along the way to cover
beta api
and this entire set of apis were totally
exposed
you can imagine also that if a beta api
is exposed there are some shortcuts
there that should definitely not exist
on apis and definitely not open to the
public
we really see a lot of those
this is common because of the simplicity
of ci cd and
again i
i try and explain to people that there
is such a thing as too fast i mean
sometimes too fast is not
the best way also developers are focused
on delivering and not documenting i
believe that documentation was my
the thing i hate this most hated most in
in my job as a developer
developers like to deliver they like to
build not to develop not to document
and it shows
and
really with cloud and deployment
automation it's so easy to spin up new
apis and
we have api's hosts that have been
forgotten
complete environments that have been
forgotten and this is something that
you can know just by
walking in an open space of a
of a company of developers and hearing
in the in the air someone yelling what
the heck is a qa3 old apcom or something
like that
and
we do hear that sometimes if you do it's
a red flag
so that was the top 10
i hope it was not too much
i want to summarize some stuff for you
to to take home with you
so
i hope i showed you that modern api
based apps are different than the
traditional ones
i hope i managed to convince you that
being different they have their own
security issues
and they should be treated as those the
attack surface is much wider this is
something we need to remember we know
that instinctively but we need to
remember it actively everything we add
makes our attack surface wider
there is more data moving between
components we don't always have control
on this data we don't always know where
it came from or what the purpose of it
this is something that we need to
remember while we are writing our code
and access control is a real challenge
don't forget that
thank you
questions
yes please
yeah so uh
your examples seem to be taken from rest
and i'm wondering what the top 10
ranking is equivalent for
odata or soap
okay so yeah the reason that
the examples are around rust is because
this is the most popular one and it was
almost the the only one when we wrote
that
top ten
we're actually starting to work on a new
version
uh hopefully
it will include graphql and others
um so you can expect that towards um
probably middle or towards the end of
the year
the ideas are the same but you are
completely right there are some changes
that are relevant
for different types of
api
technology
we have a running microphone
so i've seen a lot of
other apis out there like swagger's a
new one that i've started to see out
there to where people just pull down
this you know whole you know api and
line that into an application
makes me nervous right because all of a
sudden we're starting to trust other
libraries other examples other apis are
there some apis that are good more
intrinsic or is it literally just how
it's used as an api like should we just
not be trusting some of these you know
kind of pre-built modules that we
download from github
if someone that knows me will hear these
questions one after the other they would
think i actually implanted them
because another topic we're discussing
now is not only the way that we treat
apis with our information
but also the way that we trust other
apis exactly what you say and i think
that we need to make that extra step
this transition of
let's take a similarity from open source
open source has a lot of dependencies
and again it's great it's good amazing
we love it it makes everything fast
sounds like api right but then sometimes
we have
problems
specific packages are problematic and
supply chain etc the same with api
suddenly you might find that a specific
api you trusted is not as trusted as
it's supposed to be
or maybe it's even malicious or maybe
they just themselves did not care about
security so this is definitely
another new front for the api top ten
this is definitely something we need to
take care of because
the trust issue here
is is getting problematic
more questions
okay so if anyone still uh wants to chat
i'm here for the next couple of hours
just walking around
question from uh questions online cool
is there a tool out there that we can
find out those exposed apis that are
forgotten
i think there are many different tools
i'm not going to name any specific ones
there are different tools that are
trying to find automatically
your apis
i think that the best way is to do it
not totally automatic but do it in a way
that is
you know smart in a way that will you're
looking things in in areas that you may
have forgotten them and things like that
also you can you can
try to look at the
at other
other tools like osp zap which is
open source
and others but the outputs out there
okay i'm not sure i really answered the
last one or just dance around it but
okay yeah there's someone typing
something potentially someone typing
that's what it says
he's holding everyone hostages
i guess i do have a follow-on question
if you were to design
an api model or
it's extremely broad how how do you
design secure api this is
probably a topic for a book or
or a phd
but i think that awareness is is the the
main thing i
i need to push here just to understand
what might go wrong and understand
the parts that are a bit squeaky and not
completely secured
and keep
again access control keep it in mind
from the get-go
and making sure that you document
everything that you have
very clear protocols of spinning up a
new api very very clear protocols of
deprecating ones
if you don't use something remove it if
you have a version that is not in use
remove it
that is that just awareness
okay they never they never finish it up
okay so thank you everyone i appreciate
you coming here
be safe
thank you
yeah i
have to
this is exactly what the talk is all
about
so when they say okay you need