all right how about now coming through
okay
thumbs up all right good deal all right
thank you all for being here um my name
is andy applebaum i am going to be
presenting on building and defending a
machine learning classifier
this is really just my experiences in
the machine learning security evasion
competition in 2021 i took third and of
course i have the
meme up there because i had to
um a quick outline
just about me i am a security researcher
i primarily focus on the intersection of
security and ai i previously was with
mitre where i did a lot of stuff with
the attack framework caldera threatened
form defense things like that
personally i am a an avid chess player
um i love playing chess and if you ever
see me on my phone i'm probably just
playing chess uh this presentation is as
i said my experiences in the 2021 ml set
up competition
um it includes two segments uh building
a classifier used in the sec in in the
competition and also attacking other
people's classifiers
in the competition and it also includes
a lot of like lessons learned and kind
of side observations that hopefully for
others who are looking to kind of get
into machine learning and security might
be useful
this slide deck is also accompanied by
some open source code it's available
online really the defensive stuff i did
the model i built the data all sorts of
stuff to kind of hit the ground running
if you wanted to run with this on your
own as well as a white paper and another
talk at a separate conference called
camless where i focus primarily on the
defensive aspect
as one disclaimer this is was a side
project for me it was fun it was solely
a personal project so it was very much
me saying hey i want to dive into
something get better at it learn about
it um
so it it really is
if it seems a little rough around the
edges in some places
that's my excuse
as a big motivation for this talk there
is the 2021 mls competition or machine
learning security evasion competition
this was a public competition that's
been run i think
three years so far 2021 2020 and 2019
put on by a few companies on really
trying to let people build and attack
machine learning based malware
classifiers
and there's two tracks as part of the
competition there's the defend track
where you submit a classifier designed
to detect malware and the attack track
where they give you hey here here are 50
malware samples make them evade
everybody's classifiers
and as a personal project my goal here
was to just submit something to the
defender track i thought it'd be fun it
would be good to learn it would be i
don't know a good experience and it
didn't have to do well i just wanted it
to get in
just for the sake of saying like hey i
did it
so with that with that said i wanted to
give a little bit of kind of
introduction in background you know why
is there such a very specific
competition
and i i think it almost goes entirely
without saying that machine learning has
made a lot of hard problems tractable
between you know natural language
processing computer vision game playing
all sorts of stuff
the advancements are kind of through the
roof
and this includes security this you know
machine learning has been applied across
a wide variety of domains you know
malware classification guessing
passwords intrusion detection and it's
something that isn't just in academia
it's an industry too
um this is a an old chart from 2019 i've
just i found some blog of like look at
these companies they all use machine
learning or they say to excuse me they
say too
probably even more now
and really at the end of the day most
security nowadays you know there's
usually some sort of ai or machine
learning story you know when
you're reading a blog post or a vendor
thing you know it's you often find the
two mentioned with each other
and for mlsec we're really looking at
applying machine learning towards static
malware detection really looking at in
this case pe files you know windows
executables
and
there's two and this is a gross over
simplification and i apologize but
there's two ways to look at static kind
of malware detection there's signature
based where we're looking at like known
indicators
like md5 strings things like that this
is super quick it's reliable low false
positive
but it struggles with new with new
malware you'll often miss things if it
doesn't fit into the iocs that you have
by contrast there's you know what i'd
what i'd say like heuristic based
detection
where you find similarities between a
given file and a set of like known bad
files and that's where machine learning
comes in because you can start doing
that pattern recognition
and this is great because you can detect
new malware with with higher accuracy
but of course has some drawbacks where
you've got to have like training data it
can be a little slow and accuracy can be
hit or miss
and there's been a ton of work applying
machine learning to static malware
detection
two kind of popular models i'm going to
talk a decent bit about are ember on the
left this is a specific machine learning
model and a set of
data that some researchers published a
few years ago a lot of folks use it for
benchmarking and then malcon is another
machine learning framework but they use
a neural network to detect malware i
mean both are studied a lot kind of
within this this realm of literature
now if you just go off of the news and i
don't want to say hype but if you just
read about you know machine learning in
in in the news
it'll sound like it's it's a silver
bullet and for a variety of reasons
machine learning is not a silver bullet
you can't just slap machine learning
onto something and say i solved it i'm
done
you know there there's a lot of things
you got to do and
one of the issues with machine learning
is something called adversarial examples
this idea kind of came around with this
paper in 2013 where they realized that
i might have a machine learning
classifier that has really high accuracy
but what i can do is i can look at that
classifier and kind of modify things in
ways that are imperceptible to humans
you know normally
but really throw off the machine
learning algorithm entirely i know it's
small but these these pictures on the
bottom are an example here where we
start with the image on the left
add a little bit of noise in the middle
that
you know as humans we we don't see that
and you get the image on the right and
you know to us it's the same but to a
machine learning classifier you know
this image here or let's go with this
one here the dog
you know it says yes this is a dog you
had some noise and now over here it says
it's an ostrich
and so it turns out that this is a
relatively big problem within this this
kind of um
the machine learning ecosystem
adversarial examples are a problem that
started really as like hey
neural nets that's that's kind of where
they're coming from but really most
machine learning algorithms have some
sort of story to tell with adversarial
ai adversarial examples where you can
take you know a normal a thing that
would be normally classified by a
classifier and add some noise to it and
all of a sudden everything's off
and this includes security there's been
some papers in the past few years which
say like hey i'm going to go build this
machine learning classifier for a
specific kind of malware
and
it'll work great but then i'm going to
know take what i know about that
classifier and
find a way to create malware that
specifically gets bio
and there's a lot of paper well not a
lot but there's a decent amount of
papers in the literature that that talk
about different ways to do this this has
been applied to android malware pdf
malware windows executables you know
it's been applied to a variety of things
and
it's it seemed to be like a pressing
thing that the community should worry
about
which
when in in that context well yeah a
competition makes sense because what we
can do is you know yeah there's all this
buzz about security and ml lots of
research let's put a competition out
there to join the two and really advance
the state of the art
so i apologize i know that's a mouthful
um
so i'm going to switch gears a little
bit and talk about actually
participating in the competition
i'm going to be talking about something
called kipple which is the name i gave
to my um defender submission my
detection kind of
machine learning algorithm
i'm going to say kipple a lot i
apologize it's i don't know if anyone
gets the reference it's really obscure
all right so to
as kind of a preamble to talking about
how i built kipple the machine learning
the ml set competition it had kind of
four main phases there's the
registration phase the defender phase
where you build the classifier the
attacker phase where people attack the
classifiers and then kind of the the
announcement of winners and
for the defender track we had about five
weeks to build a classifier the
organizers provided an example in docker
that you can just kind of download off
of github you just run it and proof
you've got a malware classifier
and they did have a few entry
restrictions saying like hey you need to
meet these specific guidelines to be
eligible
in the competition one of them was it
needs to take less than five seconds to
classify a sample
it also needs less than ten percent of a
false negative rate so it needs to be be
able to actually spot malware but it
also needs less than one percent false
positive rate which means that it's not
just saying like hey everything is
malware so you can't evade it
and the winning model is the one that
had the least evasions the one that was
able to detect the most
so the approach i took to build uh
kipple was kind of five steps relatively
straightforward first i was going to
obtain or i did obtain a set of normal
malware just kind of going off of some
public um
repositories then using that normal
malware i built a set of anti-ml malware
kind of taking the normal malware
modifying it specifically to evade a
classifier
i then trained an initial model kind of
for baselining a little bit
only on the original malware to see how
well
you know we could detect things just
kind of out of the box
i then trained a whole bunch of models
on
different sets and combinations of the
original and adversarial malware to see
what approach might work best
and then combine the different models
together and chose the one that worked
best
so to walk through this in more detail
step one getting the malware
there are a few different sources i
looked to
the first was something called the ember
data set this is freely available online
this is
the feature vectors you know it's not
the the raw malware or the raw you know
binaries but the feature representation
of
one million different pe files broken
into
malware benign and whether or not you
know they didn't know
and um
this formed you know the basis for a lot
of the training data and some of the
test data i used
then i also was able to get random
malware from virus share
um this was actually rate limited when i
was downloading um
which was
it was like once one for every 15
seconds or something and i wasn't
working with a lot of hard drive space
for a variety of reasons
and
i only got about 7 600 when just kind of
letting it run all day and all night
there's another malware set um you know
actual binaries for called sorel
this one's freely available online as
well i was also downloading this one you
know hard drive limited and not a little
bit rate limited it's like about 32 000
samples there
i also needed some examples of benign
binaries and for that i just looked on
my own computer and got about 2500 which
were just random things accumulated over
15 years
and then as part of the ml set
competition proper they gave us two uh
some example data 150 um
normal malware instances and about 600
or
adversarial instances that were
you know submitted as part of the
attacker track
in the mlc 2019 competition
so okay i have a bunch of malware and
now i want to generate adversarial mail
where i've got the normal stuff and i
want to j i want to take that normal
stuff and make it anti-ml
and for that i followed um or i used
three different approaches
the first two used specific libraries
that are both you know open source
available online that are adversarial ai
focused so these are able to take in
windows malware and modify them
specifically to be evasive
the first is malware rl which makes
small changes chaining them together to
take a um
a piece of malware make it a veda
classifier
and the other is secondml malware which
makes a little bit bigger changes and
both have a very heavy like adversarial
ml focus
the other approach i took was to
generate new malware and for this i just
generated
lots of different versions of
meterpreter more or less and just having
it compiled to a pe file
and varying a ton of the different
options including like
throwing extra code in there for the fun
of it
and as i mentioned all of these are open
source they're available online um
they're all out there and in total i
generated about 131 000 different
malware samples spread across three
different categories the first being
looking at the sorel data i downloaded
and converting those into different
adversarial samples
same thing for the virus share and then
using msf venom so got a nice kind of
wide set of different data here
another thing i did was i've got all
that training data now i'm going to
generate some test data to make sure
that my approach is
useful right i can't you know build an
algorith build a classifier on some data
and then test it on that data because
it'll obviously know
that the the training data is you know
what what the labels are
and there are three sets here the first
was the one included as part of the
mlset competition
this is just 544 example
adversarial malware instances
the second was taking some of the mlsec
examples those 150 that they gave us and
using malware rl on them
that generated a nice small set of 1400
then the third kind of the same idea but
using sec ml malware and that i
generated you know 746.
so i got a nice little set of training
data and what i can do is look at that
and um or use that to validate that that
these different classifiers i build are
actually useful
and a few lessons learned in case
anyone's looking to try any of this on
their own
the first is to
make sure you have a lot of disk space i
initially built this on a small linux vm
on my personal pc it was less than 30
gigabytes that i allocated this was a
huge mistake um and it came as a problem
in downloading models samples anything
and even generating new data i
constantly was resizing my vm and
eventually made it to 300 gigabytes and
and
that worked well but it would have saved
me time and heartache to just start
there
and also just dedicate enough time if
you're going to do this when downloading
samples if you are rate limited it takes
time
and when you're generating new samples
that takes time as well so often time i
would just like leave things running
overnight and i'd have multiple things
running at once and this is on a
personal pc
at home my power bill was through the
roof and
looking back i should have just done
stuff in the cloud so i wasn't paying
dominion power as much money as i ended
up paying them
all right
so step number three building an initial
model and for this i really just
followed that the the basic kind of
baseline goal not gold standard but
standard of using ember
and i just followed the normal ember
model training code set the false
positive threshold to one percent as per
the guidelines of the competition
and ran the results and overall it did
fairly well
a few blips here and there but just kind
of taking ember off the shelf and
training it running it i got some decent
results you know on on the normal
malware
that said when looking at the
adversarial malware the malware designed
to evade a classifier
things weren't as nice
first it struggled with the 2019
adversarial data and the
malware rl and gamma samples when
applied to sorel you can see the 90 you
know the mid 90s that we had before
those are jumping down to the high 50s
you know these are pretty easily getting
by ember
we do see though that it can detect some
of the adversarial attacks off the shelf
um dos header manipulation and and the
two padding attacks that i had
i also noticed that um the virus share
variants over here
those were um easier to detect for ember
than the sorel variants just kind of
overall this was likely because there
was some mixing of the data there
and then the msf ones all the different
you know interpreter variants they uh
ember struggled with those big time even
more so than with the adversarial ml
ones which was i always think it's
interesting when interpreter can't be
detected
and a few lessons learned the first
thing was
if you are looking to get into this a
basic model is reasonably accurate
ember by itself on the normal malware
did a good job and
as a side project it was fun just kind
of downloading stuff off the shelf
hitting play and all of a sudden i've
got a malware classifier so it was nice
um also if you're doing this make sure
to keep good records i ended up doing a
lot of different things and
not taking good notes and forgetting
what i had tried and what i didn't try
and all sorts of different stuff that
i'm
not going to get into
and then also make sure to separate your
training and your testing data just
because as you saw with a little bit of
the virus share stuff
it was um
some cross-pollination there
and so yeah just make sure to track
where your data is coming from and make
sure to generate test data that's
different than your trained data um i've
got a little bit more on that in the
white paper but it was interesting
finding some of the results that i got
all right so we've got we've got uh
normal malware adversarial malware we've
got the initial model and now i want to
build some advanced models
and the first idea here is to just use
something called adversarial retraining
and the idea is well i'm going to take
the
you know the the amber idea and just
retrain it to include those hundred and
thirty thousand malware samples that i
generated right i'm going to retrain it
including those
and when you do that it does pretty well
it's a straightforward idea just use
those pop them in there and
we see a good performance boost and when
you compare it against the initial model
on the left the retrained model on the
right
what you can see is when it comes to
just looking at normal malicious these
two right here
normal malicious malware samples
ember does a little bit better than the
retrain model but overall they're kind
of in the same ballpark but on the
adversarial side we're going from
50s and 70s to 70s and 80s we're doing
much better just using retraining so
this was nice to see as well just
because it was like hey this is clearly
better than using ember i'm already
beating that that baseline and if i
submitted that to the competition i
would feel good about myself
but i don't want to stop there i wanted
to kind of do more advanced things to or
at least try to
and the idea i had was okay i'm going to
build a set of different variations of
what i want to train and what i want to
test on
and
the first idea was i want to follow one
of two paradigms kind of dictating what
i want to distinguish between
one of them
called all i i wanted to distinguish
between normal pe files and the
adversarial
um adversarially modified pe files and
so when i say normal i mean
both benign and malware the idea being
that
anti-mlpes those might be
distinguishable in and of themselves
which is a little bit out there but it
was one thing to test and then benign
which is i'm going to train specific
models looking at benign pes versus
adversarial pes
and then underneath that as well i had
lots of different ideas on
what different types of adversarial
samples i wanted to train against
four ideas in total one of them was to
just train against everything i called
that adversarial one of them was
variants which was just the anti-ml
pe files that are generated you know
malware rl and secamel malware
msf which was the msf venom ones and
undetected which was effectively the msf
venom instances that were particularly
evasive
so
that's eight different combinations and
of course i'm going to produce an eye
chart
i'm not going to go through these in all
detail aside from saying that
variants performed the best
just kind of across the board it was
clear that that model was was doing a
good job over here on detecting the
adversarial malware not so good over
here but did a good job
the msf models didn't do well much at
all
training on on ms on kind of these
interpreter variants it didn't really
seem to help
the benign case outperformed all i'm not
going to get into that too much
and the undetected case that was a
little bit reversed and again i'm not
going to get into that too much but
there's a bit of
interesting internals when you look at
the training data that was used between
these different models
so okay i've got a million models now
and i'm going to choose the best
combination and
basically the idea was i'm going to
choose up to three models find
thresholds for each to ensure i hit one
percent false positive rate and then
compare performance
and unsurprisingly another eye chart a
couple of quick things i'd say is
a few of the models
initial retrained and
the
adversarial along with initial those did
well on normal malware
but struggled on adversarial malware
the
models trained on
the meterpreter
uh
the interpreter instances
those did did well overall but for you
know relatively speaking they they
really weren't you know particularly
stand out
and then these models that were a mix of
variants and undetected all these
different combinations those seem to
shine the most doing the best on
adversarial malware while also doing
decently on
normal malware itself and again i
apologize i know it's an eye chart it's
going to skip to the chase which was
that i ended up choosing this row
somewhat randomly um
it's not the best i don't know why i
chose it but i chose it
and that's what i ended up submitting as
my as kipple i also did a few things to
make it a little bit stronger i
hard-coded the md5 hashes of the benign
wear that i was using just so i i
lowered my false positive
i also used something that was called a
stateful detection mechanism this was
given free to me it was something
included by the mlsac organizers the
idea behind it was whenever a new sample
comes in as benign
or a new sample comes in we run the
classifier on it if the classifier
thinks it's benign we're going to
compare it against the last you know x
number of submissions and if and if any
of those are malware and it looks like
them we're going to classify it as
malicious the idea being that if an
adversary is trying to kind of push the
classifier in one direction it can pick
up on that
after all that um about a day before the
deadline i got it in and i was super
happy
okay let's switch over to
the attacker track now and talk about
how i tried to defend my classifier by
attacking the others this was never my
intention walking into it i just ended
up
committing so much time to it that i
figured i'd invest more
as a quick disclaimer some of the
details here are missing this was kind
of ad hoc as i was doing it so
some things are embellished some of the
numbers aren't exactly right but
generally the i
idea is there
so to give a little bit of context right
when the um attacker track kicked off
there were a total of six entries into
the defender track it was kipple and
five others
and right off the bat in the first few
weeks kipple was doing great the other
models all had hits against them kippel
was basically picking up everything so i
was super happy
a couple weeks or maybe a week later uh
two models start catching up one called
am square amsqr and another one called
secret um
the other three are really far behind
but you know kipple's ahead and i'm like
okay this is good
then a little bit later um the other two
models continue catching up and it
occurs to me that at this rate kipple
isn't going to do you know it's not
going to get in the top two which is
where i was hoping to get but you know i
wanted to get there um
so i think well maybe i'm going to need
to actually do something on the attacker
track
and to provide a little bit of
background the way um
the way the attacker track worked was
specifically around scoring
basically the mlsec organizers they
provided 50 malware samples labeled 1-50
attackers can either do one of two
things they can query one or more of the
target models that they're interested in
to see what the label is or they can
submit an attack
the query is quick it's unlimited you
just kind of throw it out they get a
result back real quickly piece of cake
the attack is much more in depth that's
kind of like saying yes i want you to
count this specifically as a submission
and they actually detonate it in a
sandbox to make sure that you haven't
done that that it actually works and
this one's you know limited to about 50
an hour or so
and the way scoring works is that
attackers get a point by creating a
working variant that evades um
that evades a classifier so if i if i
submit a working variant of zero zero
one and it evades all six classifiers i
get six points
there is however one a maximum of one
point per classifier per sample so
there's a maximum attacker score of 300
they also must be functional and they
they need to adhere to a couple of rules
that i'm not going to go into aside from
that they're smaller than two megabytes
and then tie breaks are broken by the
number of queries and attacks so if i'm
querying you know five million times
against the classifiers i'm gonna lose
on tie breaks versus someone who queries
you know five times
on the defenders side things are a
little bit different you'll effectively
lose a point if an attacker is able to
evade the classifier for a given sample
however unlike the attacker track
there's no limit to the number of points
you can lose so if i submit 0 0 1
variant a and then variant b against
kipple and both of them evade i'm going
to lose two points for that versus on
the attacker's side you're only going to
get one point because it only counts for
one sample
so
with that in mind i thought well maybe
the best way to make kipple better is to
go on offense if i can submit variance
of of the different samples that kipple
detects but the others don't detect i'm
going to relatively increase the score
of kipple
this is silly in a kind of gaming the
system but
it's a contest it's fun
so
i said i'm going to give this a shot and
go to the drawing board there's two ways
to look at evasion one of them is
traditional evasion you know av evasion
fully undetectable we want to take you
know a file get it out there obfuscators
crypters packers all that fun stuff
the other is adversarial ml anti-ml
evasion things like adversarial examples
malware rl secondary malware
and having invested as much time as i
did in anti-ml i decided that this would
be best and number one i think
adversarial ml is fun i i hope to convey
that in this talk as well um
i also have the infrastructure in place
for anti-ml i've got malware rl i've got
second male malware got a bunch of other
stuff kipple also should detect the
anti-ml attacks
um
and then also i think traditional
obfuscation is harder i'm not very
experienced in this domain and i don't
have good infrastructure my linux vm
isn't a great um
av obfuscation testbed
and i'm also not sure if kipple can even
detect traditional obfuscation
so i decided to go with anti-ml and
just as a brief interlude i'm going to
talk about something called miter atlas
how many people are familiar with attack
miter attack
a lot of people
has anyone else seen miter atlas
okay so i'm going to show a little bit
about miter atlas because i think atlas
is cool it's a framework it's available
atlas.mitre.org
but as you might guess with my preamble
it is an attack-like framework for
adversarial ai attacks i'm taking that
that same you know matrix idea you know
attacker's perspective that kind of
stuff and applying it to adversarial ml
some of the things that i like about
atlas in particular and again i'm just
speaking for myself number one it
includes the full life cycle of
adversarial attacks um it's not just
limited to evasion and adversarial
examples i bring this up as i'm not
doing it nearly enough justice this idea
of anti-ml atlas does a better job
it's also broken into tactics and
techniques like the attack framework
written largely from the attacker's
perspective so as i'm looking at the
competition i'm going to go conduct an
attack i can consult atlas for
constructing the ttps i want to use
it's also backed up with public examples
from case studies and reports that are
contributed by the community to get a
little bit of examples of how to do some
of these attacks
and then it's attack-like and if you
wanted to integrate it with with some of
the other kind of attack ecosystem of
models it's it's not that hard
so with that said i had kind of a step
attack workflow the first was and again
i'm using kind of the atlas notation
aml.t0016
i was going to obtain adver obtain
capabilities you know getting some
adversarial ml stuff you know kind of
locally
i already did this um i've got malware
rl i've got second ml malware i'm good
to go
number two aml
t0040 ml model inference api access
this one's kind of provided by the
competition they've set up an api and i
can query it to access
these two target models that i'm
specifically focused on
then uh ml attack staging i'm going to
use replicate ml model the idea is that
i'm going to throw a bunch of data at
amsquare and kip amsquare in secret the
two models that are kind of giving me
grief on the scoreboard and i'm going to
query them a bunch and based on the
results of those queries i'm going to
train a model that i think can replicate
what they detect
and then i'm gonna do attack staging
adversarial um
craft adversarial data black box
transfer the idea is that i'm gonna i've
got this replicated model i'm gonna
construct a bunch of stuff locally see
if it bypasses my replicated model and
then if it does
let me get to the last one impact evade
ml model i'm going to submit those that
get by i'm also going to kind of put
guardrails for myself so that when i do
submit an attack against the target
models
um i try to guarantee that it will be
detected by kipple so i don't end up
hurting myself right i want to do that
relative and balance
just real quickly one of the nice things
about having a matrix is you can
visualize it we've got this nice little
workflow of resource development ml
model access attack staging and then
impact so again if you haven't checked
out atlas atlas.mirror.org it's a lot of
fun
all right
so profiling the competition um what i
did is you know this is the
ml model inference api access along with
replicate ml model here i submitted some
benign and adversarial samples to the
two target models that i was worried
about
these were just taken from kipple's
training data so the same data i was
talking before
i
submitted roughly 20 000 things in total
all of the benign wear all 2500 and then
a lot of malware rl
and some of the second ml malware data
as well
and you can look at the results and you
can kind of see the the accuracy over
here um they both do well on malware rl
and gamma or which is second ml malware
but what's interesting is that they both
kind of take a little bit of a hit with
the benign wear secret in particular um
misclassifies 60 of the benign wear that
i submitted as malware so it was very
sensitive to anything being thrown at it
um definitely not one percent right
there
um
so i got all those labels and what i did
is i just trained another ember like
model just following those labels
and you know basically saying if amp
square or a secret they classified a
file as benign regardless of the truth
assign it to label zero otherwise one
and then i use the same parameters as
kipple effectively just kind of building
a model that looks like what i'm trying
to evade
then to submit the attack i just ran
malware rl and second ml malware on
those 50 samples i need to make evasive
and i generate a random variance
i then
made sure that the following two
conditions hold that it evades the
replicated model that i have but it's
also detected by kipple again not to
hurt myself
and then each hour
more or less
submit a set of 50 of these samples that
are supposed to evade the target
classifier
and this is um
just a few notes
i did rely on a lot of um scripted
processes there were a lot of
submissions
um i did not i used a black box attack
against the local model which is not the
way you should do this you should use
something a little bit better
and
i should also just note that this
approach this entire workflow
is fun in the context of a competition
but is unrealistic for what a real
adversary might do
so how did it work and again please take
numbers with a grain of salt i had about
1600 different submissions as a tax um
about half of those weren't functional
or were duplicates so they didn't count
they were thrown out right away they got
detonated
not not good enough but the other half
were eligible for scoring
and i got a bunch of results to see how
how i did and when you look at the three
middle columns these are the three
models i wasn't too concerned about you
can see we've got a good success rate
evading them even though that wasn't my
goal um it was you know we can get 500
170 290 right was able to get a lot of
good points against these um wasn't the
goal but you know hey nice benefit
against am square though
only get 49 evasions out of 761 and and
that's really not a lot and not nearly
as much as i was hoping to have gotten
from running this attack
against kippel a little bit of friendly
fire um five of the ones i submitted got
by it just because of some bad practices
on my end i won't talk about them but
secret got nothing um
couldn't get it to
misclassify anything um it was just
nope it was able to detect everything i
threw at it and so okay
i apologize for the graphics but that
didn't work um
i was able to get a few points off of
amsquare but nothing on secret and i've
got about maybe a week week and a half
left in in the competition
i'm
committed at this point so i want to try
something so what else can i do well
what if i look at you know different
different individual instances i can see
here this is a chart of
how many evasions per sample there were
and you can see some samples were easy
to get by some of the classifiers
and some were a lot harder to get by the
classifiers
and if we focus specifically on am
square we can see that samples 2 and 18
we most of the 49 that got by it were
those two individual samples it was
struggling with those for whatever
reason
and so i thought maybe i could just
focus on these two generate a bunch of
ones make them really evasive
but really this is only going to slowly
generate points versus this one model so
it's not quite what i'd like to do
okay so that's not going to work too
well what about going back to atlas and
seeing you know what other ttps can we
use
i'd say okay obtain capabilities maybe i
can get a new attack type i'm going to
find a different framework to use a
different anti-ml framework and and see
if this works there's something called
map malware this uses this is kind of
similar to malware rl it's an rl a
reinforcement learning-based framework
to sequence actions together to evade a
specific classifier it's open source
available online um
dockerized2 was very easy just download
run get working
and it's conceptually similar to malware
rl it's got a very similar action space
a little bit different um but it's
really got that reinforcement learning
you download it
point it in the direction of something
and you just let it run and and and it
works
so i get it i swap out the included
model for that replicated model i had
maybe this this capability will be
stronger than the other two i'm using
initially it was able to easily evade
the model i gave it but all of the pe
files it generated were like
massive so it was just like a pending a
bunch of stuff and eventually it was
able to evade the classifier but you
know i had a restriction of two
megabytes
so
i modified it say okay now you can only
do less than two megabytes and still got
some
some evasive files out of it i got 51
valid submissions that i was able to to
throw out there but none of them really
got by only two bypass am square and
again secret didn't work
okay so no progress versus the existing
capabilities um
and again i'm invested so all right
going back to the drawing board
miter atlas what else can i do here um
got maybe a week a little bit more a
little bit less left in the competition
okay what about something fun like
reconnaissance right it sounds silly but
maybe i can use reconnaissance
and
looking at the scoreboard you can see
we've got these two columns here i know
it's a little small but i've got the
author i've got the model name
so the first one um you can see fm by
something or other it it's a random
string that's nothing i can't use that
secret is the name of a model but secret
is probably secret because they're
hiding it that's what i thought
so that one's out
a1 that's too generic don't think i can
use that but am square well what about
that and so
i go to google throw an am square and
bam i get a personal web page and a
github repository and i think this is
wonderful i can look through and see if
there's some adversarial ml or some you
know ml stuff on there for malware
maybe point me in the right direction of
what i need to do
but unfortunately there was nothing
about malware so
that didn't work
but
i wasn't quite done yet
the competition had a public slack
channel and you can see on september
10th a little bit before the deadline
for the attacker track
the admin posted the current scoreboard
and i noticed little thumbs up there
mouseover and i got a name and on a whim
i throw the name into google
i know this is this is crazy
this is crazy i i if you ever invest in
something
you just go down the rabbit hole
but i throw the name in there and i get
a bunch of hits i get a twitter a
scholar and a github and i get that
fabricio is an author at something
called secret which
turns out
to
oh skipping ahead a little bit an
academic research lab secret isn't like
we're hiding the my model name that's
the name of the lab they focus on you
know security and ml stuff and they won
the 2020 ammo set competition wrote a
paper about it that's freely available
have a blog post about what they did in
and have access to their model their
classifier online that i can go to and
just check out
but it gets better that's not it no
in the blog post they've got the code
for their 2020 model on their not the
data but the code
they got how they won 2020 and they got
the dropper that they used in 2020
and finally i'd found what i've been
looking for i think this is going to be
great and after a day or two i kind of
give up
um
my time was too short i needed more data
to replicate their model changing my
infrastructure
and even if i replicated it i didn't
think malware rl and second ml malware
would be enough to get by it
the dropper that they gave looked really
promising but i couldn't get it to work
on my linux vm
and admittedly i'm not big on i i'm very
much at the depths of my knowledge here
and
was getting kind of tired and frustrated
just giving up
just a little bit but not entirely
that did give me some ideas of okay
maybe i can find something easier to use
under traditional evasion so let's focus
on traditional evasion i went on github
looking for all sorts of just open
source crypters packers droppers setting
just a threshold of if i can't get this
to work right away i'm just gonna gonna
give up
and unfortunately most i couldn't i
either couldn't get to work and those
that i could get to work either produced
output that
wasn't a valid pe file it didn't run
uh or it didn't evade secret or amscore
so it wasn't actually helping
and working or not many of the files
that were outputted actually bypassed
kipple just because this was one of the
huge shortcuttings of kippel was it had
no knowledge of traditional evasion
that said um one package did stick out
to me call or one one program called
dark armor this is a windows avpe
evasion tool it's open source it's
python based so i can run it in my linux
vm
really really easy to use give it an
input pe file it's going to spit out a
new one with the original encrypted
and the new pe gonna
execute the old one in memory piece of
cake and best of all is i can get it to
run and it works
it's actually able to consistently evade
all six of the classifiers
and not only that what i can do is i
take the output from dark armor which is
evasive to everybody including kipple
i then run it through malware rl one or
two times
not to really make it evasive but to
make it signatureable by kibble because
kipple is able to pick up anything going
through malware rl and now the output
from the tool is able to get by
secret while being detected by kipple
again this is a contest i'm gaming the
system just a little bit
bad news though um the pe executes but
it
there's something wrong with the payload
and it doesn't actually execute the
payload so the file executes but
something's going wrong and i try a
billion options and eventually look at
the github issues and find out
everybody else was having the same
problems as well they couldn't get this
to run but i wasn't just ready to get up
i to give up i was trying one one more
thing i'm going to get this to work i'm
going to use donut and pizzor i'm going
to use donut it's open source i'm going
to convert my pe file to shell code i'm
going to throw that into pe zor and
encrypt it a little bit again open
source freely available and i i invest a
lot of time making this work and
everything and it can evade all
classifiers like dark armor apply
malware rl couple detects it but
doesn't work
and at this point i i get on to
you know
slack i reach out to the author he's
going to help me a little bit and time's
up
i invested way too much into that
attacker track my initial thing was i'm
just going to throw a little bit into it
and you can see i got very carried away
so okay so i ran out of time i did have
a lot of fun doing that but
you know ultimately couldn't get any of
those other attacks to work
so what ended up happening what were the
results um i know the title of my talk
gave it away but still going to walk
through it
walking through you can see secret took
first place they had 162 bypasses they
were the lowest
am square took second with 193
and kippel a convincing third with 231
and the other three models all in
between
on the attacker side the results are
pretty similar um more competitors
definitely than the defender's side but
secret took first they did
a you know a great job 196 bypasses they
got out of 300 but they only used 600
api queries which was pretty low
am square took a second with 167 and a
moderate amount of api queries and
me
um you can see me i'm our wch yes a
modest 55
000 api queries
um as i said i got a little invested all
right
all right
so doing a little bit of critical
analysis of you know what happened you
know a little bit of retrospective
because of course you know i'm curious
well number one
kipple had a really low false positive
rate i
there's more in if you're interested in
the paper and the other material on how
i went about the false positive rate but
it was a little
overly rigorous there
but number two kipple still missed a lot
of the malware rl style attacks if you
just let malware rl run
it'll eventually get by kippel just
acting randomly and the reinforcement
learning map malware that other
capability it relatively handily was
able to bypass kipple without too much
difficulty
but number three which i think was
probably the most important for why the
scores were so high is
you know it kippel just lacked knowledge
of the traditional non-ml evasion
techniques crypter's packers you know a
lot of the normal off-the-shelf stuff
was enough to get by it without without
too much of a
hurdle
on the attacker side i think the
attacker idea that i was following using
atlas walking through those steps it had
merit but overall had mixed results
and this is a few for a few reasons um
after the fact
amsquare ended up publishing a a little
white paper on on what they did
for both tracks and in their defensive
model they also used an ensemble
approach a variety of methods
they used
gradient boosted decision trees just
like kipple did but also neural networks
and the fun one um some rules that that
they threw in there for anomaly
detection
and from a data perspective they use
normal ember and sorel so a lot of data
um you know sorrell i only used 32 000
and i think
there's 20 million in that entire data
set so a lot a lot of training data
but probably more importantly they used
a stateful defense which compared the
incoming samples to the previously
classified ones so me throwing a
bajillion things out there
didn't really help because it's if one
of those gets classified as malware the
others are going to look like it too
and and and that along with those rules
for anomaly detection i think that's
where i ended up getting getting hung up
um being unable to evade m square
reasonably reliably
secret they also put it right up out
there um
and i was surprised they they're they're
um
maybe i misread it but their model
didn't seem too intense it was a random
forest with some custom feature
extraction
um nothing to to too heavy there but
then from a training perspective they
only use the ember data which isn't much
along with 50 normal malware samples
from the 2020 competition which again
isn't a whole lot but
they acknowledge that they have a very
high false positive rate and they even
put that little graph in there showing
that when it came to the competition
entry
what the what the organizers were doing
was they were looking at just windows
false positive identification kind of
the built-in utilities and it did and
their submission did great there but
they also looked at these other benign
wear sets where the false positive rates
up in the 80s so it was a very sensitive
model and because the organizers were
only looking at the blue box up here
they were able to meet that one percent
um classification rate
so a couple of just quick closing
thoughts um lessons learned takeaways
things like that if you do end up
wanting to get into this building your
own classifier a couple of points i'd
recommend
make sure you have enough space and you
dedicate enough time
it can be time consuming you can't do it
quickly and on a space budget but if you
really want to get into it and dive in
deep
make sure you've got both and also just
keep good records of everything you're
doing so you don't end up reinventing
the wheel or retrying stuff when you
don't need to
when you're attacking a classifier
i think atlas is a great way to reorient
or not reorient yourself but orient
yourself and kind of build an attack to
go back to the drawing board kind of
iterate that way
um it's a good way for me to at least
conceptualize what i was trying
and then reconnaissance can be fun and
you can go down a fun rabbit hole even
for adversarial ai
there's a reason it's included is that
little column there
also another takeaway i think
adversarial ml is a lot of fun there's
tons of free stuff out there if you want
to get into and want to get started
i think it's a great thing to get into
and the last takeaway is um contests can
be gamed a little bit and i am very
guilty of that
and then a couple of quick notes on
future work and discussion um
all these materials they will be
released if not already
this deck the code behind kipple it's
all out there on on github
i've also got on
on the github repository a bunch of
links
that are to others working in this space
doing a better job explaining it
my infinite free time which is
obviously not infinite but there's lots
of other things i'd like to do um the
biggest one was i really wanted to
measure the applicability of adversarial
ml on virus total to see what what if
things get by there
anecdotally it was hit or miss on on
some of those but
subjects for future work and just call
to action
if ml sex 2022 is happening i'd highly
recommend it it was obviously a lot of
fun
i hope that that comes out and it's good
to think about how security and ml
interact with each other
so with that i will thank you for
attending i think i've got a little bit
of time for questions reach me on
twitter and then
the code for kipple is available down
there
[Applause]
yep so so the the question was um
secret use custom features did i use any
custom features and no i used everything
entirely just from ember head away to
you know kind of a built-in extractor
for features and i just use that you
know keeping it very fair very simple
just curious when does the competition
get announced and how long do you have
to prepare for that before you know
you've got to have something submitted
i think they announced it in may
with the defender track because i was
looking at the calendar was announced on
june 16th that's when the defender track
opened and then it closed on july 23rd
so about five weeks is the amount for
the defender track
um regarding the
the ml evasion like the noi adding noise
to binaries what does what does that
type of
um
technique actually look like at like a
code assembly level in the binary
so like the ttp is used by like malware
rl
yeah
it's been a while like like adding
additional sections some code overlays
um flipping a few bits here and there
it's a lot of little small stuff but the
idea is like the little small stuff you
can chain it together
right into something bigger
and if we use reinforcement learning to
as an ai attack technique we can figure
out the sequences that are good
if that helps
yeah there are no other questions thank
you
[Applause]
oh