are we streaming now too oh dang i'm on
tv
okay
welcome everybody hello hello thank you
all for joining us here at the closing
ceremony for
cactuscon 10.
thank you for coming
[Applause]
as kind of uh indicated by the name here
this is our 10th uh
iteration of cactus con we started as a
b-sides phoenix and we have grown this
event a little bit over 10 years it's in
terms of total time we kind of switched
between summers or
winters type of thing and so you know 10
years approximately
this event is you know obviously near
and dear to my heart this is something
we created for the community and we're
just really thankful we could do it
especially at a time like this with a
pandemic
it's just been it's just been a crazy
year you guys have all been champions
helping make this happen and so kind of
first off thank you all for being here
and thank you all for your willingness
to kind of uh struggle through our work
through our covet policies and and
support us on this i really do
appreciate that so
um thank you for thank you for being
here
um as a bit of a logistical piece just
to kind of get um
things sort of started we have a bunch
of giveaways so we're kind of got some
items here that we're we're giving out
only to people here in person um if
you've come in through that door you
should have got a ticket uh from the
people in the back
and when you we're going to do some
giveaways at the end and you're going to
look for my wife who is somewhere here
where is my wife christine see the hand
raise that's her if it is your ticket uh
if it's your ticket go look go look for
her uh afterwards we have we have
giveaways we have some books um
specifically some actually signed books
by um alan liska's uh ransomware book
that just came out we have some stuff
from offensive security uh so like a 60
day voucher
and some stuff from sans and net wars
and there's like another book so
we do want to give these out this is
part of what the in-kind sponsors are
really about is helping put together
opportunities like this for people so
so stay tuned you too can win
cash prizes at an event like this
um
[Music]
this conference can't happen without
volunteers i know people look at me like
i've done a lot but i can tell you
especially this year i've done almost
nothing i'm very proud of myself for
that
i founded the event uh
10 years ago and i've spent i've spent
my dues as lead organizer and kind of
pretty face and then i got older and so
now it's a less pretty face
um
last couple of years ryan chapman has
stepped up and he's been our primary
organizer but due to
just a family life situation that that
is you know unfortunate and i hope he's
working through that ryan couldn't be
here today and so this is why i'm here
doing closing ceremony kind of last
minute putting this all together
otherwise you would be talking to to
ryan about all of this so
first off a special thanks to him
because because without that you know
leadership this really
this is a reflection of his work i told
him when he took over the job that the
good news is by the time you get to this
point it's going to happen one way or
the other right so there's no point in
freaking out you know and your job is
almost to like try to hold on to the
steering wheel a little bit to make sure
everything doesn't fall off and and for
the folks who know we've had a handful
of you know incidents that come up this
year and i think we've done a pretty
good job of navigating them but but
again thank you to ryan i'm really
really thankful for the work that he's
done um alex in the back he's gonna come
up and talk in a minute uh he is the
gentleman behind all of the discord all
the streaming all the video like this
guy's one one one stop shop for
everything he's been doing so much
behind the scenes to make this happen so
if you're listening in digitally and
you've been in discord and you've been
doing any of the interactions with all
of that that's all been alex and his
work in fact a lot of art as well for
this year and the the way that we've
done slides and put this together that's
that's been all alex too so
the work from him has been phenomenal
and so special thanks to alex uh for
that
uh jamie who is just up here i think
actually also with alex has been
managing all of our talks and
submissions and working on
the
board to review all of those so if
you've been a speaker here you've been a
part of what we've done jamie has has
been a big part of reviewing that and
leading it which is which is a huge
effort all on its own right i think a
lot of people don't sort of give that
credit but if you were here for this
last talk with the panel you kind of got
to see a little bit about the behind the
scenes pieces that jamie and her team
kind of go through to pick pick what
that means to be a high quality talk
here within the conference um haley here
on the front has been awesome for all
things digital media so if you like the
fact that the cactus con account
actually is active for more than like
five minutes in a year thank you to
haley like everything digital and
everything online has been has been
haley when we started you know there was
only three we started we had a pretty
big team but it was about three of us
trying to do almost all the same things
that these teams have been doing and so
you kind of pick and choose your battles
but having someone who can be more of a
community outreach media relations and
building that presence for us
honestly i think it's been fantastic and
so special special thanks to her
skyler jessica and myself we sit on the
board skyler in the back jessica is
dialing in from sunny san francisco and
i of course i'm here we sit on the board
we were all a part of the original group
who had the crazy idea to put this
conference together um skyler's still
active within the art scene so if you
like the
2022 art this is all brainchild of
skylar in fact every single year skyler
leads up the effort of finding the next
great artist and the next great theme
for what we're doing and so if you love
it and i think it's awesome uh you could
definitely thank skyler for all that um
jessica manages some of our online
pieces as well specifically around
eventbrite and the ticketing and making
sure registration and all that kind of
happens at a at a digital level um but
uh you know she's she's obviously
working uh from san francisco for this
mike who is here raise your hand mike
where are you buddy
mike here we go
mike handles all day of operations so
the last two days and managing all of
the stuff that that just needs to happen
i could tell you is one of the most
stressful jobs there is to have in the
conference
um so all the volunteers between him and
his brother matt
uh have really been managed organized
and
handled it from there so special thanks
obviously to mike and matt for all the
work that they do it's it's it's a lot
you know running the rooms making sure
the talks are going on time making sure
the speakers have what they need making
sure all the registration the whole the
whole kibbles and bits i mean that's
it's a lot right they also run the
villages so if you've been to any of the
villages this year this is a group that
manages and organizes that between the
two of them and so it's just again it's
such a big it takes a community to run
this event that's why i want to walk you
through and see like
all the people behind the scenes who
who've kind of made that happen
um eric os i don't know if he's still
here maybe eric
he helped design the badges and he's
been a big part of badge stuff for the
last several years here within cactus
con as i mentioned before we had a
hardware badge for this year and if you
can see it here on my my shiny
it was prototyped out we know what we
want to do
when we went to go order pipes it was
like a year wait time because of a ship
shortage everything we wanted to get was
just gone
and so
the good news is there's no risk in not
getting a badge for next year i think we
already know what we're doing so we've
got we've got that designed
so i think for the first time since i've
ever been at cactus con we're like we're
ahead on badges so congratulations us
um so that's cool and and that in this
of itself is like it's such a genius
thing the badges for the people who
haven't ever had one of these they're
like fully functional electronic boards
that do something and we try to make
them interesting and compelling that
even during the event you can actually
go we have a heatsink who we partner
with which is where eric is a part of
and his in his kind of crew they come
out and they actually show you how to
build these badges so if you don't know
anything about hardware hacking if you
don't know anything about this type of
tech and things of this sort that's okay
you don't have to we've actually had a
whole village for almost every single
year helping design and build and create
these like you know pieces one year we
had a passive reconnaissance network tap
that you could plug in and like pull
stuff right off the wire i mean a couple
years we've had
cool like digital communication types of
things and like every year they come up
with something and it's great so
that's kind of the core team right
behind the scenes on top of that we have
villages right so villages
these take individuals who have kind of
their own teams and manage specialty
pieces
so if you went to the lockpick village a
special thanks to drew i know i saw you
sneak in here somewhere
drew and his team put together lockpick
for this year
so thanks to you drew
phil is handling the radio ham radio
stuff and phil is a part of the core
team he's been a part for a long time
but i don't want to list him twice but
phil's been a part of this since the
beginning
he came in i i've heard a lot of people
playing with ham and they've got cool
ideas for coming in
next year where they want to kind of
take that to the next level and have
this as a permanent village here at
cactus con
um thank you to rachel
rachel ran the
career village we keep saying changing
the name of it what is it now interview
village
career village
so it's a hiring village
but not
it's a career
so it's a career village but not hiring
it's a hiring
it's all very clear
so uh i think it's a big opportunity i
think it's great i know a lot of people
who come to cactus con even the way that
we designed it from the beginning was to
give people their
first sort of foothold into this
industry that's what we wanted to do
with it and so we knew
you know arizona at the time and we had
a hundred people show up to the first
b-sides the diverse cactus con and we
knew that we needed to help people find
a way to get access to this information
and and part of it is is about job
building and career building and the
skill building that goes into it so
always been a big fan of that as
something we can do and i'm just
thankful that rachel was here to run
that village this year as well
um
barrett somewhere in here also here on
the side bear ran the capture the flag
for this year both in person and online
uh he's got a team of people behind them
they're going to come up you'll get to
talk with them in a little bit
but barrett's team is just awesome and
the work they've done is awesome we
actually started having a ctf here
because uh joe demessie who's not here
had another conference where he created
a ctf and he didn't he loved this etf he
didn't love building a conference and i
said i got a i got a room i could stick
you in and i'll manage everything else
and we've had a ctf ever since then
since i think actually
the second year we did we did cactus con
so
i'm excited that we've been able to
continue to push that forward and
continue to run capture the flags here
it's been it's been cool
um
a lot of volunteer leads uh this year so
russ uh handled all of registration if
you were here at all this year russ russ
has been a long time fan of cactus con i
always like to tell the story about russ
just uh real briefly
i met him on a drunken tirade in las
vegas
during defcon
we were trying to get back to hotels
from somewhere i don't even remember
from where
and i remember getting in like just a
shared taxi and i was telling him about
this conference and he was like yeah i'm
gonna come to your conference i'm gonna
be a part of it and like in my head i
was like i'm never seeing this dude like
ever again in my whole life like
i'm like sure sure buddy like i believe
you
and uh and i kid you not he showed up
the next year and he showed up every
year since then and now he runs our
registration so like
i mean what a what a crazy story so russ
russ has been he actually did you fly
here this year by yourself no
commercial yeah last year you flew here
though just two years ago this year
yeah
russ like literally
in his own like plane he like
that's commitment like i was
i didn't even want to drive here i got a
hotel room and i was like i'm gonna walk
so
that's something
uh emilio i don't know emilio but he
stepped up in a big way this year emilio
hi emilio uh we had we had a last-minute
change in terms of monitoring the rooms
and making sure the talks kind of went
off and emilio stepped up and ran all
that and so
we wanted to call call that out tim has
been a long time runner here and
volunteer cactus con runners just
literally run things and make sure
everything is happening that needs to
happen you know when you have an event
this big i'm sure you probably get tired
walking from place to place um and in
the same way like if we have to move
stuff you know back and forth throughout
the event these guys have done an
awesome job making sure that that works
and we can get that working there too
behind the scenes brandon p and jason
and caitlin have been helping with all
the stuff online for discord here in the
building so we have the discord stuff
last year we had everything digital so
we pre-recorded i think all the talks
and then we had live q a for everybody
behind the scenes and there was a team
behind it writing automation and bots
and getting discord working this year
because of a hybrid nature we were both
streaming things into the conference and
then out of the conference back out to
people in discord all kind of at the
same time and so the team behind it they
actually had members in each room making
sure that that was functioning and
working and managed correctly across
each group and they did a phenomenal job
i can't speak for the folks online but
as far as i've heard you know maybe a
handful of small problems but they work
through all of them and they work
through all of them really fast and so
like that experience is a big a big deal
for us as a conference and i wanted to
call that out specifically
last but not least
i want to thank the volunteers so all
the folks here
uh in aqua color green we'll go with
that aqua green
it's heather teal
sure we'll go with that
um
like i said it takes it takes a village
and some of it happens before the event
happens and a lot of it happens while
we're here and so uh with that i wanna i
know i've gone through like all these
people but a round of applause to all of
them i mean honestly
[Applause]
you know i just realized that the woman
telling me i need to hurry up in the
back
i didn't actually mention her name
but she is the magic that makes this all
happen
literally
and you could ask any one of the other
organizers and key people here that if
you want to attribute the success of
cactus con is surely not me but it's my
my wife in the back there christine
so
with with that i'll hurry up jeez
pushing me pushing me
yeah okay thanks to speakers of course
all we had a lot of speakers come in
this year we had three tracks that went
over the two the two days
we had workshops we had we had just a
plethora of things for you to be a part
of
but a special thanks to our keynotes uh
mary and charles i
didn't know how to say her name but then
she called me and she's like hey it's
mary and i was like yes i got it um and
so thank you to thank you to all them
for jumping in and helping out with this
i'm just we always try to bring in the
best in the industry and i think we've
done another great job this year
bringing in two of the brightest so if
you were part of those talks i i got to
listen to them both they sounded
fantastic the group the team is
fantastic and a special thanks to them
for kind of coming out here and being a
part of that as well
um
[Music]
next slide event partners so as i said
before like a million times uh this is a
community run event we're trying to get
everything together and this doesn't
happen without our partners our partners
are more than just people who give us
money they're people who actually have
contributed and jumped into the
conference in some kind of way shape and
form and actually help make this happen
like this conference you'll see as we
get to money it just doesn't happen
without the support of the local
community in both directions right and
so
special thanks to all of them booz allen
early warning zell and new genesis
solutions and then of course
sans this this conference is awesome and
i'm just so thankful to have you all
here
um before we give them an applause i
know booz allen actually has
a um
there we go booz allen has a
raffle to give away a prize for so why
don't you come up here and let's give
let's give that prize away and give them
a pause
[Applause]
all right hey everyone thank you so much
for cactuscon for having us come out and
appreciate seeing everybody come out by
the table um it was great to see
everybody in person in the last couple
years have been a little challenging
so we were we have apple airpods here
and the winner was vish anan
so fish gotta see a hand somewhere
all right
all right thanks everyone appreciate it
awesome
he's my partner
and then also i wanted to invite andy
jordan from uh new genesis solutions up
here just to talk a little bit
about uh his company and his experience
and things of that sort so
andrew india applause here as well
[Applause]
yeah
i get it thank you thank you so um
again this conference is a community and
i this is why it's important for me to
be a partner of it like i have grown in
my security career because of this
conference and so this is me wanting to
be part and to give back for it and i
will continue to be here for as long as
i'm ever able to be here because it's
important and i think there's so much to
it so
andrew did a fantastic job thanking
everybody here but that's really all i
wanted to do i don't want to talk about
new genesis i want to kind of celebrate
the relationships that we have here that
continue to grow and that continue to
invest in in this so thank you
[Applause]
we also have a handful of gold sponsors
sponsors are you know no less people
that we love of course we want to take
care of everyone who takes care of us
some of the sponsors like i said have
been here from the beginning bishop fox
has been a big part of cactus khan from
literally the first b-sides phoenix
stack and lou gave us you know a little
bit to help make that happen
paypal has been a long-term provider and
supporter of of this event and then axon
has been a repeat as well and we've got
a lot of new folks bechdel's here
they've come they've come back and forth
a couple times uh red canary secure
works blackberry and of course amazon
and i want to know who won that super
dope like neon
like cactus thing you won that damn
you're so lucky dude
like i saw that and i was like i i want
to give you my personal information like
please please choose me like that sounds
that's cool so anyway special thanks to
all of our sponsors like i said this
this conference is is a big deal um
equally we ask every year again there's
a free conference nobody has to pay to
come here and and it's through sort of
donations financial support of both like
people like who have companies but
individuals who uh have actually stepped
up so this is a list of literally every
community sponsor who's joined us here
this year this is just random people who
help donate money to the conference
even five dollars makes a big difference
uh and for the person who gave us one
dollar thank you very much for that as
well so thank you everybody
[Applause]
next on my list of thank yous
i'd like to thank the delta for our very
first year here at the delta last minute
as you can tell the delta is amazing as
one can tell
no we've been at the mesa convention
center for a long time now and in my
mind this is sort of uh going to be home
for a lot longer um we had some
circumstances which we're not going to
get into now or here but a little bit of
alcohol i could probably tell you more
about it
and with that the delta actually stepped
up and helped us as becoming the new
official headquarters of cactus con this
year for the last 24 hours so thank you
both to mesa thank you to the delta
and i i will say because i'm sure
there's an a whole group of them hiding
in the background but but these guys
here from the av company uh absolutely
absolutely amazing every problem we've
ever had with av like they solve it
they've been here working just as hard
if not harder than anybody else in terms
of the team so i want to especially call
out the av guys and give them a round of
applause because like
absolutely amazing
literally wouldn't happen without you
guys like seriously so
uh in terms of some statistics we had a
little bit over 500 people here uh over
the last two days which is actually
really exciting in the middle of a
pandemic you know you never know how
this will play out
i'm excited that we had this many people
willing to kind of work together in a
safe way to do this
we had about 360-ish people the first
day
and then we had i'm guessing about 200
so people
uh a little bit this day right and
between kind of those two adding in the
volunteers we we get to a little bit
over 500 in total attendance in person
but online we had 785 people jump online
to be a part of this which means this
conference is coming in just shy of
about 300 people which is like almost
almost the exact same numbers we've seen
the last couple of years which is like i
said absolutely amazing that people
would want to be a part of it and
continue to support it as we grow and
develop this as a community so thank you
for everybody who's here um we had a
little bit over 7 000 messages on
discord so a lot of interaction i think
when people think digital conference
they just feel like i'm going to look at
videos online and then like you know
trash talk on like some some channel but
like no the people are interacting
there's a live q a process there's
interaction with audience here and like
that technology and their ability to do
the hybrid that way is is amazing and
you can see that there's been a lot of
interaction digitally just as much as
there has been here in person and i
think that's awesome so definitely
thanks to all the folks who are dialed
in at home listening and into this we
had 43 help messages uh but i believe
one of them was a test message so we're
gonna go with officially 42 text help
messages
so if you were here last year
this year is the answer to last year's
problems i guess
so
with that what i want to invite up is
the capture the flag team and they're
going to give away
their stuff and talk a little bit about
the capture of the flag for this year so
round applause for these
guys hey everybody uh i'm pon eip
this is juicy k
knop researcher and mike who hacks
things uh we just wanted to come up we
were able to give out a lot of prizes
thanks to our sponsors we had quite a
few players online uh quite a bit uh in
the other room playing in person we
wanted to uh to have a little bit of
that that in person element with uh with
a scavenger hunt and a few things so we
got a few pictures prizes to give out
and then also announce who the winners
are
so we had a little bit of a fox hunt we
called it a bishop fox line we had two
wi-fi adapters i saw somebody walking
around with a huge antenna i hope you
found uh found the two aps that we had
out there we just snuck them one in the
bush here and then one underneath the uh
the vending machine
we had this really cool rubik's cube
challenge if you didn't see that mike
created that we had a qr code and you
had a scrambled up rubik's cube that you
had to solve and then once you solve
that you would knew you would know what
blocks on the qr code to color in and
then it would scan uh to be a flag that
one that was pretty cool
we had uh uh juicy here did this uh did
this qr
code sort of um like 10 stage scavenger
hunt uh we had we had them all over the
area here some riddles it was all based
off of the the matrix theme
hopefully uh hopefully some of you had a
good time looking at that
now um one thing that we did on purpose
is that we split the scoreboard between
virtual only attendees and uh and then
the folks that were in person uh the one
reason we did that is because we run
quite a few ctfs and we have a few uh
big hitting teams that i feel like all
they do is play cts because they come in
and just crush them uh they actually
cleared the scoreboard on day one
um and then we had the in-person one
with all the the in-person challenges to
make sure that it was still still
competitive i'm going to hand it off to
uh to knop here
we had almost 13 000 in prizes
juicy here is going to throw out so a
few more prizes that we have we had some
fantastic sponsors we had offset give us
i think the con in general gave us three
oscps
with uh with 30 days of lab we had
rosta mouse gave us an rto course along
with four of his c2
developer courses in c sharp uh sans
gave
he's
yeah
he uh he's in computers for a reason uh
we had a we had sans uh sponsor us with
a few
net worth continuous prizes hack the box
came in with tons tons of different uh
vip plus and pro labs um and who am i
missing
zero yeah i talked i talked about ross
mouse zero point five
so oh hack five and then hack five gave
us uh some gift cards to give out so for
us we love it because they give us stuff
we kind of feel like robin hood we get
all these great prizes and then giving
out to the folks especially all the
college students from asu and grand
canyon university they were there uh
they got hooked up with some prizes to
uh kind of better their their craft as
they as they entered the workforce so
without further ado i'll let uh knop um
announce who the winners were
sure so i before i do that like one of
the great things that we do is just like
we love the community right we love
seeing the players both you know like
what pony was talking about you know a
lot of the repeat players online virtual
but getting to know the teams and seeing
everyone come up and especially like
with the rubric cube might help so many
people and just having those inner
conversations and then you know it's
really awesome is like help those people
solve those challenges as i come along
and see them play so without further ado
i will open it up
so for the virtual side we'll go first
uh e-p-t took first place followed by
deja vu in second and then straw hacks
in third and all all three of those
teams cleared the board so that was uh
all virtual teams cleared every every
challenge
it was crazy did both only one team do
it on the first day
one team on the first day i believe but
yeah early on or on the second day they
were able to clear
so the in person though we had
first place subterranean satellite
second log for bear third hey marketers
uh
[Applause]
i don't know i always love just seeing
everyone in person just at the you know
hunched over the laptops uh just
cranking away at the computer there
hopefully you know getting breaks taking
uh taking it into the sites getting some
talks but online we had 306 registered
users 167 teams
uh 515 ip addresses 89 challenges uh for
in person you know we had the rubik's
cube we had the uh scavenger hunt a few
other things so we had 95 challenges uh
we had 138 in person
players with 43 teams and 225 ip
addresses
so
cut over for virtual so just the whole
top ten here for top nine that we got
here so you can see here
uh so the virtual
coming in fourth is cosmos followed by a
neutrino cannon
we've heard them before we figured their
place better but it was you know we're
glad they placed uh wolf packets
followed by
i don't even know how to pronounce that
russian
and then shadow brokers and thundercats
so
in person though this is kind of what i
what i enjoyed seeing everyone out here
so
a lot of good names
i appreciate that creativity
so again we just want to thank everyone
out there for coming out and playing we
want to thank cactuscon for having us uh
hopefully you know we can come back next
year and host another ctf so
uh this is i don't know kind of a
pilgrimage for all of us we enjoy coming
out here we enjoyed doing a virtual last
time we enjoyed doing this hybrid so
hopefully next time we're definitely
looking forward to coming back uh we
also want to thank a number of folks
that aren't here right now so we both uh
for the handling of the virtual boards
we had reihan and cone virus snipe
uh goshen
ash was here for a little bit she took
off uh and then of course you know our
sponsors again so thank you all for
having us really appreciate it thanks
for playing
in our grand tradition of giveaways i
want to invite rachel up to talk a
little bit about the career village
that's not hiring the hiring
hiring village it's not a career
a scavenger hunt
oh and helper and there's a helper so
yes
plot twist uh so
what's the difference between a career
village and a hiring village a hiring
village you can get a job um there's
definitely some of the volunteers knew
about jobs that kind of thing but we
were really focusing on the skills
process right
so we did mock interviews we reviewed
resumes we talked about career paths
those types of things and really honored
to have about
just close to two dozen volunteers that
spent either a couple of hours or you
know the whole day several people spent
two days we had a ceo come in and spend
two full days and give all of his time
to share his his knowledge so
awesome and we wanted to be sure to
uh thank everyone for making that leap
to come
out in in this condition that we're in
now uh and we did that with uh you know
these treasure hunts scavenger hunts and
we're giving away
two 100 gift cards we have our vanna
white here so
it's very very official if you're not
is
uh
thai man's sin
[Applause]
um and i'll actually i want to uh
so you might have noticed the helium
balloons we have i think three sets of
them in the back they're in a white bag
so if you have you know kids or family
please take those balloons with you
you're welcome to have them they'll last
probably a month so
a little entertainment there
all right so the thank you everyone
thanks for that of course grandpa's skin
i was gonna say in our grand tradition
of giveaways if someone left their water
bottle here
[Music]
you've got about 20 minutes before
someone gives it away also this really
interesting
buffalo trace
mask if this is yours
please feel free to collect it
afterwards we can
share it's kind of like i thought it was
lingerie for a second i was like what
what just happened here did i miss this
did we stream it
all right
so uh before we get to giveaways i
always like to talk about the money this
is a non-profit organization uh
you know it's an actual federally
government recognized
nonprofit
this year between actual sponsors
and the community again this is people
who just donated cash
um we were a little bit over ninety
thousand dollars in in that sort of
earnings i guess right donations
um so
you might ask yourself where does that
all go where do we do with ninety
thousand dollars because it seems it
seems like a lot
about half of it this year went into av
right to be able to stream and all of
the things that kind of come along with
managing the actual event and the
conference the largest portion of
spending was here
the next biggest one of course is the
venue the venue
we have to book it out several years
sort of in advance or we typically make
a contract to keep the dates that we
want to have
and the rest were split between things
like the swag the t-shirts the the
lanyards the masks all the things we
bought for the event
the art and the print is sort of a
portion of it here
there's an operational piece we've got
to pay to have people come out we've got
to help people who come in from out of
state this is a part of running a
conference and so we use this so we
could keep them here and give them kind
of that benefit of being a part of it
and invite them out
uh and then the last bit was legal and
accounting but
depending on how the next couple weeks
go that might that might be larger
so uh that leaves us with you know a
little bit over 16 ish thousand dollars
that sort of sits in the bank
that money actually goes directly into
next year's conference and so when we're
when we book the reservation we pay it
over the year uh so that the last thing
we do is we pay off the final balance at
the end of the event and so while it
looks like oh you know why do we have
all this money sitting around just
understand that's so we could do this in
a way that's responsible from a
corporate perspective when we first ran
the conference we did not figure that
out very well and so we were just
literally gambling salaries to determine
if we could get enough sponsors as we
would pay for the event ahead of time
anyways right so um
so we think we got that figured out
moving forward
um with that that's kind of the end of
our our closing ceremony we're going to
do our giveaways it sounds like uh
it sounds like christine disappeared so
i'd like to introduce you the new
christine
for for today's evening
i know
yeah we'll go by prize we'll start with
prize and we'll go from there
start with the book okay we're going to
start with the book only because it's
the only thing i have physically here
and so the person who has won the book
is
let go
ticket five three zero
eight four one eight
five three zero eight four one eight
let me see your
let's validate this here
yeah so we have a sans net wars uh
subscription it sounds like continuous
description
yeah so if you're into the sans networks
and you want to be a part of that we're
gonna give that away um that is not here
so you have to give your information to
to mike and we'll get a hold of you
after the conference to sort of give you
your your voucher as it was
and that is
530-8455
[Applause]
uh the next thing i'll do is i'll give
away one of the signed copies of
alan liska's ransomware book and that
will go to
530-8407
yeah
ransomware
[Applause]
oh sorry sorry my bad
not bad
all right uh we'll do the offensive
security pwk 60-day voucher
next so if this is you
you would be
530-8447
that's 530-8447
[Applause]
okay next up
i got four more copies of the
autographed book here and so five three
zero
eight four seven three
[Applause]
five three zero eight four five two
it's not you skylar
last call five three zero eighty four
fifty two
going once
going twice you fail okay
five three zero eight four four four
[Applause]
all right i'm gonna pull both of the
books at the same time so you can see
that i am not
picking people
okay
five three zero for both of them
84 68 and 84 70.
are you 68 or 70.
68 that's you
and 70. perfect
[Applause]
okay
so with that the last thing we do in
cactus con closing as our time-honored
tradition
is this is your chance to ask us
questions and uh and get answers usually
what i'd like to ask you first and
foremost is
what what did we miss right we try every
year to improve we're trying every year
to continue to offer interesting things
to people i mean obviously with the
pandemic we had to make some concessions
we do plan on reintroducing cactus con
kids as soon as the pandemic allows we
are looking to have the hardware badges
and hardware hacking next year but but
apart from that like what would you say
you want to add any features questions
comments about cactus con now is your
your last chance before
we drink
which means you're holding up
come on you don't have to be
can you save us from the digital
armageddon probably not i don't think we
can stop that from happening
that is a great question what our dates
are for next year um if my wife was
still here she probably knows
we're working with the convention center
to get those solidified i'll say that
typically we'll know within the next
couple weeks after the conference last
year was an interesting one like we knew
we knew the first two because we had
those reservations but because of the
pandemic we moved our contract we had a
three-year contract out
but i think we're currently negotiating
it'll be around the same time of year
for next year that's what we're shooting
for is to continue to be in this like
february march time frame i know that's
tough you had to choose between us and
the renaissance festival
uh
that's right now so
that will explain where at least a
hundred or so of the people were
yeah
but i mean why not both right why not
both
any other questions about
the conference
yeah i like that idea
all right
okay so the great thing about the
conference being at the delta
is that uh we have the conference room
uh until midnight tonight and so if
you're staying here at the delta or
you're in the area we're planning on
doing kind of a little bit just hanging
out there and figuring out food you can
get booze right from the hotel and then
walk them over and then we'll figure out
how to eat after that right some
combination
yeah we'll figure it out we'll get food
i mean
we'll probably figure out the food
before we drink
i don't know something like that so
starlight lounge that's probably we're
going to go hang out for for the
miranda it's calling it starlight line i
think it is called the starlight lounge
oh room the starlight lounge sounds
pretty
good it's not a nightclub yet yeah it
could be
i mean if we're streaming the bikini
lingerie thing going on
so cool all right with that thank you
guys of course
you