bring tonight a small consulting
practice too
and this talk isn't the most technical
talk right it absolutely isn't but we're
going to talk about something that to me
is kind of important and i'm going to
take a second to talk about why that's
important and i've spoken at a lot of
conferences i spoke here uh probably
about five years ago i spent the last
couple years outside of washington dc
we're now back in arizona
but what happened was a buddy of mine
this is a last summer a buddy of mine
came to me and i've never spent in any
talk i've ever done i've never spent
like the first two minutes talking about
why i made a talk i just kind of get up
here and start talking and go right into
it but this time's a little bit
different so a buddy of mine came to me
he works for a um an agency that i will
not name and what happened is he
messaged me and he's like hey i want to
talk to you about a wireless issue i
have
to see if you can help me with that i'm
like yeah no let's talk and i had an
idea of what it might be and then when
he actually when we got together and we
talked i was actually like dead wrong
right he was something completely
different
and what it was was
he had a confidential informant someone
who was working with a very very
dangerous very very dangerous group that
i think everyone in here agreed is a bad
group
and he was meeting with this informant
and then leaving and going back to his
job back to his normal life
and he was worried about being followed
from meeting with his informant and he
seriously he did not care about his own
health he thought like no i can protect
myself he was worried about his
informant he was worried that if someone
followed him after meeting his informant
figured out where he worked
that now it would go very very poorly
for that informant right he was worried
about the informant's physical safety
and he had heard me years ago speak
about wireless and talk about the
concept of using wireless to help tell
if you were being followed and so he's
like yeah so he went to his agency's
technical people and said do you have
anything like this and they said no
and so now he's reaching out to me do
you know of anything like this and i'm
like no but i'm like you know what this
is actually kind of a cool little
project and so i'll work on it i said if
you don't mind it's
may take me like a month or two to knock
this out because it's going to be my
free time but i'll start trying to work
for it and try to figure something out
and so
that's where this talk is coming from
and so before i'm like as i'm working on
it i'm like wow this kind of my this
might make an interesting conference
talk and then the next thought is okay
number one would anyone care right would
it be relevant would anyone care would
it be interesting and i thought yeah i
met that bar
and now the next bar was kind of a
depressing one the next bar was could it
potentially be used to do any harm right
anytime you start talking about wireless
you start thinking about invading
people's privacy right you start
thinking about like stalking and things
like that and stalking is horrible right
it just kind of ruins people's life when
it's going on and this is where the
depressing part came and i realized that
number one the way this was designed
that no it really couldn't be used like
that it was only designed to try to tell
if you were being followed and the
second part is damn this is last summer
this is a little bit before like the
apple air tag and now an iphone kind of
tells you if there's an air tag that's
been following you around
but this is before that and when you
start looking at the amount of apps
designed to spy on people and follow
them and tracking devices on cars versus
the amount that's out there that's
trying to detect
when someone gets so desperate they're
coming to my butt to try to help them
out with this problem you start
realizing that yeah i think this is
worth talking about there because we
need more things like that you know the
iphone trying to let you know if there's
an air tag following you was a great
start but at least like hey let's start
throwing some stuff out in here and see
what ideas we can kind of come up with
and that's where this talk is coming out
of
so plenty about that we're going to talk
about the methodology
about the hardware about the software
and then a few issues that i ran into i
was doing it and how i figured out a way
to solve them not saying it's the best
way saying it was the way that kind of
my mind worked and it seemed to work
so this is a technical conference right
so if i sit here and say sdr
you know we all think of like
software-defined radio right i was just
down in the vendor hall we had like a
nice little radio display right there in
the radio village very very cool
but anyone who's kind of maybe a little
more old school or involved in
tradecraft and certain things like that
right you think surveillance detection
route right and it's just as basic
sometimes as like switching lanes and
seeing if anyone else behind you
switches lanes right can be getting off
the highway
and then getting back on the highway
right and telling who got off with you
who got off right and that's you know i
kind of chose this uh
this map for this because anyone who's
kind of lived in that world and spent
any time in washington dc you realize
the beltway is set up to be one giant
surveillance detection route right there
is no denying it it's just the way that
it's set up
and so my buddy he knows this tradecraft
he knows this tradecraft frankly better
than i do but he was looking for
something a little more technical right
kind of like a more technical method to
help him out and method man if by some
miracle you ever see this i am so sorry
for using a picture of you where you
look so soft right like i just wanted
something with his name on it like all
the respect in the world i know this
isn't the best pick but it had your name
on it so i'm sorry he did a fox sitcom
called methane and red with red man some
of this he brought on himself
so
one option to kind of figure out and try
to accomplish this
is to look for persistent digital
signatures and this is what i mean by
that
go to starbucks and grab a drink
go hit a gas station top off the gas
tank now go to a bookstore if you can
find one post up for a few minutes read
a magazine and then take a look and see
what digital signals that i see at all
three locations right if i saw a device
at all three of those locations
could be an indication that potentially
i'm being followed and this is kind of
the the methodology that he had heard me
speak about years ago he just couldn't
find anything that actually implemented
it and his technical people for his
agency couldn't either and like i said
i'm like shoot i'll give it a try right
let's do it
so what we're going to do is accomplish
this by passively detecting wireless and
bluetooth devices that we observe around
us 100 passive this doesn't do anything
to try to connect to them try to follow
them nothing like that at all 100
passive there are some things we could
do that are close to passive that
honestly wouldn't probably get us in
trouble or detected but i wanted to keep
this 100 passive
the devices could be part of an active
network connection you know we have a
lot of now vehicles that are giving out
wireless and so people's devices will be
connecting to that so we need to look at
that but we also need to be looking out
for vehicles that are not part of an
active connection but are therefore
looking for an active connection or
they're looking for networks that
they've connected to historically
so hardware right keep it cheap stuff
that probably a lot of us have sitting
around anyway and it started off for me
with a raspberry pi because i have a
closet full of raspberry pies for some
reason right there's like two of them
that i actually used but i had two
raspberry pi 3s that are like still in a
box you know never been touched i'm like
sweet here we go so i made a one for him
and one for me just kind of testing him
out certain things like that so once
again this is hardware and it's not the
only thing you could usually use a
beaglebone or a lot of other type of
stuff too but this is what i had
available for free a lot of us probably
have alpha wi-fi cards or other quality
wi-fi cards available for two when i
started working on this project and i
had like six seven alphas probably but i
went to the kismet the wireless software
we're going to talk about in a second
they run a very very good discord server
i went to the kismet discord center and
i asked them like hey what is in
everyone's opinion kind of the best card
out there and it was fairly universal
for this model right here you see the
awso36
very very good 2.4 5 gig and 5 gigahertz
both very very good range
the form factor honestly isn't my
favorite i like the old style better but
it comes with like a 3 foot usb
extension cord so it actually makes it
far more usable so it doesn't have to be
like sticking right out of the side if
you don't want it to be
for a power source since this was
designed to be used in a vehicle
honestly i could have just gone
cigarette lighter but i wanted to make
it a little more portable than that kind
of you'll see like self-contained when
it looks like a tangled mess and a
little pelican case but it's a uh just
like a little anchor battery pack and
now i switched to a more powerful
battery pack a a cheap little battery
pack that i had just like a normal
anchor like probably even smaller than
this will power up with the pi with the
wi-fi for i think it was just under
eight hours so it was like seven hours
and 50 minutes then i got another more
uh beefy or battery pack and it'll power
it for about 24 hours
the one thing that i didn't have that i
had to buy was a screen like a little
screen for my pie and they have a bunch
of different form factors right they
have like seven inch screens they have a
tiny little ones like this i just got
the tiny little one with the case i
think it was like 22 23 off amazon
i put the screen on installed the
drivers on the pi screen worked great it
was perfect then i started testing it
and like an hour or two later i noticed
wait a second i'm not seeing bluetooth
anymore
i tried to troubleshoot it yeah you know
what blew the image away reinstalled the
image bluetooth works now great went
through everything installed the drivers
for the screen and now it killed the
bluetooth and so i realized that the
drivers for this screen were actually
killing the bluetooth i googled it was
like a well-known issue and no one
seemed to have a fix for it so at that
point i'm like well i can try to
troubleshoot this or i can spend like
three dollars on amazon for a little
bluetooth usb adapter and just solve
this problem so yeah big surprise which
way i went right so this worked fine
with the pi and it added in the
bluetooth capabilities and saved me from
linux troubleshooting because ain't no
one got time for all that
all right so that was kind of the
hardware side of it what about the
software side all completely free all
open source right and what it starts and
it ends with kismet if you played with
wireless before kismet is fantastic you
know the new version is even quite a bit
better than the old version if you
haven't you're interested in wireless
it's a great place to start totally free
open source does a ton of great stuff it
can try to detect wireless attacks tries
to automatically capture like handshakes
from wpk certain things like that it uh
it can try to detect drones which is
kind of limited because a lot of the
newer ones right they don't use like the
you know the new dgis and stuff don't
use wi-fi anymore they use kind of a
little custom protocol but it has all of
these really really amazing features and
it's not just wi-fi or bluetooth it's
zigbee it's sdr it's all this and i'm
using like none of the cool features
it's such amazing software and i'm using
none what i'm using is the fact that by
default everything it's sniffing
everything it's detecting and it's all
completely passive it's all writing it
down to a sqlite database the file
extension is a dot kismet file but it's
actually a sqlite database
you can have it generate pcaps and other
things as well there's uh there's
actually no need to because if you're
trying to do that on the fly live as
you're capturing it's more
computationally expensive right it's
more horsepower to try to be capturing
in that format and if you capture it in
the sqlite database it does such a good
job at capturing that that you can
actually take and generate a pcap from
that after the fact so there's really
like i said you can just kind of capture
the sqlite database and then if you need
to
do anything else off of that
everything else is just python or shell
scripts right it really is and you can
see my shoddy python code i made the
github live yesterday it's i'm not a
professional programmer right i would
never insult programmers by calling
myself one
i can write what i consider ugly but
functional python code that helps me
helps my friends helps my teammates
right that's really kind of what it is
so i try to comment things and make my
code as easy to manipulate and
understand as possible and you know
rather than trying to maybe make it a
super elegant and concise just because
number one it's easier for me to kind of
troubleshoot and maintain and switch up
later and i think it makes it easier for
other people as well
any time right
any time you're going to speak and i
speak all the time i'm a sans instructor
i've spoken a lot of conferences i've
done all that any time you go to speak
right the imposter syndrome kicks in you
know you start asking yourself like you
know who the heck am i to be doing this
you know and everything else and
especially when you're going to write
python code
you know when you start i've had to
testify in court before based on python
code i wrote for forensics and it was
like wow you know like everyone in the
court's gonna like know like the judge
is gonna call me out for like the crappy
way that i handled a format string or
something you know
and everything went fine but it's like
still it's you know so i try to remind
myself right like perfect is the enemy
of good right you don't worry about it
just get something out there doesn't
mean you don't do the best you can and
you try to just like you know take a
dump and then throw it out there but
also like i said just throw something
out there right and i love that quote
too by robert watson watt and he was the
gentleman who was designed with um
trying to set up the air defense system
in london during world war ii to protect
him from the air raids and it's a little
bit of a depressing quote but give them
the third best option to go with the
second best comes too late and the best
never comes
anyone who's been doing most things for
a while kind of realizes that's
unfortunately very very true
so we talked about this by default
kismet starts up a new sql live file
every single time you start it it's got
that kismet extension so what our python
code does we always have it spit out to
the same directory and i've got the
python code when you actually start up
the program because kismet i wrote i um
i set kismet up to start up as soon as
the box boots up or like 30 seconds
after boot up so then whenever you run
this code that we're going to see to
kind of tell if you're being followed it
goes to that directory and it grabs the
very newest kismet file and that's what
it starts incorporating as a source
all right so now what about the
methodology right kind of the fun part
there absolutely were some puzzles here
so
to see if there's any wi-fi or bluetooth
devices currently in the area which i
also saw five to ten minutes ago 10 to
15 minutes ago and 15 to 20 minutes ago
right because conceptually i thought
like you go to location a then you go to
location b and you go to location c
and you do that but when you try to
start executing you realize now you kind
of actually needs to be rolling right it
kind of does need to be rolling
especially if you're going to be driving
around certain things like that we need
that to constantly turn over
if there are if there are any devices
that i'm seeing right now that i also
saw five to 10 minutes ago 10 to 15
minutes ago or 15 to 20 minutes ago
fire me an alert give me a little bit of
information is it wi-fi access point is
it a wi-fi device is it bluetooth low
energy what are we actually looking for
and right now you see this and you're
like wait a second so you're telling me
all the data's dumped in a database
and now you want like this is the
world's simplest sql query right show me
anything i'm seeing right now
that is in the database in this time
range or this time range or this time
range we actually can't do that though
we really can't it's not solvable with a
simple sql query because at least in the
normalized there's a lot of data in the
sqlite database in json there's a lot of
like nested json that we kind of need to
step down too and we'll see an example
of that in a few slides but as far as
the fields that are normalized for
everything that it's seeing like a wi-fi
access point or a wi-fi client or
bluetooth low energy whatever it is
there
for a mac address it has the first time
that it detected that and it has the
most recent time that it detected that
but it doesn't have everything in
between
so it's not just as simple as saying
show me everything now and then show me
everything five to ten you know that
kind of that we can't solve that in a
query but there is a solution and once
again i'm not saying this is the only
way to do it i'm just saying it's the
way that my mind kind of thought to do
it and it's to start making lists so
like i said i have kismet set up to
automatically fire off his suit right
after the box boots up
when you actually go to execute this
code and i'll show you my laughable gui
like you'll have to take off your masks
you're laughing so hard on my horrible
horrible user interface
but if you uh
if when that code starts up it goes into
that kismet.kismet file and it says okay
give me a list of all the devices that i
saw five to 10 minutes ago last 10 to 15
15 to 20 and it takes those and it puts
them in a list
now it initializes a list of current
devices that i'm kind of seeing around
me
and now every minute i add any devices
that i'm seeing into that current device
list
like i said this needs to be rolling if
you're going to be using it on like a
two hour drive or something so every
five minutes we take the current list
and now we make that the new five to ten
minute list
the old five to ten minute list becomes
the 10 to 15 minute list so on we drop
the 15 to 20 and that just continues on
a loop because at every minute it's
looking for new devices every five
minutes it kind of rolls over and does
that like i said not saying it's the
best way to do it it was the way that
kind of my mind thought to do it
every minute we grabbed the devices that
have been seen in the previous 60
seconds see if any of them are in the 5
to 10 10 to 15 or 15 20 minute list and
print an alert to the screen if so
so
we don't want to alert on ourselves
right yeah it's like just kind of like
common sense and if you've ever like
played in this role in the signals
intelligence she stuff and you know like
if we all were meeting together before
we were gonna like go do a mission what
we would all do right as we would all
like okay does everyone have their own
devices they're gonna take with them
right now and turned on everyone got
that okay cool now i'm gonna basically
push a button and make an ignore list of
every device that i'm seeing so far and
now that's basically going to be a list
of devices whatever else that i don't
care about going forward right that way
we don't alert on ourselves so we added
in the same functionality right at any
point you can create or delete an ignore
list of every mac address that you've
seen in that latest kismet file and so
that way like i said if you're going to
be driving somewhere and once you're
there then now is when you're going to
kind of get worried you can fire this up
let it go on your whole drive there and
now when you start getting close you can
create that ignore list of everything
you've seen so far because you don't
really care about that so once again not
saying that was the only way but this is
pretty standard and kind of the signals
intelligence and certain like that world
so we definitely needed to add in this
functionality
so
wait a second how do you do all this on
a tiny touch screen alright imagine
you're driving
right to do something and now you have
this like tiny little like you know
three and a half inch raspberry pi touch
screen
and let's be honest what do we need
right this needs to be like the world's
ugliest most basic fisher-price my first
gui like that's what we need here so
like don't laugh
just kidding you can totally laugh like
i would lose respect for you if you
didn't laugh but this is kind of the uh
you know get a you know what's sad you
know what's sad i think i was sober when
i wrote most of this like that's
i wish i could at least tell you like
listen i was three old fashioned zinn
right don't judge me too harshly
but i actually think i was sober not i
wasn't sober for like a lot of the code
but for this part i actually think i was
but i mean like i said seriously think
about it like i said if you're driving
around in certain things like that this
is the best way that i can think of on
the screen you know taking more time in
it i'd probably
maybe make something a little more
elegant but i mean even with my big
finger you know i can still kind of sit
there with a little stylus or something
and i can still hit the buttons to check
the status what it does it just pops
open a little window and it checks to
make sure that you have a wireless
device that's in monitor mode right we
have to be able to put it in monitor
mode to do this and it checks to make
sure kismet is running if it detects
those things it displays that knowledge
in green if it doesn't detect those
things it displays in red so checking
status kind of does that just makes it
very very simple green or red to know
that everything is good to go create
ignore list delete ignore lists and then
run chasing your tail which is just the
the name that i called my python code so
world's ugliest gooey i know all right
back to the uh sorry
sorry
so now the fun part time for some field
testing right time for some field
testing
so what i did is this had been working
great in the office or at my house and
so now hey let's take it out in the
middle of nowhere start turning on some
devices and start seeing what happens
and it's actually like a year ago when i
was living in washington dc it's easier
said to done like to go out in the
middle of nowhere right but that's one
advantage of arizona i can very very
easily go on the middle of nowhere
there's a big desert all around us so i
went to the middle of nowhere no one
else around me started turning on some
devices and i saw a squat
right everything was working fine as i
was testing it before but when i took in
the middle of nowhere i saw nothing i'm
like okay
so but i was still capturing the data so
i went back home
i took the data that i had captured
converted it to a pcap vial the akisma
gives those utilities right there it's
very very simple
and i loaded it up in wireshark and this
is what i saw right
and i played with wireless before and so
i knew that right modern devices for the
past you know several years now start
trying to randomize a mac address is
like a safety sake right i knew
mac address randomization was a thing
i had no idea it was so frequent though
this is two devices
this is two devices in a very very short
period of time and if you look on the
very very far right right you see the
ssid that they're probing for
that's all the same network
this is two devices
using a different mac every single probe
request looking for a network like
that's crazy
right that's absolutely crazy like i
said i knew mac randomization is a thing
normally i'm pacing all over the place
but the microphone's right here i guess
i could hold it but
but yeah like i said it was just way way
worse than i thought and it's like okay
well
i
i need to compensate for this somehow
right there's a couple different
strategies here but i wanted to try to
keep it to the passive one right that's
why i want to try to keep this 100
passive if at all possible and it
was so the logic to look for mac
addresses needs to be in place because
once again right what happens if someone
following you has their phone hooked up
to their car wi-fi that's a very very
common feature now well now the mac's
not moving around right the mac is
pretty stable so we need that mac
address functionality for something that
either doesn't spoof
or is actually part of an active
connection right we need that
but now we're going to have to also add
in some functionality to look for things
that aren't part of an active network
connection right and so therefore it's
like all right well a wireless device by
default right if it's not part of an
active connection it's going to be
looking for an active connection right
what have i connected to before you know
what have i connected to in the past
it's going to be looking for those so
let's try to use that
so kismet normalizes some fields in the
database but it's honestly not mini but
as i said earlier there's a lot more
kind of in a json blobs
and so there you can see there the raw
device json actually having it walk down
it's nested json so that's the code i
have dot 11 device
down to there to the probed ssid record
and then the name of actually the probed
ssid and so this is actually the network
names that they're looking for so now
even if a device
is constantly rotating its mac every
time it's looking for the network i'm
also monitoring for what networks it's
looking for and i will start to use that
same exact methodology i don't care what
the mac is if i see a device look for
you know samsung smart home now and then
five ten minutes now in 10 to 15 minutes
to now now i'm still going to alert on
that we're still going to trigger on
that so now i kind of have both bases
covered if it's part of an active
connection or not
and to put a bow on this now we need to
add this capability into our ignore
lists too right before our ignore lists
were only based off mac addresses so now
when we have the ignore list we fire off
both the mac addresses
and the networks that they were looking
for as well
let's take a look at what this will look
like actually to a user on the screen
all right so you see started up there
the date time
says 308 max added to the ignore list
right they were kind of loaded in there
and 27 probed ssids right so 27 names of
network that were loaded in
it says the name of the logging file
this is all written to a log file too so
i'm going to kind of go back after the
fact and see what happens and now it
just kind of runs right now it just kind
of goes like i said every minute it's
checking it's updating and then every
five minutes those lists roll over
so
this was uh this is running at my home
so you have like a bunch of bluetooth
low energy from a lot of home automation
stuff that's why you see it kind of
littered with there but now after
running this for a little bit all of a
sudden either one of my neighbors
something like that turned on a new
device someone came over to visit
something but now all of a sudden we had
a new device pop up right and it was
probing for samsung smart right they're
probing for that wi-fi network so we see
it there yeah there's a new probe for
that and it's in the 5-10 minute list
and then after a few minutes it was also
in the 10 to 15-minute list
and then after a little bit was also in
the 15 to 20 minute list this is after
running for probably like half an hour
and then it's not kind of like a new
device like i said either one of my
neighbors turned on something new
someone came over to visit him or
something but it stayed there for a
while
right so nothing fancy it was just
trying to like okay let's see if we can
effectively do something to try to make
this happen
this is the mvp version this is what it
looks like as i was testing and i mean
mvp here not like the sport context of
like most viable player i mean like the
business context right minimum viable
product this is me but before i'm really
worried about like form factor like as
fancy as i got you can see the antennas
out of the sticking out of the side
there right actually drilled a hole like
a boss but now before i like spent a ton
of time on form factor and customizing
and 3d printing in any of that right
like i actually wanted to make sure that
it looked good and then i'm like all
right cool like now i'm going to make it
look really really good before my talk
and then last week happened and last
week was crazy i was working paris hours
all week long getting up at midnight and
so this
this is as far as i got is actually
trying to make a little bit better right
you can see down there the the wi-fi
card in there i haven't even had a
chance to drill the holes yet the the
power pack that power pack is actually
outstanding it's called as storm i got
it as part of the kickstarter it's a
really really good one but like i said i
even had a bigger one that i got from
amazon and that would power this for
about 24 hours which is way more than
anyone needs like i said even a small
battery pack was powering it for like
seven eight hours which is most of what
people need
so what about the path forward here
right
the path forward what can kind of do if
this is a
interesting to anyone if anyone likes it
you know just kind of going forward what
kind of add-on well number one we can
start adding on more wi-fi adapters
right now i've only messed with one or
two of them tops but you know it's
having one wireless adapter on two
megahertz isn't bad because you know you
only have like not too many channels but
then when you start adding in five
gigahertz right there's a lot of
channels up there and so having multiple
wireless cards you're gonna be better at
picking stuff up so that would be one
protocol adding more wireless protocols
all right right now it's doing uh it's
doing wi-fi and it's doing bluetooth
but
you know there's other things that we
could be doing i've seen some research
out there for a few years on um like
tpms sensors little low tire low
pressure sensors and tires i've seen
some stuff on that they go a little bit
further than you think they would and
some other things
gps tracking right that would be a big
one to kind of add the gps capability in
here that'd be pretty simple to start
logging that too to when you went back
kind of after the fact and analyzed
where you were when you started to see
certain things for the first time i
think that's kind of like one of the
natural next steps
and then just some generic kind of post
capture log analysis like i said
everything it sees i spit out into a log
an additional log file in addition to
obviously the kismit log itself so
especially adding in a gps being able to
after the fact generator port of what
you saw where you saw certain things
like that on a journey in a nice usable
easy format that
kept you from having to do it manually i
think would probably be one of the first
things that i would add in from this
point as well
if you want to check it out
the presentation's right there said a
bitly vscc underscore cyt
cyt is chasing your tail right if i uh i
tried for cyt but someone had already
taken that bitly so it's cc for cactus
con underscore chasing your tail
and the code if you want to laugh at it
is right there my github name is azmat
it's uh chasing underscore your tail i
had someone like two nights ago asked me
for my github
name and i'm like yeah it's it's a z mad
i'm like if you see like that i have
like a little badge for being an arctic
code contributor somehow but the python
code looks like it's not even worth the
tape that it's saved on like you're in
the right place
you're absolutely in the right place
if you like the wireless stuff seriously
check out kismet it is fantastic it runs
on like all sorts of different things
it's all linux based unfortunately i've
spoken on wireless before to kind of
less technical crowds than this and
sometimes i show them some things and i
get people that are like oh my god this
is amazing i'm gonna do whatever it
takes tell me what i need to buy i'm
like the good news is you don't need to
buy anything right it's just all in
linux not windows they're like okay i've
got a linux person just like tell me
what i need to buy
and it's like nah really there's nothing
to buy it's you just gotta get at least
not afraid of linux and after like the
same thing and seriously i've had this
conversation like a dozen times i'm not
even exaggerating right and after like
three rounds of that it goes from like i
will do anything until they're like
faking a phone call right like oh hey my
wife's calling see you later good talk
like yeah no it's but seriously like i
said kismet is fantastic for pi for
computer for whatever the discord on
there was very very good a lot of
knowledge on there you know trying to
willing to help people getting started
and certain things like that
so if you like more wireless kismet if
you like privacy right and it's not like
a salesman hey if you like privacy you
know everyone likes privacy right but
seriously i could hear from the wi-fi
component you know you probably already
checked out kismet but if you're here
for kind of like the privacy aspect of
it sansa one you know as nasty as covet
has been at least there's been a couple
kind of bright spots coming out of it
one time
and one of the ones is all the sans
summits have basically gone free now for
the past year for forensics for counter
thread intel for some other things and
uh coming up in april the stan's ocean
summit right i've spoken the last couple
years i don't think i'll be speaking
this year but i'll be involved in it but
they usually have some pretty good talks
on not only open source intelligence but
there's also some privacy theme talks as
well so and they have the historical
ones all up there that are there to
watch for free too so like i said if
you're here for kind of like the privacy
kind of aspect of this talk if that's
what's relevant to your interest
there's probably a couple talks there
that you'll like and it's free i think
it's uh in the past last year was two
days i think this year it's going to be
one day but it's going to be like all
day long like they're starting up on
european time
and having stuff for that and then like
rolling all the way through like the u.s
time and stuff like that so yeah i think
at that point it's like technically a
marathon like we're raising money or
something
all right special thanks to right to
mike kershaw he's the uh he's the
developer of kismet i had a couple
questions and i was working on this and
i could reach out to him and he was
nothing but super helpful and like i
said talking about like don't even waste
your time doing a p cap right you can do
it after the fact it's just
computationally expensive for no reason
whatsoever
and then i think two of the the biggest
kind of wireless gurus that i know
dominic white singh on twitter i'm uh
i miss you brother i'm hoping to get
back to the u.s this year for black hat
defcon he's a south african based and
then uh josh wright you know another
kind of wi-fi guru when i have a
question about something you know before
you um
before you even start down a road to
something it's nice sometimes to talk to
someone just to make sure like hey this
is what i'm thinking of doing
does this pass a smell test to you right
or even just as important right like why
am i going to spend time doing this if
someone else has done it before you know
are you aware of someone else kind of
completing a similar project in the past
if so i won't even kind of go down that
road right
so and that was it i told you i wouldn't
keep you all late right
told you was running long so thank you
all so much it was fantastic
[Applause]
i'll be around right after this but if
anyone has any question right now feel
free
right i think i'm supposed to like toss
this or something but there's no need to
go for it
you can talk you have my pro oh you
actually want to catch it you want me to
toss it damn i should have warmed up or
something you got to warn me next time
oh that was a beautiful toss
um so you're saying uh that there's a
database right a sqlite database so if
you're in a very heavily populated area
for a few hours what's the size
constraints that you're going to fault
you'll find with that sqlite database
yeah it's a great question so the
question was if you're in a very very
heavy populated area it was like does
that sequel light database get out of
control it really didn't seem to believe
it or not it really didn't and i was
running this for a decent amount kind of
a long period of time i never had an
issue with it getting too big or meeting
up with x-fil
it's not going to be
super tiny
because like i said the data is granular
enough to generate a pcap afterwards
which is like it's not saying something
so i think i would design it probably
slightly differently if i was planning
on leaving it somewhere for you know 24
hours or more at a time i'd probably
decide to automatically roll over
restart at the end of the day but when i
was testing the battery life i would
have this thing running for seven hours
with no issue so yeah and i apologize
for not remembering like the exact size
but i never ran into an issue with it
but like i said it's not like you know
16k or something because there's
actually a lot of data in there so
no
oh right there
short toss you got to toss it too i
tossed it you got to toss it come on
there
thank you fascinating talk especially
considering you could trace the ssids
back to the people who might be
surveilling you
um i did have a question about mac
randomization um do the ouis
ultimately when they do that do they
trace back to the same vendor um i would
assume they do but i don't know
yeah that's a great question as far as
the mac addresses and it's going to vary
between different devices but if you
look at that that is a smorgasbord this
was two devices
and yeah i know it's an absolute
smorgasbord of stuff out there so i
think it's going to randomize for in
this case you know these devices i think
for others they might stick to their
ouis to try to be a little more well
maintained you know and honestly too
like i said my goal is to keep this
passive
but let's be real right if i was like
seriously concerned about um trying to
which is another possible path forward
right and then one in there that i
didn't mention one possible path forward
right is if someone's following you
trying to figure out who it was that was
following you
and if the ssid they were probing for
was unique enough that's possible i one
time i was i was speaking to a
government agency on um dark web
the dark web ooh scary
i was speaking on the dark web and uh at
break one time one of my buddies was
there and he came up to me he's like hey
you were in seattle last month and you
were staying at the marriott hotel
downtown right by there and i'm like
yes i was all right second grade rules
right i'm like a second grade teacher
though show your work all right there's
a few different ways you could have
figured this out how did you actually
show your work and what it was was i was
i was teaching i had my um little mifi
that's sitting in my backpack right now
i had that on that was my internet
source and if you think about it like if
you look up linksys and wiggle there's
going to be a million of it right grab a
snickers no luck but aren't our myfi's
and certain things like that oftentimes
a very unique name like verizon 650 lima
you know six foxtrot charlie that's a
very very unique name and my buddy saw
that's what i was using for my wi-fi he
put it into wiggle and he saw the
different places where my thing had been
spotted before including the previous
month
you know they're in seattle so there's
some deon d anonymization with this two
aspect and so like i said i kept this
100 passive on purpose if i was willing
to trade some of that passive nature
it would almost likely never be found
out and what would happen was at that
point if i saw someone probing for
something what would we do we would
mimic that ssid
we wouldn't actually serve them up a
real active connection but at that point
that we would serve them up the ssid
they were looking for they would
de-anonymize with a mac address
and so if i wanted to find out number
one a unique ssid probe we can start to
look for and figure out where they're at
and like i said if i was willing to
trade and they wouldn't make a real
connection so the odds are they would
never even know that happened if i was
willing to trade like i said being 100
passive for that we could even figure
that out a little bit more so but yeah
like i said that's two devices and
that's a smorgasbord so good question
great question
anyone else
all right it's lunch time getting that
guy there are a couple that came in oh
i'm sorry
that's right
i tried to get you all the lunch i
failed one of the questions is could the
hardware for detecting other phones
looking for wi-fi networks be in the
phone if so could the code be in a phone
app
so could it be in the app like so the
hardware looking for phones become the
phone right my mind just exploded for
the wireless now it's a great question
for the wireless you got to be able to
put this in monitor mode right you have
to basically convince it like listen
wi-fi card you've been working hard
connecting all these networks for me
why don't you just basically take the
next hour off you know go smoke a giant
bowl
and don't even worry about connecting to
the network just kind of look for what's
floating through the air right and
that's very very difficult to do on
windows systems and it's very very
difficult to do with the embedded
hardware in a device like you can't take
the wi-fi card to say can't right i
don't like to speak in absolutes
but you don't really want to take the
wi-fi card in like a raspberry pi and
try to convert that into monitor mode
that's why we add on the second wi-fi
card so usually in my wi-fi testing
you're not using the built-in wireless
to do certain things like this for
monitor mode you're actually putting in
an external one and doing it so great
question
and then another question is could this
be adapted to identify apple air tags
that are repeatedly could this be
invented by app layer tags and certain
things like that absolutely absolutely
it would um you would have to like i
said it's a matter of kismet is so good
about incorporating different types of
radio you know different types of
spectrum the sdr and things with this i
just kept it to wi-fi and bluetooth but
like i said that would absolutely be one
of the path forward like i said one of
the first parts one of the first parts
my brian went to was um
it was kind of like tpms low pressure
sensors and tires but other anything
basically the wireless if kismet can
ingest it we could actually add this
into it so
awesome
all right i'm six foot four i'm really
easy to spot if you have any questions
hit me up thank you all very much
appreciate it
you