do it live
all right
and we
are live
okay we got started a little bit late
and so this is going to be just like one
minute with george ortiz hi george how
are you i'm doing great wow you
pronounce my name so well
thank you
i rehearsed it in advance uh we are
since we got you started late we're just
going to ask the most important question
what are the benefits of purple teaming
over standard red teaming or blue
teaming individually that's a great
question so purple teaming is a function
right doesn't mean you stop red teaming
and you stop blue teaming to do this
just like you don't stop vulnerability
assessment because you're doing
penetration testing um
benefit it really comes down to value uh
most times you do a red team engagement
takes a while from the engagement
actually happening to the report to the
reveal to working together
and try to fix things um purple teaming
should happen between those times um and
really it's the value of educating the
blue team in what you are doing what the
red team is doing and the blue team
educating the red team as to what uh the
the blue team's doing you know everyone
learns right it's all about
collaboration working together uh you
know being a herd being a community the
malicious actors are working together we
should probably work together too uh
it's just
a more efficient way of uh of improving
that sounds great so we're not
abandoning red or blue we're just adding
some purple in there for the spectrum
exactly awesome well if you have any
more questions for george feel free to
hop over into our track three hallway
con jordan if you can join us there and
then we're gonna jump on over to our
next shot thanks so much