all right i think we're live with our q
a now fantastic thanks for your talk
bryson really appreciate it um
i uh
i know you're looking forward to coming
out in person and omicron kind of
delayed that so sorry about that
mucho sadness
indeed
uh well let's see if we have some
questions uh folks that are in either
the discussion or into the
q a and discord you can feel free to pop
your questions in here
um
so let's take a look and see
what we've got
we have people saying great talk which
it was uh looking into the c2 matrix
good ideas
um
so you know in in your talk you
mentioned something about talking to
your boss and for a lot of people this
is going to be a really intimidating and
awkward conversation uh do you have any
recommendations of how you would start
that conversation or ask for that
conversation with your boss
uh yeah so
um
i don't know that everyone is as
intimidated talking to their immediate
boss but i think that's the first
starting point which also even if you
are intimidated talking to your boss
is recognizing everybody else has a boss
and as we go further up that chain
the less they have any clue about what
you do right they're they're busy doing
other things and that's one of the key
takeaways that i wanted to imprint with
everyone is that understanding that
in cyber security we get frustrated a
lot because like why don't they get it
why doesn't the business understand and
appreciate what we're doing
and
the reality is they're doing for the
most part just fine without us until
that very moment of course when when
what we were predicting would happen
does happen
um and so i'm trying to help you know
we're talking with your boss
understanding their boss their pressures
what they're trying to do and then how
that aligns with the business itself
will reduce your frustration as well as
hopefully head off some of those things
before they they do happen
oh yeah so in terms of how to do that um
i mean
there's no reason to have an adversarial
relationship with your boss they're a
human being too
so starting with little things
establishing small talk
um how's the weather what did you think
what did you do last weekend i mean it
sounds silly but it's a starting point
to a conversation where you can then
start to feel more comfortable with
asking more pointed questions like
so what really was happening last week
at this event and we're trying to do
these things why are we trying to do
them what's the point um
uh
that's where i also recommended starting
to get more into the business speak with
tying things to like well what are we
trying to accomplish this quarter what
are the key performance indicators or
okrs
um that's that's the latest buzzword out
of the silicon valley is okrs which is
really just objectives you know so what
are things we're trying to accomplish
what are and how are those being
measured um and that'll give you a lot
of insight into
what's driving them in their own you
know pressures and decision-making
calculus
right
yeah and i think what you mentioned is
really important about the language you
know the buzzwords those actually mean
something uh you know to bosses all the
way up the chain and figuring out how to
translate is i think you know the crux
of what you're talking about yeah um
i think also asking you know and how can
i help
bosses love to know that you want to
help
so that's valuable too
um
you mentioned in one of your slides also
you know the kind of difference between
regulation and real security
and this is something i mean we were
walking to lunch and talking about this
precise thing actually so uh any
examples about uh
what kind of real security things tend
to fall through when we only focus on
regulation
yeah so the intent of that slide was
even was even more than that i wanted to
start with
um so
i think everybody gets that compliance
is not real security in our field right
if you're in cyber security 99.6
understand that statement the problem is
then when they do that they look down on
the requirements they look down on the
need for that or that the business looks
at it that way why does my boss push me
about a checklist it's stupid it's not
real security
well the reality again going back to the
business perspective is that checklist
is existential
the business is not legally allowed to
operate unless that checklist is met
and so recognizing that that is where i
used it in the concept of maslow's
hierarchy of we have to start here
before we can do any of the other things
right it's like eat your veggies before
you're allowed to go get chocolate chip
cookies and in this case real security
is the chocolate chip cookies uh and so
following that through real security
then is how do i build off the checklist
concept which is exists everywhere in
some form to start to piece together
things that will make a difference for
applied security to
business needs
great
thank you
and i think one other thing that is uh
maybe not like central to your talk but
the people might be interested in
is
your career trajectory and how you
started a business
anything that you wanted to
mention about uh that's that's a big
leap that i know a lot of people are
curious about
sure um in fact i have a talk on that um
so if you if you google my name and or
entrepreneurial adventures
i've given the talk at def con and a few
other places in fact
i'm giving it monday night for
washington state university so one of
the things i like to do is part of
giving back to the community is speaking
and
interacting with college students
so i'm happy to come and speak at
colleges answer their questions and to
me the best one is that one right what
does it mean to be an entrepreneur
because the starting point is
understanding how does business work
right cyber security is a part of
business it does not fit by itself and
starting your own company is inherently
a business
and so
in that talk i go through the different
models of businesses why that's
important why you should care what does
that mean uh and i think everybody finds
it interesting to actually kind of like
oh so that's everything that's going
behind the curtain on this whole place
that i work at
um
to start a business i think comes down
to two key characteristics
and
one that i think everybody assumes
intuitively is you need to be the
smartest or the best at something
look at me like the blank look is not
faked i am not the best of the smartest
at anything um what i do have and what i
do think an entrepreneur requires
is one
uh passion
and
that word gets thrown around a lot but
what it means for an entrepreneur is you
have to want to do this idea so badly
that it hurts you not to do it
when you're starting a consulting
company it's because
you need to do you want to apply those
services your own way when it comes to a
product the fact that that product is
not out there bothers you
because if you're trying to do it for
money uh first of all most of us don't
make money doing it um not the way you
think um i mean i'm clearly not doing
this from a yacht
um
but
that uh that's what's gonna get you
going through the morning because every
business of course goes through
hard times right not everything goes
smoothly and the thing that's gonna get
you out of bed on those bad days is
going to be that passion that it's still
you still want to make it happen and
you're going to go as far as possible
the second one
is tolerance for bs
when you run your own company
everything comes down on you
you want to learn health care insurance
for all 50 states i didn't want to i had
to
right you have to that's what is
required to take care of your employees
that's what's required to run a company
is all of the administrative
minutia
all of the details all the regulations
of things you don't care about you have
to you have to care about that because
nobody else will
uh so you have to be able to accept that
you're going to be putting up with a
bunch of stuff that is not core to what
the company's purpose is but is
absolutely just like the question
earlier about regulation
it's mandatory
yep
and it comes down to taking care of the
people that are going to be working for
you like you mentioned and getting the
job done that you want to do at the
first place yeah so branching off that i
just this is going to be a little bit of
a tangent but this is nothing to do with
my presentation everything i would like
to sort of follow that up to
giving a call out to how i think we
should all be approaching this in
industry
cyber security inherently is
an industry that brings a certain type
of person into it who has
either an engineering mindset has that
passion and curiosity that drives
wanting to understand and do things that
are typically abstract to most folks
and as a result
right so
we never know when something's going to
fail in our industry
this isn't like information technology
or traditional engineering where i can
engineer something to a particular
quality assurance
we are defined by a threat that is
continually changing and is inherently
unknown and so i think those those
attempts with that personality to to
want to learn everything and to be right
creates constant anxiety in us because
inherently we're never sure
there are i i joke there are no experts
because we're never sure there is no
objective measurement of security it's
just i think it's working because even
then when it's not we don't know until
we you know do know right attackers
don't get found immediately
and so the call that i would put out to
everyone
is
kindness
what i mean by that is starting with
kindness toward yourself right to
reducing that anxiety to looking at
work-life balance to recognizing you
can't solve all of this you can't be the
individual hero to overcome a system
which is a business like i talk about in
my talk where they don't care about
security or where you are in a place
that does but you're under resourced or
you're trying too hard or you're all of
these things um so be kind to yourself
take care of yourself because you can't
take care of anything else without that
and then the corollary to that is treat
everyone with that same kindness because
they're going through the exact same
thing that you're going through
those are both really true awesome
well thank you so much i really
appreciate you spending your time with
us at cactus con hopefully we'll see you
in person next year uh if anybody has
any additional questions you can feel
free to pop them in the q a and discord
or in the track 2 hallway um and uh
thanks again bryson so much you really
appreciate it
take care