hello and welcome to the network
forensics analysis talk
my name is ramya talhi i am senior
incident response consultant at cisco
telus intelligence group
for today agenda will be talking about
couple of topics
we'll be starting with defining the
network forensics what it is and what it
does
the second topic for the tools and
platforms that is available and can be
used widely the third topic we will be
talking about the dilemma with some
encrypted protocols such as tls
ssh rdb etc and how we can overcome
those challenges
and the fourth topic is for real world
apt advanced persistent
threat attacks scenarios
where they are using
and utilizing some encrypted protocols
such as dns over https to hide their
compromise
so let's start with network forensic
definition i have found a good
definition in wikipedia for network
forensics which says
it's a sub-branch of digital forensics
relating to the monitoring and analysis
of computer network traffic for the
purpose of information gathering legal
evidence or intelligent detection
so network projects is a branch of
digital projects beside
other
hosts memory mobile phones etc
and once we combine a network forensics
with other datasets like host or memory
we would generate a good visibility and
investigation journey
all right so couple of tools and
platforms we have
to perform the network forensics
analysis job the first tool which is
very commonly known
uh in this field uh called wireshark
wireshark is a tool to read
and
filter the investigate any b cap file or
trace files if you have a b cap file the
first thing you go into wi-fi to just
lock it to what
what's going on
as a conversation also you can look into
statistics you can walk into end point
etc as we will see in the next slide
uh it has another
version called t-shark which is a
command-line version
you it's really
a useful tool if if you are looking into
a scriptable option for this tool
tcp dump is exactly as t-sharp does but
it have
it is based on the ppf filter
and also it doesn't understand
application layer it is much faster than
let's say tshark in reading huge pcap
file
but it has a limitation to understand
layer
7 so that's why
the speed come from
sometimes you need to swap
between them so you need to use tcp dump
to slice this packet back and send it to
the oil shaft called d-shock and vice
versa
zeke is a fantastic tool to read the
metadata of
most of the protocols
used in the internet things like tls ssh
rdb http
whatever protocol is there it has
ability to read it and also to provide
you with
information uh things like
if you look into tls
like the issuer
um
also it provides you with the hash etc
for the ideas sometimes we are looking
into scanning the pickup without going
into the details
so we are looking into signature-based
dedication rules
things like snorts or rikata it is a
good option to have
to pass the pickup through the ideas
so you can just install snort
or
sorry cutter to
scan your pickup
network miner is a nice tool to
visualize the picab you you are just
importing the v cabin to this tool and
it will provide you all the information
without
without knowing anything about the
pickup just
going through the tabs and you'll see
much and tons of information
for example if there is any picture
being traversed in clear text it will be
available there you can see export lock
into the that picture
the same from the password etc
okay so let's look into the network
forex challenges so we we got couple of
uh network forensics challenges in here
which have
a big impact into the network forensics
investigation
also for network monitoring for any
environment
uh we will discuss about those
points and how we can overcome each of
them
we'll be discussing a couple of
challenges that might limit the ability
to investigate the network traffic
the first one is inventory assets
collecting the packet capture we need to
have a list of inventory assets if we
don't know for example uh where is the
critical surface
or servers that we are aiming to
have
the packet capture out of it we would
not be able to collect it and acquire it
or even monitor it
so if we don't know the asset
that we have then we don't know what to
protect and what to monitor as well
the the second thing is the network
baselining baselining here we mean
uh we need to understand our network
very well especially in terms of
throughput also the protocol being used
a couple of statistics that we have and
we will see an example in the next slide
encryption so encryption is the most
challenge that we have in network
the sophistication side
things like tls search rdb and other
protocols other encrypted protocol as
well
um that attacker now uh
utilize
things like drh which is dns over https
where they hide their traffic
based on this protocol so we'll see
how we can utilize some
tricks and tips to understand the
pattern of the attackers
the last thing is the data source is
availability and usability we need to
have the
data sources
to be available and usable
so both of them need to be
existed in place
if you look into the cis cyber security
control you will see the control number
one is inventive and control of interval
wise assets
so this spot the priority number one for
this inventory assets so figure out your
assets that matter
can be
application can be safe forms can be
services
so find out the important and the
critical mission of your business
then
after that you have the all information
about them
make sure it's protected make sure it is
monitored so in this topic we'll focus
on
the monitoring and investigation as well
so finding out the inventory having the
inventory in place having all the
details about them
patch them
back up them
test them
all these very
critical information and critical
mission to have in your environment
find out the pattern to find
abnormalities in our network
does need a network-based mining we can
look into our protocols
traverse to our network we can look into
that robot we can look into default
statistics to find out those
metrics to identify
the maliciousness of the traffic in our
network
for an example for the packet length we
can log into the dns if the packet of
the dns length
exceeded that amount of identified
packet length that mean we need to have
to receive
alerts
and it should be a red flag
also
the iteration the same goes for payload
and toby if it's higher that's mean
disabled investigation egress and
ingress as we can see here we can
identify exfiltration in this picture we
can see
from the end of january we have spike
until 400
so that means
we have seen
abnormal traffic especially in the
weekend
it's not in office hours
and also we can see
a different
protocol like a protocol that we are not
using for a huge amount of bandwidth so
a lot of use cases actually can be built
over those for
category
let's jump into network profiling and we
can use this network profile especially
for the encrypted traffic as we
discussed earlier the network traffic
has a big challenge for the encryption
most of that protocols we have used
today
is encrypted if you log into the http
base for example it does use tls
rdb use traders we have ssh which is
encrypted we have
many many protocols is encrypted by
default
uh also these encryption actually it's
limit limiting the uh the ability to for
the investigation and monitoring but
still we have
some ways
and workarounds to find out the
malicious traffic over there and we will
discuss about ga3 which is
a way to identify and profile the
theater's traffic
that initiated from the host machine
also for j3s which is the same as j3
bots
but this is to identify the surface
the third one jarm is a way to identify
the servers
and we can
actually categorize the safe hubs based
on their tls mechanism as we will see in
the next slide
we have hash and hash saver which used
for ssh fingerprint if you look into
ssh connection for example and you are
connecting from your host or laptop into
the server
actually those connection can be used to
identify you and or identify anyone
from the uh the collection of the ssh
as we will see
the rdb remote desktop
it does use tls and we have
very interesting
actually
information about it to find out
the use of that being logged into that
rdb to identify the attacker activities
as well the community id is a way to
profile the
let's say
the net flow
so we it's actually a hash
value
being generated
for the flaws itself more details in the
next slide
so talking about j3 now
uh it's a way to
read actually the hello packet of the
tls handshake as we know
and as you can see from this picture
actually j3 will calculate couple of
fields from tls hero packet
and will provide you with md5 hash those
md5 hash
should indicate into specific client
uh
[Music]
this
this profiling actually being built by
salesforce team
uh and
actually they are doing a very fantastic
job
uh and to determine
the way to profile these encrypted
packets as we will see uh j3 j3s and
hash as well
so
how it works actually it does calculate
md5 hash value based on this version
if you are in 1.2 if you are at 1.3 it
does
it has some different hash for those
values as well so any value being
changed in those parameters it will
accordingly change the
md5 hash as well
i accepted ciphers list of extensions so
if there is more extension or less those
will affect
by
the calculation as well
elliptic curve analytic curve format
all of these should be
actually matched to have a same value of
the md5
the same goes for j3s
s here means the the cfr
so
j3 is the difference between j3 and j3s
the j3 actually looking into the client
hello tls handshake we have j3s looking
into the server hello since we are
talking here about the server
so from the safer side it will calculate
three parameters and tls only not like
j3
as we have more than three so in here in
j3s we are looking into theories version
accepted ciphers list of extensions that
set we don't have
elliptic curve etc so it will look into
these three
parameters and it will determine
the md5 and it will calculate the md5
hash for you so it should be unique
we have here some of useful use cases
for identifying j3 and j3s fingerprint
if we look into the for example
profiling toward client and also tour
safer
what we can do actually is looking into
j3 fingerprints
for an example this is the hash md5 hash
of j3 of torque lined of some previous
versions
where you can actually do some threat
hunting and to build some use cases if
you if you have a theme if you have any
dataset that you are looking to
that does have j3 then
you can just lock into the haystack
for these hashes
and also you can generate your own
absolutely
for j3s it's the same for the server
if someone like uh
just running the tour as a surfer then
you can look into the finger movement
for this hash as well
some attacker actually manipulate these
values as we will see in the next slide
so we can discuss this further
another example is here for ransomware
families so we have trick bot and emote
it
one of the things that you can look into
the ransomware you can look into the
client for an example j3 we have trick
bot communication tls
and also we have
the c2 safe response so this is the c27
response of the attacker say for
backhand
the same goes for emoted so
you can see how how useful is j3 and ga3
is for identifying the malicious traffic
in your environment either from the
client side or from the safe website
both should be
actually uh useful to identify those and
you can investigate this further looking
into other data sets and also for those
and points which which actually generate
those uh
communication and connections
now let's jump into some search engine
for j3
we have actually two websites in here
the first one
j3er.com
where it provides you with
a search capability google like
search engine where you just paste the
jf3 value and you can identify what is
this client uh
actually of the same form so this this
is the first website and we have another
website in the next slide
this is another website you can log into
abuse.ch j3 fingerprint and you can log
into a specific j3 after you are looking
into uh for example if you have a list
of j3 fingerprint you can look into them
and it has actually a good um
a good function or good feature here to
list for listing reason where it does
label by the malware family if you look
into the first hash here we have trick
bot
and how many malware samples being
submitted into this website also it
shows you sometimes time for the first
scene
so
it's really make our life easier by
looking into the j3 once you have this
implementation
then you can just figure out uh what
client is connected to what server
from the tls even though if it's
vergil 1.3 where there is no hostname
being
embedded with the tls since it is
encrypted not like 1.2 etc
now enough talking about j3bj3s let's
talk about impersonation so
can the attacker now manipulate and uh
impersonate the j3 absolutely yes
it's impersonated and it have been seen
in the wild so changing the cypher suite
of tiers version will change the j3
completely
as we have discussed earlier we have a
couple of elements
for tls like taylor's version if you
just change that if you just change some
extensions adding removing
then this will be
changed accordingly
other factors needed to tackle this
issue so what we can do to tackle this
issue we can look into other data sets
like other dls characteristics and
extensions
also from host correlation if you have
a data from the host itself you can just
correlate it with the host event as well
one of the things that you can utilize
in partial to manipulate and impersonate
the tls
is to use enable to decipher suite
command
then you can position
in extension uh as we have seen here
called tlsth edss
uh into lower
priority so changing the priority or the
position
of specific talents cipher suite
will change and impersonate the tls
accordingly so attacker might use this
way or another way
to just manipulate
tls and this is just for the
investigation you can manipulate the
the tls
uh in etls actually exchange extensions
to change the md5 fingerprint of the j3
there are a couple of limitations for
identifying j3 and j3s fingerprints
one of them is
these fingerprints merely based on the
taylor cipher suites so it doesn't look
after the sci-fi suites
also uh it doesn't look into the
different characteristics things like
alpn which is application
called negotiation it doesn't look into
it and it doesn't look into anything
else than these dls characteristics
which is already determined
from the previous
discussion
also this makes the j3 not very unique
and some clients
might share the same md5 fingerprint uh
bear in mind that
these md5 finger fingerprint might match
with other so there is a percentage uh
or some false positive within the j3 and
j3s so this should be considered uh
once you are doing the
or building the use cases and doing the
threat hunting
or investigation can be manipulated by
changing the cypher suites extension as
we have seen from the powershell you can
just manipulate it with lowering or
position
uh the tls into a different position
so j3 and j3s is good tool
and good mechanism to trace the tls but
it doesn't
doesn't provide you with accurate
and
uh let's say clear answer
if this is
uh if this fingerprint is for ex-client
or why
but it at least it provides you with
some context
surrounding the use cases that you have
the salesforce team actually built
recently charm fingerprint so this is
let's say
another level that we have for tls
fingerprint but the main differences
between j3 and charm is charm is made by
live scanning for those earphones and
it's just considered for the safer while
j3 and j3s is a passive
uh tool where it calculates the md5
fingerprint for client and server
so a job actually is an active transport
layer security tier let's say for
fingerprint tool it is active so you
need
to interact actively with the server to
collect these java finger and print
so scanning with the jar and provide the
ability to identify and develop server
on the
internet um
you might have a couple of servers so
let's say you have a load balancer and
you have a couple of servers behind that
load balancer if you go for example and
see salesforce or
for google they they they have a lot of
servers to serve
the clients
but using the germ
can you can have
a unified fingerprint can indicate this
this fingerprint
just related to a specific company or
specific provider as you will see in the
next slides
we can use jump to quickly verify all
safer and globe have the same serious
configuration so it's really looking
into the tls configuration to identify
the cipher of groups
as we said google cell swaps you have
multiple servers might share the same to
this configuration those servers will
provide you with a single unique
fingerprint of the job
since they are
they have shared tails configuration
so
also it's called this disparate uh
same forms on the internet by
configuration
to identify the server might belong to
google or the salesforce as we described
earlier
also to identify the malware on c2
infrastructure
and other militia server on the internet
you might have the jam fingerprint for
the c2 back end
so you can utilize charm to actively
scan the servers and identify those
tls configuration
so here we have two different
uh examples we have the salesforce
cell phones and we have google servers
we can see in the upper of this picture
we have
uh we have implemented or executed the
germ
python script to the salesforce team
saidswatch.com and also we have
fours.com both of them
shared the same tls configuration now we
have a single unique uh jar and finger
i'm going to
indicate
into this empty ls configuration so we
are we are looking
and we are dealing with the same
entity
also the same goes for the server of the
googles of the google we can see google
and youtube they are sharing the same
tls configuration
so it's really provide you with the
context about what you are dealing with
what what kind of the self-helps that we
have even though we have a different ip
as you can see in the this picture
but still
we have the same dls configuration and
we have the same unique charm
fingerprint
now let's look into the rdb or remote
digital protocol
we know that rdb is encrypted by tls and
there's a couple of ways that we can
deal with rdb
to unleash and discover mobile formation
and pivot into different
data points that can be beneficial for
the investigation
looking into the rdb protocol in
wireshark for an example you can see
clearly what user being used
during the rdb session
if you look into
the image and below you can see
in ascii format that we have cookie
equal testing so the testing is the
username being used so i just use this
in
in the lab and i have used the user
called testing just to show you that we
can capture this information and this is
very critical information you can
utilize your scene to do threat hunting
based on specific users
some attacker used
or create their users in the systems so
you can track those users using the
cookie field and the rdb
now it's the time for ssh finger event
we will see how we can
identify the ssh connection how we can
identify the client the server
we can identify even the operating
system being used by the client and
server as well
cell sports team have developed hash and
hash server to identify
and fingerprint the ssh connections for
the client and server so it's
exactly as j3 but for ssh so it is md5
hash value uh
from the set of the algorithm and ssh
protocol after tcp hand check so we have
tcp handshake and firsthand then we will
have
ssh connection and transactions
so from these connection uh hash safe on
dash can be calculated based on the
algorithm called ssh message kicks in it
it's transferred in clear text so you
can read it without encryption so it's
being transferred from client to the
server in clear text you can look into
for example in wireshark it does include
the different client application strings
as we will see in the next slide
cable of benefits using hash and hash
server so we can utilize it to attribute
to such connection with creative
accuracy than only by ib we can look
into
the
connection and application being used
for resistance for an example if you are
looking if you are using potty if you
are using any other
systems or even an ubuntu or any linux
machine and you are using the terminal
we can identify those as a user agent
so we can see the client
version and operating system as well
with the same conversion of ssh and
the operating system
uh one of the things that we can utilize
hash and hacksafer is
with regardless of the nut devices so if
you have a couple of workstations being
compromised by uh
attacker what we can do is we can look
into the ssh string of hash server and
hash so we can log into the client on
the server
uh regardless of the nut devices as we
will have these ssh connection
uh being captured and hashed
by those two algorithm it's analogous to
http user agent so
you can use it as http user agent and
web browser so we can identify as such
version if it's version 2 or anything
else or they are using open ssh or any
other different
tool
then we can identify the operating
system
let's discuss about client and server
ssh communication and how it's being
done
so once the client need to communicate
with the server in this search first
place
will have the tcp three-way handshake
and after that it will have ssh
communication we can see from this
illustration we have self-help
identification string client
identification string where
everyone from client and server will
send their strings which is user agent
like in http or in browser
this strings actually contain the ssh
protocol and the client also the
operatic system we can see we have open
ssh and ubuntu as a server and we have
open ssh and
debian or raspberry buy from this from
the client
so after that we have ssh message geeks
in it
two message one from the client one from
the safer and both of them can be used
to generate the hash and hash saver
fingerprint md5 value
we have two section here clip text and
encrypted so clear text can be
utilized by the finger printing for user
agent like for the string from the
client server and also
search message kicks in it for hash and
hash save for fingerprint the encrypted
part is for the data payload where it's
encrypted and it's not visible for
for the man in the middle
looking into the hash algorithm from the
client how it's been happening from the
wire shark
practically we can look into the packet
called client key exchange
initialization and we can see the value
so the below value actually used to
generate the md5 value out of the hash
so the hash actually will be calculated
from using these values from the client
and the server from the next slide we
will see
how this being calculated from the safer
site
here is how the high server calculate
this value from the same for key
exchange initialization and it has
different value where it will be used to
calculate the md5 hash for the hash save
up so now we have
uh hash and hash server where we have
client and the safer hash value we can
use it for our threat hunting
in our environment to see
who is communicating to who and in what
client so we can see the operating
system the client
and also the end points
we can look into ssh client string which
is in another packet
so from the client side we can see
clearly here that the client used ssh
version 2 open ssh 407 so we can map
that with our
actually
ssh
and ssh fingerprint as well
now we'll be talking about the hashtag
dilemma so if you have been in a
situation where you have a lot of big
caps let's say over 500 gb and you have
been asked to
investigate for any maliciousness within
those packets so it is not an easy task
to handle so we have couple of ways
to show you how you can handle such
situation and what are the things that
you need to consider
in prior to go within this investigation
first thing that we need to look into is
slicing and merging what do you mean by
that is
by defining this the right scope so we
do have a timeline and we do have
an overview about the incident of about
the case that we we need to to lock into
it or also the threat hunting so we have
couple of things that we can look into
or also we have source hybrid
destination ib anything that can be
filterable
then we can
just shrink the time or we have we can't
select specific
any criteria that might
align with our investigation in this
case if you have
let's say one terabyte of packets then
it will come down
maybe 80 percent less or more than that
if we have the writer formation in hand
so one of the things that we can use is
to use
edit cap so edit cab is a tool
already
packaged with the wire shark if you
install it in your machine
then you can use it to slice
the packet based on
the time for example if we need to have
to specify the start time and stop time
we have a specific timeline we can use
dash a capital or dash b and we can use
the format as described in this slide
to identify the timeline so we need we
are interested to look into
let's say
one week
ago then we can specify the time
the time step based on what we have
from the scoping
another way to look into the pcap is by
splitting
the
the single p-cap into different
p-caps based on specific amount of
packet
in this example i have used edit cap
dash
c1000 which means that
you are telling the edit cap to just
count the first 1000 packet and throw it
into a single file then start from from
that
so what i'm doing here i'm reading tcb.p
cap read the first 1000 throw it out
into the current folder and
just do this
continuously and throw that into tcb
underscore analysis that we cap as you
can see here is we have a list of the
pcap files every and each file have 1000
packets this is very useful to split it
out into a different
and a different p caps where you can
look into
just small amount of packets and also
it's very useful
to use a different tools
so it's easily uh loaded into your
tool things like network miner and etc
now a time to merge all them together so
we what we can do actually is to merge
the the needed result out of the p cap
that we have analyzed into a single p
cap so
merge cap then dash w which we mean that
we need to output into the single file
which called out that p cap
and we can also combine them with all
the output of all
the splitted picab
we are looking for so a that we can't
beat at picab
both of them will be made together into
a single vial called out that pickup
what we can do actually after we have
these analysis to use some ideas things
like snort or cerricator and here i have
used snort to read the file that pick up
and reading the configuration called
snort.conf
dash l to show you the result in the
screen
so snot actually is
an ids has a lot of signature built in
you can develop your own you can also
have some community rules or you can
purchase you need to any
snow signature
or you can use cericata which is
available all uh publicly in the
internet
then you can scan the entire pcap to
look into any
match with uh signatures that available
from from the snort
we'll be talking about two avt use cases
utilized by
a different attacker group that being
reported
publicly and how that
utilized
different protocols to evade the cyber
security controls and even to be hidden
in their
network traffic
the first case is for dns over https
malware which called
doh
and the attacker here used the uh to
evade all the cyber security
detection tools and network monitoring
systems as well and we will see how they
are deploying their malware and what to
do about it
let's first look into the dlh and
identify
the main characteristics of this
protocol so it is dns over https and
it's used by 443 tcp
as if it was tls
and querying dns using https to protocol
so there is no more
53 udp protocol
of traffic in here
also we have more privacy and it does
make security analyst job harder by
investigating these
traffic
since it is fully encrypted
and blindly passing all
the cyber security monitoring tools if
it's not
using any mile in the middle decryption
so couple of browsers supported it
like firefox chrome etc so advisory here
welcoming the uh to hide
in the haystack
so attacker loves
actually to have uh evasion
over any cyber security monitoring tools
to hide their track and also to mislead
the cyber security analysts
first manual sample will be looking into
his
six spot
where
the attacker actually used
their code to use doh which is dns over
https
so i will be
looking into their code and how they are
utilizing drh
to achieve their objectives
this is the snippet of the malware code
in the first square we can see that
two domains being encoded by rc4 format
and both of them uh
both of the domain are actually ending
with that hk after you
decode it
and then and the function which is in
the other square we have
doh
so actually what this function
does is
looking into or resolving
those domain using dns.google.com where
it does support doh
and also
they are actually using type a where
they can translate
to the ip
we will see how this request being being
done from the next slide
so the attacker actually used
the dodge heavily
in this sample
just to
[Music]
do the dns lookup for those domains
this is the other snippet that we can
see demonstrate that how the dns
resolving have been handled so we have a
get request and to
google the dns.gov
google.com
that asking to resolve this domain which
ending with that hk the type a which is
one of the types that dns have
to
resolve this domain into the ip and we
can see the json format in the below
section we can see the ib have been
appeared for us after resolving from the
google which starting with one one nine
two eight four eight
and two three one
so attacker successfully
accomplished their objective by
resolving
the dns of their domain after
decode
their domain from the malware code from
the rc4 they do
they are doing the resolving using the
dns that google did come and they can
accomplish their objective later on
we have another use case used the oah in
different way so the attacker here can
actually they will load a malware binary
from the internet using doh and we will
see how
this have been accomplished also we will
see
how you can see and log into this and
wireshark
the first thing you will notice in wi-fi
that the server name which is
dns.google.com
from the http traffic so this is
actually decrypted from wi-fi it
does show you that the dns.google.com
being
communicated using http to resolve
specific domains
here we can look into the full picture
where
the attacker used get command into
dns.google.com to resolve mimikatz
domain
using text record without using dns sec
which is set to false and we have the
full uri and below
we can look into the follow up i here
and we can see the user agent of the
attacker where he is using chrome
version on renders
once he did that you can look into the
full payload in here you can see this
payload started with
tvq and this is base64 format and
anything in base64 format starting with
tvq usually
it does indicate that it is a
binary so the attacker successfully able
to
retrieve the payload in base64 using
domain
over https or dns over https
using
just https traffic so the analyst when
he log into the traffic he will see
https traffic and
he will not be able to see all these
information
i would like to thank you all for your
time and i appreciate you have been here
and it's the time for the questions if
anyone have any questions
you