okay uh hello everyone uh thanks for
joining my talk today at cactus con
uh i'm going to talk about ransomware
yes unfortunately it's still number one
thread and still there are quite a lot
of ransomware attack nowadays
and today we are going
to focus on log bit ransomware one of
the most active
uh ransomware gangs or ransomware
service programs
if you prefer
uh so my talk is titled needs ammonia
beats
a dive into log bit transformer
operations
very soon you'll learn why it has
such an interesting name
okay i think we're ready to start
uh first of all just
a few words about me
my name is alex guten i'm
head of
global different team
at group ib
so we are responding to various
cybersecurity incidents all around the
globe we have
dedicated teams in europe in middle east
in asia
and of course in russia
uh personally i'm doing digital
forensics and instant response for 10
years already
i love intelligence-driven approach very
much so that's why
i'm talking about tactics techniques and
procedures of various protectors very
often so
my team me
and our colleagues all around the globe
can be ready such attacks can understand
how to properly respond to such
incidents and how to build proper
detections so they can detect in time
and they can prevent
such attacks and
at least prevent
ganks from ransomware deployment
i offered a few books
maybe you even are aware of some of them
for example windows friendly cookbook
practical mobile forensics and of course
quite a few
of blog posts and various research
papers you can find it at group ib site
and
for example if you google my name and
you add the effect to it you can find a
lot of
stuff as well also currently i'm working
on a new book
called instant response in the age of
ransomware attack
uh it's gonna be is going to be released
very soon so
if you're interested in such materials
you can just
follow my twitter for example
i'm trying to collect certificates just
like
many fellow
instant responders and security
professionals currently i'm holding gcfa
gcti and mcfe
okay
more than enough about me
let's keep going and start discussing
our main topic log bit
okay so let's start
from the overview
so first of all log bit is a ransomware
as a service problem
so
there can be quite a few
different affiliates
who may just
borrow
ransomware
from this program
and then they may use various tactics
techniques and procedures we'll discuss
all these in details during this talk
and finally they'll deploy ransomware
also
as
many
ransomware affiliates nowadays extra
trade data as well logweight provides
their own dedicated leak site so
accelerated data can be posted on it and
they can show it to their victims
or threaten their victims then yet they
don't pay when they will definitely
publish the whole dataset they executed
so
in fact this
ransomware service program started back
in 2019
first
ransomware sample
detected in the wild
encrypted files and added abcd extension
to them but it still
works and
there are still quite a few of attacks
perform this ransomware nowadays
usually log bit extension is added to
encrypted files and what's more in june
2021 we saw
a new version of log bit so called log
bit 2.0
as i already mentioned
these guys and their affiliates of
course they focus on double extortion so
they not only deplora and somewhere
enterprise-wide
but they also
extra trade data
before ransomware deployment of course
it's not in every incident in some
instance they just skip it and don't
accelerate in data but still in many
instances we faced and we responded to
they excited data and they even have
custom tools for date acceleration we'll
discuss
such tools later
okay so if we are talking about numbers
even based on information provided on
their dedicated leak site since log bit
2 release they performed more than 300
of attacks
so quite a lot of and of course there
are attacks the
information about those
were not posted on tls so
in reality the number of attacks
even
bigger than 300
and talking about ransom demands it can
be very different up to
50 millions but in some cases it can be
for example thirty thousand dollars or
one hundred thousand dollars so
when some demands are different depends
on the company and log bit attack
uh really different companies because
the main idea behind it is
they have different affiliates
affairs have different capabilities and
of course
they attack different companies
okay let's move forward
so let's start from the initial axis and
here we have
the answer to
uh the question that you may have why
this stock is called needs among the
beats
so two main
initial access technique they use
is compromising vpn credentials they can
buy it they can
exploit public-facing application
everybody remember i think pulse secure
and vulnerability in photogate that was
really really often
used by lockwood affiliates and many
other ransomware at the service program
affiliates and of course rdp
these guys
perform brute force attacks and they
rely on some vulnerabilities and rdp to
gain initial access so
talking about our needs
here is why
this talk was named like this because
during the analysis of threat actor
slang
we found out that
they call
then they use compromise vpn account
to
gain initial access to the compromise
network
they call it
and they want their virtual machine to
be into the network they call it to neat
into the network
so
they put
they get vpn access they put their
virtual machine with all those pin
testing tools like metasploit cobble
strike
crack crap map exec and all that
and start their post exploitation
activities or they just
perform a brute force attack
against 3dp get the password or acquire
both rtp access or vpn access from
initial
access brokers and then perform their
post exploitation activities so quite
simple these two techniques are the most
common
for log bit ransomware
but it's not all
they are trying to expand their
capabilities
and
here are two messages from very popular
forum that is used by
various right actors including
ransomware gangs
the firm is called xss dot is
and here are two messages so
in the first message uh
log bits up that's the official account
that is used by
uh logbit ransomware the service program
runner
he asked if anybody can provide him the
contacts
of
the owner of trigbot
and the second message
he
posts about that he's still looking for
contacts of trickbot creators so what
does it mean
uh
lockpit
wants to expand
its capabilities and to expand its
affiliate capabilities for initial
access so they already have experience
with exploiting public facing
applications they already have
experience with brute force and rdp they
have experience with using compromised
vpn accounts
to gain initial access but
uh there are other ways for example
spearfusion with malicious attachments
to infect victims with bots like cubot
trig bot iced id and all that and for
example
another competitor to be
the most active group is conti and this
group is using trigbot and bazaar
and cubot and icd and so log bit uh
wants
uh its affiliates to have similar
capabilities so most likely likely in
the nearest future we'll see that
even
more diverse initial access techniques
are used by this protector including
spearfishing emails including
uh delivery of trick board bazaar load
and all that
okay
once the protectors
got access
to the compromise network while vpn is
one thing they can use their uh own
virtual virtual machines with better
stools scanf vulnerabilities for example
discuss it later
but
let's say
they got to the network uh using rdp
brute force and potentially they already
have some elevated credentials because
very common talking about
such attacks then
ransomware affiliates attack public
facing rdp service
they may
get
for example administrator accounts that
already have local administrative
privileges so they
can use quite a lot of tools
for post exploitation already because
they have
their feet on the land they have access
to at least one server and maybe
that's kind of terminal server and even
uh guys with domain admin accounts may
usually hang on these or for example
uh this initially accessed
administrative account that's
administrator account then the network
may have the same password for local
administrator account and the same
account name for the whole network so
they can start moving laterally
immediately
but still
many networks and many servers they have
at least some security controls
implemented and at least some security
products installed so in most cases to
drop
more tools for post exploitation for
example to dump credentials to start
scanning network to start active
directory reconnaissance they need to
disable such tools so
if we are talking about log bit
affiliates they very often use various
rootkit detection tools so originally
these tools
were aimed at
defending
the host or finding abnormal or
malicious activity
but
in the hands of red actors such tools
can be used to
bypass defenses to evade defenses so
uh if you're talking about log bit quite
common tools are the following so first
of all heron
h rs word then process hacker and pc
hunter some of these tools for example
protest hacker and pc hunter
are quite common for various groups for
example especially those who are focused
on other people's faults
like dharma like phobos and all that
uh if we are talking about her own
interest work it's quite uncommon tools
with asian origin
but again if we are focusing on
underground forums and all this we
may notice that
the person behind log bits
account log beats up
in some thread he posted that
now he is living in china so maybe due
to this fact
uh
arsenal of uh their affiliates uh
includes some tools
that are usually used in china or other
asian countries
okay let's move forward
of course anti-root kit tools are not
the only tools that are used to for
defense evasion
just like many other
ransomware as a service program
affiliates
logbed affiliates use various scripts
uh to disable antivirus software
uh in some cases it's just one liner
like you can see on the slide for
example to disable a set they use wmic
and try to
uninstall it
and another example with windows
defender this time protectors attempted
to use powershell to disable it
in other cases there may be
page files that include quite a few
antivirus software vendors so in some
cases uh threat actors may use more
opportunistic approach so they not
target on specific antivirus software
that is installed and they don't perform
any reconnaissance for example with the
same process hacker they may just look
through running processes to identify
uh which antivirus software installed
and try to
disable this antivirus software they
just just may have a batch file that
tries to disable
almost
any possible
antivirus software products so that's
another approach they may be used so it
depends on the affiliates of course
and one more thing
apart from disabling
antivirus
protectors may
try to
make instant response or forensic
analysis or instant investigation more
complex because
especially in our recent incident
response engagement
the third actors attempted to
wipe folders with their tools so for
example they
wanted to
they wanted
c windows temp
to be their staging folder there they
drop all their tool set tools for
exaggeration tools for network scanning
uh
some
parts of post exploitation frameworks
and all that
and once they perform these activities
they just wiped the contents of these so
you won't find files sometimes you can
recover it
sometimes you can just
extract this information
from various forensic active artifacts
like m cache sim cache some windows
event logs and all that
but still you won't find the files
next thing
uh as they move literally quite heavily
so
you can usually find quite a lot of
valuable information
in windows event log files and
they want to clean
such locks as well so as you can see on
the slides there are quite simple power
shell while uh one liners so first one
was used by logbit affiliates to
wipe
uh
the staging folder that they
stored all their toolset and the second
is uh
to clean the event logs because they
don't want instant responders to track
their activities and they want the life
of instant respond responders be more
complicated unfortunately
okay
credential access
of course in some cases
protectors may ex have access to
elevated credentials immediately
uh
for example if they boot first local
administrator account
but still they need more because they
want to move laterally
that's why they need
in perfect world they need the main
admin account or at least
local admin account that has the same
username and the same password on
various hosts
uh lockwood affiliates still use memory
cards just like many other ransomware
gangs
this tool is really really easy
can be really really easy detected but
as we already discussed
in many cases protectors disable
antivirus software and other security
controls so they can
easily use
any hacking tool
for credential dumping and all that so
they
use this capability and this opportunity
and still uh vc mimikaze very often uh
they may rene rename it for example
to mimi.xy for
x64 or x86 dot xz or just one dot xz it
depends on the affiliates but still
because it's widely used
what else
they also use various tools
by neurosoft
so some examples include
internet explorer pass view router pass
view web browser pass view mail pass
view and many many others so usually
they just drop an archive that includes
all these tools that are downloaded from
the official news website
and they run it in a very optimistic
manner they
don't know
what kind of credentials
can be captured they just run everything
and collect
and excel trade all information that is
collected and then they're thinking
about
which passwords and which account can be
used
in the future during their post
exploitation routine
uh
one more thing is just regular
legitimate tools they can
transfer such tools from the c2 or they
may use just building tools like for
example tuscan gel that can be used to
dump or sauce
or they can use sprouts down to double
sauce or they
may
abuse other living of the land
techniques to dump it
so
uh techniques for credential access are
quite plain and quite simple but still
very very effective especially if
the threat actors disabled antivirus
software already
okay let's move forward
and
talk a bit about reconnaissance
just like other protectors that are
focused on rdp access or vpn access
log with affiliates use various network
scanners
during almost any intrusion so very
popular examples include soft perfect
network scanner i think this network
scanner is
the most popular network scanner among
all ransomware gangs that are operating
nowadays other examples include advanced
ip scanner angry ap scanner and advanced
sport scanner so these scanners can be
downloaded freely from the internet in
some cases threat actors use
build in
capabilities like web browsers to
download it from the official website
especially when they are talking about
rdp access
uh enel brood a quite popular tool for
performing brute force attack against
rtp servers
of course it's used
for obtaining the initial access but
it's not
the only thing
for attackers use it for
uh another thing uh as they already have
some credentials for example they have
administrator account or some other
account and they want to check if it's
wedded on other hosts internet so they
maybe they don't need to dump more
credentials and they may use
already compromised accounts to move
laterally and to deploy ransomware so
quite easy so that's why anal root can
be used on initially compromised host to
check
these accounts
again as
they may already get some
credentials
they may dump some credentials via
mimikats they can brute force some
credentials again there is another tool
we observed them to use for credentials
checking this why
this time this was abusing smb and it's
very popular and called handwork
assembly autobrood
so
again one more tool for testing obtained
credentials
and
another tool i think
anybody who's involved in penetration
tests in the red teaming
is well aware about it is bloodhound and
especially
uh the part of it that's called that's
called shophound
that's used uh by logbait affiliates to
find religious relationships within an
active
directory environment and discard the
attack paths so
where they need to get to to
dump elevated credentials they need for
proper lateral movement data
exfiltration
and of course ransomware deployment
so as you can see
uh protectors use quite a few tools of
course not of all these tools will be
used in just one attack it based on
various
instant response engagements
we had
okay let's move forward lateral movement
once
fret actors got initial access
once they got elevated accounts and
and they already
uh perform basic reconnaissance
oh
in some cases they already know quite a
lot about the network they are ready to
move later so first of all they used rdp
even if they got initial access via rdp
they can still use it to jump from one
host to another
this type of access is extremely common
and many protectors including lock but
affiliates they even have batch files
they can execute remotely for example
yps exec
to enable rdp and remote hosts and they
really love it and they use it very
often
of course plus exploitation frameworks
metasploit cobble strike crack map exec
very important point here regarding all
these so of course they use cobble
strike and metasploit quite often crap
map exec it's not that popular but still
we observed some incidents where the
affiliates use this framework
but what's more important is
mainly they focus on vpn and rtp access
so
they may
not use it
very extensively instead they may uh
just
use rtp to move laterally and then uh
they may choose one or two servers there
they'll execute cable strike beacon and
use it for redundant text so for example
this server may be even not encrypted by
ransomware
and
maybe instant responders or system
administrators of the company they may
just keep it thinking that
protectors didn't do anything malicious
on that
and such servers with beacons they may
allow for attackers to resell access or
just get back
to
ask for ransom again
or
just to
deploy ransomware again if the victim
refused to pay
so that's very important thing even if
you don't see
any evidence of cobalt strike usage make
sure you connected data from as much
hosts as possible and you are sure that
the fractal actors didn't use it
uh
next thing is putting
nowadays log bits also provides linux
version to its affiliates so they need
to move laterally not only in windows
environment
but in many cases they need to get from
windows environment to linux environment
and they need tools
for this so based on our experience and
our instant response engagements we
absorb that the fret actors use put it
to
perform sage connections to linux hosts
and deploy log bit
and of course again as we already talked
about vpn access uh and that protectors
prefer to knit into the network
of course they use various
vulnerabilities especially tunnel blue s
and b ghosts and zero log on to
move laterally once they get vpn access
and once they put their
uh
pen tests and virtual machine into the
network
let's uh talk a bit about redundant
access separately a bit
so first of all
in almost any instant response
engagements with
lobbied we observed that the threat
actors
used legitimate remote access tools
so
some trivial examples include any desk
but in some cases they may use very
uncommon and
hardly
detectable
tools like remote desktop plus
again if we are talking about networks
the
company use one or maybe a few
are rdp servers and protectors may for
example create additional accounts
and if such servers
are
public are still public facing after the
incident then the threat actors
especially if the victim refuses to pay
they may use such service to get back
into the network and perform post
exploitation
again and deploy ransomware or extra
trade data one more time so fdp is one
of the most common
and most popular building tools that are
used by various protectors and just like
i already mentioned
cobblestrike a very very very popular to
amount any ransomware
affiliates
so
this is used quite often and again as i
mentioned on the previous slide they may
execute beacon on just one server and
use this beacon
uh to get back to the network if
the company started remediation process
for example
and blocks vpn accounts blocked
public facing rdp access and all that
they still may use that small common
strike beacon on one of the servers to
get back
okay so
one of two main goals of the thread
actors is data acceleration
uh
protectors use various tools uh in some
cases and they used even web browser but
usually we are talking about web browser
thread actors don't trade a lot of data
using the browsers they may accelerate
for example as elsa's dump they created
or some or things like that if we are
talking about accentuation of large data
sets like 10 gigabytes 100 gigabytes
uh that's
very common
for my ransomware fees to execute
large datasets they use appropriate
tools so first tool we observed was
filezilla
absolutely legitimate tool
of course configured
to transfer data to attack a control
server
next tool that's very important among
a lot of
different protectors
are we will
[Music]
and many others hive
is
win scp
block better figure is used as well and
the most interesting tool that is used
nowadays by the threat actor is stillbit
it's custom tool
that's provided to log bit affiliates
as part of ransomware service program so
they
may use not only ransomware but also a
stealer that can automate
their acceleration activities
and make life of affiliates much easier
let's focus on it a bit so
as you already noticed i think
blockbit
ransomware service program runners they
like
to provide comparison tables to their
potential affiliates these tables are
located on their official dedicated link
site so both for log bits and four steel
bit
so they claim that their ransomware is
the fastest in the business and their
stealer is the fastest in the business
as well
another very interesting thing
they can notice uh on this screenshot
is
log bit provides
other means that
his affiliates or other ransomware sort
of program affiliates use as you can see
it's our clone
and
also you can see that there are a few
examples of
common
cloud services that are used by many
ransomware adservers program affiliates
it's yandex it's mega it's mail.ru it's
pcloud so all these pieces of
information are very important as well
so you can use it to focus your
detection capabilities so to focus on
during instant response engagement so
uh
getting back to stillbit and some
highlights we saw first of all files and
folders for acceleration may be
specified by affiliates so it
they can use various
command line arguments that help them to
choose how exactly
acceleration process will be
so of course uh they can configure which
files of all for example system files
and systems and system folders may be
skipped during exfiltration process also
as some
organization may have
good detection capabilities
affiliates may specify the amount of
data to be extra traded over 15 seconds
so this can help them to avoid detection
and of course just like log bit
ransomware itself still beat can detect
itself after excitation process is
finished so we already learned that
affiliates tend to delete everything
from their staging folders they tend to
remove windows event log and of course
tools that are provided
by
uh log bits
runner
they
allow
affiliates to remove these tools
themselves as well
as i already mentioned uh
log bits have
its own
dedicated link site so here is a
screenshot from this site
usually there is some information about
compromised companies or at least they
claim they compromise these companies
and there is a timer
after this
data that was exfiltrated if it was
accelerated to be published on the
website if
the victim won't pay
so quite common many ransomware gangs
have this site and as i already
mentioned very important and interesting
thing is condition for partners and
contacts as ransomware service programs
were banned from popular
hacking forums
nowadays some protectors
publish information and contacts for
their potential affiliates just on their
own dedicated link site
so ransomware deployment once post
exploitation is finished they have
proper credentials uh
backups are removed
and uh everything else is performed
properly
uh ransomware affiliates logbed
affiliates they are ready to deploy
ransomware in some cases the process is
quite straightforward they just jump
from one host to another using rdp copy
runs away and secure executable and
double click it so it will run
in other cases they may copy
executable on the target hosts
and then use ps exec to execute it a
very common techniques used by many many
uh
ransomware affiliates not on the log
base
and
one thing that's less popular but still
used is group policy modification
so
this allows
a lot bit affiliates
to automatically create scheduled tasks
on remote hosts that will execute a
piece of ransomware
what's more important this is a built-in
capability
in log bits so
even if uh ransomware affiliates are not
uh very good in active directory
configuration they still can use this
piece of ransomware they just need to
execute it on a domain controller for
example and ransomware they will do all
the job for them
so let's finish
the stock with some highlights of log
bit 2.0
so of course it removes shadow copies
just like any other ransomware but using
two methods by the way using vss admin
and using wmic
uh
files encrypted with
as128
in cbc mode so if
you don't have access to private key
then unfortunately
it's impossible to decrypt files
ransomware may mount and encrypt data on
file shares
so
if there are some
network shares then
if proper
things
are in command line with which
the ransomware
is executed then
network shares can be mounted and then
encrypted as well as and as i already
mentioned uh
it may create
group policy object for cell
distribution first of all and it's not
all because
it can add
other very important from protect this
point of view things for example
a batch script to stop various services
and processes both antivirus and some
processes that for example
lock the files from encryption
and it can add a group policy that will
disable windows defender
finally just like steel bit it may
remove itself after execution
so that's it
i hope
this talk
was quite
interesting for you
and you will use
information on tactic techniques and
procedures described in
in your instant response engagement and
to tune your detection logic
still if you have any questions
i'll be online and
are ready to answer all of them in
discord thank you
you