hello cactus khan
welcome welcome welcome
thank you for coming to my talk
and thank you to the organizers for
running this awesome conference and
having me back
it's actually a second time i present at
cactus con so excited to be here i must
have done something slightly right last
time
um and just happy to always be sharing
what we've learned
and giving it back to the community so
welcome again my name is george ortiz
and this talk is called operationalized
purple teaming
now this talk does pick up where we left
off
last time
and if you missed it at cactus con 9
i gave a talk with bryson bour called
the full purple juice not the watered
down stuff
and this covered how to run purple team
exercises now you may have heard of
purple teaming you may have done an
exercise already or maybe not if you
haven't don't worry we'll use the first
intro slides here to level up and make
sure that we're all talking the same
language and then from there we'll get
right into operationalized purple tv
for that we uh we'll get a little bit
technical as well
we are using a live and real use case on
leveraging cyber threat intelligence
to
emulate an attack and then be able to
detect and respond to it so
hopefully you're all excited or as
excited as i am i love purple teaming i
think it brings a lot of value
and uh
let's do this
so
the whole concept of purple teaming was
when
i looked back probably around 2014 2015
worked at a large financial organization
uh i had a big team
i ran a uh the offensive security team
there was everything from vulnerability
scanning vulnerability assessment pen
testing red team etc
and of course we had a very big blue
team that did security operations center
and uh
threat hunting
etc
we also had a cyber threat intel team
and what occurred is that all these
teams worked in silos
and this is what we're seeing in a lot
of organizations today you have your
blue team defending over there the red
team attacking uh on the other side kind
of adversarial there uh as far as
relationships and culture and then the
cyber threat intel team trying to
provide actionable threat intelligence
um so here you see them depicted as the
unicorns if you haven't seen these uh
unicorns these are our mascot over at
scythe where i'm the chief technology
officer and uh they make awesome
stickers so i'll uh i'll post uh some
info here see if you can get some swag
but the whole point of this was these
teams are working together are working
separately
in silos how can we bring them together
so that they work together and that is
the concept of purple teaming bring them
all together
not every day but bring them together so
that they collaborate and work together
so
again if you've never heard of purple
teaming let me give you a very quick
intro on that a purple team is a virtual
team where multiple roles work together
the roles are cyber threat intelligence
it's a team that does research on a
particular adversary understands the
adversary that is likely to attack the
organization
and grabs threat into what attacks have
uh these threat actors done what are
their behaviors
the red team is the offensive team
that's in charge of emulating those
adversaries in the organization
essentially testing the people the
process and the technology to see if
they can detect and respond
to that attack before
boom right before impact you always want
to be left of boom
and the blue team is a catch-all phrase
for the defenders
in your organization might be the
security operations center it might be a
managed security service provider you
might have a hunt team you have might
have a deferred team that stands for
digital forensics and incident response
and like i said purple team brings
everyone together so
we wrote a free resource here called the
purple team exercise framework and that
covers leveraging cyber threat
intelligence preparation
exercise execution and lessons learned
so you can continually improve so again
we presented this last year at cactus
con i'm gonna give you a little bit more
info on this and then we're gonna get to
the net new stuff which is how do we
operationalize this so from the cyber
threat intelligence phase
this was taken from katie nichols and
cody thomas sans summit talk uh a while
back and really loved this uh really
implemented this a number of
organizations um so essentially it's if
you are in cyber threat intelligence
your first thing is to understand the
organization understand um
the threat model
and identify adversaries are likely to
attack that organization an adversary
must have an opportunity an intent and a
capability to attack
once you pick a particular threat actor
an adversary that's likely to attack
then you gather threat intelligence and
the thing with gathering threat
intelligence is that there's a lot of
different types of threat intel nowadays
right you've seen most of these i'm sure
you've seen the
david bianco pyramid of pain that shows
different types of indicators
something like a hash value an ip
address a domain
those
while technically some threat intel
we're not really interested in that
we're interested in the adversary
behaviors in the pyramid of pain it's
called ttps tactics techniques and
procedures and this is what the threat
actor does their behaviors so
cyber threat intel needs to extract
those ttps
and then map them to mitre attack
miter attack is of course the common
knowledge that we use uh used to have to
explain this but i think by now everyone
understands attack right it stands for
adversaries tactics techniques and
common knowledge really a common
language between these teams are going
to work together between cyber threat
intelligence red team and blue team
so then we analyze and organize those
see because the cyber threat
intelligence is gonna come from what
they saw in an attack and how you see an
attack is not necessarily how you
perform an attack so we have to do some
work there and create an adversary
emulation plan
this essentially tells our sponsors and
our senior management this is what we're
going to do these are our goals these
are the objectives of the adversary this
is what we're going to test and see if
we are susceptible if we would
fall for this uh if we'd be impacted by
this adversary then we emulate the
adversary now that does require some
preparation
purple team exercises the prep phase
generally is longer than the actual
exercise that is true for red team
exercises as well if you've ever done a
red team engagement you spend a lot of
time on prep lots of people don't talk
about that right most people talk about
uh some new cool way of uh doing it some
trade craft but there's a lot of prep
that goes into this so
again all this is covered in the purple
team exercise framework which you can
download it uh on github it's totally
free um and i'm just
summarizing this for you here very quick
so we get to the operationalized purpose
in preparation we have to pitch a purple
team exercise to a sponsor show them the
value that is gonna come out of doing
these uh exercises we're gonna have a
number of preparation meetings as we
bring in the people that are going to be
part of the exercise we set up the
target systems
we normally do this in production
because that is where you have your
actual people process and technology you
can do this in a lab you can do this in
non-production
but if you want to test
uh and have actual real and timely
results productions can be the place to
go so if you do this on target systems
you need to ensure that all your
security tools are on there that you
have accounts that you're going to be
leveraging
and
of course the red team has to set up
attack infrastructure which is a whole
nother uh
talk but again covered there
the metrics metrics are important and
really in purple teaming and adversary
emulation as a whole we have changed the
metrics that we're used to right
if you think of a vulnerability we have
a cve a common vulnerability exposure id
it has a cvss score it has a priority
and
that vulnerability is either open or
closed right it's there or it's not
there it might be exploitable not
exploitable
when we talk about
purple teaming and emulating adversaries
and ttps a lot of these ttps you can't
just prevent it's not going to be closed
ttb you're going to be able to detect
that so we have to talk about data
sources did we have visibility
was there an alert
did our team see the alert was there a
response and then we get to a point
where we're actually tracking time
metrics you read one of those uh defer
reports or um
you see
a lot of time based metrics right mean
time to detection and these actors got
in there and they were idle for this
long so we want to measure them
and then it comes time for the exercise
we bring everyone together it's an
exciting time you have your blue team
talking to your red team to your cti
team some stakeholders some observers
and
the exercise coordinator goes in
presents the adversary says today we're
going to emulate this adversary these
are the behaviors that were observed
these are some technical details then
you have a tabletop discussion what do
you expect to occur when this particular
ttp is executed and you document that
it's interesting to see the expectations
from the different teams
then the red team is going to emulate
that adversary or that particular ttp
sharing the screen allowing for the
other teams to learn and see how an
attack works
and then we swap the blue team then
shares their screen they show
what is going on how they detect
something if there was an alert if there
was a log maybe they go threat hunting
because
it's a full knowledge exercise
if
something
didn't meet expectation or you determine
that you should probably have visibility
about this particular behavior then you
do detection engineering which again
it's a process of understanding an
attack understanding the data sources
and turning those on and then this loops
you go through and do multiple ttps
of course the whole point of this is
value uh here we have a screenshot from
plex track it's a great platform for uh
managing not just vulnerability
management but also red team and purple
team exercises it's really cool shout
out to our friends over there plexus
track and over here on the left you see
the first time we ran this emulation did
about 20 some ttps and there were no
alerts
no alerts means there's no response
right unless you have your threat
hunting team that found something as we
did the purple team exercise we were
able to trigger
13 alerts which
then allowed us to train our team our
team saw the alert they followed their
process and they were able to respond to
that um
to that threat
so that
very quickly is a purple team exercise
again if you saw our previous cactus con
talk
uh
you you this is definitely just a
reminder
so
we left off we had this awesome purple
team exercise
and
everything went great but what happens
next
well you can continue to do purple team
exercises maybe in a monthly basis or on
a quarterly basis right where you bring
these separate teams together you do an
adversary emulation these exercises can
be a week long could be a day could be
two hours but what we started
implementing in organizations that were
maturing past these first couple of
exercises was an operationalized purple
team and that's what we're going to talk
about here something that we've
implemented and seen something that you
can take home and do yourself
so what's an operationalized purple team
that's dedicated internal teams doing
cyber threat intel red team blue team
and then working together when that
cyber threat intel comes in new threat
is out there we hear something on the
news let's do that as a new ttp is
discovered it's analyzed and if it's net
new it's tested
and then we are starting to see some
dedicated purple teams uh in some
organizations mostly in the financial
sector that of course is not a
requirement but we did put something out
called the purple team maturity model
because now you have this process that
your people are following called purple
teaming and you want to track and see
how it matures and how it's improving
so that's what we're going to cover
today so let's focus on operationalized
purple what does that look like
new cyber threat intelligence comes in a
new report was just released microsoft
just released something or mandy or um
fireeye or sophos or whoever released
this new cyber threat until they have
observed an attack out in the wild
we
look at that and we essentially spawn
our team we get and assign someone from
cyber throne intel someone from the red
team someone from the blue team to work
together
they then go and they analyze this
threat intel they're gonna read through
it they're going to extract those ttps
map them to attack if it wasn't already
done by the cyber threat intel provider
and we are going to correlate this with
previous tests let's see
if this anything here is net new if it's
net new we definitely have to test it
then
we do our tabletop discussion
what are the expected detections and
response to these ttps
you document those
and then the red team goes and they
emulate the attack they show how to do
the attack of course this requires a bit
of work from the red team understanding
how that threat uh perform those attacks
those procedures and then
we have our blue team doing detection
engineering now that they saw the attack
they can enable uh
the logs and create alerts and then
train their team
to be able to see this now the original
purple team exercise framework did not
cover that so
about a month ago we released version
two of the purple team exercise
framework that's open for comment we
actually put it out on github make it
easy for anyone to read it but also
contribute to it so these steps are all
outlined in this free framework that you
can download um on github
so let's do a
use case here like i said i like doing
uh actual real life things so
step one new cyber threat intelligence
comes in one of my favorites is the
deferr report the default report is free
you can sponsor them and i actually
recommend that you do if you start
leveraging the information that they
have
so the deferred report you go to the
deferredreport.com they released these
reports of real intrusions by real
attackers and you read that right there
on the headline right the truth behind
the intrusion
and i love them because they provide
lots and lots of detail so
it's december 13th
the fur report comes out
we now can
begin our operationalized purple team
process now threat intel doesn't just
have to come from free and open source
resources right uh it could come from
the internal cyber threat intelligence
team from internal vendors from red team
maybe the red team found something new
a new method of doing something
cool that's what the red team does right
so it could come from them or it could
come from the blue team maybe the blue
team observed a new attack
that
isn't on mitre attack
right that happens
actually to be added as a technique
in mitre attack
it must have been seen in the wild
so we have a little bit of a chicken and
egg problem where maybe the red team
found something new maybe the blue team
observed a real attacker doing something
new
you can still work with that it doesn't
actually have to be on attack tech is a
great way to start
now if you do see something new do
contribute it to attack attack has a
sightings so you can actually let them
know
and uh they'll get added to the next
version of mitre attack
so regardless of where the cti comes
from
it has now triggered our process our
operationalized purple team process so
we notify the purple team you can do
this and through a ticketing system you
can do it through a tracker there's
multiple ways of actually implementing
this right uh from project management
tools to um
to even your vulnerability management
solution that you currently have
to any ticketing system right so however
you want to integrate it you notify
everyone that's considered part of the
purple team that a new
uh new cti has come in then
you can either self-assign this so i'm
looking i see oh look something new came
in oh i like the default report let me
assign this to myself or of course a
manager can assign this to you
essentially you need cyber threat intel
red team and uh blue team together so
new cti comes in we initiate the purple
team
all right
so we have initiated
the purple team
that was uh the power rangers if you
have no idea what what you just saw it's
okay it's how i insert comic relief and
a
chance to to have a sip of water while
uh well you all watch a quick video
so
we have brought the red uh the red blue
and cti teams together
our next step here is to analyze and
organize the ttps
and in that step we need to extract the
tactics techniques and procedures the
behaviors and map them to mitre attack
so one of the reasons i like the d4
report
is that they do some attack mapping for
you over here on the right you actually
can see
this is the bottom of that rapport and
i'm gonna demo it here shortly
and there's already some miter attack
mapping
now the thing with miter attack is that
these are
techniques
not procedures right ttps are actually
three different things
tactics which are the goal of the
attacker to gain initial access
a technique
spearfishing with a link
and an actual procedure of how did they
do that spear phishing email right
so
while mapping to miter attack is great
in purple teaming and adversary
emulation we actually need procedure
level details
and the d4 report is great at providing
those procedures
but
they're not provided in a
consumable way
we have to consume them and go through
our process which i'm going to show you
here so let's just read a little bit
from the top here the malware bazaar
loader was delivered to an endpoint via
email which included a link to onedrive
the onedrive link directed the user to
download a file that was a sip which
included an iso inside
once open mounted
on the user system it was determined the
iso contained a link file and a dll
the link file masqueraded as a document
enticing the user to click and open it
once the user executed the link file the
bizarre loader infection was initiated
that's a great paragraph it tells us a
lot
were you able to pick out
all the
ttps from there
spear phishing link right with a one
drive
there was an iso file there was a sip
file those are defensive asian
techniques
there was a link file which required
user execution that's another technique
and there was a dll
so quite a bit of ttps there
um just uh in that one
paragraph
so let's
take a look at some more graphical views
so the default report also provides a
timeline we can see here the original
execution was from a downloaded bazaar
loader sip from one drive that had a iso
mounted
has a dllx executed and it had c2
command and control to some ip on port
oh c2 as well
and down on the bottom we also have
another image that this iso file had a
dll
and a documents dot link that documents
dot link rand run dll32.exe
with a dll called
sharedfiles.dll and an entry point of
basic score
okay
so let's analyze this for real now we
read through this and let's break it
down over on the right we have our
actual procedures so tactics the goal
initial access that was through
a spear phishing link and the procedure
was the malware was delivered to an
endpoint via email which included a link
to onedrive
then
there was an iso
an iso
is
a
defense evasion technique
and
we know this because i've actually done
some work on that one before
uh so the ttp for that is actually one
five five three zero zero five which is
subvert trust controls mark of the web
bypass
mark of the web we'll talk about this in
a little bit
then
there was a that link
uh ran or run dll dll32
there's user execution right the user
actually has to double click
that uh link so we have user execution
there and then c2 was set up over 443 so
command and control is the tactic and
the technique is application layer
protocol over web protocols https
and then
buzzer loader was observed executing the
well-known uh
windows discovery commands 10 minutes
after execution
so
let's take a look at this let's jump
into our first demo here
and uh again shout out to the default
report
we uh read this first paragraph here
and extracted a number of ttps right at
the procedure level but we can continue
to read the case summary and as we go
down there's a timeline which is
fantastic
right covers three days of this
particular attack
and then it's broken down by
technique uh tactic initial access via
one drive link we get more information
about that
when uh the link is downloaded it's a
dot sip and actually here we see the
name of the sip new dash documents dash
thousand five that doesn't sound like
new documents but okay
uh i guess it worked in this particular
instance
and then that brings down an iso
then we have execution another tactic
how did that happen we see run dll and
look here we actually see the shortcut
it's a documents is the name
and
it has a little documents icon but the
target actually runs run dll32
with
uh pulling in that shared dll and the
entry point of basic score this is all
going to be important for emulation
and here we have that image i showed
and
two of the c2ips are the ips important
to us
no right we're not going to use those
ips in our attack we're not simulating
we're emulating
and so there's a bit of that there's
persistence
and actually it isn't all the way until
we get to discovery
that we actually find the next set of
steps see the attacker did discovery 10
minutes in
but in this threat intel report we
actually had to scroll down quite a bit
to find that that is when they did that
right and here we have some discovery
then they executed cobalt strike
surprise surprise it's a ransomware
attack of course they used cobalt strike
and then they ran some other procedures
and then on the second day they did more
discovery so while the differ report
breaks us up in mitre attack tactics
we still need to analyze and organize
these
in uh our method so just so you see how
i go through these i break them down by
tactic technique and procedure and build
them out in a time method so very this
is the table i showed earlier
we wrapped up with the bazaar loader
observed executing 10 minutes later that
is a time-based evasion then discovery
multiple commands ran some with typos
um
and then they executed run dll32 again
then they did process injection then
they did discovery again etc so as we go
through this this is what i mean by
analyze and organize
so
that is
um a little quick demo there on the
threat intel part
we have built this uh
essentially
spreadsheet because that's the number
one infosec tool used the top tool ever
used by any infosight professional is uh
is a spreadsheet right so we've built
that out and now the question is
is there anything net new here well they
use cobalt strike we've tested that
right until our heart's content
hopefully everyone can detect some
cobalt strike in their environment but
really
spear phishing we've done that
uh run dll32 you should have definitely
tested that one already have some
detections in place because
lots of ransomware uses run dll32 really
the the one that stood out here
was that they used an iso image
what is an iso image
how does an iso image work
that an iso image was like to burn cds
back in the day for those young folks
out there before streaming we had cds
and we used to burn them it was a lot of
fun and not burn with fire burning is uh
building a cra i'm getting too much into
that hopefully everyone knows what a cd
is and we use iso images for that right
to this day you can download an iso
image for say installing the latest
version of windows nowadays you would
put down a usb put your machine up you
install from that iso image
now the interesting part of an iso image
is
that it is not formatted in ntfs
ntfs is the file system structure that
was introduced with windows nt that
stands for new technology came out
around
uh yeah poor naming convention but
we still use it today
the ntfs file system
allows for alternate data streams
alternate data streams means that you
can put different streams into what
appears to be a single file
and that is how mark of the web works so
when you download something from the
internet and you try to run it on
windows you generally get a message
right it's called smart screen pops up
and says hey you downloaded this from
the internet are you sure you want to
open that and of course everyone clicks
yeah open it anyway but it's a defensive
mechanism right
you might download a document you open
that document it says we're not enabling
editing here because you downloaded this
from the internet
that is done through mark of the web
now an iso file
is not formatted in ntfs and therefore
it cannot use alternate data streams
which means the file cannot be marked as
being downloaded from the internet
whoa cool
so attackers are putting their malware
in iso images
so that
they get around this control
and that is technique 1553.005
subverts trust controls with mark of the
web bypass so essentially you create an
iso
you put in a shortcut
you put in a dll
the shortcut executes run dll32
you then sip the iso and you upload it
to a public onedrive
onedrive
you've probably tested this you either
allow access to onedrive or you don't
allow access to onedrive you may be
monitoring onedrive if you are bless you
uh because there's a lot of stuff on one
drive right
so
we look and we see have we tested this
before now if you haven't tested this
before
where would you look to find a test
atomic red team
atomic red team is a free project uh
sponsored and uh ran by red canary
actually shout out to adam mashinshi uh
who's one of the the folks over at red
canary
um
uh and
they have a bunch of
simple tests
an atomic test one test
that allows you to emulate so you go to
atomic red team look up this ttp
t1553.005 and
it's not there
all right guess we got to build it
ourselves
so we move on to step three
step three
we
have a tabletop discussion you say look
what's net new here
iso files adversaries are using iso
files now so what's our visibility there
how can an iso file get into our
organization well
you can click on a link and download an
iso from the internet you can click and
download a sip from the internet
or maybe from an internal site
what about an iso attached to an email
hmm do we have detections there where
would we have those detections well
maybe our external security provider can
block iso files from coming in because
why would an iso file come in right or
maybe it is used do we have any
detections okay and you
brainstorm these
once the iso is in though
all it takes is a user double clicking
and that mounts the iso
any detections there
what about executing something from an
iso
and unmounting the iso and you have this
tabletop discussion with
the team with the purple team
then step four you emulate the attack
right this is would be the red team
has to figure out how to create an iso
right so
if you go do a little bit of googling
you find some stuff uh twitter is one of
my favorite places so shout out to uh
matt grabber at manifestation who posted
uh some stuff on this
um outflank also talked a little about
mark of the web i wrote a blog post on
scythe about mark of the web but we
actually hadn't done it through iso
so did a little bit of work there to
figure that one out
and what about creating a link file
most people know how to create a
shortcut well my friend john may sean
francois
um
over at trusted second a sans instructor
for the purple team
uh curriculum teaches security 699
advanced purple teaming
wrote a little tool
on
generating links
generating little uh dot link files
so we do some work we see some folks
have done some of this and we put it all
together that's what i've done here
essentially
wrote a step by step of how to emulate
this you set up command and control
using https on 443 and
through your c2 you generate a dll
payload
if you don't know how to do that you
need to go watch uh or look up the c2
matrix we show that in multiple c2s not
the scope here right
then
i actually created a folder and a github
uh repo
where you can download and do this very
easily it uses a project called folder
to iso so shout out to that essentially
it's gonna grab everything that's in a
folder and convert it into an iso
so you're going to put your dll into
that folder
you're going to create a short call
shortcut called documents
you're going to set the target
then you're going to run folder to iso
it's going to create this iso you then
sip it
you then upload it to onedrive and get a
public link to it
you
put that link in at a spear phishing
email you send it across someone opens
that email they click on the link it
will download a sip they unzip the
document they double click the iso to
mount it and then they double click
the shortcut to execute yeah lots of
user awareness training would go a long
way in this attack but it's a long chain
so let's do that one here real quick
all right i've actually already created
the sharedfiles.dll
with the entry point uh that we
mentioned
we are going to move this
over to the source directory that uh a
folder to iso
so we put the dll there
here is our documents link here's the
properties of it we can see here
executes run dll32 with
sharedfiles.dll and the entry point of
basic score
so
we're going to want to
go into this directory on a command
prompt
okay we're in that directory
and now we're going to
copy that so
copy and paste again this is all
provided for you here it is run dll32
here's the one liner
here we see it run
and it would have created an iso
right here in our
um downloads folder so
we now need to sip this
so
you can just do send to compress zip
folder
and there you go
now we take this
upload it to one uh onedrive get a
public link
send as a phishing email we're gonna
skip that step again
you
for fishing uh let's move this out to
here
all right so this is one machine called
helios
i have
um
a c2 running over here
this is sky
this is a machine that is our
victim we have placed this over in our
desktop
as if we download it we double click the
zip file
it has an iso we double click the iso it
mounts it as a drive
and if the user double clicks documents
nothing happens
right
um of course we know something's
happening in the background but the user
can actually close all that
and
they have no idea what's going on
if we go over to our c2
we actually have a new
system
uh sky just ran in
process id 30366
and then we have a shell and of course
we do everything else right but
everything else is not in scope of this
particular attack
we just did the net new part right
so we show this attack off um to
our blue team and our last step here is
detection engineering so in detection
engineering again it's a process um
there's a great detection engineering
workshop uh by chris peacock he's at
secure peacock um he's actually running
runs every month on how to do detection
engineering again kind of out of scope
of this but it's another process that
the blue team follows they come up with
a hypothesis for example an iso file
downloaded from the internet by a non-it
user is suspicious
an iso file sent via email is suspicious
and iso mounted uh by a non-it user
suspicious right and shout out also to
cyber monk on twitter
a great person to follow as well uh we
do a lot of back and forth and uh
twitter based purple teaming so i was
working with chris and i said hey chris
you got a sigma roll for this
and of course uh being a contributor to
sigma chris uh peacock from my team has
a lot of knowledge on this and found
this one quite quick
so
it's a sigma rule if you've never used
sigma it's great it allows us to build
these rule sets that you can import into
basically any
control you have any sim you have right
you can try you could put it as elastic
as splunk wherever you want
but as you read through this it's not
exactly what we're looking for this
detects the amount of an iso image on an
endpoint and it tells you the log source
you need which isn't
important for detection engineering
so
when we do detection engineering we need
to make sure that we're actually logging
what we need to do we have that data
source
is it logged locally
and of course you might have different
log sources here right one is the
mounting of an iso but what about the
downloading of an iso that would be in
your proxy
an email
with an iso attachment that would be in
your email
antivirus no antivirus isn't going to
catch anything is it
your edr
does your edr detect this
it should
it might have the capability to but have
you turned it on right
biggest problem with ddr is that it's
not something you just plug in right
it takes people in process to turn
things on
tune them for your environment
or sysmon sysmon logs right
then if you log locally is it logged
centrally
is it sent somewhere so that you can do
threat hunting at scale
and then can you build alerts that are
fine-tuned and do not create a lot of
noise well over here on the right randy
pragman uh who works over at binary
defense actually again twitter purple
teaming uh
posted this and showed me how they were
detecting this
and getting alerts uh at their manage
detection response solution um it's a
mssp of uh detection response they
showed the alert and then now that you
have an alert you repeat this so that
your
team when they see this alert they know
how to respond to it right so again
shout out to randy
lastly
we just built something new
let's contribute back
right you did all this work
why not put it out there i mentioned
earlier i looked in atomic red team it
wasn't there so i did the work and then
i worked um
with carrie and adam so shout out to
both of them at red canary uh carrie um
is one of the main maintainers of atomic
red team so shout out to her very very
helpful if you want to contribute to
atomic red team it's a free resource
least you can do is contribute right
if you use it so we put that out there
and now anyone can run and do this
so once you start opera operationalizing
your purple team you can start tracking
the maturity level
all right this is again process show
to your stakeholders that your their
investment in purple teaming is paying
off apart from having better detection
times and uh not getting impacted how is
the team actually doing this something
that we built internally
uh the
purple team maturity model was built by
tim schultz who works with me at site
and a lot of the work here as you saw
wasn't just me cyber threat intel with
uh natalie cano from my team
uh detection engineering from chris
peacock and we evaluate ourselves on how
we're improving
so to wrap up
purple team can be applied a bunch of
ways most organizations start with the
purple team exercise
they do a couple of these you can do
larger exercises smaller exercises and
then you can operationalize the purple
team now that that collaboration has
been built you can
trigger it when new ttps come out
following our process of analyzing and
organizing it table topping it emulating
and detection engineer and you
uh
rate yourself and improve through the
maturity mod
now if you like this stuff there's more
content available on threat thursday
this is a free community resource
uh essentially it's a blog series along
with adversary emulation plans we
introduce an adversary consume the cyber
threat intel
map it to mitre attack
present an adversary emulation plan
share the adversary emulation plan with
you on our community threats github it
is the largest public repository of
adversary emulation plans available for
you right there
then we emulate the adversary we covered
detection and response and
of course all free to the community so
all that is done because we love giving
back
if you want to learn more about purple
team uh and do some formal training we
have a free purple team workshop it runs
um at least once or twice a month so
head over to site dot io slash purple
dash team dash workshops completely free
it's about three hours you get your own
lab environment you don't have to pay
cloud fees because site pays them for
you so again just community
contributions that we love uh tim
schultz has an operation purple course
uh available uh and then of course sans
has two purple team courses security 599
defeating advance adversaries purple
team tactics and kill chain defenses
that one's more around preventing
and then sec 699 purple team tactics
adversary emulation for breach
prevention detection that one's 50 red
50 blue and the blue part is all
detection
no talk of prevention because you can
only prevent so much it's inevitable
that someone's going to get in
the our goal is to detect and respond to
them
faster than their impact
i always put references i did not do any
of this alone purple team exercise
framework is free
uh shout out to the deferred report for
providing the cti here um on site we put
this community threat out so not just
that particular initial access but
everything from the deferred reports
available there shout out to everyone on
twitter um that's helped out red canary
uh jean mays cyber monk uh the sigma
project chris peacock tim schultz thank
you all
and i put my uh about me page at the end
because if you're still here you still
care i appreciate you thank you for your
time um george ortiz the chief
technology officer at site um an author
and co-creator of the purple team
exercise framework the c2 matrix uh the
sans red team course i contribute to
mitre attack atomic red team cvss
version 3 and 3.1 uh the global
financial markets association thread led
pen test framework and i'm a fellow at
issa and a technologist fellow at the
national security institute thank you
again for your time i will take your
questions on discord and
have a wonderful day thank you cactus
khan you all rock
uh really appreciate you putting this
together
and uh we'll talk on discord have a good
one
you