hello everyone uh welcome to another
session uh my name is burhan and i will
be talking about what are we missing in
web applications so before going further
i would like to introduce myself my name
is mirza berhanbek and i'm oscp
certified along with some other
credentials ewpdx and ecppt etc so
my main core motive and my main core
research area nowadays is red teaming
and i'm more interested in thread
hunting and
web application is my core
so i'm working in web application and
mobile application penetration testing
field for around seven to eight years
now but i'm more into now red teaming
and trade hunting kind of things so um i
started my career as a bug bounty hunter
uh back in 2012 and 13. so
uh acknowledged by google microsoft
facebook amazon and these are the
few companies that are the top notch
there are a lot of list
that i am already listed in so by bounty
hunting hackers one you are already
aware of that right so uh you know the
potential of the bounty hunting uh i've
been working with uh many companies as
of rendered the third party consultants
as well uh so work for each and every
uh what we can say sectors or the
business units financial health business
energy utilities in the government
sector so i'm more
uh into the third party and the vendor
side so i got a chance to work with
different companies on the different
level with executives and to the
layman's as well so
so mainly uh i've been working with the
financial industries so the banks the
insurance companies and there are a lot
of things going on in the market so now
today's my topic for this presentation
is related to some financial and the
banking application but moving forward
uh i would like to just display the
major change and what are the current
roles and the what are the critical
vulnerabilities in the web application
nowadays there is a change we thought we
will talk about the change right
uh but the major change this is the os
top 10 i'm sure you most of you guys are
aware of this what is the os top 10 so
in the os top 10 we have a baseline we
have a framework to match and to compare
and to test the vulnerabilities and mark
them or we rate them as well we
calculate the cvs as a score as well so
we do a lot of things with this
benchmark or the baseline um
what we get reporting or the checklist
so in 2017 and previous prior to that we
are using oas
for a long time
so we are talking about the
uh 2017 uh checklist the injection was
on the top number one then broken
authentication sensitive data
xml entity injections xfs these are all
listed according to their criticality
right
but in 2021 2021 what we call it now uh
we have a revised list of the
vulnerability practicalities right so
now if we
just map it and we compare it where it
was and now it is on the top of the list
the broken access control things then
the injection will move to number third
and we have ssrf as well we have a lot
of things introduced in this new
checklist last checklist so this is the
current checklist if you download that
from the os website you'll find a lot of
things a lot of checks going on in the
new one
so my main question is change why why
there is need of a change for a change
why why why we change so
this is a human nature and this is
connected to everything everything
evolves so
how we are protecting our web
application back in the days now we have
to protect our web applications in
different manner and with a different
methodology right so we cannot protect
the web application as we were doing
previously so we have to obtain we have
to change we have to introduce new
methods and new techniques to break and
expect it once again so that's why we
need we need change in everything that's
why the os top 10 was changed previously
as well
so static and dynamic scanners as most
of the people are aware that we are we
will be talking about their scanners uh
manual assessments and all the other
things but uh to rest assured static and
dynamic scanners work uh on a very
different pace right most of you guys
know that but the vulnerability and the
issue that i will be discussing in the
further slides uh is kind of a
vulnerability that
no scanner can detect
without the human interaction you do
this static testing you do the source
code reviews you use the front end uh um
what we can say test the web application
from the front end with the like unit x
net sparker and many other scanners that
are available in the market i'm talking
about the commercial uh
scanners as well the specific kind of
vulnerability that cannot be detected
without the human intervention
is coming in the furthest lens so uh
just to be
on the safe side i would like to just
introduce an example to you guys that
how injections are protected focusing on
the sql injection how they are protected
previously and now how they are changing
in the factors so uh nowadays the
frameworks and all the other things are
very smart they protect the web
application or the
any kind of application there are
built-in security libraries built in
their plugins they have the
uh multiple things that are predefined
if you talk about the dotnet we have
multiple security libraries in the
cryptography in the injection input
validations and what's on whatnot so
talking about different vulnerabilities
we have frameworks we have libraries we
have multiple other things that are
protecting the web application from the
front end and the back end as well if
you follow these secure uh
coding programs or if you are following
that you're coding uh techniques so you
will be
uh seeing multiple things that you are
missing in the uh
code of the web application previously
but now you are putting the validations
as you like it and you are making the
web application or the
any kind of application much secure so
these uh this is just an example of the
sql injection i'm talking about multiple
other things as well so now if you move
forward to other vulnerabilities this is
the case for the other vulnerabilities
as well uh we have multiple things to
protect them but there's one thing that
cannot be protected until unless you put
a share place for the spine on that
thing that is a business logic flaw
so now
uh we are talking about the business
logic clause what are the business logic
flaws how they are uh arise how they how
we can achieve it how we can hack it and
how we can protect it so what are the
business logic plot uh i'm sure most of
you guys are very well aware of how
business logic flaws are around so what
are the business logic law a very simple
definition in the scheme uh there are
step a b c if you follow a the door will
be open b then there's a door c it will
be open after you open the door b so you
have to follow the sequence a b c but
you directly jump from a to c that's a
business logic flaw that you are not uh
allowed to access c without accessing b
but if you are accessing a uh c directly
from the a that is a visible logic for
so breaking any kind of logic breaking
any any any kind of logic you are
obtaining business logic flaw right so
what are the business logic flaws uh
vulnerabilities basically uh might be
you are losing your data you you might
lose your data or you might lose your
personal stuff as well because uh either
uh what we call it indirect object
reference vulnerabilities can be the
part of this as well you're accessing
the data without the permission of
another user or you are breaking the
logic of the system you're not
hacking someone but you're just breaking
the sequence of data or transmission
so how do these vulnerabilities arise
negligence simply a developer can put a
check on every protected thing but if
they are missing somewhere something and
they are not checking the station or if
they are not checking the um
user roles basically so you are
destroying your web application or the
system application and you are allowing
someone you just change the name or just
repeat the request without login or
without user uh checking if that user is
able to or if that user should be
viewing this or not but if you are
losing that you might lose your data as
well
uh what is the impact of the business
logic flaws vulnerabilities um in my
view of disaster
why
uh if you follow hacker one or other bug
bounty programs the most most highly
highly paid vulnerabilities are of
business logic plot where an attacker or
researcher tries to um inject the
their own logics or they try to break
the logic or the sequence of the logics
so they are most highly paid
vulnerabilities so for the sake of the
example uh there was a boy who tried to
bypass the otp system mechanism of the
instagram right um if you remember that
that's perfectly fine if you don't go
and check that article as well a boy
tried to bypass the otp in the instagram
uh portal and he was able to bypass it
perfectly
as per my knowledge uh they paid him 20
000 us dollars
that's a big amount they fixed that
he tried to do that again somewhere
and he bypassed that once again so they
paid him 15 000 us dollars again so in
total 35 000 us dollars for a single
vulnerability that was a business logic
flaw so if your business logics are
perfectly occupied perfectly designed
no issues not to worry about a thing
from this side but if there is the logic
law in your web application that might
create a disaster for you
so
what are the common vulnerabilities in
business logic flaw we call it blf in
short uh the most common vulnerabilities
are i'll i'll just put it like that uh
we trust user
we trust user that they will follow the
intended sequence but nowadays everyone
is smart so we don't follow sequence
right we want to check the application
we want to dig into the application as
there are a thousand and multiple
100 of thousand developers
testers qa testers security consultants
they're in the market they're in the
boom so they do their job seriously but
they do take the vulnerabilities in the
web application then as well so you
cannot uh just stretch that
user will follow the intended sequence
so this is the main perspective so you
have to protect everything that comes in
your way
uh failing to handle unconventional
input does come with the input
validation thing so you have to make a
validation request for every every
everything so first of all if you are a
developer or you are owning a website so
just check the input validations on all
input that are coming from the front and
to the back end so you can put a a
healthy healthy white list drag on the
blacklist checklist in your web
application so you will be protected
properly
so
if you are trusting the client side
controls uh please don't because the
lines and controls can be bypassed at
the bottom
if you are not aware of the burp suit
just download it and play with it you
will be amazed how it will be changing
your web application data from the front
end so our user won't always supply
mandatory input for example if i'm
asking you the date of birth so date of
birth
might contain hyphen or slash for the
special character list but if someone is
putting brackets if someone is using
dots or something else so this is the
species right so you have to see it as
well because you have to control the
input validation from the front end so
it won't be going to the back end
all right so moving forward i would like
to just hear an example uh that i came
across during my tenure for doing a
penetration testing for a bank so it was
an oracle system for financial fraud
management and i
found that vulnerability i disclosed
that vulnerability to oracle and it was
uh properly disclosed and
and cve number has been assigned to that
as well in 2019 so that vulnerability
was very simple uh there were two users
uh one was uh
a reporting user we only can see the
reporting and one was the admin of the
system right so the admin of the system
can see the logs and all the other
things as well while on the other hand
uh the reporting system uh user was just
able to see the report so what i did i
just captured all the requests and the
response from the
verbs tool so there were two people if
you can see on the left hand side and
unless ep and any list and why so i just
manipulate and i change the request ids
and multiple parameters in the request
and i'm gonna try to follow the sequence
and i try to break the sequence how
capturing the request from the admin
users all the requests and playing with
that uh with the normal user that was
the analyst
the reporting uh
user so by playing multiple times
multiple times multiple times i try to
do that and somehow i bypass the
and i am able to see with the analyst
uh normal user the reporting one that
has low privilege uh in his bucket
so i try to just forward the request and
i can see all the logs and all the other
things in my system these are the new
alerts that were dated and analyst
we can see that analyst sc is able to
see all the alerts so these are the
system alerts you can use any any kind
of search and you can uh see the logs
and all the other things as well so this
is the main vulnerability of this uh
complete program that you can manipulate
the user data from the front end and the
server responding you without verifying
its user identity uh that is is that
users
already logged in or if that is capable
of viewing that
or if that is already assigned to that
user but without verifying they are just
displaying the data so that was a
vulnerability a very critical
vulnerability for the bank as well
secondly uh there was another
application i tried to just bypass it
without any burp without anything that
was the logic i'll try to explain that
but that is a very very um
common thing that we try to do while we
do the test and this is very very uh i'm
might say interesting at a funny on the
same time how uh there was a login right
username and password we tried to put
the username and password and the
sequence say that it will be sending a
otp uh just like any other banking
applications okay so i check the uh
sequence username and password then
there's an otp send on my mobile number
i forward that encode to the application
and it's logged in so these are the
sequence right then i try to do one more
thing i try to just not put the original
otp i try to uh make a request with a
non-valid invalid request the ot so i
tried to put the username and password
correct when it asked for the passcode
that is an otp uh
i try to put zero zero zero zero one two
three four five six seven
or any random number that i like but it
says invalid passcode and it when we
press ok it redirect back to the
username and password field as you can
see on the uh third image and the bottom
one b pentas one and the password
something something
now when i press the login it doesn't
check the odb and it just opened my bank
account so the sequence it when you when
you put the username and password and it
asks for the otp you put the wrong otp
it says invalid passcode you just press
ok go back to the login screen for the
username and password once again and it
won't be asking you otp again boom so
the check was checked for the otp once
but it was not checking the otp every
time i'm providing the username and
password so this was a very interesting
and funny on the same
time very very very interesting finding
for us as well because we were not
expecting it we were trying to just fire
up our burp suit and all the other
things to test the web application for
this bypass but somehow
uh we never
burn our burp shoot either so we we just
found it so sometimes what happens you
find the vulnerabilities that are on
your way that are not that much hidden
but we
neglect them because
we think these are
very very low hanging fruits but
trust me check everything
follow every sequence and do anything
you want to do with the application
you'd never know which thing will be
exploited and which thing will be
bypassed
so moving forward to another financial
application that was the internet
banking system i try to bypass the otp
here as well
how i try to capture every and response
from the server to the machine and
mercedes server and i put it in a
notepad a sequence of the notepad uh
there were 20 30 note pairs i if i
remember are tabs on the notepad plus
plus so i try to capture every request
in the response that house are
responsing on every request i'm making
to the server so this is the key point
you have to keep everything with along
with you um you never know with work and
which will not work so in this
particular example what we did we try to
put the username and password as always
are correct
it's then the otp right so what we did
uh we checked the server response we put
the correct otp for example there's a
highlighted dnn uh text otp underscore
text four one three
three four two you see the otp right so
this is an otp we put that and we
observe that the server is sending the
page redirect something something and
home.aspx
so this is a valid credentials valid otp
and a valid response from the server so
what i did i try to just copy it and
save it in my file so i can see how
server is sponsoring responding when i'm
putting valid things
then i try to change something uh in the
next request and respond what i did i
just put uh invalid otp so let's have a
look at that as well on the left hand
side the topic screen uh
you can see that i put the username and
password and then ot
uh incorrect otp by the way so the
response for provided otp is incorrect
so server responding that the otp that i
put was incorrect and it was not
bypassing uh to the dashboard of the
home screen so what i did remember i
just saved a valid response from the
server in the previous request i just
copy and paste that request in the
response in the burp suit and forward it
and the server without checking the user
it just observed that the section is
valid so it showed me the dashboard of
the phone screen so i can see the home
screen and the dashboard on the right
hand side so this is how i bypass this
third application by just following and
breaking the sequence and just copy and
pasting so the page over here is once
again copy every request and response
you are making against the web
application you never know which one
will work so
security design flaws we all know that
business logic flow arise from the
security device law because the logics
are failed that the design is failed so
there is a business very close and where
are we lacking so you remember the
example previous example i did uh with
the second application i just bypassed
the otp by just putting wrong and going
back and log enemy
this particular image is from the ports
for your website and it's showing the
same thing attempt one you went valid
attempt to password invalid you know
password invalid with m3 bypass boom you
are into the database or that much you
know the system application anywhere you
want
so we have to focus on the design clause
as well if we are talking about that
methodology is to test your application
see in the first few slides i say no
static or the dynamic scanner can work
for the business logic law so how we
gonna test it how we do it so there are
a few things that you can use for the
burps tool the fourth thing is automatic
there's a plugin available for the burp
suit you can download it you can use it
and you can just repeat the workflow
with the different user groups and the
role i personally will uh
give you the
guide for that as well in the upcoming
slide but uh over here i just would want
to uh include a thought that whenever
you are trying to test an application
just take three or four different roles
user along with you and just check them
uh vice versa across them as well
so what to look in source code
um you just have to divide and model the
workflow that will help you a lot a lot
because a smaller application will work
but if you're talking about the
large scale application the erp system
and these kind of things so you have to
divide and model your workflow to
identify where controls were carried out
and where they are not carried out and
how much access you need to get someone
or how much the access a specific group
needs so you have to be very particular
what business rules process are doing
what is supposed to do basically you
have to
gather all the information understanding
of the url any kind of application then
how it is working then you can secure it
right so if you talk about the what you
have to ask if you are a developer if
you're a cu if you're a security
consultant if you are a design designer
for the application you are the
architect of the application you have to
be very particular about these things
how by what means you are getting the
data when how often for how long you are
obtaining the data or you are sending
the data out where to variant from where
from where the data is coming to where
the data is going and who is sending the
data for how much time taxes will be
granted towards what with what whom from
room to room with room for whom from
where you are getting the data you are
processing the data you are struggling
the data in the database
storing for the temporary purpose then
you are moving from the temp folder or
something and if you are deleting from
the term why and how they are being
carried out so there are thousands of
questions that you can create the
thousand of questions you can ask to the
business owner or the application owner
or the infrastructure owner as well so
you have to ask a lot of things before
going for a launch of the product so
thank you very much everyone for your
time and i'll see you in the next
session in coming years um this is the
thing that you have to focus the
business logic flaws these are the main
key components of your web application
where you like the most because you
secure that skill injection you secure
the accessories but you are focusing on
the logics of your web application or
any kind of presentation
thank you very much everyone for your
time and i'll see you around thank you
bye
you