hello today i'm going to talk
about a well-known smell some of you
might remember my talk
at both 2018 in which i presented the
evolution of snake which is another name
for the infamous chola apt group
and i'm back to present what changed
since 2018.
in the past two years we investigated
several incidents
involving two online high-profile
organization
i'm matu faux a mario researcher at
essex
and my day-to-day job is to track apts
using the reset telemetry
first who is tiola according to this
recent tweet from the us cybercom
she lies injuredly a russian sponsor apt
they have been known for more than 10
years with for example the compromise of
the u.s military in 2008
using the infamous agenda ptz1
more recently they have compromised the
german foreign office
and several mailboxes belonging to the
french military
these are just a few public examples but
most of their attacks
are not public because jonah mainly
target organizations that don't talk
about
cyber security issues
in the past years the main target we
observe
are ministry of foreign affairs in
europe
government in central asia diplomats
in in the middle east
uh diplomats in south south america and
some private companies in
asia so for asia we don't have
first-team information but
this is based on submissions i saw on
various total
attackers motives is important when it
comes to defending against a specific
threat actually
to our knowledge chola conducts
espionage
operations and is interested in private
documents
of his targets contrary to other group
they do not push miners or run somewhere
thus it is likely that chola will stay
undetected for months
or even years
the generally collect document in bulk
meaning that it's not possible to
determine the subject of interest
just by looking at the accelerated data
this is an example of a mysql query that
your operators were
performing at regular interval to
collect recent documents
in the central database they show that
they were
interesting in doc docks and some
specific pdf files
this is another example that we found on
another organization
in that example they use the winrar
application
and they are collecting documents such
as dot pdf for excel files
from specific folder and the recycle bin
when it comes to compromise the target
the first step is to get
in in the machine over the past years
children have used techniques such as
spearfishing emails or money the middle
attack probably at the isp level
but this is not what we have observed
recently
since season 18 the main cause of
compromise are
importantly clean network and watering
all attacks
the former is quite common as it is
it is a challenge to totally clean a
network owns compromise with jola
watarimal attacks also known as
strategic web compromise
consists in compromising websites that
are visited by the
person you you want to infect in the
case of tyola
selected visitors are redirected to a
fake flash update page controlled by the
attacker
this is the summary of the last watery
mall attack
that happened in 2019
they compromised several websites
related to armenia
and the second one is interesting
because this is a ministry of the
republic of
artsakh and this is a region where war
took place
this fall between armenia and azerbaijan
on those websites they added a
piece of obfuscated javascript code
that is responsible for loading a
fingerprint script
from the cnc server so this fingerprint
script will send back to the cnc server
some information about the visitor
then if the visitor is deemed
interesting we believe that
this is a manual choice by the attacker
they will be redirected to a fake flash
update webpage then
the visitor need to manually click on
the link to download the fake flash
update and manually
execute it so there was no exploit
involved
then once you has executed the fake
adobe flash
update application
uh uh malware will be installed before
september
2019 it was skipper which is a
well-known
jolla first stage and then they switched
to a
newer malware families we called
netflash and pie flash
by flash being a custom python
background
as the main goal of tool is to stay
undetected for a long time
generally months or years there are a
few implants dedicated
to this task today i choose to present
three of them
the first one is light neuron
it persists as a microsoft exchange
transfer agent
which is a plug-in system for the
microsoft exchange
mail server and it's generally used by
anti-spam products
it allows full access on the uh
email traffic as uh it allows
to set up callback on events such as
when an email is received by the mail
server
so this is a summary of how the
backdoor part of lanyard works so this
is a passive backdoor
and in that case i will present a case
where the exchange server is already
compromised by like you know this is not
how they first enter the network and
compromise the
mesa i'm presenting how they can execute
command
on the server so turtle operator will
send an email to
any email address of the compromise
organization
and they will add a specially crafted
attachment
then this email will be received by the
exchange server
as like iran is installed as a transfer
agent
uh the one of its callback will be
called
so latvian will process the email check
the attachment if it's a pdf or a jpeg
it will check if
there is a specific signature if the
signature is there in main exact
it's an email that was created by a tool
operator
so it will extract encrypted data
decrypted and this decrypted data is
a command to execute and the command
will be executed
so it is a passive backdoor meaning that
black neuron is never reaching out
to a cnc server but this is the
controller actual operators is directly
sending commands and commands are
executed
the other function of live neuron is to
modify legitimate emails
so as i said before it has access to the
full email traffic of the compromise
exchange server
so let's imagine that someone is sending
a legitimate email
to to anyone in the in the compromise
organization
so the email will be received by the
exchange server uh as before it will be
processed by life neuron
then you will apply some it will apply
some rules
so this will define
xml and they are tailored for each
victim
so there is a rule enzyme in in line
neuron
and it uses a logic operator such as n
or and conditions
on specific fields of the email can be
specified
for example two-field or form field and
based on that
uh let me one will take some actions so
actions can be modify the email block
the email do nothing and
also dump the email on disk so in case
of modi
modification it's quite powerful as
we can imagine that um like neon can be
used to add some zero day in an existing
world or i don't know excel document and
then it will be
delivered to to the final receiver
finally there is another version of
knight neuron called netruns it's
fully in.net later on there is a one
module in dotnet
and also one module in cyprus plus for
for uh such things
things such as the rule enzyme but in
in netruns it's fully.net and it
implements only a subset of
functionality
so if you want more information please
check our whitepaper
you have the link here
now let's jump to the second long-term
implant which is comrades
version four this is the descendant of
legend.btz
which was the one we used against the us
military in 2008.
it has been extensively analyzed for
example the
publication by g data uh from several
years ago
this version four is in full sequence
plus and it uses several design patterns
it so it shows the level of
professionalism of its developer
it persists using a portion loader based
on the
open source project power supply
one of this is distinctive feature is
its virtual
file system in fact 16. this is not the
first time
taller use uses a virtual file system
for example there is one in the snake
root kit
but so in that case on this this is a
regular file but once this decrypted
it's it's a fat 16 partition
it contains several folders in for
example there is a
configuration for the command control
channel that uses email in slash etc
slash transport
slash main and if we open the cookie.str
file we have access to
the cookies that will be used to connect
to the gmail wave interface
there is also configuration for the http
network protocol and also log files
there is one called working.c4 log
c4 standing for change4
change being the internal name of
comrades
so in this working dot c4 log there is a
lot of interesting information
such as the last commands executed by
the background
the second distinctive feature of
comrades
if it is are its cnc communications
so the the first cnc channel is
called legacy and it is an exact copy of
the
combat version three protocol we believe
it is intended to be compatible
with old cnc server overdue the need for
the operator to redeploy your full
network infrastructure
the second command control channel uses
the gmail web ui and it is
an asynchronous email protocol
but in synchronous i mean that operators
are sending commands that are
that can stay on in the gmail inbox
waiting for the backdoor to connect to
the gmail
inbox to to retrieve it also what's
quite funny
is that it embeds the html parser called
gumbo which is also developed by google
so first the chiller operator sends an
email with a specially crafted
attachment
to a dedicated gmail mailbox so these
mailboxes are created and
under the full control of child
operators and are not compromising main
boxes
however they generally mimic the name of
an employee of the of the
compromise organization in order to to
be
more stealthy
then the compromise machine will connect
to this
mailbox using the cookies i showed you
earlier it will check for new emails
so this is an example of an email for
the second the example is
displaying outlook but directly it's in
the gmail web interface
we can see that the email was sent from
another
free email provider called gmx
and there is also an attachment
uh it is actually not excel files there
is
just the extension but it's actually
encrypted robots
then comrade will pass the html of
gmail in order to retrieve the link to
download the attachment
it will download the attachments decrypt
the content and execute the commands
so this is an example of a set of
commands
sent by the attacker to comrade
in this case the application acpvt2.txc
is a winrar application
so first they will compress some data
then they will mount a cloud storage a
onedrive cloud storage
and then they will copy the compressed
data to this cloud storage
so it is quite interesting to see that
they are using
uh another network channel to
to transfer stolen data and they are not
using the command control
channel gmail
this second example this is very similar
but
this term they are using rpc backdoor
which is containing the powershell
loader kcl.ps1
so rpc backdoor it's used to execute
comments on another machine of the local
network
and this the name of the local machine
is specifying the
iv key variable so
as before they will compress some data
then they will mount
the the cloud storage and then they will
copy
the archive user so
in that case the storing data isn't even
going through
the machine compromise with comrade but
it is directly
going from the other local machine to
one drive
if you want more details for example
about
the command control protocol please
check our white paper
again on our blog withifsecurity.com
and now let's jump to the last
long-term implant which is scratch
it was previously undocumented as this
talk
is recording i'm not sure if the white
paper will be available
uh before or after botcoms but you can
check on our blog
so crotch is a tool set mainly used to
collect documents
and it used plotbox as a command control
server
according to our visibility it was
active from 2015 to early 2020
and as you can see at the bottom of this
slide
crotch is the name given by by its
developer
so crouch was never publicly attributed
to chola
when we found it so we had to identify a
few elements that allowed us to make the
attribution
first on the same machine and had five
days
five days of interval in september 2017
gazer which is another chola backdoor
which was attributed several years ago
to chola
was dropped at the same location as
scratch in c intel
intel upd.exe secondly
the dropper and loaders of crouch and
geyser are very similar
so pdb packs are very similar they both
use
a cap file and their loaders are using
the same encryption key or a se4 key
to load the final payload in memory
it's also interesting to note that
another group
the dukes or apt-29 were also there and
the malware components are linked to
what we call operation ghost
so crotch persists using dll jacking
this is not something we see often with
stroller
so they are chrome firefox one drive and
more recently
an old outlook finder executable
also there are several versions the last
one the v4 having
been released in july 2019
and in that new versions for some reason
they removed the backdoor function on it
so this is a summary of crotch
functionalities so first the backdoor
part which is available from
version one to three social operators
they can
upload comment to the dropbox accounts
in the form of a fake zip archive so
only the few first bytes
are the zpeder but the remaining part of
the file
are custom formats of crutch
so they will upload it to a dedicated
robot second which is
as the gmail accounts they are created
under control of the attacker they are
not compromised accounts
so on this on the second we can see
there are a lot of
fake zip files with the very
generic file names so the compromise
meshing with scratch
where you reach out to the dropbox
storage and then download this
fake zip decrypt them and execute the
command
so this is an example of a decrypted
[Music]
zip fake zip so the first bike is
the common id in that case it's three it
means
drop the file on disk we now have
the the path where the file will be
written
and we can see the content of the file
in the beginning of the context
uh the two first bytes are in z which
means
that it is a windows executable
so now uh the documentary resting part
which has
in all versions of crotch including the
last one
so it monitors local drive but also
every time
a removable
storage such as a usb key is plugging
the computer
so it choose a window application
it's called eslp.exe on disk
they will compress files that are newer
than
seven days from this usb key
so for example pdf file doc file excel
etc
so once they have this archive they will
upload it to dropbox
in so in case of uh
the crotch restaurant 4 it is directly
uploaded
on dropbox and in case of version 3
it's first being put in a
fake wire archive so there is a second
layer of
of encryption and this fake raw is very
similar to
the fake zip it used the official
dropbox http api
to upload the file there is a token to
authenticate
to dropbox and it's all coded in the
malware samples
then the actual operators can just
download
this this idea from from dropbox
so we monitor
we had access to some of the command
executed by uh
by crotch and we noticed that at some
point they drop
a recovery bad door we call service dns
it's a simple bat script that persists
using a windows sidebar gadget
so this is the main code of this bat
file
you can see that it does a dns query of
type
hm4 to the cnc server dns query of type
hm4 sold
written address information about the
server but in that case we try and it
returns a url
so that's kind of interesting
[Music]
we create this url and it returns a
command
so it means that the dns hm4 is
the command control channel to to
receive commands
for this recovery backdoor and this is
not a technique
i saw before so it was it was new for me
so finally some recommendation
[Music]
so use complex unique password and
two-factor authentication
it may assume that very simple but
this is using stolen credentials in the
main way chola used to uh
move laterally on the network they also
use a lot of
powershell so whenever possible you
limit or
forbid partial execution and finally
they have several tools such as rpc
backdoor
or hyperstack that is used with the
carbon framework
to manage matching the local network
using pipes so
if it's possible it's better to limit
communication between the
local machines then after compromise
make sure to clean and reinstall all
machines as i said at the beginning
the the generally just keep a foothold
on the compromise network and they won't
need to
to to use the exploit or anything to
reinfect the network they just reconnect
using credentials they've stolen before
so change
all the password review the list of
accounts because they generally create
new accounts
that they can and they can then
come back using for example ldp
finally they are generally moved to the
active
directory server and also mail server so
this is the first thing
to clean because if you change all
passwords but
there are mimikats on your activity
directory it's kind of useless
so to conclude there are very few
headlines about tula compromise but
a lot of high profile organizations such
as governments
were are targeted or were compromised by
this group
also they tend to attack always the same
targets
and can stay in the same network for
months or even years
and basic arguing can complicate much of
their operations
and they will make more mistakes if
it's harder for them thanks for your
attentions
feel free to ask questions