all right hello everybody my name is
michelle
i'm a phd student at cispa and i'm going
to present to you our paper called
xlasik
leveraging os diversity to automatically
extract malware code signatures
this is joint work with my supervisor
christian rosso
now to motivate our work what we are
actually trying to achieve
is that given a memory dump of an
infected system we want to
attribute which malware infected the
system that is we want to
automatically create signatures to do
this task
now if we look at existing solutions
that we could possibly use for such a
task
is a b labels or error signatures
the problem is these are usually very
sort of generic signatures as it turns
out they are not very accurate because
they mostly focus on strings and data
so if you have ever worked with yahoo
signatures
you probably know this right you apply
it to a sample and it shows something
that doesn't really make sense it
matches random data as belonging to a
certain mobile family or
something like that so it doesn't really
work that well
now this by itself is a problem you
could say you just need to improve the
signature that's fine but another
problem that we find
is that usually off-the-shelf signatures
that you can find online for example
are not really intended for being used
with memory amps
that's actually a big problem in our
experience they
really are intended to work with samples
and if you try to blend them to marine
labs they simply don't work
so we basically want a solution to
overcome that we want a solution to
automatically create such signatures
and that they work with memory dumps now
a big problem here is that we want to do
this in a very in a completely forensic
setting
and therefore the analysis surface is
the whole memory number of the system
and as you will see soon this is
actually quite a challenge
now why is this actually a big challenge
so the problem is
that if we look at the memory right here
on the left
that is infected by a malware as
indicated by this little red guy down
here
now if we want to understand how we can
analyze this
we have to think of the memory as memory
pages right
as you probably know memory is allocated
at a page granularity
and it makes sense to look at pages as a
natural boundary of the memory dump sort
of
now if you think of a memory dump it's
quite big right it
could be multiples of gigabyte on a
modern system and however if we actually
look at the footprint of the malware we
will find that only a very few pages are
actually
infected right so here we have this huge
number of pages
and we have like one two three four five
in fact
pages and of course in practice it's
even much worse we're talking about
hundreds of thousands if not millions of
nine pages and maybe 100 or a few dozen
of uh infected pages so it's really a
needle in a haystack problem so how can
we actually
as a first step understand which of the
pages are actually interesting
in terms of being attributed to the
malware and then we can start thinking
about how we can generate the signature
of those pages
but the first and the really important
step is to find those pages
automatically
our idea to solve this problem is called
cross os execution
so here i'm going to give you a very
high level overview of our approach
and later on i'm going to refine the
actual details as we have implemented it
in practice so what you can see here is
a very basic
pipeline of a malware analysis system on
the left hand side we have a
set of malware samples that we want to
analyze
and in the middle we have a sandbox or
sandboxes that we will use to analyze
the samples so the way it works here we
take this
black sample and we execute it
now however the interesting step is we
execute this in two different machines
in particular we executed in a windows
xp machine and then a windows
7 machine those are virtual machines
with a predefined snapshot
and we execute those and then we take
the memory dump of both systems
and now we have those two memory dumps
and they both have
infected memory pages that are infected
by the same moment
now how do we solve the problem of
actually understanding which of the
pages are interesting
and as it turns out what is a really
useful way to do this in practice is
that we take those two memory knobs
and we intersect them now what does that
mean
i will tell you later in detail but the
basic idea is those systems
are similar not identical
and their similarities should be mainly
the memory footprint of the malware
and if we do this the really important
aspect is that as i have said before
the windows extreme redundant the
windows 7 when we're done
are inside in the order of gigabytes in
size
and the actual footprint that we get by
intersecting is much smaller we're
talking about a few kilobytes
maybe so the very basic motivation
and observations of this idea are as
false
first of all as i've previously
mentioned most of the pages in memory
are really uninteresting for us they are
basically
we can basically consider that noise
right so we have b9 processors we have
services we have
kernel code we have libraries device
drivers and so on
they are not interesting and completely
useless for us in terms of generating a
signature for the malware
and the other observation is that we
have two systems that are similar
but compatible in particular this means
the malware is very likely to run on
both systems
first of all because in our case we use
windows and windows is the ecosystem
that is very well known for its
backwards compatibility
and also malware authors usually
try to make sure that their marble runs
on as many systems as possible
for obvious reasons and the interesting
aspect here is that the forensic
footprint of those
operating systems is not identical it's
actually vastly different
so by intersecting the memory pages
again we will get into the details of
how this actually works
but by doing that we can actually
abstract from the background noise
automatically
now a problem that i can already
foreshadow at this point is that the two
operating systems
while not being identical they are still
similar and they still
share some footprints so as is probably
not really surprising
there is legacy code in windows that
will be shared between different
questions
and part of our task will be to identify
those similarities
and abstract from them in the learning
phase of our system
so here we can see a more detailed
overview of how our approach actually
works
this is a figure that can be found in
our paper
we will in the following slides go into
the details of every step
the way it works as a very high level
idea is
on the very left hand side we start with
malware that is executed
on two different windows versions then
it goes to some process
that we will describe in the following
slides and on the
right hand side you can see the final
result of this process which is a
fingerprint for this number
and as i've said we will now go into the
details
of every step of this procedure now the
first two steps of our
approach are explained here the very
first step the execution step
i think it doesn't really need that much
explanation we basically
take the malware and execute it in two
different virtual machines with
different versions of windows
the only thing that might be interesting
to mention here is we use
snapshots that we have previously
created and we execute the malware on
both systems for the same amount of time
after that we take a memory dump a
memory dump here is represented with
such a grid
and each cell in the grid represents the
memory page
the individual letters stand for
different contents so if two cells share
the same letter
that means they have the same content
and the x suffix in some of the cells
means that the page is considered
executable by the operating system
so in the page tables it has the
execution bit set
and we will use this later because as i
have previously mentioned we are
interested
in code signatures now the next step
is the unique step in this step
we filter out all the pages that are not
unique in the memory dump
to understand this first of all i think
it's intuitive to understand that
something that appears
let's say 20 times in the memory lamp so
one page appears 20 times
it's probably not characteristic for the
marble in practice what we have seen for
example
is that it's very likely that
several processes on the operating
system use the same library or maybe
study link for example
and because of that we will have the
same code multiple times on the system
and that's of course not interesting for
us
right um so it allows us basically to
abstract from such noise in a very easy
manner so what you can see here is for
example that
the a page the executable a page is
filtered out
the b pages footed out on the top
because
those are all not unique in the marina
so a appears multiple times
once it's executable one is not and
that's because it's sorted out b appears
multiple times c and so on
and all these pages are filled out in
this step and the result of this
are the memory dumps on your right hand
side
the next step is called the common step
it's also a very simple step but it's
very central and very important to our
approach
in this step we are basically
abstracting from
background noise of the operating
systems and the way this works
is we basically only consider the
memory pages that are shared in both
memory dumps
and by that we filter out the pages that
are not shared which we consider the
noise of the operating system
so in this case as you can see in the
first memory dump h
is not shared in with the secondary
number
and j and k of the second memory dump is
not shared with the first one we done
and therefore we consider h j and k
noise
and we keep d e f and g and by the way
that they appear
at the same offset here does not matter
d could also appear in the first
position it's just coincidence in this
case
and this basically is where the strength
of our
approach comes in because this
automatically
abstracts from noise as i have mentioned
before the operating systems while being
different
they are still similar and they share
legacy code and
data that we cannot necessarily abstract
from with
our intersection idea
in this step we want to solve this
problem
so what we have done so far we have
computed the unique
and common pages in this step we want to
understand which pages are
characteristic
so it's basically the last that
abstracts from all the noise
and to abstract from the noise we have a
deny list a deny list
is a list of pages that we learn
in a learning phase once that
exactly contain this noise these noisy
pages that we cannot abstract from by
intersecting
we will surely get into how we build
this deny list
but at this point we just use the deny
list
and we use it in a very simple fashion
we take the memory pages of the memory
then and we remove
all the pages that are contained in the
denial list
so in this case e and f are in the deny
list and they are removed and we are
left with d
and g which we can which we calling
the characteristic pages of the malware
that has been executed
now to build the deny list we proceed as
follows
the procedure is outlined here first of
all we start with
an empty list an empty denial list in
the first step
and then we do something which we call
an idle execution
we basically run this whole crossos
apparatus that i have previously
described
but we do not insert the malware into
the system we just let it run without
the malware
for the same amount of time that we
would run it with the malware
but it basically just idles it does
nothing interesting from
malware and that is point of view
um then we take the memory dump and we
extract the unique common pages
as before and then we add those pages to
the denial list
if we have added a new entry to the deny
list we
proceed again from step two so we repeat
the whole thing and we repeat that
until we do not have any new pages
it turns out in practice that this
process terminates quite quickly so it
maybe takes like
three or four iterations before we do
not see any new pages
and that's mainly because we use
snapshots and
things are rather deterministic every
time we start the operating system
so after this we have learned the pages
we have a denylus that we can use
as previously described the final two
steps of our approach are explained here
the first step is the code extraction
step
in this step we simply remove all pages
that do not contain
code so in this case the g page will be
removed
and we are only left with the page that
will be used for the fingerprint
generation which is the last step the
fingerprint generation works by
extracting engrams so the way it works
is we use the sliding window
that we slide over the d page and we
extract its
n-grams and these engrams will then
later be used
for uh matching a memory dump that is we
compute all the engrams of memory dump
and we intersect it with the
engrams of the generated fingerprint and
depending on the size of the
intersection
we will have a match but we will get
into that later
the only important step here to mention
is that for the
code extraction we use a quote heuristic
that disassembles the
page and looks for a common
x86 code patterns like for example a
push to push a call
then you do a call a test and then a
conditional jump
and depending on how many of those
patterns you find
we consider a page code page
and the details can be found in the
paper it's important here to mention
that we do not rely on page table
information
or os information because we want our
approach to be
generic basically our approach depends
on nothing
except for the instruction set
architecture x86
but changing that is merely an
engineering effort
so after this step we have finally a
fingerprint that
can be used for detecting
the presence of a malware family in my
radars
now let's come to the evaluation of our
paper
so first of all i'm going to explain the
data set and the setup that we have used
we have used the virtualbox hypervisor a
windows xp virtual machine and the
windows 7
virtual machine um virtualbox that
doesn't really matter you can use any
hypervisor you like as long as it is
capable of creating a memory
dump which i guess pretty much every
hypervisor can do
the only interesting part here is that
we have taken great care to set up the
vms to
have a rather silent memory footprint so
we have disabled as many services as
possible
we have made sure that there is not
really any network activity
there isn't really any new processes
being spawned that much
so we have basically taken care that the
systems are really silent
that basically makes for example
generating the denial list
a lot more efficient and it also
makes sure that we do not introduce any
new noise
we reduce that as much as possible we
have used 70 popular marble families
such as carbon microtrans timber and so
on
and in total we had 197 malware samples
the full list of the families can be
found in the paper
now this number 197 might sound a little
small
but we want to mention that we have
taken great care to create a very high
quality data set so we have basically
executed all those smarter samples into
the two vms windows xp and windows 7 vm
and we have basically babysitted all of
the 394 marble executions and have made
sure that the
actual family really becomes active in
the system
so basically we can be sure that all the
labels of all the memory lamps are 100
correct now as a first step of our
evaluation we wanted to understand the
family uniformity
this graph can be found in the paper and
without going into too much detail what
we actually want to know here is how
many samples of family do we need
to reliably detect the whole family
so basically this works here is on the
excesses we have the number of family
samples that we can use to build a
fingerprint so for example if we have
three samples we create a fingerprint as
described before for each sample and
then we
take a union of all those engrams and
this is now our fingerprint for the
family
and on the y-axis we have
how many engrams we have left if we
intersect
this fingerprint with the engrams of all
the memory dumps of the family
so for instance to give you an example
to make this more clear let's look at
the
kilios this red dashed line case
in this case even if we have just one
sample and we learn the fingerprints
and we intersect those encryams with the
engrams of all killers memory
loss we see that we have more almost 1
million
n-grams after the intersection
so that means knowing one sample is
already enough
if we compare this for example with
let's say this
uh purple line which is in my main
one sample does not work that well we
only have
very few engrams and
if we have two it gets better and three
and of course the more we have the
better it gets
so we can see some families are more
uniform than others
and we can also see that the
intersection size is vastly different
right
so for examples is very uniform and
contains almost one million
encrypts in the intersection but
for other families it's vastly different
for drydex we need to know a lot of
samples because there's probably much
more diversity in the drydex family
and we need to know like uh one two
three four five six
samples to probably properly detect
drivings and so on
so for other uh the families are quite
different in both aspects which
is important for later when we actually
want to
develop a mechanism to detect those
families and memory items
now here we have the most important part
of our evaluation
where we have actually taken out an
experiment to develop
a mechanism to see how well we can
detect the
presence of a marble family in a memory
dump
the way this works is as follows for
each marble family we have created an
equal split of the malware samples
so for example in the case of carbonart
we have used five malware samples for
learning
the fingerprint and then the memory
dumps of the five remaining samples for
a matching fingerprint and you can see
here in the
corresponding cell that on average 5.51
of the fingerprint have matched and the
average entropy of the
matching engrams was 4.26
and in you can see in the other cases so
in the case of carbon
only carbonar conventional average
variable in the other cases it did not
match that well
it's not really 0 but we excluded
a result from the table if the average
was below 0.01 percent
chest for readability reasons and based
on those results we have then
evaluated optimal thresholds for both
the average matching
portion of memory lamps and also
for the average entropy
um as we can see on average
it works out as expected so the
family a fingerprint for family on
average matches
really well only with its own family
in the case of forum we have one false
positive
that is explained in detail in the paper
why we have that false positive
just to say that our approach of course
also has limitations
and if we proceed with the remaining
family members so the table is split in
two for readability reasons
and we can see that it also worked
pretty well for
others we did not
get all true positives in the case of
nymane and also virat also had some
cases where it didn't work that well
but all those for all those cases we
actually did case studies
with quite some interesting insights
that can all be found
in the paper in total the result of this
evaluation is that our
approach gives a true positive rate of
and a false positive rate of 0.15 which
shows
the feasibility of our approach in
practice
now let's talk about the limitations of
our approach
um so we make some assumptions that
could be challenged by some people
so for example what could happen is that
the malware behaves differently on two
operating systems
and has a different memory footprint so
the intersection won't really work
that can happen it mainly applies to
droppers so a dropper might drop a
different campaign on windows xp than it
does on windows 7
might show up something randomly for
other reasons that
i don't that we cannot know in advance
um
so in this case of course our approach
won't work
another problem is that we assume that
the malware is always present in memory
which might not necessarily be the case
for example you think of ransomware so
there's
there are ransomwares that just change
the desktop background once and then
they exit and then leave the memory
and the desktop background then contains
the ransom message so in this case if
there is no memory footprint of the
malware
our system doesn't work however the
infected memory dump will also not
really have that information in memory
because for example in the case of the
change desktop picture it will be
on the disk right so yeah it cannot work
in the case
then there are also very complex packing
schemes or fiscation schemes that we
cannot deal with
so for example if you have something
like vm obfuscation or you have packing
schemes where functions are
lazily packed and unpacked on demand so
whenever you need a function you unpack
it and when you don't need the function
you pack it again that's really out of
scope for us that doesn't really work
because at the time we take the memory
dump we can only see what is unpacked at
that moment
and that can be different on both
systems so these are also out of scope
in the reviews we have also seen that
some people mentioned alternative
instruction set architectures
that's not really a limitation because
adding a new adding support for new
instructions and architecture is merely
an engineering effort so for example if
you want netbyte code you just need to
add a disassembler for that bytecode and
write a new card heuristic
so that works now to conclude
i have presented exo-essic with the
crossos execution which is the first
methodology to exploit us diversity
from for malware analysis it works in a
purely forensic setting
it is completely automatic and most
importantly it is also completely
independent of
any os or idiosyncrasies in particular
i don't see why this wouldn't also work
for linux for example or any other
operating system
we have seen a promising evaluation
that shows that our approach is actually
feasible in practice with a 93
true positive rate and a 0.15 false
positive rate
so that's it for my talk you can see
again the overview of how
our system works and i'd be happy to
answer questions