basically on the talk structure me
home
automated machine learning and data
mining techniques a problem
the you see Hong
him
me Hong ball
you know Miami being
some top then I'll
I'll conclude that with some some
examples of Hall
in a bit of mining and machine learning
is probably not the only answer
and if and when it has to be applied it
has to be applied with some gonna domain
knowledge
are and you know it has to be combined
with all went up other approaches in
order to make
up for a holistic solution solution okay
so let's look at the threat landscape
arm in the last 12 to 18 months
I'll again I'll targeted attacks have
gained
the tragedy I'll you know thanks to
attacks like
RR all you know stops that
social networking that Holmes provide
manage source of information for wage up
attacks can be targeted I'll even to
most sophisticated users because the
attacks cat a whole lot of context
packets are definitely
learning from all the techniques used in
targeted tax
and we expect many of those techniques
to land up in a packet
to make a make up for the attacks to be
extremely sophisticated I and yet seen
more and more
are that a attacks are using
arm stealth techniques in order to
remain Dahlman
arm and hidden in enterprises for a long
period of time
are specially as they are becoming more
and more targeted were specific
enterprise and have a very specific
aim in mind unlike before it was about
martz infection
getting users I'll is uses
information across the Internet are have
users cannot ass as me a you know all
these PC or
are arnie via mobile so you
music community mobile homes you follow
and
are progress in the same posh you CNN
lot of
movements in grease or the last two
years and we expect next year to be
a to be innocent you know increase to be
in a similar fashion
saw I mean what has really happened or a
beautiful over the last few years is
that
are the attacks have up you know
my good enough be from of relatively few
threads
to a micro distribution model where arm
few number of billions of exactly the
same hat are spread across large number
of users
so very small stall make its way into
a million some machines across the globe
all with the same
anti-semitism machines Tom I mean the
same shop who was born in millions
sheens what we see now is mulatto
maidens a window and market for example
proper gonna get into millions of users
but from a five talking
fingerprint on a few we saw 10 had
close like 18 millions and harkin had
close to 1.6 million
so if you were to look at up from a fine
thing up in front of you would think
that a million
threats but they're really bored onto
you know the same time which is harkin
spread across millions of users so the
other
challenge for the traditional
signature-based security approaches that
which relies on a fingerprint which lies
in the fact that you have to have a
sample in hand in order to produce a
fingerprint
doesn't really fit this model so what
are the odds that a
traditional signature-based security
solution will be able to discover all
the slant
becomes extremely challenging K arm
so when I talk about tracks I'm and
threats being unique at the
at the byte level what really goes on I
in a simple animated step is
arm haggadah basically the look that fat
they used to
which are effortless produce in order
produce
up by Moody's which differ data byte
level are
in order evade a signature be security
engine
and most of the attackers these days
come in with built-in functionality
to muted the file to appointment this
security engine is no longer picking up
the threat it so that no one has
produced one
and and give it back but they would
trade and they have a whole bunch of
security engines
against was there checking the five up
and military Italy
can find a million which pretty much
have aids as many security engines as
possible
again so all this is automated again
because this is a city they're trying to
do anything is amiss technology all it
takes is
install a product I'll obey the product
called on the leaders of nations muted
the five best in
if it is detected then you're really
into is not good enough you needed it
again and again and again and
you can do that an automated fashion
they could be ginning abide adding a
bailar adding a section
I wanna arm and the
attack in 10 producer Martin pretty
sophisticated
arm you know these are some examples be
in charge here you know
pointedly couldn't you know kids you
really don't have to know a lot about
them
but you can use them in a very powerful
fashion here's an example with their
asking the user to supply at the the
attackers
be happens by the FTP account details or
gmail account details for the keylogger
would start sending information
arm you know they are attacked its rich
have a specific ups which is built an
hour
I'll in often spilled into made specific
security vendors
I and again you know depending on the
capabilities of the
a in on kids the price will ease
and they are migrating to the cloud
model of course the whole industry is
migrating to was about so
why dollars of agents have been a file
are any can
pretty much up take advantage of their
pricing
all models like you know for a dollar
you can use 24 hours
summit as many files and get as many
minutes as possible
I that are again guaranteed to invade
are you know security engines and then
on the base to the pricing bill
unless a whole bunch of security vendors
was the investigations and guarantee
that image those
engines are missing out which has
gained a lot of attention on the last
are arm
18 months up is you know we've seen
examples of these rare all that is going
on is
basically just the skating on the binary
again so
these are whole bunch of misleading ups
concedes minnows
connection and does express help experts
settings
they all come with different names but
as you can see there just
skins on top of the basic same
misleading at
ARB so all that is going on as the
template for the UI is changing
but the basic functionality of the a the
matter remains the same
I'm so in this case if be seen I you
know for example for this particular
are missing out we saw forty nine
different clones
for exactly the same arm attack that was
going on
arm on pretty much what I mean an motors
most with me
on the way from having a back page which
supports the
product me you have a 24 by 7 helpline
one Asian on number and everything set
up nobody automated fashion
so you know is the point being that the
bites change
but beavis on the sides really don't
change password stealers will continue
to steal passwords
spam bottle can you imagine it spans and
rogue anti-virus will continue to pop up
the synapse for the user to
taken download on so in a sense the by
to changing
the signatures have been committed but
the Beavers don't change
so hence beard based detection dans
are basically take advantage of this
basic fact
a it is an engine that ignores for the
thread looks like
but the tax what on the missile what the
trend us
okay so that's the whole point to be
here based detection
engines and they've been around for more
than two decades there's nothing new
about it
arm saw before I go into more details
one thing I would like to clarify arm
over the last couple decades
we have progressed from a detection
based industry to a production base
industry
our prevention base industry but there's
a whole lot of confusion on these
Thompson to Marty's detection proudly
implies
at least in my mind arm detecting a
threat after the fact that it has done
something malicious on the system
and the product has to then take an open
meeting at fat
as well as appearing the system to
restore the settings if
a registry setting was modified it has
to be restored to the usual state
in the fine was modified it has released
or to the ozone state
if you are for example its sequels file
was modified on the militias entries in
the atty was positively apparently so do
the usual state
say so it is challenging to offer
protection to the end users
for detection base model because you are
not always guaranteed to be able to
repair the state in the usual state
and I'm gonna be fine modification is
extremely hard unless you have a copy on
a very smart engine it can be worth
the bunny level changes prevention is
before the back
right so before the sample runs on the
system
and does anything militias you should be
able to detect it right
arm and and Prevention becomes extremely
challenging especially in terms of being
able to pay system because
how do you detective threat before it
runs yet to claim it to be ruthless
right so up its its
pretty challenging but again there are
I'll ways in which
even that model becomes viable so
protection in
in all could be both I the detection
based on prevention based
I and an users can take advantage of
either those morons a security you know
engines can implement both the models
and Palin
on as a as a mention challenges are of
course you know can all the changes that
it was if you have a ditch
nation is mourning and you know
prevention based approaches
bitch action do you block you know how
much do you monitor how invisible you
get
and what is the performance or head of
such a model it
arm here's here's something that you
need to think about
right if if a man is doing 6 actions
and you are monitoring all those six
actions but you conclude that it is
malicious in the fifth action in ISE
at prevented the sixth-most most
malicious action that it was about to
take
you know does it are doesn't convince
your the fact that it is a prevention
base engine
arm I think only if the force 5 action
to talk with completely reversible
by the security engine and I think it
would for the Prevention baseball
and and i think thats that's the more
realistic stance
and that is how it should be I a really
dollar if that accrue
up in all be here a bit attention
engines which can block
and conclude with you know good success
rate on the poster in that there was a
because
there's not much context that they have
green or
home an insult to those other I mean I
think
I'll the all all these mornings can fit
in a security
arm engine in Palo so let's look at the
liggett legacy
rules bisbee be able security arm
they're basically lose weight and
publishers activity
they could be as simple as things like a
finance from a temp folder
rights to run one ski creates a file in
sequel in Windows
and martha is a browser homepage on
analyst would write such a rule
is pretty confident that there is no
legit software that runs from the temp
folder
mario has a brother home page right to
fight a Windows key and so on so forth
are and hence it is malicious arm
another example would be a file on from
the temp folder there's an open process
to another vendor service processors
up rights into the process memory and
create a more threat
again if you believe that this is up
very unlikely to be here for tweens
offer
any of those this behavior across a lot
large population of malware
he could be lighting such rules amps
so legacy systems are simple and
intuitive expert systems
they require dormant domain exports to
know how to distinguish between good and
bad
the allies amendment this part the
trends and denied the rules
arm and the product may have an ability
to let you can let the administrator so
the user's
are you know interface with the I'll be
here in June and write rules if they
think
up they can arm design they they can
design rules
many specifically is to in tailored was
the environment
arm in an enterprise on the
applicability of course is
many security products specially in
enterprise products been administrators
do one such inability I'm and in some
cases this may be the only answer
are you know there might be some touch
which can be very easily
detected and re mediated through a
simple rules we don't need
whole lot of arm complex specification
or the traders
arm the benefits of course of this model
is that it provides
Bronica written in simple signature be
security arm
it can provide a precise reason for why
a detection
happen and out why a pretty good thing
was identified as much is because
it it is backed up by the rule that
trigger right take a look at the ruling
and say okay this is one on that that's
why
this thing was malicious arm you can
name a threat
and so it could be again many contextual
and you can take relevant actions
because now you can say
up it these are the actions undertaken
it is this type of fat
and so in order to remediate I need to
take this action that you could be
come in a process delete a file repair
industry
are simply coming to file and that would
be good enough they can take
are or you can this has been a process
that could be ma commandos political
process in this case if you try to shut
down its gonna reboot machine
are you can simply suspend the process
and taking off on the side effects
before you go about terminating the
process
arm to the gonna advantages so you get
lot lot more contextual in writing
this kind of rules of course the
disadvantages skill ability rating of
skill because
you require human experts we looking at
these threats day in day out writing
rules
right and and replies domain expertise
more importantly
does it really imply lower rates you
know it's really up to the analyst for
the quality that lets you have
it's mostly based on the gut feeling
that the feeling that this is not gonna
trigger on
police officer up but that's not true I
mean
people I don't consequences of their
even example that border before
running from a temp folder right into
run key
up dropping a filing system for you can
imagine I
an installer dropping its child
processes up in the tempo run taking all
these actions
on admission is trying to distribute a
patch are trying to do something in an
enterprise environment and we've seen
that happen
okay so so to say that one model
provides lower rates compared to the
other
is merely an illusion because are he
even domain experts don't really can
capture the two behavioral diversity of
peace offer
across the globe in a slaughter of
creative talent out there was going to
let love create a program in
arm so back to scalability are Sophie
conclude that in appearance are far less
than five innings and being able to
carry model is a good way to address the
problem
I then what happens when you getting
your shot too hard to conclude whether
it's a new $5 million to really a new
malware
and the same out maybe pat differently
that same Alan maybe skin differently
arm so is the answer to analyze the
thread I guess
know it should not be the only answer
maybe one of the answers
arm I think it has to be augmented with
automation
you can collect that Iran you can mind
that it and create models which can
offset far the scale of the problem that
we're trying to deal
so I'll quickly got was a machine
learning basics I'll
and thence show how we can apply machine
learning to solve this problem
and how that is not the complete
solutions well okay so
machine learning is basically I'll an
approach to artificial intelligence to
get the computer tool on
arm by showing it lots of examples okay
arm so he in this case up in a given the
face
up in the machine learning are Martin
should be able to pick up the fact
that the name the pollen that I'm okay I
in some cases arm hand programming is
not possible in machine learning may be
the only solution for example like this
election
think about writing a piece action
program by hand right i mean we're gonna
ride
up a SoCal are on lips which has
to round circles with white and black in
a nose and a mouth you know i mean that
definition could even fit the
piece of human was the monkey it so are
the hand programming may not be the
answer in
many in the cases handwriting detection
is another example a machine learning is
probably the best answer
so from the central question machine
learning is how can we build computer
systems that
automatically improve with experience
and water the fundamental laws that one
on learning processes
arm and it can be best described as a
process which tries to improve
its performance at a party about to
experience
the arm and and by that experience i
mean
examples of the data that would show and
it will try to figure out
are hard to are detect are
the example are by the features of the
example that it has been shown
so this was to predict what the are lay
below the Cactus League of
the data that is van you given on
example twin
and public about how that more with
examples as a move forward okay
so it's basically discovering
relationship between the variables the
system input
and the output arm and trying to the
deck for the hidden relationships are
you giving an
and you say this is the obscene intense
in
when you're trying to train the model
what you giving it is
leaving one basic some feel machine
learning
machine learning that you're doing
labeling and you're saying
here's the data usually and try to
discover
what is the relationship between the
data and the label such that
be given an unknown example it can
predict want to label all
known example is on the base load modern
has loaned
many bed in the living examples so the
billing bought a machine learning a
computer science
statistics cognitive science and
information theory
are and they all ask a very distinctive
question
and machine learning basically up built
on all these questions
and but poses a very different question
I'm gonna move on
to more I'll more
in for me the problem domain that
this into a time machine learning but
arm
one thing that is important to I'll note
that there are basically fourth
for I'll top-level categories a machine
learning
one is supervised machine learning which
is as I mentioned armed supervised
machine learning is very given labeled
it up
and a given examples and tries to build
tomorrow in order to predict what the
label oven on examples
and on supplies machine learning problem
is very good lot of examples
they are not labeled and the system
tries to figure out what relationship
exists between those examples are trying
to build clusters
so plus occasion would be a classic
supplies machine learning
oMG thats clustering would be I would be
an example up on supplies machine
okay semi supplies machine learning is
where you have a mix of labeled and
unlabeled data
you might have very little label it a
and you could have lots of unlabeled
data
and you're trying to build Martin's ARB
oh and trying to improve the models on
the basis of the label Leah
because very few of them arm you try to
a measure the entire of the model that
you build on the label it and try to
improve it
reinforcement learning is is you know
classic
example is robotics very kind of I'll
give it it has a sequence of input on
actions that can perform
and there is a rewarding to know the
model but if it takes a wrong decision
it is by National Grid makes the night
decision then it has awarded and tries
to
improve the decision-making process
because the price maximize
up its behavior towards an expected to
war so the foreign
basic categories and um out bro and
emphasize and follow this will talk
about problems as in most in supervised
machine learning
but and that is up fish in a pond
supplies as well
to the basic sensible she learning
involved to pick up that feature a
presentation free to ask
arm you have input and output in your
trying to figure out what features
relayed mostly up to for to the examples
and how they help you distinguish
between
one class or the other again and in in
our case
what we're really talking about is
matter samples right so does the clean
sample
on it is a militia sample if I give you
a whole lot of cleaning
clean samples and militia samples are
what machine learning significant orders
what other distinct characteristics that
has been dismissing wooden bat
and those cactus 60 something that we
10+2 up
use our domain expertise and tell that
you know maybe this is one of the
features maybe this is gonna be just
maybe this'll all the features
and it tries to use those features in
conjunction to the best extent possible
on the missile examples to build a model
in on those
features such are trying to been
features on its owner tries to
leverage in apply up those features in
order to come up with the most accurate
models
and I've examples to go about trying how
haha I will be
doing that so you you do that you
compile it enough by compiling that it i
mean you collect the data
arm armed and in the new to the machine
running out and they don't
because it went awesome machine learning
algorithms arm
you train the algorithm you value the
resulting in trades that process over
and over again
jill is targetting models which perform
than expected
advocacy level the many choices have
tools available
up many free ones back has one that I'll
be
in using in my devil armed
the only problem is it's a dollar beers
application is not scale well to large
scale data
arm you have long I mean it's
got many fancy you are you can look at
the data sets and how
that is said split across various
features and so on so forth
arm then you have orange which is native
see
base application has very nice Python
interface is again
has I can drop are you I as well so we
can talk
using command line using pipe are you
can use I can drop
in order to evaluate and are loaded and
a valid response
and then put 54 more you know for most
of these
the colors not very on showing a very
well
but I think shining example the so the
input file formats are usually
you know of five letters a file format a
very simple text file format where it
has a header
but just ice for the features are and
then comma-separated values
all each and every example that you
might want to cap represent
using those features arm MTSU palaces
tab separated or CSV files arm any of
those
would be the type of tubulin provides K
so now let's see how we can apply
machine learning to be able to guarantee
so the goal here is to train tomorrow
and provide are made and meaningful
information about unknown samples that's
really what the goal is right
see getting inundated with a lot more to
samples coming in
and you want to not treat them all in
order to I'll a
you know offset the demand for two main
exports to be looking at each and every
sample right to you want to
are offered that work a little bit too a
in automated machine learning-based
systems arm
22 goals that you may want to fulfill
one could be just identify a class or
label you might want to say this is
gonna this is bad
are you might want to identify an
association so you might have a
collection of
threats office families are and you
might want to know whether
this new incoming sample closely
resembles Mitchell the various
touch families that you might have an
inflection
so one would be a prosecution problem
the other would be a clustering problem
the so so basically I application of
arm in information extracted implies we
hear that
the that we want to pass by the sample
provide information to the analysts
for the purpose of labeling all writing
definitions
arm so either they can just use that
information
and improve the quality of the engine
are you could send directly use the
Marlin order been a real-time prediction
engine
both the up applications are up
something that is going on in the
industry today
arm so in terms of machine learning on
the steps that I talk about generally
machine learning now wooden wall you
collect the samples
and I see samples I mean labeled samples
so you note that these are
militia samples and these are a valid
samples would set up a VM
for the monitoring thing look so
monitoring thing what becomes
pretty critical to ha you would go about
using this
going forward because you don't want to
build a monitoring framework really want
a good morning X Factor to the framework
and then applied for our real-time
protection arm because you want
the enforcement and the collection
points to be very close to each other
almost the same
arm and that early cleared for example
again
I you wouldn't bush and on the samples
in some kind of automation system that
you would have built on a farm were two
machines
you would collect a sample behavior data
you of course would want to recycle 2
p.m. because as you know not where
they're going
make changes to the system that you
don't want to show up in the next 10 the
next sample
you extract information a format
suitable for data mining
ukraine the models and your test and
deploy the models and again
menu to buy the morning to either
deploying it merely for information
extraction are you for replying for
real-time protection
okay Sol here's a here's an example for
the monitoring framework would look like
up the it could simply be built on
something like
detours the are using use a more refined
looking
arm and it would collect information
like the pen name call on
rate so you could hook pretty much every
export Oracle 32
and log the API that was called are you
could also collect the data or
information
I could collect information like which
it a call this API
stayed on the process at ECA you could
extract the features
and dumb X at the pictures under the law
quite into waters
the i five right up our fight the issue
file .txt fine whatever suits are
up machine learning to party that you're
going to use
arm and the features that would extract
things like
has you ira vindo right doesn't happen
have you ever know
are I mean more to be malicious samples
for example
box may not have any user interface
element now that's something that
I'm expecting domain experts you come up
with are soul and
domain expert might say yeah I mean for
a person the cases I don't see
you I in trouble matter so that that is
an interesting feature
arm so the that's what I meant by
creating features using domain expertise
okay does
doesn't do not become a negation are the
talk or IRC doesn't talk or its GDP
is it registered in an all the stock
location right Solanki on one ski
service are enablement on support does
it create a Windows Task
doesn't modify a be filed on the system
does it create a be fine
does it inject into clustered process
and you can have a definition of just a
process like I'd mention
minoso this is an example of a transfer
process again so these are the kind of
examples of features that you might
have which you want the machine learning
system to
take advantage of and figure out what
combination of Twin Falls
on these various questions you want to
ask about a good what's about to happen
should be mine in order to come up with
I'll a model that can very accurately
predict
whether this unknown samples clean on
militias
arm not sure whether everybody can see
this
up clearly are not up but basically the
features that I have
up in this up are fine but I've created
things like create window sure window
find window
shall execute delete file will file
create file
is to be send request device happen both
with all the whole point will be this
API
up state information that I'm collecting
our
has a window a doesn't have a listening
port
does it create starts doesn't modify the
p5 creates a be fine
does it injected is it registered as
awful start in the last attribute is
how long has it been created since okay
so
it's a warrant thank you doing is trying
to build a model to be so these
missed out the sex of a sample are and
created since seconds as
is an interesting arm future you can
pretty much say that
manner is usually very interested in
taking doing a malicious activity as
soon as it lands in the system
okay but at least offer doesn't
necessarily have to take any action
it might be sitting there you'll onto
that it may not take any action on the
user on track to the
applications on support saw that itself
might be a very interesting feature that
you might want to use in
connection with all the other features
in order to distinguish between good and
bad soften
so sample that does a whole lot of
activity in a very short span of time
my group more malicious then it leans
offer that does very little
for a long period of time because it
requires use in traction constantly
get so let's a see if I can arm
do the demo
okay so he s mecca arm and
because one of the tools and I mention
and
when launched the Explorer arm and I
have bill
the of file from arm basically from the
are from around I'll its lost a fumble
that i've collected like a non
90% of those arm
so here's home his ear are fine
okay so many Lord in our file
as a short I'll hard look like pre
people to create
ob-gyn all the various features and if
you look at the
class which is you know the glass is
basically on the last line of each and
every
up dana point that I collected for each
and every sample at and wannabe chain
saying that the state is a modern
demolition sample
on a valid sample a you know I have
forty-seven good examples and body too
bad examples
okay I want to upload the data arm
I basically can use a whole bunch a
built-in
are machine learning technologies I'll
are modeling technology that are
available I'll pick one
many commonly used a 48-hour decision
trees because
and reason isn't reason are good is
because
you can see Howard a ride on a
particular conclusion by looking at the
media's
up you know walking on the tree and
saying okay on how did it make a
decision whether particular samplers
malicious or not and you can reason
about the morning
armed other models provide you with math
mathematical polynomial function
and it is very difficult to reason about
100 and I'm in that model and say that
this file its mission
so somewhere use G-forty aid leave while
the default options and on it was
head start and it creates a morning
agree that the efficacy of the model is
pretty bad sixty-two percent
correctness and 30 seven-percent arm
Andheri
I nonetheless the disciples baseball are
this is not an innocent on but you'd be
training a mom that you want to deploy
in production
but if you look at the Mon that was
created you know if it
look lookin the you know some some
national
decision to deny that if create if it
created a file
and it was created in less than six you
know six thousand
arm seconds are and if it
did ascend request then it is bad and
there are 19 examples was that
that bad example country good examples
I'll but if it did not do an HTTP
request
and it was registered as at an auto
stock and it did try to find I've been
on the desktop
I'm then it is malicious I V eight
examples of those which does that and
you
valid examples so those are the kind of
things you can observe problem on that
and bells
are you know again the more our dataset
you get the better quality that is that
you give
up you know better model to get okay
arm I i was gonna both men are in charge
them as well but
I don't think I have enough time for
that out so basically once you build the
classifies you wanna black los pies
I yeah I I mentioned you know that there
are whole point
on regional collect information and the
whole point on which you can enforce
the decisions that you are deny from the
models and they may or may not be the
same
one could be simply for collecting
information the others could be simply
to leverage that information
invalid the Marlin taken action because
not all who points
a suitable for taking a block action
okay the design
of up near the trying to take a block
action might depend on
modifying an outcry matter of of the
pack on
forces are turning up returning on an
opponent on support so
you might want to decide then Mitch API
do you want to block action on an
with you guys want to collect
information okay
I again but it has to hope you do want
to hook a high-level API which allows a
long black
131 hookah low-level API again
lower-level API's could be very
up chappie right because local sleepy
eyes
are fitted onto some low-level EPS
I am what kind of action you want to
take filling an API or
hitting a trade or process of modifying
are proud to those on the meanest choice
love
block action that you might want to be
so you know that is hype
use but in reality is it doesn't really
work out
that easily and he cannot really go
about applying at
without understand what's going on are
one interesting thing that
be absorbed was lot of samples failed to
run an automation
and more importantly good samples failed
running on a mission and that because
that samples are
fairly stand long they don't have much
dependencies the London easily
good samples on the other hand armed
have a lot of dependencies
arm they might be depending on
configuration so if you get a good
sample
but you don't have all the other
dependencies are the country Asian that
it expects industry
for example it may not drop the field
line right are it me
required use in traction again if you in
automation for launching extn if it is
betting on a
arm okay Council ballot box and you'll
even running for
10 seconds until can done with our
meeting the sample it hasn't really done
anything it hasn't launched its
motivating for use in traction to happen
okay so we automation and dependency
convict would be
some other challenges many samples del
Malaysia samples on the other hand
deliberately field running on a mission
they have
the mobo capabilities rate arm a simple
instructions
in order to Dec much on my mind are they
might
check their own filename they might
check the bidding process for example is
my pin process I E R Explorer
and if it is not the infield Ron are
they might check application settings
when
since in this case they were checking
for I extensions by then able to not
have been ordered able to sample does
not run
so they getting pretty clever because
they won't be made automation to a
certain extent
K I samples may be stale if you're
running about your sample the CNT
so I might be down in the sample mean of
Rhonda's check the network connection at
a connection did not succeed at Exit
doesn't mean that it is clean because
%um really not seen its
full behavior are had it connected to
the CNT
arm and then they are the Arsenal since
eight they might be
missing dependencies the keys of termite
required of a dollar to be installed on
the system
militia samples might require might be
targeting a specific part by the
application like Adobe
benefit is missing from your VM set up
then the sample with federal
K arm and then there are talented and
machine learning like imbalance in a
sense you have lots of good examples
very few bad bad examples on my sword
you cannot be just missing
and you might try to possibly had a
fight and it might be such
corrupted that you might be able to
collect all the features
are they might be enormous features
right now
in classic machine learning what happens
is ahead an almost features are usually
considered out lives and you know mater
below to delete will be the outlet
but in in our case up you have to think
you have to stop and think whether the
enormous value is a feature that you
want to take advantage of
and has been deliberately put n or is it
just matter of wrong data collection
large me you know section size for
example is a very common technique used
by malware to evade
it was injuring because I don't take too
long time to Lord that fide
are and past machine learning I without
rain domain expertise is going to say oh
that's out i did i do on a train on it
but as 10 minutes but he's gonna say
though that is interesting because that
never happens and clean
and I have I know that it happens in
malicious files because it is a classic
they were active listening to me
so we should use that as a future rather
than trying to prove either data
so you gonna combine both domain
expertise as up who've been trying to
build machine learning
on and here are some examples: on the
other talent is gonna be non-profit
website so
tax which are not a process by
themselves are
Inc movie courses data a malicious PDF I
is going to make it will be to behave
maliciously
so what are you really gonna Creed as
malicious and what are you really going
to me didn't want to go alone
so machine learning I'll you know as I
explained as is does not really apply to
NPD's
arm but there are ways in which you can
getting on the problem
late lots of examples of non-core files
which
are known to be malicious on up in court
an ex parte in them help
link via SMS I am espy's screensaver
star pledged
there's a long list of such fights
last example there P fires but they're
running in the context of a trusted
process
like mondale who are not solve so that
some thought militias but the deal that
advances militias
and but if you absolve the behavior of
Runyon 320
you not been on this much is actually
enhances militias you operate that
to the ba'ath that it loaded on the
command line not to the process itself
and
taken spawning immediate action again
so hard you are to meet these that's
probably one of the biggest challenges
and as these in population of non
process-based that that
come across all the time arm how do you
up
hall and reinforce the protection and
what
what is it that should be limited in
these cases all these have to be
decision that you have to artwork into
the solution
as you try to automate okay so in terms
of
conclusion arm what I would say is you
know be
in a big hurry madeline is not be
wandering at as possible 5
right so BC millions and millions of
files in a very short span of time
but be here really the median so the
tech families another one
warning that quick and automation is
probably one of the
solutions not the only solution one of
the many solutions and what you can do
with the
scale of the problem are but you have to
be aware of the pitfalls of automation
you have to realize what works and what
does not work and when it doesn't work
up you know you have to identify the
pack
I'll that the it might be deliberate
in the nature the problem that the
sample is failing in our pension okay
saw does because the samples of Ron
doesn't mean that
arm you give up are again example that I
did for example
where it is checking the payment process
being I and how many clean sample for
example I want to check that
right so if I can capture that behavior
are
as a future even though it does not run
I'll
that the presence of that featured some
might be very conclusive to the fact
that it is malicious
I don't know of any please offer that
trying to check for the it's been
processed I E N
and his running if it is not funny
games maybe I could think of are so the
challenge
really is you know water the matter is
about an application with the
the configuration file are and that is
all that is right I mean if you
getting mad images about application and
comes on with %uh
condition file which causes it to be a
maliciously arm
then we're really trying to train on
what are you trying to immediate
I have an example of up I mean I don't
know how many are familiar with GD
bought
a DD what was an MI sea-based bought are
and
8 drop minimize the application to the
convict fun
and the country if I was able to on the
neck be a match the application to
connect to chat room
and take this actions are so it's a it's
not manipulated its
check some exactly matches up the reason
I'm actually and it's a convict which is
really driving the malicious activity on
behalf of the
am I see other kitchen knife you want to
automate that you might conclude the
fact that
and IC applications militias up but
are if if you know if a signature up
analysts gets for love the fact that you
conclude this file is militias
they might issue a signature on the
missile they might issue an AB signature
on the basis of the
check some other five and that is a
mistake you wonder why because
it's on the Massey aperture that
militias because then you would really
such a signature and we're
by Paul am I see across all the users
machines
it's a combination of beer the UMass the
application was dropped
very well it running as are and and arm
you know it was a grueling confirmation
information from its own so for that
minute militia duty but was running from
Windows affordable me
I'll probably post a video that in the
speakers India
so those are the meanest his arm and arm
to conclude the fact that you know blow
machine learning is one of the ways in
which you can do with the scale
the problem you know you have to use
machine learning with the combination
domain expertise in order to make it a
very compelling solution
but nonetheless it's not the only
solution has to be augmented with
many other approaches in any
any questions and Ivan pretty fast