just one warning in the beginning of the
storm
I'm not going to present a plan of some
kind of 102 make
the internet secure I've just collected
some thoughts on
IT security from a more global point a
few or according to come from closing
its
the leading fused in debating walls in
peace am
I'm operating on the strategic level so
on for someone like to to introduce my
IE I'm
I'm interested in giving the storm point
I chose that public and
1i try to discuss security on a
strategic you
am lost you I get to talk you into deep
sec 2010
which was titled cycle on the horizon
and there was some
others have all related talks like cyber
crimes have a warm
I'm connecting the dots and currently
there is a big hype in the media in
Europe in Germany and in other countries
to
on cybersecurity sign in security and
the possibility of its I'm war I'm the
German press
interested in writing articles sent the
Chinese army is trying to attack us via
the internet and
and there is a lot of long Balchin
been going on in the present a medium
and among we are all going down tomorrow
because of the Internet
so on my try to I'm do some kind of more
technical analyzes the first time was
possible and gave a talk on that last
year
and according to my analyzes according
to Charles Evans
I'm Sibel war is not possible each
because more means
that you able to force you enemy to do
what you want
by overcoming his power and that is not
possible on the internet you still have
to use
morning on me like tanks infantry
battleships and so long
so in my opinion the times time was
little bit X agreed
however am that the media and the
politicians and to whom other people
talking about I'm securities in my
opinion
I'm very good development because
several years ago
a securities awareness was almost
nonexistent
except for security professionals song
am if I remember correctly in 2000
there was an incident where a
15-year-old Canadian shot on eBay and
Amazon using
script hacked by German hackers from an
orphan
I'm he took out his own and and evening
he too got Amazon eBay and that was the
first time that
IT security was reported on a large
scale in German media
souls and Sam on and when it has been
rosy especially by media and by Obama
journalists
but some in my opinion
not anyone involved in the discussion
knows what he's talking about
dentists especially true for Jones
possibly surgeons
a.m. and for some glycine speaking in
the news on security incidents
um there's also something that is very
likely that
are politicians and lobbyists group
using the security
topic to push on I can go to send again
known for their political
point if you for example in Germany's
some political parties interested in
getting more regulation to the Internet
in in more surveillance & surveillance
technology
and using the time would be paid to sent
that again to the median Swan song
the discussion could be enhanced in
quality to me
so what does between development and IT
security or why is
IT security becoming a Morris global
problem
am it. information technologies emerging
too many new fields
and with and information technology
emerging to new fuels
IT security also images to new fuels
many of those fields for people looking
in those fields
on what to wear of information
technology problems and information
technology
security problems for example Electrical
and Mechanical Engineers which I have
already worked with have a complete
different concept of security
electrical engineers interested in
electrical security social security
means for them
that using of the device cannot touch
the electrical
contacts in the inside so the use double
shootings or something like that
this is a complete different concept of
security compared to IT security
and they do have a very static rule on
static view of security
for example in Germany there is an
organisation for standardisation which
is called in german teen
it's comparable to the american and iced
tea and
it publishes moves on electrical
engineering security and mechanical
security
and if any engineer developing a new
device is following those rules
he will get no problems final so if
anything happens and he followed those
rules
he's on the safe side nothing will
happen to him am
this does not apply to IT security you
cannot create for some reasons
such a static rooms such a list of
static routes which
which have to be followed
so from one has to change am the
mindsets
those who are working I am as electrical
or mechanical engineer with
IT security on T in general
international with IT security
I'm networking and especially the
Internet is also emerging to new fields
on for example there is the vision that
ipv6
and able to teach coffee maker and
church to be online
so smart living is a new I'm idea
where Joe home should be stuffed with
information technology
intelligent information technology so
you could use your smartphone controlled
heating at home millions too much
offense
and you could instruct your fridge to
automobile online because you're running
on
disciplines this this is some kind of my
solution for the people
something information technology it's
also my vision for the people
working in IT and building homes but
once again an those people designing
those products are not
having IT security on the mind the only
twelve possible IT security problems
which will definitely a rice when smart
living homes smart homes are built
I'm lost to head to talk to guys doing
research into smart me to field
intelligent smart meters I'm those are
using have a legal
the heavily relying on information
technology and
the welcome to come sit almost
completely of electrical engineers and
they have absolutely no idea
which aunty security problems put my sim
and
once again for the manufacturers of
those things security is expensive
to make something to chew costs money to
design secure in a sexual way costs
money
to make security checks cost money and
security is not sexy
people who are buying technological
products I T like
mobile phones computers or something
like that on mostly not
interested in security the engine
student at a computer look sexy
and behaves that they won't undertaken
to funny scenes with your computer or
mobile phone like taking photos taken
movies
be always on mine with Facebook for
spill something like that
so IT security is mainly completely
ignored in the design clothes and doing
closes off
Technology Information Technology um
the old Greek in saying of course hmm
maybe you know what to whom come from
long once some kind of profit
always want that the remember pretty
Trojans will go down
and she was completely ignored in this
is some kind of Chris Henderson miss you
call it in psychology talk
the people who always moaned about his
security ignored at one point in time
and that usually happens to me if I C
but you have to keep his security in
mind each and every meeting
people start leaking or me and or not
longer interested in what I say about
it. security
so I can stand there and talk to them
and to completely ignore me
because it doesn't have to be a a point
of view or down
interests especially I'm the guy sitting
the controlling and public relations and
marketing
definitely not in transit to listen to
an engineer
on IT security specialist because they
are completely unsexy
and they usually not wearing suits and
tights
ties um one honestly interesting point
is lost again from
short analyzes of stocks made and
there's one thing that is really
interesting about stocks not because
stocks not protect programmable logic
controllers in SoCal
shield sees which used on industrial
control systems
so it doesn't detect the normal average
Windows desktop PC or something
sometime SmartPhone mobile phone or
something like that by attacked
industrial control
systems am according to Symantec brought
from
a large paper on stocks not engage
abroad and the minds of this
nowhere and stocks not included the
first created
PLC Richard so started with the first
time
the root it was designed for
programmable logic controllers
or at least the first known rootkit
there may be others
which have never been discovered am
unfortunately those industrial control
systems for mehndi
again developed and operated by
electrical engineers who have the
different concept of security
am for the malicious software might
attack appeal sees
or industrial control systems the ones
who have been attacked by stocks and
women we used
am Indian uranium program especially in
the run
and there for people think that started
was due to attack the
uranium problem which was which is
running but the run
but one could use that rude crude
mmm to to attack different kind of
programmable logic controllers for
temple Houston traffic lights
or at airports for the on security
controls for the security
measurements them another interesting
thing that currently happened
is that a car has been hacked by
americans accuse you resurgence
with a menu pleaded or do city mp3 CD
so the many pleaded CD and got control
of the computer
which is controlling the car many
control that computer in
you can of course also heck that current
change for example the petals fall break
and
gas or something like that to you to
change the steering wheel and
which is also interesting you could many
people like the car
and use a rootkit or something like that
to clean up after an accident so no one
will be aiming
in a forensic analyzes to find out that
that car has been hacked
in anatomical not on mechanical me
so a lot of you and protection act as a
committee opened up
and once again 96 out his jury duty
IT security doesn't play a role in the
design of the systems
I'm there will also be a talk on
automotive security home
tomorrow SMSing is tomorrow
am this the diagram chart not rated on
the IEEE
five years ago from a crippling am they
have
a diagram of intruding on which which
was shown by this
dotted line and they had have another
line of attack sophistication
and what I found most interesting in
the development of a tech surfaced
occasion and into the mountains
that a lot of attacks undone by intruder
Smith very very
in few knowledge about IT security and
computer systems and all
most the tech is on and well-educated
seconds people with a lot of
knowledgeable technology but most from
vulnerabilities and exploits the use by
script kiddies other people who just use
pre manufactured computer programs
scripts or
exploits that are available on the
Internet
I am I for example for this some zombies
pop dance
and distributed denial sons booknotes
containing usually thousands or even
millions
of zombie computers computers which
under control point children whose rude
kid
and can be used to attack some boy but
they are usually used by Simon group to
extort companies like banks
so the blackmail them that the answer
should pay some money or they will shut
down their network
a website with distributed denial of
service from the service
am those botnets are usually created by
automated scanning of large nets
and networks and automated exploiting of
detected and already known
vulnerabilities
most of the software used by police have
a crime group that uses
vulnerabilities which around the old
they don't use
unknown 0 to explode like the guys who
developed Stuxnet
the union's exports which already known
and
sometimes there were even pensions are
available for them
I'm the main average use of computer
systems are still not aware
on many other jews often are still not
aware of but he's a cutie in 20 security
concepts on
they don't they are not interested in IT
security they of course not interested
in keeping the system up-to-date
um many young people who
I personally train an IT security were
sent to me by the company for training
say why should anyone to take me I'm
just an average user I don't have
anything special I don't have
much money on my banking accounts for no
one is interested in
taking me or is something else so from
unfortunately many people don't invest
time or knowledge in 20 security and
if they are we had of IT security they
often lacking the skills to secure
Honda systems and according to
report given to Microsoft about 40
percent of exploits
use my abilities were security patches
have been available for more than 12
months
all these security incidents
could have been prevented because the
security updates for Microsoft
already there and they have been there
for at least 12 months
some am forty-percent these explored a
very
easily to be prudent very very easily
but unfortunately
they are not present
I'm another problem which I'm very
interested in is
since I studied psychology do focus a
lot on social engineering and security
women's
and social engineering is in IT security
technique or technology to circumvent
security mechanisms by misusing human
behavior
one could say that a social engineers
taking people instead of checking
computers
or to sum it up in
some salt and why should I tricky DC
must've looked past me if I can talk to
use into revealing his password
and that social engineering um is now
combined with technological was gripped
attacks for something
you can use automatic scripts and
programs
to create enhanced spear phishing
attacks
to collect data password to install
moments from a chance
for example you can on check social
networks for the name a friend's
often intended to the target to see for
example
who went to school with room and then
you can forge that identity
from former school comrade often
intended tyrant
and features identity and send mail will
Trojan horses or something like that
under that fake identity
and the possibility that the attack will
be successful is
much higher if you use such social
engineering and Hans
spear fishing methods and ten to fifteen
years ago when I
first did social engineering you had to
do a lot of research had
to work not to find information and
facts about people for example with whom
they went to school or
which other managers Laden or something
like that or am
which football club they are a fan of
known as you only have to go to Facebook
you find all the daughter their online
they are presenting and
the daughter to you and you can use them
and you can
do the research within a single hour
maybe even less
and what is another interesting you can
do this automatically
the astronauts the way to be which
harvest for example Facebook to collect
those tonton
and those standards and used to me great
spew phishing emails
and those emails a very very successful
have a much higher success rate than the
standard
a Nigerian scam email where people are
try to send money to Nigeria
on other African state so and this is
one of the
most interesting and most people me a
technique tunes
for the next yes I would say I'm
especially with
the combination of smart mobile phones
for people
telling directly whether crudely on
whether currently walking around his
location based services and such
and combined those starter from the
mobile phones with the data from
Facebook you can do a lot of
interesting social engineering things
yeah
I'm the wrist another point that came to
me
being a psychologist by training I'm
I think of IT security is not just the
technological problem
and psychology would say it's
multifactorial so you have multi demands
on the defectors of IT security
unfortunately most IT security
professionals
specialist just seeing of IT security
yes the technical technological problem
but IT security also has besides
technological to mention
a psychological dimension the social
dimension
the political dimension and of course
legal dimension I would like to give
some point
did I mention for the slides am
IT security has in my opinion to extend
its limitations to technology IT
security professionals
should call parade with for example
psychology social sciences education
signs
deduct X adult education law politics
and I would like to show why and how um
the human factors are also very
interesting when one speaks of IT
security or security in general
I'm human factors research as a branch
of psychology especially industrial
engineering psychology at least in the
german-speaking
the country's and human factors is
interested in working on man-machine
interaction for example
there is research project on Mon at my
university
on the pop into flood of complaints and
electronic assistance and toss
so is it a good idea by some a common
infections too
and develop electronic assistance and
give a lot of information to you
I'm still able to cope with that
information all my
information create some kind of denial
of service in your computer
duties and shot on your brains week on
steal the car anymore
am machine injection does not limited to
poppin scars and airplanes and also
applies to interaction between users and
computers
uses an operating systems and and
operating system
that is not usable that has poor
usability is usually an operating system
with a lot
of security flaws because and many users
will not be able to to get along with
that computer system will
make security fields make install
security problems
I'm another point for human factors a
psychology in general is
security weapons and capacity-building
the main questions
questions or problems are usually focus
when doing
security whens campaigns and companies
how'd we motivate people to get
interested in IT security
this is really huge problem standing in
front of the name saying
IT security is a big problem usually
doesn't work you have to find other ways
to motivate them
and to get them to get them interested
in IT security
like already said most people say I'm
not an interesting target I don't have
any money I don't have
security all specials but without on my
computer something like that I'm just an
average
John Doe why should I be attacked by
some
and them there has to be much more
research in in motivational and
educational psychology on how
tomb get to those people on how to get
those people interested in IT security
and once I got them interested in IT
security
how do I train and educate people and
that how do I change people to install
pensions
installing pensions is somewhat easy for
30 June
its somewhat easy to to to explain and
educate people installing patches spot
on
much more complex security missions for
temple trip to Hershey
I started to give talks on trip Tom
Murphy fifteen years ago
and it isn't really big problem to get
people
to know how to use for example pgp to
intrude males
and I've been in a peace deal available
from Houston I have tried to train at
bees the developers to use pgp which
I completely failed I only got two other
guys to use pgp and those guys are
developing
operating systems and the armed able to
get along with PGP you are not
interested in
so how do you want an average computer
users and then
and the company to be well IT security
and to be interested in IT security and
how do you want to educate and train
them
another problem I'm I'm focusing on
social engineering
um social engineering if you want to
prevent social engineering
you have a social problem and social
problems can only be solved by social
solutions
you cannot solve social problems by
technical solutions
so if you want to do something and
social engineering you have to use
psychology
and other sources social sciences
somebody cations
on and unfortunately the research in
social engineering
on a professional university level is
not that high
I broke my bachelor thesis on the
problem on measuring IT security and
on on how to develop condoms to social
engineering
and I really had to run around and ask
professes failing to supervise my fuses
because
when globe psychology or didactics
professors have the I would
white would like to write about IT
security information technology
the main we certainly got computers I
don't have any clue about them please go
to another going
cell there is a problem that that
psychology or social science do not
cooperate with technology that well
most people who interested in technology
study technological
cause like in the computer science
informatics electrical engineering such
and those who aren't interested in
technology usually take something else
like solutions
and with very hard to get those two
kinds of people to work together
and unfortunately they do have to work
together if they want to solve
if we want to solve security problems
so to sum it up there is a lot to do
let's get it on let's do something
am now all some problems all things that
could be enhanced
for the manufacturers software um
manufacturers of software have to deal
with security problems
one good example is Microsoft only
stayed
evolved lot during the last ten to
fifteen years fifteen years ago
%uh they were not interested in security
problems if you think of the user
management of Windows 95 Windows 98
it still sends shivers down my spine
that those computers when the Internet
the days back them unfortunately
Microsoft has evolved a lot has changed
a lot of politics and policy
within the company and they develop in
Rolla pensions
they established that patch to stand
firm imprudently
am to get in contact with the huge
resurgence with white had taken
am they work together was people
reporting security holes and flows
um Apple for example now has some
Sudan whitehat hacking who reported
security
problems and operating system and is in
my opinion not the way to treat
security experts point companies saw
manufactures a software have to be to
web security matters and they have to
establish
a strategy management method to to cope
with that
problems
arm another dimension I mentioned as
politics and law
of course these views on them into
germany by
it is very hard for me to understand
German also I'm
absolutely not be able to understand
american ring usual french laws
soil megan's little bit to Germany
am in Germany we do have a concept of
product liability by the manufacturer so
if you manufacturing any goods
you are liable and responsible for the
security and safety of the product
you cannot sell a computer which got
some fire when you turn it
on if that happens you're required to
to repair machine and you also forced by
the courts to pay some money for people
who have
been threatened by John products another
concept is that abuse liability by the
user so
and as the user of a technical systems
you also
responsible and liable for the safety of
that system for champion
and you are responsible and liable for
the security and safety of
a car when you're running around wasn't
so if you're driving a car with the
brakes on it working
you responsible completely if anything
happens no insurance yours will pay for
the exit and
if you drive the car which broken breaks
unfortunately the court in Germany have
need and some decisions
that the users in Germany I'm normally
not responsible or liable for the
technical security of the computers
because to called the dungeons IT
security isn't too complex and too
complicated topic
we cannot force is used to be
responsible for the security because
a they would be forced to learn a lot of
things and we can't refuse to do so
soul a many the judges ruled but those
people are not liable
for security problems for example they
were
decisions made by courts of people's
whose computer have been turned into
zombies
and Houston botnet attacks and the
victims of the pot next
botnet attacks and issued the owns
of the zombies and they wanted of course
some money from them or at least that
the the judges say that those people are
responsible for the problem in should
fixing computers but unfortunately the
judges were not willing to do so
I am in my opinion this should be
changed I'm not am
more you're more explode and I'm also
not that much into politics in Germany
but
arm we could at least try to to start a
discussion in the media room politics
that people should be liable for the
security and safety of their computers
and in my opinion the manufacturers of
software should also be responsible and
liable for the products
and my opinion is completely
unacceptable that big companies like
Google Microsoft Apple so on
a producing operating system with
security problems and security holes and
not react on it
I can be clear to me that you can never
that you never can get one hundred
percent of security or
on a technical system but at least the
manufactures have to establish some kind
of management strategy or at least the
strategy on handling
the security problems and if they don't
and willing to do so
they should be forced by the law but
politics to
to implement and this does not only has
to be done by
establishing a new a new long but for
example
government or offices could decide to
not use
software produced by manufacturers who
are not willing to invest in security
and safety
others one example some years ago and
baton of Munich decided to switch to
Linux
on the complete on management and two or
three days later Steve
form of love has flown directly to
Munich to talk to
the city management that they might
change their decision so
once the tournament going on something
switching to the next the
Steve Balmer came directly to Germany to
do some spinning
public relations on so it works and
might for example works if
for example the German armed forces say
we are not willing to buy my personal
computer
operating systems anymore because in
securing and
that would happen in my opinion why
would say that steeple Mon
or another manager would come at once to
Germany to
try to prevent the German armed forces
for doing so from doing so
yeah politics security politics or
security policy is in essence of every
government and the discussion
war and peace is of course something
that is usually done by security
politicians
bye bye governmental states of the
United Nations armed forces
so arm each government is responsible
for setting a police forces firefighters
hospitals armed forces and so on to
protect the sit-ins
citizens and the Internet is now being
discussed but politicians
mostly in very strange me so currently
there is a debate
on the remote forensic tool German law
enforcement community
they've developed some kind of the nose
mood can't to spy on
from YouTube's in and unique
and one of the tribute to spend all that
there might be something wrong with his
computer turned it into the case
computer clock in Berlin
and term for weeks ago the case Computer
Club published together was a big
German news-journal 10 pages
analyzes of that remote for in Dec 29 to
call it in
the politics and now there is a big
discussion going on if the
politics the policies I'm the law
enforcement community if they should be
allowed to develop such huge
such good kids and deploy them in the
wind
especially since the security of
magnitude
is very very limited has a lot of
security falls
of consumption could has ministry to the
rights who joins on the computer and
the developer of the dream could use to
hardcoded password for this
for the communication between the
command and control server and
the router should and that password
percent can text over the network
so if you if you just catch-all
eavesdrop on the password you can to
control over any of that federal
children holes
and the password for that Trojan horse
is in every case the same it is r2 d2
c3po
some there is even some kind GM and the
German please available
arm I don't know if the no-nonsense is
completely legal in English but if you
read
if you are able to read German go into
the fund for 20 minutes I think they
have a lot of articles missing
arm yeah you should also talked to
poland
politicians you should trying to educate
them
you can avoid holding for them to
confound
upon a new political party arm
the German pirate party on the plane
plenty of people in
no is with all 15 pirates a member of
the berlin poignant
because the people are when the the to
be cool the old
parties are discussing Internet and
computer games and
it. problems topics and in a very
strangely and polls in voted completely
full
pirate party in provincial all 15
members of
or fifteen people who'd been 15
available to be elected
when elected into the burn in Parliament
and now each and every single political
party in germany has and again on IT
security computer games and so on
because they are frightened by this
development of course
arm another single politics good to
if the manufacturers have suffered on
Campbell security the government could
force him by
law by avoiding buying their problems
much uncertainty
slide
I'm yeah not only thing the nation's
shouldn't
work on on cyber security IT security
but also
the United Nations governments in
countries should cooperate in fighting
cybercrime
and soul if you sign a crime someone is
doing so I'm a crime from Russian on a
German computer
of course the German police cannot
the fight against those russians because
they are working in a different country
and they are not
germans doing any crime sold the
governments in countries should
cooperate in fighting cybercrime
are all really corporations for example
in fighting terrorism
hiding text laundry or something like
that money laundering
and and and tax crimes and should be
extended to IT security and IT problems
and cybercrime
many countries on what the way of
cybercrime
I did some research on the situation and
clean white Russia and Russian
and unfortunately most of the Russian
police forces
are not without the time chronic since
and if they are when they don't have the
technology they don't have the time and
money to buy
am computers for forensic tools
something like that and they don't have
the knowledge
solo the police forces of States rooftop
don't have that knowledge could be
trained by
other police forces as we offer example
it wrong he doing in Afghanistan
a lot of Afghanistan policeman offices
trained by the German police
the German Federal Police in Afghanistan
thing having training programs for those
policemen they could do the same
for example for russian policemen inside
a crime so the russians good
fight time tram in a more efficient way
so
maybe in in the near future the united
nations are able to shut on cyber crime
gangs
least those who want to come to you can
in
more sophisticated manner else holding
solvable problems
am like a already set according to
Microsoft forty-percent
exploited used moon beauties were
security pensions have been available
for more than 12 months
Microsoft evolved and implemented to
cyber security strategy
which is a very good thing think of the
times when Windows 95
was ruled on Microsoft didn't give a
fuck about
computer security but unfortunately the
Jews did not evil
they are not interested in not easy to
use it don't have know when and if they
don't have the skills to
sent to harden and secure the system's
so arm some some
Enzo ideals how the different
by means of security could work together
what they could do so
as a psychologist I would say psychology
is responsible for awareness from
training and education
um as far as I know on No really
scientifically based
the pre class problems available for the
training and education of
IT security skills on some hand books
available in the US
developed by the and honesty anthems
also
am an and manual available by the German
office for and security in information
technology
but they all morning some kind of hands
on not
really the scientific base with the
tactical few million swansong
when I brought my pension seasons my
professor bait me to use tools manuals
people 30 not scientific based
so we should do a little research on
that field
and there will also be a talk on human
factors research he on deep sink
today so if you're interested in that go
to the talk it
and will be very interesting I think am
the politics the politicians and
politics could make users more liable
for security problems and so
if you want to get rid of Bulls easy
solvable security problems which are
usually
explored by striptease we have to make
the user's line before the security and
safety of the optical computer systems
and this can only be done in the end by
the politics so
am at least one laws established in
Germany that every users as possible for
his computer
and people I am forced to pay money if
their computers are exploited
then they will definitely react because
you can get almost any German
to management about money arm
the medium can also do something about
we on this and they can cover the topic
of IT security but please do so in a
serious way
there is a lot of of of media coverage
on on the topic of IT security which is
not very serious sandwiches
more in the sense of oh my god we're all
going to die to morning
and the Chinese army is trying to take
in San trying to june's and you should
use the internet on
that's not way to discomfort problems
I'll the social science could do
something about knowledge management in
organizations
this is a big problem I usually face
been doing security runs campaigns and
companies and organizations inserts
it's a big problem too if you already
have the moment it's a big problem to
deployed in an organization so that
every member of this organization is
aware of what he's a cutie and
am has developed the required skills
and capacities to to social security
problems soul
a lot of what has to be done not many of
his work can be done
by IT security in specialists a
professional statement
technical background some has to be done
by non-technical
by people with non technical background
but in the end they all have to
cooperate and
I think it's its vital for forty
security that
IT security professionals cooperate with
non technological professional
saloons mmm the last night when I have
to say something about
am to sum it up IT security has many
dimensions
and IT security professionals and
resurgence and people who looking out
his security have to connect to the time
engine
problems can often only be solved and
some all of these dimensions
only there's only a very limited sent IT
security problems which can be solved
completely by
technological met in small pensions or
something so
most problems you extend to multiple
dimensions
20 security and another thing IT
security is not stated
study it's an evolving process it's the
pros and cons
means management so for example on
economy on management professionals can
also teach us something about it.
security
the can teach us on how to manage to
choose how to manage organizations to be
up to date with a knowledgeable
something like that