back leaving everyone thank you for
staying
awake and alive long enough to hear me
as
as only seven talkback
nearing attacks which is a project I'm
working on at the moment
and Honda chief it through modeling
categorizing
and conversing the attacks am seeking a
bit more detail
first interview pat pat myself and this
the first time i present its conference
sour to get it back on the myself this
in words in each night their subsequent
terminology insights engineering
something which is generic and if you've
done it before you might know I'm
and some of which I have to come up with
to explain concepts
we can look at the Y why do we actually
need a site
a solution to social engineering and
chase models
the hope for checks type built around
models is quite a few doing different
things
and we can look at what they do how we
can model section change back to how
they work to help us solve it
we can categorize the models
so we can to be defensive categories for
different types of sections near an
attack
we can convert the idea is to get a
solution to do that
we convert the attacks from stations
near attacks
and something else and that allows us to
find a solution a man of a shot by
looking briefly towards the future
what you can do to improve or expand to
full time to show you here
so I first saw her mine I'm not going to
give you my hoe see
day and as always I'm a finally a
student at the University York
in the UK I'm studying computer science
and this project actually my final year
project
doctorate plus sizes negatives on the
goods
night it means you can ship their
athletes just one saying is being packed
and neck
scientific everything I've done has got
justifications behind it
I'm not gonna show you these
justifications if you ask me about it
the and/or after with a happy explain
them on the downside mean special
project
I've only been working on this for a
month filter 23
and part-time I've only gone a month
foresight to guide
and has an awful lot more that could be
done in future for this
went fine on your side the entire for
first tent information security
which is a pen testing social
engineering up
two things each night the the dictionary
is it worth my talk
I will start by looking at what what you
mean by solving
and Sykes engineering and then is more
than this
social engineering generic stuff like
attack and knock and finally some
projects to fix stuff
attacks and stories what I mean myself
like
as the picture shows superbly that is
not a solution
in the proper sense there's a number of
problems with it
if the bottle breaks if you can't read
English
of person Seikon hey when the shaking it
the solution is incomplete
as time trying to use academically I'm
looking very much for us
scientific definition of the absolving
I'm trying to find something that always
works
I will all will solve everything now
obviously
so all sections mary has its limitations
is not necessary possible welcome back
that the aim is to find something it
sold all sections and tax
what I mean by station generic
I'm not talking about computer viruses
infecting humans
have awesome that might be I me talking
about us ko kaise deception
session from a session sneering boils
down to this action
and South any view hearing it from basin
you have seen the BBC program possible
all the wheel muscle japan's I get here
k
you make your you be in the ship the
show is all about confidence tricks and
confidence our test I contracts conning
people
hustling them to get money usually I
don't we make it
a distinction between contract con
artist in contracts and social
engineering
and because at the end the day that both
doing same thing that both receiving
somebody
to achieve a goal and sluts at last pic
effectively the definition I'm going
with
using deception to achieve a goal
whatever the girl may Bay
then some sections your genetic stuff
the mock miss the person who's being the
same the victim
in the attack as you as it were the mark
is always a single person
certain attacks you might be off
thinking some have multiple not
example phishing attack I could send out
one email to a million different people
for this purpose is my models I'm
consider each mark to be a separate
model
to the you consider individual marks the
reason for this is we're looking for
solutions that will position the marks
point
yet we can't be most marked the same
time
attack a is this is the section
geneticist the person actually doing the
deception
companies that have attacked a most the
time like me to play safe engineer a few
seconds
this can be plural again as you'll see
later on
it doesn't matter whether it's a single
percent a whole group of people doing
the deceiving
you can just consider is one person some
very project specific stuff
if you consider social engineering let's
take an example
the attack has this girl he wants to
achieve less to do that is to make three
phone calls
is gathering person I and ask this
question is gonna ring
person pay and get this that information
he's thinking person's say
and use the first two pieces of
information chief the girl
that whole thing I just described is the
story
it's the entire incident from the
attackers point to VA
we've reached in March 20 so each of the
individual phone calls individual attack
because each one has an individual mock
and so what we're trying to look at the
individual elements
the reason for this is obviously if you
can stop one at the attacks
the overall story but work anymore and
so to solve
sections Mary attacks as long as you can
so one of the best one of the things
that make up
the overrule the overall story the
attacker gets uses to get to install
you can stop station engineering
what's the point there is the very
famous quite
that no one's quite sure who started
because there is no catch for human
stupidity
and it's very apt uses a general's as
general thing
all very naive they tend to be an
experienced
and the usual ignorant the correct
things today
this training out there some great
training either sections in a ring
but it can't be perfect know how could
the training is it will never achieve
perfection
because what you're affected joint day
is make people aware of their own
weaknesses
how to fight them that's not really a
solution that's trying to fill in the
blanks as it were
well we're looking at you look at the
diagram thing done so software engineer
sure some people have you recognize this
is the sort of problem she faxed
trainings ever gonna be bottom right it
works it does its job
as in the has brought your issues with
it I we're aiming very much for bottom
left we want something that's cast on
the will do the job how we gonna do this
we can ignore psychology if you've ever
read a book on social engineering
look from any website talk 21 account
when talks conferences
people talk nonstop about psych the
psychology behind it
you should take advantage of this motion
use this witness in human behavior
if you read something body language like
this you can achieve this
put on this fancy costume you become
someone else entirely and alleviate
I'm sure if you've done it alcohol haha
Yellow Jacket
in a city with a briefcase on the side p
you can use psychology to Chi session
generic
the problem is is too complex it's
almost impossible to model sites
engineering
including the psychology because there
is not take when the world
put it down the reason I can ignore
psychology K
is because we cannot make the assumption
that it will work not
after certain amount of psychology after
a certain amount of social engineering
the attack will succeed if we assume
success
then we can black box the psychology 8
books were gonna assume that it will
work
and we can certainly something on much
simpler model I'm so that's then
something we can and soul
so how much gonna go back to its remedy
these models from
Russ not war stories I went to the
library
which is a BS issued is a scary place
I read books I look on web sites I
started reading all the stories
actual social engineers have been out
that you've done it and written down
their exploits in a book
and I started documenting the documents
about a hundred Saif up
I'm going to undertake take to these
attacks the model up
when I model these attacks and remove
psychology day
and ended up in obstruction it turns out
this fall models the couple or the
social engineering attacks
now amazing enough for mothers is
reasonably so lovable
and so that's what I proceeded today but
first
a bit of a disclaimer if I if in the 100
model
if the 100 attacks the night document
I've missed something
than anything i show you from here on in
if the beginning as opposed to a
complete solution
which is as I said at the start what
we're aiming for
let's continue on the assumption that
I'm I've got it right and we haven't
missed anything
and as you say I don't think I have and
if you can think many examples a social
engineering attacks
are isn't shown in my model please yell
it out all set to be and
I really don't think you will says that
took models
and which doctor we removed all the
stuff we took into the relevant stuff
but has backed the picture and Einstein
very wise inside we didn't get a file
there is still enough detail in done for
them to be relevant and
important the good news is it meant
because you move psychology
you can strip at a lot of detailed
otherwise would be important
for example if a social engineer cop
tries to contact the mock
on the south side or in person on the
street
all fire email in each nation army as
the marks going to react differently
but week knowing cycle the day and so it
doesn't matter
you can ignore how the time to actually
does the things he does
providing you acknowledge that he doesn
t do that
said it was well as looking example
first attack on che is this from
due to do with information bill is the
Micronauts peacock
I'll
you're right attack
this model shows information the mark is
trying to that the attackers joins get
information off the mark now the two
types information I've modeled
public information which is not essay
published
but since the information that you could
get legally without necessary to any
section general hacking
a private which is everything else now
obviously in a company or in the
military
privates going to be broken up into
different levels confidentiality
but for the book the past as a model
that will encompass within private
at the top as augmenting only got
contacts you've got these two boxes
which is the attack to contact the mark
they stood the reason there is today
is because the first one is the attacker
contact the mock
this is fairly normal I'm bringin I
bring my speaks them on the
I speaking our email was hacked the
other one came about
when I was reading a kevin Mitnick book
I wanted that can mimic his dad and I
was a very famous American section
engineer
has been in after President and had good
guy and has written like two books
about that things he's done leading in
illegally
and wannabes but one of the stories he
ok to tell if I can switch
so that a number that normally went to a
place of s so that
police officers who came from a shed
actually went to his mobile site
needless to say the marks run the number
and with director is now behind
after psychological point you then need
sunt was a police officer he's genuine
we can tell this guy stuff nope in fact
station genetic has one is the second
box the attacker gets the mark to
contact back
United downside the psychology book says
mission as a set
black box-like ellijay we've
acknowledged that at every stage
we need the social engineer may have to
do something
may have to do some convincing Matthew
some tricks
but will issue we go through on the far
left you'll notice
in adults the next two case we're
assuming it works
that that the clarity see you can see
where it could fail book
will take them out like six we can
assume the attack works
the fun thing I want to mention it is at
the bottom the two boxes the mall
realizes they've been attacked and not
doesn't realize they've been attacked
those few who forced the hustle the Real
Hustle
will be where the turn on to burn the
mock
Ifans techa burns the mock in these the
market realize that they be attacks
they realize they've done something
wrong they realize the attack has
managed to get him to do something I
shouldn't have done
it is Mikey important for an attack in
nearly all the time to not
burn the mock the reason for this if the
market doesn't
Anne stakes for civil you can't use the
same attack again
in the future because the marks going to
be on TA second a
said another attack in the store a may
not work
the mark my can tell it boss I feel we
wished you could buy just tell this guy
on the final of private information
and again two things to fix it now
Michelly you know the statistics
that rarely happens people like keep
very quiet that make such a stupid
mistake
but it could potentially influence the
story answer is vitally important most
the time
that you end up in the market doesn't
realize that being attacked box
the next model is all to do with gaining
entry
and you'll notice the time models
identical except the two middle box on
the right
where effectively the goal has changed
now what I mean by gaining entry like it
mean in a physical sense
are you trying to break into the process
have time will tell high-tech
where you follow someone through it all
like hold the door open
always my favorites when you turn up to
adore the specs but a cardinal in space
but a pin number
carrying loads of stuff from tired and
somebody sees you naked
they take eighteen they let you in this
very peaceful
it doesn't however include things on
social engineering
for example if somebody walks through
that door when I wanna just kept it for
clients as
that's not social engineering but
catching a double unless
election but he deceived somebody to
take Advil and the city to see some
gonna take advantage of that weaknesses
it's not sanctions Marant the other
example took a knee injuries the virtual
site
getting into a system getting into a
network whatever it may Bay
noun the you go I'll make a very
important distinction K
if I bring someone up an awesome thank
you's and I'm for that password
and they give it to him and I use that
to log on that not gaining entry about
the previous not lots information
because they've told me what I wanted to
hear
if I however bring up a sysadmin and
side
I work for your company Department axe
I'm away on business and the VPN access
Catholic I'm look myself after that can
you create new account
and they did it you've got you gained
access
you convince someone to affect to be
opened up but rolled over into that
system
specially for you
next model is all to do with my life we
just had a talk on my lap
I'm here is actually the model that
despite the social engineering aspects
of it
the market of access the Malla is a bit
over
cover everything box books include not
only techniques like fun send someone a
an email with the malicious attachment
the techniques like by 10
if I stick some malware on a USB stick
leaving the car park
or fight before you guys who came in
dropped USB sticks with my wife this
room I suspect find out
lost I repeat length hair because people
were to pick them up like the man
I don't dapper that included in the
house
access the box you don't necessarily
need to contact the mark in order to it
hence why this the direct line to that
box
the market access it not much use if he
doesn't the mall i guess im still
now this boxed wasn't originally that
because of the the malware installs
itself
it would mark does open the attachment
to plug in the stick
and immediately get instilled that
doesn't need to be modeled
books is not part of the social
engineering attack
however we've all had times where we've
come up with you still come across my
lap
where the user has to actually do the
instill it's a job
rapidly got click Allow or instill it's
a piece it amounted to be some outlets
the skylight is an adjustment program
they've won first and
instill sister there are numerous
examples that
hence morning back if you've got to
convince the mock
to do the install you've got to be able
to not make you feel to model psychology
and social engineering aspects
up getting them to do the install the
final model
is pretty much everything else perform
an action
I ask someone to do something specific
the example the got example the court
this autos another one from kevin
mitnick's book
it was too big I rang up telephone
repairman and Sat
on to a new copy of your company
directory which is all that
confidential numbers that the public
that have access to it
but I can't deliver to you and slot but
your own company directly back
to stick your old one out on the porch
an operatic might drop off the new one
needless to say the old one went and you
will never turned up
you call somebody to do something he's
gone and done it well she's gone and
done it
so we got the four models we can
consider these categories
affectively that's what they are they
pop-up the rescue all such engineering
attacks
but the real the reason they're all the
different what we would normally think
of as categories
is that the categories based on the goal
of the attack what the MOX actually got
to do
let the attack sexiest as opposed to the
methodology
that the attack uses normally we think
things like fishing
which is a technique that an attack use
it it's not much good for me trying to
think how do we solve this
you console fishing but thinking about
solving the malware
we now have to stop things we've never
had to stop people accessing now we know
house
me know how to stop malik et instill as
you'll see later on
to save the aim here with Cassie
consider his catchphrase is we're trying
to as
the the example of the analogy I'm using
is we're trying to cure
the course not just the symptoms
we can put more together and end up with
a nice big model
that is effectively what you just sayin
this to work
yep and as you've still got basically
you information model
your perform an action you gain entry
and your mouth and models
but you've also got a big line going
around an attack at the box that I if
you can read it has the attack it begins
the
the attack begins the story
if you think back to when I started to
talk I was talking about tax in stories
this model of them just showing love the
attacks put together
action shares the stories because
obviously the attacker can go through
one attack
look back into a different tack and so
on insightful
it is complete this is rather useful
because we can study this weekend to
work a mess because this theoretically
shows all possible social engineering
stories
anything an attacker could do using
social engineering
but we also love it to do that being
young and being British
I'm getting used something I labeled
sleepy two principal
after they see you don't know the UK
showed lupita
it's a kid's TV had been running full
must be at least 30-40 years
and that famous arts and crafts and
makes me feel things out plastic a piece
of paper and I'll
egg cartons and things with the catch
find his 1 I'm a Dahlia Telstar
I'll tell you what today and then
they'll pull out the finish one from
under the table
this is exactly the philosophy I wanted
to use to South Station engineering
rather than trying to invent solutions
on the spur of the moment
just come up with some miraculous cure I
thought let's use what's already been
invented
what's already been invented computer
security solutions
and so was not done as you pass a is I
took security social engineering models
are shipped same day
converted done in two models compute the
corresponding computer security attack
and then researched the back the current
industry best practice solution
that to do this is Val the simple we
just can't we just a bit of translating
on the models
you don't have an attacker you have a
backup yet from all
your sister now we don't need to specify
with missus a network a web app a system
of some description
you don't contact Mark yet complex
systems are you connect to it
psychology becomes hacking annual few
details so
reach nicely I'm hoping to go to see
this model
that is based on the model we just saw a
few seconds guy minus the link back
am right and everything translate it
you still got the same lane you've still
got the systems are surprised
information at
you still got the systematic gives ACA
the information
you've got the Performing Akshat for
example you think that as
seek rejection for example command
execute you're trying to get the system
to do something it shouldn't do
gay and tread happen to a network into a
web app
and now when I was pretty much till my
lap
so we now start looking for the best
practice solution so we look at them one
by one
if we look at information what we
usually do
if we go system and somebody asks it for
information
had we confirm their own out the
information but we authenticate them
and we confirm their authorized is
something we've been doing a website
something we be doing on network since
day one of computers
has white that
retaining entry after stops on gaining
entry into your system
we've had a fire will you can close any
unneeded polls
you can use an access control system
again if they've got a
connected to your network you can
authenticate them to confirm they are
throwing taxes back sir
access back part is the web whatever and
if they do succeed in through a lot
you can please make sure you know about
it you can use an IDS
malware this is easy we will be in
protect ourselves against malware
donkeys yes you can restrict movable
media
I know it easier said than done but
suddenly a lot technique special ones I
was mentioning
about USB sticks don't work the comp not
the main
you can scan traffic you can use 19 iris
keep the antivirus new computer
up-to-date understanding of the software
don't let your employees do whatever
they want ago a lot lot lot
lower-risk being infected with malware
applying to perform an action the same
thing confer authenticate
authorized it's the same stuff over
afghanis the same stuff we've all been
using
with a computer security the day's is
nothing new I'm showing on these key
sites like done his research
but now want to take the solution sorry
we cite and use them for social
engineering
so we got convert them back we're going
to back to the real world
were we get back from Pacha to attack a
backup system to mock back from connect
to contact
backpacking to psychology possibly ok if
you bet
ensure the solution still works now this
is where it gets a bit difficult tonight
you are very weakly line
over well I going to do what's that
might come up this point on what still
needs doing probably by someone in the
industry
it's kind of the implementation of the
system
we think I can come up I come up with
the frame with a car with how you can do
it
but actually converting those solutions
back is a really big problem
as you can see in a second Vic solutions
got to meet the
definition we came up with again it's
still got to be completed gotta sold
all possible cases it's not always work
it can't introduce an heiress it can't
go role
and as we all know that's exactly what
security solutions do
if this is an example if we look at with
patented
sections near information model we've
still got the same solution
but if we think that computer while
we've got the problem we can't we've got
website
networks that is secured with its a
username/password
I they confirm if you say you are and
that you run out again
but most the ten tests and probably most
it was everyone in the room
will have come across situations weapon
docking doesn't work
it's been implemented incorrectly some
program for got a line of code
vital has some minor mistake that means
you can get around it
implementation is pot it doesn't work
for this to work
implementation the speakers has come
back at one of the website
this the prime using the using this or
Solutions Inc
information is something that the
military been doing for a very very long
time
if I rang up the US Joint Chiefs and
says hello
I'm Barack Obama I would like to launch
a nuke Russia
vannatter let me do it unless I can
confirm I am Barack Obama
I'm allowed to launch a new now on that
now US military's want to shoot if
memory serves to create death
on something or other before was allowed
to do it
that if they're using the system while
we use me and businesses
we've got the solution we know it works
they use it
but we not using it nevermind
gaining entry you can't use a final you
could use a security guard
they work very well if they're
well-trained you can't close ports be
kind close entrances and exits
how many social engineers climb into an
empty about to win that has me locked
for
like access control systems the shoot
the Metro any those trains
net travel networks tend to use barriers
to stop use wondering on to them
why don't we barry's in business make
sure that actually work
of them when we do use barriers just
like on the train systems
the ones that you can jump over or climb
under
or just pushed through a
finally we hit again girlfriend Kate and
all the all the old author who say they
are
all they also want to do this a 90 s
system
you mean something like CCTV a buy it
physically telling someone's doing stuff
in your business if not no good just
having in the lobby
if sections may goes up stairs into your
server you want to know what services
played around with
is no good wondering in seeing the
unplug one cable in assuming that's it
when in fact at the back one of your
rocks is plug in USB stick with malware
my lap ok enough the solutions are
exactly the same
restricting removable media use
anti-virus
it's tough we've been doing for ages but
we don't do it very well
now I realize I'm I'm typing very me
that he left the industry
because I'm talking theoretical as
opposed to real life
the solutions this post academic can say
that this is what you could do
to prevent the problem as opposed to his
something you can actually taking the
bases and guaranteed to work
perform an action is the same stuff
authenticate non-authorized
we got to get up but this is kinda the
ok smart girl
to come up with a model like this that
shows all possible social engineering
attacks
and more importantly shows the solutions
because we can I start using this as
policy
we can take this to a basis in sight let
let me in command is for you of you in
the business
she bosses let's implement that if we
implement all these red boxes
theoretically we not gonna we no longer
gonna be a makes concessions in a ring
attacks
it's much better chance at a let's send
a lot of on training
Republic to do it next year again and
the difficulty somewhere in the middle
but it's better than doing nothing well
let's join improve on Monday summits
even better than the training
as you probably guessed there still a
few holes to fill in this is by no means
complete my suspect it won't be for a
very long time
you can improve on it you go back to the
beginning to look a bit more detail
start more tax you could put put
together models have more information
more detail in them
of state as a whole huge pressure
implementation how you actually going to
use this
against the day that's the whole point
the whole point to coming up with ideas
like this the whole point if trying to
improve the world
is people to use it if you look at the
number people who
still wonderful to see sup to security
problems
that was solved 5 10 15 years ago
it's shocking let's try not make that
mistake recycle engineering
if we come up with a solution is China
getting out but let's try and get people
using it
even if they use it badly it's got to be
better than not using it until
as last trying to me down we started out
once the SAR
with warm water with war stories options
so you can start with a lot more stories
than on half
but us acting got the mall you can make
some models
you can model the section January
attacks you can model the conversions
into the site into the computer world
you can bring the conversions back you
can extract
it's vitally important you're struck you
don't have started never gonna succeed
but you could obstructing the mall or
less the night half
units convert them the conversion
process on youth was a simple as I could
make it
the reason for that is the simpler says
the less likely something's gonna go
role
all the conversion process is going to
introduce address you could potentially
come up with a better conversion process
and then you can solve it then you can
come up with an implementation
they can use it take it out and get
people using it
okay I K and I think about time
questions