with that with an introduction
the Windows Phone 7 its price new fine
OS
s so for those you out familiar with I
try to provide an overview
and outside about ask you to model the
stage features
men finally add perhaps the most
interesting bit vulnerabilities
and I I want Peter
I won't be covering admonished
application security
cloud storage are you I X native
applications really this talk focuses on
the platform security the OS level
security
offered by the platform and
so Windows Windows Phone 7 fines day and
currently there's this multiple
different OEM's its it's the same base
operating system but the hand
this different a handset manufacturers
out there the original equipment
manufacturers
day and with updates the same
the same base operating system buy
microsoft across
all at the OEM fines however the OEM's
are allowed to make
customizations to the base OS they're
allowed to write their own applications
device drivers and so on to actually
support the platform
and this actually gives the Iams an
elevated level have access to the
platform which normal develop as well
don't act at and then finally
well its it's a closed platform that
you're not meant to be tinkering around
with the
with the operating system and any from
the uses that
perspective all I can do is really
configure the settings
which are exposed and but they cop make
changes to the underlying OS
and this is a and how the undocumented
as well
so this all this research is purely from
a reverse engineering
perspective said
the the OS well the OS based on Windows
CE
it somewhere between six and 7i think
where the code base his fault
on Dec customizations were made for
Windows Phone
axis paw to Sabah in you the newfound up
on
and all the funds in the market
currently the run
arm architecture CP is and with that
like tibet address space process
so I can see fogging a by virtual
address space which divide
to take bites by the for the Connell I'm
see gigabytes for the
use a lot and at
when when you play updates the moment as
well to Windows Phone 7
well that pushed out by out by the
Windows Update Service
they required to tell the of I am with
seeing
there is soup of over-the-air updates in
future
but currently it's not at not
implemented
all updates as well cost the need to be
digit code sign
to actually execute on the device and
so I think it's really important to
understand the application model
how how applications are developed for
the platform what functionality
application developers get to normal
normal developers
at which not not the OEM's
that they restricted to writing managed
code
they restricted writing see shop on on a
customized theirselves life
X in a framework I'm select you see the
additional
security of the a the dot net se la
all types safety in so there's no actual
native code
allowed farrah third-party developers
its
it's a little different from the mobile
operators and i'm noah adams
they're actually like to write netted at
for device drives and so on
sectors in an elevated level access to
the platform
and there's also no no side loading
out load applications directly to you to
Windows Phone 7
fans unless that developer lot at
so for testing purposes you can pop
occasions on that if they develop
lot but otherwise all all applications
developed for the pokémon
they need to go fight by the marketplace
to go through a market marketplace
verification process
I know if the verification process
passes than
the code is signed and it's allowed to
be deployed to the device
so the
the security features well there's a
number of different subsystems
at which work together to really
maintain the security of the
up fine and days the systems that
worked with this with this concept if
this this overall concept a chamber
based security model
its it quite and novel idea where
basically processes
us on boxed and respected by the level
of trust
required on on the device so for example
at the top of the AM at the top for this
model you have
they trusted computing base the trusted
computing base is where
the Connell the condom device drivers
all security critical functionality
actually
and is is implemented in the truck
computing base
so is as an attack at to compromise the
security folly
you really have to have your code
executing in the trusted computing base
and then you have the the elevated
rights chamber
elevated rights is for use in
device drivers ones which on and
McConnell
so drivers which need to provide
globally accessible services across the
am
across across the device
and then below that you have a stein
rights which is for
it's for native code on the device which
doesn't need to provide
globally accessible services but still
needs
still needs met code Axis two to the
device
and finally pop probably the most
interesting chamber
fall for developers and security
professionals
because the the first three are actually
that fixed permissions sets the the OS
the poll the security policy the OS
basic controls what
commissions processes which I executing
in these different chambers
have got and so these
that fast 3 the top three stocktake
the nation's and the the bottom on the
the least privilege chamber LPC is
basically
it controlled by an dynamic capabilities
so when you develop an application for
Windows Phone 7
you specify what capabilities the
application should
should have these things which I
security
critical our Privacy critical
functionality
such as access to the camera accessed
the microphone
networking in sao and and what these do
up
when when the application is deployed
onto the device
then the capabilities the past on the
Chamber's provisioned
with that that the LPC chambers
provisioned
with with access to this their
additional functionality
but by default the LPC chambers really
lockdown
and you can access any this
functionality without the capabilities
so this this works together is well with
the AM with the code signing Michael
on the device so binaries which shipped
in the wrong
in the operating system at build time
there
there in place the trusted because they
got built into the OS
and but they still require the policy
entries to actually execute on on the
device
and any the bindings which he parks on
the fine
after their the wrong is being built
then these required to be carried signs
with about
holiday code signing certificates so it
means if you keep up byron fine
than while execute because a it's not
had signed
I'm be there's no policy and you that
specifically allowing it to execute on
fun
and there is an exception to this which
is develop
lot devices for testing purposes then
they they have the ability to run LPC
unsigned unsigned code
so this actually maps to you the
certificate star on the device
and so if you take a look at the this
this CA hat which is for the trusted
computing base
Sep code which signed with the
certificate which is
at which chance to the TCB
subsea a is on in to load into the
trusted computing base
chamber there's also one
so I'll these map to the different
chambers I'm from the chain
base model I showed previously and the
bottom line is fall
the least privilege chamber which is
where when you submit
submit your applications to the
marketplace the side with this
code signing stuff and
this is all controlled by policy files
as well so in the policy files
you have haha hash fingerprints
are up the code signing certificates
and is basically states that's if Cody
signed with the
stiff sky shallot hash in the paint that
value
then is authorized to you to have
execute access into the at
that that's a window said for that for
the TCB chamber
so that's may be similar to you system
on normal Windows
an unauthorized that code to loading
that the TCB chamber
side so this is controlled in the
Connell is a module in the country
in the Connell and its this budget
although the fire fire modular
controls all the authentication and
authorization on the device
it's the centralized pine centralized
gatekeeper for security
on the phone itself and
so uses the uses the policy framework
policy entries
which I'll at talk about in a second to
determine
whether determine the authentication and
authorization
on the fire I'm uses the code signing as
well
there's a this to critical data bases
which is used by the light the fire fire
the county be don't fall I which is
where the accounts
use names group at so an assignment
start
on the policy database which is where
the policy and cheese
and the poll the security policy for the
device start
this is a obviously this is protected by
the test computing bases well it's in
the Kyle
sewn attack ads to bypass this are
compromised this to actually
helpful controllers advice and
there's three this three function three
functions which you use to
loaded verify or authenticate file that
basically just checked the code is
signed with a valid code signing
certificates
and if Kurt sign with a valid code
signing certificates
than and authorize a should check is
performed to ensure that the code is
authorized load from the target from the
college and back to the target jam
the requested target time and
finally have the load the fire fire
provision cutie fucked occasion
this is called when in your application
is installed to define
all the capabilities apart the Chamber's
created the user group assignment
is is performed I'm policy entries
are actually am created to allow it to
run
so this this policy framework rejected
referring to you
and this is essential I security policy
for the fact
there's just one security policy on on
the have
find itself it's basically at it's
controlled
its net it's a xml-based so the modulus
it
when you ca when you have bills the
operating system
there's axe about policy documents which
database specify what and
what security critical functionality
should be exposed from that module
on the fact and these policy exe files
they're all combined into one big policy
XML
and then finally it's compiled into s
at this centralized policy debate
database
and this is this is for ICM for fast
lookups on the device
said doesn't impact the performance by
at by performing all these
are authorization and authentication
methods and this cause protected by that
the trusted computing base as well
said to come from my sis pH policy units
comprise the trusted computing base
and policy entries themselves well their
work with these things called
at international results identifies
at irri's basically identify things like
the registry the filesystem
resources on the five it's quite dry
nearly unspecified
single resources I can specify
wild-card matches so everything for
example and
registry subkey will be matched by these
by these irri's and
these used in the in the policy the
policy files
so this policy for basic states that
that the load the fire fire and
for slash window slash past sexy so
that's the filesystem
of in the and
on the five up binary it basically
states that the
that stop buying a house execute access
I'm I'm load access
see the see that target chambers said
and said so the fault for that user
account
and for every every binary which is on
the fact
there needs to be an Associated policy
entry stating what chamber can
execute and I'm wats what rights
house
there's also an went known leon when
does he call Craig processed crap and
you prices as well
but septra processed rations also
protected by the security policy
and at one process cards on a new
process by calling track process
unless there's and security policy and
stating that it can
so X in this example
the Cup basically states that
the account
can lodge slash when does
slashed the prague so that's the fund
our basically states that
TM this is a capability in fact
Laura I'd be capped by a base States
Internet Explorer icon
spawn the phone dialer from from the
browser itself
by any the calls from it's a great
process from the web browser
will be signed books and be restricted
by the policy changes
and then of course as I mentioned
resources are
protected by the policy entries as well
so any access
when request is made to access the
registry
all the filesystem than a policy
decision needs to be made to determine
whether this
going to you sexy Donna
so the this also I'm a number of exploit
mitigation techniques as well which is
built into
Windows Phone 7 he's address pay
address space layout randomization so if
it does you are familiar with the ass a
lot
basic randomized the memory address
space up that process
so that data is not predictable
locations
and so for example if an attacker
injects
shellcode than they won't know where
boxes in memory
whether start back that kinda thing
and it may just basic increases the the
difficulty far knit sock it to perform
attack against the platform also has a
execute never this is that not excuse
for memory protection
so many pages are mocked us i right
ball then they won't be executed well as
well and this is enforced by the harder
tyres well
and the CPU so
as an attack ad then that that was
basically it from the security model
I'm not going to speak about how how to
that
what bypass the security model how to
perform a tax on the platform
there's a number of different stages
which you need to go through to actually
compromise platform because of all the
security protections
and so the first thing I really want to
do to
with to enable our parting and
there's no way at the moment see to do
any kind debugging on the device
ketzel all I kinda normal stuff for
debugging has been stripped out
device and so
day the only way I father security
researcher care
actually find a way of enabling
crusher fighting that's a if you've ever
seen Doctor Watson pop-up
windows when a process crashes its
equivalent if that's a post-mortem trash
trash them the problem is you've got 128
K
information is trash dumps you have the
registers you have the stock frame
you have a few bites around instruction
pointer the program counter in this case
I am makes it quite tricky to exploit
just working from crackdowns signs with
this restricted him out
nation I'm the pro
this in the problem is well is if even
trash dumpster enables are you well even
taken it
I you can enable crash them being and
you can actually access the crash times
because
in your application you're respected you
the least
deadlock privileged chamber at least for
this chamber
so the sandbox stops you from accessing
me and
axis in the crash dumps it's necessary
to find a way of actually breaking out
the sign books
to access this file system path to get
the trash dumps
of I'm say camp farm see can load them
up and windy BG
start looking at why why prices crashed
iraq iraq's like fart and so this
this involved abusing a capability a
totally undocumented capability
differences the
to the OEM's to the handset
manufacturers
called ID captain drop services and
this is actually available in the public
development STK
you can you can use this functionality
I'm
by using reflection dotnet reflection an
instantiation
objects on the fine a name based abusing
this capability
and REM device drivers to access the
file system
so that stage you've got you've got
crushed them thing working
where you really want to I you really
want to be able to you
do static reverse reverse engineering of
the binaries
to look at the assembly language code
I'm fine for me abilities
any assembly by reading and sir
in order to do that well Windows CE
modules that not normal P
file formats basically requires
combining the sections
together adding a PE header to that
and then went when it's in the correct
format you can load the code section
sign up in
and I the Pro and you can start reverse
engineering and looking for
better sir
at this stage and you what you really
want an initial vulnerability some
weights guess
code execution on by say you might find
you might find vulnerabilities for
example in the web browser
but even if you gain control over the
the program can set and
the instruction pie what the inspection
which is going to be a
next executed than the
the problem is that you still have to
bypass the hassle %ah
I'm not excuse for memory protection
well
because you don't know where your data
is in memory cuz yes a lot
you also even if you can find your data
shellcode which injected
then you still wouldn't be able to
executed because you the memory paging
mocked is
not executed see you need a
vulnerability to actually I'm
to get around that and unfortunately
that vulnerability is not patched
the moment by Microsoft so I cannot
disclose their Salah
at Daz lax and ability at the moment
but since that's that fix that now
publishing
visor that so at that point you've
gained code execution in the least
privilege
chamber but the less privileged same is
not a great pic is
you basically restricted to what the
functionality
at which the application you exploited
Haas
its sign books you really want to break
out that sandbox
maxis the sensitive mation on the fact
and so outside outside a Tucson Boxwell
you have the things like that amassed
database the
the sensitive information see me some
kinda privilege escalation as well
to to break out at the sign books and
give you either Tzvi
elevated access to the active device
and so just a little TCI I had a feeling
that set
doan's for introducing variabilities on
on the platform because a previous
big for two reasons really one that they
have elevated access to the popcorn
and and secondly that we perform though
the research on
on and ride for example where
where the OEM's hide interviews fund
abilities
on the platform father for their
handsets
so an Android we we discovered that
there was I am
hasty said implemented this
install Commission on the web browser
for some reason
I think to do flash dates and but
the its it's basically a case in
bypassing miss
Katie modeled see to provide additional
functionality
but also weakens the scary model on the
device
there's also the case if sound recorder
them
HTC implementing their own sound
recorder
and now on Android I think that you need
a
you need the permission to actually hot
to
access sound recording functionality
it's a scary
critical at think
but page to see it implemented their own
sound recorder
which did just that if you had a
malicious application Android
the naked issue cuts on using mass and
using it sa PC
and points and finally the HTC loggers
well
this made news recently where they've
been tracking quite
am a large amount mation from from the
end-user
privacy critical information so
I thought about applying this to you to
Windows Phone 7
seawall REM and abilities were actually
introduced
and so I really wanted to stop by
and looking at way affected fingerprint
devices
time what oh yeah I'm what hun said they
actually were
and then that way you could deployed
device-specific payload
it wouldn't require writing next flight
to talk to all the different devices
depending on what device fingerprint
then you can at
deploy payload for that device
and the way i'd thought but in this was
it turns out that the user agents the
israeli actually exposed what the
devices
I'm so this one for example is a hedge
HTC hd7
at this one something on the a
sevens an attacker can targets can
perform all
targeted attacks against uses are of
these devices
for some reason also dispose that
running on picture
so I explained a web browser
vulnerability at
game today an initial code execution on
the device
and say he can say the program
says here said there's a just as that
a value to demonstrate controllers s and
but down after this you really need to
bypass the ass a lot the non executed
memory protection
at you to get to get your initial code
execution
as I mentioned and that some parts to
the moment side
Chur
yet sewed up that's the dots a crush
them
which I took of the device I and and
transferred it to my piece a
so I used them I used business no
sockets afar either and
I'm and Windows Phone 7 nama sockets up
you but you can do hedge hedge yet
yet yet
yet I'm this research is well was
performed before manga
I'm so this is like no to Anzac and
but yet in my case I used HTTP
it is transferred the crash dumps from
from the device
I post them back to my webserver and
then west
once I downloaded them from that and
then using that
and I you can load them up and win DVD
on on a normal desktop PC and start
looking at these
these times so lucky times a bus
as mentioned as well as the context and
so
days you've got no access to any
information the heap
at a and most the memory pages 128
kilobytes in this done
so you've got the Reg this stock frame
quite tricky to write an exploit with
just the registers
a stack frame where and where track and
sometimes have any
halfway track as well
and sir the
the OEM capabilities am I started exact
examining what
REM's getting and they had the specific
at
capability called ID capping drop
services
its it's used for novel applications to
access device drivers
and additional services on the device
it's telling documented
in the public at the public STK there's
no code for this
but you can use a reflection are you can
take the Assembly's
of the phone I'm use those link yes
those
name caller functionality and
so this is the case really instantiating
the right objects
using the comp bridge and I'm I'm
creating this manifest file
WP interrupt manifest
in the archive this pace and this allows
you to
see right native code and so I started
examining the device drivers which
which were implemented on my hd7 fine
and turns out that something had
implemented
device driver which gives you average
reading now between
by access you the entire memory space in
the Pro
process that includes the condo memory
space as well
sir you remember the yet day
Connell that trusted computing base is
mcconnell
so if you've got to read an opportune
right excessive kind of memory
then there's a there's a high chance
that you can at Gate code execution and
the context
the Cardinal as well and bypass the that
the protections implemented in the
trusted computing base
so the way I did it was to you schiesser
so it
this is the case Yvonne opening applied
device
hun dil Caesarea to the device driver
and crate instructed me
to instruct with the with the road
with the read or write access specifying
the address
and specify what you want to write
address an incall in the device i/o
control
and analyzed do followed by rights
anyway anywhere in memory space
and site up how can you turn out you
read and write access and see you
code execution the context the Kyle
and on on Windows that you have
on normal I went to it so you have to
pee there's a similar structure on when
this
it's called the K data struct and every
sides
its affects memory address every act
and every process so
this is quite an old-school method you
can basically
you can basically patch system call
handlers so that point
an attack controlled bit cud and then
when the system polish made then that
the
code to be executed in the context to
the Kyle I'm your privilege escalation
will succeed
so and this is the case using the read
the opportunity method to dump out data
in its heyday struct locate the
necessary function pointers
the point is to the system call table
and
yeah and then patch those pointers
these are implemented using API set as
well
and so it's just a case a patch in the
function pointers
I'm teacher in them the attack country
shellcode then you have code execution
and have
so I was when you release on abilities
were which is
limited to you a hasty 7 devices
it turns out that some sand had
implemented in abet
functionality themselves 5 device
provisioning those devices
allowing them to make configuration
changes to the device
and so I added to the binaries fault the
something as well
I located a direct you to a bustling
wanna something binaries
at which it's meant to be a device
position x amount bytes
and d but the problem is
Kat you have a job younger right access
to this directory the Sun but
that prevents you from having access to
this directory
so you need to I'm
you need to be able to you rights the
yet to
to write see see you can use the direct
you to us and ability to write to a
directory which you have control up
so this is a case if constructing a
posture director you
right axis deer and writing
that XML problem is you don't have
you cock traits new processes because
that policy restrictions
turns out something is up actually
implemented a
a device driver training processes
so this case what to do well you can
extract sensitive information and use
drop
Rick for example maybe disable the
policies are certificate checking
if you are my rights and maybe you want
your application deployed later
and would've been nice if the US Code
that together on this policy fake and
certificate
fake a that since I like the gym
functionality
me license Baker
they are on
popped off fixing develop law
I'll with
and you know is that these functions
have the same name the gem
functions controlling yet the there
so did to pick
okay so this is me loading the web
browser going to a
going to a page which is good exploit
Manalang I'm
which my malicious website the web
server
tops delivering the exploit payload on
the bottom there's
Explorer on that I'm
the Explorer handler receive a file from
the phone with good excuse for
I'm tet that transferred but the
back to the attack over the wifi link
I'm
and a second missions the you should see
this never have
the browser transferred back to the
attack so
mango well nine goes the the latest
version
it restricts the method I used to write
debug and about the exploits
but ultimately the designs still allows
the Iams to make
to implement these these security
and these that risky functionality
am so it's really up to Microsoft to
make sure the Iams code is
same code quality out as the base
operating system
my conclusions on this really like
it's a strong triangular security model
it it clear that a lot of thought has
been putting
this security model requires an attack
it to go through multiple different
stages before they came
exploit the platform also that
shows an attack in these multiple
vulnerabilities I'm exploit mitigation
bypasses to attack
on at shows that
an attack can use oh yeah I'm fine
abilities if say
specifically want to talk handset they
can go far the lowest hanging fruit
they don't need to go Microsoft code
base they can go far
REM's code if it's less echoed quality
standard
and letter there any questions