oh sorry how do you how do you pronounce
that is that the joke
the joke so my first name is a French
name
and my last name is a Polish name so it
should be Jefe so that's why people say
snoke because no one is able to
pronounce both of them
okay got it
um
snorky is our next speaker
he is a red team leader at Medallia uh
security by day and a security
researcher and VOIP hacker at night
uh he's the ambassador of happiness
and Healthy Living what do you mean by
that
I like to be away from keyboard so I run
a long distance so that was it keep me
illc and happy
good for you man
so since 2001 he had uh he has been a
penetration tester and red teamer who
has released advisories and tools
on VoIP Cisco products active directory
and sap
and he has spoken at various security
Focus conferences including hack that do
Troopers I.T underground activity hack
in the Box ssdic Recon and black hat
Arsenal ladies and Gentlemen let's give
a warm Applause for snorky
hey guys so I will try to be short I
know all of us waiting for the party I
tried doing something fun so let's see
if you get fun during this presentation
I will share my slides so there is a lot
of content there you can take pictures
of course but at the end I will show the
slide so you should have also content
so quickly about me I already says that
it's hard to pronounce my first name or
my name so usually people say snarky and
unfortunately for me Google no or meta
LinkedIn everyone know everything about
me so feel free to scan that and you get
more details about my me my life and so
on for the joke if you use the active
directory check for Tony Mitchell
account maybe you can find more about me
so today today is the goal of this
presentation is to
share my uh feedback and my experience
about fishing attack and how it could be
really efficient for the red team
activities
um
we'll try to introduce some techniques
um and tooling that I did to
kale a fishing campaign during
forwarding perspective and the strategy
here is not to get the phishing to get
access to on-premise system but really
to Target is or SAS infrastructures and
environments so nowadays there is a lot
of companies that not rely on on pure on
premise where you have to get in uh make
lateral movement and compromise or
active directory a lot of them now use
with zero trust model or with with what
happening with the kovid we have a lot
of remote position so all people start
to move to the pure SAS services and
that where we can make efficiency
or at least as an offensive perspective
we can be efficient when we make fishing
against such infrastructures
um short disclaimer I'm not the original
author of the Mirena and necro buzzer it
has been done by two malfators which is
a Michele uru and Giuseppe Trotta
they're already present the proxy that
we that are using that we use for this
kind of things and today I will really
focus on the the
necroposure but the automation behind
the proxy if you want to get more
details on the uh on the proxy there is
a YouTube link there where they present
all the proxy works or we can bypass MFA
and so on so strongly advise you to to
watch this video and on my side yes I
get involved in this project for since
I wrote a couple of documentation and I
did the implementation of necro buzzer
for Adobe brace Lambda function that I
will present
so what the value adds for an attacker
when we speak or when we talk about
phishing so fishing is still relevant in
2022 of course
um it's an easy way to to steal
credential of course we we just need to
get this credential and replace this
credentialing sometimes or if you have
the MFA you have to get more deeper but
the problem you can bypass also MFA it
has been introduced several times with a
evil ngx or Mirena we can do that so
depending all MFA has been implemented
you can get a you can get a wetwood to
bypass this MFA restriction
um also we all we can use phishing for
uh persistence so the easy way is to add
an attachment when you send your email
and you have this wrapper and they
installed malicious uh binary and you
get a persistent or remote access on
this laptop but with the SAS server you
can also do that you can I will
introduce you a way to backdoor GitHub
account and how we can optimize that and
how we can get persistent with this
GitHub access
you can also do a data exploration as I
said with the SAS people does not
necessarily use on-premise file server
they use a file sharing on on G Drive
Dropbox box whatever so if you fish this
kind of platform you can optimize your
data acceleration you can optimize all
you can export all this data in in
really few minutes
you can do the same with the code
repository if you target GitHub gitlab
all this uh code repository you can
automize to clone all the repo and and
do much more
of course we have the issue for the
phishing uh when you you have the
mindset for an attacker
um
nowadays there is plenty of detection
related to uh about phishing
um
users are at least for some of them
enough aware and Report easily fishing
and if you do a Mass fishing you can get
really detected quickly and they can try
to lock your domain and so on
a password password
it should be like underwear I hope so we
have this comment at the beginning of
the conference where we have to watch
everyday brush or two sensor on so we
also need to to change the underwear
frequently as a password but in the fact
I'm not sure if all people do that
unfortunately
and we have also this issue with the
multi-factor so depending of which kind
of multi-factor you you use
um yeah uh it's it does not allow you to
to make a password spring with an MFS or
you can get limited over that parts
and there is a really an effective MFA
today it's a u2f or web odd so with a
physical token and with this kind of
access this kind of protection
implemented yeah it it can block you for
your phishing abdent
as a last of not least it's when you
make some automation after your phishing
campaign you never know how much success
you will get with this phishing campaign
so the primary if you don't configure
properly your infrastructure your right
team infrastructure you can screw
yourself that's happening on my side and
that's why I start to thinking to make
something different
so all these points introduce the work
Factor so the work factor is an estimate
of effort or time need by a potential
adversary with a specific expertise and
resource to overcome protective measure
so it means that
all these protection that is in place
make the hard life for attacker but all
we can maximize that as an attacker
perspective to overcome this measure
so if I think back to the slide we say
that we can get easily detected but okay
we can get detected but how long it took
for a Security operation to block our
domain how long it's took to to really
stop the string of this phishing
campaign
if you optimize everything in less than
one minute 42 seconds we get everything
that we want it's
too late for them we already get the
data that we're looking for
about the password and password in 2022
is it something we really need to rely
only on password I have not because we
use MFA but if I just get one session
one cookie maybe it's enough for me to
replace that and and do much more
Factor okay we can we can just bypass
MFA time two times and if we target an
SSO portal so MFA is just require wines
so when you get log in size or SSO But
after when you click on all other
application so this is the MFA is not
required anymore
and the last part that where I start to
work on this project it's um serverless
so I do some phishing campaign it was uh
too much success fully for for me and I
brought my entire infrastructure because
I spin up so much instances and I don't
have enough resources to under that so
that's why I start to look about
serverless compute compute node and how
I can scale easily with the serverless
things
so the main ID based on the phishing and
automation it's look like this design so
let's say you target your your victim
it's target.com
so you ask to your victim to go to
target.com and in the middle you have
your proxy which is Mirena and you
mimics the the domain and you use
target.io for example that's up to you
open your imagination to to make
something close to the to the domain
that you want to Target and all the
traffics between the browser and the
real target.com go to this proxy so you
can grab the login you can forward all
the two-factor authentication so let's
say they use a tootp or push
notification you can realize that there
is no issue and when the session is
opt-in Mirena just forward all these
information login so credential login
and password in clear text the the
cookie to network browser and then necro
browser can spin up some other instances
other browser and optimize what you have
to do
so necro buzzer initially when we start
to work with in 2018 on this topic it
was uh based on uh ongoing written in go
and we use a CDP library to interface
with the Chrome
we moved to CDP to perpeteer which is a
node.js implementation so we instrument
Chrome or Firefox in idles or in GUI
mode up to you to do that there is some
limitations of for example for Chrome if
you want to add some plugin inside
Chrome you have to use the QE mode so
the not the endless one
and um based on that we we are able to
get more um efficient with a with
Puppeteer because it's really useful you
can really interact with a browser so
it's really nice to instrument a browser
it's fully used for uh people that make
qualif qualify uh where the the
qualifies as a product and and make
tests or regression tests they use
Puppeteer once they do that
on my side um I just um so necro buzzer
can initially be configured on
on-premise or in an ec2 instance or in
Cloud providers what I did on my side I
just move away from compute node I want
to really go away to infrastructures and
I go to serverless so I use AWS function
to do that I'm still relying on
Puppeteer and
in order to change some attacks in some
step I can use step function or not it's
up to you and to store all the proof of
my campaign when I screenshot some
access when I extract some data I store
all of them in the S3 bucket
the advantage for me to to use adobe's
Lambda function was it's easy to scale
as I said I just get a one endpoint and
everything is in terms of infrastructure
it's managed by AWS it's cost effective
so at the end I don't pay much on on
this adobe's Lambda function so this
lambdaq can stay there and I only pay
when I get to a real session and real
things that has been really
get pawn and yeah as they call my Lambda
function
and something was also interesting um
when you you do fishing time to times
you have to avoid geolocation so with
the Lambda function you can also specify
which country you want to deploy your
Lambda function so if you target a U.S
company you would like to deploy your
Lambda function in us if you target some
Azure you won't like to use something
based in Azure so that's why also it's
quite interesting to use Lambda function
so now between the Mirena which is a
proxy and a puppeteer which is the the
instrumentation we have to specify some
we have to to make some config file to
allow them to talk between them so what
we just need to do is to specify the
AWS Lambda function endpoint so the URL
of this endpoint and we also specify
which profile we want to use so we can
really customize our data we want to
share to network browser so I just share
one of them for GitHub there we'll do
the demo letter and you say okay I would
like to instrument GitHub that passes
the keyword that I would like to look
inside the repo so I look for
certificate VPN credentials something
like that inside some repo it should be
whatever you can use token API you can
use a lot of things I add an SSH key
because the purpose of My Demo will be
to show you how I can add myself an SSH
key to backdoor this account and then if
they rotate the password I'm still have
this SSH key which allow me to continue
to pull the Repository
then you share the cookie of course
because you have to rely on this cookie
to get authenticated on GitHub
one advice if you play with Mirena be
sure that your Jason the syntax that you
use for your digital is properly set
with uh because if if you miss that you
can get some weird error and a little
bit out to debug so just be sure you you
get a popular Syntax for your season
what it looks like when you instrument a
puppeteer so is that just a good snippet
that from from GitHub instrumentation so
first of all you have to add some
modules so I provide a module to to make
some simple screenshots so each time I
get an access I screenshot my access so
I call this module
the second point it's a common AWS so
it's only available so it's it's a
package that you can download and you
can deploy on other breaths
when you you got that configured you
specify which how you you want to open a
browser how you set your cookies that
you stole previously with Mirena so you
load this cookie to this property
instance
I'm sorry I'm smarting we have to pass
your presentation for our traditional
hardcore drink
okay everyone
all right all the way down
I really love your uh
uh not the presentation yes
your what do you call that
no
how he talks what's the term
yeah yeah so so uh can you read this for
us
it's an announcement for our uh activity
in one of our active Villages of course
okay so what this is what we have uh
going on there and by these speakers
so right now you have the malware
analyze 101 awesome one
this one performed with the awesome
people like Louisiana
and then is Lego so two sure uh awesome
ladies that will teach you how you
analyze malware so feel free to go there
and get fun there thank you very much
very good
snorky everyone thank you thank you so
much
so
um back to the presentation uh with some
more difficulties with this kind of
whiskey but should be good
um
so yeah what I said you have to set up
the cookie that you stole with a Mirena
to this paper instance Puppeteer
instance you specify that you want to go
to redirect to github.com login then
when you go there you go to SSH settings
and you can add your tricks a click so
you click on a add key and then you
click on where you can add your SSH key
and you put this SSH key and yeah your
back door easily GitHub account like
that
so that's what it looked like
you send a phishing email to someone you
say okay you have to go to GitHub it
will be a redirected to github.fec
github.fake redirect into the real
github.com is specifies credential
you'll get the screenshot in clear text
and the cookie you forward all the stuff
to Neco Brothers in the Lambda function
this network function say oh got it I
get that it's for GitHub I spin up a
puppeteer instance in Lambda I open
GitHub with this um
credential go to the to the SSH key add
this SSH key make a screenshot store
this screenshot in this bucket and
that's all
so
too much of said let's try to make a
demo
by the way the tool it's already open
source so feel free to go there and play
with that
I provide some templates so there is
already a lot of templates to to play
with GitHub and so on there is also some
skeleton where you can automize what you
want to do
um so SSO one uh it's sleeve has a pure
pose
um and also I just need to to share that
part
you can see that there is a lot of uh is
the last Bridge people complain because
they get fish and we have e-crime
Services where people can rent a fishing
campaign from this a crime so we don't
want necessarily to help this ecrime
organization to make bad stuff and make
money all about that so everything is
there I will show you in details how you
can do that feel free to reach out to me
but for sure will not necessarily share
all the payload uh privately
so back to
okay
let me open the search connection
okay I'm good
so first of all as I say all the the
code it's already public so you can go
there and you can play it I I will add
some content that I share today but most
of them it's already there
now let me show you so
let's say I Target these guys
um it's a SNK Dash test
put his password
so get connected on GitHub it already is
everything there
if you go to is the setting of these
guys
and go to the SSH key for example
you see there is no SSH keys there is
nothing all fine good
now
um I will run
the the marina so the proxy
so the proxy says that I use a pun with
me domain and all these kind of things
will be redirected to github.com
I skipped the fact that I send an email
to him whatever you do what or with the
Discord or whatever you can do a lot of
things to to mimic that and at the end
these guys go to your domain
and when you go to your domain
it should be able to reach github.com so
you can see there is no uh alert
everything was uh look like GitHub
because it's real GitHub we just
proxifies the traffic to GitHub
and these guys start to uh singing so
now if I back to the the Mirena you see
that here I assign an ID to these guys
because it's a one session
so I can twice each session
and from the the fishing website I put
the same credential
and I'm logging
so I am logged to GitHub everything it's
exactly the same because as I say we
just proxify things it's totally
transparent for the for the victim but
if I'm back there on my own necro buzzer
instances
you can see that I get in clear text the
credential of these guys because yeah
I processify the traffic so I realize is
data to the real github.com
and what you can see also
somewhere else
yeah there
you see that the Mirena gets a full
session so I get a cookie get everything
so we we send
this information to the to the necro
browser to instruments uh behind this
session
so now I will go to my Lambda function
on AWS
I will check the log
so I get a new log session there
and they say oh you get a session and it
seems that you get a result so I have a
screenshot that written there
so I don't know the result
and if I look the result
[Music]
it should be not like that
okay interesting let me so the result
should be a real screenshot with a SSH
key uh something going wrong let me
check that quickly
so here you see I just followed the page
and the ssk has been added the 10420 I
don't know why the screenshot does not
working but at least we get the SSH keys
that has been added automatically behind
what I uh what I got so yeah it's where
I don't know why I don't get the
screenshot but usually I have the proper
screenshot maybe it was a too fast so
that an example of how you can use
phishing to optimize a lot of things and
extract data backdoor do whatever you
want with the fishing just not uh think
about stalling credential but just
thinking what you can do after this
credential has been stolen
so back to the presentation now
consider that you now instead to have
this you see the pictures with the
guitar but consider how it can be
powerful if you
exploit an SSO portal from the SSO
portal you can get a
plugin one OCTA all these kind of
providers and they give you access to
plenty of interesting targets so behind
the SSO you can get
jira Confluence GitHub some email plenty
of good stuff so
you can just share all this kind of
activity and be able to really
exploit one entry Pond and then get for
each of them and compromise each of uh
things that you can reach over the SSO
portal so for example on OCTA you have a
list of all these
applications
you can easily extract this list with a
a national query or a document get
element query and you can get this list
of of application and based on that you
can start to optimize things so let me
go back
to the Shell
so
just increase a little bit so as I said
you call for the screenshot you you get
the Lambda function
uh you set up your
environment so you you put the cookie
username and so on you say okay let's
open a nocta
and then you say okay let's go and and
grab all the information that I need to
um
all the applications that I can reach
from this user for the OCTA session
then from here you fetch all the
applications that have been reachable so
that's the screenshots that I showed to
you previously
and then for each of them what you can
say I say Okay
um in this list of applications do we
have calendar okay if we have Canada
open the browser click on this link open
calendar make a screenshot let's say oh
you have a GitHub Okay click on GitHub
open it extract all the repo make your
SSH backdoor do something else a token
whatever so you can optimize all the
steps that you want based on the list of
all the things that you have here so
is that the skeletons that I will share
I will don't make necessary something
click and ready because as I said I
don't want to help a crime but if you
are a red team and you want help to
create this skeleton feel free to reach
out to me
um and yeah and basically at the end you
make screenshot and so on
so
um what you can also do it's with the
lumbar Lambda function I really quickly
introduced that before but you can also
use a step function to change that so
instead to use uh each time
node.js things to to instrument you can
use step function to call your your
Lambda between the Lambda so it's also
some things that you can explore but
yeah straightforward
now I have to provide some advice to get
effective when you make your fishing but
also how you can limit this kind of
attack
so all you can get effective so
um you have to make a proper Recon
phases when you try to make fishing I
mean that um
to know if a company use a SSO portal or
if a company
um
have a central point to get
authentication what you can do is to go
to a lot of
uh let's say Gmail Office 360 and try to
use a really
um whatever rundown at the domains that
you Target and usually if you do that it
will be redirect you directly to the SSO
portal that this company use so that's a
good way to detect uh which kind of SSO
portal you want to Target
then feel free to you have to build a
proper pretext to give this user say
okay you have to be redirect to the SSO
portal so you can link on the media
coverage marketing Twitter press release
to say okay the the work on this topic
in this company
so now I will do something that close to
this
topic and I will build my project to say
based on this topic you have to get
connected internally to do something
else and there they know the project
they know that they use this SSO portal
so it seems legit for them and they can
share a
with more
facility or more easily the credential
if you do this kind of things
so preparation phases it's really really
important so um
um don't make a domain that you you you
you acquire a domain and then you you
just make the phishing campaign no take
your times you have to get some history
behind this domain because uh as a
reputation it's it can be checked so you
can be screwed with that
um the certification authorities that
you use so if you decide to use Latin
script because it's a straightforward to
use lesson script in some company that
not necessarily trust let's unscript
because it's too much easy to get a
certificate so maybe you have to buy
another kind of certificate with another
certificate authority to get more trust
um
for the content delivery use a CTN or is
that also why I use AWS because usually
people does not block a WS IP ranges so
if you're behind a WS IP or if you use a
cgn to to cover your your
infrastructures they get more trust and
they'll not block you for that part
I already share that but Lambda function
deploy your London function in somewhere
where close to your targets and the cost
exploitation phase
the main advice log everything so yeah
you see I try to make the the
screenshots the screenshot failed so it
should work but in this case it's fell I
don't know so in your company it can be
also failed but at least you have the
log and you know when it has been done
and everything like that so that really
uh really good to do on the opposite for
the blue team and the Security operation
um some advice for them we have to use
MFA password it's really really
um
not enough today so we have to make a
full Mutual client Authentication
especially token so I love to use UB key
for me it's really a good alternative
it's quite cheap for a company to to
deploy ubiki so that's my main
um
recommendation for for them to to block
fishing
we have to review and rotate IPI and
token so as I saw as I showed to you
previously you can backdoor with the SSH
key so we can but so also we can also
add a token so all these kind of things
should be reviewed rotted to be sure
that each time there is someone then
choose a token it should be rotated and
be really well defined
um
yeah you can with the SSO providers
there is plenty of things that you can
do for example what we uh we you can
Implement it's for some sensitive
resources you can ask to reapply a
multi-factor authentication so in with
the OCTA for example you have the push
notification so depending of um if
you're already open a nocta session you
just get just a push notification so
people have to validate that they make a
connection to that so if you do this
kind of tricks it's block all my
automation because I could not rely on
that and people get a lot of push
notifications so they can be fatigue and
they can open one session but at least
it's block some automation
um
so last part please don't blame the user
the user have to work there is plenty of
email they receive a lot of stuff so
um and we we we cannot blame them we are
security Engineers so we have to provide
them a proper solution to get secured
and to get their job done in the in the
good way so
um of course much if we introduce
security we we decrease their um
the
the convocality or the the friendly
things that we have with the I.T stuff
but yeah it's something that we we have
to to help them and um
uh and not blunt them
is that for the presentation I think I'm
on time
um
if you have any question uh feel free to
ask you can use Twitter this email to
reach out to me you can scan against
that and and get my contact so any
question guys
no question
guys any questions from the crowd
I'm still up 10 minutes so yeah let's
say um because we were just so
mesmerized by your accent
exactly
let me just try again 10 minutes guys if
you have questions about the interesting
uh topic I will try to just
replay and show you that I'm not
cheating and you should get a screenshot
because it's something that she walks
oh you're playing the demo oh yeah my
demo does not working so I have to
replace that I have 10 minutes so yeah
so I just flush all the the previous
things
restart Mirena
back there
reload
be good
I got a position
so I got the session
orchestration was done there
okay
good evening
yeah we are so as I say
um you can screenshot and that's the
screenshot that I took during the
automation so if you see the the key
that has been get air
if now I'm back to uh
I'm lost between my screens there
if I'm rolling these pages
I get the key there which is a key that
I add recovery key so for example you
know I use recovery key to don't make
any malicious activity to say yeah it's
a recovery key and it's look like legit
and if I go to there yeah that's the the
names that I use recovery key there when
I do the automation
so yeah I'm still there for a couple of
hour and for the party as I said so feel
free to reach out to me and just ask
some questions if you want more details
Sun guys
[Applause]