security like the 80s how I stole your
RF and we'll be exploring cve 2020 to
27254 and more here at root con 16. so
who am I my name is iPhone Rajesh and
I'm I am an aspiring security researcher
and student uh here at UMass Dartmouth
uh you can follow me on Twitter and even
check out my GitHub repository and
here's my website as well
and I worked on this project along with
Papa Mikhail also known as scorp and
he's the sub gigahertz architect at
flipper devices the company that makes
the famous flipper zero and you can
reach out to him on telegram or even
check out his GitHub
so what got me into hacking my journey
started about seven to eight years ago
um after watching videos on YouTube such
as
um uh Dr Charlie Miller and Chris
valsak's uh videos on the famous Jeep
hack hack 5 videos and even uh Stanley
kafka's open sesame attack
so small disclaimer
um yeah all of this is only for
informational and educational purposes
only and most of all no key fobs were
harmed in the making of this video and
everything that I will be talking about
over here are already known and it can
be readily found on the internet and if
you'd like to everything's already up on
my GitHub repository you can go download
the files
um go through things learn how to
demodulate it yourself and even download
the custom firmware for the flipper zero
that I'll be talking about soon
so
story time so how did I get into this
right so I was doing this
um course last semester under my
professor Hong Liu and um for the class
um we had to do either one of the
projects which was experiment a cyber
security solution or understand the
cyber security incident and
for this I decided to do type A which
was experiment a cyber security solution
and I thought it was a perfect time to
pick up a hacker if and try something
new
so I was searching around for ideas and
I came across this cve which was 2019
tour 626 which spoke about a simple
replay attack on a Honda HRV 2017 and
as far as I knew rolling codes have been
out for about 20 years and I personally
didn't believe that a simple replay
attack would work so
what did I do I picked up a hakare from
Facebook Marketplace learned new radio
through Justin montreblano's uh
a video from the car hacking Village on
Guru radio and basically submitted for a
new cve which was assigned as cve
2022-27254 and I did this work uh with
Blake Berry also known as hacking into
your heart until the CBE submission
and here's another picture of that too
so this was featured in the media such
as the record Fox News threat post and
even the register
and I was also interviewed by Abc's Good
Morning America
and yeah that's pretty much about it so
a little more about keyless entry
systems so
in vehicles after 2040 in
um most of it like over 72 percent
already have it and after 2019 that
number has only gone up to 91 percent
and
um we can all expect this number to keep
Rising even because even the lower end
trims of cars now come default with
keyless entry which is an amazing
feature
so what we'll be exploiting over here is
the remote keyless entry as opposed to
the passive keyless entry so the remote
keyless entry was first introduced in
1982 uh uh On A Renault Fuego and it
operates at either 350 and 433 or 868
megahertz depending
on which part of the world you're from
so the way remote keyless entry works is
um you press a button on your key fob
and it's as good as broadcasting a
password maybe 15 30 feet away from you
and everyone can listen to it and only
your car knows that yes that's the right
password and only then it will unlock
for you so there's no verification or
any form of two-way handshake it's
purely a one-way thing so a little more
about rke so because it's every because
everything is dealing with frequency
over here you have three types of
modulation which is amplitude key
shifting frequency key shifting and face
key shifting and like like the name
suggests the data is transmitted either
in the amplitude frequency or the phase
of the wave but in this case we'll be
looking at frequency key shifting
because that's what the key fob operates
on so a little more about static and
rolling keys so like the fixed code
suggests
it's like the same password or same code
being sent over and over again it never
expires whereas on a rolling code every
time the button is pressed the code
keeps rolling and it keeps changing so
even if someone did intercept it you
could not use the same code
and do a simple repeat attack like this
so the tool is that I used throughout
this was fccid.io
um any RF transceiver I personally use
the hack RF
um and the usrp and then moved on to the
flipper zero and for analyzing and
understanding what the wave looks like
um you could use gqrx or spy Str based
on your OS and what you prefer otherwise
another cool tool is the universal radio
hacker which is really user friendly and
good for people new to
um messing around with any sort of uh RF
signals and then glue radio which is
another another amazing open source tool
so
the FCC ID for this is kr5b
krv52x on the which we can get through
the key fob and here's a picture of the
document itself
so looking at this we can already tell
that it's some sort of frequency key
shifting and we know that it's around
433.62
six one two four thirty three point six
seven megahertz ish but we can we can
dig deeper into this and then the RF
currency was like the hack RF flipper
zero yardstick one in the usrp 10 to 10
uh help you receive and transmit any
sort of RF signal something that I
should mention is that the hack RF and
the usrp are software defined radios
um whereas The Flipper 0 and the
yardstick one are computer controlled
radio devices so one main difference
between these two is that uh for a
software defined radio all you need to
know is the frequency and you can simply
tell it okay listen on this frequency uh
save it and play it back whereas for a
flipper zero or a yardstick one you'd
need to tell it exactly the exact
specifications such as
um
what's the Frequency it's on what sort
of modulation what sort of encoding
decoding
um the difference between the
frequencies every time it shifts and
things like that
so our first tool gqrx can show us that
um it's again FSK like the fccid.io
document suggested
and here's a little video of that and
then s by SDR does the same it's just
that I use that on Mac OS and this was
on a Windows
and this tells you a little more about
the way the key fob operates so it's at
433 as well as for 34 megahertz ish
so uh universal radio hacker is the
user-friendly app I was talking about
and you can do everything from capturing
demodulating flipping and even
transmitting
um any RF signal that you'd like through
any device
so this is the flowchart for glue radio
and this is how it's captured so all
it's doing is taking it from the osmocom
source which is the hack RF and then
just saving it so these were the
um
settings that I had used for gnu radio
and you can download these files from
GitHub as well if you'd like to try this
out and here's the same file for
transmitting so after saving the file uh
you can simply multiply it by a constant
throttle it to the sample rate for the
hack RF which was uh 2m and then just
send it to the hacker and it will do
whatever
the file says
so here's a little video
thank you
so like the video I showed you I first
used the start file to and and Replay
that in order to start the car and then
replay the unlock file so I could not
only unlock your car but also started
um and this is another one of my
favorites
so like you saw the key fob has a
feature where you can roll down all your
windows and even open the sunroof and in
the summer
I'm a huge fan of this because uh having
a black car doesn't really help and it's
really hot so using this feature really
helps it cool the cool the car down or
get some air in but let's say I didn't
like someone didn't like me
um and they did the same attack on me
and they captured the the same file for
rolling down the windows and sunroof and
then came back in the winter and repaid
it this this is pretty much what could
happen to you
and
moving on digging deeper into the actual
key fob so after opening up the key fob
this is what it looks like and when you
take a closer look at it
um at the data sheet for the nxp
pcf7900 you can then look at the
actually pins for this so this
um this chip uses
um SPI and all of this was done by Scott
um who took only one night and three
beers to reverse engineer the entire key
fob so
a little more about this so SPI was
developed by Motorola by Motorola in the
1980s and it supports either three wire
or four wire and it consists of
um your serial output uh Morsi which
stands for master output slave input
miso which stands for master input slave
output and sclk which is the serial
clock so in this case
um we just use the the key fob over here
just used
um the three pin output and like the
pictures uh where you can see we used
Sala logic to understand what's going on
in the actual key fob and here's a
picture of that so
this is what it looks like so we use the
mercy the Miso and the the clock and
figure out what's what's going on inside
so
you might be asked to
what do these numbers mean and what
significance does it have so to quote to
quote Dr Weil it's in the data sheet and
um after looking at it more closely you
can then see that each one of those
numbers like 0b 1 1 1 0 1 1 1
um actually meant
um was was nothing but an instruction
for the key fob and what it should do so
this is the useful information that we
extracted
so such as miso zero
b1000 100 meant toggling the lower bit
for the FSK and then
um the picture that was there in the
first uh in the first slide was actually
the one for the baud rate which was
0b011
0011 which does nothing but
um uh tell the key fob to select a
certain word rate which we've calculated
over here so throughout this thing
um we found out that
it operates at 433
657070 Hertz by looking at the frequency
config one low byte which we've
determined through the data sheet and
then like likewise it's at
434.1769 uh 48 Hertz and we all we
already knew that it's at it has a
frequency shifting key modulation but
the deviation wasn't precise through
gqrx or S by Str so that's why this
helped and we know that too now and we
even know the baud rate and which is
very important for what we're about to
do next so after that
um after looking at the
signal we can tell that it's Manchester
encoded so how do you calculate or how
do you demodulate it rather because it's
still encoded by something and if you
want to uh change it to Binary you would
need to know how to be modulated so to
do that remember the number 62.81
microseconds and then this is all you do
so to calculate the Manchester bit rate
you divide one second by the shortest
duration which was 62.81 microseconds
and divide that by two
um so that gives you about
7961 kilobytes per second and that's a
quick math for you
um so now what so we already had the
previous file and then just by using
another analyzer for uh decoding
Manchester we feed in the bit rate and
then even though the
screenshot over here doesn't highlight
it we
um also enter the Preamble bits to
ignore which was 20
um and the software does it for you it
will just demodulate everything that you
have and like you see over here it gives
the whole value in either binary or in
hexadecimal for short and
so you might be asking why did we do
this right so uh like I said earlier The
Flipper 0 is not an Str and you need to
tell it exactly what to do so then using
all this information uh Scott wrote
custom firmware and made this happen so
we now have uh
433.65 and 434.17 frequency added custom
to The Flipper and also a modulation
which we named Honda one and there's
Honda 2 as well which is more sensitive
but it does the same thing and it is FSK
and it follows all the parameters as you
saw earlier and here's a picture of the
sprcr capture so as you can see right
below you have the actual key fob
capture and then above that you have the
flipper 0 as well and as the picture
suggests the capture for The Flipper
zero when it's replayed
um it is a bit noisy and that's because
of the cco1 chip which is already known
but
does it really get the work done it
looks the same but does it work let's
find out
foreign
all you need is this bad boy a flipper
zero and you can capture
um any key fob for any most 10th gen
Hondas and just do a simple replay and
it will work so
time for some memes you guys might have
heard of a Civic with a laptop it's the
most feared thing in the car community
um and this is a cool picture as well on
the right where someone actually managed
to get Linux on their car car's
infotainment system rather
so
imagine a Civic with a laptop and a
hacker F1 isn't it the ultimate War
driving setup so through like like the
picture shows
um all you need to do is wait in a a
parking garage or rather than even
having a laptop you could just leave
this in a tiny little bag
um come the next day analyze everything
load it onto a flipper zero and then you
can essentially go replay the same
capture and pretty much open
every anyone's got up so
you might ask what's the solution to
this so I'm not gonna suggest
um putting your keys in a variety of
pouch and actually a true word for it
um because it's not a permanent solution
right and uh even then you'd have to
remove the key from your Faraday pouch
every time you need to go uh open your
car or drive it so
rolling codes right so you're telling me
to prevent a simple replay attack
um just use rolling codes because every
time you press the button even if
someone hears the password
um it still expired there's no way you
can go use
um an expired code to unlock
right
yeah I don't think so so
um my body Kevin to 600 uh who's uh part
of the kayaking Village
in China
um actually came up with a flaw called
as uh rolling pawn and we also found out
that the same vulnerability was also
spoken about by my friend Levy and his
uh his professor at uh black hat and
their talk was called rollback so
um I guess it's even uh ruling codes
aren't safe because all they're doing is
um replaying
um a sequence of captures in a certain
order so that
um the pseudorandom number generator
in the car the counter gets
re-synchronized so think of uh rolling
codes as a for Loop so every time you
press a button just imagine
um I keeps incrementing every time and
the password or code keeps changing but
imagine if you already had an old
capture for a certain value of I and you
were able to re-synchronize the car to
that value of I and then use an expired
code
um against it which is now valid
according to the car
and here's a short demo of that
[Music]
so there you go so even a newer car
which has rolling codes is now
vulnerable and according to the
researchers at black hat
um they estimate about 70 percent of uh
asian-made cars to be affected by this
vulnerability and are working towards
finding out what cars are vulnerable to
this
um attack and
they still don't know why which is
really alarming so
uh when Kevin first came up with this
research uh Honda claimed that it wasn't
possible same thing like a simple replay
attack when I put mine out and here he
stopped to his friend uh Rob Stumpf and
he read an article about the about the
same on the drive and actually proved
that the rolling Pawn or rollback attack
still works on a newer Honda
and
this is what happened after that too so
um they did say that there is no
indication that they reported
vulnerability to unlock and lock doors
results in an ability to drive an Acura
or a Honda vehicle
um and that's partly true because
um to drive away with the car there
still is an immobilizer present within
and you'd need the passive keyless entry
uh system
um in order to do that so that's the
only way you can disable that I mean
sure you can use a relay attack but then
that's not worth looking for over here
so
when they said this I thought to myself
challenge accepted and here's a little
video of how I stole my own car in just
under four minutes using
um another tool and a flipper zero
thank you
[Music]
foreign
oops
[Music]
foreign
so like you saw once you have physical
access into the car
um almost everyone knows that there's
the OBD2 port located right under the
steering wheel and which gives you
access into the car and
um through that although we use a key
programmer over here
um I'm sure you could do the same with
just an OBD2 to a USB and a laptop
running any any sort of software where
you can
send canvas messages and access the UDS
so
um here's an example of that we already
have J Turner's
uh kantot which he also gave a talk
about at car hacking Village and I'm
sure he's giving one at root con too so
with software like this it would take no
time for someone just to download a
script uh plug it into a car and do
whatever they wanted because once you
have physical access into the car
if you know what you're doing
um you could drive away
um and do whatever you want with the car
like it's your own
so
um this is a very serious issue
um and
um there's also a senator from
Massachusetts who who sent out letters
to most of the automotive companies
um asking them questions as to why this
um rise in vehicle that was happening
and
in fact the nhsda approximates the cost
of stolen vehicles to be about seven
billion dollars in 2020 alone and those
statistics are only for the United
States just imagine uh what the damage
on the number will be for worldwide
right and about 804
000 Vehicles were stolen in 2020 alone
again and that again is only for the
United States so
we did
um have a 2018 Civic uh hatchback at the
car hacking Village during Defcon a few
weeks ago and I was doing demos for
everyone that came and
um we also had the firmware available
when they scanned the QR code
for The Flipper zero and uh as well as
the unlock and lock files for the car so
only if you had a flipper zero I could
um I would help you out and help you set
it up for your flipper zero and then you
could go mess around with the car have
fun and here's a picture of that and
then
on the right we have a picture of uh the
whole kayaking Village team who uh I'm
really grateful for for having me there
um and also I had the honor to meet the
president's cyber security advisor uh
who's also the national director for
cyber security for America uh John
English and he gave me this really cool
challenge coin as well and
um he also played with the flipper zero
and managed to unlock and lock the car
so that was something really cool that
we did at the car hacking Village
um
so what next
um you can join us on this journey too
so even though this presentation only
spoke about fixed Goods
um Kevin and the other researchers from
uh the black hat dog called rollback are
actively working towards making a
database of every single car affected
out there whether it's
um due to a simple replay attack or a
rollback attack and we're exploring
other attack factors as well so if you'd
like to
learn and try this out on your own car
you can sign up at the Google form or by
scanning the QR code below and the
reason why
um we all feel that it's very important
is because uh just because the number of
share just discuss the sheer number of
cars out there and uh the fact that a
Honda Civic in the United States versus
Philippines or India is going to be very
different
um due to different regulations or laws
or whatever and having an exact
um
a number of cars affected by this or
knowing what cars affected by this would
not only help law enforcement but would
also help consumers in understanding
um
uh whether their car is affected or not
and hopefully
um this this whole initiative uh would
bring about a positive positive impact
on Automotive cyber security and help
create keyless entry systems uh a tad
bit more safer so please feel free to
scan it you can reach out to any of us
and we'd be more than uh happy to help
you and these were the stickers that I
was giving out at car hacking Village at
Defcon as well so on the left we have
the cve 2022 to 7254 sticker and on the
right we had the rolling phone sticker
as well so
a huge thank you to everyone the Flippa
zero team my friend Avicii who designed
the stickers actually uh the College of
Engineering at UMass Dartmouth
um
um East Coast chickpeas for helping me
out with the programming Keys uh car
hacking Village Defcon
um McDonald's and mass cyber Center as
well as root con and everyone that made
this happen including Dax uh Jay and
everyone else and a huge shout out to
the umassd cyber security Center and
professor kaslingham fiendella professor
Liu Zhao Professor Weil as well as my
mentor Sam Curry
um and Jerry Woody uh Conor McLaughlin
and everyone from kayak English Robert
Justin Jesse uh and everyone yeah so
um
here's uh more references of further
reading if you'd like to do and in case
you can't find anything here or if you'd
like to know more about this uh feel
free to reach out to me and yeah have to
plan it