um so I will need to maybe do it a
little bit slower through times and
stuff like that but I'm really
interested and excited to be here so
thank you for inviting me and I will now
talk about the presentation
um while details from acting power grids
into packing oil pipelines so a little
bit about me my name is Brock Steinberg
I'm a Founder at White pointer I'm also
an accurate residence and vice of it by
Adventures obviously an offer sentiment
in one labs and the speaker of Dev
connectivity and many other conferences
I give my masters in algorithms in
computer science and I love doing
research from iot Linux web apps
whatever you name it algorithms
otherwise malware and much much more I'm
also a DJ and a party lover so make sure
you check out also my Mixcloud and with
that in mind let's start
so iot attacks are anywhere
like really really everywhere so the
other team malware landscape landscape
has been increased by 125 23 in
healthcare over the last year and
Scandal systems are under attack
um Industrial Systems hospitals really
really everywhere so why attackers are
targeted and focused so much heavily on
iot and critical infrastructures so
first critical systems are tend to make
more damage because well they are
critical and in that sense if you can do
as an attacker more damage maybe the
probability for the payouts for the ones
who are payouts and stuff like that will
be increasing so because the Defenders
want to protect the systems as immediate
as they can to remove the attacks itself
so the more damage can be in court and
the probability for the belts will be
probably higher that's why uh one option
they try to attack them it's either they
can protect this kind of system because
it's harder to really inspect inside
what is really happening behind the
scene I think even initial access to
organization like VPN servers routers
Etc and and the scale so many devices
have almost the same configuration in
this team and landscape and there have
been used uh extensively for deployed
ransomware deduce attack uh theft of
source code technological source code
and much more crypto Mining and even
disabled and damaging critical
infrastructure uh Nations that no not
even interesting and much more infection
attempts over the first half of 2021 was
over a billion last year hundreds of CVS
many many Industries are impacted and
targeted so with that in mind let's go
into our first story so our first story
is going to be with the Russian Ukraine
uh cyber War we're going to explore the
power greens we're under attack and send
home apt thread actors
so let's recall the Russia attack on
Ukraine the Cyber attack on
2022 we started this year so they were
targeting Banks most events in Golden
MPS internet satellites and energy
providers actually at every kind of
critical infrastructure you can name
probably would have been there
um including uh I voltage critical
substations and much much more
um what was targeted is actually they
were trying well uh in a sense in
retrospective we can say that try to
disable electricity they were trying and
actually succeeding disabled uh
satellite invert connectivity and they
were damaging and wiping out critical
infrastructure data to make recovery of
this critical infrastructures way way
slower so they're trying to do as much
them as as they can to make the whole
more efforts uh in much much slower to
make their own
efforts into different Defender efforts
to Ukrainian Foods much more slowing
some sense and how to try to do it so
um sorry
so they're trying to use in the story
too which we will deal and focus here
after they were trying to do a couple of
wipers uh malwares uh many many versions
of fiber males they were targeting
multiple various os's
not just Windows machines also the end
of Solaris and much more and they were
disabling also services and ingoing and
outgoing Communications to make the
recovery even stop
so with that in mind a bit of context
about that this apt group so this
storage in ipt group is a part assumed
to be a part of the gru which is part of
the uh the the Russian uh kind of uh
government the intelligence Forbes and
it it's soon to be this unit uh seven
four four five uh five and it had
assumed to uh to done multiple harm and
damage to those blackouts were uh from
around 2007 uh forward wounded by the
FBI is really really malicious threat
actors this is the central one apt book
and
in this uh in these current events on
around March and April 20 2022 around
this status this year they were
targeting uh banking Korean governments
using the caddy wiper and medic wipers
which are all these quite good for
Windows uh they were trying to also
attack uh the energy providers uh uh in
Ukraine specific energy provider in
order to shut down electricity uh using
again wipers for Linux and windows as
well the extra family and the Callaway
pro version too and the using also in
solitude to affect uh with the ICS
protocols uh specifically the IEC 104
um uh protocol affecting substation
electrical substations so we're trying
to make it all happen damaging critical
infrastructure and much much more and
about the cad wipers so the first
version of the catalypse
subscriber just should raise the disk it
does really interesting things so the
first he tried to where to recursively
iterate the directories it overrides
maximum of 10 megabytes
um and probably to make it run maybe
really faster it use the right file than
the Cisco with zeros and also rewrites
uh the partition table of MBR and GPT to
zeros so it will be uh really hard to
recover the drive itself the second
version which was deployed in the energy
provider which was used further in
another Windows machines uh use this uh
uh interesting load them so it's called
ID patch and it uh well you can see they
use also this uh patch version of uh Ida
will threatitude remote debugger which
is really interesting choice maybe I
don't know a trolling choice or
something like that and it used it to
execute the Shocker itself uh this uh we
can see that the arguments here they
were using like uh key and the circle
path so the shadow path the shortcut was
encrypted and decrypted in inside this
uh
um
uh inside this uh uh
binary and and they also added a
specific time argument for timing this
attack on a specific kind of uh time as
needed and
so this is like
up to you about the white bread Windows
Viper the Ring of swipers are also
interestingly using either shred or didi
to just wipe the the outdrives they also
try to disable the in-going ongoing
Communications and remove it like the
system the unit configs to make like the
the whole operation of re-recovering it
really hard though because you can't
like remote connecting to the machine
and try to move the malware you need to
really physically connect to it because
they were removing all the outgoing
medication before doing the wiping
itself and these are about wipers now
about the story itself so the installer
the
the timeline of it we start with again
the Russia invades Ukraine uh around the
end of February uh Russia event and
until then it was assumed that December
was infiltrated and actually compromised
some energy facility with an high
voltage substations so inside that
facility uh the central group actually
already infiltrated and it's soon to be
waiting uh for the time to attack so on
the 8th of April we know that the power
grid attack was starting by uh some task
scheduling of the industry too there was
a task schedule to run it and affect the
system but uh fortunately they were
protecting it and remove uh removed the
thread immediately on the 12th the
Ukraine said announced that there was
the attack on the 13 actually the us
along with the FBI understand stuff and
now it's also what they do they were
found a new ICS malware new iot called
by dream that was uh much more generic
and also targeting uh many more kind of
devices maybe it was the future brand
maybe they didn't really affect it we
don't know any uh samples of it in the
wild really really uh as far as as we
know uh that we're trying to affect uh
specific uh kind of um
uh machines
and you're trying to use it afterwards
and we don't know uh so before we dive
in about how the industry too the the
second version of the industrator trying
to uh damage the electricity the
electricity the power stations in
Ukraine let's recall being Destroyer one
so in the story one uh is well
is responsible soon to be responsible in
2016 for the blackout for around an hour
in part of the Ukraine capital
and uh it has this unique ability to
speak the iot protocols of IEC 104 I see
one on one and also bcoa and stuff like
that it's really really interesting
about the factors that really raised the
bar and resets the uh the damage vector
and impact the blast radius can be done
with these kind of things it actually
directly controls switches and circuit
breakers and protection relays and one
of the most exciting well
well depend on which side of the map of
course but like one of the most
interesting I might say about
understanding about this uh attack would
be that it was actually using uh those
Pockets uh to make this system
unavailable so it was dosing the Siemens
uh protection relays uh to make them
shut down so whenever the the turn on
button will be switched uh there will
probably be some damage occurred because
there were no protection relays they
were trying to do uh this uh really
really hard damage into this machine
they were actually using this in a day
in there as assumed to be by the cell
wall group so we can see on the left
picture actually this device after uh
being then dosed this is the C protector
Siemens device and this is the industry
one
and uh going a little bit more on the
eye level side uh on the electric
results uh one-on-one uh we can see uh
some intro about it and understand how
they try to do it so how did the
electric uh the electricity grids and
way of operation communication working
is that usually there are scatter
clients so on the first point you can
see the scanner clients The Scholar
stations monitoring uh the rtus they
have to use are usually connected to the
substations themselves
any specific salvation uh probably have
its own kind of rtus the remoter in the
units and these units are connected to
the scada clients using a router so why
they use the router because many times
these color clients actually can
communicate over a TCP and of course
that like iot devices these iot devices
are not communicated with PCP they're
communicating with IEC 101 so they use
this extension called IEC 104 using the
aec router on the second Point here to
convert TCP communication into this
ic1r4 communication and therefore the
scada can communicate with the anti-use
so
in respect to being destroyed they were
sitting on all in the scada areas and
they could actually control directly the
rtus so they tried to do both uh to
communicate with the uh with the rtus on
the first install on the second soil
they were just uh as we know using their
uh this cutter with IEC 104 which is
this TCP extension of a ic1 not everyone
okay so this was the main like the main
core of the uh the how to use uh ic104
on one and one protocols but on a higher
level uh by the amazing paper by drivers
crash override we can see that there are
many ways to communicate with these
substations the scada clients can
actually control multiple kind of
devices plcs uh
um rtus and rpus with different kind of
protocols
the engineering work position is usually
used to control with over tcpap uh the
the the slave ought to use and we but
there are also other possibilities
attackers can use to uh attack us not
just attackers of course also engineers
and and the main controls of these
systems so the obviously servers and one
way to control the plcs and the HMI uh
which is the monitoring and wondering
infrastructure that can be used as well
um to control the rtus of the IEC 101
protocol
so this is the basic about the electric
grids Proto operation this is our
Network kind of templated network for a
station from Electrical uh with the
station facility maybe would look like
and with that in mind uh let's look
about their intent so instead of first
attempt the first one on 2016 was
assumed to be uh the following so we
were trying to de-energize the power
lines a name they were trying to deny
operate investigating control in
delivering the star version we're
actually wiping out the Outer Drive
wiping out computers to make them
unavailable to communicate with uh with
the devices afterwards there were
disabled protection relays and they were
waiting so whatever by they were waiting
so they were waiting for the operators
to turn on the device because now they
want they have the protection organized
to help them whenever there is shortages
or high voltage scenarios so whenever
the operators will manually join all the
electricity without the protection less
physical leverage would be would be done
and that's where the original attended
the first one probably in the second one
as well they want to damage efficiently
and effectively these lines to make them
disabled for uh for the longest period
they could they go down and get the
second version this is the the recent
one publishing
found out and Publishing module in the
every lab and this year uh and these two
samples it was task scheduled for April
and 8th on on the afternoon and this ad
is also interesting debug logs and one
cool thing we can see here on the right
you can see the the test scheduling this
camera the XML we can see that
interestingly bundles and no privilege
was required actually because they were
just send
TCP packets over the IEC 104 protocol so
they didn't have any other privilege or
any interesting kind of stuff you can
see here that the Run level is also
least privileged so it's really
interesting to see that the attackers
were really focusing specifically over
uh over this uh uh effect and damage for
the substations uh these two samples and
overall samples which I've got to around
11 uh substation trying to effect and
manipulate them they were knowing
beforehand you can see here on the left
screen the pickup itself sending the
data elements right we can see the
packets themselves they were knowing
beforehand specifically the IP addresses
the IDS use the iOS which are the
addresses the physical addresses and the
current properties of the the fields
they needed and they knew what they want
to do then it was a a range and
sophisticated attack was started in
specific ranges between and off the
specific switches they wanted not all of
not all on they were targeting it
specifically we can see it also here so
for each for example in first sample we
can see uh for each substation uh they
know the the IP address the iuis the
artists that were targeting and what
they wouldn't want uh to do with this
iois and again they were manipulating
the system also using uh the candy
wipers the the wipers themselves so
they're we're doing like this movement
all together parallel of wiping all the
hard drives and uh and affecting the
substation so it would be really hard to
recover these systems and the Damage
will be permanent as they can
uh that's that's really astonishing this
really uh intense uh um amazing stuff
and also interesting non-tributable dtps
for this attack is that uh they were
trying to use some new sophisticated
ways uh to manipulate systems so uh they
were using numeration of that males gpos
but hidden inside without having
privilege uh using some uh
interesting method with idsi adapters in
Powershell they were scheduling attacks
without that schedulers in I think the
new version of the caddy wiper uh which
is really interesting probably kind of a
timeout or something like that although
add the the prepare that passwords and
the iot addresses the initial compromise
actually is not uh really uh widely
known as far as we know and for this
time but soon to be the new they knew
that that the the attack Vector itself
the new uh they had these prepare
passwords
um they they were in the system for for
many many times before that so they knew
all all the details they they really did
uh intelligence over the systems before
uh using and attacking now uh that's
really really inspection they did this
interesting no mimikats technique to do
uh credential dumping they were using uh
these else dumped with a mini dump uh uh
like kind of uh we similar to the crash
down kind of uh thing when when
something's probably kind of crashing
but using kind of different kind of DNL
dlls as we see uh as we assume here
um so this is interesting way to dump
the credential and with that in mind we
go to the second story so this was about
the history of the industry to amazing
attacks so many interesting ttps said
was planned to Be an Effective but a
function Unfortunately they didn't go
out as planned so uh it was uh
fortunately Griffin but attack was
really really uh threatening in pristine
the second is about the health system in
Iran so the health systems in England
is comprised of uh composed of of the
the public health system the HSC the HSE
is the main uh the main Services of of
the the public health system in in
England it has more than 35 hospitals in
Iran around 70k employees
and it was attacked it was attacked uh
really really bad by the continents last
year
so the eye level attack story starts
with what as you know it uh or or might
not but
as many of the attacks are with fishing
uh they were sending Excel to some
employee the employee opened with
spreadsheet this fishing spreadsheet
that gave the attacker to ability to
connect and control the the first uh the
first the patient zero the first system
and to give access to the system
probably with a macro or some problem
one day I would uh I would estimate and
soon it was just a macro or something
like that was triggered but probably it
could be one day as well and from there
on there were later moving in the
networks using uh known passwords leaked
passwords uh using one day and and much
much more and eventually deploying the
ones who are inside the system uh they
were doing a lot of noise and it's
really interesting to see how this stack
actually evolved so 19 19th of May uh
um the CEO of HC says
we know the attack was happening we
don't know what data has been taken but
we know some that that was compromised
and we won't pay and this is like really
really kind of uh not such a good way to
to deal with it with that openly in the
sense because they didn't tell you
really nothing they just say they won't
pay anything and they try to recover it
by uh themselves
and so regarding the timeline uh one
interesting thing to notice in the
timeline is well first there were the
attackers were in the network inside of
the networks eight week eight weeks
before uh really uh doing the ransomware
really uh getting to know out of the uh
getting identified eight weeks in the
system until the real deduction happened
and the real removal happened
um and this is the the story itself so
on 18th of uh March uh efficient email
is clicked and the HSC employee thinks
this Excel and the organization is
infiltrated
on the end of match you can see that the
timer here so they were around I think a
week or two and no one got noticed them
anything at all they were executing
cover so I can win cards like popular
stuff right so really using that the
antivirus well first of all let's let's
deal with that so antivirus they didn't
use does it seem to be uh modern kind of
videos modern kind of xtrs uh it seems
to be like all kind of ways of
protection and also it detects him but
didn't block it and why it happened is
because well the antivirus operated in a
monitor mode well amazing so the execute
code so I can win cards they didn't
block away and then the attacker
continues only to the point where on the
mave on the May from December May began
that I'm in privileged probably with
some non-link password from that web
password again no one
again because they will not Mito mode or
Google attacking continues to do later
movement extract more services in other
hospitals sorry
and
also uh uh attacker execute calls like
at One hospital
and now the antivirus doesn't work in a
monitor mode it doesn't work in monitor
mode it detects the common strike and it
tries to Grant on it any fast
so we can see here that the attack uh
was not that sophisticated but more the
cyber security maturity level was really
really low so again we continue on the
10th uh one Hospital stock notice about
this corporate Striker Lads it has this
security provider whoever they should be
concerned and the antivirus providers
say to them well the threat was removed
by your systems uh the threat was moved
in this computer that where the alerts
are are called so the risk is low but it
doesn't mean that the virus didn't
spread already to another place in the
network right so they were so focused in
this Centric approach and didn't thought
about their effects widely and the risk
is low saying that without all the
context in relevant network is
astonishing
on the 11th attacker Brute Force the
passwords doesn't succeed uh with good
for their passwords first doing that
executes one day popular one day
successfully on the system and doesn't
get noticed at all so this is another
thing like
I I'm I'm like oh my God because no one
notices
ignored completely uh and it's really
really astonishing to see that uh on the
first thing the security provider email
address this talk about many other end
of the events since 7th of May and you
know what the stock team doing so the
soccer team is advised that there are
threats in the system and they just
restart the service they just restarted
their service team and restart the
service and I'm like
why the sorry for the language
um
in continuous on the 13th One hospital
again once ago actually detects attack
doing the correct thing he twisted all
the password using it installing the
house prevents the spread doing all
things correctly but didn't share this
information with all the other hospitals
so others because viruses still going on
and not correctly uh ir and and
cleansing is doing for the other uh
hospitals under attack
and unfortunately on the 13th the
ransomware is executed in all the
exploited hospitals altogether
so the answer just to recover the Run
survey itself so the ransomware is the
control somewhere the new version from
the 2021 and it encrypts fibrarily it
has these multi-ways of 32 threads with
Cha-Cha 8 symmetric encryption it uses
interesting mechanisms just really works
within the threads themselves uh it will
move backups and it also encrypts
backups uh and we can see examples here
for how it removes local backups uh from
the system from the VM backups it also
encrypts the main backups if there are
existing some backups like that and it
also
um these fashion encryption features
maybe to get avoid
maybe its way to avoid detection
um about uh but or maybe it's the way to
do it faster probably kind of above uh
it's increased parallelly with jumps uh
the files uh with uh one megabyte of
jumping in between of them uh so that's
a cool theme and the impact on the news
is really bad so this is from the from
the site when we were backup sites of
the hospitals themselves we can see many
hospitals got uh cancellations CD scan
cancellation MRIs 10 installation
appointment cancellations more than 20
hospitals all got affected this also
comments on the web people waiting for
for treatments for weeks and months or
treatments and now the Cyber attack and
again they can't get treated because
there is no opponent no no nothing it's
really really bad
um that's really sad story I believe
um so the aftermath of that more than 20
hospitals got impacted appointments and
ID system got shut down excellent
machines CD scans appointments and much
much more of each other because their ID
systems mainly of them shut down
interesting to say that uh maybe it
occurs that conscience in the middle I
don't know maybe they they seem they
raised really the the impact really bad
and they they demanded initially
19 million uh dollars but they gave up
and sent the keys
nonetheless
it was still hard to cover three months
to recover uh only by the by the end of
September the HTC recovered more than
thousand servers and and and thousand
around thousand applications themselves
really really bad attack high impact uh
the estimated damages without even
paying for the key itself without even
paying for the attackers was around 600
million dollars estimations out there uh
really really bad because of the
recovery because of the decryption
because you need to clean all the system
to check on the system because you need
to upgrade the system replacing them
they have this whole system called I
think memes means something like that
which is an old kind of hospital kind of
related systems that is really hard to
update so
uh really bad again and the cost of this
I have been really high uh also data
leaks more than 500 in general records
was published out there and yeah so this
was the aftermath
um what we can take from this attack so
we can definitely start this well first
configurable security tools there are so
many logo figures Securities it was not
updated ones more than 12 months without
any updated antivirus rules all systems
listening system
uh probably any any uh more kind of one
two years before and one they could have
worked in this system because they
weren't updating the attack was not that
sophisticated but more that this The
Defenders will not prepare they have
these low cyber security opportunity in
the systems you know idea ideas AV
provider effort to move uh they say yes
the risk is low and they will do not
feel after that they don't share the
information
they restart the servers to as a
protection mechanism uh really really
astonishing really bad
um they didn't have ways to prioritize
and and the standard way to to mitigate
and to deal with incidents so attacks
will happen they didn't wait to mitigate
them uh correctly uh communication they
were lacking communication uh sharing
data between the hospital even when the
attacking runs the record
so really bad attack misfortunate or or
also mispreparedness and music
penetration as well and many many points
to be taken from it and very interesting
bullets for you
uh so our last attack we're going to
deal with and we're going to tell about
is the colonial background attack uh
this will be our concluding wise story
uh event so Colonial Colonial is one of
the biggest uh companies from oil uh
Transportation on gas utilization it is
one of the biggest pipeline in the east
coast of the USA we can see the pipeline
and the Parkland route on the on the
picture of the right uh this is the
largest pipeline system for refinery in
the US uh more than 50 of the fuel
consume in the east coast is actually
arriving through these pipeline systems
uh and it's really really important in
the aspect of oil and gas uh from
anything
and yeah it was attacked and it was
attacked really really bad so on the
19th May uh the colonial uh company
shuts down it's applied the colonial
Pipeline and why it was doing that it
was doing that because the PCS managed
the colonial program got attacked by
ransomware they will notice this runs
over uh was going on and they will
immediately uh shutting down the system
and handling that uh the attacker will
probably use the attacker was probably
used some unused and old VPN account a
password they found in dark web without
multi-factor authentication without a
factor authentication really bad and
then also the buying Administration
involving that and and also enter enter
into the picture and helping them the
FBI actually corresponds and and and and
managing uh helping managing the effect
as well
um you know this is really a nation
state kind of thing that really is that
widely uh important subjects so they
were really trying uh to help the uh in
this course of events uh the timeline of
this attack was on this well it was
assumed to be on the 16th of May 20 2021
and
uh probably as I told you with this
click that password they were
infiltration infiltrating the systems uh
the ransomware starts on the 7th May the
news government military form and the
pipeline has also taking uh to minimize
the exposure uh you would ask yourself
like removing shutting down all the
pipeline but remember that at this point
they didn't know if the attackers were
actually trying to manipulate and even
damage their the power and says they
didn't know anything like that's that's
really important point so I believe that
they've been doing correctly uh taking
down the pipeline to minimize the
exposure and the impact and the blood
strategies of the attack itself few
hours corresponding and we've supervised
by the FBI you're actually paying so
they were paying around
around 4 4.4 million dollar uh 75
Bitcoins to the attackers themselves and
couple of days later five days later the
pipeline is fully restored but we can
see here uh that
it wasn't uh restored without any impact
without any damage uh many pipelines
many by our main gas stations were
actually impacted uh gas prices went
High we'll talk about it a little bit uh
later in the slides uh so regarding the
APT group it should be the dark side
group this Amity group soon to come out
from Eastern Europe or Russia I guess
this uh interesting business model which
called Ross roswell's service model
which they operate uh run solar Services
they will
um they will help attackers incorporate
with attackers to deploy The Ransom and
take shares uh take cuts of the of the
deal itself they develop also the the
malware itself this is the notice
they're doing uh on the 2021 it was
called the dark side on somewhere uh
this year it's called the black matter
will run somewhere the changing names
probably uh a more advanced uh malware
some splitting in the school but again
this group is really evolved in really
doing much much damage out there in the
world uh related reverse engineering
this threat we can see that it tries to
delete the backups again each removal
Shadow copies from the system it removes
all the backup Services we can see the
backup Services uh being queried we can
see uh the there's so many the
interesting backup Services you try to
move all of them from the system and it
tries uh it uses for first encryption
symmetry piece and it is really it what
it does is really interesting you
Generate random symmetric Keys correctly
it encrypts the system with salsa 20 uh
with the sigmatics with this symmetrics
uh symmetric keys and afterwards it
doesn't need to send any of these Keys
it just encrypts all of the skills the
public key embedded in this front
somewhere and remove all signs with this
key and evidence out there
and this is the square of operation the
impact again really really high impact
uh there was a temporary actually full
shortage we can show we can sell the
left picture around for five days
uh some areas without gas uh we can see
on the left picture gas station being uh
uh uh rushed by so many cars so many
cars waiting for uh for gas uh more than
70 percent of the filling station around
areas from North Carolina to South
Virginia went out of gas people were
buying like Panic buying more and more
buying which led for shortage which
ledge for sorry for gas prices going up
and the eyes in disease on the right
picture we can see a gas station and
disabled because no gas transmission
problems stuff like that
um but wait a second you mess with the
FBI and there that was the point that
the FBI got in line got into uh uh
evolved into the involved in the in the
scenario and trying to to do its way uh
um to dealing with these threat actors
it was a really nice that matter and as
a nation state matter Biden was
threatening also this group threatening
the attackers will be
will be dealt with and every refmi
definitely why sorry the FBI statement
uh around the 14 was actually uh uh a
couple of days before on the uh uh sorry
a couple of days before uh the that
thing was happening and on the 13 the
dark side group came out of the world
where the servers does not exist the
servers the last video of the servers
the National Floor uh the money many of
the the some large portion of this money
probably and stuff like that and it
seemed to be linked in a sense the FBI
took actions uh to mitigate these threat
actors so the aftermath on the seventh
that we're the FBI actually recovers
around 2 million dollars for the
attackers themselves they acquired the
private keys from before the wallets and
decrypt and maintain the Privacy with
probably seem to be we don't know really
how they they managed to do it but
assume to be down like that you can see
that uh there were they were recovering
64 Bitcoin but uh because probably it
was almost only because but the Bitcoin
was went down so they actually lost uh
loads of money probably because of that
as well
um on the 2007 of June uh also their
service the dark side server went down
and removed completely uh I don't know
what they are there but create shocked
for doing that on the Ava mat was
actually a congressional hearing on the
subject with the colonial pipeline CEO
um we can see here and it is actually
admitting we didn't know at the time we
didn't have the answer was the pipeline
was actually changed for days and
typically it is not something that
actually does so they didn't really know
they assumed they didn't change their
pipelines but it wouldn't have been much
much was uh if they weren't uh
in the things inside the systems and
they didn't disable in the pipeline
itself and as the the Joseph planned the
colonial providence CEO said uh even the
best in class is still suspectable so
lessons we can learn from that that
attack is that well do the basics clear
your unused account unable to factor
authentication backups and and data
guarding assume attack would happen set
up your emergency response plan IO plans
make all your plans ready for for
attacks because attack will happen and
you want to minimize your attack radius
your blast values
um look over the Legacy entries Legacy
systems uh all user all the apps fix and
update them and manage these systems
um get the best out of each expert each
expert has its own kind of expertise as
its owner kind of uniqueness raise your
skill level and learn from this kind of
experts again increase your cyber
security mature level educate your
personal inclusive skill personnel and
configure the help configure security
tools
this was about the first attack uh this
conclusions are all stories in here I
want to thank you all uh for this
amazing opportunity to speak about this
interesting astonishing attacks I will
embarack from Wild pointer uh please you
can follow me on Twitter link to
whatever and I was really really excited
and interested giving you this story I
have so many credits for so many amazing
Giants and
I'm working to make all the information
and many information public
thank you all these groups for sharing
your knowledge as well
with that in mind thank you
that's it
thank you very much Barack for that
wonderful pop
[Applause]
no okay so
um yes we are live and uh if you have
guys have any question for Barack I'm
sure Barack are you able to hear us from
here
he's holding the microphone and you
could ask your question live
Barak are you able to hear us
excuse me
can you hear us
yes yes I can I can yes all right so
I'll be opening up the floor for some
questions although you're not seeing it
we do have a lot of people
um uh listening to your talk right now
so from anyone do does anyone from the
audience have questions sorry please
please raise raise the voice a bit
so again for anyone who has questions
for Barack
uh do come on stage anyone
are you all good all right
so how about this uh for everybody that
are here physically if you do have
questions barack's uh
contact details it's already on the
screen uh I hope you don't mind Barack
but they'd be reaching out to you
personally for some questions
true no problem
all right thank you very much time and
we really appreciate you doing this for
us
for sure thank you for inviting all
right have a great day
thank you bye bye