it was a joy lost knowledge this
presentation is swept under the Dragons
tell me about necro set so i started out
i reside with pictures that kind of try
to describe me edit thank you Frank
so just a little bit back after I'm
having really a 12 year old stuff in the
32 year old man's body I like my vocal
exercise science fiction starter I like
bourbon ooh yes hyphen cigars so in
addition to having really good
Louisville bourbon house
every time two years old bourbon on
here's the Gulf house Friday night so
tell much i like it into a DB tough up
and something to her miss Alden evening
terms though I do move my mind starting
to shift a little bit at attentive host
equal force academy tool I mean it's
more about me I want to be some of his
flavors I actually got talking to what's
wrong with my presentations that saw
this fun event so all views and opinions
in this presentation or my own and do
not reflect the opinions or beliefs of
my employer or any other affiliated
organizations so don't worry angry
letters remember
I like it feeds me sort of legends of
dragons never played actually a current
asset but should how many in the room in
action plate
you're at a hacker thank you so I really
get this presentation I thought the Venn
diagram of like dungeons and dragons
players and like DVD players would be
very late but oh it must almost be the
same circle no actually I think first
one did the presentation to people the
room actually the answer that as an
affirmative on a room of like 20-30 some
are people so I was a little surprised
but you know it's it's a standard
role-playing game you know before with a
shooters role-playing games were world
of warcraft
DICE's character sheets lots of robots
and all these things came together and
the little ventures as opposed my
presentations I enjoy searching the
internet for things safe mode safesearch
being an optional function
so I always liked this slide it's going
to be what people actually think we've
done this with dragons that play you
know it's I think it's very true I think
it speaks a little bit too to the
mentality that some of the people but
also to the way that people have
received you know people were I think
this even come apartments to the point
that spacer was talking about earlier
date has talked with use talking about
this perception
we had the quotes from from the director
and from from the head of hair for Cyber
Command basically talking about you know
they very much hinted at these
stereotypes of hackers and inviting
professionals in general I think and and
so if you know you see a lot of that
here annoy people have perceptions so
the first lesson that kind of take out a
ton from dragons is that it takes a team
you know and by that in those & Dragons
you have to care the important thing to
take away from this is never whether
it's done from dragons or modern RPGs
like warcraft you know pc bae systems
they all have similar constructs and
that's because most of them in the end
they're somewhat based on letters and
dragons
so all those games have different
reasons versus have different skills and
abilities different traits we all have
different they're different classes
which had different skill sets right you
have you have combat and physical
characters like barbarians and fighters
who get in there and beat the crap out
of everything you have naija users you
stand in the back in cast wizard cast
spells and heal people and so you have
different classes that have come
together to make a crease of team
because you know one person alone can
necessarily do everything so whether
it's Dungeons and Dragons you're going
into it
you know you've got your Dungeon Master
they're being the story or you know
you're playing modern role playing games
and you've got dungeons and grades all
these other things you know you can't go
in there by yourself you need to have a
team of people let's come together to
make you stronger than you actually go
again searching the interesting too much
actually did find a picture with
somebody to kind of explained classes
and legends of dragons using the
Avengers
so what class is a nympho set so I kind
of trying to break this up kind of give
a high level view couple classes but
it's not strictly speaking all of them
right you're going to have developers
guys who are great a code who build the
programs that using who may build the
exploits that you're using their testing
writing the scripts that you can use for
animation whatever else they might doing
you've got you venture metasploit
masters you've got your pen test teams
you have your guys who go in do your
testing their skill sets are very driven
behind us behind those totals functions
we have hard drives right guys who who
know the ins and outs of tribes who know
who know how to how to configure
maintain computer systems most abstract
want to have up here is the network
gurus you know guys no water shark you
know the man who you know
guys who can look at a pcap and can like
figure out exactly what's going on
without any tool except Wireshark and a
couple filters they're like this is
exactly what's happened
there's dozens of tools that automate
lots of that grade you can adjust all
these P caps and I'll show you pictures
data flows but you know you spending in
those nothing's perfect you still have
those guys who just do that I'm looking
fo essence right whether that's desktop
server based it was folks or mobile guys
and a lot of times these are overlapping
other areas right because your
developers odds are going to have some
specialty in one or more of the
operating systems because anymore with
all these mobile constrained
architectures developing is more
restrictive than just writing hey I were
ansi c co double column in the system
and it should work so second we got that
so in Dungeons and Dragons a dispositive
multi-class you know in the real world
we called the jack of all trades but
it's very you know it's this idea you
know somebody who's good at multiple
multiple things you know there's the
same you know jack of all trades master
Tom I tonight the disagree someone with
that I think you can have somebody who
has a broad range he's maybe not good at
all of the skills but he might be
excellent at networking but and it goes
to you know he might know about hardware
he could be you know good dad or or have
we're just having our general skills and
other areas that may be useful another
portion of Dungeons and Dragons days
alignments and the first time I is
limitation I got really bogged down into
the alignment
and the second time I did it I further
clock down to it because this is one of
the questions I got asked was why don't
understand the alignments and then I
realized something important this from
the projector this presentation which is
it doesn't matter the there's a couple
slides out of here that seriously it's
not human ok a bit like a so so the
important thing here you know with all
these isn't so much to get bogged down
in the wherewithal and how to's of how
characters and classes and alignments
work with in Dungeons and Dragons but
the thing I think that is most important
and what I'm trying to get across is
that it takes a mix of all of these
things right so you can apply to some
extent people into different areas and
alignments and you have to have that
right in the agent we different
personalities on the team if everybody
is the exact same things the exact same
way and has that same mentality you
don't have somebody who may not just
about that person who's can look at this
from a different perspective and be like
a wait why are we still doing this the
same way if we did
something else maybe would work better
so I didn't leave this one extra
sidelines kind of clarify for anybody
who really does care display the good
versus evil that one's pretty clear most
people get get the concept you know Cary
brothers affecting the innocence that
wants to kill everything
more table muffled chaotic OHS gets a
little more confusing for so I love the
send
but the waffle side to a rules order
tradition try to explain the lawful
people because people like uh Camille
awful people the best way to describe it
is the door world dominator a person has
this moral code of structure but it may
be different from everybody else's but
he wants to impose it on very he wants
the Walden kind of his vision whereas
the cab people individual is the whole
destroyer right if you don't care how
the one of the better examples for cab
evil is installed the dark knight the
portrayal the Joker in that movie is
pretty spot-on for chaotic
and so what did i do I had make version
of this that has alarming stigmatism so
you know I tried to break it down a
little bit the good on the top and bias
but you know the it's basically all your
different types of testing feed rate so
CA your certification guys they're going
to be lawful oh great they have a set of
rules they won't follow the rules and
make sure everything gets checked off
and everything is done right that meets
those rules they're not you know if
they're just like okay this is good this
is good that's good it all looks good
they were neutral good you know I kind
of put routines it and the reason I said
that put that there was they're not
quite following the rule of doing see
anywhere but on the same side they're on
where I say that think the red team's
are which is you have a red team during
the true penetration test they need to
be looking at your networks and the same
methods and ways that that your black
hats in your wife
particular your black pants or your main
adversaries are going to attach the
devil the river so they have to be Milan
the kids
and the end within your organization
within your groups those are always
going to be perceived as the good right
there the ones trying make better some
of the some of your add meds and your
help desk folks probably see them is
equal because they come in break
everything and now they get stuff fixing
the great lawful neutral milego brought
blocks are developers but I couldn't
find another good pitcher for in
Melbourne that the help desk is true
neutral white hats chaotic control the
bottom of the lawful evil those those
are the bosses right she's going to have
to mobile to have the order but but but
ultimately they get they sometimes get
to where the put the put neutral evil as
the lawyers you know you did maybe the
lot of people but you know it's to them
it's more you know about keeping their
keeping the company and keeping your
bottom
then if you out of people's the black
hats
this is a guy to anything n want to
break into your networks that are the
ones who want to and you know still
information they want to fix your
websites whatever nefarious reason they
might have you know whether it's just
for the the giggles order for the lulz
you know that's ultimately that's you
know before your enemies I suppose
so the second lesson
media director this is where the dungeon
master so
so those have been played before you
know Dungeon Master's one who's created
scenarios that you're playing and who's
depending on how he will in how people
he is have had some whose main purpose
and lightness to make sure you all dodge
others want to see you to progress and
so it's really you know this is what's
behind that little screen adult steven
all the plans but i think that's the
important thing right this is the person
who has the plan it has the vision of
what of what needs to be done and a lot
of times the other side it's the if the
players and once actually playing the
game whose job it is Jackson came great
in the end how many of us have managers
who are actually doing the doing day to
day technical another so much but
it's you know moving the way herding
cats it's quite the reality I my second
run around as a manager
trying to get everybody in the same
place at the same time to do the same
thing is or even something similar to
the same thing is very hard for you if
you've hung out google at hacker
conferences it's again very similar
right how do you get everybody who can
in the same direction at the same time
yeah
even though I'm pretty sure people the
fire alarm right now their vehicle
hackers will be round like I don't seem
shy don't smell okay I don't smell smoke
I'm he okay bit I will admit to coming
up this time I don't know if your dose
by the elevator there's these stacks of
recycling that's the top one has a cell
phone on it there are no cell phones in
it right now that was a little sad I was
hoping somebody might be might be the
cell phone
then I was going to change the whole
direction of the topper talk about why
don't you sell phones so we have any
Dungeon Master's right you know people
will dictate what we're doing dictation
store into it you know how things are
going to be done whether it's the
customers whether that's customers are
external to your company doing
consulting if you're doing I to support
head and an internal support for your
for your own company right then the
other people with your company area
customers your team needs you your
technical team
your troop supervisor is even tougher
man
because in the end you know as you go up
there how much vision they have
specifically for you narrows but their
vision overall fits in so if you upper
management level there's the global we
know I have this this is what the
company needs to do the supervisor
should bow that will say ok will make
this happen the mic would we need to do
this and so then that leads out to you
if you have team leads between you and a
manager they filter out in a delegate
tasks you know they another ones that
keep us truly on traffic that right so
all these people kind of dictate the
story to us they're the ones who leave
and if you did have if you didn't have
this sort of structure right then you
put a hundred hundred guys in a room and
try to convince the doll go in what
direction are they going to go there not
somebody truly to step up we you know
the odds of attica the both of them all
won't be in same direction are going to
be something are
or at least in the same general grip
so we got into the third list
and this kind of grows out of again me
googling answer for dinner so everything
had worked as a doctor great I did not
have to fabricate these pictures of
innovating before but I thought they
look incredibly similar to the fact that
one is a metal diagram
it's just eight shows I think it shows
kind of the is a little bit bit so maybe
a little it is a bit too little in some
sense but it's a it's kind of fun dagger
to look at but the reality is when
you're playing Dungeons and Dragons you
navigate a dungeon and going as a team
you looking around to find you know
treasures or sacred princess and you go
through the potential at you go through
and it ultimately you're trying to get
tier incorporate whatever that is it
varies but
you navigate through from point to point
to do the same thing in that works right
if you're coming in as a tester and
you're looking at network you're doing
the exact same thing if you're in goal
is to get back for all the data is
stored you're going to navigate through
and whichever method is most effective
sometimes you can walk straight in
because it's a giant hole in wall
instead of a door and other times you
have to work a little harder and so
that's where the first thing comes
obstacles when you go into a dungeon you
have things that are going to be you
know they might be doors you all's
making traps we have the same thing in
network sorry we have firewalls
different types of appliances that are
all doing the same thing and some extent
you can even argue that
well non-direct necessarily directly
strict obstacle you know if there's a
lot of traffic ideas and I guess become
the exact
the room
child obstacles well if it's a door in
dungeons and dragons like you have a
world who comes in Dixville great get
you through and now you're on to the
next tonight estate
and you'll be in a network if you're
doing your time to attacking trying to
get into a network from now
places and different ones to where you
have to pivot in front well I got one
machine now I need to try to use that so
it's not that sort of straight
and so you know we work around obstacle
right and some of you might just turn
off
if you don't have a road to pick a lock
you were buried at the door until it
falls
which comes to Travis you know whether
it's the Indiana Jones style of giant
bowl or you know it's honey pots or
is it designed to lure you away from
your old target you know it's always to
try to to capture your attention and
keep you from getting where you want me
and that guess they're just other forms
of obstacles sometimes you just have to
run with there's creatures right Anika
dungeon you had to convince of creatures
if you've ever played DD there's
probably
thousands of in the various books rule
guides and your Dungeon Master pronounce
will be equal with
sku
you know whether it's little innocent
looking Cobalts or skeletons or purchase
dragging you have different things you
have different pictures again who who's
who are always occupying your what
so I try to create some creatures bento
said you know and this is where you have
your IDs or IPS is your near antivirus
your seems you know anything doing a lot
of collection any of those sort of
things that are monitoring and watching
that you know they may not necessarily
unlike the creatures in a dungeon which
could actually literally more times than
not these are going to just alert you to
the fact and somebody's there somebody
else coming to kill you back so
but in the end all these pieces come
together and so you get this this view
that where you know you're trying to get
to a goal and that goal is your treasure
right so a network this treasure could
be anything range if the person is going
to be attacking your network is you know
people we're going to fix your website
maybe if you go well it is just your web
server if if you actually have real
proprietary data or
how personal
personal information than the network
people might want then that was the
treasure
you know dozen dragons it's always you
know it's almost it was troubled armor
since for such a fine
your goal is to get something the other
knows there might be more altruistic
management
but I mean in cold rain and use that as
a side effect of coming lots of gold so
so the fourth lesson using your
imagination playing the game great
here's this map again how do you go from
pieces of paper and little markers on
there to seeing yet you know seeing your
team and senior yorker come together and
destroy a dragon we'd have to use our
imagination right if you don't have any
imagination Dungeons and Dragons doesn't
come from so what's the reality of
computers that ain't the very cliche
image but there you know when we
interact with computer systems and
electronics in general we have some sort
of human usable interface right but the
reality is that human usable interface
is just a cover for what's actually
going on
and this goes all the way down to both
working on computer systems to looking
at networking trafficking my background
of college was never me and
I I think
correction likes of the NM
like where
Kirsten w but the reality is even that's
not everything right I mean really is
the physical layer thing which mean
you're using that signal is sent in one
of various methods right over ethernet
the voltages along the water or
modulated to represent fits the you know
wireless you know the signals signals
are changed amplitudes and frequencies
in order to to accommodate the same the
same concentrator so we have to in some
ways abstract this because you know it's
not to me before
so this also leads to solving problems
you know
two pictures again I like
so you know the keyboard not found press
f1 to resume or the using six different
adapters that you can put your microSD
card
but ultimately you doing dungeons and
dragons you you know whether you're
running into a trap or you run to a wall
or something gets in your way to futures
we're going you know we had an infosec
we have problems we have to celebrate
things I always work the way they're
supposed to
through those high ball thingies address
was not sure
which kind of feeds it's nice into less
than five which is the elements a chance
nothing ever goes the way you expected
you I think anybody who's ever worked at
the computer is well aware that
even some of us who were the experts are
more small fix something by magic break
we don't know why wasn't working five
minutes ago but I just did x and
outwards so done with dragons you know
some kind of show beginning you know one
of the elements was all the dice and all
the table so everything the game is
based on this on the system of chance
you know you have a character sheet that
has you know certain stats and points in
it but in the end or you do anything you
have to pick up one of these dice and
roll if it's a bad night cursing the
whole time
so again more great pictures you know
dungeon dragons the dice that may
ultimately they when you're doing
character creation you roll dice to
interest animals when you go into combat
we inform any actions nice to see you
pit what you're going to hit you know
when you're go to hit something you know
you roll your damage and there's nothing
more frustrating than having the big
bulky barbarians swing and miss and roll
one and then chop the head off of this
from an infosec it's the same one right
we have devices that break we haven't
put into won't work loading code that
doesn't compile exploit the run
blue screen whatever it is we run into
these problems right so it's always non
clear-cut you know sure ninety percent
of the time you might go ahead and run
the same vibe commands on every computer
it's going to work perfectly but you
know the next week you go back and you
do it you know you did it one day patch
tuesday turn around and come back the
next weekend you know something's not
working again it's always fun to try to
figure out over
end of this just working as well you
know anything that can possibly go wrong
with there's there's plenty of lists on
the internet of work these laws of
combat dragons anything else and there's
probably ten times as many for work
these laws of computing apparently some
very angry sis admins exist out there
who have nothing to do in their free
time except break lists
names
so the summer
so there's five lessons right it takes a
team having people who can work together
who have different skills you can come
together and together better than
the funny thing about it takes the team
is I probably took a longer life to
learn that limit ensure that we first to
admit that up
all evolved five years ago yeah thank
you thank you be honest yeah that would
be about ready till about five years ago
yeah I more times than not my mentality
was I can do a fashion for myself with
less people
and I'm probably messed up some crap new
year director beat somatic GPU and
straighten going in the right direction
every network was it done you have to
use your imagination as I learned every
day
things
so I put a good thank you so we're good
i fail to do this with every other time
the other times I've done this
presentation this year so this is going
to be a big retirement its presentation
kind of experiment I gave you four times
but
much like space for excited this morning
you know how you know
James came up in casting a dirty contest
and talked I got it too but it
definitely felt a little friend I you
know I'm not saying she fun secret
meeting horror but it doesn't it was
kind of like yeah you should really
submit because you know not everybody
goes to every conference it's just like
I'm sitting down and she's standing up
which is the only way she could be
looking down at me and it was a little
it was a little intimidating that's all
I'm gonna say but like to thank psets
Delaware for having me here a second
year represented in fact I'd like to
think I actually taught somebody
something that you're not sure I think i
just read to me or people think
Darrell's got a car matters own they've
all allowed me the opportunity to get up
here try to impart some knowledge much
of it if somebody takes something away a
couple more things and you won't break
it but this makes my ether old feed
batches this anybody that for all the
feedback and drove get it again I also
love to make him and fozzie max for
Pecola mean the couch is gone but it was
an effective heckling and not
mean-spirited so I appreciate it no I
think everyone is here today coming and
listening to what I have to say and
anyone else who may be watching food to
them I talked earlier in the year who I
felt a thing
does anyone have any questions I managed
to get through in 30 minutes
I'm sorry