um so the
the next talk is not about the virus
total
um it's so it's about detecting uh
emerging threats uh
before they reach fires total before
they are shared and so on and uh so
andreas and anastasia
have the floor thank you
well i'm not andreas yeah yeah not andre
sorry hey yuri
andreas unfortunately uh was supposed to
talk
unfortunately he could not come so um
i'm um
you're undressed today no you're
undressed today yeah i'm andreas today
yeah yuri
and
anastasia you have the floor thank you
so
we're going to talk about today about
the work that we've been doing for uh
probably a year
to
try to develop the machinery to detect
emerging malware in the cloud at scale
using fuzzy hashing
and uh there is a large team worked on
this project and
anastasia polycova uh
and me yuri zufoish you're going to
present today but i want to mention by
name that uh gantan
ali hon yang
made a
very significant contribution more than
i did
leading this group
and
andreas so we are from alibaba cloud
but
andreas is from dhamma academy of
alibaba so this is a research
unit of alibaba group
and so uh
in the picture uh we kind of like to
think about uh ourselves sometimes as
minions
we
believe to serve
so um so these are the speakers today
without andreas
so with that
i'll let
anastasia take over
thank you yuri thank you dominica for
farm
reference so i'm anastasia palikova i'm
secure senior security engineer of
alibaba innovation security lab and
today
we will start with security reasons why
did we start this research and
how it goes what we achieve
but first first things first why
um when you work in a
big company and you have a lot of
customers in the scale of basically
everything is huge
you start to treasure little things and
the little things become big so
third-party validation of any iocs you
have comes with a price
first is a latency and latency from the
both sides in our case first of all when
we talk about validation of the
show value in our case
we're talking about not one child value
we need to validate manually somehow but
we are talking about huge pipeline of
the show values we need to validate
so we need to build the whole pipeline
put them into the queue validate them
with virustotal usually because we use
it
and then wait for results and then
interpret this result so latency comes
from the boss side from our pipeline and
from
third party validation in our case of
aristotle
um of course license are not free so we
need to pay to virustodo to get an
access to the data obviously
and
it's not very
bad i would say
as long as you have a budget you can
afford it but it creates a huge
dependency of your security program and
your security software to one particular
third-party vendor who provides you with
validation and then dependency can bite
you back one day for example what if why
aristotle decided to go out of the
market on the country or work with only
particular companies or revoke our
license for some reason how we're going
to proceed should our security program
stop or what we're going to do of course
in case
of our team we're serving the cloud
customers it's not acceptable at all we
need to continue operation
second
reason is ambiguous vt result
interpretation probably
you all seen this very frustrating page
when virustotal just returned you no
results found i have no idea what you're
talking about
how we should interpret that
is it malicious
is it brand new is it benign we don't
know
so that's frustrating but not that
frustrating like very unclear result for
example we all know that the virus total
has around 60 different aging engines
that contributes to detection
and when you validate a challenge and
only two
of the 60 agents tell you yeah we think
that's malicious what are you going to
do are you going to trust
how you're going to validate it if you
don't have
any resources to go deep inside of the
malware binary and reverse engineer it
is it's malicious is it false positive
on
this two vendor site is it false
negative to others
how we should treat it
and of course there is some geopolitics
stuff like malware targeting chinese
customers in underreported to aristotle
a lot of other co-workers in
alibaba cloud use completely different
source of ti than virus total and
a lot of malware goes under the radar
when we're talking about chinese market
and malware targeting chinese customers
i know you have heard about chinese
malware a lot as it was for the previous
day and for this day probably we will
hear again and again
but
when it goes to analytics
and to reverse engineering or some data
about this malware best you can do find
something in mandarin
that you need to translate using google
translator and virustotal usually
absolutely not aware about this malware
last but not least cloud specific
threats
you know as any as a cloud provider
alibaba shares security responsibility
with the customers so we cannot be
responsible for everything some binaries
belongs to the customer and those
binaries are part of their business and
their operation
but if we can see only the value how can
we
guess is it a binary balance to the
customer is it a malware is it
well-known binary we already seen
nobody knows
so considered all of this problem we
decided that we need to start our own
research and we need to take our
validation ioc validation at least
partly at home and not ship everything
to the
vendors outside because of all these
problems listed about
and there is a tale of
two cities
this is a virus total and our cloud
so in our cloud we gather particular
information about binaries we gather
chavalio and md5 failure
and if we have some suspicions about
this particular binary we going in check
it with varus total like hey what do you
think does it look like any malware you
know
but unfortunately and sadly too often we
receive the replay like i have no idea
what that no results found
and again it we start to frustrate what
we should do with that how we should
classify it
so
it leads us to the idea so maybe we try
to verify
not the right data we asking for the
wrong
question and we
receive the incorrect answer
this is how we start to gather and
collect fuzzy hash
come on
i'm sorry
so fuzzy hash i believe most of us know
what it is fuzzy hash is a contextual
hash that basically can consist of three
different blocks first is a block size
second is hash one and divided by uh
column the hash two
in this example we provide you with
ssd fuzzy hash
values for
fenix miner family
let's talk about distance
if you
look a little bit closer to all these
hash values
i believe
nobody needs to be genius security
researcher or data analytic
to
notice this eyeballing
you know um common parts and i believe
i balance simul
similarity in between several hashes
and some difference
so yeah let's show some respect
this minor tries its best
and if we cannot look for the fuzzy
hashes as deep in our case and we can
look only on
md5 or chavalio we will never ever guess
that this chavalo or md5 value belongs
to the same aware family they are
completely different but because fuzzy
hash is contextual we can see the
similarity with the bar eye
and we can see the difference and if my
sore red eyes can see the difference in
similarity machine can see it even
better i believe
so
why not to try
so the one term we need to know is the
distance what is the distance uh
distance is a function of two uh
of two fuzzy hash values
and it basically shows how similar they
are
usually distance lie in um
in a range from
zero to one
or from one to 100 depends on algorithm
you use
but basically it's bigger the d is
bigger the distance is less similar
your character is up
ok i believe that every second security
engineer every first security team
once came up with this idea and think
okay
fuzzy hash it looks so great we both can
cure the world if we implement that
why nobody did
in a large scale
because the idea looks much more simpler
than implementation itself
and why did we dare to try why did we
give it a try why we start to work on
this project
because we have some advantages and some
privileges of course
i'm not trying to
tell that our team is any better than
yours
but probably our data set is bigger and
first obstacle
every security team runs it i is a
question do you have enough data
because even i don't have enough data
and i have like very few lonely show
values i'm going to compare to each
other
games over
if i cannot benchmark them and if i if i
cannot measure the difference in between
known malware or known benign files and
my unknown hashes
how should it work
no we need a huge database of hashes and
we need to label them we need at least
a little bit of knowledges what is
malicious what's not
algorithm and computing power
this obstacle can scare
almost anybody away because when you
start to
think about okay fuzzy hash is pretty
long and to be honest fed
line we need to find the similarity in
between and we need to compare it
pairwise one by one choose a million
differential values how can they afford
it what our gram should we use and
especially if you going to rely on
publicly available algorithms like for
example java library for fuzzy hash
probably first try and first run
will scare you with a bill for cloud
computing or for your own hardware and a
lot of team will give up on this project
um not blaming anyone it's really
expensive if you're gonna do it like
that
use cases
we all like security research and we
will do it for free like let's be honest
because it's it's fun it's interesting
it's something we love to do
but who's gonna pay for our toys if we
have no use cases
and especially for expensive project you
need to justify the budget you need to
have use cases you need to
make your
research productized and applicable to
something
and of course great team
um
again i'm not telling the my team is
you know
greater than yours but the one
advantages we have our team is very
diverse we have everybody we have uh
data scientists we have engineering part
we have securities and we have analytics
so this has led us to spread the task
and work faster and build the whole
pipeline
and productize all the research our
scientists provide us
okay so as a code provider we have all
of that we have a lot of use case we
have a lot of problems we see samples we
have no idea about every day in enormous
amount
uh algorithms can be in computing power
computing power is not a problem to the
certain level considering that we have
the whole cloud behind us
but again we need to be modest and
optimize all the algorithms
and to optimize them what do we need
we need a good engineer engineers we
need to get we need good scientists and
we need somebody who is able to validate
the result of this research
so great team comes into the place and
if we have all four
answers on the place why not to try
let's start with sample collection let's
see what do we have and how big the
sample size is
so
uh
at the bottom of the slide you can see
an example of the data we gather from
you have customers machines
we do it with special software like xdr
and logs like every other cloud vendor
does
because there is no
no secret
so first of all we
take md5 because it's relatively short
level relatively easy to take and
relatively inexpensive second we take
chavalio which is already longer and
more expensive
and the last one is deep which is to be
one is pretty fat and pretty expensive
to take not even
compare but just to get it and gather
but anyway
we start to work and we and we gather
all of the about from the cloud security
product
so our ssd library size in the cloud is
100 million and we're still counting
what do you think 100 million samples
is it a good news or bad news
okay your best guess
well i would say that for data
scientists it's a really good news
big data everything's supposed to be
classified very tightly we can find a
lot of connectivities in the graph
everything looks amazing for engineering
part it looks terrifying it looks
frustrating it looks like how we're
going to do this
and how this miracle in between of
engineering and science happening
yuri will tell you right now
i think we probably need to speed up a
little bit since we are between us and
lunch
that would be my guess
so yes as
anastasia mentioned that
i was able to assemble a great team uh
that comprises of different
specialties and that allowed us to
execute not only the scientific portion
but the engineering implementation and
what
challenges obviously that we were trying
to solve is how
how to process the library and by the
way the library it's important to know
note that the 100 million
samples was collected from the customers
who
authorized the security software that
actually make it possible so
and what we wanted to do is to compare
essentially each of the symbol to each
of the sample right to calculate
pairwise similarity but if you try to do
it on 100 million times 100 million uh
even the cloud provider even large one
uh will not be able to process it
in any uh limited time or cost so we did
uh quite a lot of
tricks to reduce the space so for
example uh we limited the block size uh
to let's say half equal or double we
also implemented pretty
interesting uh optimization our engineer
implemented
the way to scan only for those that have
seven
characters matching uh as a
pre-filtering so
uh in in this uh steps uh um also oh and
by the way you also need uh redundancy
cleanup because a lot of zeros and
binaries for example
uh manifest
themselves in a long character um
repeating characters so uh there's a
uh it's it's a usual
practice so with all this pre-filtering
we reduced it to
manageable for us as a large cloud
provider
and but still nevertheless we ran for
several uh days uh the algorithm that
created the initial space and spent
probably about 50 000 instance hours
which
[Music]
i'm glad we had the resources for it
so what what we
constructed
is a
basically a pairwise similarity between
the 100 million uh
uh samples
and uh what
what can you do with this right
uh you create a large graph so this is a
representation of the graph there is
just a kind of foundational uh storage
layer
but
uh what
the next important question once you
constructed the representation
of your library
what do you do next when new binaries
appear so that's where we added a
pipeline to detect
new sha values
which is pretty
straightforward
although at scale nothing is
and we compare the
the ones that we see for the first time
we compare to our graph and we
evolve this graph
in close to real time so we are not
re-running it's like for several days we
can
do it daily or hourly
so
what
what this uh produces is a very very
nice
representation so once you construct the
graph obviously
there are a few challenges with this uh
in order to even construct the graph we
had to make it in parallel
and
do a lot of tricks that from the graph
theory
that andreas actually was
the driving force for it scientifically
but
it allowed us
to not only create eye candy
visualizations
which will
add more in the paper but also
uh
seeing it as subgraphs
uh connecting uh known and unknown uh
malware samples out of hundred million
uh samples we approximately had uh one
percent labeled
um so mostly by our researchers at a
certain
point of time
and
that created
different opportunities to
to do two different kind of analysis
so if you have this graph representation
you can
do both um
lookups essentially or analysis with the
prior information with the seed right so
when you are trying to see what your new
malware when new binary is connected to
what
what similarity it has
and when you don't have a seed what do
you do
that's what we did at scale as well by
clustering the large graph that we had
into
sub-graphs without having any seed
information
so in a way
if you if you have a sub-graph where you
know one of the
binaries you know that pretty much the
whole sub graph is probably bad
but if you have a sub graph that is has
high similarity but nothing is unknown
then you're just waiting for
security researcher or virustotal or
somebody to confirm at least one member
of this graph and then you can propagate
it right through the subgraph but you
did the homework and you this sub graph
is waiting to be uh annotated basically
um what what's interesting uh is the
difference between polymorphic and code
reuse similarities
so for uh polymorphic we
set uh
a higher threshold so let's say 97
uh because it changes a lot
uh and oh another trick that we used uh
for polymorphic uh
malware is
because it changes so much and there are
so many different uh
uh
very similar uh ssd uh fuzzy hashes so
we just stopped at 5 000
similar ssd
and we just don't add them uh anymore
because uh
more like there's no difference of value
between five thousand to a hundred
thousand of uh different flavors of the
same thing polymorphic but for the code
reuse
something like 80
ish percent is more appropriate
because it doesn't have all the same
components
and
also we
observed that sometimes even lower
percentage signifies a certain
reuse
or shared library
in which case
we didn't do it yet but we can do a
component analysis and actually compare
the binaries rather than the sha values
so uh that actually uh
as as being a leader of this group i
just want to emphasize that maybe if
somebody wants to do some
this project at scale
what is what was super important is to
have one team where scientists and
researchers and security researchers and
engineers work together instead of just
throwing the scientific prototype to
engineering department and wait like for
half a year or a year for execution so
you you got to have a very tight
collaboration and essentially the same
team
they all need to be in the same team to
produce these results at scale quickly
so now
i give anastasia back
to dig a little bit deeper
okay let's take a look at the real case
scenario because
yeah i will try to go fast because
everybody is hungry and i will keep it
nice and fast
so um let's start with our old
well-known malware sword ddos and
probably you know that this mower is
polymorphic one what does polymorphic
means it means that this type of malware
can change its copies during the
self-replication
and
[Music]
sergio dos is well known as a malware
for linux machines but in the last
several years and in the last months it
starts to adopt new techniques for
example it starts to infect the windows
machine as well which has come as a
surprise to be honest because it's not
really easy to adapt something that was
created for linux to infect the windows
machine considering the all the layers
they have inside of the separation
system and even more it adapts the
technologies to exploit vulnerable
container services so now your malware
can be run not only on your instance but
in on all the containers of your
instance in the cloud which
would give which give it um
a great scale to be honest and more
possible ways to make money and perform
the ddos attack like it used to be
so
sergio dos has a special function random
md5 and this function
works to
change the hash value the chevy
md5 and
the charm for
new samples of this mower
but it still has a well-known pattern of
creating the directory it used to run
this directory usually locates in your
serving or tmp
and it it has
random letters no numbers um all
lowercase this uh all the difference 10
10 letters name for the directory when
it starts
a different fresh value can bypass
threat intelligence like various total
and sore exploit this function a lot
so alibaba quote has a lot of rules we
gather them over the years to
investigate how does it work
what
features this malware has and how we can
and all the samples we can keep will
label it and we keep in our database
let's consider one example how
polymorphic polymorphic
detection invasion works
let's um take a look at the picture
first initial
um malware binary that
was dropped at the machine has very
particular md5 as you can see it on the
first line
then during the self-replication process
this malware create the copy and modify
this copy with a rand md5 function
basically what it does it does part in
the
end of the file with random data random
strings
and change the directory also also it
loves to change the directory from user
bin to bin from user bin to tmp and vice
versa so in one moment
several seconds we have completely
different file with different size
different md5 hash and absolutely
different location
but we still know the algorithm how it
names the directory and some other
patterns of the behavior because we've
been observing this malware a lot let's
take a look at the fuzzy hash on these
two samples we just discussed
so md5
looks completely different it's like
there is nothing else there is nothing
in common but they cannot trick fuzzy
hash that easily because again fuzzy
hash is context contextual
uh contextual value so when we see
the same samples but from the half of
the hash view from says dipsha
we can for we can clearly identify where
this random md5 function works and how
it changed the value and it's not
significant
so if we looking for similarity and
similarity is an opposite of distance
distance um shows
how far away
samples from each other and similarities
are an opposite how close they are
related how much they have in common
usually the range lies in between um
zero and one when zero is
like this binary has nothing in common
completely different and one these
binaries are similar completely
identical
and again if we take the ds
if we take the similarity function
from two of these
hash values we can see that that's
significantly high
it's very close to one
so
from the our point of view this is the
same malware
it doesn't matter that the file has a
different
size and different location and
different sha or md5 value this is the
same
let's take a look at them real example
this is sub graph extracted from our b
graph
and this is sub graph for x ordinance
all the blue dots are unknown binaries
we see them for the first time we have
no idea what it is
and we try to compare the new binaries
with some uh with something we already
know and we know about sordidos right
so if you look at the distance you can
see that the that similarity is pretty
close to one even the
the least one uh 0.79 it's still pretty
close to once and uh half for example
so
from
data science point of view that's enough
to prove that this is malware guilty by
association looks the same if something
walks like a dog flies like a duck and
looks like a dog it's probably a dog
right
but
from the point of view of security
engineers how should i know okay that
looks similar but i need to verify is it
the same malware is it the malware at
all
so unfortunately we had a problem to
share internal tool screenshot and
everything because of server because
logs gathered by our internal
proprietary security software but what i
actually did i went to the machines and
pulled all the logs
provided by these binaries running and
what we can see that they have
absolutely identical behavior to all the
malicious sort the dos file it's the
same
i verified
i approve the algorithm algorithm got
productized
and let's take a look at the results
what do we get what did we get
so
sergio doss on virus total the first sha
you can see very old one and very
significantly
malicious i would say
almost all the virus total genes
consider it malicious and report it very
well
but what to do with other
uh 200
11 000 samples we have
that's a lot right so we start to try we
start to verify it again with different
vendors to see how much overlapped we
have we already know they are malicious
we already we already validated them
with our system but what about other
vendors and apparently that
we find out very interesting thing avira
has a very good overlap
73 persons
that's impressive but why aristotle has
only one person and
1.2
uh persons of overlap how come
you probably know that avira contributes
to virus total result as well
but
you know business-wise i guess they
don't contribute everything because they
need to sell us to sell their own
licenses and maybe that was a huge delay
but we tried to verify it
not on the very fresh data as well
nothing actually changed so it's
possible possibly it is a delay problem
possibly it is a limitation of
contribution of other vendors to
virustotal itself but
that looks a little bit frustrating
so yeah polymorphic techniques can
bypass virustotal
and i think we get we get a pretty good
results to labeling all of this stuff
itself
but let's quickly take
um
the take a look from the different point
of view we've been talking about
difference
our threat actors tries to introduce
into the malware to make it look like
something new but what about similarity
itself let's talk about code reuse
code reuse is actually a technique that
shares in between malicious software and
behind software as well because we have
the same libraries we have the same to
be honest github when everybody is copy
and paste takeover flow you name it if
code quartz exists somebody is going to
use it even if it's not the best quality
like i i've seen it already many times
so this is an opposite
approach what we're trying to do we're
trying to find
the piece of shared code in between of
different malware samples and malware
families
why because we want to know
we want to track the malware campaigns
and we want to know
the evolution of malware families it
works absolutely the same but in this
case we targeted not the difference but
similarity itself the target and sharing
code and i have a few cute pictures from
our data scientist to show you the
result
and this is a graph from ransomware for
ransomware and from miners
it shows the shared code
in between of
different samples inside of the families
what do you think why they look so
different
it because it looks like the ransomware
reuse quote much less and they have very
few significant families and the miners
almost all of them look the same
how comes
mostly
this is my opinion but i believe that it
has some some you know rational business
behind that the ransomware is pretty
unique
uh it's relatively expensive
malware it has different um encryption
keys it has different set of exploits to
get to the machine
and it has
different techniques of getting the
payment interact interact with the user
and index the whole file system that
works with different file systems that
you need to index then cipher then
encrypt
so yeah it's not that much to reuse to
be honest and they have several families
but overall it's it doesn't look very
similar and miners what what i want to
do as a hacker to create
like a
malware with a minor i use the normal
miner absolutely legitimate software
that people use for mining and they need
to weaponize it so what i need to do i
need to create a harness that will
deliver
my miner to the target machine exploit
some vulnerability right so most of the
code are still the same it is the same
miners the same
algorithms the same protocols just the
hardness for delivery and droppers are
different everything else is the same
this is why they looked
pretty different
but the difference can be even greater
so this is mirai and engine tesla mirae
is
one of the first open source malware
everybody can pick up and use
supervisory to reuse super easy to add
new exploits to weaponize it and asian
tesla is a remote access trojan
very highly obfuscated very highly
packed so in this case it's really hard
to find shared code because of the
application techniques
but anyway we still managed to do this
let's go to the finals i know everybody
is hungry so to recap the flow
searching for the graph and you're
searching the graph for new binaries
is much faster than any third-party
validation because we have everything at
home we know exactly what we are looking
for we optimize all the data we optimize
all the algorithms for search we know
exactly this is
our
uh
our two and we know how to use it
in-home validation approach remove
uncertainty of vt result interpretation
because we label everything we know
where it belongs we have all the samples
here we can take a look we can reverse
them if they want virustotal does not
provide this information
and present workforce implemented in
security products in alibaba and we're
still working on expand of you know
expansion to expand our contribution to
this product
one question is deep essential basically
no
any other fuzzy hash you can afford will
do
for example lzgd
is bigger one it takes a lot of space on
your on your disk but
it's much more
accurate i would say in it and it can
track like swap the data and
fragmentation and everything so it's not
critical to use exactly ssd everything
that
listed here skills you need whatever you
can adapt whatever you can support
whatever you have capabilities so please
take a look and try to build it
okay okay take aways from everything so
successful malware
evolves and comes back again and again
um nobody knew that we're going to be
talking about miray and sordidos after
seven eight years
after the first release but they're
still here it's super easy malware to
adopt it's super easy to change super
inexpensive to
use and you don't even need to fire your
super expensive
zero day and they works just fine just
modify it sell it and go
so
we cannot get rid of this in in in the
near future i believe
big companies face specific malware
threats and we have unique security
needs so it's easy to overgrow
even best third-party validation
so far we find out that the label
propagation clustering are two major
techniques in ssd graph framework if it
does sounds
a little bit intimidating no worries
it's absolutely standard algorithms to
work with the big data label propagation
allows us to provide the attribution to
the family and clustering just allow us
to gather naturally
data without labeling
to the to the clusters we're going to
investigate
and besides the everything we listed
the potential use can be
even detect the supply chain pollution
and if you don't know what supply chain
pollution is probably everybody seen
this
sshd
malicious server that looks exactly like
a sshd but
it has a trojan side so this is exactly
uh
pollution of the supply chain when you
install something benign and you believe
that this is a part of the system but
it's already got screwed somewhere
it's pretty much it's it's the last word
i wouldn't just want to tell to
aristotle guys we still love you
for sure
we still love you we're still with you
you contribute to community great but
for us it's time to go it's time to grow
and we are here for that thank you very
much
just just one last uh uh note that i
would like uh we're five minutes late
already okay thank you
for the invitation and alibaba for
making this trip possible so and the
paper will be published upcoming
conference paper thank you