alexis
you have the floor
all right thank you eric thank you all
for being here on this early morning for
the best talk of the conference
apparently
um cool so when i imagine air gap
networks i see things just like this
picture in my mind
small castles totally cut off from the
internet to protect the most sensitive
stuff top secret documents power grids
nuclear centrifuges maybe
but whenever we analyze a new malware
that seems to target these types of
network not gonna lie there's a little
bit of adrenaline rush because we know
we're looking at uh something like a
tool that an attacker devised to attack
something of great value that probably
went unnoticed for too long
hold on yep
so my name is alexey i'm a senior
manager at eset i'm here with fakundo my
manager yeah not yet
a researcher in my team in my montreal
team
and we're here this morning to discuss
how threat actors have been attacking
air gap networks with malware
specifically built
to operate in these restricted
environments
you'd think this type of malware is
pretty rare which is kind of true
but in 2020 alone four new frameworks
were exposed uh previously unknown
frameworks and that's what prompted us
to revisit this whole category of of
malware and put all of them in
perspective to try and understand how
they work
and see if we could come up with some
effective detection and defense
mechanisms and actually we published um
the result of this study in a white
paper a few months ago
on our
company blog
and today we'll just summarize some of
the key findings of that study
and so first we needed to agree
among among us what
constitutes a malware that targets an
air gap network
because there are no predefined
definition out there at least from a
purely technical perspective so this is
the definition we use for this for this
research so it's a malware or a set of
malware components acting together a
framework
that implements an offline covert
communication mechanism between an air
gap system and the attacker
and we believe it all started a little
over 15 years ago
with apt-28 who developed and used a
malware called usb steeler as early as
in 2005
and then followed 16 other frameworks
developed by other threat actors for a
grand total of 17
up to this day
and a few of these frameworks have been
attributed with pretty high confidence
to well-known threat actors such as dark
hotel mustang panda
but for others the attribution has been
less clear-cut or flat-out controversial
but regardless of the exact attribution
we can really state that they were all
product of nation state actors
hence the title of our research 15 years
of nation state efforts
so in our analysis we studied
all the existing reports are there and
we compare them based on several
properties with a specific focus on
those that are really tied to air gap
networks such as how does the malware
actually get executed on a system that's
on the air gap side of the network
and how does the malware establish a
communication channel with the attacker
to effectively jump
the the air gap and so for this we
formalized
the anatomy of air gap networks but from
really the malware perspective
and we came up with two distinct
categories connected and offline
frameworks so let me show you how that
looks like
so most frameworks belong to that
category the connected frameworks those
are built to provide fully remote
end-to-end connectivity over the
internet between the attacker and the
compromised systems on the air gap side
so we consider the target network as
having two sides separated by an air gap
so at the top you've got the connected
side where the systems have internet
connectivity
and at the bottom is the air gap side
that's where the attacker really wants
to get to
and that's a fairly typical setup
because people who work with airgap
system also need
the internet to do their regular
activity browsing the net getting emails
and naturally that connected system will
be the remote attacker's initial target
the point of entry if you will so
techniques used to gain control of that
connected system are not so interesting
they're similar to what we see in
everyday attack what differs is the type
of payload that gets deployed
so one thing that payload will do is it
will wait for a usb drive to be plugged
in and it will weaponize it that usually
means two things uh there was there
there will be a malware component that
will be copied on the drive and it's a
component a sample
that is meant to be really run on the
air gap sign and there'll also be a an
exit some sort of execution vector
something to launch or trigger the
malware to execute itself it can be an
exploit decoy document uh trojanized
software facundo here we'll be talking
about that in a bit more details later
on
so when the drive
the weaponized drive gets inserted in
the air gap system that's when the
execution vector
triggers and the system becomes
compromised
and that malware running on the air gap
side
will typically do some automated
reconnaissance and file stealing
activity
and copy all that data back on the usb
drive in real real funky ways
again facundo will give some some great
details later
so that's the exfiltration part from the
air gap system but that's not enough the
data needs still to reach the attacker
right and for that the drive containing
the data needs to be connected again on
the connected system
and the malware running there will
automatically extract the data and relay
it back to the attacker through
via the internet through some some sort
of c2 protocol
and all these steps will take place
automatically without any intervention
from the attacker um some some
frameworks are built just like that
everything is hardcore that but other
frameworks are more evolved and they
actually have a communication protocol
that allows the attacker to
interactively
exchange commands and responses with the
isolated systems
and so in these cases we'll really see
two distinct protocols
one that
goes over the internet that will connect
the attacker to the connected system and
another one that is between the
connected system and the air gap one
so the connected system really acts as a
proxy for the attacker
in other rare cases um the attack
scenario doesn't involve any connected
system on the on the victim's side
so we call these offline frameworks but
you can think of them as mission
impossible frameworks
because in these cases everything
indicates
that there's a presence of an operator
or or a collaborator on the ground to
perform some of the critical actions
such as weaponizing the usb drive or
even physically carrying the drive to
execute the payload and leave with with
the stolen data
and now i'll pass the mic to facundo
we'll give some details about
some pretty interesting https and just a
quick note it's fakundo's first ever
presentation so i hope you'll give him
some support
[Applause]
so as alexis said we focus on the
malware properties that are specific to
attacking their gap networks
we divided
into three broad categories older
techniques to execute the malicious code
for the purpose of gaining a foothold in
the network or conducting reconnaissance
of
potentially air-gapped systems
these strip categories are
automated execution non-automated
execution and only triggered
non-automated execution deliberately
performed
so let's begin with the automated
execution exploiting the remote
code execution vulnerabilities is one of
the most effective techniques to execute
the malware 11 such vulnerabilities have
been discovered and patched in the last
decade
and only two have confirmed use in the
wild
the most famous one is without a doubt
this tuxnet lnk exploit which only
required a user to view an lnk
files through windows explorer to
trigger the vulnerability
however it was later discovered by
gasperski researchers that the equation
group funny have been exploiting this
vulnerability
signs at least 2008
and even after malware released a batch
in 2010 funny gauss and mini flame
continued to use it for
five more years more or less
but science the discovery of this
malware no other
base exploit based
code execution has been observed in the
wild to compromise our gap networks
for our next category we take a step
back from the complexity of software
vulnerabilities and
instead we focus on the human factor and
deception tricks
in this scenario the aim is to trick an
unsuspecting user into executing the
malicious code
we have sell three techniques
one is the abuse of windows autorun and
how to play future
the planting decoy files to lure the
potential victims
and rigging
file existing files with malicious
code for example
that hotel ipt
retro malware
replaced
the world office documents with rtf
copies that contain an exploit that will
launch the malware on the system
and also run c by dark hotel would
uh infect
executable files in all of the drives
that were available so that's a kind of
old-school value stuff
usb but now
at least five of the 17 frameworks have
abused the autorun and autoplay in one
way or another
usb stiller and agent btc as well as an
earlier version of stuxnet
that implemented an outrun file that
contain both the executable and the
outer run instructions
it disabled the autoplay to force the
user to go to my computer or use the
entry in the navigation tree of windows
explorer
and with shell
with the shell dll it add an additional
open command
to the context menu that executed
stuxnet is the potential victim clicks
or double clicks on the drive shortcut
now mustang panda custom plugx malware
uses a much simple trick
it hides all the existing folders
in the drive and creates lnk files
for each one pointing to the malicious
executable in the cycle being folder
this technique
kind of preserves the appearance that
the drive is
clean
now perhaps the techniques under this
last category are the most puzzling
the analysis indicates that the
attackers did not intend for a user to
execute the malicious code but it
appears that the concept of operation
was to have a human asset covertly
execute the malicious components in the
target network
now how do you think as malware research
that we can
identify such a scenario
that's it
let's take in this interesting case of
usb corporate by the apt cycle that also
known as goblin banner hey mark
in this case the core the code running
on the connected site responsible for
weaponizing the designated usb drives
copies the malware for the air gap
system in a hidden folder on the drive
without any execution vector
the analysis indicates that the only
possible way for that malware to execute
it is someone knows exactly where the
malware is hidden and launches it
deliberately
and there is no indication that it is
part of an update mechanism on the air
gap side
now
in 2015 we discovered a malware on a
mission
something like this
we called it the usb tiff
at the time we could not attribute this
sophisticated malware to any known
groups
but it was until two years later when
the ball
seven leaks occurred that we began to
suspect that this malware was part of
the lambert's
apt group toolkit
new finance helped us to narrow down the
candidates in in this couples of of the
league to an implant code named
margarita
the description of of this system fits
both
this scenario and the capabilities that
we found on usb
the human asset let's call him tom will
weaponize the usb and create
circumstance
in the target machine in which he will
have to see certain files on the usb
drive
he will launch a notepad firefox so
truecrypts uh trojanize applications
and the software will in turn silently
load the malware and in the background
it prepared the data for exfiltration
finally on that note uh getting the
malware executed on the target just
one part of the mission
the collected information needs a way to
leave the air gap system and safely
reach the attackers
we will now present
what we consider some of the coolest
ways that the attackers have managed to
achieve this goal
so
going back to 2008
funny the funny malware sets they were
already too high for
even some of the most sophisticated
marvels that were developed after like
say flame gauze project sauron
and
at the same
the same time in the developed by groups
that are at the same
technical skill level
one of the funny most interesting
feature is the capability to create a
hidden storage
space in the usb drive that use a fat
file system remember that this malware
is a little bit old too
they achieved this by creating a
directory entry with a combination of
two attributes that make it
uh
that make it uh basically
invalid for for the parcel so when the
windows find such an entry it it is
ignored and essentially it is invisible
to to the user and basically to any
other tool
this entry contains an offset to located
an allocated space of almost one
megabyte in size which contains the
collected information as well as both
the the commands the modules and stolen
data and the result of executing these
commands
it's also worth noting that funny the
flame sorry uses a similar trick but
instead of creating this directory it
directly creates a file with an invalid
name that windows ignores because the
invalid name is just the dot
so that's nice that's a more optimized
technique
now
ramsay is a malware that we discover in
2020 and we attribute to their hotel as
i said
the attackers came up with a
decentralized way to spread the the
stolen information around the system
drives as well as the network and
removable
drives
when one c is executed into a following
process it will hook the close handle
api and when the hook is executed
it checks for the extension of the file
that was opened by the process
if it is a word document it will open a
special container that encapsulates
all the collected and compressed
information
this same container is also appended to
every word document that is found in the
available drive
currency
follows the same philosophy to receive
commands
it will look for other types of files
which might potentially have
appended another type of
con container with instruction to
execute
certain modules or
batch commands in the system
at a specific
target machine based on the gu id that
is only unique to every infected machine
now to alex
all right so how to defend against those
those types of attacks um so there are a
couple of proposals in our paper but if
you have to remember only one thing from
our talk
is that it's always always always about
usb drives okay there has been no
publicly reported cases where any other
physical medium
was used to jump the the air gap no
electromagnetic electromagnetic signals
no acoustic signals nothing is authentic
like that so just usb drives
so how to make it harder for attackers
to use that
those drives to compromise air gap
networks so
obviously physically disabling usb
drives on the systems that don't need
that don't require
that that connector
for the remaining systems where usb is
necessary
there are some policies that can be
implemented in windows
to disable file execution
when they come from remove removable
drives
and we can also think of implementing a
like a middle box that would sanitize
usb drives whenever they go back and
forth
between the the two network sides
and that that station could for example
remove unwanted file file types like lnk
and autorun files and perform an
anti-malware scan
of course that won't prevent
an attacker on on the ground to just not
or to bypass that policy uh but still
that uh that box would um would really
interfere with uh lots of attack tactics
we've seen uh used uh even recently
so that's how to defend um and since
many of us here are malware analysts um
i also wanted to share some some quick
tips or things to keep in mind uh when
analyzing that type of malware
and so remember that most frameworks are
connected and we'll have two distinct
components uh one running on the
connected side one on the air gap side
um so to get a full picture of the
attack you'll need to find and analyze
two different samples so if you only
have one chances are you're missing the
other one and you should look for it
and when you analyze one or one sample
you should try and determine quickly
which side the component is meant to be
executed in and understanding that early
on in the analysis will really help
focus your work and you'll have a better
understanding of of the whole attack
much much faster
now to identify a connected side
component
you can look for their three main
properties so the first one will be a
function to to go online and communicate
with a c2 obviously that's not really
specific
but at least it's going to tell you that
that
sample is not meant to be run on the air
gap side
second property there will be code to
weaponize usb drives
but careful
don't jump to conclusions because you
just you might just be analyzing a
simple usb worm that has nothing to do
with air gap system
and finally there will be code to read
the content of usb drives to extract the
exfiltrated data and then relay it back
to the attacker
as for the airgap side component the
main thing that will be present there is
code that will perform reconnaissance
and search for files to steal and of
course code that will write that data
back on the usb drive
and one thing that probably won't be
there is code that communicates with the
internet
and all that seems pretty um pretty
normal pretty basic but i still wanted
to uh to mention it today because so we
we read what 20 20 something reports
fakunder and i and in many cases some of
those key properties of the samples that
were described uh were just not
not described and it made the whole
understanding of how the attack took
place pretty confusing
so if you're about to write a report
i encourage you to pay attention to
these components into and to make sure
that they are described in your analysis
um and
in closing
so malware that attacks air gap networks
are challenging to analyze not only from
the technical perspective but also
because samples are hard to come by
air gap systems don't always
have nt malware solutions running and if
they do
by definition they won't be sending
telemetry back to vendors which creates
a huge blind spot for us
and at the same time attacks happen in
really sensitive networks
so victims are not likely to share
information with with researchers
or to make any
details of any attack public
and an example of samples that are hard
to come by that's
a good example is ramsey
the research started by
spotting a trojan eye 7-zip installer on
virustotal and we eventually determined
that that was the component
meant to run on the air gap side and
we start looking for the missing
component the other one that would be
running on the connected side and that
would parse the ramsey containers
extract the stolen data and give it back
to the attacker and
this is a real screenshot of our
internal wiki
and that task remains incomplete uh two
years after
after that that work
so who knows maybe that sample will
eventually come up and we'll figure out
how dark hotel really operates
the ramsey framework
so thank you all for your attention if
you ever come across
some some some malware you think is
targeting air gap networks don't
hesitate to reach out to us
i assure you we'll honor any tlp you
decide
and i know recently that there has been
a few incidents about tlp being breached
and some some trusted relationships were
a bit shaken
and it would be easy to just decide to
stop sharing all together it's much
simpler but that would really be a
mistake i think we just need even more
information sharing than ever
so there are many trustworthy people out
there trustworthy organizations so just
don't give up just yet thank you
[Applause]
we got a fan here
so you have a question
thank you hi pedro from midside so great
presentation thank you um
so there are and other many uh
fascinating ways to exfiltrate you know
data from air gap systems such as
acoustic
uh electromagnetic emissions air hopper
like like you said why do you think
we don't see that in the in the wild you
think it's
not really uh from the operational point
of view working or we just don't find
those samples
i can venture and answer um your guess
is as good as mine um
probably there are some i mean we're
just seeing the tip of the iceberg
what's being reported publicly right um
but on the other hand those techniques
they still have to be implemented by by
malware right so
we have quite a
i i think we have a good visibility as a
as a global community in malware and
malware specifically and if if we don't
discover it today we're going to
discover it later on
but but the point i wanted to make is
that
those techniques you mentioned
they make the headlines they make great
presentations at black hat and
everything and i think there's a lot of
attention being given to those
techniques
even though they haven't been seen in
the wall and even though even in recent
years
everything is going through usb because
usb works
i assume
so before like implementing a big
faraday cage around your air gap systems
make sure you tackle the usb problem
first and then move on to something more
complicated
thank you quick question how many of the
samples were targeted on on ot or scada
systems out of the 17 because a number
of the air-gapped systems or many of
them you will have the top secret blah
blah blah but another number of air gap
tip systems are the ones you spoke with
the power grids or power grid maybe not
but production and so how many of the
samples were targeted on ot or scada
systems
just one
i think
i think it's just
just sucksnet the so the goal of all the
16 others were clearly espionage file
stealing
only stuxnet had
let's say an operational
mission
although there was some file stealing
capability
but yeah
another question
vitaly left
um could we say that these attacks are
closely aligned to insider attacks
so for the cases where the um
the execution vector doesn't exist like
the one facundo mentioned where the
malware meant to be executed is hidden
and there's like there's no way
a normal user would know where to look
like would fall for it and execute it
inadvertently
in those cases yeah an insider job would
really make sense
but that's not the majority of the cases
especially
for the frameworks that are connected
where the whole chain starts from
remotely and then there's a
usb drive getting weaponized
so there are some cases yeah
it's pretty clear that there's someone
in the inside or someone on the outside
but kind of
breaking in and doing something bad
uh follow one question
what are the are there trends in the
data targeting mechanisms
so once you have this autonomous malware
on the air gap system it needs to
retrieve
data so are there data types that they
typically go after how does the
targeting system work do you see trends
in that
uh yeah it's mostly the basic basic
stuff they'll go after documents and in
some special cases they go after like
autocad files and that that type of
stuff
mainly there is no nothing much
surprising though it's let's say just
like other regular malware trying to
siphon all of the data that they can
and in in some cases the list of like
file extensions would be hard-coded and
there's no other way for the so
basically the attacker knew in advance
what files they wanted to go
to go for and and nothing more and um
like the case of a usb
steeler or so many usb
the the the apt-28 one
there was no way for the attacker to
request additional file extensions it
was a one-time thing these are the files
extract everything and move on
last question yeah up there
thanks a lot for the presentation
sarkari head of sir to you so just a
comment on the defense so one thing i
have seen implemented
to also try to defeat kind of like the
insider threat
is basically um when you like the
operator takes the usb drive from the
connected system he connects it to he
has to connect it to a different system
running for example linux
which kind of like images the drive then
pass it on to the air gap it system
and then afterward he has to plug it
back to the linux system again another
image and also see if there are
elements that have been copied from the
air gapped system and then plug it back
to the connected system
and
if the operator does not do that so
every day at the end of the day
there is a sysadmin who comes to the
linux box and check
also they have systems on the connected
system in the air gap system to match
the three entries and ensure there is
kind of like no gaps or something that
has been installed so this is kind of
like a variant on the anti malware or
sanitizer
that makes total sense and that would
break like probably all the attacks that
that we that have been documented yeah
so i see it implemented
once um in in real life and i think i
found that very neat it is very neat
yeah thank you for sharing you're
welcome
thank you
another question
one two
three okay thank you very much