you have the floor
thank you
so hi i'm daniel this is jeremy we both
work from fort on micro and we're very
glad to be here in real life for this
conference after two years of
pandemic and we'll present you the
result of our investigation that we name
operation gambling puppet
so this is the outline of the talk so we
will see some intentional infection
vectors
malware discussion discussion targeting
infrastructure et cetera et cetera
so it all started with a sample from
belonging to the x-nut malware family so
it targets linux operating system
and we found that the command control
server domain name was familiar to us
and actually it belonged to some
investigation we did two years ago named
operation derby control so this was a
targeted attack so it was interesting to
us
so we we searched a bit more we voted on
that so we found more samples
we found different malware families then
we found out different platforms were
targeted so actually windows on
macintosh
we figure out some of the targets of
this
attack some infection vectors etc etc so
we had a lot of material and we decided
we could do some paper so this talk is
the result of this investigation
so let's discuss the infection vectors
the first one is a chat application that
was offered through a website that you
can see here in the screenshot on the
left
the chat application was called mimi
which actually in chinese means secret
so this chat application was advertised
as being like secured application
and as you can see on the bottom of the
screenshot
it was offered for the windows on mac
platform on the website is written in
chinese
so when we look at the the application
itself we found out it was written
using the electron javascript framework
which is based on the node.js runtime so
this means it can run on different
platforms without changing the code
actually you just need to recompile it
and
sorry
sorry sorry
and then so there is a
one file that references the malicious
payload actually electronman.js file
and so if you can look at the excerpt of
this this code depending on the platform
it will run either the uso private
executable in the devs folder or if it's
darwin which means actually mac os
platform it will run during x64 on the
bottom of the screenshot you can see
the content of the devs folder on
windows platform
and actually you can recognize what we
just saw actually
the usual way of loading some plugix
malware family which is some legitimate
executable that will load
through dll side loading some malicious
dll that will actually decrypt the the
payload
which is the third file
so if we summarize this the target will
visit the chat application website
download the installer and depending on
the platform it will run either plugix
or some malware family in mac os
platform that we called orat that we
will see later
one thing to note about this
website is that you could register
through it either by email or by phone
on they were limiting the prefixes fund
numbers to some countries so this gives
an idea of what are the targets for this
trade tactor so you can see that there
is u.s and canada and all the others are
countries from southeast asia
the second infection vector we found is
a bit more complicated
it all starts with the tradactor that
will
first find a
legitimate website
and it will exploit a persistent
cross-site scripting vulnerability so it
will inject some javascript code in that
website
that code will be triggered when the
target visits the website and in this
case what the code does is it will load
a third-party javascript code from a
third-party server
which we call here here xss platform
it will also load some php script
and then after this code is run it will
redirect
the target to a final website which will
offer some fake flash installer
so if the target then falls for this
viewer and install the flash
fake installer it will get delivered by
a malware we saw this technique being
used for different malware families this
is why i don't specify which malware is
delivered because there were multiple
ones
actually the the crossroads scripting
display contains some call to display a
message so you can see here the message
you can see it's written in chinese
so the if you translate it it will be
just saying that the flash version is
too old
this was
kind of surprising for us that this
flash
trick is still used because flash is
supposed to be end of life since the end
of 2020 and then we found out that in
china there is an exception to this rule
and
actually adobe allowed a third party
editor to still
offer the flash installer in china so
this is interesting something that we
learned
so the script would do some checks
display this message and then call the
php script on redirect to this website
so this is what the final website looks
like again written in chinese offering
the adobe flash player
we think that this php script probably
collects some statistics about the bit
themes on in those that third-party
server that was hosting the javascript
on php script we we looked around and
found like an authentic authentication
panel
it can written in chinese so you can see
the top left
the xss ping tie message which means xss
platform and on the bottom
some message which is some disclaimer
actually in chinese
stating that this is a private access
platform and that there are other free
online xss platforms around
so what we believe is this platform
is some kind of
vulnerability platform that allows
actually the
transactor to scan for cross-site
scripting vulnerabilities in remote
legitimate websites
we found that two legitimate websites
were exploited
you could identify the first one
which was a website news websites aimed
at the chinese community
of a big u.s city
unfortunately we could not identify the
second website because it was an ip
address that saw no domain name and it
was offline at the time of we when we
checked
the third infection vector is a dmg file
which is some kind of installer for mac
platform
desktop
desktop actually not phone
mac and then
it contains some pre-installed scripts
so here you can see the script is very
simple it will just like download some
payload from a remote website and
execute it
and
we can note that the the file was named
bitget.dmg
and we found that bit get is a
singapore-based cryptocurrency exchange
application so this probably means that
it has some relation to the
targets
so we let jeromiel discuss the malware
now
so in this section we will talk about
malware toolkit
so this thread actor was very active and
they used like all three major
they used malware for all three major
platforms which means like for
windows linux and mac
some of these malware families are known
or has been previously used either by
some other groups or they are
publicly available on github for example
so this is the list of
the known families on windows in this
presentation we will not go through the
known families we will focus on the new
ones the custom ones but we plan to
publish sooner or later the paper and
blog post there will be some details
even about related to these families so
for known windows mulberry families
they're like plug x we've heard about it
today to ghost threat kabul strike and
others
quasarat was mentioned
for the new families which some of them
we will talk about today was the puppet
loader puppet downloader overat
another mfc downloader and hello bot we
will talk a little bit later about them
under linux known malware families like
xnode hellobot papyrat
reptile rootkid hiding like one of these
previously mentioned families
and for mac we found like one
compiled under mecco mac os which is
called orat originally written in golang
but it can be compiled under different
platforms so let's start with i would
say the most interesting malware family
used by this trajectory which we named
puppet loader
why puppet loader because there had been
like string as you can you can see in
this small screenshot below have been
like a string directly found
in in within the malware so the outer
authors themselves call it puppet loader
it is a custom malware it has five
stages the lightest stage is the
backdoor itself
and it uses for encryption somehow
flawed rc4 implementation
so when i talk about these stages so it
starts with stealthy loader
which loads
in a stealthy way a dropper this dropper
drops
basic loader which is the third stage
then it drops one bmp file like bitmap
file but in
in
to this bitmap file there is attached
there are attached some encrypted data
with core
and another bitmap file with another
attached data with the another stage
then the basic loader decrypts and loads
this
core from the bitmap with core
and the core decrypts and loads the main
client
so these are all these five stages
i mentioned that there is something with
flawed rc4 implementation
so how
how it was implemented so in the right
there is there is the code for
pseudorandom
generation
and
the most important part is the swap
functions
swap function and the swap function is
implemented in the in the five steps in
in the table on the left it's kind of in
a strange way like they have like
temporary value then they assign the sum
of like two locations because it wants
to it wants to
swap
locations from table with offset i and j
so it use some sum
then some
some subtraction and so on
so if you want to go like step by step
so in the left there will be the table
which i showed you before and in the
right table are the actual values so you
can see on the right there is originally
s i and sj values
s i is red sj is green and after all
these five operations or the steps the
the
red should be in the right column and
the the green should appear in the left
column so after the first operation you
can see the temp value is sum of these
values after the step two s i equals to
some of the values
after the third step temp is equal to
s i
then
then the second column that sj is
assigned the original si value and in
the last step which you can see that
that these two two values are swapped so
it seems to work
what happens if i and j are equal
so in the first step temp is assigned
the double
the double value of i because i points
to the same place as j
so s i plus s j
equals 2 times s i
in the second step s i is assigned the
stem value so the s i as j and temp
is now equal
all of them are equal the same value
which is 2 times s i
then it gets then it gets subtracted so
suddenly temp value is zero
and later everything is zero
so what so what happens for the internal
stage of the rc4 cipher our this
internal stage should be permutation of
all the numbers from 0 to ff and each
number should be there exactly once so
you can see here
in the in with this arrow the left is
sorry the left is the stake before
and the right is after so there is like
one zero here and one zero stays here
but also when when it wants to swap
this value to c so after the swapping
this 2c becomes zero so suddenly there
are two zeros and the longer this
process runs the more zeros appear in
this internal stage and after long run
they're almost all zeros so
the the encryption like doesn't work
so we have seen this this weird
implementation or this flawed
implementation also in like two more
malware families one was this puppet
downloader and one was like some
userland rootkit from tigerplug
now let's talk a little bit about puppet
loader and talk a little bit more about
these five stages so the first stage was
the stealthy loader
so it hooked several functions from
ntdll
and then also used some undocumented
ntdls functions
to avoid recursive hooking problems
these are like rtl push pop and get
frame
this frame is some data structure
pushed on the stack and it contains some
pointers too to some buffers
it can be the buffer with the payload
buffer with name of the files
size of the payload and there can be
some open handles and so on
then
the the loader tries to load like one
legitimate func legitimate dll in this
case it it's called asic field.dll it's
some some file from
windows system 32 directory
then hooked anti-open file replaces this
asic field with
lz32.dll
then hooked create section
changes the size of the created section
to correspond the size of the malicious
payload then the hooked
nt-map view of section function
again changes the size of the payload
and copies malicious payload into the
file and then antiquary sec then hooked
antiquary section
will compute the difference between
actually loaded the
image base and preferred image base
it and when it is not at the preferred
image base that it returns this this
error that status image noted base
and the loader rebases and loads
the
dependencies
so the stealthy loader loads in a way
that
if you parse this peb ldr data structure
it tells you that asic filled the dll
file was loaded if you run process
monitor it tells you that lz32dl was
loaded but in reality in the reality
none of them was loaded it would be
malicious payload
which is in this case the second stage
the dropper
the dropper drops just dll file and two
bitmap files
so nothing interesting here
this the third stage is the basic loader
which searches for previously dropped
bitmap files these bitmap files are as
you can see here very small
like 30 33 times 11 pixels with an
overlay there are encrypted
encrypted uh
next stages it decorate it decrypts them
runs them
stage four is core which runs
logging thread
which
locks all the information about about uh
progress of running the
the puppet loader
and they're like list of supported
command line arguments you can notice
that sometimes the right typos like
instead of invoke there is in oak
and so on
fifth stage is the main backdoor
supporting the main like typical big
door functions
cnc communication
is via udp udp
and again rc4 encryption the flawed
encryption
and the key is here
here randomly generated and sent within
the data stream
now we will continue with another
interesting malware which is orat
written in golang we have seen it
compiled under windows and mac
it has some configuration which is
in overlay which is encrypted after
decrypting you can see the information
like local
like type of encryption
cnc encryption cnc address
if it is used as traffic forwarder or
not
it runs the local server so the the
attacker has to or can
connect directly to this to the infected
machine
and issue the commands
it uh it's implemented via something
called the registered routes so
there are like these are the list of
paths which are supported
by the back door
and the threat actor basically goes to
this for example to the
url address slash agent slash info to
get information about the machine he
wants for example screenshot and he
calls
slash agent slash screenshot and so on
and on the right there is the example
like in in golang how simple it is to
to write
this type of code
also we will i will mention like two two
families for linux which are somehow
interesting these are like xnode and
hellobot they are like not new they have
been seen before or reported before not
not reported to used for espionage
features
espionage
goals
they are they have also like typical red
features but for us what is interesting
they are interesting
configuration files which are usually
simply encrypted with with xor
they contain lots of simplified chinese
commands and then they also contain some
identifiers on some notes usually
related to gambling
also like one interesting thing about
these two families is that
there is like one one special file with
this strange name
and it tells that
that the machine is already infected by
x node but when this is
but when this is noticed by the hello
bot the hellobot runs this command f
user minus k something which
which finds out which processes are are
opening or touching this file and if it
finds them the
the hello bolt kills the instances so it
shows that either either before the
thread actor used
used x note and then updated to hello
both and wanted to kill the previous
instances or there's some
competition for for the resources with
maybe some other group
so now let's talk a bit about the
targets
so we used three sources to find targets
first one was of course our telemetry
but also we used the previous malware
configurations that we discussed
and we also found some key logs that
were generated by malware related with
this traductor and we found them in the
wild so we could analyze them
so quick word about the telemetry
the
we got more hits coming from china
actually there were downloads of the
fake flash downloader
but we also found some hits from the us
but we know that they all came from that
legitimate website which was actually
oriented to our chinese community
on the other heats were from hong kong
malaysia on taiwan
then about the the key logs that we
could analyze we could identify some of
the victims based on some of the content
of those keylock files
and so they we found two chinese
gambling
companies websites actually on one
malaysian hosting provider
and the last the configuration files as
you mentioned there were some kind of
campaign identifiers or notes and we
found some of some words that might
refer to the targets or the campaign
a few examples for example there's yabo
which is a
huge gambling website
same for
w88 there is some gameworks that might
be actually changing based gaming
company etc etc
so
the targets are mainly in china but also
in some other southeast asian countries
and u.s
we found out the main targeted industry
is gambling but not limited to that so
we've also found one company in
education two companies in i.t services
and one company in electronics
manufacturing
so now let's discuss about the
infrastructure
so i say here it's a big infrastructure
so i think this is in terms of apd
groups because this morning we saw
infrastructure that were like thousands
thousands of
servers so this is kind of ridiculous
but in apt it's quite big like 50 cncs
and if we you look at the domain names
we could find related subdomains so more
than 150
and there is also like 12 different uh
remote access tool families so which
means the protector has to set up 12
different back end so the controllers as
well mentioned before so this is like a
lot of work to maintain all of this
we can note that many of those domain
names
have their ip address hidden by
cloudflare
and in some cases we found that
multiple subdomains of one single root
domain were linked to different malware
families so let's see an example of this
so
there is the github.wiki
website which actually
has this those subdomains there are more
than that but for the example we will
just limit to these four subdomains
so if you go to that github.wiki page
actually we'll
land on some
page that contains legitimate github
documentation so we found out it's an
exact copy of the docs.heatup.com
website
but then
so this probably is to to
lured uh any i don't know analyst that
will go to this website maybe it will
flag this domain as uh legitimate but
then we found some
malware sample from hellobot that
was talking actually to a sub-domain of
github.wiki so this was malicious of
course we found that this other
subdomain delivered some alright malware
sample
which had the cnc to a third subdomain
on this same
deal.github.wiki delivered a papyrite
malware sample which talked to a default
subdomain of github.wiki so you can see
this is like kind of complex
infrastructure
we even found another subdomain of
github.wiki that if you go there you
will find this like malware panel
so it was quite interesting
so a quick note also about the domain
names
so if you are like me and don't speak
chinese you will just look at this and
say okay that's like seems like regular
regular domain names
but in fact if you translate them or you
talk to some colleagues that speak
chinese
you'll find out that dash eight means
actually a big dick
that what's unima
means i your mother and shabi means
so
yeah we were wondering
is the protector trying to pass some
kind of message or something yeah we
don't really know what's the purpose
maybe he's a frustrated teenager we have
no idea but it was quite funny to find
this out
i know a word also about attribution
so this is always tricky of course so
what we can say with high confidence is
that the tradactor speaks chinese
language
because there is like this xss platform
it was actually we found out in the html
code for this platform that it was
downloaded from a chinese forum the
panel itself is written in chinese the
malware panel is in chinese a lot of the
crypt decrypted configuration files are
in chinese etc etc so we saw all of this
in the the bottom you can see the
screenshot of the controller we found
and the the title is again chinese like
home delivery master controller so this
we can say we had confidence
but we also found links to non-groups
and
every person that work on chinese
traders know that it's a mess actually
so let's see an example of this mess
i
said that it all started with one
subdomain actually shoppingchannel.net
which was linked to our previous
investigation operation drb control in
this investigation the tradactor used
the hyperbrow malware family and as far
as we know this malware family is only
used by the iron tiger attacker also
known as apt-27 or emissary panda so
this is what first link that we we have
second link is that xnode malware family
actually in the report from dr webb from
2015 they attribute this malware family
to chinese
group
and this group
we found an integer blog post that
attributes this group to operation
operation pizza ciao which is some white
paper but
i think this link is based on some
encryption key for some ghost rat sample
and this operation visit chair was
actually also also attributed to iron
tiger so we have two links to this
trajectory but we have another totally
different link
so we found actually one of the plugix
dlls was signed by a stolen certificate
from the gravity company which is some
south korean company i think
and
this company was mentioned in a blog
post from co-intelligence
that linked this
compromising but to the winning ti group
so we have another link to another known
trade actor we also this blog post
actually also mentions a blog post from
eset where they also mention
some malwares linked to with nti
and they
think that gravity might be one of the
compromised companies that are
displaying that blog post mentioned in
that blog post also for the record
operation derby controller also had some
links to win nti actually because we
found one ip address that if you look at
the passive dns data contain a domain
name that was also attributed to winning
ti so
as you can imagine this is all really
messy
so we decided that okay these are some
links that we we want to
mention to the community but we prefer
to just take another
our own transactor and so it will be a
new name i think it's earth berber rock
or something like that that the one will
remember of course
but whatever so
in conclusion
this is an advanced trait actor
so we showed that the infrastructure is
big they have a lot of development
capabilities because they have some new
malware families that are complex they
have to maintain all of these back ends
so they have a lot of different malware
families used
they target three different platforms
and the targeting is mostly but not
limited to gambling english industry
and we we show some links to some known
chinese protectors some maybe last thing
we we have to mention is that gambling
is uh very is regulated in china so it
might
make sense for
these countries to try to like see which
companies are in the gray zone or not
complying to the rules or something like
that so
yeah on the i think our blog post will
be published probably now
uh it will be just an excerpt of the
windows model analysis and i think the
full blog post with all the other
analysis will publish maybe in two weeks
something like that
so thank you and if you have any
questions
thank you
okay is there any question
in the room about
gambling puppets
yeah over
there hello uh thanks for the great
presentation
uh
my question would be
it seems that a lot of the tools you
described and definitely the activity
has
this
state nexus sense that i guess we could
all guess where it's coming from
um
but i guess my question is um whether
you think there's like actually a
financial motive behind this operation
and whether that could be
some kind of a criminal uh syndicate
that branches out of those
otherwise state-sponsored uh
actors
i don't believe there might be some
financial motive because uh well we did
not find for example any coin miner or
stuff like that and also because the
previous produce investigation operation
the op control
in that case we found that they were
after the databases coming from those
gambling websites
so my personal opinion is that maybe
it's more related to getting information
about the customers of those websites
maybe
but honestly we don't have the the proof
for that so this is like my own feeling
maybe you should get a mic
yeah i'm sorry for asking so many
questions today but
excellent guys um i was curious like you
mentioned that they use this app that
fake app bit get right yes and you you
kind of said that it kind of suggests
which uh where the the targets are right
and bitget is the
the one that has been developed maybe
used in singapore somehow right
i said
so it's related to the the targeting but
not i don't say bit get got targeted or
actually we don't have the inflection
vector for this this uh how it was
delivered we don't know yeah i
understand maybe not the not the
developer of bit yet but you suggested
that this is linked to singapore and
maybe the targets could be there as well
right so yeah like like in china in
singapore uh online gambling is actually
restricted it's a criminal offense
so there's probably no none or maybe
like low targets when it comes to online
gambling however bitcat is uh the
application used for uh cryptocurrency
and crypto assets trading so i wonder if
you sell any access to
uh the cryptocurrencies businesses being
targeted within this campaign or none at
all
honestly no we did not see that but but
yeah we have limited telemetry and yeah
maybe we missed something it cannot be
excluded that they are directed to
over there
it's the last question
hello really nice talk just
one question when i've looked at the
configuration that you show in the
slides of some of the malware they were
communicating directly outside of a
network on some non-standard port
which usually is not exactly usually is
not
something that will go nice in the
company if you are
you mean this screenshot yes exactly so
is it targeting individual on
non-protected network or is it
targeting
people inside the company
like
yeah
we we don't know but we had no hits on
this
specific marble family so we we don't we
don't found any alright hit in our
telemetry so we cannot say uh who was
targeted by this
stuff but but it was delivered actually
by um one of the infection vectors i
mentioned so
yeah but i think we are right if
they must be targeting probably some
network which
doesn't like filter this on typical port
because like i agree if these ports are
blocked then
it wouldn't work for them so
it
must be like it must confirm what you
are saying
okay
okay thank you very much