all right yep you are
I'll give your quick intro suspect errs
here he his talk is car hacking a
college students perspective in this
presentation Nikhil will provide an
overview of targets and show some car
hacks will also go through common tools
we can all use to accomplish our goals
so yes thank you so much everyone for
sticking with us this is the last talk
of level up and we're ending on a good
one so take us away Neko excitement yeah
Jason if it did you wanted to jump in
I'm sorry about that no no I was just
hurting out I'm super excited about the
talk well thank you yes I'm I'm Nika I'm
you know 23 college student I hacked
cars and I've you know I've done a bunch
of private bug bounties with Jason and
Sam they know me and a couple of my
friends kind of well because I I'm
always trying to bring people out and do
carking stuff with me so uh hope you
guys enjoy so you know before we start
there are a couple of things that you
should not do and one of those is uh you
know don't go out and steal cars after I
teach you how to steal cars cool so um
you know a couple of things please play
with your own toys share as much
information as possible it's super
useful for the community
do not break NDA's while sharing
information um as a lot of that is
involved in bug bounties and such as
previous people have said but you know
trying to be like as general as possible
help people reach out you guys can
always reach out to me or my friends um
we're always trying to get more people
interested in car acting it's really fun
and people always come with new in
different perspectives so it's always
good to have and you know most
importantly have fun while doing it
because car hacking is one of the most
rewarding experiences you can have the
yeah a little bit about Who I am my name
is Nico my handle is specters uh I am
currently studying cybersecurity I
wouldn't say I am like a full-fledged
hacker yet because I still have a lot
that I can improve on personally but you
know that's always a goal right so I'm
always working
towards and trying to meet my own
personal goals to say like I am now a
full-fledged hacker I skateboarded my
spare time
my OPSEC is complete garbage so uh you
know one of those goals I have to meet
um and once again at cars for fun so
what's this talk about um mostly it's
going to be about like hacking cars on a
tight budget because when I first got
into this um I was obviously in college
I have a bunch of loans that I need to
pay off for school so you know I didn't
have a lot of money at the time so there
are ways to get around these issues by
you know building your own hardware
using open-source tools there's a ton of
things out there and we're gonna go over
a little bit of those in the slide as
well as like more expensive tools that I
eventually adopted um as I was getting
like more and more bounties submitted so
I'm more specifically we're gonna go
over car basics we're gonna go through
my personal methodology of hacking into
cars which we'll touch on later after we
go into getting initial access I'm gonna
talk about tools I'm gonna talk about
software and then I'm going to tell you
guys how you can get on to cars and then
maybe after that I have a little bit of
time to possibly show a usable simulator
and like how to get onto the canvas how
to drop root shells on IOT devices and
like radio systems so go over that in a
minute so uh recommended knowledge these
are not required because I definitely
don't know all of these but uh it will
help you in just car hacking and in
general right so you always want to keep
learning so having a basic basic
understanding of how car works and how
it operates
um because then you can like choose
specifically what you want to target
like nobody's gonna care if you change
the tire sensor value or like the air
pressure value of your tires to zero on
a car it's like Oh whoo
you're making alerts happen on the
system but you know people are gonna
care if you like legitimately like maybe
a mess around with the trends and it
breaks something because that'll be like
a big issue after that so we're gonna go
over uh well I mean
having an understanding of like just
different protocols like ADB SSH tell
that being able to reverse engineer is a
really big one that I personally am
struggling with that I'm always trying
to build on um a lot of car systems use
different programming languages it's
it's pretty much all over the place in
terms of development some use like an
Android front-end or like an Android
like system and then some will use like
some random Linux kernel rights like for
example Tesla uses a food to
mind-blowing write they write their own
C C++ code to run their own personalized
software's which is also really cool so
we're gonna go over car basics as you
could probably tell cars have computers
I know right whoo so this is actually an
ECU so an ECU is pretty much a car's a
way of handling different types of
messages between sensors it's like the
liaison between those two so this will
pretty much direct each sensor where to
go how to respond this stores all of its
uh sensor information and you can pretty
much like reprogram different cars and
different sensors with this did you mean
introduction to e C's as you can see
these are like a Diagnostics center
right in the center that is an ECU and
this communicates with you know exhaust
gas oxygen sensors tons of things so you
know there could be hundreds of sensors
in a car that you can mess around with
engine control unit is what ECU means
and it has two-way communications so you
can actually have a center receive
values for all of this so that's really
cool because if I send uh let's say a
value to unlock the doors well now I
just got into the car now I'm stealing
the car right so you know there's here's
an example of pretty much a canned
message that we have up here
so pretty much uh like you could have
multiple sensors in a single can message
and this value right here which is one
two three is that specific sensor and
then these values control something on
that specific sensor so that specific
sensor can be used for one part of the
car but it controls multiple things on
that so you know like engine oil right
so it could tell you the levels of
engine oil it can tell you the heat and
a couple of other values that would be
mixed in there as well so car radios are
also computers very interesting I know
this is actually an Android auto system
that I personally want to build but
people have already built out so really
easy to set up you can buy Raspberry Pi
you can buy a screen and you can start
practicing like messing around with some
of the like kernel stuff that you could
do once you get an initial foothold onto
the system so what type of systems do
infotainment systems run and
infotainment systems by the way our car
radio sorry if I get a little confusing
first off we've Android made by Google
so it follows a couple of Google
standards which is pointed out by one of
my friends buses can fly Q and X which
is surprisingly made by blackberry
it's a Linux sub kernel really
interesting and used on a ton of cars so
you know definitely uh you could
download it for free online like a
developer version you could start
messing around with that do we have
Windows automotive
it's alright I i I've seen cars habit
and they have very silly things
associated with them but uh hopefully
that could flush out in the future and
then we have a boon tube which obviously
I think by now everyone knows that Tesla
cars have a up into uh you know a Linux
distribution on to their infotainment
systems like the giant pad screen what
protocols are on all these systems glad
yes uh first off we've Google our we
have a TB on Android so a TB is pretty
much how you can drop local shells for
debugging Android information or to like
add programs do a couple of things a lot
of people who are hacking Android
devices will pretty much drop ADB shells
onto these devices and then like you
know send pools to get a apk files or
something of that sort right pretty much
again applications and things like that
or to mess around with the kernel a
little bit um SSH very common protocol
it's used to just remote in sometimes
it's
locally within the car or it could be
externally over like you know GSM why
fire anything else right uh
like it can be over like a telephone
network Q and X also has SSH windows
surprisingly has RDP and SSH abouttwo is
SSH and obviously everyone's favorite
all of them have telnet which is
sometimes really ridiculous it's almost
like developers specifically want to
pick on you can those security people
and they're like where did you use an
outdated version of telnet and it's
gonna drop straight into a root shell
which is something I saw on Twitter
recently with a another car that had
like a Windows distribution on it so I
was also really cool a couple the
interfaces so once again we have Wi-Fi
USB LTE GSM all these like wireless ways
to get into the cars I've seen stuff
over HDMI um I've seen Tesla's own like
Ethernet to weird adapter type port um
so there's a tons of tons of different
ways that you could like mess around
with the interfaces on cars and a lot of
cars have really interesting things like
associated with them so I've seen
examples of interesting interfaces like
you could tap a corner of the screen
four or five times and it would open up
a show and it would just give you root
access to a car and like that's
something that a lot of vehicle
manufacturers are like looking out for
now so you won't see it as much but
these things still exist out in the
world so my methodology well we're gonna
talk about goals first so what are some
of the goals that you want to accomplish
um just getting you know actually want
to light a car on fire um but I'm sure
if you did you would make tons of money
like tons of hush money because uh they
would be like don't tell anyone ever
um oh yeah so the goal is either
compromise user data so we pretty much
want to like jump on to let's say an
Android system and start messing around
with you know the users personal
information like where they live where
they're going what are the last three
places they visited what's their current
GPS location these are all things you
can do inside
some of these radio systems as I you can
totally just like docks that person and
find out everything about them if you
could do that remotely that's like a big
deal to a lot of people um just because
like you could start tracking very
important people so another thing is you
can try to gain access to one of the
many car computers so getting external
access to ECU's wireless access to ECU's
pretty much means that you have a way
that you can damage the car um in some
cases there are firewalls that try to
prevent this but if you can circumvent
that firewall that's also another big
bounty that like you just got for
yourself um so you know there's a
standard out in the u.s. of allowing
engineers and like local automotive
shops to be able to read data from the
ECU's um so this comes with you know
obviously games and applause alright
like you're letting a ton of people be
able to rebuild cards do everything with
cars that they need to you but you're
also giving them partial access to the
cars computers and this becomes an issue
just like when someone says it ECU reset
to the car there are some functionality
you can lose if somebody's like in the
middle of driving you hack their car
radio and you send that message um so
it's always really interesting things to
look at so getting remote or local route
on an infotainment system uh once again
this goes with the other two things
which is if you gain its if you jump
onto a radio system to get use your data
or if you jump on there to send messages
to the car specifically um you're pretty
much gonna be able to control the car in
multiple ways excuse me so if you can
find a way to make it easier to steal a
car such as unlocking doors and starting
a car that's also a big deal um a lot of
companies will look at that and be like
okay there's gonna be like you know a
big publicity around this or people are
gonna start stealing cars and you know
certain areas or you know all over the
place um or they're just gonna do for
fun right like this is these are things
that companies will think about and just
in terms of car aking if you can hack or
clone key fobs this is like also you
deal just because you could potentially
clone or you could like hack the entropy
to some key fobs and you could just
start unlocking all the certain like
specific cars that were made by the
specific company um also very big deal
you don't want that so you definitely
don't want that information shared oh
yeah so these are some of the goals that
you know as hacker myself I'm trying to
accomplish while I'm hacking cars so how
do we uh how do we practice this um it's
kind of hard for myself as a college
student to be like hey I'm just gonna go
buy this car and start doing research on
it which you know that's a legitimate
thing that people can do um you can
borrow a friend's car I've had multiple
instances so far where I was interested
in Tesla hacking and I had somebody
reach out to me that was like hey um I'm
you know I'm interested in adding these
binaries to my Tesla I will let you hack
my car if you can help me try to figure
this out and you know like dropping root
shells on Tesla's is cool and being able
to just hack that car is just such a
great experience that I can go like use
it somewhere else um you know obviously
you could buy the car there are
researchers that will like legitimately
like rent the car buy the car park it in
there likes garage and then just sort of
like doing stuff on it I have access to
a garage because I'm friends what I'm
like a local automotive person so he
lets me use his garage to like lift cars
mess around with it sometimes and then I
get to like take that research go home
usually I just like read can messages
and then replay them at home to try to
figure out like you know which Seuss's
became us to just work with specific
sensors and things like that um you can
buy parts that you think are exploitable
so you know you could buy ECU's online
and you could buy radio infotainment
systems online just a quick google
search of the specific year make and
model of the car and then what part it
is and then you just go on eBay or you
go anywhere else you could just buy it
um ECU's usually range like anywhere
from that need to like two to three
hundred dollars right so buying one is a
little bit harder but uh to circumvent
that you just go to a junkyard this is
my favorite thing to do you just go to a
junkyard and you rip one out and then
you try to convince the person that
you're you know bartering with because
you know ECU's are a common thing that
people just take from junkyards um and
you can just like be like hey you know
I'll buy this a piece of metal for $20
you know trying to convince if you're
gonna scrap it or something
but it works more often than not which
is usually a really fun time so a couple
of the tools we use though I
there's tons of tools out there um
obviously I'm not going to mention all
of them in this slide I am going to
however mention like a couple Oh teach
cheap ones that I like personally
so just for communicating with the can
bus or the obd2 port we have the
contacts the Knable Minton net who is a
another researcher that made his own
hardware if you meet him I think you can
actually just ask him for one of his
business cards he might give you one for
free
might have to convince him um and then
he'll tell you how to like create the
hardware great researcher great dude
knows what he's doing um value can is
another one value can is made mostly for
window systems and like they have like
other versions of the value can that can
work with like Linux kernels and stuff
but pretty much it's it's a little bit
more expensive but you get the nice
software package with it that pretty
much gives you like ease of use easier
functionality easier setup it gives you
like a whole really nice GUI where you
don't have to really type a lot of
commands so if you're trying to it may
be like an introduction of car hacking I
know that intrepid systems goes to
DEFCON and they reduce the price of
their value can stuff you can go and
like buy one there you can go to a local
con maybe that intrepid zet and try to
buy one off of them other than that on
the website that's listed for $150 and
up depending on which version you get
and they're really good I personally use
one I like it a lot um the new USB
toucan is out actually too so it's $69
um I bought one recently and I really
like it it works well um once again just
some of these things are a little bit
expensive if you're really just trying
to get an introduction to car hacking
and you kind of just want to like read
messages from a car and maybe mess
around with it a little bit I would
really suggest the can table very small
very lightweight
very easy setup gives you the whole
guide online and everything about it is
super simple uh some key fob hardware if
you're trying to like clone or hack like
you know radio frequency stuff or like
car keys itself you could buy proxmark
proc smarts to like do a close range
attacks on them you could buy like blade
RFS or hack RFS or yardsticks to like
try to intercept messages you're doing
like rolling jams or things like that
most of the time people will intercept
messages and try to figure out how these
keys are doing these challenges in
response and these are all good tools to
use um once again though all of these
are really expensive I think all of
these are like a hundred plus dollars so
if you wanted to you could probably get
an SDR and still accomplish the same
goal you just have to make sure it's
under uh I think like one Giga heard to
uh be able to like read some of the
values you're like five hundred Meg's I
think is around usually what those
values are maybe a little higher or
lower from there yeah so some of the
software we use for all UNIX ah UNIX and
Linux distributions um so for the RF key
stuff we have RF cat um I've seen some
great vulnerabilities get exposed with
this tool I've seen a bunch of crypto
stuff get cracked with this tool uh a
lot of great things have been
accomplished with this tool so I really
enjoyed that one there's a bunch of
other tools and there's a repo of a
awesome like car hacking stuff on github
which is also really great to look at
hacking Android tools uh obviously you
just want to get Android tools for ADB
access if you're gonna hack a can bus
you can use scape II which is like an
open-source Python repo that pretty much
lets you craft your own types of packets
and you could communicate to and from
the car with that tool um very cool it
supports can didn't know that until
recently can utils which is pretty much
a already written like it's like a repo
pretty much like C code that
communicates with the canvas so you have
like canned dump which will display a
bunch of things can player which can
actually replay log files from can dump
specifically can send which can send
single and multiple messages can gen
which
you can actually brute-force a bunch of
specific sensors and stuff and sniffer
which gives you a nice like display to
view all these messages messages so to
get o to pretty much set up we have sake
cannon nestled kin which is uh
dependencies that you're going to need
so you need the daemon for some kin
interfaces and stuff which comes with
kin utils I think it just comes
precompiled on the SE package once you
set it up Doe software for Windows once
again you have RF cat because it's open
source it should work on both may take a
little bit more setup you have can't act
the application which is a prebuilt
application that you just download on
your computer and then you use it to you
communicate stuff I can utils once again
which has all those other C code tools
Wireshark actually reads canned stuff as
well because it communicates over serial
though and you can plug right into USB
you can also download ADB for Windows
computers giving you shells that you can
drop on to you know Android systems we
have vehicle spy which is like the
really nice version that intrepid owns
and this like this is like a free trial
for it pretty much but this is one of
the easier systems so if you've had more
money and you wanted to car hack a
little bit easier replay messages easier
and stuff you have vehicles Y that you
can pretty much use once again cost
comes with ease of use right so um then
we have scape II again which you can
craft your own messages and just
communicate what's things so what I
carry on me personally I have a value
can for Windows with vehicle spy I think
I have version for um so it specifically
only works for Windows I have not
figured out how to set up the Linux
driver that they had for it I think it
is online gonna have to ask somebody
later cane table once again this was
like my quick easy introduction to car
hacking with that especially when I like
wanted to switch over to more
open-source tools I use that minty nets
nano can and he has another tool but uh
the ESP like 32 can communicate
device which is listed on the right
those are some pictures of that tool I
carry a USB 2.0 cable Taipei to Taipei
and pretty much that's just like if cars
have USB there's some cases where you
plug into that USB and it'll like trying
to assign you an IP or it you know has a
shell that you could run through through
ADB um tons of different things that you
can do just to get onto system so I also
have USB to Ethernet which once again
the president Lee some cars have IP is
being assigned over USB stuff so what
you connect up to it it just you can
like scan a bunch of stuff and then try
to drop shells
I also carry a logic analyzer there's a
couple online that are really cheap only
like a couple of dollars uh let's see
which one do I have oh it's in Chinese
pretty much I like one on eBay or like
Alibaba and bought mine I think I
ordered mine for eight dollars it was
two dollars shipping and handling so ten
they were from ten to fifteen dollars in
total um really good tool really good to
have I really want to get a say Lee won
but stop willing to spend that much
I carry a soldering iron I carry pins
wires solder obviously and I carry you
are two USB which is used for hardware
hacking um and then I also carry two
laptops one Linux and one Windows I
specifically use peridot us because it
just comes with all the tools that I
need for carking precompiled but I have
also used like pen two in the past which
is a Gen 2 security distribution um I
just like hated my life when I tried to
compile anything else especially drivers
so I stopped using it so some of the
canvas basics
so pretty much we have a DW Ken which is
a dual wire Ken
so essentially what we're gonna do is
we're gonna take two wires we're gonna
plug them into specific ports and that
should give us Ken messages so as you
can see isone are not yeah
iso fifteen seven six five minus four is
pretty much the can hi can low port
switch is used on most vehicles um so
essentially you could just take two
wires you could plug them in and then
you can start you know doing a
numeration you can get a logic analyzer
and analyze some of the can messages i'm
they're just really cool and then these
are just like grabs explaining how they
work there's a lot of things involved
with can and there's a lot of different
ways that it communicates so don't take
this graph and like think it's just
gonna work instantly some cars have
security systems in place to try to
prevent you sending T X messages right
which is a transmitted messages or you
know some cars will have specific like
values you'll need to send just to
receive messages right so so this one
it's a little bit more complicated these
are pretty much the structure of ten
messages so here in the top right image
on the left side we have first off the
start of the frame which is almost
always gonna start with the zero and
then we have the arbitration field the
arbitration field is pretty much like a
sensor ID so essentially when we go into
the arbitration field and we're looking
at it but we add up these ones and zeros
and we come back with a sensor specific
sensor that can control you know who
knows what
unless it's listed somewhere in
documents after that we have RTR which
is remote transmission request which I
personally haven't used and that's
usually always set to zero for me as
well um but there are cases where you
could use them and that's listed in like
like CSS electronics or you can go to si
use website and read the standard for
those we have control fields which
pretty much just tells you like the
length of the message that you're about
to get or send we have the data field
which is all your sensor values so like
if you had FF which is 255 you're pretty
much telling this Pacifica Center it's
you go to max value or to do something
right and most of the time when ECU's
are programmed usually programmed to do
like a greater than x value or their
program to meet a specific value so
doing FF on like fuzzing with ffs is
sometimes really good and could just be
quick to identify some card utilities
like what they do and I personally use
it to like find out which one is gonna
be like unlocking the door which is
usually 1c0 so my arbitration field
would be one c0 and then I'd spam it I
swam all the data fields with SF's and
it'll knock the doors um and then after
that we just have the normal like
acknowledge field and a frame field in
the communication field um so yeah and
then down here in the bottom left we
have 29 bit messages which are longer
sensor IDs but shorter data fields or
the same data length data fields but
just longer Center IDs so you could
pretty much add a ton more sensors in a
car with these um so these are both
standards under I say 91 41 I believe so
Handy's used in a ton of things um I
have some of them listed above but most
of the ones I use obviously our car obd2
port scan FD um I have actually seen a
lot of you know construction devices
have canned messages on them um and I've
also seen Hospital devices use canned
messages which is kind of crazy to me so
tan is used on just tons of different uh
just tons of different machinery which
is really cool so getting initial access
to a car once again we're gonna want to
start from the outside and make our way
into the car right so the first thing
that people are usually gonna think of
is the key fob or like I want to be able
to unlock the door with the key fob and
I want to be able to you get access to
the car well there's already great
research done on that and I've seen it
done I personally don't do a lot of RF
stuff but I'm trying to learn currently
um but you know you're obviously needed
like good crypto skills you're gonna be
able to take
I guess RF data and be able to like
clone specific keys or you can like
crack like specific like hardware values
that is being generated on keys and then
you could just like break into cars so
in one of the Tesla examples which is
like the Tesla key fob peg we actually
have Leonard he's walking by and he
takes in a proxmark and he cloned
somebody's ID then he goes back to the
car and then he uses that to pretty much
unlock the car or take it and steal it
uh which is really awesome I've it was
like my first time seeing it I thought
it was the coolest thing in the world
you could find that online websites list
below obviously and there's a lot of
great research that Leonard puts into
that so I would definitely defer to him
on any of the key fob car hacking stuff
though what types of car centers do we
have so externally to the vehicle we
will have pretty much like lidar or
we'll have like some weird infrared
camera that like no guides car in
specific directions and stuff or even
like cars tire sensors that we can get
access to the vehicle with um finding
like external parts of the car and
making your way in is really interesting
just because you know like I could grab
a car tire sensor and I can plug
directly into that and then I can lock
the doors I can start the car maybe I
could drive the car away um you know
usually like there's a mobilizers in
place for that but all of these things
are possible if I can get access to the
inside of the car and unlock the doors I
can pop the hood I can replace the ECU I
can take the car away like these are
these are all things that matter but I
won't be affecting multiple cars at once
so one of the big things in bug bounties
that's kind of shifting towards I think
of better changes you know instead of
affecting a single card you infect you
affect like hundreds of cars or
thousands of cars they've like other
sensors on the back like parking sensors
Tesla has like guidance sensors on the
front - like seer people I've seen there
was an example of somebody placing
stickers on the ground and may pretty
much make a Contessa like able to like
drive off the road or it was like
identifying it as something as like a
specific object that I needed to avoid
I'm also very interesting and then uh
you know we have like cars with a once
again like different types of radars GPS
lidar there's sometimes cameras that are
external but that one specifically had
an internal camera oh yeah these are one
of the things you could try to get
access to you just to get inside of the
car so next we have the obd2 port let me
get inside of the car um pretty much the
first place you're gonna go and you're
gonna want to look at is the obd2 port
why because you can pretty much
enumerate every possible value in obd2
or in these Ken messages and you can try
to identify all the different types of
centered sensors what they do how they
do it things like that
so uh this is just a quick slide on like
setting up CANbus hacking hardware not
gonna go over it but I have it in the
slides just so when people go back and
download it yeah so here's an example of
some canned messages so once again we
have our arbitration IDs which is like
one one one right at the top the length
is eight and these are some of the
values right so essentially like so one
c0 is a good one
once the zero is usually used to unlock
and lock and unlock doors
um and I always find that values like
spread across a lot of cars I think it
like involves like specific standards
probably or whatever it may be but if
you send value like four but I'm I like
for a um the car doors will lock if you
send for C the car doors will unblock
right so essentially you're just going
through and like fuzzing all of these uh
so once again just spamming ffs on these
to you these are all hex so or you can
do it in binary as well um spending like
a value larger than a specific value may
activate some functionality in the car
or you have to meet a specific value
which just requires a little bit of
brute forcing which these can messages
literally communicate at like 25
milliseconds or 250 milliseconds though
you have a lot of time this top one is
actually vehicle spy uh and this is
Intrepid's like specific system so it
pretty much gives you like everything
you need to know I actually handmade all
these text messages a couple nights ago
and I just wanted to kind of give you
like a visualization of what this tool
looks like at the bottom we have can
dump which once again is another tool
that's used on Linux instead and you
have the ARB IDs which are the sensor
IDs and then you have the length of the
messages and then you have these
specific messages themself so uh very
interesting slide to look at definitely
go out and try the tools yourself always
really good so getting initial access to
the infotainment system so this image
actually I thought I had the source
under it but apparently it kind of moved
this is the boon to system that's on the
Tesla cars
very cool somebody actually dropped a
root shell and you know we got these
images and stuff and we were pretty much
able to look at it I believe the way
they dropped the shell too was just
connecting that like specific Ethernet
cable and then uh yeah like they're
weird like interface cable that comes
out to Ethernet and connecting their
computer running a scan on it and then
found some open ports that they
eventually ended up exploiting don't
quote me on that because there's a bunch
of different ways you could do it you
can reflash portions of like chips on
there and that'll drop you into shells
I've seen a lot of people do that too
also a really good way to get initial
access so if we go back to this slide
and pretty much have all these protocols
once again let's try to keep this in
mind when we go into like those
infotainment systems you were trying to
get initial access right like we should
be doing the normal steps that it takes
to you get initial access to a computer
right if we're trying to get access to
the radio specifically because all it is
underlining is just gonna be like a
regular computer so you need to
enumerate it like you would um and then
just like scan it for exploits like
anything else Q and X doesn't have a
large I guess like database of exploits
for it there's been like more and more
release as time goes on just because
it's a widely used system but um you
know most of the time you're just gonna
find like weird miss configurations and
custom apps um
custom applications that are being made
by developers you're gonna find like
weird backdoors that developers make to
try to get access to a you know root
shell those are happening less
frequently too so as time goes on you're
gonna need really good reverse
engineering skills just to be able to
reverse like assembly code to make
exploits right like so now that all
these applications are moving to a less
uh you know a misconfigured way you're
gonna have to start finding exploits in
you know code right like buying
deprecated code that's used in these
things too maybe uh you know do a buffer
overflow and then execute shell code all
right like there's there's tons of
different ways to go about it and if all
else fails you pretty much have you know
once again your hardware hacking skills
so this is going to be like the day
underlining thing that you're gonna use
to at least get initial access right so
there's a bunch of different things you
do um you aren't in JTAG are still two
big things that can drop you and to you
at least use your shells um I've seen
cases where I've like gone to a radio
system
I got a UART shell on it and then it was
a root shell and it was like oh well
that just gave me access to you
literally everything I wanted and then
from there were pretty much once again
downloading custom apps reversing them
seeing how we can affect more than one
specific system how can I reach out to
you know back-end databases that this is
communicating with how can I still use
your data all things to keep in mind
right so to do this essentially all you
need is like four pins and you would
solder them do either here here and just
see what data comes out so I'd use like
a logic analyzer before just like
plugging directly into it and maybe this
will like drop you into a shell so
there's great resources online dev ttyS
zero comm is one of them that just
teaches you how to reverse serial ports
this one's like very basic and just in
terms of like this drops a UART show
this will drop you into a root shell and
you're done right um whereas like
there's some things where you drop into
a shell and you'll have to get the
whatever the devices are start rebooting
and then you kill the boot process or
you like interrupt the boot process
somehow by their you know shorting out
some pins or or you know spamming
control C or control Z which is very
common like those things will literally
drop you Nichelle's as well um so like
IOT hacking pretty much applies to car
hacking and itself just to get like
initial access onto the radio system and
then to later like enumerate all the
different processes all the different
files that are on that system and to go
back and pretty much be able to exploit
those things remotely right so like this
isn't gonna be a big bounty value cuz
like if you drop a hardware hacking like
you drop a UART shell onto a radio
system anyone's just gonna be like okay
well you need physical access to do that
but it for an example attacker is going
to buy this radio system take it home
dropping UART she'll take all of those
files and then make exploits for all of
the you know custom applications running
on this they're going to enumerate
services they're going to see if this
communicates with GSM at all um they're
gonna see if this firmware is vulnerable
there's there's just a tons of things
you can do once you get this but this
itself is not worth any value right in
terms of like monetary value if you
submitted this as a bone that's great it
helps the you know it helps the like it
helps the automotive manufacturer
identify their process in terms of uh
you know like shipping these things out
and not like fusing these specific like
these specific like you are ports or
serial ports or anything so still
reporting these are great for people to
know and like you at least get credit
for it um and then you get a little bit
of satisfaction knowing that you can
still do this and you could pretty much
take this at a numerate everything else
right um so other things I've seen
people do is like remove flash I've seen
people like reprogram flash oh my god um
some people are crazy
like they will literally take some of
the chips off and they just start
reading directly off of them I'm very
cool very interesting I've been part of
a process once where we did that and we
brick something I've also seen the
process of somebody just literally
touching like putting a piece of metal
between two pins like a coin and it
dropped them into a show like
mind-blowing stuff so those are some of
the ways to get like initial access and
then once again after that it's like
even if you go through all of these
processes of trying to get initial
access on the system the thing that's
gonna matter most to automotive
developers or automotive manufacturers
is they're gonna want to see you do it
remotely right like they're gonna want
to see you affect more than one vehicle
they're going to like these things are
gonna only start increasing as time goes
on and then once we start implementing
you know vehicle to vehicle
communication or vehicle to emergency
vehicle communication they're gonna want
to see people start hacking that stuff
right like they're gonna want to see
multiple vehicles get hacked or they're
gonna want to see um an exploit that's
able to
stop these types of communications right
because I think it's BTE
so vehicle to like emergency vehicle
communication if that gets cut off then
there's an issue right um like somebody
could potentially die which is something
a lot of people would be worried about
so just keeping that stuff in mind is
always good and then seeing like where
the future is headed um there's gonna be
a lot more of just like doing stuff
remotely
or like versus like doing stuff locally
on a car because if you could affect
more than one vehicle that's really
important if you could track people
remotely that's really important um a
lot of car companies definitely do not
want that um whereas like you know if
you can pull out a radio system and
Hacket once again like that's not
something I valuable to them but once
again good a numeration step really
would suggest it very easy to do very
easy to learn as well there's a lot more
advanced stuff you can do with it as
well um quick shout outs so uh these are
all my friends that I work with um I
love all of them some of the people in
the flood crowd group actually pretty
much everyone in the flood card group
very great community to talk with I've
learned so much from this community they
have given so much to me
in terms of knowledge and like resources
that I can use that I will probably
never be able to repay them
so I'm doing a shout out for them once
again I like if not pipe does radio
frequencies are are F star F hacking
stuff and he pretty much can tell you
how to get a ham radio license shell
does red team pen testing stuff that Dan
does a ton of awesome research stuff
netsuke does a ton of reverse
engineering stuff same with our tu and
buses can fly buses can fly it does car
acting stuff or to you does car acting
so there's a ton of people out there
that you communicate with and they're
like more than willing to help and talk
to you Leonard and minty also people
mentioned in his slides they created
hardware they create you know a bunch of
different exploits for cars to emaan
jacket is just uh one up like a personal
friend um he he pretty much got me the
contact with like a person who owned a
Tesla and I was able to hack it so um
and I'm like still meeting up with this
person trying to hack their car pretty
much the great times um pretty much
everything else locally SAE if you were
in college I highly recommend you sign
up for SAE
pretty much they teach you how to hack
in the cars uh and they allow people
from I think around the world to pretty
much they like pay for your flight or
you could like I think it's like a
scholarship system so you sign up for a
scholarship you fly out to Michigan a
bunch of car automotive manufacturers
come out and they
let you hack cars they teach you out of
hack cars they have trainings the
knowledge I I've only been car acting
for one year but the amount of knowledge
that I gained from SAE is just amazing
the gentleman that actually taught me
below is this picture here
that's Decker he actually was on a
History Channel series called the forged
with fire um like where he made like old
medieval weapons which is really cool um
and then obviously like shouts of
bugcrowd
I could not have gotten into car hacking
as much as I did without them pretty
much accepting my random reach out of
hey I wanna hack cars I want to try a
bug bounty and hack cars will you let me
try and then I found something and lo
and behold they were like you should
come out more you should come hang out
you're a really cool dude and I really
love bug crowd they've really helped me
out in just a bunch of ways um my local
Def Con group um you know I present car
hacking stuff there I'm you know trying
to present more trying to reach out more
I really want to give back just because
of how many people helped me and then
once again that crowd we have a Twitter
so uh you know follow sub you know
whatever you're Elsa
yeah gang stuff um and then if you like
the images I actually got the images
from any artist that was online I really
loved his art artwork um so all of the
background images and pretty much like
all the really nice ones were made by
this artist he actually does create his
own content he's also a photographer he
loves teaching he loves giving back to
the community from what I can tell he
seems like an awesome dude um so you
know I reached out to him and I asked
for his artwork so uh yeah that's pretty
much it um I was trying to do like a
full knowledge dump of everything I had
does anyone have any questions no big
deal um like I said if you guys want to
reach out to me my my personal
information is at underscore specters
underscore on Twitter and yeah that's
that's pretty much the best way to reach
out to me I'm also in the bugcrowd
researcher
the bugcrowd community discord channel
so I'm at lame so yeah I'm also on there
so you can always reach out to me as
well great well thank you so much
Niko I know the bits that people did see
because the the stream was up for most
of it but it would every once in a while
kind of spits and sputter or whatever I
guess on the YouTube side but people
were giving you good feedback so
appreciate it and we will have a full I
have a full locally recorded version
that's going to be uploaded in the next
couple days yeah for sure so like I said
if anyone wants to reach out feel free
thank you Sam thanks Haddix I really
appreciate you guys inviting me to this
stuff I need to like start doing this
for it's all good we've really really
appreciate you sharing your knowledge
and giving back like you said a lot of
people helped us get to where we are and
it's great that you're able to kind of
turn that back around and help others
bring them up to where you're at so
thank you yeah no problem anytime