now you're up
the stream so let's see we can give you
an intro fill if you haven't if you're
not already familiar with Phil Philip is
a member of the bugcrowd ambassador team
he's been a really great advocate for
bugcrowd but also for the info ii hacker
community he's done a lot to give back
to his local community where he lives
and we are really excited to have him
here today to talk about penetration
testing and then hopefully give people
some good tips and tricks and techniques
and and words of wisdom on how to get
into the penetration testing space so
that you can do it on the side or even
something like the bugcrowd ng BT
testing which is basically a penetration
test that we work with our crowd with so
yeah Philip thank you so much for
joining us today and I'm excited for
your talk take it away I think Sam
thanks thanks for the introduction and
this is an honor this has been a goal of
mine since level up one to eventually be
able to present here and I've learned a
lot of good information along the way
this is how I found out about the
Ambassador Program last year through
through level up to and so this has been
one my goals so it's awesome to be doing
this today and thanks for the
opportunity so to get started Sam kind
of gave you a little overview of a
little more detail on my background I'm
a pen tester is my day job I'm an
adjunct instructor at Richland College
I teach ethical hacking web application
pin testing this past January made a
year that I've been teaching and for for
a long time I've kind of mentored people
and helped people that were interested
in becoming pen testers or other areas
of security so so sharing on people in
teaching was something that was a
passion of mine and teaching was just a
further way to enhance that to do it on
a broader scale and then becoming an
ambassador this played into this meet up
but I started here locally in the Dallas
area called the palm school project it's
a monthly meetup that's educational
teaching
penetration testing techniques and
ethical hacking and there's a lot of
other we're lucky to hear Dallas to have
like Dallas hackers Association and a
local Def Con group that we have so much
here locally that we're lucky but one of
the things the other ones the other
groups were doing that do presentations
on certain techniques but it didn't
really go into details so people that
renew you know was that have to go home
do a lot of studying to try to figure
out what was being said so I saw the
need for my students competing my class
completing my class to continue on in
their education and then people locally
that just maybe couldn't afford the
training as a way to offer training to
them so that's how the pone school
project was started and be an ambassador
just played into that because being an
ambassador you give back to the
community you teach others and one of
the goals that I have is trying to teach
people to be researchers so this played
in my to the grand scheme of things that
I was doing so this played in well I've
been in InfoSec NIT for over 21 years 15
plus of it's been security alone I
started out as a system administrator
spent eight years doing network security
and application security application
security is where I got interested in
pen testing so the over the past seven
years that's what I've been doing is pen
testing I finally found the job and I
really enjoy a lot of their positions
even as security and IT after a while
you kind of got bored and it wasn't as
interesting but pen testing has remained
just as interesting as it was when I
started it kind of to give you a little
more about my background the scenic
route I guess you could say my nonlinear
path InfoSec is before I ever got into
IT I start out as a pro-wrestler wasn't
a really good lifestyle after getting
married I needed something where I had
travel as much stable income somewhat to
school to be a CAD draftsman and then
from being a CAD draftsman I learned
about sysadmin work which was a lot more
interesting to me I found out if they go
into CAD school that I had more of a
niche for for technology so that led me
to be an assist admin then an InfoSec
and then eventually become to pen tester
and during my pro wrestling career
actually one time I did wrestle a bear
so there's a couple pictures up from my
old pro wrestling days back then when I
was getting started
I would never would have never known
that I'd be using my brain for a living
because I was always into powerlifting
and you know did the wrestling thing and
thought whatever I would do would be
just physically based but after getting
a little education I learned that that
uh technology was a lot more fun and so
we're gonna discuss today we're gonna
describe pentesting the types of pin
tests specialization skills for other
roles needs to be a pen tester the
things you need to learn to be a pen
tester learning resources how to get
experience in certifications that are
helpful in being a penetration tester
and this is one of the slides I shared
my student each semester and I want to
share this message to anyone that that
may be new to pen testing you have to go
hacking or security research I got this
quote from from one of the spider-man
movies when Uncle Ben was telling Peter
that you know with great power comes
great responsibility
so you want to remember this whenever
anytime you're hacking make sure you got
permission without permission it's
illegal and better off you want reading
written permission proof that you have
the permission to do that and either you
do you go through some company to do pen
testing or you go through like bugcrowd
and doing bug bounties that way you've
got permission to do it you know you can
run into some problems when you get
someone as hey can you test this system
it's mine
and it could be someone else's system or
someone's trying to get you to illegally
breach a system so you definitely want
to be careful with this and with a
felony on your record it would make it
really hard to get get jobs as a pen
tester or in security at all so keep
that in mind and what is pen testing so
pen testing is assessing security from
the adversarial perspective exploiting
vulnerabilities gained access to systems
and since the data basically hacking
that's why I'm more commonly hear the
term for a pen testers ethical hacking
this is more a better way to describe
penetration testing can be kind of a
confusing term so any time I tell people
that aren't in industry what I do for a
living I tell them I'm an ethical hacker
and make
it makes a lot more sense to them than
then penetration tester wipe in testing
well pen testing gives you a better
understanding of the scary is the risk
severity of security risks if you've
exploitable vulnerabilities or higher
risk it higher priority for mediation
than and justification for budgeting so
low level finding may not be that high
risk so this kind of if it's exploitable
then it's a higher risk and this is a
good way to show that these items or
exploit offal exploitable and it's
easier to get budget to remediate items
when you can prove that they can
actually be exploited because sometimes
there's some low level or informational
findings that you may not be able to
exploit they're not that risky but if
you can prove that they're exploitable
that's a good way to get the budget to
to remediate those and plus just from
from testing this way testing security
you're able to find things you wouldn't
find with just a typical vulnerability
scan you're able to dig further past
that vulnerability and see what else can
be done what other Gumm abilities lie in
that system behind the firewall the
antivirus and other endpoint protection
on it and regulatory compliance this is
a big thing that drives a lot of pen
tests at our company a lot of our tests
are based on PCI so this is where we do
most of our work for PCI plus another
thing about pen testing it's a fun job
with a lot of great opportunities used
to in the past the only job you really
seen out there were contractors or
consultants most companies didn't have
their own internal pen testers but
that's kind of changing what the times
people are starting to add their own
internal pen testers because it can be
expensive in some cases to use only oli
consultants or contractors and a lot of
companies like our company is there's
numerous companies that have big
penetration testing teams and companies
are adding pen test teams as time goes
by pen testing jobs you know most
commonly some of these when you're
looking for a job you'll see some of the
titles as penetration testers or pen
testers but more commonly you'll see
something like security consultant
analyst or engineers you really have to
dig into the job descriptions to find
out if it's you know
an actual pentesting job sometimes
because typically you'll see like
analyst or engineer some other word
synonymous with pen testing as ethical
hacking offensive security adversarial
security and these a lot of times will
fall under groups known as threat and
vulnerability management so when you're
looking for a job just kind of keep you
know like the threat and vulnerability
management several companies I work for
that was the title of our pen test team
in pen testing skills that are valuable
in other areas sake analysts the
understanding malicious traffic can help
you as a stock analyst digital forensics
and Incident Response if you're
responding to an incident if you
understand the attack vectors then
you're going to be able to you it's
gonna make your life easier you're gonna
it's gonna give you an edge figuring out
how how things were how these breaches
occurred network security analyst and
engineers this is value of them purple
team's where you're doing both defensive
and offensive applications security it's
really good note that area as well so
you can do some of your testing you may
not necessarily be doing the pen test
but be able to perform some kind of some
kind of assessment security assessment
of the software is kind of it's good to
have in security researchers as we know
as bug hunters this is a good area to
have pen testing skills a lot of good
bug hunters come from pen testing
backgrounds for instance Jason Haddix he
comes from a pen testing background so
you may be a bug hunter but it doesn't
hurt to expand past the application
layer to understand the network layer
and some of the other areas that can be
exploited in types of pen test targets
so these are the items that you would
normally test and some of the most
common ones common ones are listed here
first network your internal external and
wireless networks application web app
that client mobile and cloud and then
your hardware hacking network hardware
routers and switches and even down to
some of the more newer technologies like
IMT and medical devices you know medical
devices you want to make sure that these
are secure
leave the devices are secure at least on
a secure network to prevent someone from
having access to pacemakers or insulin
I have done wireless pen tests for
hospitals before and it's interesting to
see all the wireless is connected
wirelessly to their their Wi-Fi network
in transportation this is where your car
hacking comes in handy all tort all
types of vehicles
you know buses planes cars with the
autonomous autonomous self-driving
vehicles coming out this is you know
becoming a lot more serious area that
they need to make sure that these these
cars or buses accept or whatever vehicle
is secure so this is a popular area I
even saw that there is a college in
Texas that were proposing a vehicle
pentesting course or degree part of
their security program so this is
starting to get to be well more visible
area that people are realizing the need
for security people social engineering
so you're actually trying to hack the
human element
sometimes your endpoint protections your
firewalls all this other security may
prevent you from actually breaching the
network but if you can get someone to
click on a file or let you in a door
then there's possibilities to hack into
those ways so that's one of the targets
that pentesters red teamers will try to
hack buildings your physical security
this is very important you can have the
most sophisticated security everything
can be locked down great but if
someone's able to get in the door and
get physical access all bets are off so
this is one of the areas is good and
it's usually typically done within a
social engineering engagement types of
pentest knowledge this is the knowledge
of your target your testing so as a pen
tester the first one we're going to look
at is black box this means like limited
to maybe IP addresses at the most and
it's more of an attacker approach and
this requires a little more time than
like the white box your white box also
known as crystal box it's detailed
system info including accounts for apps
testing documentation is can be Visio
diagrams more information a lot of fan
testers think that this is not this
is kind of cheating a white box pin test
that when you have a little little time
to test then you want to be able to test
all the controls and a lot of this
requires be able to access the
application as a user and even
administrator when I test applications I
like to have multi levels I like to have
administrator and other roles that may
be of users are on that system so that
way you can make sure that they can't
get to information that they should get
to even administrators there's some
information that they shouldn't see they
shouldn't see full unmasked account
numbers and social security numbers and
you also want to test the CV can
escalate privileges so if a lot of a
user can get to admin and so forth
access information they shouldn't and
then the next level is gray box this is
kind of a little more common what you
see partial knowledge of target this is
kind of a cross between black box and
white box testing you'll get usually in
this you get more you know IPS you know
URLs and that stuff and not necessarily
accounts a little more information then
black box but not the full extent white
box but all these different types of
testing are important and a lot of these
are dictated by the amount of time you
have for the pen test if you've got a
week on an application you're gonna be a
lot better off to a white box test and
compared that to a malicious actor or
malicious actors have all the time in
the world so that's one of the things
that a pen tester runs into the
limitations of time and the types of
tests testing depth isn't going to kind
of give you the different levels of
what's required in a test and some of
those are standalone functions in the
threat and vulnerability management
program first we look at your
vulnerability scans this is your necess
your next pose your Qualis your scan
against these items and then for
application web inspect or app scan net
spark or some of these other types of
vulnerability scanners you're just
looking for vulnerabilities with this so
this is not giving you the level of
depth as a pen test but this is just
scanning for vulnerabilities looking for
your low-hanging fruit and this could be
dedicated groups and a company that do
reoccurring scanning in your next
is your vulnerability assessments a lot
of times as a pen tester you may start
out doing vulnerability assessments and
a vulnerability assessment is basically
the vulnerability scan plus validation
you're validating the findings you're
making sure there's no false positives
there's somebody it's little this kind
of simplifies it there's more things to
it when you're validating those
vulnerabilities you can use other tools
outside of the vulnerability scanner but
this is the next level of the process
and then from the vulnerability
assessment comes a pen test these are
taking these other two areas plus you're
adding exploitation so your the the
vulnerability is that you were able to
validate now you're gonna try to see if
you're going to exploit it them and
exploitation and common terms hacking so
you're gonna try to see if you can hack
into those systems through those
exploits and then you have red teaming
and adversarial tests people have been
in most people been in the industry for
a while will have a different view of
red team a lot of times this looked at
generically as the red team is offensive
blue team is defensive but in the field
red teaming is more of adversarial
simulation so this is a step above pen
testing and one of the best definitions
I heard of that is wire fall from Dallas
hackers referred to this as testing the
blue team you're testing the controls
you're testing the staff you're seeing
how they react most times and Red Team
Red Team your adversarial simulations
they don't let the security people know
this is going on so that way they can
test their reactions make sure the
things they have in place to protect the
network are working properly and then
the people that are watching these items
and monitoring network or CMEs and
blocking or be able to at least identify
these attacks and this is the part most
people want to hear I like to cover up
front about pen testing so you can
understand these other items why you
need to know that so this is where is
that usually what people like about this
talk or that when I give talks about
becoming a pen tester in this talk I
didn't mentioned first is kind of an
evolution of the talk I do the first day
of class for my students my first day of
the ethical hacking class telling them
about you know gun testing and what's
required to become a pen
tester and so technological knowledge
you have to understand technology you
have to understand something before you
can protect it or before you can hack
into it so you need to understand
networking operating systems especially
Windows and Linux and security so you
need to understand security understand
firewalls how firewall rules work file
systems how your file permissions work
and then also application understanding
some applications security if you're
just a generalist or pen tester that's
not specializing in application security
you still need to understand web
applications a little bit understand
word about the applications security and
how those function and then hardware so
understanding how servers work and
workstations and so forth understanding
computing in general so these are the
things you really need to understand
going into this and to kind of add on to
that when I started my first pen testing
job my manager at the company that
worked at which wasn't kind of
consulting he always encourages to build
something he wasn't really pushing us to
learn how to hack he said you know if
you learned how to build it then you can
learn how to break into it so the next
thing you need to once you understand
those other technologies to be a pen
tester you need to understand how to
hack and so you can give this through
classes conferences meetups and
self-study is the route most people take
even if you get to go these classes or
conferences and stuff then you still
need to do some study on your own being
a pen tester or in a lot of areas of
security alone it's not not a really
easy job to it's if you don't go in you
know if you're gonna succeed you don't
go in with the mindset that I'm gonna
work 9 to 5 and that's it and and you
don't want that this mindset if I'm only
going to get training when the company's
paying for it if you want to get ahead
you've got to study on your own the
people that get ahead you'll take people
that have been in the industry a long
time that's the nine-to-fiver that I'm
not gonna study unless the company sends
me for training they'll get passed up by
the
you people so just to stay up with
technology this is something you need to
spend some time on your own outside work
studying and if you're trying to move
over from another area you know if
you're doing you know web development
somewhere they may not let you spend the
time studying you know pen testing so
any rate these are the different
different areas you can learner that and
far as the self study home labs are very
valuable this is one of the best ways I
learned better hands-on videos different
tutorials blogs and articles Twitter's a
real good resource that's where I get
most of my information and Twitter's how
I found out about bug hunters that's one
of the reasons I was drawn to bugcrowd
was just finding some of these
researchers and bug hunters like Jason
and some of these other guys that really
taught bug hunters I've learned some
interesting web application pen testing
stuff for them so that's who I follow I
get most of my information from Twitter
a lot of people put up tweets maybe
they've got some tool that's coming out
that hasn't been you know mentioning an
article yet that hasn't really been
fully released to the public so this is
a good way to get in and find out this
stuff early on and so the hacker mindset
is something that you need the hacker
mindset it's pretty interesting because
being a pen tester being a hacker being
you know a security researcher the one
area the one thing about this part of
security is it takes creativity so it's
kind of a combination of creativity and
analytical thinking and so this has
developed it's similar is similar
developing the mindset of
troubleshooting because when you first
go in somewhere like my one my first
test admin jobs all I was doing was
installs we were rolling out servers so
there wasn't a lot of troubleshooting so
I had extensive research and then my
next job we I was an environment that's
very unstable systems were overloaded
not configured right constantly breaking
and I was really overwhelmed putting a
lot of hours and I was close to quitting
the job but then I stopped thought I got
all this experience installing but where
I'm really lacking is I'm really lacking
experience with troubleshooting so I
stuck it out so the same thing with
hacking
you kind of go in and like
troubleshooting if you know you're not
connecting make sure the cable is
plugged in make sure that you know
you've got your network card configured
right so these little details as you
practice hacking then you kind of it
becomes second nature so you know if you
see a unprotected upload that maybe you
can upload a war file and create a
malicious JSP page on
Pachi Tomcat server so as you learn
these things you know how to hack one
thing that you can build upon that and
this is best developed through
repetition and hands on hacking
experience that's something you would
get through labs or bug bounties and the
formula for becoming a pen tester is
technology technology knowledge plus
security knowledge plus the hacker
mindset these are the three items needed
to be a pen tester and where do you
start so you start off by developing
your plan you want to assess your
current skillset forgotten look at all
the things that you know so far and
perform a gap analysis on the skills
needed look at the things you need to
learn like we discussed you need to
understand networking you need to
understand operating systems so you look
at these items and find out where your
weaknesses are and that's what you need
to focus your your learning towards in
developing this plan we're like we were
looking for the gaps now it's time to
fill the gaps if you have no idea
start with the basics operating systems
hardware and networking think you know
A+ certification progressing towards
like network plus and then if you have
IT experience then you need to learn
Linux and security and networking if
you're you're rolling and IT you may
know networking but these are some
common areas that that most people need
to look at and if you have InfoSec
experience builds gaps in basics that
you're missing with pen testing and
ethical hacking participates ETFs and
bug bounties and your labs and it this
goes for the the bottom step everyone
built a lab everyone you know some of
the most experienced hackers I know have
labs and they've been pen testing for
like 20 years
so it's you can always learn and when
you have a lab you can only
test the proof-of-concept that you may
try to use on a bug bounty or maybe
you're doing a pen test so if you have
this lab you can test these exploits
because you're not always gonna run to
these exploits in the wild so if you
have a lab you can build a lab put in
these multiple apps and test these you
know the latest exploits and get
experience CTFs there's a lot of online
CTFs you know to conferences or other
events like our meetup Dallas hackers
Association we have a CTF each month bug
bounties are a great place and the thing
I really like about bug bounty programs
it's an actual production environment so
you're actually getting production
experience when you go in and do an
interview with an employer and they ask
you how you do you know ask you about
cross-site scripting or sequel injection
you're able to describe these and tell
them how you were able to exploit those
in a bug bounty so once you get this
experience this is actual real world
you're doing you know this in the real
world a CTF is a simulated environment
it's purposely vulnerable so that may
not as be as helpful but if you're doing
like a bug bounty and you find bugs in
there then it's going to go a lot
further and get it helping you get a pen
test job and pro bono work or volunteer
work do free pet pen tests for nonprofit
organizations or small businesses they
can't afford pen tests so this will
actually give you a real-world
experience and people that you can use
as a reference when looking for those
jobs and will mention this probably even
more throughout this talk the labs
personal lab and online labs is a good
way to get experience if you can
describe how to use these tools you know
you can use that information on an
interview and specializations most
people who start out as a generalist in
the generalist you need at least network
wireless and and web app sometimes
starting out like when I was starting
out at first I just did network and web
application and moving into wireless but
this is more of the generalist role your
typical pen tester no it does wireless
network and web app in an application
you can specialize in application so you
can do web app mobile apps they client
and cloud and then
where you can specialize I specialize in
IOT network hardware medical devices you
know you can work for some company as a
researcher testing the different
hardware devices vehicles your
automobiles trucks multi passenger
vehicles and vans and even aircraft
those some type of specializations and
you're starting to see more of the
vehicle jobs more of the car hacking
jobs out there in some of these areas
that you don't see as much people in
this may be a good way to to something
to focus on if you're just getting
started out as well because since
there's not as many people in those
areas that maybe there's opportunities
there that may not exist in some of the
other more populated areas although the
security field is understaffed so once
you have the right skills and experience
then it's only a matter of time before
you get your foot the door and then your
labs you know we talked about labs so
you're minimalist lab this is just
putting virtualized hosts using vm
virtualbox hypervisor whatever
virtualization you choose to use on a
desktop or laptop I look like a laptop
because that way you can carry it with
you if you travel you go on vacation you
can still spend a little time in your
lab or if you get bored at home you've
been studying you need to go somewhere
get out of the house go to a coffee shop
maybe study for a bit so that's that's
kind of a nice set up to have there and
then your dedicated lab so then you have
like a machine or some raspberry PI's or
some small devices that you can set up
with VMs on there that's put learn
multiple VMs and then attack from
another system and then as you get more
advanced labs you can get individual
computers for servers and routers and
switches so you can break it down but
all the things are the things about
building some of these the more advanced
stuff you'll get a little more
experience learning how to build
networks you know setting up these
applications that are vulnerable they're
the vulnerable VMS are great but in what
way to take a step above that is to
download the vulnerable applications and
build that out yourself and then your
attack platform you've got your lab set
up so now you need to be able to you
need something to hack with so the most
common one
you're gonna see as kali linux it works
it's a pretty good packing distribution
has most the tools installed by default
if not it's in the repositories for kali
linux and can be installed fairly easy
and then in bunty with the pentester
framework script from trusted set
security trusted sec it's a little
script that she can run on a bun too and
it will install all the different pen
testing tools if you'd rather run on a
bun to you and then peridot s is another
linux distribution that's got all the
pen testing hacking tools is installed
and it's also good to get some
experience with windows when backtrack
came out eventually it was it was the
predecessor to kali linux that's where a
lot of people started going that way but
now with all the powershell tools and
and be able to operate hacking tools
natively in a Windows environment it's
good to have a Windows VM or a
standalone Windows system that you can
hack with and so you can take like
Windows 10 and use fireeyes Commandos vm
scripts and the commando vm scripts is
similar to if we think about it coming
from using the pen tester framework
script is similar that it's automates
and installing the different pen testing
tools on Windows 10 so you have all the
power shell even Metasploit all that
installed on there so this is also a
good intern alternative if you don't
have much experience with Windows
administration then you definitely want
to look at this because you know being
able to run PowerShell natively and all
these tools is a great option and
whatever I was consulting up I had like
a Windows VM on my attack box that I
used so I like VMware and Windows 10 I
usually use like Ubuntu or Mac OS was my
my host OS and then I ran VM those other
tools and we'll have targets so you
create your virtual machines you can get
the targets from vult hub there's a lot
of great vulnerable VMs on there some of
them some of them are from CTF that's
been held at conferences too that I
recommend getting start out with - as
far as you met your
cultural virtual nerble hosts vulnerable
VMs is Metasploit will to the Metasploit
Ville 3 those are really good as well as
the wasp webgoat you can create your own
target VMs download the software from
exploit DB so you may not find but VMs
they have particular exploits on there
so you may and some of the VM since
there's licensing for Windows it's a
little more difficult to find some
vulnerable windows VM so a lot of cases
you should create your own so by
downloading the software from exploit
Eevee you can build your own that way
and recommend a reading so here's the
the books I recommend starting out with
pen testing a hands-on introduction to
hacking that book is by Georgia Weidman
I've used that book for my first three
semesters of my ethical hacking class
later on we went to the pen test plus to
give students an option to be able to to
be able to get a certification to study
for a certification and then the next
book I recommend after you get through
the penetration testing book is the the
hackers playbook version two and three I
would start with two and then you can go
on and move on to three from there
version three gets into a lot more red
teaming so if you're the red teaming
thing interests you then that's a good
one to move on to you and web
application hacker's handbook this is
the second edition this is really good
for web application pen testing and I
recommend it for anyone is a pen tester
because sometimes if you're on you're
doing a networked pen test and some you
may not be able to get anything but you
may find a vulnerable app so
understanding how to do perform some
level application pen testing is very
important and then the last book I've
listed on here is the Red Team Field
Manual this is a good reference manual
it's got a lot of different syntax for
Cisco Python scripts Linux and Windows
system administration stuff it's a
really small book easy to easy to carry
carry around with you and with a lot of
good tips that can be helpful to a pen
tester even anyone in security or blue
team
and then here's some learning resources
that that are pretty good when getting
started out the top portion you can see
the divide between these two lists the
top portion are resources that that cost
money obviously so SANS Institute has a
lot of really good courses related to
pen testing in other areas of security
and then this kind of as this goes down
they kind of get a little less expensive
than he learns security that's a good
place for for courses online courses
they have I've taken their web
application pentesting class when I was
first get involved and what about pen
testing I took their mobile security
assessment and mobile pen testing course
which is really good I've taken that and
there's another site virtual hacking
labs if you're interested in the OSC P I
would recommend starting with virtual
hacking labs before you sign up for the
OSC P virtual hacking labs has like an
Associated class of course with it a
course manual and it shows you how to
perform different pen testing steps and
then as you get into the lab the labs
pretty nice they're fairly fairly new
systems in there and even like mobile
devices so this is a really good place
to start out with and also each one of
the vm's they'll give you the level of
difficulty in the VM and the ones that
are rated easy or beginner we'll give
you some pointers on what to do some
hits to hack that system as you get to
the more difficult ones you get less
hits which they're kind of they wean you
off so once you get those more
experienced systems you've been working
this lab so long you really you know
hopefully working towards you don't need
the hits but it's a really good really
good place to start and I found out
through one of my students my first
semester someone recommended recommended
it to him and I really don't like to
recommend things unless I've try it
myself so I had I got you know like a 90
day subscription to it and played around
with it's a really good really good
learning resource and then pentester
academy they've recently added some labs
it's amazing the number of labs they
have on there now anything from Web
Application pen testing to network they
have CTF
they've got stuff
related to Wireshark different Network
sniffing I mean it's a really great
resource then practical pen test labs
this one is super cheap I think this one
was like $64 for lifetime access it's
got a little short course it's got some
online labs that you access through a
VPN and then these next items below are
free resources and bugcrowd University
if you're wanting to be a security
researcher or if you're wanting to just
be a pen tester there's some very good
information on there that covers a lot
of the good basics for penetration
webapp pen testing and this this
semester I added this to my started a
web application pen testing course at
the Community College where I teach and
part of our curriculum is bugcrowd
University so we covered that and the
SANS pen testing blog this is a good
place for all the cheat sheets for in
map Metasploit so i would sign up for
sans to get their emails to get more
information but the blog follow that
blog we have a lot of good how to's and
cheat sheets and then hacking tutorials
don't work this is another great site
this one was actually created by the
people that created virtual hacking labs
only this is a free site they've got
tutorials on open boss which is the open
source vulnerability scanner as well as
in map tutorials and Metasploit there's
a lot of really good tutorials on there
and this is free and then cyber AIT
they've got some some good resources on
there actually the advanced pen testing
course on there was created by georgia
Weidman and i actually was was using
those videos for my class so that way
they'd have some videos to go along with
their reading assignments and labs and
then the web security Academy this is
ports where the creators of burp suite
they've come out with instead of
updating their web application hacker's
handbook they're going to start
publishing new content to their web
security academy and they just recently
added more content this was part of the
curriculum for my students two semester
part of their labs were to go on on on
to this website and go through the
different tutorials on there they give
you really good explanations of the
vulnerabilities and how to exploit them
and then you have labs that you can
actually try out the exploits for those
vulnerabilities and of course they're
covering that so far the main some of
the big ones of the OWASP top 10 in
OWASP org this is another great site the
OWASP top 10 there's a lot of free tools
on there like burp I mean like a SAP
attack proxy which is a good replacement
for burp suite if you don't have a
commercial license of burp suite and
there's like a page with just vulnerable
uh different vulnerable applications on
there a page dedicated that so that's
one if you're gonna do anything with web
application you have that you definitely
have to check out that for sure and I
recommend that dating one because all
pen testers need to know some level of
web application pin testing and then
hack the Box hack the box that you
that's a good resource I saw recently on
Twitter a 16 year old kid that just
recently got his OS CP and he's been at
he said he spent a year on hack the box
to get his OS CP so that's a really good
one and over the wire CTF those are good
like over the wire dot org core slash
wargames
I think it's the bandit CTF series that
if you're wanting to learn about Linux
security or UNIX security those are
really good at learning Linux in UNIX
security and after this this is already
post up so if anyone wants this page of
the links to the resources if you go to
the hacker maker comm learning -
resources this whole list is up there so
it will be available there in
certifications these first first - I got
listed the CH in pen test plus these are
good entry-level certifications the CH
is really widely recognized by HR and
management so these are ones that you
know some that will help you get points
towards you know HR for you on your
resume because people are used to seeing
these the CH is also a DoD cert so
companies that
or doing business with the government
have government contracts they'd like to
see people with DoD certs like the CH
and CISSP a lot of the CompTIA certs are
on that list I'm not sure if the pen
test plus is made it yet but the pen
test plus is anyone it's a little over
it's coming up on a year old they
released the beta stuff last year and I
switched my class to the pen test plus
to offer them a certification path at
least the first two are just you know
really good certifications to get your
foot in the door but once you get we
progress down this list like the sands
GP n + OS CP these are two of the most
widely listed certifications on for pen
test jobs most often I see those
actually these last four I see them a
lot and the sand stuff is really good
but it's expensive
but then offensive security their
content is really good and really
recognized and with the the offensive
security stuff you actually have to go
into lab and hack into systems to get
certified so it's more of a hands-on
type exam opposed to answering questions
and scenarios and stuff although there's
a lot of value to the sand stuff but
kind of to give you the where I see the
value and stuff like the hands-on labs
is a lot of pen test jobs you go for
when they give you your technical
interview part of the technical
interview is they usually give you a
Cali VM to hack into a vulnerable VM or
a network they have set up as vulnerable
that you perform in test on so although
the the knowing the answers and
understanding that knowledge is
important that the hands-on aspect goes
a long way towards getting a pen test
job the GXP n is sans advanced pen
testing and exploit development that's
kinda like the next level above these
the GP n + OS CP and then osce is a is
heavy on exploit development it's kind
of similar to to the the GX pn but these
are all really good certs to get to get
your foot in the door and even though
you want to make sure you know the
contact is just having the certs a lot
of times won't get you the job you gotta
get a technical interview
you've got to be able to explain
different vulnerabilities methodologies
and how to hack into things you need to
understand these so if you go through
one of these things don't make sure you
stay you know practicing in the labs
keep this content fresh because you get
your OS CPE and say like you're working
the helpdesk and then you finally get a
chance to interview for a contest job
three years later and you have to be
keeping up with this you're probably
gonna have a hard time in your technical
interview so the certifications are
definitely the way to get your friend
the door I know a lot of awesome pen
testers they have no certs but they're
able to prove it on the interviews but
as far as what I'd advise someone that's
a beginner sometimes you need that
certification just to get to get started
in job tips professional networking
community is huge I recommend to my
students every semester to join the
local meetups go to the local meetups
you want to become a regular you want
people to know you and kind of know what
kind of jobs you're looking for I had a
recruiter ask me for a list of students
that might be interested in pentesting
jobs so a lot of my students I knew of
another guy that was a recent college
grad the hit stated one of the last
Isles hackers association meetings and
I've known him for a couple years so I
know he's good responsible person smart
and can do the job and he had mentioned
one meetings that he was looking for a
pen testing job so once this recruiter
approached me about the jobs I passed on
his information he actually got the job
so getting into the community and
knowing people people knowing your skill
set goes a long way my last two
full-time pentesting jobs have been
through people I know in the security
community my local community and I get
side work from people that I know in the
community in LinkedIn you want a good
LinkedIn profile this is not Facebook so
you want to make sure you have a
professional picture you know kind of
you know it's like your resume to your
online resume so keep it clean don't put
controversial stuff on there have a
professional picture on there you know
be truthful like you would your resume
new things you learn put on there but
don't put something on you're not gonna
be able explain
in the interview and that's my advice on
your resume period if you use some tool
once you know you really want to put
that on there and go through the
interview and the more items you have on
your resume that you're not able to
answer how to use or describe then
that's gonna kind of not look too good
for an interview and prepare for your
interviews so before you go in there
especially when you're just starting out
and you really might you don't know the
OS top-10 like the back of your hand
then I would recommend going up you know
go through the OAuth top ten understand
the vulnerabilities and how you're able
to repeat those vulnerabilities early on
in my career one of my best interviews I
went over the wasp top ten like the day
before the night before my interview and
sure enough those come up on pentesting
interviews more most of the
vulnerabilities you're gonna hear can be
easily a wasp popped in even though the
people interviewing you may not even you
know that may not be their background
but those are just some of the most well
known vulnerabilities out there and be
able to explain the basics like the
three 3-way TCP handshake in the OSI
model
people are still asked stuff like that
especially me and getting a management
you know maybe you're not using you know
referring the LES model OSI model lot in
the job you're currently in some
management you know their background
where they come from
at a time where is more important so
just kind of understand these the know a
lot of these IT basics just brush up
before you wanna don't be a total
surprise look at the job description and
the things they want you to know and
make sure that maybe some of these tools
you used go through review the tools
brush up on it before you go into that
interview and with that's all the
content that I have prepared for this
but I'll leave this open for questions
all right we'll see if we have questions
from the chat but thank you Phillip
Thank You Phil and anyone can feel free
to reach out to me on DM and I'll be
happy to answer their questions
all right we'll see if anything comes in
through the chat does an awesome
introduction thanks fellow well thank
you my pleasure there's a lot of
discussion going on especially
around the certification stuff about
like some people really rip on the sea
eh and yeah I was just I was telling
people oh my my personal view is that
anything that shows that you're
dedicated to the field gives you a leg
up and the sea eh I think it's a
cost-effective one and it does give you
pass for like resume pile of someone who
doesn't have it if you're not gonna take
an entry-level cert and you're coming
from nothing like you've never had a
security job before you got to make sure
to like put all of your CTF experience
and you're like pen tester labs and all
the stuff you put on the fly before that
make sure to fit that into your resume
because I mean at the end of the day a
hiring manager who knows anything about
security and I've done this lot is
looking for that passion or that proof
that at least you put in effort to do to
do the stuff even though you've never
had a practical job to do it or the
actual job to do it so that would be
something I suggest yeah and I'm with
you on the sea age I don't I'm not a fan
of it myself and I've kind of you know
kind of battle me for I've said some
pretty negative comments before in the
past about it and was approached by
ec-council one time about helping with
some content and just because I don't
really believe in it I could but I mean
I just couldn't bring myself to I feel
like I was selling out but like you said
it's a foot in the door and someone
that's a desktop technician and they
went through the time to stay the ceh
that goes to show something because
there's a lot of people that that will
work in the field that don't put in the
effort and so at least a shows or put an
effort and trying to learn yeah
absolutely
the door you know just having those
certifications that's when it's most
important okay oh you go on accompany
people senior experience they don't care
about certifications because you're
gonna be like explain how to do any kind
of vulnerable
your latest exploits and explained
methodology all that easily but someone
without that they definitely need it
just even get you know someone to even
yesterday I suggest the same thing to
people like I personally I didn't finish
college I dropped out and some people
asked me about that and you know those
first few years in your career it's all
about showing that you've got the skills
to pay the bills kind of thing and once
you get past you know you kind of win
people's trust and you can point to your
resume that you have past projects with
success obviously that helps but in
those first early years that's why these
things these certifications and whatnot
can be helpful the weight yeah good you
separate yourself from everyone else
everyone else is coming in with a
bachelor's degree none of them have
searched than you have certs it's just
kind of a way to stand out in the crowd
exactly um Casey had a question about
kind of the market he says given that
the market tends to think about network
and map testing as different things how
do you think that difference affect what
newcomers learn so he said he I think
he's kind of suggesting like how can new
bug hunters kind of make the transition
from app testing to network penetration
testing and how do those worlds kind of
coexist with one another today in your
experience I think as far as application
understanding how to find the
vulnerabilities and stuff you can
translate it because I think if you know
one or the other it's easier to learn
the other I really think most people
getting started out or more intimidated
with the application side of things but
yeah if you're just of course kind of
like it might be showing how to analyze
your skillset and do this the gap
analysis on where you need to go so
that's basically what someone would need
to do look at the areas in a weekend and
because you know even some people that
are doing the web app maybe they
understand web server somewhat and they
understand HTTP protocols and stuff like
that just they just need to I would say
step back and learn the basic
like Network+ related stuff you know and
you have to nest I do that Network+ but
like professor Messer has a whole video
series on a plus and Network+ and
security plus so that's what they we
just need to to learn those areas okay
seems to be the biggest seems to be one
of the biggest hurdles for most people
in general understanding the network and
the piece of it Casey added an
additional thing to his question he said
or nope he just deleted it so maybe he
didn't want that question but um let's
see what else were people asking they
were headaches here welcome to chime in
if you wanted yeah I mean I think
Casey's question was trying to basically
separate out like again like a sub
question to the abstract versus and that
second stuff I think I think my view on
it is most pen tests these days like
they get sold at least are actually
application tests that the network pen
test style of port scanning and
vulnerability assessment leading to
exploitation then pivoting on the
internal network and then exploiting
more things and then getting domain
controller you know access or you know
access to personal data that that
skillset is highly technical but I think
it's I see it less and less these days
and so a lot of pen testers so you
should like do that for their full time
Johnson move to red team jobs where they
they now do like full scope pen testing
and include social engineering and just
do all kinds of adversarial simulation
and so really like you can start out
either way I actually think that think
that net net pen is a little bit easier
than aspect to get started pretty easy
to learn how to like port scan and and
then like do some vulnerability analysis
and it also gets you like really fun up
on scripting and you know sometimes some
exploit development or at least learning
how exploits work and so that's what
it's a really good path so probably more
beneficial start out wasn't that pen and
move into abstract but I think it's I
think with me
a challenge with half-sack is that
there's so many different frameworks and
like web servers and technologies and
aspects so when I started learning
aspect it was super daunting it was just
like there is so much crap on the
internet that I have no idea how it
works so it was beneficial for me to
start in that pen and move to abstract
because I had the hacker mindset and I
knew I knew kind of like that the core
of all security problems are a lot of
the core of all security problems are
like configuration issues and input
issues right like putting stuff close to
go and things being misconfigured and so
it because I knew that from Network
moving the abstract I definitely had the
right mind Tretton I tried to get spun
up on everything else so that would be
my answer I guess yeah I agree with that
I think also too with a lot of people
you know because because you remember
earlier on they weren't doing
reoccurring vulnerability scans
internally and so I think since more
companies are starting to do more of
that kind of between their pen tests I
think there's less stuff out there the
scope of the pen test probably lighter
because they're not fine as much stuff
and it's easily to go easy to go through
yeah I mean I I was just gonna say one
of the things one of our analyst about
Kevin he's you know he worked for us
full time now but he he was in one of my
asset classes and he had zero experience
and a couple of couple that he put
himself through all of the pen testers
lab things and pen tester lab now has
free certifications that you can get if
you complete a whole bunch of their
exercises in a row but you can get free
certification that doesn't like mean a
bunch in the industry but it is a
certification and you can put it on your
resume and like it's you know like I
guess like resume building for a spec or
a pen test or the security information
could probably be its own talk and like
what to focus on how to do it but
there's a whole bunch of paths to get
into this so yeah yeah like the pen
tester lab stuff and how now they've got
it set up to where you can post it on on
your LinkedIn profile shown what badges
you've completed
yeah it's oh someone's actively learning
too small lessons
you
yeah as far as teaching I can't really
think of anything maybe if I could add
like an advanced pentesting course at
the college where I'm at I was wanting
to add what about pen testing which I
was able to add this semester which was
good it was nice to add something new
because after so many semesters teaching
the same thing it's nice to have
something new in there and what is most
profitable if you're talking from a
teaching perspective I guess have you
taught like its sands or something like
that probably most profitable if you did
you know private teaching which for me
it's kind of as interesting because that
someone recently asked want me to do
some training for their company which I
would do but I've had individuals come
up and ask me hey I want you to be my
mentor if I pay you will you teach me
and I can't take money from an
individual I mean I got into teaching to
help other people I teach at a community
college and that's I had the opportunity
to teach at a private school and make
more but I like to be able to teach
people I want people bill afford it if
my dream is if I had say like if I have
a dream come true for me is if I won the
lottery or someone gave me millions of
dollars here do this I would start up a
free school you know I'd offer a free
school and it wouldn't it would be
focused on security and pentesting and
it would start out with some of the more
elementary things to get people up to
speed where they need to be good pen
tester but if I just had something this
big chunk of money I would start a free
school because teaching people that's
one of the reasons I started pong school
was because some people were having
difficulties getting in my class and you
know I wanted something that affordable
for anyone so all they have to do is
show up and learn so if I could do
whatever I wanted to that's why do you
and just teaching helping people is
rewarding you know it's not about the
money because I could make more money
teaching somewhere else but I continue
to teach at a community college I like
that it's affordable most people can
afford it themselves or they can get
student loans or their companies will
pay for it so I like the affordability
yeah that's kind of one of the things I
like about bug bounties and like
bugcrowd they're offering opportunities
to people that otherwise wouldn't had it
have it and that's kind of why I think
I've
kind of fit in with your culture because
I really believe in helping others and
it's just not about not about the money
when it comes to that well that's a good
note - Leon thank you so much
Philip really appreciate the love and
the sharing of knowledge and yeah feel
free to throw up your information there
how can they find you yeah they can find
me on LinkedIn or or Twitter and then
also my hat my website the hacker
maker.com so as we mentioned earlier
I've got a link up for the resources so
it's just learning - resources so if
they want to get those links so feel
free to send mediums I'm constantly
communicating people with people on
LinkedIn or Twitter that are wanting to
get into pen testing or just security in
general awesome
well everyone in the chat please give
him a round of applause on on the
YouTube chat thank you so much Philip
you you can find Phil he hangs out on
our discord as well so you can join the
bit ly / hacker discord and we've got
several of our other folks in there as
well so thank you so much Philip really
appreciate your time great talk and
we'll get set up for our next one thank
you thanks for the opportunity