my name is Alexander I work as a
software security engineer poor in those
open source technology center in today's
thought is focused on a fuzzy approach
that target system components in and
read the main points of the presentation
first we'll have six and that deals with
a set of general methods and concepts
that can be used for housing in an
Android environment this approach will
not try to offer a complete picture but
rather to give an example or a starting
point for someone who is interested in
this topic then we'll see how this
approach applies to several real-life
rising good targets from the Android OS
will see how they approach applies to
finding stage fright which is the media
from Morgan Android and then we'll see
how this approach applies to the Android
application installer towards the end of
the session will also have an
alternative approach will discuss how to
use the popular American flag you look
inside the the Android OS approach first
we'll see a few methods in which we can
generate from this set up for our
funding needs the actual execution or
running of the tests won't be taken into
consideration for the section because
this is a process that is highly
specific for each target so we will
discuss about this in more detail for
example for his project example then we
will go on and see how we can monitor
the results
inside the funding campaign under it
will see how to do this and to get the
results in real-time in the Fortune case
when running a positive campaign and we
have
other results or other crashes we need a
way to automatically sort out the unique
issues so we can see we can develop a
mechanism will see how to how to do this
and in the end when we have only the
unique issues and the few unique issues
need a way to analyze them to debug them
to sort the sort them based on their
severity and receive their exploitable
or not so generally speaking about
causing we have mutational focusing on
one hand and Jonathan focusing on the
other hand causing needs that we take
initial set of inputs or this cases and
we tried to apply different mutations to
them we need to take into consideration
that while applying those mutations we
need to make sure that the target
component system that we are fasting
needs to believe that we are feeding is
valid so we need to pass those initial
test cases but give them structure
invalid generation proton generational
fussing is based on the fact that we
tried to create the march from input
from scratch
we need to know the internals of the
formatter the structure of the data that
we are heading to target and based on
that format we need to try to create an
important that is also my farm but also
structure is valid for the projects that
I'm going to talk about today this is
the to set that we've been using so
first there is the basic funding
framework which is a mutational father
at targets application that applications
that consume filing put this to the BFF
is based on other popular tool
it's based on a modified version of this
still don't have books which is actually
a very small tool but more more
specialized 1 it specializes in
targeting multimedia products both of
these tools work on Linux environments
have announced on down there is actually
a collection of many small farming tools
its main advantage and the reason why we
used it for our project or projects is
the fact that you can pass seat to it so
when you actually get a crash you can
easily go back and reproduce that crash
and also there's the American fuzzy
little I think you are all familiar with
it I'm going to talk more into detail
about it into a separate section of the
presentation so let's say we've
generated Rd and we've executed on the
device we need to wait to see what
happens if it's possible in real time
with that we are feeding 22 the Android
OS if you're familiar with the landing
system Android you know that you can
access it through the locate command the
thing is that each time a fatal crash
occurs which time crash occurs at the
native code level in Android a fatal
message is generated and inserted into
the local buffer the local buffer
contains messages to and from all the
new system components are not only from
applications as well and they are sorted
using priorities there are total seven
priorities for messages that are
including two local local buffer we are
interested in the fate of messages so
what we do each time we
sound test get this case to be executed
on Android device we also partitioning
cert fatal message in the local buffer
so for example this is an artificial
certain messaging to the local buffer
you can see it has a fatal priority here
you can manage using this command the
priority the component and other useful
information about the test case usually
I'd recommend that you answered here
information about how to actually
reproduce a crash for example if you are
facing media files this would be more
simple example we could include hear the
name of the file that was sent to be
decoded on the device and then have that
media files saved let's say locally on
the local machine that is connected to
the meander device so each time you send
that this case we get and when an actual
fatal message that is actually generated
by the system like this one that's a
segmentation fault will have a way to
reproduce that crash because this cases
are sense sequentially we know that
these segmentation fault is Europe is
produced by this component also as I
said earlier it's important to note that
we must including in the message a way
to actually reproduce that crash because
in some cases it won't be possible to
actually saved put that caused that
crash you can you can have information
like seed or or stuff like that
so we generate the data we've executed
and they are and we've generated the
logs for testing campaign let's say
we've run
testing campaign for a period of time
one day and we've generated deadlock
that has the template that I mentioned
in the previous slide if we have a large
number of crashes and we can go manually
through them we can go and check each
photo singer and seed that caused it and
see if it's unicorn up and get
information about that question we need
to wait to sort them in an ultimate
matter what we do is besides the fatal
message that is generated each time
crash occurs in the and read local we
have an entry that is generated in the
daytime storms files on the device so
you have what is known that is generated
for each crash in Android the tombstone
file contains a lot of useful
information contains the type of signal
the code for that signal the value of
the registries at a time of the crash
and back brace for that pressure what is
interesting for us from the perspective
of power from the perspective of the
trust mechanism is the program counter
value for the last component in the
backtrace so this value will be unique
for each crash the thing is that we need
to carefully applied this mechanism
because if we are testing on different
images on the phone bills of Android if
we will have the same identical crash
the program counter will differ so this
mechanism applies only if we are testing
on the exact same bill different runs
here are more details about the actual
implementation of the trio's mechanism
so let's aim had initial testing phase
where we executed the files and we
generated that the logs that have that
specific format we save the logs with
that specific format and we parse them
identified the crisis see what input
produced the crash it can either be
directed the file that produced that
crash or ways to reproduce it and for
each of the identified imports what we
do is right across from the crash we
resent it
device see if it actually crisis the
device if it does generate the tombstone
so we grabbed that one stone which had
the program counter from the backtrace
and if it's a value that has not been
previously encountered many pools that
it is a new issue what we do then is we
save the tombstone because you want
information about the crash and also we
save the input if it's possible or the
exact information about how to reproduce
the crash issues generally speaking we
most cases we are left with a number
that we can go from and try to analyze
them the first place we go to see
information about the crash is as
mentioned earlier the tombstone signal
type and the single code can give us the
first clues of what's going on with that
that crash there are also useful
information in the registry values that
will solve algeria's generally contains
useful information from look at so
additional information besides the stuff
that is that is on the screen
where else can we go we can go to the
message those are two examples of
grasses on stage fright the first is a
narrow for and there were six and this
is how we can identify what is going on
with these errors so one is an invalid
read and wanted to write Jerry speaking
in these are the types of issues that
we've encountered but I'll talk about
this a bit later on you can also use gdb
for that you first need to enable DHCP
server on the device you can do this
case you can either start the process
that you want to debug and attach the
GDP server to the process idea of the
target or you can actually if the
process can be started using an
executable binary you can start to
directly using gdb server and mentioned
the port that will later be used from
the local machine to mention the target
they all you have to do is forward the
TCP port on the local machine on the
machine that is connected to the Android
device restarted EB target the remote
port and continued the reason the
process execution it's also useful if
you have the Android tree and you've
built an image that you've actually
flashed on the device you can load the
debugging symbols and have more
information on your debugging session if
you have access to the source code which
is the case of Andrea generally speaking
there are some bands that you have that
you don't have access to the source code
like 20 what was the exact line of the
source code that produced the crash
occurred at the time so far and the
backtrace and you identify the program
counter value for the components that
you are debugging in the example on the
screen
we don't really want to see the exact
line of code from the functions from
Lipsy would actually we want to see the
component that crashing early stage
fright for example and that is why we
take this program come to value and pass
it to crystalline this is the path to
the symbols from the and retreat so you
need to build an image and i truly
flashes on a device in order to use
address line in this way
ok example how we applied the things
I've mentioned until now to real testing
scenario the station right framework is
the media from working and read it has
been highly publicized lately because of
the so-called they tried but I'm gonna
try to to show you how to report
wrongdoing against it
first of all a few reasons that make
audio and video attractive terrorist
attack vectors
the fact that audio and video are by no
means that something complex data so the
streams are parsed by a lot of
specialized components which can result
in a lot of memory issues memory
corruption issues then there is the fact
that we have a large attack surface this
means that the chances of finding an
issue that is actually destroy the world
are higher in Android and in general I
think there is also the user perception
that media files are harmless so users a
normal user as well
have second thoughts when downloading or
playing media files from untrusted
sources and also towards specifically
because it has basic model and only need
special permissions win for example
surfing the web and downloading a media
campaign or also there was the victor
that made the stationary bike popular
sending the media for this is the
overview testing process in this case so
what we need to have is a large set of
valid media files we try to force them
so too much from them in various ways
using the to say that I mentioned in the
beginning of the presentation but in the
same time trying to keep them structure
we then direct them to the appropriate
decoders so for this specific case the
target is the stage right media
framework we monitored system for
potential issues using very similar
approach the one that I've mentioned
earlier and then because it is the case
the project gave a lot of crisis lot of
results we passed the results from the
three r's mechanism and analyze the
issues separately
project so this project began sometimes
in March 2014 we looked and so try to
figure out how to actually pass the
invalid media files to our target and
the first solutions were passing the
media files to different player
applications from Android or trying to
use the G Java API however the best
solution we came up with was the state
right command line interface that can be
optionally built from beyond retreat
into and then pushed onto an Android
device this had the main advantage that
it bypassed the general air so we had
access directly to the native kohler of
the states right now from work and that
is actually where all the crashes occur
all the issues appear this is an example
of the uses of this by ensuring it has
the main functionality of the coding
audio and video files also for
audiophiles it can offer playback
capabilities there is the advantages so
that you can try to force the uses Java
software codec and hard work over there
so we had two tests in both scenarios
and also the possibility of extracting
the family of four the mediafire this is
also a place where crisis cannot go when
parsing the image associated with this
is an example of an actual that is
constructed using the approach of
mentioned earlier for this specific
example the files were my phone using
the basic funding framework which is I
said is based on a modified version of
Zeus so each time we do what we do is we
have the initial valid media files we
face them locally so not only devices on
performance issues and then for each
first five we send it to the device will
push it onto the device and try to be
coded busing it as a parameter to the
stage fright minor
this time we do this we also assert that
message with the song this case this is
simple we have the funding of the media
file that is also saved locally on our
computer when an actual segmentation
fault appears we all know that this file
is responsible for this crash and it
will be easy to reproduce it because we
have the final say these are strong
results so the project as I said earlier
began in March 2014
this was a time when we first reported
the first issues to google the initial
results so during the first week on a
classroom devices that was composed of
less than 20 device Android devices had
thousands and thousands of crashes and
that's why we had to come out with
automated trust mechanism to sort out
the issues the first serious issues that
affected the stage fright library were
included in the Android partners
security bulletins from September 2014
these were the girl flows are similar to
the issues that are coming on as a
statewide bug they have the CD ideas
from the screen the tool is now open
sourced it has been open source in
February 2015 it's available on github
we don't actually use it anymore as it
is to use it as a complementary solution
alongside with FL I'll be talking about
this
towards the end of the session
I will move on towards the next project
example which is facing the Android
application install process this is an
interesting project from a few
perspectives first there's the fact that
the component that handles the install
process in and read more specifically
during stalled amok
runs with high system privileges so any
issue that is found and is found to be
exploitable can be considered to be a
high-profile issue then having an EPK so
any PK's the file that we used to
install an application on the device
then it begins the file it contains the
job of the composer of a cold and native
libraries it's one of the few ways in
which an unprivileged user can sending
put towards
system components tour's previous
components and Android and also there is
the fact that there are regularly found
by fostering are not usually found by
regular evaluations so are not found by
chicks that are done for example before
the applications are uploaded into the
Play Store we identified two approaches
to testing approaches one specific to
Android versions before lollipop because
of the dog carts which so we 400
lollipop we had done virtual machine
after death or lollipop and marshmallow
we have the Android runtime art the
steps that are taking during the regular
install process in android
we've seen that there are two components
for each of the
Android versions that are interesting
from my perspective in the case of
lollipop and art it was dismemberment
next to vote and in the case of get GATT
and other previous versions and it was
this component they sought takes text
file as a parameter and converts it to
10 85 which is actually regular is then
used to open the application it's the
files stored on the device and its use
to to play the application uses
different file format so it can receive
text file into an optimized text which
is then stored on the device so these
are our main targets the next vote and
accept the thing is that they installed
the month which is the company that runs
with high system privileges for us this
pro processes without dropping
privileges so these are in turn
privilege components they would this
would be general testing flow we need to
have initial set of APK files from apk
files what we do is we take each apk and
we extracted components in this is
basically operation because the PK's
generally speaking just enough I'll then
we was the apk components that are of
interest to us and then in the case of
dog be coming to repair kit SDK and send
it to me and install process in the case
of art the things are more simpler we
can actually are you know she passed
different components directly to the X
200 see about that
components of an apk things that are of
interest to us our classes point X
because this is the fact that we will
actually be facing an alternative
funding target could be the enduring
manifest XML but this is not in the
scope of this project directory contains
the signing information for the apk so
for example if you have an apk and we
start modified things around it the
manifest file the textile and then we
repackage it and try to install it on a
device that won't be possible because
the signing information won't match so
after we modify anything in particular
point decline to reinstall that
application to re-sign it this is the
approach on Android Kit Kat on Dec sup
the thing is that although the next up
is a standalone binary in the Android
device so you can see it in the end of
advice you can pass their other
parameters to pass to it and these can
be obtained from Ursa like environment
so what the solution that we came up
with was to actually simulate the entire
apk install process and for that so we
takin apk we we far as the extracted the
file for the moment let's say we found
it now explain later exactly how we do
this because it's important we remove
the original text from the initial apk
using the apt to we were packaged deal
became known as the new first text this
is not also between we need to create
restore so we can actually signed that
apk we knew that would
the key to we remove the old or outdated
meetings directory and then we signed
the petition that all we have to do is
just run adb install and try to install
the apk excerpt will actually be
responsible for parsing the corrupt text
file and any issues that will occur
generally occur in to this component
thing to do except this is an example of
a log that is constructed using the
following approach mentioned earlier for
this scenario you've used the word
answer to so we need to have in each
message that is inserted into local
buffer is the name of the apk the name
of the initial valid apk and the scene
that we have used to fund the next lap
now we don't actually saved each apk we
just have a safe place when we encounter
people sing like this one assimilation
for all we have to do is take the valid
apk and passage for the process I
mentioned in the previous two slides and
the first step we can use or dams are
too was a text file with the seed and
this should give us the exactly became
that produced the crash in the case of
texts wrote the things are remote
simpler because also there is a
standalone by on the Android device show
you can pass takes out of it and the
father is the output so all you have to
do is just 16 2002 minus minus text file
and the textile you want to pass it in
my notes Minnesota in funding for for
the output this is the log example for
this case
we have named directly the name of the
decks because in the case of the next
time we don't bring the apk so what we
do is we have the initial pool of APK
files and we extract the initial
textiles however if we do encounter
something like this one we take during
shows XRD and visit with redemption in
the seed if if next world crashes so we
have a question that we actually also
try to reproduce the crash in a normal
user scenario we try to me to the next
file into the original apk and try to
produce the crash when using this area
also so for example we show on before
you wouldn't want to include appeal
seeing a report will include a text file
but also the apk file that would produce
the crash it would be the same crash but
with two different attack because they
see as I said earlier the actual funding
of the textile is a little bit tricky
we've identified freeways of performing
the first the fighting against the
textiles the thing is that the Android
OS employees a large number of
registrations at install time against
the textile to check if it's actually
valid so we've identified these free
alternatives I'm gonna go through each
one of them the first one is so these
are examples of those verifications
verification errors so we do have
exposed and start modifying things
through it
these are two types of errors that
encounter for example but file size but
took some other thing is we don't want
these
areas to appear because it means that
the system didn't actually parse input
he just stopped in the header in so that
things aren't alright and there there
isn't a way actually to produce a crash
in this scenario so what we want to do
is to treat the system to believing that
the trial is actually valid for this we
need to understand the text file format
I'm not going to go into detail and
there are few important sections first
there is the header that contains
general information about the file
things like header size file size six
arms magic numbers and you but also
specific information about the section 6
offered to buy this photo ID's header
will contain two fields of set for that
section and the size for that section
fields contain the actual content from
the compile Java code from the from the
compile Java code and also there is
optional field the map that contains
information regarding the officers and
the type of content that is inside each
section
so the first start firing randomly the
file and then come back and try to
repair as much as possible in this case
what we can repair is the magic number
which is a constant the checksum because
we can recalculate the checksum for the
resulting file after the fighting has
been done this is also the case of the
show on signature in the file size these
can both we computed the head of size
and then you are constant values and if
by any chance we modified it during the
round of funding process we we come back
and correct values is a more targeted
one because the data section contains
the more the most interesting
information like strings and variables
we only does this section so what we do
with the initial text file with split
entry we have the first part with the
header and all the sections we had the
second part in how the third part the
map we found was only the data randomly
using renounce up and then we blew
chunks back together and we come back to
the header and tried to fix is not just
possible we started the fields from the
head there that we've fixed as in the
previous approach we can also take a
look at the map upset so for example if
we withdrew funds the data and it grew
in size the opposite of the map will
change and this this field can be
computed we have information we can
actually calculate how big is the fuzz
datafile and also that a precise
these this is actually the approach that
gave the most promising results so most
crashes in the most interesting ones
there's also this approach which is a
completely now fighting method we just
take initial valid textiles and we
passed them food the basic funding
framework we don't look at the head of
it all and then just pass but it back to
the next owned by honoring this would be
an example of log in this case for this
scenario we save all the text files that
are being generated and if actual
segmentation fault occurs or other
freedom single we will have that the X
files saved on local machine results so
the number of crashes wasn't as
spectacular as in the case of stage
fright but in the initial phases of the
project we had about 1,000 crashes not
unique per week on a cluster of thirty
to forty Android devices there is a
critical issue that occurred using the
targeted funding approach we've reported
it to Google and the TV assigned in 2014
November 2014 there are also a lot of
low priority issues that were reported
both in jet and lollipop
but these were not considered to be
exploitable there are the project is
still under development so we have a lot
of issues that are under investigation
to speak a little bit about an
alternative approach that uses the very
popular American Plaza look to a few
words about the tool in general it's an
instrumentation based funding to
Universe 2000 modes the normal and
instrumental mode it also has a third
let's see more though the Peruvian
rabbit note that you know you can feed
crashes to try to get new crashes from
crisis that already occurred its main
advantage is the fact that detects
changes to the program control show and
confine your pets and finding
interesting this cases that can be sent
to the target it's pretty much automated
he detects both crashes and hangs it
tries to do best effort to sort out the
issues I used a modified version of the
two version that was developed by my
colleague Adrian he developed a report
for the tool for Android its public
available now it's on the mailing list
from the AFL to this is how we used to
france stage fright
if you've ever worked with fell to know
that there are few prerequisites before
actually starting the tool in the case
of Android what we need to have on the
device is fruit mounted device these the
route and remount are less serious so we
can push the AFL testing binary and also
the target by for example in the case of
stage fright because the binaries
doesn't come
building to the default and retreat
money to build our own buying and then
pushed on the device so we want to push
down in system being new to have the
device mounted also you want to load
angel seeds things'll valid media files
and a prerequisite that the specific to
film is released to said the scaling
government governor to perform to
performance thing is if the initial
media files contain important that
generates across from the beginning the
DFL to real rejected so if you want to
automate this we need to make sure that
the show scenes that we load onto the
devices do not contain inputs that
producer crash when we are working with
the classroom let's say then some
devices we need to figure out a way to
to do this in an automated manner so
what we tried was we start the fell too
with a timeout and check if it finds a
crash that produced the producers crash
and if it does wait until the time out
dance and restarted again so we have a
loop with a four-run with a timeout when
it gets rid of old test cases that
produced the crash will then go and
start their film normally and redirected
so pretty
results reporting format to definitely
let's say so can we can run it
automated manner
diagram that shows how we've integrated
the custom funding to help so we have
the initial phase the sea generation
were we generate valid first media files
we load the seeds onto the devices were
we start using the the process that I've
mentioned in the previous slide we run
FL 24 period of time usually two or
three days then we get the crashes and
hangs the thing is that on each device
after we report an issue as being unique
but another device will also report an
issue is being unique although the
issues aren't unique for the general
target that is why we need to pass the
crisis the results that if I'll give us
food for custom based closer we pass it
then we generate the logs I mentioned
earlier and from there we have the logs
that are parsed and passed through the
trash mechanism where we actually get
the real issues there's also another
reason why we need to the media files
food our customs officer is the fact
that the media files running on a
restricted environment in FL so you can
see for example you have to set the
memory limit and the time oh we're in
the case of our Father the media files
run more closely to normal use the
scenario so some questions that are
reported to have may not actually
reproduce in normal user scenario
some results using this approach the
most notable was a heap corruption that
could lead to arbitrary code execution
using the media server process this was
discovered this summer it was included
in the Nexus security bulletins from
August 2015 there are also a lot of
protein issues things like more pointed
references or division by zero stuff and
a few conclusions
first of all rounder environment is a
little bit trickier than normal Linux
environment also stage fright is not
really a bug was more like a library
that has a lot to lot of issues and it's
really important know the internals of
the compound that you are targeting so
you can actually have better results
there is also the case when you perform
downsizing and get lucky that's also
building that's about it
these are other people that contributed
to these projects Adrian developed and
report for AFL Costa Marc seem also have
a lot of the incoming port for the
projects of us supported the development
of these projects and also if you have
questions