I am Baltic Sea from for site security I
am very gratified to see so many people
coming up through this is a topic that
is at best
terminally obscure and geeky and I i was
thinkin nobody loves this stuff but me
so much I'll talk a bit about passive
DNS and some interesting conclusions
that we have come to using passive DNS
turns out you could do more with it than
making daily basis that you do lookups
on which were exploring some of these
some of what I want to describe our
commercial products but all over
commercial products are also made
available free of charge to academic
users or other people who have sort of
superhero second lives where they're not
paid for the work they do that uses our
stuff so please don't treat this as a
commercial presentation if you have some
idea of how to make the internet safer
or how to do study using this please
contact me I'm always interested in
grant proposals of that kind
nevertheless this is all output from a
commercial company and I'm very
interested in some of the conclusions I
can draw about the global DNS that we're
not really possible in my previous
nonprofit world in other words takes
quite a bit of equipment and people to
come up with some of the stuff so these
slides are available there was some kind
of an online proceedings available from
blackhead Europe and you will have a
copy of the slides and you know that
there are almost 60 of them I'm not
gonna go through them in detail the
reason we have very detailed slides in
case you want to read up afterward what
I really want to do is get through sort
of the top level of the material and
save time for questions
so I'm I'm counting on you guys to not
be shy leave time at the end it will be
wasted if you don't use it for questions
so everything you do on the Internet
everything anybody does on the Internet
statistically speaking begins with the
DNS transaction every mouse click every
finger tap everything you're doing every
email you send every website you visit
is going to form some number of tcp/ip
sessions that you probably know about
how those are constructed in terms of
the packets but in order to figure out
where to send the control signals of
tcp/ip DNS transaction is done first
what's interesting there is I really do
mean all activities in other words
everything that any good person or any
malicious person wants to do is going to
begin with a DNS transaction and
certainly the world's intelligence
services various governments of
discovered the DNS is a wonderful day
tomorrow I'm going to go look at what
people are looking up in order to figure
out what their interests are no doubt
some of the commercial social networking
companies are doing the same I am going
to describe our approach to personally
identifiable information later but the
important thing for now is to just
realized that if you are malicious
person and you want to do bad things are
going to be incentive in Sandton your
victims to make DNS lookups domain names
that you control or make DNS lookups
that lead to addresses that you control
or maybe name servers that you control
and so by trying to set up the malicious
infrastructure that will be used to
victimize people you're going to have to
put things into the DNS is an awful lot
of anonymity on the internet and
certainly with who is law enforcement
services around the world of told me
that it is absolutely hopeless to
use who is to go find out who did what
to whom for attribution or recourse or
whatever you know part of that is
because of who is privacy where there is
a large number of people who are
concerned about activism political
activism and the possibility that a
nation state could act against its own
citizens if they then had a like a
protest website or whatever I don't
think that's the biggest use of DNA
whois privacy I think criminals are more
likely to be doing that but even when
you don't use whois privacy you don't
really have to use an accurate home
address or phone number or anything else
so we think of who is as a joke but this
is not a joke if you don't put the truth
into DNS it won't work and so if you can
gather an awful lot of DNS material
thing you can find out an awful lot
about what the bad people did in order
to create the infrastructure for various
attacks and show you some of that now if
you look at all of the DNS traffic that
comes in or system and it is over
200,000 events per second coming from a
global network of over 500 servers and
it is a difficult programming problem
I'm not saying that the people at Google
where people have Transpo card
processing data of that magnitude
trivially at this stage with when they
first started it was hard and when we
started it was hard and most of its junk
most of it is duplicative a lot of it is
Dennis tunnels lot of it is just stuff
the gym that won't help you at all look
at it and so we have had to come up with
various ways to filter down reduce the
volume increase the signal increase the
value and one of the things that we've
done is to tune out the old invariant
stuff look for certain patterns like ok
I've never seen this domain name before
you know it is
is it is in dot com it's it's a new.com
name I wonder if it was just created
right now or if maybe it's existed for a
while and I'm just seeing it for the
first time this type of filtering is
absolutely necessary and in the security
information exchange which is one of the
things that I said is available either
commercial or noncommercial depending on
who you are I see some customers in the
audience we have different channels for
different versions of that data so
certainly anybody who wants the 200,000
per second
you know it's it's available but it's
hard and we let people know that as hard
as I mentioned that there's a lot of
personally identifiable information in
the DNS so whatever drawn here is the
standard three-level model of how DNS
works this laptop is representative of
the bottom of this model this is this
would be a stub resolver it is making
queries of recursive servers probably
somewhere in this building that are
connected through the door part of the
service of this wireless internet when
it makes those queries that is
personally identifiable information
because somewhere in the infrastructure
there's a binding between the MAC
address that's a 48 mid Internet address
that this thing uses when it talks on a
wireless and the IP address and later
somewhere in the NetFlow there's going
to be a binding between what that IP
address when contacted and so if let's
say this was used to surf the web surf
some dirt part of the web that was
illegal in this country it is possible
through the use of subpoena power and so
forth for somebody to ultimately
determine that you were probably the one
who did certain things because you were
the one who owned the laptop at the MAC
address you got the IP address you did
the lookups so I don't like that so
further up that church you see the
recursive servers they have a cash and
cash is the reason the DNS is scaled was
originally an academic toy but it's now
serving two billion users and it has
designed hasn't changed much and the
reason is that if you would if this
laptop asks for something that has been
seen recently if somebody else's asked
for in recent hours that's going to come
out of the cash and so all the popular
names tend to get cash everywhere and
then the unpopular stuff the rarely
looked up stuff goes further that's
where workers Observer has what we call
a cache miss a nice to go up to the
authorities servers were content is
injected into the DNS in order to get
the answers would then go into the cash
and then go back to the studs we put our
some serb of the rigors of because I
don't want to know the IP address of the
person who did look up not every passive
DNS collector does this and if you are
using a recursive name server somewhere
that is not yours if you're not the
operator of this thing in the middle
you need to worry about what they're
doing with their query logs because they
know what you did so a lot of perfectly
good free software that will perform
that recursive DNS function for you I
wrote some of it called bond with their
power DNS there's been a lot of very
good software if you're not sure who's
looking at your traffic you probably
should be running your own recursive
name server rather than using Google's
or OpenDNS or your ISP's so I'm not in
the surveillance business I have more
data than anybody as far as I know but I
it's not attached to any end users I
like to help with investigations I like
to enhance investigations but I don't
like to be the place where they start
one of the really hot buttons about any
internet security person would be online
child abuse materials
you know sometimes called child
pornography if I was in possession of
information about who had looked up a
name that I knew was associated with
that I might even have disclosure
obligations to my own local police
department I don't want that not that i
dont wanna stop that from happening I
just don't want to be at that point in
the loop
rather be the place where you can find
out where those demands were served so
that you can go to enhance an
investigation but again I am NOT going
to help start them so upset about that
except to just try to drive home every
time I talk to a new sensor operator to
get my network extended I have this
conversation to let people know I won't
know what your customers did what your
employees did what your family didn't
know any of that because we're looking
above and all that information is below
so distressed details were just said
that there's other information also that
we have to filter out upstream for
example if you have a local network but
is using that and certainly any mid to
large company has a good chance of
having some servers inside your network
that don't have globally unique
addresses there in network tender there
in network 192 168 whenever and if you
were returning information about that
network through your recursive server
you probably don't want it in my
database you probably don't want me to
analyze it that would be information
about internal business prior practices
are internal technology policies so we
filter that out in the field in the
sensor itself but then we filter out
quite a bit more of a day after we
receive the data in the center which is
what I call the security information
exchange so inevitably there is some PRI
of it isn't your IP address is what I'm
saying and then also has to get filtered
out so to the extent that you're
participating in any passive DNS project
or that you think your recursive name
server might be doing check that so
most new domain names or useless their
malicious they are created by somebody
who has the purpose of either committing
a crime or spamming people are annoying
them in some way I will tell you now
that I have watched the stream of newly
observed domain names we take that
200,000 events per second and boil it
down to things that are legitimately new
over the six-year history of our
database and it's about one new
delegation per second it's bursting so
it's about fifty thousand a day to
86,000 seconds in a day so it works out
to about one per second over the long
run half of them are five-letter randa
five random letters top TK which is the
total islands this is a URL shortener
for spammers like bit ly for spammers
you know I'm not sure why we built a
global Internet in order to help those
people do those things but they are a
lot of the rest of it though is not any
more useful than is just stuff that was
created in order to 42 to make a certain
phishing attack work so it might have
some well-known brand name in the middle
of the domain name somewhere and it's
just created for the purpose of sending
too much spam trying to get people to
click on something that maybe they think
is their banker their grocery store
whatever and then credential theft and
then poof the domains gone well as to
these things really we could live
without their there might be a million
new domain names per year that the
internet legitimate Lee needs in order
to facilitate communication between
parties who want to communicate with
each other and the rest is for people
who want to communicate with me that I
don't want to communicate with
background so it's unilateral service
and you see me at the bar later I'll
tell you things I think we could do to
to make that better but right now let's
focus on the analysis
an awful lot of the block lists or IP
blacklist server network reputation
systems actually started the first
antispam company called maps and GPS
back in the nineties which we later sold
to pay our lawyers because it turned out
sending spam was not illegal but
stopping it was an antitrust violation
so learning the hard way but there's an
awful lot of reputation services out
there Spamhaus is probably the best
known and everybody is using them and
when you see those queries in your query
string you probably don't want to save
those either but as criminals create
resources they may get their hands on
some IP address space or they create
some domain names and then they create
some findings in DNS between those names
in those numbers various providers like
Spamhaus are gonna discover this they're
gonna see spam
they're gonna see other than to get
complaints and because we now know that
who is garbage can't complain to the
person who purports to own the domain
you'll pretty much have to stop it
yourself you know you can't stop it from
coming into the internet at the far end
you have to stop it from getting out of
the internet at your near and we do that
with network reputation systems this is
not the most efficient way to build a
global internet but it is just don't
hate the player hate the game so as we
kill more stuff they will create more
stuff that there is not some critical
point above which if we just kill off
enough of their infrastructure though
give up and decide to get real jobs we
have we have to be prepared for endless
escalation along this track is why we
say a lather rinse repeat
hurricane here
DNS if you're just looking at your part
of it that you're creating a vanity name
you might have dub dub dub dub Baltic
Sea don't order something like that it
looks like the picture on the right
words it's it's a big place but it's
mostly static and that's not true as you
sit in the middle of it and watch what
people are looking up which is where we
are it looks much more like the picture
on the left there's just a huge amount
of material flying around all the time
let me give you an example of what I
mean by that we're seeing somewhere
between 150 and 300 newly observed
hostnames per second the delegation
points and it told you about earlier
like name.com and talking about so
domain.com and that means that out there
in the internet host names are being
added to rate of hundreds per second
no I don't think we're adding hosts at
that speed I think most of these names
point to things that are not real hosts
and I'll get into that moment but if you
look at the other view which is how many
DNS changes are we seen in other words
this name in this type like dub dub dub
done example.com would be a name would
be a time for Andres has this name and
type pointed out something differently
before this this moment in other words
I'm I seen a change at delta in the DNS
well we're seeing even more of those
then we see of new host names and I
don't think that that represents the
actual churn of Internet infrastructure
being added and remembered and changed I
just realized two billion users regard
ISPs in every country and so forth I
just don't think this represents real
stuff and I'm I was right
so I have a movie which I'm hoping this
is a debug trace protocol trace of the
new observed them in general are new
leader postname channel so this is
trying to keep up with a three hundred
or so record per second output rate
obviously it's not succeeding but you
get the idea that staring at this would
give you know where you really have to
be prepared to watch this with software
rather than with humanize
caution you against putting it in a
database and then running queries
against it I realized that Big Data
makes that possible but that doesn't
make it useful so we use a continuous
processing model we don't treat security
information lives particles we treated
as waves and so everything I've
described to you so far except that
six-year historical database six years
and growing is done in RAM and we have
just a long string of pearls we're
certainly little Linux blades and limits
when you servers in Iraq somewhere
continue to receive the raw data break
it down further
yet the cooks data from the guy upstream
of them korean break it down further and
so forth
I don't know of another way to process
data at this volume except to do this
certainly if we had had the idea that we
would put everything in a database and
then from the database create the
outputs that we've seen I would have
nothing to show your day so you know i i
am just barely old enough to remember
punch cards and green bar paper and that
is how data processing worked in those
days you put everything in a database
and your inquiries against it and again
makes that possible but that doesn't
make it useful so please as you consider
how you're going to process your own
syslog trials for example think about
how to grab everything that's happened
recently remember the important parts of
what's happened recently in then
basically treated as I don't know
hurricane with puzzle pieces from flying
through the air and if you grab a piece
that happens to fit another piece in
your hand then you're making progress
don't wait for the hurricane and then at
the end of the day see what you got
so the struggle but newly observed
demands and hostnames obviously all host
names are domains so we're stuck with
some bad technical terms here for
marketing reasons our first channel was
called new injured domains by which I
mean delegation points for example in NL
it's possible I think for people to
register names directly under the
country codes you could get all of
exceed and only here and that would be a
delegation point but if I create host
names at my house like server one
observer to dot Baltic Sea . and all
those are not delegation points so
anyway
bear with me I'm sorry for butchering
the terminology but we call that the
longer things host names and the shorter
things domains even though it's really
the longer things are domains in the
shorter things are delegation points
right so we observe demands for new
observed delegation points look like
this in our data scope obviously its
binary data on the wire and so what
you're seeing here is the domain we
discovered the delegation point we
discovered and when you're looking into
the region the DNS transaction that
caused us to discover it and in this
case the resource record name was the
same as the delegation point that this
is this shows us no longer names but it
does in this case tell us what the name
servers were for a delegation point that
is potentially useful information if you
have some idea that other things that
have pointed at the same nameservers
turned out to be evil maybe this is evil
to you know that's the kind of thing
that you have to kind of thinking that
goes into the continuous process and in
describing anyway we're not saying that
all new demands are bad I happen to know
that that's true but that's not what we
say what we say is nearly 20 mins newly
observed demands deserve
have extra scrutiny good so welcome to
come to that later here are some demands
that we saw we took a twenty-four hour
snapshot of our newly observed I mean
channel we just looked around for people
and some other fairly well known brand
names and we found that people get used
a lot and if you look at the bottom 100
people update information I D mumble
mumble it was clearly part of a phishing
attack that was where somebody got some
targeted email that said PayPal can't
reach you until you go and correct your
information please login by clicking
here and if you're not an information
security professional you gonna look at
that and say oh PayPal update you click
on that it's sad that we had to build
the whole human economy with monkey DNA
but that's what we are willing to click
on things
PayPal accounts all.com and so forth
I'm using PayPal's my example obviously
there are thousands of brands that are
abused in this way but to be
successfully abused in this way you have
to have some idea that people really are
likely to be customers of it right if
you get this email and you are not
people user you're gonna you're going to
know what's false so you won't see
things were grocery store however make
sure beer but you will see your bank and
you will see who your cable TV company
and so forth but a lot of the in those
examples you see the lot of the branding
violations were not at the top level
right so then the second one for example
account check PayPal account check paper
held up pick whatever don't come pick or
pmdd come is what shows up as a newly
observed delegation point but the longer
name is what you what actually is used
to carrying the militias information
which is the the branding solution and
that's why we have a second channel that
second channel is going a lot higher
volumes hundreds per second as opposed
to one or two per second
here's one of the observed first name
looks like so it's very similar schema
and you see the domain name that we
pulled out of it but you can also see
that they are named had this pile of
junk . the the delegation point and I'm
not gonna try and say that word you can
whatever but it's a real words in the
dictionary and the its interests I don't
have no idea how they come up with this
stuff
perhaps they have a dictionary that
feeds them names but we did some deeper
checking on that wanted to say right
what is this and who is was useless so
we went deeper into it said that was a
CNAME CNAME is an alias in the DNS that
means if you look up the our name you're
going to get redirected to the thing at
the bottom there called the our data so
let's take a look at our data front
instead secret media dot com that
doesn't sound safe to me that sounds
like something you might want to avoid
so we get around on their website
learned almost nothing except the Wall
Street Journal's had an article about
them being an advertiser who is pretty
good at evading at blocking and turns
out that's what this is for which is
that these are the names that appear in
the website and saw your ad blocker
would have to know every one of those
random gibberish things . this
unpronounceable second level name in
order to know that this was an ad
because the ad blocker doesn't get a
chance to see what the CNAME points to
know that the CNAME should be poisoned
in anything that points to it should be
poisoned so it's a layering problem with
that is kind of a loophole in the way of
blogging happens I'm giving you can
expect to see a lot more of this and
then the web browser people will catch
up and actually exposed the CNAME to the
ad blocker plugin in order to to close
this loophole so yes this is it's just
random crowd
we looked around to see if there was any
pattern to it there there there was a
little bit of a pattern to it but not
enough that you could hook onto it with
some algorithmic plugin you really have
to know what is what seemed at points to
if you're going to discover that this is
something that a blogger should should
grab but we also looked for me since we
have a database to go back six years we
looked in center and can we just find
all of the other things that have
appeared in the last week that we're
seeing aims to that same place we found
seven hundred thousand of them it shared
this particular unpronounceable second
level name but then we found a whole
bunch of other interesting stuff atomic
power seductress now I want to go there
so we have drilled down on a single
example but you understand that in the
24 hour sample we took there was a
hurricane of similar wreckage
if you want to protect yourself from all
of that you're going to need to spend
some time contemplating that hurricane
and deciding what it means to you and
what what it means to you in terms of
policy that you might want to have
toward these new names or policy you
might want to have toured domain names
that have this type of structure of this
type of pattern like being a whole bunch
of different things all seen him into
the same place that could be something
you just decide it's got that many see
names I don't want to go there no matter
what it points to ok I do want to say we
in the security industry are clearly all
trying to do well by doing good right we
want to get paid for doing meaningful
work and a lot of the meaningful work
involves two defense it involves
figuring out what the criminals are
doing now or what they're going to do
next to them helping our customers avoid
damages from from those actions and
that's all good but we need to do more
because this to me what I shown you so
far
signals a structural defect in Internet
Governance itself right the DNS is not
was not created by a company owned by a
company called a lot of companies behave
that way it is so we create the danis
every day by making queries into it by
putting our content into it and we need
to take a look at how it's being used
and how it's being governed and see if
maybe
changes to the way domain names are
registered changes to the way who is
handled changes somehow to the way
criminals are allowed to use this could
maybe save some of us some money rather
than having this endless cat-and-mouse
escalation by my DNS changes so far I've
told you about newly observed delegation
points and newly observed fully
qualified names and that's interesting
but we decided to look deeper and since
we're seeing somewhere between half and
two-thirds of is my estimate of how much
of the DNS we can see from where we are
it becomes interesting to look at the
Delta again these are changes where you
had a certain name in a type that
pointed to a certain value up until now
10 points at something else will what is
responsible for that change it could for
example have been something we call fast
flux which is a way of evading take down
it could be that somebody had a
legitimate renumber an event they had a
server then needed to move it to a
different subnet they give it a
different address and that shows up as a
change how do you tell the difference
well let me give you some examples so
this is a one record snapshot from
channel 249 the security information
exchange and see the timestamp you can
see it's a new domain record seed Li
tutsi see was the name and here you can
see we've got those 51 areas of the body
I'm telling us it's not a new deal
mainly food or about the domain name for
a while we know about the art this are
named for a while and we note about this
army man tied together for a while but
we've never seen this are are associated
with it before and so that means that
the are set the set of borrowers
associated with it is also a new so that
address becomes interesting 2009 at 126
$2.99 at 2:31 wasn't previously pointed
to by this so it's gotta have some kind
of service on it now services are very
lightweight lot of IOT devices are
actually servers even though they cost a
nickel so I don't want to make servers
sound like they're heavyweight expense
of objects but still the existence of a
new one can be for good purposes or bad
and in this case it was bad
through this year was an interesting
example we have differing this by
replacing the actual ASCII . characters
with bracket because this is something
that virus total vote that's one of the
virus total told us is a current example
there is actually a virus which is new
enough that it's infected a lot of
people that is generating queries like
this with you generate queries like
those you could expect a phone call from
your ISP perhaps so in this case we had
this random looking name that had an
address
8885 dotty dot 170 and there is stuff
posted there that you do not want to be
caught fishing and so this is criminal
stalking other criminals in this case
this is not malicious software so much
as malicious content and the what made
their address interesting is that it was
suddenly pointed to buy something and it
had not been pointed to before now so I
think every new address needs to get
scrutinized every new name needs to get
scrutinized it's sad
that that's true I wish that Internet
Governance worked a little bit better so
that we didn't have the indy five
percent or more of the new content on
the internet being malicious in some way
but given that that is the situation I
think we all have to start saying that
if its new it deserves scrutiny and all
of our research supports that accept
this content delivery network they
specialize in hosting content for people
become globally available it's available
in every country they serve it with low
round trip times low latency high
bandwidth and so on there there is one
of the first really successful companies
that does this but they do it in DNS and
show almost every answer they give is
tailored for the particular user who
asked the question which means that it
looks new and different but it isn't
it's actually it means the same thing
it's just pointing different domain
names into different parts of their
global infrastructure and so as you
start processing things and you say
cocaine these new bindings these new
names are new addresses are unknown
binding between a name and address
deserve scrutiny one of the first things
you're going to do is wait lists all of
the CD ants and yes that'll make you
blind to malicious content that is
hosted there but Akamai at least has a
very active abuse department they take
down the bad content fast enough that
you don't need to worry about them being
used as a loophole against you but we
have to wait list because they're
responsible not Akamai itself but about
half of the 300 pence per second that
we're seeing in our excuse me $600 per
second that we're seeing are some
seating area somewhere and you know you
don't waste your investigatory powers on
stuff that is probably not trying to
hurt you so ideally oil filter it out
down through global
noise level that you can actually spend
a little bit of energy looking at
everything that comes out the far end of
your of your deepest filter ok I'm
rushing through this twenty minutes left
ok so we decided I think I mentioned
earlier that we did a 24 hour snapshot
and when we gone deep on a couple of the
things we found in a 24 hour period and
then let me tell you the characteristics
of the full 24 hours we ended up with 29
million changes that we're seeing in a
24 hour period and you can see the
normal diurnal pattern so you can figure
out from this exactly which
industrialized nations were awake and
using facebook or or whatever different
times but my god that's a lot of changes
so these new delegation points apiece
domains were interesting in this case
told you it's normally one per second
here it's about two per second train
there's 86,000 seconds in a day here we
saw about twice that number of new
delegation points created raise your
hand right now if you think that that
looks good content got added to the
internet during that time so clearly
this is this means that dennis is a good
business to be in I guess Verisign and
NuStar and all the various top level
domain registries and go down in the
other large volume registrars know that
but I'm sort of letting you know that
there is a huge market for creating the
stuff there are discounts there are ways
to get them for close to nothing since
we are rejecting emails that has started
quads in the body of our messages we've
taught the spammers that they need new
domain names for almost every message
they sound and so the industry has
responded by learning how to create
domain names at that speed and at a
price point that spammers can afford so
so Verisign had a different estimate
which I thought was interesting they
thought that dot net had grown about
one-third as much as what we saw net
which they would they were looking at
the domain name to find out how many
names they had seen created during a
year and our estimate is that there
should be about 64 million of them
there's was a lot smaller so it turns
out that they don't use the PSL
so the public public suffix list was
created by the browser community in
order to figure out what the the top
level of a cookie should be so if
somebody tries to give you a cookie for
calm hoping that you use you allow
anything ending in.com access to the the
DOM for for that web page and so forth
that's a cross site scripting
vulnerability so the PSL is just a
ham-handed coarse-grained filter to try
and keep that from happening but it also
helps us to determine what is and is not
a delegation point so for example it
isn't always a second level name in the
UK delegation point will tend to be
under . CEO dot UK which is their
version of dot com and so the simplistic
way of thinking about it where you would
say anything that is at the second level
is probably in television point won't
work around the world there are some
things even longer than that if you look
at some of the dynamic dns providers
where they are effectively a TLD in the
sense that you can buy subdomains of
something but it might be a third or
fourth level named by the time you're
done paying for it so you really need to
be looking at the PSL and we love her
friends to various I know that their
report was wrong because they had not
done so we saw seven million newly
observed long names in that same period
and those who make seven million of what
we saw here knew our names it if you
extrapolate this we're looking
almost three billion new fully qualified
names per second per year and I wish
that was wrong
most of these are short lived which is
why the DNS doesn't grow without bounds
and then explore because of the laws of
thermodynamics most of these things are
taken down because they are criminal or
their abandoned after they have been
abused and then they don't get paid for
so they didn't look at this stuff
disappears mostly in the same week that
it's created but we also want to take a
look at data types of all the changes
all the things that we're knew where was
most of the change and here when you
look at SOE changes this does not
include serial number changes this was
something else about it so I and what is
mostly was was a new as a way that we
haven't seen before so it is a start of
authority Institute thing at the top of
a zone that tells you how to tell us
administrators and other name servers
had a handle that so obviously a records
ipv4 was the big winner interestingly we
had almost a third of a percent of our
sample was ipv6 that is better than
we've ever seen so that I don't mean I
don't wanna say that that gives me hope
that 36 could take off some day but at
least it's not dead yet and we have the
equivalent of high-frequency trading
here and I'm not gonna
I'm gonna run at a time if I go through
this in detail so I'm not going to do
that and i mentioned CD announce
location dependent dancers the study is
worth reading and if you like these
slides and you want to see more we
actually have a longer technical paper
about this on our website for security
dot com and again you can see Akamai
dominates so we we will ultimately come
up with a secondary channel that takes
the changes channel and simply filters
out all the CDM stuff in order to create
a lower volume higher signal higher
value channel
so that people who want to do this type
of analysis will have a starting point
that isn't full of all those could which
really is it's the one of the things we
do the most often when doing the type of
waterfall or continuous process and then
I'm describing is reduced filtering
stuff out and trained make a fair value
of derivative of the channels and the
raw data which is it's both a fire hose
in volume and its deluge in terms of the
number of different particle types so I
am gonna just skip a lot of this because
it's just too would take way too long
programmatic name generation you've
probably all heard of demand generation
algorithm that's on Flickr was a famous
one back in 2008 2009 the idea of a DGA
botnet is that if you want to infect a
bunch of computers with software that is
going to contact you
the bad guy to get its instructions like
you should I did officer who should I
spam you know what would you like me to
do and I'll get it taken over this end
user's computer you have the problem of
if you use a domain name then it's very
possible that the law enforcement will
come to your house and take all your
stuff so what you do is you don't use a
static name in the case of conflict or I
don't know exactly what this was born in
case your contractor was done based on
the day and so they ultimately would
start a random number generator a
pseudo-random number generator using by
seeding it with the day of year and the
year so on any given day it would be
trying fifty thousand names that we're
somewhat unique to that day there were
not good math people so there was a lot
of collisions on the same name that used
on more than one day they were slobs
compared to the guys that do it today
but you know it's been six or seven
years and what that means is that the
bad guy has an opportunity especially
since these names were split over a
hundred and sixteen different effective
to oldies which were in
hundred and ten different till the is
and some of those TLD is where small
island nations that don't exactly have a
large security team that is ready to
block this stuff what that means is that
if the bad guy decides that on a certain
day he wants to actually command the
botnet what he has to do is register one
of the fifty thousand names it's going
to use and if you can register it and
get contacted by his box faster than we
can notice that he's registered it and
take it down then he will have signaled
a botnet to go do something potentially
damaging it was the largest botnet I had
heard of at the time its contractor had
11 million unique IDs per day coming
into our sinkhole there are bigger ones
narrow but it was him but contractor
itself is only shrunk down to about 2
million a day there's still a million
and it's been seven years might indicate
that we don't care as much about DGA as
as as we as I think we should anyway
there's notify get notified 869 are you
is not a DGA so actually way off topic
here this is Ben in the Spamhaus
blacklist for quite some time we're not
totally sure what these names are but we
know they're programmatically generated
and I'm gonna just we're down to our
last 15 minutes here so i'm ok here we
reversed
and we change the dots who the bracket .
and so you can see that PayPal appears
sometimes at the end sometimes in the
middle of labels sometimes as a label in
the middle of a domain name sometimes
misspelled with two else this is the
kind of thing that bad guys are doing
you know I am NOT going to say who is or
is not our customer but I will say that
we we do sell this to some commercial
people who want to do brand protection
order for themselves or for their
customers and this is the kind of thing
that you guys will need to be doing at
some level whether you pay somebody else
to do it or whether you decide you're
going to do it yourself you need to be
paying attention to the way that your
trusted more marks are being used online
far from your network ok so I started
this company thank you started this
project as part of a non-profit company
I used to work out internet systems
consortium in 2007 I took it private and
made it into a commercial entity in 2013
because I was capital constrained it was
not that I was not paid well enough it's
Anna could not by enough equipment to
hire enough people to do the job and
went to serve to be done I'm trying to
increase the observability of the
internet trend have a deal it instead of
every security company coming up the
gate and setting up whatever sensors
they can set up and then building
fortresses around those sensors to keep
their competitors from being able to see
the same things because ultimately
competition was how you win customers
build revenue and so you're company is
one of the structural defects that I
talked about it is something we do wrong
that helps the bad guys
honest-to-god there are some of these
cease operating on Sand Hill Road in
Palo Alto and Menlo Park not far from my
house that specialize in creating new
security companies and then
running them in the traditional Harvard
MBA style of building boats around every
one of them and if I were a bad guy I
would put tens or even hundreds of
millions of dollars into that company's
funds because they helped me so much if
I'm a bad guy we just can't we can't
overlook this we can't pretend that this
could happen against our will we have to
be complacent and we have to be
complicit in order for things to get
this bad this fast so that's why we
started this that's why I'm growing it
commercially that's why we make this
data available both commercially and and
on commercially I want everybody to know
what's going on so that they can all
either do something about it for
themselves do something about it maybe
as part of a internet superhero
nighttime project maybe do something
about it for their customers but also so
that we can all be jointly aware of how
bad it is so that we might be able to
put some pressure on Internet Governance
to get the systemic defects fixed at
that level as well
whois privacy is just a travesty i I
cannot find a defense of that or let's
take another example when I was a kid I
dot com name took two or three days to
create because they don't come zone was
only generated twice a week and so if
it's generated on Tuesdays and Fridays
and you created on Tuesday you might get
it in that day a few critter Wednesday
or wait till Friday that seem reasonable
to me because I gotta say nobody no team
anywhere
spends months developing content
developing an idea for a new business
and then gets to the day of the launch
and says oh my god I forgot to register
the domain name for now because they had
a race to the bottom right . bills and
done in phone not separately then
ordered people all came in and said we
gotta find a way to distinguish
ourselves from Verisign well they're
only publishing twice a week where we
can publish every day Verisign looked at
that and said I think we could do it
every hour
somebody else so I think we could do it
every 10 minutes and somebody else oh no
I think we could
every five minutes eventually then race
to the bottom and you hit the bottom and
turns out the speed the photo and only
travel through fiber at a certain fixed
maximum rate and so by the time Liard
unsettling and done getting all of your
servers about 30 seconds has gone by and
so that's why thirty seconds is the
reference standard now for creating a
new generic delegation point but can
anybody tell me please what the non
criminal purposes of a thirty second
turn around for a new domain name
because when I needed one for let's say
for site security not come you know
anytime that month would have been fine
so because of these new channels you
gonna watch all kinds of stuff you
couldn't watch before we have one
channel that pulls out just the annexed
domains and that means that if we've got
academic teams out there who were doing
DGA research where they're trying to
reverse the reverse engineer the
algorithm that creates these names and
then they're sort of looking for you
know where who is patient zero what was
the first part of the world this name
god looked up in you know we actually
have enough data to inform that research
and their commercial prospects as well I
don't sound like I'm still in the
nonprofit world I just came from there
and then finally you know there's an
awful lot of weird stuff and some of it
you can discard on moscow you can come
up with simple techniques like oh it's
Akamai so I'm not going to look at that
others might require some serious
competition to figure out what you're
going to ignore and then cut the station
is a form of wisdom because it will
teach you
which parts of the internet or being
used in what way and again the internet
was not created by a company is owned by
a company the Internet as an illusion
that is made up by us who use it and
that's because we decide to follow the
protocol but our systems work and that's
because we all follow the same protocol
that other people can get work done and
can make money and can create new
companies and so forth
so somehow out of this group illusion
that we all jointly create we also need
to take the reins in hand we need to
decide what kind of an Internet we want
to create we're using our power
mindlessly we're creating an internet
that we don't like five minutes and I
hope that you're gonna fill them with
questions
user
so technology has been trying to secure
DNS itself so we have transaction
signatures to protect zone transfers
against tampering of DNS sec to allow
crypto authenticity seek invalidate when
you receive something that I really was
generated by the owner of that domain
rather than a be inserted by some
advertiser in the middle maybe it's
supposed to be a negative answer but you
got a positive answer and you visit the
website and it is an ad that is related
to the question you were asking there's
a lot of different kinds of poisoning
I'm not seeing the connection between
poisoning and who my service of Akamai
so can you restate that part of your
question
yes
ok so Pasadena system we go through five
or six stages between deduplication and
junk filtering and so forth as possible
and sure most of you know the to steal
wifi in a coffee shop by running a VPN
over DNS because they're paywall allows
DNS to work even before you paid the
money all of that stuff is trash that I
don't want to my database and who is
Mike worried that you described as on my
list of poison that is something that we
had to discover ultimately by looking
the the graph of names if if some if
there's a name that has too many
children we look at a human has to look
at it so calm as a hundred and thirty
million children at last count and it's
allowed to have that many children but
if it's some deeper thing and it's got
millions of children that's an
indication that we better study and that
it's probably something like what you're
describing in particular the video CD
and people are not as mature technically
as Akamai there are an awful lot of CDN
producers that there should be a video
CD ants that partner up with cable TV
companies they will have it be that if
you wanna watch a certain recorded TV
show pre-recorded TV show or
movie or something like that that will
send you a to a pay wall and then after
you enter your credit card or your
password or whatever it is you meander
they give you a CNAME to give us an
impact your browser so that your browser
will connect to the place that will
actually start the media stream and
that's seen a manned up encoding your
end user IP address in clear text plus
your region plus maybe your customer
number of sometimes your password it's
all in there so when we see that
somebody on my staff will start changing
our filters so that we stopped recording
it we will schedule you know major
renovation of stored data from two years
ago to remove it from the permanent
record and we're getting on the phone to
that video CDN provider to to explore
with them the possible benefits to their
business of one-way hashing so that's
what we do have one minute left any
other questions
so for the purpose of these slides we
didn't do anything fancy when you grow
up obviously the people that we sell
this feed to our professionals at this
and they're using sound effects and
other similar types of things such that
if it looks the same or sounds the same
one spoken they will treated as
suspicious and then they'll have a
scoring system and if they find enough
different reasons to treated as
suspicious they'll open it taken on
human eyes will go after it so you know
a true amateur system other than making
the slides for the presentation would
certainly want to say that if it's if it
would be Microsoft except that one would
have to be changed to an eye then you
want to treat that as Microsoft but we
didn't do that so that is something our
customers do in this case we're not in
the brand enforcement business we just
sell wholesale to other security
companies who have that is one of the
sidelines I am in 20 minutes so I'll be
in a hallway you can stay as long as you
want but I gotta get off the stage
before the hook comes thank you very
much