thanks so much for a stick around as
long and coming to our talk money to
spend on a recent graduate of the
University yelling no posts tagged in
Indiana University in the great pleasure
to give the talk today with my
colleagues at the University at Buffalo
and that their personality was actually
wanting was not able to make it to you
but he was still part of this this
project so what's the project that we
will talk to you about or give you a
brief agenda of what's to come to first
we gotta talk about the same origin
policy which most of the people might
probably know but still it's important
technical background that we will talk
about the concept of what we call a
cross-site scripting solutions and then
we would erase this generalized this
kind of attack and under must and will
talk about the period of study we
conducted on the web and then talk with
the conclusion that sold the same origin
policy is the most basic security policy
on the on the web
let's assume for the sake of the
argument that we have an attack that has
successfully lured victims resided in on
this page where you can obviously
because it's under control you can also
retrieve HTML but also he can host some
javascript in August tries to gain
access to a remote domain in this case
gmail.com and one very important thing
to note in this cases that since its
founding in your browser if you have
cookies that are valid for gmail.com in
your browser will attach these cookies
to the outgoing request to gmail.com the
reply will come in and this would
obviously be really big security problem
right because in this case as an
attacker could simply read all your
emails from gmail that is exactly where
the same origin policy kicks in and
stops into action because the states
that only resources which sharing
analogy is hereby defined protocol the
hostname or IP address and the port may
interact with one another and this this
is not the case then the same origin
policy actually drops this connection or
just as excess
gmail emails safe however it's slightly
different from JavaScript so if you
think about you often think about jQuery
jQuery but a lot of the multiple
vehicles to themselves but rather have
for example hosted so there needs to be
a way for your browser to include script
content from a different domain
it's also often the case with
advertising because of advertising that
running on your side you don't want to
force the JavaScript itself but rather
have the and therefore the same origin
policy somewhat reelect for scripting
commands so it's perfectly okay to use
scripts for us
remote domain and your browser will
actually fetch till steps and then
execute them in your page and one very
important factor in these cases that
included cold inherits the origin of the
including side that means I have to take
a lot of work and I route something from
si.com then the cold running in a
technical or both run on the same cold
it's cold and why this has security
implications if the availabilities in
the third party code as we will see in
the stalker had also some security
implications the other way around
so let's go back and will be to 2006
gmail was hosting a file
context of Jason would actually have the
context context story of the user who is
currently locked in this case I we see
this John Doe and Jane Austen's contact
and what it could do is he could have
his own website and then to the
following so you would do a script
source of gmail.com / contact Jason but
this doesn't look like the JavaScript
code words
executing anything however there was
back then which would actually allow you
to override the era con structure that
means in this case the fire would be
included and then the jaws capacity
would say this is a new era when I have
to invoke the instructor and their guy
in here you could easily steal this this
secret a time there were a number of
attacks for example with us we're
basically the JavaScript engine would
interpret things as it should interpret
because it looked like JavaScript or
even in one case you wouldn't executed
but it would give you an error message
that would say some variable not defined
whatever you could lead the content of
these of these felt however inclusion is
basically an attack that is a little bit
more widely defined the previous attacks
as I said before with this reconstruct
other issues related to the
implementation of the browser via text
so doing that now will not work anymore
however but we would have to kind of see
is are there are other ways to leak like
private and one thing that all these
attacks have in common is that they are
you a script source and then included
some content that looked like a script
but no one's afraid she looked at what
happens if I try to look at just hope
that is actually be a regular pages to
stick to that is
maybe some dynamic nature to those found
so I only static or is there some
dynamic duration and if that is the case
it is actually some dynamic component in
there is there any sensitive userdata
increase this script that might be
dynamically generated on the southern
side and then last but not least whether
it's actually possible for her to get
this kind of information over the way to
my colleagues of us a little bit about
the methodology and the abilities
thinking then yes we are looking for
JavaScript process and we are
specifically interested in JavaScript
routes that are generated by the sober
and we also addressed in the userdata
userdata is usually somehow connected to
a user session so basically we're
looking for JavaScript files that are
generated based on the user's
authenticated session and it just me and
for this purpose we build a system that
were detected script and just report
them to us and with this system we don't
conducted an empirical study to see
whether we find scented if you had a $10
goodbyes and whether we can leave them
across the main boundary similar to the
attack that just showed so let's have a
look at the detection system for so this
will be billed as about extension so
here we with with a normal browser we
just visited website which we are called
the outcome and this will not come might
have the legitimate script that this
site uses to to provide some
functionality and what we would like to
find out is if this group is dynamically
generated and has used it in sight so we
built about extension that runs in the
browser and while he battles will not
calm it would fetch all the scripts from
the page and it would try to find out
whether there is some state dependent
generation going on so what the
attention didn't it requested the script
twice in one stated with cookies so with
the India authentication context of the
user and runs without cookies so we got
to two different so sorry Mr Jobs
prosthetic we get basically the same
trial back into somehow dynamically
generated based on the user's
authentication state we should see some
some difference in the script and that's
exactly what we tried to find out by
dishing the two different responses so
whenever we see a diff that there is
like a change we we know this javascript
might somehow depend on the user's state
so what did then is we went to the Alexa
top 500 websites and we registered
accounts for the first 150 sides that
allowed us to register counts so they
had to have a registration form it
should have it it had to be possible to
register free of charge without paying
money and also the registration had to
be possible for us so some sites
required social security numbers of
countries that we weren't able to get
and so we just reached registered to
those sides that it has that and then we
went to those sites and manually see
that the sides with you the data so we
were interested in whether scripts might
contain userdata so we need to put the
user dating to the application process
so we went to all the sides and for
example in a in a shopping application
we put things into a shopping cart we
created wish lists in a social media
source social networking site we created
an account and sent messages or interest
or two away
or something so so that we get some
private data into it and afterwards we
use our extension to browse the site
again and he was a different kind of
functionalities and to all the pages and
like interact with the site and Encanto
all the different scripts to decide
where he was and always tension reported
all the scripts that were dynamically
generated and these are the results that
we found so we investigated 150 pages
and we found that 49 of the pages had
some kind of dynamic generation of
scripts so dependent on the user session
state and we manually look at these
forty nine trials and we found out that
34 of those types contained unique
identifiers of the users so there was an
email address or an account I D Onofrio
name and birthdate something that
uniquely identifies you as a user with
entrant at 15:50 script pages have
scripts that contained other personal
information like your street address I
don't know you're maybe your shopping
shopping cart entry your email address
email us your banking information and we
even from seven pages that had seized of
token authentication tokens in scripts
and so it seems to be a lot of diverse
groups that are dynamically generated $1
comprise contain very sensitive data so
the question is now can read the data
somehow like the attacks that appeared
to 2006 and for this I quickly want to
reiterate on the on the attack model so
what we've had is we have a set of
renewable websites we have tried that we
control here its attack of the door and
we we assume that means some are able to
drive uses to their websites so by
sending out links by email
or contact your child or something and
in this website we can include the
script that dynamically generated from
will not calm and this would generate a
request with users and based on this
cookie the runner combo to generate some
kind of service I'd hoped would run some
kind of server-side script and generate
the JavaScript code then it would send
that generated code back to the to
deposit the browser will just say ok
this is a jobs proposal executed and
basically what we're trying to do is we
tried to poison this environment so as
we learned this script here this runs in
the origin of a decade or so basically
uses the global scope of attack dog and
we are trying to come up with him some
javascript that would poison the global
the global space and the global
functions that are winnable in in that
website so to make this script leaked
the data to that functions and basically
I will only present the most obvious
ones because of timing reasons we found
at five different methods to lead global
and local variables and so on but I
don't have time for all of them so the
first message is obvious so description
I just have global variables so here are
three different kinds of global variable
declarations and JavaScript and it might
be just generate a variable that is
called first name and contains to use
his first name or email address and
Twitter status very easy so the attack
includes descriptive in a technology and
then after executing the script
the global variable BB
herbal in the global space so the attack
again just exit sub I just with aiding
attacked or the attacker can learn who
you actually are looking at the Scripps
of the pages did you actually looked
into the second approach is also very
very obvious so what be resized at work
sites usually split up the functionality
so they have like a base library that
contains all the common functionality
and then they have like some business
logic that would you still common
functions and so on and usually the base
libraries including this one script and
the business functionalities in to read
the second script so what he can do is
an attacker instead of like including
the that the common base library you
just write your own base library with it
the same set of function names all the
functions are available to the script
and then you just include the script
which will pass some sensitive user data
into this this library function here and
if you set it up correctly you will be
able to receive data detect until we
concede so the attacker would just in
this javascript declare his own library
it would set up that the function that
has the same name as the script and then
you can just exercise whatever data
dinner so these are the most obvious
once we have also some some methods
where you can read local variables that
are not passed a global functions but
that's too complicated for justice 25
minutes talk so we then tested all these
methodologies against the scripts that
we actually find these are the results
so after 39 scripts or 49 domains to be
found
we were able to exploit forty of the
domains and the reason for not being
able to exploit the other nine is that
for these 90
able to guess the URL of the script so
the script that was dynamically
generated had some kind of token in
there for example a few websites he was
a session IDs passed in the Urals and we
were not able to guess he's taken so we
were not able to like include the
scripts within our page and I think this
was near a coincidence that we were not
able to do I think what developers are
not aware of all of this issue and
nobody protect against it I think it was
just quit and basically what we would be
wary between chief is from the Saudi for
domains that had a unique identifiers we
were able to meet this identifies of 28
pages so basically this enables us to do
DNA methylation by getting it is added
to our page we were able to tell his
email address or his name and so on and
so forth from the 15 occasions where we
had personal data personalized a time
the script we were able to exploit 11
and we found all kinds of things we
found phone numbers email addresses we
found banking data credit card numbers
and so on and support from the seven
scripts that contained see-saw
stockman's we were able to exploit for
us and I would present a few of them
soon so now I would like to go away
little demo that we prepared and I hope
it works he actually do this because the
poorest posture and then the network
here and more stable so you can exceed
but that's actually browser window its
website that we set up a website and we
control and I'm not going to show the
source code of this website because
these actual winner abilities so we
contacted all of those forty websites
and told them hey you have a problem
there we got three responses of suicides
and two of them fixed it and one of them
didn't understand the first level
support in understand
rented from them and he just dropped the
case so we have plenty of examples so
let me quickly we had stayed December
times we have three different things and
this will actually be pulled from
different sites so this could just be an
arbitrary web site that you visit to the
first one is quite interesting so now we
did it gets the script I hope it works
yes it works so it includes this script
from another page that I'm not going to
disclose it found in a script the name
is our testing account of this user and
it actually found the phone number of
this user and this because on the side
you had to provide a valid phone number
then an extra pick someplace from
shopping side so the shopping site
allows you to create wish lists on the
shopping side and just wish this was
shown like in the budget on the page and
they used to dynamically generated
script to get the data to the page so
let's requested and waiting for some
time it takes awhile because it's really
slow so he is the wish lists of the big
quite popular shopping site and you can
see what do you think you could like
crazy like a result page where you are
you offer these items to the person just
visiting your website because he's
likely to buy these things and then the
date the other one is pretty interesting
so this is from any provider and
enterprise has a small ridges on it on
his web page and shows there in five
latest emails budget and teammates were
actually contained in in a dynamic
script so we can just click and wait yes
there is you can scroll imported now it
doesn't really well you can see
the first email so you can see there was
an email from this person and you can
see the subject you can see the date of
the you know and you can also fueled
technical information about the
urologists in to see the content but I
think the subject is already like and I
think and you can also see how many
unread emails he has in his account so
there's also an interesting fact ok I
need to go back to the slights now
interesting examples are too complex to
demonstrate so we'll go with all over to
other examples and this was a very
interesting one so we found a news
website and its not swept side had a
CSRF protection there was nothing not
really anything of interest in a new
side but you could lead off the new site
so we used this exercise attack to steal
and isn't allowed us to protect and
nurture its a news I didn't have
anything interesting but we figured out
that in the profile page of this inside
there is a cross-site scripting the
crisis gripping is only explainable by
the user himself by changing his profile
in putting a cross-site scripting
payload and salt only a page that only
the user himself concedes but well we
have a sea surf token so we can just
send profile change requests so we did
that and then you are a bit of timing
and we executed in payload and from the
process in pale beer able to read the
Facebook or token that they had because
they're like this Facebook integration
we were able to login so we were able to
access the user's Facebook account and
we were able to post in its name for
example this Canadian for example to
create a warm and pretty girl
service of this was the most senior
thing that we thought we saw on the side
holster and 50 said like a very agents
driven WI you could also all kinds of
Sense UI interactions and to put up the
CIA is hosting provider dynamic
JavaScript to pass the Australian from
the back and the front and so you weigh
between 30th open and with the obstacle
you able to talk to you today PRI
able to do everything we were able to
reach files to write files to delete
files and as an interesting fact this
file hosting provider had multiple other
services so they had emailed calendars
and so on an unusual one API token of
another service and authenticated to the
service as well so we were able to still
lost open and then take over all the all
the services company provided to use its
ok I will quickly go over how to be an
easy winner abilities in the first place
so as opposed to the attacks that have
been shown in 2006 cent and other years
our taxes are not based on prozac works
so you cannot easily remove an era
construct a call or something but is
based on standard jobs computers and
that's why we cannot extend above sea
level and basically because of the other
taxable Honda died in prison it's very
hard to craft a dynamic script that is
not leaking any data so what we what we
do as a recommendation is that you
should and prevent script files from
being included by third parties and you
can I do this by strictly for checking
which is very helpful or by using secret
opens in the USA that they did that
identical cannot include your script in
the pitch but this is only a step that
you should only do when you read
we need to have this dynamic scripts
powerful for whatever reason what you
really should do it you should separate
your JavaScript code from your sensitive
user data so you should have studied
javascript and have a data provisioning
service that is not like handed to the
browser as a script file and that we
protected will be protected by the same
origin policy and last but not least I
want to talk about one other topic which
is why the security people and about the
content security policy so the kind of
security policies is a new mechanism
basically white preventing access by
whitelisting JavaScript and like in
high-level point of view it requires you
to externalize all your online scripts
to external sites too late on white list
to host and what we will be selling our
investigation and study instead a lot of
easy line scripts are dynamically
generated and contain sensitive
information and usually unless goods are
not prone to our tack because it cannot
easily include any night script into an
attack a page and if you introduce
content security policy and you blindly
move out all your lunch groups to
external files then you will get prone
to this attack and I think security
policy in this case will make this issue
a little bit more widespread ok let's
come to the conclusion so we
investigated the security of dynamically
generated JavaScript files we found that
about one-third of the most 150 popular
websites used to dynamically generated
JavaScript and most of these dynamically
generated files contain sensitive user
date and we showed some ways to delete
this data and we found out that we were
able to lead a town about 80 percent of
all the cases so far the forty nine
domains we're able to exploit 40th them
and the consequences can can range from
simple privacy issues where you get on
myspace web is adding a website
up to full account hijacking whole
account gets taken over by an attacker
and injured introduction of CSP might
make this problem worse with that I
would like to thank you for your
attention and feel free to ask any
questions
we didn't want to do that
popular content management systems or
other software the answer is no we just
stick to 150 pages because it was a huge
effort to do that just because seating
we we had to see all these pages read we
had to put all the different user data
can imagine that being such an
application and we had to find all the
scripts we had to manually click all the
functionalities and so on so we decided
to limit the same people study to do
this website because we spent weeks
making websites and creating a tones and
so on
immediately videos kind of happened and
we will start to really interact with
with basically MediaWiki which is
running on didn't find anything they are
from what I record and there's nothing
you could actually deployed it was
interesting and the second question do
we have any plans to open source too
tall I think currently we don't have any
any plans of the tool is really simple
so I think it's really like a hundred
lines of code so you can created from
scratch really easily in like half an
hour according
we we we had a Chrome extension and if
you look to the debugger API in Chrome
it was hella web script whether request
was coming from so we looked at this
type and there's a type script which
came from strip that has gripped in
there that's what we looked at you might
have an interior might have liked X hrs
which are used to retrieve this but then
again if you can actually crossed many
boundaries read at least not but I think
as I said I sense that I think there was
another way we ought adopted it using
the mutation Server API so basically
would inject according to the paper
itself and every time a script element
whatever then we looked at the US
a little bit