and now we're gonna have a talk about
Active Directory password blacklisting
and let's welcome Larry
Chang hey guys so today I'll be doing a
talk on something called Active
Directory password blacklisting and I'm
sure most of you guys know active
directory along with open LDAP or two of
one of our two of the most common
directory services tools used today in
most corporations and specifically I'm
going to talk about how you can employ
Active Directory password blacklisting
into your internal networks and the
benefits this will provide so what we've
seen in the past couple years is a lot
of times corporations might try to
enforce more stringent password
requirements by upping the complexity or
for example requiring that certain
categories are met or maybe even
expiring these passwords and I'm going
to talk about why this sometimes isn't
necessarily a good idea up to a certain
point and will explicitly talk about how
Active Directory password blacklisting
for example can solve a lot of these
problems so just a brief presentation
outline first I'll give a brief overview
and what Active Directory is for anyone
who doesn't know then I'll give a brief
history on password requirements and
from this I'll branch towards the need
for Active Directory password
blacklisting and then my expectation of
this is I'm gonna show a demo and I'm
gonna show how easy it is to install
Active Directory on to your domain
controllers I'm gonna do a live demo for
that and then I'm gonna talk about how
we installed it here at the company I
work with which is Yelp so I'll talk
about the various commercial options we
explored and then how we kind of change
to picking an open source solution and
kind of toggling that to fit our needs
and then that's when the demo will
actually start and I'll show you how to
install it really quickly
and then just some brief transition
thoughts as someone who is primarily
UNIX based programmer like some thoughts
I had moving to a more Windows oriented
programming environment and then I'll
talk to you guys about how you can
create a testing framework around Active
Directory password blacklisting and then
I'll just do some results that we have
here Yelp and then some final
reflections Before we jump into this
though I'm from Yelp Yelp is supporting
about 50 million businesses worldwide we
have like 300 services and we're not
actually all about restaurants we do a
lot more than that for example like home
services as of 2017 was about 20% of our
revenue so that's pretty cool so what
does Active Directory so most of you
probably know Active Directory as a
database system which it primarily is
right it's a database system for
organization of objects on a network
using this hierarchical logical
structure and it's comprised of three
logical components which are domains
trees and forests so basically have
domain network objects right which can
be users computers whatever and then
these form trees which are all along the
same contiguous namespace and at the
very top you have the forests which
represents trees and domains sharing the
same logical structure and in terms of a
security perspective these forests
represent the outermost layer behind
different domain object groups so you
could maliciously change the network
configurations within domains of the
same forest but not between different
forests and as you all might know it's
also primarily used as an identity
provider from any single sign-on
solutions you guys might also use it for
authentication for internal network
services or whatever corporations to
utilize and a lot of people think LDAP
and Active Directory are two of the same
things so act
directory is the actual database system
right and then LDAP is one of many
protocols that Active Directory can use
for communication between different
objects and manipulation of different
Network objects so that was just a brief
overview on Active Directory I'm sure
you guys already knew all this so now
let's talk about password requirements
real quickly so no matter what
corporation you use you're probably
gonna use some sort of requirements that
look like the following you're gonna
have between x and y characters right
and you're gonna make sure sometimes
that it doesn't contain certain words
like this might be the user handle or
some PII data related to your employee
like first name or last name and then
maybe inclusion of some certain
categories you might want some uppercase
lowercase numbers non alphanumeric
digits and a lot of times and this is
recommended by the NIS T before which is
expiring your passwords after a certain
time so I just wanted to talk about this
briefly and what I wanted to say is
sometimes this trend of upping the
complexity by toggling these
requirements doesn't necessarily make
sense and isn't necessarily efficient so
of course enforcing a certain minimum
password requirement will always make
sense because otherwise you can't
prevent against brute force or
dictionary based attacks on very simple
common passwords and of course it also
makes sense to always allow your
employees or users to make their
passwords as long as they want up to a
certain point because it's all gonna be
you know hashed and salted in your
databases later however what does not
necessarily make sense is ensuring a
minimum password length that is above
something like 12 to 14 and the reason
behind this is it actually makes it
cumbersome for the user the same applies
to inclusion of too many categories
you're basically increasing the entropy
to the point that makes it very
for users to remember their passwords I
mean we all know those various obscure
bank accounts where they require like
three or four more different categories
and we don't even remember them so the
point here is it's not necessarily
efficient and this also applies for
password explorations so the NIS t isn't
necessarily recommending this either it
only really makes sense especially
assuming that you have two FA configured
for all your devices already it only
really makes sense to expire passwords
if they've been deemed to be compromised
or susceptible to a breach or seen in
some sort of dump and I'm gonna explain
exactly what I mean in a second but this
all centers around the idea that humans
are very much predictable right if Bob
uses a very stupid password like
password and then suddenly the
requirements are changed to ensure you
also have to have a number there's a
very high chance Bob will use password
one is the password
so to summarize why should we integrate
password blacklist in an ad and what was
the point I was trying to make from this
so I have three main points the first is
complexity doesn't necessarily override
predictability just because your
passwords are complex doesn't mean
they're not very commonly used then the
second is complexity doesn't override
for each ability and I made up the word
breech ability so it sounds nice but you
get the point
so basically leak passwords will always
remain a standard attacking vector and
we always want to prevent against
against this and this brings me to the
last point right which is complexity
doesn't protect against dictionary
attacks nowadays one of the most common
attack vectors are these leak password
dumps that we use dictionary attacks
against for example LinkedIn in 2008 or
2012 they got hacked by a bunch of
Russians and this is what you call
password sprain there is a very good
chance that those credentials utilized
by those LinkedIn employees were also
being used for other different websites
or organizations right passwords brain
is the term to reflect this and it's
extremely common nowadays
so this is where Active Directory
password blacklisting comes in and given
how popular it's used as a directory
services tool it makes sense to all
these just have this installed in
whatever corporate systems you're
working on because it's incredibly easy
and it just gives you such a high
defense layer against these targeted
attacks so Yelp so we knew we wanted to
integrate some sort of Active Directory
password blacklisting mechanism into our
services so at first I was tested like
figuring out what kind of commercial
option we might want to look at but
ultimately we decided against this and
this might not necessarily be the best
decision maybe you might disagree but
for us the reason was there was a lack
of transparency so I'm gonna go with it
exactly how this works later but the
basic idea is this is a very sensitive
service and we're dealing with right and
basically this process that does this
authentication is called the local
security authority for Windows Active
Directory and in this process called the
LS a SS any uncaught exception if there
is one would cause a crash and yield at
blue screen of death we all hate right
so we really wanted this to be as
transparent as possible and finally a
lesser point is just that we thought it
might increase yelps attack service area
if we relied on this single vendor
solution so given this we did we decided
okay we should install a password filter
how the hell do we do that and I was
actually tested this project and I had
no idea like how Windows programming
works or what domain controllers were so
I had to do a lot of research but it
turned out it's pretty simple you
basically have this one interface called
a password filter a DLL and DLL stands
for dynamic linking library and I'll
explain what that is in a bit but
basically it's just this one interface
you have to put it into your windows
system32 folder
and it's comprised of three functions
one is this thing called initialize
change notify so when your computer or
domain controller boots up this function
will be called to indicate whether or
not your password filter DLL is loaded
and this one isn't it's important you
can just be by default return true this
is called on your DLL to indicate
whether a password authentication was
actually successful and the password
changed again this is only if you do
stuff post authentication so it's not as
important it's only maybe this last
function you have to implement and this
will make such a huge difference in
whatever corporate environments you're
working on you just have to implement
this function to perform your password
validation and install into your local
security Authority or put it in its
registry and then you're done and I'm
gonna talk to you exactly about how to
do all this so just any more details
this is basically how the authentication
flow works the client makes a password
change request this goes to the local
security authority which is the Windows
service responsible for all these types
of authentications and author
authorizations and then for each
registered password filter DLL of the
local security authority it will call
that password filter function and
depending it on whether or not that
returns true or false the password will
be committed to the s a.m. or Security
Council manager assuming that it was
approved by all registered dll's so you
can actually register more than one DLL
which is really interesting if you have
various different types of pasture based
authentication mechanisms you want to
employ and the security manager this is
just Windows internal database for
storing all these hash credentials it
uses a combination of ntlm and LM hashes
the details of that I'm not as familiar
with I'm sure some of you are though but
yeah at the end finally these changes
are synced to the actual DLL via
password change notify and the
authentication is done so that's how the
flow really looks like
so knowing this we did more research and
we explored various open-source
solutions and we found one that really
fitted our needs best which is called
open password filter and the links are
here at the bottom if you want to take a
picture it was actually a of this
former open-source solution that we
decided to utilize and the reason was
well 3 main points first it was super
easy to configure it provided
configurable operability with a sequel
database so all you had to do is you
know pipe a bunch of hashes into your
Ellyn provision database within your
network and then just connect it with
that and then also what's very important
is it incorporated the service-oriented
architecture so what does that mean
so remember when I said the DLL is
extremely sensitive and I dealt with
this initially thinking I could do the
DLL on my own any crash there you'll get
a blue screen of death and it's
extremely frustrating so instead if you
have the DLL call another registered
service you can execute this fail open
design such that any crash on your
service because by default return true
and you'll never have any issues with
the blue screen of death on your DLL
itself and I'll show you how that
architecture looks like so basically
it's very much like the architecture
diagram you saw earlier you have your
local security authority a client
password request to sent to this and
then that's calling the password filter
on every registered DLL this instead of
directly authenticating through the DLL
code you actually call through your
loopback interface this thing called opf
service so the open source solution is
called open password filter so opf
stands for open password filter so you
call this service and then that does
authentication for you and of course
it'll do this authentication using
whatever registered sequel server you've
had provided and then given success or
failure this will then be committed to
your security accounts manager so that's
pretty much how the flow looks like and
now I'm going to show you exactly how
you can install one on whatever domain
controller using
I don't know if I mentioned this earlier
if you don't know Active Directory all
the authorization and authentication is
done on the actual domain controllers so
you'll have to install these dll's on
every registered domain controller on
your network so how do you install this
well it basically boils down to these
steps and on the right I've highlighted
some like windows commands you can use
to help assist you with this so first
you want to configure your domain
controllers and I'd suggest just
starting with the standalone domain you
know just run a Windows Server 2008 r2
instance or something and install your
own standalone domain controller and
make sure Active Directory domain
services is installed in everyone next
thing you want to do is set up local
group policies this is for testing
purposes you want very bare minimal
password requirements just for testing
purposes so stuff like password will be
installed into your database and you can
make sure that's being blacklisted as
appropriate this is just a convenience
thing then finally load your common
password hashes nowadays I think the
most common one is having been poned
comm and most of these hashes are all
sha-1
so you can just download them there and
then import that into your database
which is the next step you know creating
the database importing the hashes then
you want to move your DLL to the systems
registry and then start your
authentication service so remember the
DLL is calling on this service to do the
authentication and sorry this is where
you actually register the DLL because
you have to put it in this notification
packages registry so that the local
security authority knows to load it on
boot and yeah if you do this you're
pretty much done and like the reward is
so much it's really simple it shouldn't
take too long you really should have
this and whatever corporate environment
you're using but anyway enough with the
talking I'm going to show you how you
can do this on in a demo alright okay
whatever
alright I'll just deal like this okay
cool so here I have installed a Windows
2008 r2 server and I'm just configured
you know Active Directory domain
services and I've installed my own
standalone domain so what we're gonna do
is we're gonna create a database and
we're gonna have password filtering
working and just start everything off
I'm gonna show you that and I'm gonna
turn on the key caster so currently my
password is admin 1 2 3 4 if I use the
password password it's going to
authenticate cuz I've configured you
know very bare minimal local security
policies and that's just to show you
that doing this works so I'm just gonna
revert back to my old one all right cool
so I changed it back to admin one two
three four exclamation mark this is
probably one of the very few times you
want to have key casting on when you're
typing your password next thing I want
to do is just really quickly copy this
so here I have a PowerShell open and the
first thing I want to do is I actually
want to get this snap in for executing
sequel server commands which is what I'm
using so let me just add that really
quickly I should have done this before
the demo but oh well so I'm getting that
snap in okay cool
so now we're gonna create a database
right and I hope you guys can see that I
think it's big enough so first thing
we're gonna do
oops that's the wrong thing I copied let
me just copy this real quickly alright
everything's gonna go perfectly from
here trust me alright so the first thing
we're gonna do we're gonna create a
database and we're gonna call it
password dump alright next thing we're
gonna do we're gonna create a table for
this so we're gonna create a table for
that password dump database using the
database object basic schema and we're
going to call it blacklisted and then in
blacklisted we're going to
two variables okay we're gonna give it
hash ID which is an int which is not
null and then a hash which is a varchar'
and since they're sha-1 hashes are gonna
make it length 40 and this is of course
is also not null so that's done next
thing we want to do we want to create a
user or login so logins are for
authenticating to the database and then
users are for the specific table so
they're a bit different so I'm going to
create a login I'll call it a b-sides
reader and I'm gonna say it has the
password equal to let's say b-sides Las
Vegas 2018 and I'll give it a default
database of what we just created which
is password dump so that should work
alright cool next thing I wanna do is we
want to this is why I don't like
PowerShell cuz you you can't paste it
keeps dying okay here we go
next thing we want to create the user so
let's use password dump and then we're
gonna create the user create user and
let's also call it b-sides reader for
the login b-sides a reader cool and then
finally we want to give it read
privileges so we're gonna give this the
role which is we want to execute this SP
IDI role member and then we're gonna
give it the DB data reader role for
'besides reader so that should work okay
so now create a database that I've
created a login and a user for accessing
that blacklisted table next thing I want
to show you this directory right so I've
pretty much installed that thing called
opf which is open password filter I've
installed a pre compiled version there's
some small configurations I added from
Yelp but it's pretty much gonna be the
same thing you just go to that link you
saw earlier and install the pre compiled
version and you see this hashes dot txt
file right so if I open this basically
I've downloaded a bunch of sha-1 hash is
from have I been poned comm like the top
1 million or something and I've also
prepended an ID to them
so we have these hashes let's import it
into our actual table so I can just do
bulk insert and then password dump DBA
blacklisted and then I'm gonna insert
the actual hashes which is from my users
slash administrator slash hashes file
and it has to use these field
terminators so the field Terminator in
this case is a comma and then the row
Terminator is actually a line feed which
you can use this hexanol character for
that should work okay so now it's
importing which is awesome and we can
just quickly show that it's actually in
there so select from password dump DVO
DUP blacklisted and yeah you can see we
imported that into our database okay so
we got the database configured and again
you can just re-watch this and just
follow what I do and you can install
like faster blacklisting into your local
orgs so next thing we want to do is we
want to actually register the service so
what we can do is in this directory the
precompiled directory that you can
download you'll see the four files the
DLL the actual service executive or a
configuration for that and also this
nice testing executive ole just for
testing the service itself not the DLL
of course so in that configuration file
there's a bunch of predefined keys and
values you can add to this since I have
this you know standalone domain
controller is gonna be on localhost and
the database we call it a password dump
right and then the table name was
blacklisted the username was 'besides
reader and the database was 'besides Las
Vegas 2018 or I think yeah that should
be it alright cool so we configured the
installation configuration file and now
the next thing we want to do is actually
install the service so if we go to
windows.net 64
me too and then it's called install
utility XE we can actually just install
the service and again this is all on
PowerShell
[Music]
so that's been installed successfully
next thing we want to do is we want to
move the DLL itself into windows
system32 so let's copy that really
quickly so copy the DLL into windows
system32 cool and that should be it next
we actually want to quickly start the
service so the SC start opf ok the
service is started we installed a
database we imported some hashes into it
we configured the installation
configuration we put it to system 32 we
started the service that should be it so
next thing you want to do is remember I
told you that these dll's are only
loaded by the LS 8 during boot so you
have to restart your computer so I'll
just do that really quickly I feel like
there's one thing I forgot I hope this
live demo works well it's taking a huge
risk it's gonna work
don't worry all right so um cool that's
gonna take a while I don't want you guys
to wait for it to shutdown so while that
loads I'll just give you another slide
some implementation gotchas question ok
so some implementation gosh is
especially if you don't want to use an
open source solution or if you want to
install your own DLL yourself or
configure your own DLL or your own
service one thing any crash in this
process means you'll get a blue screen
of death which means you'll need like a
kernel debugger if you're actually gonna
do all the coding logic in the DLL so I
don't suggest doing that completely
replacing a DLL actually requires two
reboots so one for actually clearing the
registry and the other for actually
loading the library and like I said this
DLL is only loaded during boot by the
local security Authority
via this notification registry of the
local security authority and then yeah
the DLL has to be installed on every
network domain controller so don't
forget that don't don't just have an
install on one otherwise authentication
pipe to other domain controllers won't
work and another interesting gotcha is
these password policy error messages
they're hard-coded into that into the
Microsoft operating system so you can't
change the message that says these
password requirement complexities aren't
met which can be a good thing or a bad
thing depending on your needs let's see
if it finished it still didn't finish
okay so just hear some thoughts I had
transitioning from a UNIX programming
environment some more windows heavy
especially with PowerShell first thing
is what's a dynamic linking library I
didn't know what that was
now I know it's pretty much like the dot
L IB files except it's a shared memory
that you don't have to compile when
importing libraries in it's all shared
in one contiguous memory chunk on demand
when your programs loaded
another thing I learned is I really like
using PowerShell I thought you know the
transition was pretty seamless we went
from batch to PowerShell the programming
language is really intuitive I thought I
just I don't know I really had a great
time using it other question I had is
what's the domain controller you know I
didn't know what this is but this is
where all the authentication
authorization is done for Active
Directory I also thought it was
incredibly convenient that UNIX and
Windows use the same line terminators so
this made it really easy when I was
programming in UNIX and then moving to
Windows another thing I asked myself is
how do ID bug in LCS process without
going crazy so this part was pretty hard
it was kind of mundane attract kind of
really stressed me out so again that's
why the service oriented architecture
suited our needs so well another
interesting question is how do I test
LDAP authenticate
across the domain of a thousand plus
users so this is an interesting question
I'll talk about this in the testing
framework part and if you guys I don't
think you guys realize this but this was
extreme sarcasm and this is also
sarcastic all right let's see if it
actually installed so let me just log in
and I'll show you the password I'm using
which is admin one two three four that's
weird I never got that before okay geez
all right let's hope this works so if I
open CMD one thing I want to show you
again is I'm using really minimal
password complexity requirements so if I
theoretically changes the password sure
work may I mean it should get
blacklisted another thing we want to
check is that the DLL has been
registered into the LLC's registry so we
can do that by doing something like reg
query I think it's
hklm slash system current control set
control LSA and then you can search for
notification packages so we can see that
it has been registered and another thing
we can do is we can query that the OPF
service is running so it does seem like
it's running another thing is that's
useful is this open source pre compiled
version it can it provides a testing
framework so you can just check whether
that is really weird
I've depth that's just outrageous I've
done this demo like ten times I've never
gotten this star failure so I'm really
sorry about this this is this is crazy
sorry oh I actually I used the wrong
executive all so it's all good actually
I was just using the wrong executable so
it promotes a testing framework called
opf test password and this just tests
that the service authentication works
and as you can see testing the password
password results in a failure but let's
see if the dll actually works so if you
change your password and again I'll show
you what I'm typing sorry my old
password was Evan one two three four now
if I try password it's unable to update
the password so that was all alive it
actually is a lot harder than it looks
but everything worked which is nice
thanks alright so that shows you how
easy it is to install everything now
I'll talk about how you can test and
employ this and they Yelp we pretty much
divided it into four phases first thing
you want to do identify what kind of
passwords you want to deploy especially
depending on the policies you set you
might want to use a different set of
passwords meeting your policies also
depending on the scale of your users or
employees you want to adjust accordingly
so first phase identify your passwords
second is you want to test your password
filtering service on a Sat alone domain
you know just like what I did just run
up Windows 2008 server r2 instance and
then hopefully you have a development
domain configured or a lab domain with
multiple domain controllers that you can
finally test this with and then you want
to slowly roll this service out to
production servers and something I call
non enforcement mode which means at
first you want it running but you don't
want it actually authenticating or
blacklisting you just want to log that
it would have otherwise succeeded and
then after a while like two or three
months and you know making sure
everything is what it looks like then
you can actually run it in enforcement
mode where you actually deny the
passwords so phase zero require
passwords this should be pretty simple
it looks something like this you just
gather a bunch of compromised passwords
or sha-1 passwords and if they're you
know plain text already just sha-1 them
yourself like on the Ray you can see
some scripts for doing that
and then maybe you want to filter these
against those conforming to your
policies these are just some random
policies I made at the bottom and then
you want to move to your actual testing
framework so what we did was we kind of
divided this dump of pastures we got
into four different groups in reality
there's only two groups you care about
right which is whether they're in the
dump or whether they're not in the dump
and again this is all for testing
purposes but because there's also this
you know pre-authorization done on
whether the complexity requirements are
met we divided again into two more
groups so you have four in total and
this is just for completeness sake so
yeah and number two stuff to just
generate sha-1 hashes of those you plan
to put in your password dump so that
they're in your actual blacklisting
database and then finally you generate a
PowerShell script that or whatever
script you want that basically tests
whether these resets and LDAP binds are
actually being successfully done so if
it's not in the password dump but meets
the complexity requirements it should
right so you're just testing the
expected behavior of all these groups
using something like a PowerShell script
with you know resets and LDAP binds and
then of course at the end you want to
log all your results including the
average reset time so that's what this
looks like
you know I divided the password into
four different categories and then just
rather this huge powershell script for
verifying the behavior ie that for each
you have an expected outcome and an
actual outcome and you want to make sure
these are the same they're all
correlated properly so just in terms of
the results we got a Yelp so the left
diagram it doesn't really mean anything
because no password filter dll's are
configured so the fact that the the the
last right columns are kind of different
it's just random but then in the results
with the DLL configured you can see that
the average time of course and this
includes passwords which are in the
black list so of course the the time
will be a lot lower
but what you'll notice is the yes policy
no dump in the right side and the yes
policy note up on the left side are
pretty much the same so the overhead was
almost minimal you couldn't even notice
it so that was the standalone domain
next you want to move to the actual lab
environment right so it's gonna be the
same as I talked about earlier except
you're gonna do some more things
differently so you want to be indexing
these logs to your sims somehow alright
so you can make something in like syslog
with whatever timestamp to do this and
you also have an additional cross
verification check with Windows events
logs so for 73 and for 74 are the codes
for success and failure respectively and
then finally you want to toggle between
enforcement's and non enforcement modes
so when you suddenly roll this out into
prod you want to make sure that non
enforcement mode is toggled just in case
there was something you missed and then
slowly look at the results from your sim
data your logs whatever and make sure
everything is correlated and once that's
guaranteed then move it to actual
enforcement mode where you're actually
denying these blacklisted passwords so
that's probably going to look something
like this you know putting in this block
and being able to index all this like
having this ability to see everything
very conveniently that's what seams are
for right and yet then we got these
average results which are that most of
these password DLLs they didn't impose
any overhead whatsoever it was extremely
marginal and then yeah finally you put
it into production and yes I spend most
of my time making these planes so that's
about it finally flexions
let's ensure good communication between
all teams most of the people I was
working with was remote in London and I
was the only guy in San Francisco so
ensuring that everything was documented
it was very very very important and that
that's the second point I wanted to make
you know also you want to be very
patient with everything especially if
you do plan on making your own custom
DLL and maybe using a kernel debugger
you want to be very patient and the last
thing is I hope I don't touch PowerShell
again and I don't guys didn't find the
sarcastic comment that funny I thought
those hilarious anyway that's about it I
have a blog post which details all of
this so you can check that out or you
can just search Yelp Active Directory
password blacklisting it'll include the
code for the testing and I think also
the code for our steps for instil
installing your DLL and then lastly
yelps hiring especially for the security
team I'm part of the corporate security
team so if you're interested you can
talk to me later but that's it
so thank you
[Applause]
yeah what you used inside the DLL yeah
so if you look at most password dumps
these days most of them will be hashed
already and I think you'll find that
sha-1 hashes are the most common but the
actual authentication flow works in such
that you have the password pass to your
local security authority and then that
actually so your DLL service will sha-1
hash that password and compare with
what's in the dump yeah so there's been
a lot of discussion over the past few
months about how large blacklist should
be if you make them too long you know if
you use Troy hunts half a billion
passwords you're going to really annoy
users and if you make it too short
you're not getting the effect that you
want so do you have any opinions on how
larger yours and do you have opinions on
what the appropriate size is yeah so we
use about I think it was like ten to a
hundred million and we didn't really
face any performance constraints and
also depending on where you're sampling
these passwords from you might for
example the sampling a bunch that
conform to your password policy so we
did take like for the sha-1 hashes you
can't know unless you like do a
dictionary attack yourself with a bunch
of GPUs but for those that you do know
you can actually filter them against
those that pass your password policies
and then shot one of those yourselves
and put them in another interesting
thing you can do which is really
effective is so we at Yelp not only do
we sample these commonly used passwords
but we created our own using some
algorithms that would add where it's
like Yelp or maybe even the months of
the year because they're extremely
popular and will be used by your
employees trust me yeah yeah for the
filtering message have I included the
hash ID yeah yeah yeah that could be a
good idea especially for your testing
framework so what I showed wasn't our
actual official spunky index it was just
something I generated but yeah that's
right so so right I said in an earlier
slide though it doesn't seem like you
can change that message because it's
hard-coded into Microsoft's operating
system so unfortunately you can't
configure that oh oh yeah you know it's
this default message that's always
returned on a password authentication
failure so you can that you can't change
that unfortunately quite a practical
question about updating the passwords to
cross the domain controllers how do you
do that okay so that's the reason the
service-oriented architecture is so
great right so the database doesn't
necessarily have to exist in your domain
controller the domain controller is only
calling this DLL which calls upon the
service which can
so currently yeah we're doing that and I
guess that's why he asked about
scalability concerns so that is
something we have to think about okay so
oh yeah okay so so actually what we did
is we understand your problem and
because of this we explicitly targeted
the most commonly used passwords instead
of just random password leaks and that's
how we got the top 10 or 100 million
from various sources with having been
pwned calm being just one of them
because we ran tests on this and we did
realize like almost all of these either
weren't conforming to our password
policy or we're just too so obscured
that no one was using them and again
this is for our internal corporate
systems we do something entirely
different for actual user authentication
since the error message in Windows can't
be updated directly did you have user
education outreach type session or when
this new blacklist was implemented right
that's actually something that's ongoing
which is a great point you're making
which is how do we notify the users that
this error message might mean that
they've been blacklisted so that's where
the logging infrastructure comes in so
you can configure these logs to detail
this the specifics of why a user was
blacklisted or not and currently what we
do is we basically scrape these logs and
then email our individual employees or
users who have been compromised through
this attack but you know developing a
better strategy for this is something
that we're currently thinking about
um I mean the biggest problem with me is
I just didn't know anything about
PowerShell and it was really stressful
learning about how to debug everything
but after you like if I had this demo
and if I could see this demo I just did
when I was doing it could probably take
me a week honestly yeah anyone ice
against known password my question is
that have you gone beyond this where
you're actually searching passwords that
are already in your database hash
however Microsoft's doing it in your
domain and you're alerting those people
your password it's a very common one you
need to change it right so we're like I
said to him we haven't developed an
accurate pipeline for telling employees
that they've been compromised because of
blacklisting we've only made it really
general at this point and right now what
we're doing is these emails through
scraping of the logs which isn't very
efficient but this is a relatively new
service so we're actually doing that
right now it should be done pretty soon
hey yeah do you know if there is any way
to use kind of a wild-card to avoid
certain words from being used yeah so so
that's why this DLL is so useful like we
added some of this logic to our password
filtering service too you can just put
that in the service that the dll calls
whatever type of you know pattern
matching you might want to do you can
put it in that it's really easy to
configure it's just basic reggae yeah
thank you yeah
just a another quick question about the
service because it is a service I assume
that a couple of things it can be run on
one instance or on a distributed
framework potentially and also if you
can write your own rules in that service
can do things more than just regex can
it use like custom functions and things
like that I mean yeah yeah it's all up
to how you want to program it the the
baseline is you have this DLL with this
interface and you can implement these
functions however you want so yeah it's
really really you know flexible I was
wondering I I don't know is there a way
to check for this is not exactly what
you're talking about but is there a way
for to check for duplicate characters of
any character in a password yeah you can
you can just uh do that function so so
the DLL is just this file that will call
whatever service you've registered and
your service can be running like c-sharp
C++ or whatever and you can do all this
filtering on your own it's just like
basic code matching so you could
definitely do that that's that's
something a lot of people do actually
which is duplicate consecutive
characters what confused about is that
for example if your if your if your
password was 12 characters long yeah
how would it how wouldn't know that the
the you typed a twice and that that
position that a twice was you know ten
characters and versus two characters in
in the hash that you have oh okay sorry
so the LSA right the password that it
gets passed is actually in plain text
that's why this is such a you know
sensitive service that you want to make
sure it's very secure and then it does
so you would do the checking there and
then you - it and compare it against
your database but that's why you have
there's a lot of security concerns and a
lot of people might ask like oh what if
you pipe it to you know localhost what
if someone's sniffing on your domain
controller but usually the the general
response is if a malicious hacker is
compromised your domain controller you
have much bigger things to worry about
right
anyone who like to ask how nervous
various aside means when you deployed in
production I'm sorry what how nervous
may your society means when you deployed
this in production oh yeah
I mean that's why I emphasizes not
enforcement and enforcement mode so we
were doing non enforcement mode for
almost like one and a half months and I
could do a bunch of aggregation on the
data we've already employed and we knew
there were no issues whatsoever so it's
just a matter of resetting the service
with enforcement mode turn it true so I
wasn't nervous at all actually
you you mentioned you're still kind of
in the process of the user education
component of this I have other plans for
expanding this or changing the way that
you've got it implemented yet or is that
still something that will come with time
I think this is probably the final part
I don't really see any other issues like
we have the password filtering installed
we have the logging infrastructure there
it's just making the whole pipeline more
efficient for when someone got
compromised and it's in their log to
directly messaging the user for why this
is the case but that should be the final
part yeah questions
less chance questions I think that's it
all right cool thank you guys so much
[Applause]
[Music]