okay hi everyone this is a talk on
attacking aetherium DAPs but first quick
show of hands who here is interacted
with a death before okay good
so this talk kind of assumes you don't
have any background at all with
aetherium deaths or theorem in general
but the point is that daps and aetherium
and the world of blockchain is really
taking a big role in people's lives
today so it's super important for the
traditional security world to understand
kind of the mechanisms behind blockchain
security and ways you can penetration
tests adapt for example rather than just
a regular web application so that's
going to be intent of this talk I work
at Gemini the next generation digital
asset exchange very exciting company
it's kind of at the forefront of
cryptocurrencies and a very cool place
to be on the ground floor and we are
hiring so if anyone here is interested
feel free to come up after after the
talk and give me your name and resume
and all that but even more important
than that we're having a party tomorrow
at the presidential suite at the
Bellagio from 7:00 to 11:00 now I can't
I was told by the recruiting people that
I can't just announce it publicly like
this so what has to happen is you have
to give me your name and then I have to
put you on the guest list so you can
either come up to me or just tweet at me
or something
send me a private message and I'll get
you added just mention at the door that
you came from this talk from seeing this
talk I hope to see most of you there so
again I'm a security engineer at Gemini
I do a lot of blockchain and smart
contract development work and before
that before being a Gemini I was at
mandiant where I was doing penetration
testing digital forensics and Incident
Response so what is a dap dap stands for
decentralized application now this
decentralized bar is important because
it gives us a few more attack vectors
than the traditional application you're
used to pen testing and hopefully by the
end of this talk you'll see that it's
very easy to migrate over into the
penetration testing world for dabs and
smart contrast
so let's talk about what a standard web
application is first you have your
client over here you have your server
most of the time is just a simple get
request or a post request that goes to
the web web application a lot of times
web applications are just a front-end
for a database a way to manage the data
that's being returned from that database
so when you make that get or post to the
web app that web app might interact with
another server or a series of them but
ultimately it just sends you data back
right get post data back with some level
of indirection there so again you're
just really interacting with the web app
logic and that's kind of the point of a
web app assessment is you're going in
set logic you're looking for places
where access controls aren't implemented
properly vertical privilege escalation
horizontal things like that so that's a
standard web app but when you introduce
the DAP the decentralized part you have
a third component to it a little kitty
there really is a smart contract or a
series of smart contracts in aetherium
so not only do you have the interaction
with the web application but you also
have this thing called a smart contract
this is like web 3 apps that we're
talking about essentially so the
workflow of one might look like this
you'll do the Gator post like you
normally would to the web application
but then there's a read or write to a
smart contract in the blockchain so it's
not just going straight to a database
and then back to you there might be this
level of indirection where the web app
talks to the smart contract and this is
kind of where new attack vectors come in
after the reader right then the data
would come back to you at the end of
that so it makes sense to everyone oh
cool
so the point of being able to use adapt
or being able to interact with aetherium
smart contracts through a web
application is that you need to have a
private key involved somewhere right you
need to own your private key and be able
to use it through this web application
that ultimately talks to a smart
contract so block chains are based on
public key crypto so how do you how do
you get a private key involved right so
traditionally if you weren't going
through a web application you could
publish a transaction onto the ethereum
blockchain by signing the raw bytes
offline and sending it to a third party
node like in Fuhrer for example or you
can run a node yourself sign a
transaction broadcasted it yourself but
through a web application how do you
introduce public key cryptography with a
private key you own and that goes altom
Utley to wear a sign message ultimately
goes to the etherion blockchain so one
way to do that is through meta mask so
meta mask is a very popular in browser
extension I think it's something like
1.5 million total downloads so so far
between Chrome and Firefox and it's a
wallet in your browser so you can
interact with these steps by having your
own wallet as a Chrome extension or as a
Firefox extension sign things have them
go through the dab like that so this is
kind of what it would look like this
would be the extension it would pop out
like this when you click on it you have
a password to seal your your wallet and
this is adapt the crypto Kitty staff
that everyone's familiar with at least
on some level so if you wanted to buy
this Kitty for example you would
authenticate to your wallet
you'd unlock the wallet and you click OK
buy this Kitty and when you do you get
the arguments needed to buy the Kitty so
meta mattes will then populate the
arguments you need the amount of eath to
pay for that kitty the destination which
is the crypto Kitty smart contract and
all that and you can click Submit or
reject but clicking that basically
prompts you in your Chrome extension the
meta mask extension so this is how you
can have your own identity your own
private key in your browser interacting
with a DEP
so this is what the smart contract on
the back end would look like this is for
the crypto kiddies
smart contract you see this array of
kiddie objects there's a kiddie index -
owner mapping so ultimately when you
sign the transaction when you send the
eath and you send it to the appropriate
function like we just showed a second
ago these data structures get updated on
the smart contract so that's kind of the
workflow goes from the web application
you saw it gives you an interface a nice
clean interface to interact with the
smart contract you send the transaction
through metamath and then this
ultimately gets updated on the
blockchain these these arguments the
these data structures rather so this is
just a gif of going through the workflow
and actually you're gonna see me buy a
kitty and I actually had to buy the
kitty for this demo so now I have this
kitty so I don't even know what it's
called a good sire
so okay buy this kitty you see the
prompt come up I click Submit and now I
am the proud owner of good sire and good
sires for sale so if anyone wants good
sire please talk to me after the talk
yeah give you a good deal on good sire
now it's also a good time to tell you
I'm giving away eath so send me point
5/8 and I will send you back much I'm
not giving away okay but let's talk
about how you can set up a DAP in a
local environment so you can do this
test in yourself now so who's heard of
truffle here okay so truffle is a smart
contract development and testing
framework it's made by consensus which
has really been a trailblazer in this
industry making great tools for
developing smart contracts developing
gaps but if you want to test created app
locally that you can test with burp
suite for example look up truffle and
there's a petshop tutorial so that
tutorial tells you step by step how to
make a DAP how to make the web
application front-end and the smart
contract behind it and you just
ultimately run this command below but
you should look into that so when you
have that local environment set up this
is Pete's pet shop you'll see meta mask
you'll need meta Massa interact with it
still you'll see
is installed in my browser on the top
right and what happens when meta mask is
communicating with so meta mattes you
can give it the blockchain to which or
the provider rather the node provider
that you you want to interact with
ultimately so this is a local
environment so I'm running the etherium
blockchain on just localhost seven five
four five it can communicate with that
every ten seconds or so meta mask
queries out it does if get blocked by
number right that's madam at some way of
saying okay this is the blockchain I'm
supposed to be interacting with I need
to know the latest block I need to know
the most recent information about the
accounts and this wallet and everything
else so every ten seconds you'll see a
request if you were intercepting a
requests to wherever that provider is
and trying to see what the most recent
block is to get the most recent
information that's how that's how a
madam asked works on any blocks when you
provided essentially any aetherium plug
chain so again this is the this is what
the petshop looks like and this is the
JavaScript that handles the adoption
function so I told you again there was
like a web application portion and in
the smart contract portion right so if
you were to click for example adopt
Frieda this first dog right here what
you'd be calling is handle duct and what
handle adopt does you can see below does
app contracts adoption deploy then
basically call the adopt function on
that contract artifact so it recognized
the contract because it was developed in
truffle it's got a really nice interface
and it just calls the smart contract
function adopts ultimately so this is
kind of a bridge between the JavaScript
to smart contract and this is actually
the contract behind it so this is the
smart contract so when Handel adopt is
called we saw it called the adopt
function that's the function that's
actually being called this is a smart
contract it's set it accepts a pet ID
Frieda was pet zero so it would check
that the pet ID is in within range
there's only 16 pets and then it would
update the data structure to reflect
that the adopter of Frieda is the person
sending this message so that would be us
when we send that transaction
so that's the entire workflow so before
I actually adopt Freda this is the
adopters array right here you'll see
that every adopter is just the zero
address because no one's actually
adopted anything yet
but as soon as I click adopt I submit
the transaction I noticed I don't need
to pay any for this because it was free
the contract didn't say require the
value being sent to be above this
certain amount it's free you just click
it and you adopt frita you click Submit
and then you'll see if you checked that
data structure again that array the
first index now corresponds to the
address from which we sent that
transaction so that data structure was
updated to reflect that we are the owner
of frida so what does that transaction
actually look like if you if you took it
if you looked at it in birth so I just
showed you Mehta mask coming up and you
click and submit if you intercepted that
transaction you would see the from
address right there right the to address
is the smart contract address the value
and data and I'll get into this more but
it's very simple there's only four or
five fields that you need to worry about
so you can see from two value data gas
gas price so from is my aetherium
address the one that's being populated
in that a in the in the array two is a
smart contract address the adoption
contract that has the pet the pet array
value is zero again because it we didn't
charge that this contract didn't charge
anything for the pets and data was his
number hex hex value at 85 etc right so
let's break that down a little bit why
was this the data we sent to that smart
contract it's because we call the
function adopt right
the first four bytes of data in a in the
data field or the function identifier so
it's the hash of the function name and
the kind of arguments it accepts and you
can take the first four bytes of that
hash that is how you tell the smart
contract of what function you want to
interact with so that's what's taking
place the first four bytes of the data
parameter that we provided is the
function identifier of the adopt
function so once a smart contract gets
that it says okay these are the four
bytes yep I know that one that's the
adopt function I'm gonna send this over
to the adopt function and then it takes
the rest of that data field and it
populates and it does whatever else it
needs to the argument it accepted again
was was a pet ID and we adopted Frieda
which was the zero with pet so you'll
notice that after the function
identifier it's just zeros right
that means we're calling adopt because
we have these first four bytes here we
stripped that away and the rest is just
zero okay that means you're adopting
zero you're adopting Frieda does that
make sense
cool so this is a really bad slide in
hindsight because you can't see my mouse
but things like cross-site scripting
become a lot more dangerous with apps
because what you can do is you can
manipulate meta masks ultimately to send
a transaction to somewhere you wouldn't
expect and it's not immediately obvious
where you're sending the transaction to
with meta masks implemented the way it
is currently so what's happening here is
I'm actually hovering my mouse over that
adopt button there but I'm not actually
clicking anything and when I hover my
mouse it prompts meta mash to pop up and
say oh please send some ether here right
so if a malicious person gets JavaScript
on to adapt what it'll happen is that
they can get your meta mask to pop up
with a transaction and you might think
while I was expecting that I'm asked to
come up because I wanted to make a
transaction on the site but in reality
the destination addresses to one
attacker Ellen's so it's a little bit
trickier because you're trusting this
extension and the extension can seem
legitimate because it's kind of outside
the realm of the site but in reality
it's malicious
the script that's that's making it come
up there was actually an instance of
this in the wild that John showed me
John do wanna stand up say hi this is
John basically ether Delta decentralized
exchange had cross-site scripting
vulnerability where III also allows you
to trade tokens between two different
tokens essentially and these tokens when
they're listed on the site their fields
populate on the site so things like
their name their symbol etc so there was
an attacker who took who made a smart
contract published it and in their name
field their ERC 20 token they made it
some malicious JavaScript
so when ether Delta pulled the basically
the ERC 20 basically every part of the
ERC 20 protocol from from the contract
they loaded in this malicious javascript
from a smart contract onto their page
and what that javascript did ultimately
was it sense
whoever's private key they uploaded to
the site it sense all their ether to
another wallet so again it was in the
name field there was some JavaScript
there and it was loaded into the site
and that was an example of how
cross-site scripting is really dangerous
when you're dealing with private keys
and meta masks for example so again
there's the web application logic and
then there's also this third part the
smart contract and the important part
about the parts mark contract is that
it's public so it's publicly accessible
there's no rule that says you have to
interact with the smart with the smart
contract through the web application you
can go directly to smart contract which
introduces a whole set of other
vulnerabilities the web application
might have a really well defined way in
which you can interact that smart
contract but there might be a glaring
vulnerability in that smart contract
that you'd only notice if you went to
the byte code directly so there's kind
of another attack vector we're gonna
discuss so smart contracts kind of serve
as another data store they're publicly
accessible and it's like everyone wrote
their own version of that software to
store that data because no to smart
contracts are really the same
right you have a bunch of people making
smart contracts storing ether in there
storing valuable customer data and they
can make it really they're making it
themselves so it's not like there's one
single instance of software people are
using to store this data that's been
tried and true every single smart
contract is a little different so
there's a lot of vulnerabilities with
that as you as you've seen so you kind
of have this two-pronged approach you
can attack the dab through the web
application but you can also attack it
directly by going to the smart contracts
as well so beyond that there's kind of a
third prong and I'm gonna talk about
that in a second it's going through the
web application to get to the smart
contract in a different way there's this
concept of modifiers and smart contracts
where only certain etherium addresses
can issue the transaction you're denied
if you're not able if you don't have
that appropriate key right so only owner
is an example of this only an owner can
only the owner of the contract can
update this field in the smart contract
for example a lot of these DAB's rely on
a special key in the web application to
issue privileged rights to the smart
contract based on the clients data so I
make a getter post request and the web
application will say okay I'm gonna use
my privileged key to write this to the
privileged spot in a smart contract so
it's not just what you can do directly
to the smart contract but can you also
get the web application to make a
privileged write on your behalf can you
trick him into thinking you are the
owner
bye-bye buzzing the.you know the access
controls of that web app so it's kind of
a three pronged approach what can you
get the web the web app to return to you
just regular web application penetration
test what boner ability can you find by
accident the smart accessing the smart
contract directly and then can you get
the web app to interact with a smart
contract in a way it didn't expect so as
an owner as a privileged key essentially
so this is an example of kind of how you
would use how you would sign something
in crypto kitties this is how you would
prove your ownership of a certain
address right you would sign the message
they give you a message to sign and
you'd sign it and they see okay this
signature matches the etherium direct
address that we're seeing from you so in
a pen test you'd want to verify that
that signature validation is actually
being done correctly if you could just
pop out the etherium address that you're
providing it and replace it with another
one basically say hey I'm not this with
your name address I'm this one and you
provide a signature that doesn't
actually match up to that if your name
address you want to make sure that the
web application is validating that that
they're saying okay that doesn't
actually match up we're not gonna allow
you to sign in I've actually done this
before where I've been able to
impersonate someone else or create a
denial of service for that person if
they ever wanted to sign up because I
said I intercepted the request which
I'll show you in a second and I replace
my aetherium address with theirs so this
is an example so if you sign if you were
to sign up for example you would provide
an aetherium address that you're saying
I want to sign up as and you'd provide a
signature of a phrase that that you
would both know like crypto kitties in
this case what the DAP should be doing
is validating that that address matches
with that signature so if you recite was
a different address would the DAP reject
you ultimately I found AB swear that is
the case well that's not the case too so
cryptic ladies is that properly so that
was good to see but when you're already
authenticated so that's how you sign in
right you can use a private key when
you're already authenticated you can do
things like go to settings here and you
can change some variables about who you
are right and this is kind of that
duality of web applications not
everything you change about your account
or your profile requires a signature so
at some point it becomes a regular web
application right if you have a cookie
you can change things about yourself
sometimes without requiring a password
for a DAP it's like if you have a cookie
or if it doesn't require a signature
then you can do things without requiring
a signature again so stealing someone's
cookie might allow you to do things in
that DAP without actually having the
private key again so if I were to change
my email or my nickname for example like
here you'll see it doesn't require a
signature anywhere so this is nothing I
mean changing my nickname to Miao is not
going to cause big problems for me if an
attacker did that but it's an example of
where this duality exists not everything
in adapt relies on public key
cryptography some of it is just a web
regular web application
so there's that duality there so I'll
give an example of another one that's
another DAP that's designed with
security in mind and I'll talk about why
these best practices are kind of
implemented there so you can understand
the attack vectors that they're
defending against so Blum is a really
big app it's a big big DAP and it's a
good example of this if you guys want to
check it out it's at bloom Koh so this
is kind of a sign-up process you would
enter your name your phone number and
email address and then it will tell you
what you did what you what you're doing
right so you're signing your email or
you're signing the message rather to
prove ownership of the the key kind of
like we saw with kind of like we saw
with group that Katie's a second ago so
nothing new there so the validation
takes place against the signature and
the etherium address you provide but
when you sign in you're providing not
only the signature but what you're
signing includes the date and your email
address right so does anyone know why
you would be signing the date and your
email address when you want to sign in
to the DAP
what does the date have to do with a
signature right exactly yep so this
prevents replay attacks I'm gonna get
into that in a second so this is what if
you were to intercept that request you'd
see the email address the signature and
the date they would validate that the
date is within a certain range first of
all it's signed properly the date is the
same one of the server has and that date
is within a certain amount of time so if
an attacker intercepted the signature of
the sign in then they couldn't actually
just replay at another time they
couldn't reply it in a year or a week or
something like that because it wouldn't
be May 2018 anymore
so email address checks the wallet
address tied to that email addresses in
their servers right it checks that
you're signing you're saying I'm signing
in as this person wait a second let's
make sure that key matches that person
and a day to provide prevent replay
attacks so any DAP should have a
signature of the email of the date in
their signup and their sign in rather
similarly inviting people gift might be
broken
alright anyway but similar a similar
concept when you invite someone to bloom
you have to sign that person's email
address you can validate okay I actually
want to sign this person invite this
person and not this other person now
let's talk about that other prong that I
talked about attacking the smart
contracts directly smart contracts have
a whole host of popular vulnerabilities
associated with them there's a really
good site called - no it's like a wasp
but for etherium and it talks about kind
of the top ten for aetherium I'm not
sure how those were chosen exactly with
their very good examples re-entrance he
attacks overflow and underflow denial of
service these are all good examples
you'll find there I'll give an example
of an overflow this was a recent I think
three months ago four months ago
it's called batch overflow a
vulnerability
basically these people implemented a
token and they wanted to make
transferring tokens cost less gas by
batching the transaction into one
transaction rather than having
individual transfers individual
transactions for every single
transaction right for transfer rather so
what they did was they implemented this
batch transfer function so you call it
once you have an array of all the people
you want to receive a token and you
provide the value unfortunately they
didn't check for an overflow so there's
an overflow vulnerability here in which
the attacker was able to basically Forge
the fact that they don't have they got
to pretend that they had millions of
dollars of tokens essentially and that
DASCO site goes into this kind of step
by step there's another one
so permissions we talked about that
earlier this an it wallet function this
is in
charity one of the parity issues this
didn't have any modifiers associated
with it right this sets kind of the
owner of the wallet and it sets who the
owners are so it wasn't in a constructor
so it's not like it was only called once
it was in a library so anyone could call
this at any point and because anyone
could call this at any point you
definitely need a modifier associated
with it so you could restrict who is
able to call it so if you're gonna
update the ownership of the contract you
need to make sure the initial owner was
the one sending that transaction in the
first place
they didn't do that so someone set
themself as the owner and blew the
entire thing up these are real-world
world problems I mean these are the kind
of owner abilities we're dealing with
right now very simple very
straightforward so it'll be good to have
all your eyes on it after after this
talk hopefully symbolic execution is
kind of a really powerful tool to use
towards auditing smart contracts I'm
gonna go over a brief example of what it
is and some tools out there that employ
it so instead of concrete execution
where variables are given concrete
values like four or five or six mmm
symbolic execution allows you to parse
through a program and provide a symbolic
value so it's not tied to one value but
basically a range of values that are
possible so when you're going through
the program you fork it every
conditional the the symbolic execution
engine will essentially fork and
traverse every path and at the end of
that path when it gets to the end state
it'll tell you the conditions necessary
to get to that end state so ultimately
you can find out a way in which a smart
contract could overflow by following the
logic of what conditions are necessary
to get there so here's an example this
is from Mark Mossberg at trail of bits
they're really really great people at
auditing contracts and they've done a
lot of great development work if you had
a concrete value here like var was 45
right you'd skip the first part of the
conditional and you jump to the else but
in a symbolic if it was a sign of
symbolic value rather when you get to
the if bar equals 42
the symbolic engine would go through
that but it would also fork and it would
go down the else as well and it would
just keep in mind the values or the
conditions rather that it needed to to
meet to get down that path so when it
gets to the end it would say okay I had
to meet this condition this condition
this condition let's see if these three
conditions are ever possible and if
values exists that meet all those
conditions then you can get to that end
state ultimately it's another slide from
mark from Trello bits this is an example
of how that end state calculation gets
done so when these are all assigned when
you have a B and C assigned symbolic
values you can go down every path here
in this tree and you'll get the end
States and the conditions necessary to
get to that end State so what we're
checking here is to see if that
assertion ever fails right assert X plus
y plus not Z or Z does not equal 3
there's a path in which that assertion
takes fails and it's when not a and B is
less than 5 and sorry not those are
Greek letters but when that takes place
when those conditions are met so that's
how the symbolic execution engine works
it'll tell you okay I got to this a
search assert failing if and only if
these criteria are met and then what's
called the constraint engine a
constraint solver will then tell you if
those constraints are solvable
essentially if that's a valid situation
if that can happen and the thing about
symbolic execution it's powerful against
smart contracts in particular less so
for things like sandbox for sandboxes so
in sandbox is for example it would be
really valuable to be able to traverse
every single path of a binary but the
issue is when you're dealing with really
large binaries that are importing VLS
with thousands of lines of code it's
difficult we'd run out of computing
resources it's impossible a lot of these
malware samples send you on a wild goose
chase so smart contracts are limited in
size because of gas considerations it
costs money real money to publish a
smart contract it part cost a lot of
money to issue transactions to that
smart contract so it's more powerful
against smart contracts so Manticore is
a good example I mentioned that it's by
the people at a trail of bits
symbolic execution tool and it will
traverse these paths like I mentioned
and let me see if I can get this to play
okay so here's an example of it so you
have this burnable token right here and
that's the source code for it right
there's intentionally some bugs in it
and they run Manticore against that
contract and it's going through all
these n states and it's finding the
conditions necessary for that so soon
it's gonna find an underflow
vulnerability and it'll essentially see
here it is enters or underflow at self
instruction it'll remember that end
State and it'll tell you the arguments
needed that satisfied that condition an
example those arguments that satisfied
that position
another thing for another approach
rather than doing symbolic execution is
just going through the binary yourself
right so you can actually use ethers
play for example an other tool by trail
bits to get the bytecode of a smart
contract at an address and disassemble
it and go through it and it's very easy
to do there aren't that many
instructions in the EVM so I recommend
doing it I actually wrote a blog post
about this too which is pretty easy to
follow along and another really popular
symbolic execution engine if you are
interested is mithril by consensus so
similar concept to Manticore both have
really good documentation and I
mentioned that reversing post so I'll
just I'll put it here for anyone who
wants to check it out that's it thank
you very much if you're interested in
coming to the party like I mentioned
just feel free to reach out to me and if
you have a resume or anything like that
come up afterwards
so I'll take any questions thank you
[Applause]