okay so as he had said I'm Andy Gish
Johnson a pierogi powered on Twitter if
you'd like to follow me we're gonna I'm
gonna present about building a
collaborative or a teaching sock so
first a little bit of Who am I I'm a
blue Timur
I'm from Pittsburgh I got my start in
the steel industry then I went to
Highmark Blue Cross Blue Shield it's
always been blue team and now I'm with
Carnegie Mellon University we're trying
to build a we're continuing to build a
student-focused Security Operations
Center related to all of that I'm also
an organizer for b-sides Pittsburgh we
celebrated our eighth year five hundred
attendees our conference is also at a
casino so what am i doing
so at Carnegie Mellon University we are
at trying to implement a teaching sock
that'll be follow the Sun so the overall
idea is students will learn a theory in
class they could come to us and then
apply their theory in a real security
operation center using Enterprise
Products it's going to also be a fall of
the Sun like a lot of popular security
operation centers so students at our
main campus in Pittsburgh will be
working with us they'll be working with
professional and fellow student
colleagues at our cutter canvas
transitioning work as you know our day
ends and their day begins part of the
job I'm gonna try to or try to focus on
learning compliance we're gonna be doing
PCI and NIST and then additionally
there's going to be a collaboration with
a research community Carnegie Mellon's a
research organization we have a lot of
people doing research rather than them
build test environments they could come
to us collaborate with us test different
ideas we've got a network we've got
thousands of people thousands of
different products let's see what we can
do
so how did I get here from there or how
did I get here from where I used to be I
think we've all had the same kind of
experiences you know you're working in a
blue team space there's this compliants
obsession you've just got these bad
alerts you've got a missing alerts you
know how many people have the same like
low quality high volume alerts like
internal failed logins or my pet peeve I
just hate them they're almost always an
IT issue it there's no real value unless
you are focused on meeting that
compliance goal or meeting that SLA like
I need these open tickets so I could
close them so I could meet my goal of
you know I need 13 or 20 tickets a day
20 of them are failed logins boom I'm
done in a half hour
I open you know service now or service
manager tickets to all the IT
organizations time to sit back and relax
related to that you know if you got the
siloing where you're just hunkered down
on these tickets you're throwing out
ServiceNow tickets to groups you're
sending emails but nobody really wants
to respond to you or are you really
making a place any better your emails
get ignored maybe you're using the wrong
language hey database admin I saw these
failed logins against this host what
database is against you know I got a
hundred different databases running on
this host let alone this is a clustered
host like it you know you're not helping
me you're just sending me a ticket that
I'm also gonna ignore and then finally
career pathing like I really like the
blue team but not everybody else does I
like looking at logs not everybody else
does when I've had junior colleagues
like what path do they have how do you
get people to find something not
everybody wants to go into AI or not
everybody wants to go into sim
management how do you provide them an
internal career path so that you can
continue contributing to the
organization and they don't just leave
and then how do you find people within
the company that you know want to help
you
so I mean that those were the
experiences I had had and then finally
when I reached a senior level was like
it's time to fix all of this
so one try you know use compliance for
good like map your goods security alerts
to these compliance controls so back to
internal failed logins how about you
know instead of that because it's always
an IT issue almost you've probably got
password lock out so you've got to
factor authentication or even got like
these mitigations maybe of auto block
for an IP do you really need to look at
you know this alert this system tried to
log in five thousand times with the same
failed password that's a waste of your
time you've stopped it in most cases sir
for instance maybe of an alert hey
instead of looking at failed logins I
wait till a user gets to like a duo
prompt and then instead of completing
the two factor the second factor they
just sit now that's a much better alert
so explained in relation to that to
either your leadership or your
compliance person so you know hey this
alert that's you know a user is stuff to
do oh that relates to you know PCI ten
to four and it's three one eight it's an
invalid access attempt I'm not looking
at what's typically an IT issue I'm
looking at this because this is somebody
most likely trying to access the system
that doesn't have access my alerts
explain that so the junior analyst can
see you the manager can see it anybody
looking at the sim I'm running seeing
the alert knows how this maps to
compliance it explains what we're doing
so you know as a junior analyst like how
many people didn't talk to compliance
till they were a senior like that was me
I just kept avoiding compliance and then
suddenly it's my turn to talk to audit
and I was just like oh I know PCI exists
but that's it
so now you know your refresh you're not
refreshing you're learning the whole PCI
we're
like with this junior colleagues that
were working on
they understood PCI they understood nest
because they've been seeing these alerts
they've been seeing you know these
phrases they they understood an auditor
could come why they could talk to any of
us I don't have to be the guy who's
there like anybody in the room could
explain how we're compliant including my
management so so for instance I'm so
I've always used Splunk for enterprise
security this is a screenshot from for
enterprise security that's super
redacted if you've never seen this
before you go you have like your alert
you've got a description you've got some
additional fields to help you some next
steps that's not really important but
you can kind of see in the middle how
this alert which was a user performed an
action on a splint object--
so this alerts related to you know NIST
control 331 about protecting logging
systems and PCI control 10 to 2 so an
analyst looking at this you know it's
not front and center but you know we're
trying to do our job but through
repetition of seeing these alerts with
no oh you know this NIST control or this
PCI control this is why I'm doing this
job this is why this makes sense it's
not fancy
you know Splunk isn't the prettiest
interface but you know it is what it is
but you've got compliance there you're
seeing it every day you're understanding
why you have compliance it's not this
once every six months there wants every
one year thing it's cut gone to a
continuous thing so transitioning from
the compliance thing the second part I
was doing there I am doing is
collaboration so in addition to having
compliance throughout the workflow we
also do collaboration we meet with
fellow IT groups fellow groups within
the organization to review what we're
we're working on what we're doing hey
here alerts we're doing here's how it
relates to compliance so you know back
to database team here's what we're doing
do you see any gaps in what we're doing
you know we're focused on the IP stack
maybe we should which for a database we
should we should be looking at database
logs you know that could be an entire
giant oversight in what we're doing are
we looking at alerts that are entirely
worthless are there things we're missing
because you know IT people they know
what their systems are up to or it could
be something like well I see you didn't
get any alerts over the weekend we did a
major upgrade why didn't you see
anything guard did you know your logins
not working anymore or I see your alerts
are only for like one log stream maybe
you're looking at the operating system
and not any of the application logs you
see us logging in but you don't see any
of the users that sort of thing I've
been bringing junior analysts along get
them involved you know they were
involved in compliance
let's get them involved in improving the
sim let's get them talking to people
improve relations do a cross-training so
if you're the junior analyst that maybe
has more of a network focus like when we
talked to the networking team come on
along like let's talk to them you could
kind of build a bridge with that group
get your name out there yeah so here
it's a example dashboard I mean again
it's this is a pretty like a lot of
different group products but I'm using
spawn so so you know in these meetings
like for instance this is back to the do
authentication system I'll show a sim
for a the duo group it's here's all of
the searches we're running but you know
here's a sample because you're not to do
a team you're not compliance if you do
want to see everything Carnegie Mellon's
hiring so
so like here's the searches were running
for monitoring duo here's the PCI
controls the name kind of gives a
explanation but we're also there to
explain everything do you see anything
we're missing
there'll be different reports of the
kind of logs we're seeing also get these
groups integrated into using Splunk so
you know here's a sample dashboard of
some administrative activity so if we
were talking they make I we may say hey
I see there was a to FA error message
over the weekend do you know what that
was about or they may say hey I see
there's a Sierra you folks in the Sauk
didn't contact us why didn't you contact
us and we could say oh well you know we
we did investigate but we had the
necessary logs or oh we just totally
missed it we didn't even know a 2fa air
was something we should focus on so and
then also you know sample notable events
which is a Splunk term for incidents so
here's you know a sample of the alerts
we've seen are these things we should be
looking for so looking at like this
maybe that top alert where the source
was in the 199 a range hey don't bother
with 199 that's test that's always going
to have crazy stuff going on or why was
there an alert from the 100 source we
could also talk about like you know this
reviewer man they really know do oh
maybe we should talk to them and see can
they help us maybe they have an interest
in being a duo admin in the future back
to that collaboration or career path
thing or you know explain terms like for
the middle one
what's in non-anomalous loggin if you
know the IT person had a question or why
did you give that such a short response
well you know in that case we really
need to talk to that sake analyst why
did they put three words that don't
really tell me anything about what they
did you know
but we show this is what we've been
doing monitoring your system this is the
value we're trying to provide to the
organization this is how this maps to
compliance controls we know you're
getting audited we're getting audited
you know we're all part of this one big
organization let's improve this together
this is what we do in the sock all day
we're not just sending you weird emails
or giving you calls or booting you off
the network continually like we're doing
things because we have compliance
because we want to make the place a
better organization can you help us so
I've been in this setup for going on two
years between the previous two employers
I've had pretty good outcomes so like
the first year of building a sock didn't
even detect the penetration test it
wasn't until they were enterprise admin
and they got loud on purpose just to see
if we would detect anything did I
finally see an alert I mean that's bad
that's terrible
the second year we didn't block the pen
test but we detected them we detected
them within hours and alert within days
or hours is better than an alert within
months or finding out on the news you
were breached a year later right this is
all continuous improvement sock morale
improved
we went from hey you know we've got this
glut glut of alerts we open alert closed
alert our SLA s are amazing but you know
nobody was happy to the socks improving
people were seeing interesting alerts
people want to make the sock better the
whole team felt like they were
contributing it was no longer well I'm
just the junior sock admin I get alerts
in the morning I close them I go home
and then I repeat the next day it was Oh
what you know this portion of the sock I
helped build I helped improve
we went from not monitoring the
mainframe at all to monitoring the
mainframe and it was myself and one of
the junior analysts and he was like you
know I didn't know anything about a
mainframe now we're monitoring
mainframes no and then nobody does that
I mean it was amazing that we built
mainframe monitoring the stock
visibility improved people knew what we
were working on they knew why we were
working on things you know we had the
fishing intake hey I got this phishing
message but people were also notifying
us hey I did the system upgrade or hey
this system had behaved strangely did
you folks see anything it people knew
about the suck they were trying to help
us we weren't just the random people in
that room with the locked door that you
just kind of walked by or you avoid
because they're just like the auditors
and they make my life miserable you know
but yeah so that's where I started we're
in the process of building a student
security operation center we need
students so come on in a row at Carnegie
Mellon University questions up we got to
get you a mic yeah so from Ground Zero
and your first like the sock was even
just a an idea at that point like where
did you begin like how do you how do you
start so it may admittedly the first
time around you know I had Splunk for
enterprise security with all the generic
searches finally after like a few months
of just spinning our wheels we turned
everything off and it was okay let's go
from system to system and figure out
what makes sense to monitor for some
systems like okay if you've got a
Windows domain controller there's a
wealth of resources online for building
decent alerts for other systems we sat
down with those groups or
just said hey we're wasting our time
here can you help us figure out what we
should be monitoring sometimes you got
to you know grease the wheels with a box
of donuts or a cake but yeah you know
you do what you have to do and every
group has the person who wants to talk
to you and help like yeah you also have
to search out that person can you tell
us more about how you set up that
mainframe monitoring yeah so initially
it was flow control just looking at like
could we get flow data at the edge of
the mainframe we did a little bit with
intrusion detection like looking just
for like the error message and then the
mainframe team already had reports that
were being exported so it was logs that
were 24 hours old and then finally we
bought a product sync sort that
converted mainframe messages to syslog
but still that was the you know no
offense to them that was converting
messages to syslog and then it was back
to reading mainframe documentation
talking to people like phil young
mainframes 767 what should i be looking
at and then we got the terminology down
so we knew like you know behavior
profiling the things that were valuable
and not just failed logins so like these
users should only run these jobs which
are equivalent to program sir
[Music]
Phil young he's mainframe 767 he's I
think he's running evil mainframe
hacking tomorrow afternoon here but yeah
he's the guy to talk to for all things
mainframe yeah follow-on question about
replacing Splunk enterprise security
with relationship building I'm doing
something kind of similar to that but a
little terrified about how long it's
going to take like I'm fine with baby
steps forever toward the horizon always
better but at some point I want to be
able to point out and say hey look what
we did and and I'm a little terrified
about how long that's gonna take so can
can you talk about that process a little
bit please um yeah the first time it it
took about a year so we were doing well
so there was a lot of panic as you know
the audits were coming back
yeah the metrics were shot exactly
but yeah we started turning things off
turning new things on as we would write
them and because you were working fast
anyway now you got a whole mess of new
alerts that weren't very good but the
junior team understood like hey these
are only going to show up for a little
bit so where I met yeah so our metrics
were wild for a good six months of like
teach analyst has a hundred events to
each analyst is five to 100 which you
know you spread average that out over a
month that didn't look too bad fudged
the numbers a little bit
yeah yeah oh yeah and then you know we
tracked a these renew searches or
correlation searches luckily know that
we had implemented and luckily we you
all purposely we had everything mapped
to compliance so we could explain why we
were doing it we weren't just throwing
you know roles researches at outs like
we did this mapping to this compliance
role or requirement so I'm I'm very
interested in seeing what it's going to
be like in another semester or another
year because I think you're going to
have some really interesting metrics on
how you're driving the arms race because
your mainframe student and Sox students
are gonna get much better and your
little your red team students are gonna
get better and each one is going to have
some sort of area it's gonna be
interesting to watch the results I'm
very excited for the red team students
which Carnegie Mellon has way too many
awful
[Music]
way too many in a good statement just as
a blue team or you know how do you or do
you find that analysts run into like I
don't know I don't have a name for it
sock burnout we're or alert burnout oh
yeah we're there stared to you how do
you deal with that do you rotate on what
they're looking for do you test that you
know um so I tried to figure out you
know what do what are people's interest
so you know are you a network person why
don't you start meeting with the network
team with me or meeting with them even
more like for the improvement side of
what we should be monitoring why don't
you try writing some searches and see
what happens I'm here other
Splunk professionals or in the
organization that could give you guide
points because you're still contributing
to the sock and you're still making us
better but you know how do you take a
break without but you're still helping
us yeah
and then for reference that the sock
size is around a dozen people so I don't
know how this would scale for like the
200 person mega socks that some of these
banks have so being a university are you
actually using students as your junior
analysts like part-time students or so
we started over the summer with a small
test group this coming fall will be go
live the spring and summer have been
let's build this out give this as
professional as we can once the students
show up as well as the reference follow
the Sun the students at Carnegie Mellon
Qatar when they start showing up Pato
how do we perform that transition like a
you know junior professional analysts
have done transitions where I've been
elsewhere but students will be an
interesting change for that specifically
I've seen two more hands here we'll do
these last two questions and then we'll
call it so addressing sock burnout and
low morale we're to the top two three
ways that you've increased or been able
to increase the morale within your sock
one get rid of terrible alerts like the
failed log and I hate it every analyst
I've ever worked with has hated them if
there's an alert you keep seeing that
you don't like flag it like let's stop
looking at bad alerts there aren't too
many people who duck who don't want to
see an alert because they just don't
like it it's usually well this just
doesn't provide any value and then
trying to get everybody to feel like
they're contributing breakdown like
you're a senior you're a junior like
we're all part of the sock
I don't know everything you're new you
should be bringing new insights like you
know I'm getting trained in my way like
I'm getting old
tell me what I'm doing wrong break these
habits you know I used to have the
manager that got hit with the worms and
that's all that person had ever thought
about
I've been in a lot of fishing and now
ransomware in the news like am I going
to be that guy that's entirely focused
on ransomware because I saw one occur I
wants like these new people should be
telling me like hey no you you know
you're stuck in your way right
hopefully far we're gonna keep getting
fetched forever but so may I have a last
question if you are in a situation of
building go stock in a company from a
scratch I don't know sock whatsoever
whatsoever and you have a couple of
people only as the resources would you
be able to define place the main focuses
what what should these few people focus
on concentrate yeah so if you were
building a sock and you had limited
resources which I feel like is every
sock I've ever been in I've always gone
to mail filtering and specifically
egress because usually of your ingress
relatively secured but the fishing's
always going to be an attack I mean we
see that and all the other talks
everybody basically seems to come in
understanding email too so you don't
have that giant training barrier web
applications uh everybody I mean that's
tough I have trouble with web
application attacks so I maybe I keep it
on the back burner because I have
trouble but people seem to understand
web browsing because they could browse
the Internet and build the same traffic
people seem to understand email because
they're sending and receiving and those
have always been my two focuses
[Music]
the failed login thing I mean it it's
such a mess from scripting and such
all right big round of applause for Andy
[Applause]