so as you can see we have make a new who
is going to join us later Cindy Jones
Kirsten Renner and myself you know about
me cares Cindy tell us a little bit
about you sure my name is Cindy Jones I
am currently a principal security
consultant with rapid7
back on the back wall if you're
interested in any kind of prospective
hiring opportunity to go there I have
been in information security for a while
I've been an IT for really long time I
have a Microsoft certification number
that six digits and starts with a three
so I've been in IT for a long time and
it evolved to a security program and
I've been with rapid7 for about three
and a half years now and I love what I
do and Kirsten tell us about you is this
working
hello Kirsten Renner I'm the director of
recruiting at Nevada an advanced
analytics and cybersecurity company and
to tell you how long I've been doing
this the first and only program that I
ever wrote was in Visual Basic when
Visual Basic was new and exciting and I
c'n coding in index cards but that's how
long ago my coding career is another
story for another day
yeah I can do punch cards yeah they're
actually my alter-ego is the car hacking
village which is I'm thank God I have a
Hermione time-turner because I'm
actually there right now
sorting out boxes so one of the things
we're going to touch on is why volunteer
you know a lot of us think that
volunteering is cool and you know you're
part of the cool kids club to do it but
I wanted Kirsten to touch a little bit
more on the car hockey village and why
you volunteer and then Cindy I love your
story about how you got into
volunteering so Kirsten oh thank God for
my relationship with you because while
I've been so passionate about the things
that I've learned in the in primarily in
the DEFCON community but in the info
section community it never occurred to
me until we started having
these conversations hey these are skills
these are I have to manage humans I have
to manage a schedule I have to react to
problems when vendors don't show up or
things don't work out so it's there's a
lot of things that you can translate
into actual you know work-related skills
and in areas of expertise that are
occurring while you're volunteering
right so in particular just every little
detail and all the things that are gonna
pop up that you didn't expect or that
you tried to pre-plan for and so forth
all these things are gonna you know got
to remind people that you are running on
volunteer time and and sponsor dollars
and everything's not gonna be perfect
but by the way 20,000 people are showing
up so hope it works out so Cindy tell us
about your volunteering so I've always
been somebody who likes to get involved
with things I like getting in on the
ground floor finding out how things work
when I first started getting involved
with I mean I've been volunteering since
I was probably her own Girl Scout I
don't even know it's been forever
falling got sucked into a sorority in
college and became the head of just
about every Scottish forsaken panel that
there was there and when I got into IT I
would start going to conferences and I
was attending a lot but my background is
in is it an IT or or in security my
background as far as school when I was a
psych major
so I intrinsically want to help people
right
psychology scary as heck I don't want to
know about the human mind anymore I
found that out going through school but
ended up going to shoulda started
getting into IT getting into security
and when I'd show up at a conference if
I didn't know anybody was like hey is
there anything I could do to help out
what can I do how can I help out because
of that I started developing an amazing
I mean my contact list is stupid I've
got more Chris's in my contact lists
than any
I know every way if I say Chris right
now raise your hand seriously if there's
a cribbing
I know ICU one to at least three in the
room okay so but you end up getting all
these great networking possibilities and
options to go ahead and reach out to
people to get you know insight into
what's going on there feel or if you're
interested in checking out their field
and what's happening there but my
initial intro into volunteerism was
started really young it's all because I
want to help but what about your first
time when you went to DEFCON and I went
to DEFCON yeah my first Def Con
experience helping out no didn't you go
to DEFCON for a while and not volunteer
oh yeah okay so that's another thing
okay so I spent when I lived overseas
for a while and that was a gap in my my
volunteer world and I have been going to
Def Con since DEFCON a 13 and I was
always before I started building this
wonderful list of Chris's my basically
been going there and I've been hiding in
my room I'm not a really social person
believe it or not I mean I know I've
probably talked to like at least a third
of you guys in the room did it or over
the past day and a half I am NOT a
social person I love being wildly up
being quite happy in my room watching
the stream of the talks or going to the
talks and going back to my room to
recharge or what have you and I realized
I was just taking I was taking a lot
so that whole wanting to help people
think aspects of my personality I was
just ignoring it it wasn't happening so
when I finally was able to go ahead and
make that connection by wait I need to
start giving back a little bit that's
how I discovered besides besides was
just starting out it was besides the
second besides Las Vegas I got involved
with us at the very beginning and I'm
like let me help with registration what
can I do there's one of those things
like how can I help
what could I do because I really wanted
to be able to give something back that
in and of itself I actually it allowed
me to learn how to communicate with
people it was a starting point of
starting to develop some skills that I
didn't think I had I was always the one
in my room I was always the one being
shy now I'm like hey what's up what's
your name how you do it you know what do
you do who do you work for what's going
on with you and just learning how to
communicate with people on a level
that hopefully is it too intrusive but
at the same time just being able to
communicate in a means that was
effective in your confidence level oh my
gosh out there up out the wazoo my job
now I'm on a routine basis has to speak
to whether it's you know board members
whether it's a c-suite whatever the case
may be and tell them basically that
their security program sucks and this is
how it sucks I am able to go into an
organization now and confidently and sit
there and explain to them why it is that
their baby is ugly you know what's wrong
how they can go ahead and fix it and
because that is strictly due to the fact
that I've practiced communicating with
people at all levels at all skill levels
in all levels of within organizations in
order to be able to express that tool
effectively and I did a survey over the
last three months of the community to
sort of say okay how many of you are
volunteering in the community and what
are the skills that you are gaining
through that and what was interesting is
that teamwork and ability to collaborate
was a skill that 82% people were able to
say yes this is something that we got
organizational skills seventy-five
percent said that was one of the major
skills that they learned communication
were so big on communication can people
write can they speak 76% said that that
was the major skill that they learned by
volunteering planning 75% networking so
it was these key skills that were
needing in the workplace that were
leading in teams that people are
automatically learning by volunteering
in the community so kirsten sort of put
the recruiters lens on this so when you
see someone who volunteers in the
community what are some of the things
that you're looking for them to say on
their resume I see a lot of resumes that
say besides be sites be size but that
doesn't tell me anything how would
someone write their volunteerism on a
resume that would pop out for you so
before I was doing this earlier I was
over there looking at resumes and nine
out of ten of the resumes that I looked
at I discovered while I was talking to
those people that they did thing
they did things in the community they
did things that aren't on the resume and
it's important it's important that you
identify people are like should I talk
about my interest should I talk about
the things that I'm studying yeah you
should you should reveal to us what
you're proactively doing to develop
yourself and that includes going to
conferences and volunteering and and
maybe for me because I have been a
volunteer for so long maybe it's it's
something that I'm looking for but I
absolutely think that people should
should include that in their in their
resume and what I think is interesting
is a lot of people just say I volunteer
rather than say I'm in charge of
sponsorship so I'm in charge of going
out and securing funds I'm in charge of
overall conference management we're
going to go into that a little bit more
but being very specific about talking
about are you the subject matter expert
that presented are you the person that
managed all the volunteers can you
delegate can you plan can you organize
so don't just say I volunteered add what
that business component is now if it's
you just showed up for the day that's
fine but you showed up you participated
you were out there in the community
these are all things that you know
recruiters are going to be looking for
so let's dive a little bit more into
conference management Cindy you started
beside San Antonio so let's talk a
little bit more about what the skills
were that you learned being part of
these sites and Antonio and how did you
work with your employer on being able to
do that so when I first started beside
San Antonio I was doing I was working
with the government as a contractor the
depending on oh how familiar most of
y'all are with the government
contracting world but you get very
limited PTO and there's also very little
room for negotiation in those contracts
at times so they get paid for having a
body in a seat for X number of hours
that's all there is to it when you're
going above and beyond that
you're it's not going to you know and
these government agencies and the
contractors that they work with don't
receive the same benefit from being
involved with a small security
conference a localized security
conference my bosses were all in DC they
really didn't care about security
conference in San Antonio because number
one they weren't really there in the
business of security anyways the number
two there in DC they don't that's got no
impact on them so working with them in
that regard was very difficult I ended
up going the hole with PTO when I left
my last my last job with the DoD I ended
up I think I owed them my last paycheck
after my last paycheck it was nothing
pretty but for me it was worth it
because I was doing something for the
community and that was something that
really really mattered to me um since
then I've been very fortunate to have
handed off besides San Antonio I did
that for three years and that was while
I was working at DEFCON and while I was
doing my job here and while volunteering
for the rest of besides Texas
organizations DFW and Austin and we had
one in Houston so there's a lot
happening there when I was involved with
that but all that time was on me right
this is something I chose to do now
since then I've been very very fortunate
when I left the DoD world and working as
an Air Force contractor I fell into
gratefully to rapid7 and as you can see
rapid7 it's pretty present in the
community right where we're we're
everywhere and there there has never
been a case of them not being supported
as a matter of fact the reason why I was
recruited by rapid7
is because of the community involvement
that I had and that was one of the
reasons why they hired me they like it
when people are getting out there and
spreading their word
you know perhaps you're going ahead and
you know branding your slide deck if
you're giving a talk or you know but
they know that I am with rapid7 I carry
my business cards I hand those out and
they're very supportive in that regard
they ensure that I get to conferences
most conferences don't pay for so can
you drill down a little bit more income
prints management you did you know what
you were doing when you started be
seitan - oh my gosh I had no idea it was
such a mess I was really lucky I had
some mentors so that was hugely
important but I had no idea what to deal
with when it came to I didn't realize
you just don't think about it right you
guys you guys people come to a
conference so they're not involved with
it there's like wow that's a really cool
show look at the cool artwork oh look at
you know I register here or they have
sponsors that are doing this people
don't have a clue on what goes into
conference management these the Santoni
was tiny
I mean and you look at something like
this you're just like it's mind-boggling
so the finance management finance
management you're dealing with personnel
management cuz you have to go ahead and
get the crew that's gonna run the event
you then have to manage that crew you
have to hope that you're finding
responsible volunteers which sometimes
don't show up yeah that's not a hit on
Megan that's not I don't know no no you
know we you just you're stuck in a
position where you have this has to be
done to a certain level of expectation
that you set for yourself and it doesn't
always work out the way you want but you
learn so much dealing with people
gathering money oh my goodness I'm
horrible at it
I learned this because I dive in
headfirst got it done but oh my gosh
so difficult so Kirsten talk to us a
little bit more about you know if you
saw all of the things that Cindy does
now would that turn you off as to her
for thinking that she's going to be out
in the community and not doing her job
or how can you drill down in interviews
and find out the skills that she has
been using I mean would you find that
valuable in her beyond her technical
skills so from a recruiting perspective
I I have an unfair advantage in in the
lens that I'm looking through I realized
that just organizing a village is not
the same thing as organizing an entire
conference but the volume of people that
we have coming in and the the amount of
things we have to deal with today we
realized this morning we realized oh
crap we need insurance
and we aren't sure if we have all the
dedicated power grids that we need for
all the things that we're gonna be
plugging in and we don't want to blow up
the Flamingo maybe probably so for me
I'm gonna look I'm gonna look through a
different lens right but typically if
you as the candidate or as a potential
candidate are able to articulate all the
many things that she was describing or
that anybody that is is volunteering
even if you're just strictly the person
managing the sponsorship if you're oh my
god did anybody think about up lighting
is that a thing do we need that do we
want it to be dark and and why are we
just feel realizing this now a year you
know a year into it so for me I I
encourage people to make sure that you
are able to articulate those things find
a volunteer at a place like this higher
ground in particular that can help you
articulate those things on your resume
but I can't imagine any recruiter worth
their salt that isn't gonna see value in
your volunteer time the fact that you
are outside of the things that you have
to do this is what I say to students
this is what I say to engineers at every
level tell me about the things that
you're doing that help you develop
professionally that you didn't have to
do that you're not getting paid to do
that your coursework didn't require you
to do right I know recruiter worth it
isn't gonna see great value in that so
one thing that I always recommend and I
rarely see anyone doing this is any
volunteering that you do take a few
moments after your shift after the time
that you're there and write down what
you did so this this pertains to
volunteering for the day this pertains
to a competition it's keeping that sort
of journal of did I do you know
deconflict a situation
did I verbalize something in a way that
someone else understood it did it was
there a technical problem that no one
knew how to solve that I was able to
solve it's really being able to create
those real-life experiences that you can
share in an interview because how many
of us
have gone into an interview and they say
explain to me a time when you learned
something new yeah can I talk to that
right now
go ahead oh my gosh okay I don't know
how many of you were impacted by the
kerfuffle with the badges yesterday okay
it was a mess I thank you for your
patience we appreciate you I basically
had to stand in front of a line of
people and say there will be no walking
badges
go home and that was devastating for me
this is like this is I've been here
forever this is my con people come in
yes this is awesome and they had to kick
people out and they don't care what I'm
feeling they're like well thing I've
been sitting here since 6:00 this
morning what the heck's going on so to
be able to say that I D escalated that
to a certain degree and assisted with
that in that matter that's that's a
major skill that I wouldn't have had if
it wasn't for the the participation that
I have here I basically had to tell
about 300 people get out and then I got
to welcome them back with open arms
afterwards which was wonderful but
that's besides the point and and you're
gonna go home and write about that
Laurie oh and you know any sign motion
so good yeah I I think you have to
understand that these are real-life
experiences that you're going to be able
to use in talking in an interview and a
face-to-face interview being able to
talk about it when you're on a phone
screen I know we're running out of time
but I'm still going to move a little bit
farther so competitions it's interesting
that many recruiters are now starting to
look at which competitions are you part
of and really looking at are you
learning the skills that you need in the
competition so I would highly recommend
that if you're in a competition even if
you didn't win it definitely list it on
your social media profile definitely
listed on your resume and also be sure
again to look at it after the end of the
competition rather than you know
high-fiving we won having that beer
definitely say okay what was the
technical skill that I learned what did
I mess up on you know what did I fail we
learn more when we fail than when we
succeed who how did I communicate with
other people because you're actually in
an environment where there's a time
crunch there's a resource crunch it's a
problem you've never seen before and
you're working with people
that you've never worked with before gee
what does that sound like that sounds
like work okay that's real life so why
are you not journaling
those situations so that yes you may not
have all of the work experience that the
job is asking for that you can say on
your resume but if you've done 10 to 12
competitions I'm sorry but that
translates into work experience because
you've been in that work environment if
you're looking to get into another
industry if you're looking to get into
another skill set broaden your horizons
go to the car hacking village go to
cyber 912 which is a cyber policy CTF go
to any other CTF so you can expand your
knowledge if you're looking to move into
another industry really consider going
to the CTF there because not only are
you gonna learn the skills you're also
going to network and we all know the
number one way to find a job is
networking the other thing and I'm going
to ask Kirsten to talk about this as
well as presentations so you may not be
the person that wants to you know
de-escalate 300 people having to walk
out the door you may not be the person
that wants to be in competitions but you
do like to present now Kirsten what
would you look at if someone presented a
lot what what does that say to you do
you say oh I don't want to talk to them
or do you say I do want to talk to them
it it just so happens that when we did
our coffee papers you know we had to
look at a lot or presentations and then
all those presentations had to be
scrubbed so that I guess I need to
remember to put that on my resume that I
could scrub presentations you know it
takes bravery to write it the people
that are smiling may be me maybe you
maybe we're tired maybe we're nervous
imposter syndrome it's a thing google it
like it sometimes you feel terrified
like why do I even deserve to be here
why mine expert writes all normal stuff
right so the majority of the people
perform you know that are that are
getting up that are doing their
presentations
they may they may something say
something you don't agree with you can
collaborate with them they're taking the
time there they're not probably not
getting paid to do it but they're
putting together their presentation and
there's a lot of planning that goes into
that the one time you made me put an
actual recruit DC actually put some
slides together I can't tell you how
much I stressed over every little
graphic is are people gonna laugh at
that is that funny is that cute is that
relevant right a lot goes into it right
so absolutely and I also will encourage
you if maybe it doesn't make sense for
you to be in a competition you can still
you can still go to them and you go to
the talks too right there's so much to
learn and besides the competitions and
the in the CTS and the cool prizes and
all that stuff it definitely shows that
you worked on a team and some of the
best lessons my unsolicited favorite
question for if you're recruiting that
you should ask and if you're the
candidate that you should volunteer
before you get asked and I know I told
this to a couple people today talk about
your failures right you don't put it on
your resume you don't say I messed up
the thing but so you talk about your
accomplishments you're gonna reveal so
much about yourself when you describe
give your testimony to the thing that
broke - the thing that blew up - the
thing that didn't work
do you blame others do you do you figure
it out you learn from it are you
prepared in the future to not blow up
the robot so I would recommend to think
about catch your your interviewer
off-guard and and talk about what you
did and how it didn't work and what you
learned from it because everybody makes
mistakes so the one thing I would say
about presentations realize that it
takes a lot more time management than
you would think so understanding that
you know the RSA if you're gonna submit
for an RSA they close tomorrow yeah and
and that just went out this morning I
don't know how many of us missed you
know that the deadlines for tomorrow
yeah that socks right in the middle of
yeah but understanding that one of the
reasons why people think that presenting
is a hand-picked Club and it's not it is
be someone who puts through a defined
outline of what their gonna speak about
they know when to submit it they know
how to fill it out correctly I can tell
you there is not a uniform way of
filling out a proposal submission one of
the most difficult that I've had to do
even more difficult than RSA has been
Grace Hopper
and it was it's an eight section
proposal and it's great because then
it's now my foundation for every single
other you know conferences I submit to
which is you know I did all that work in
a week so but realize if you're going to
present if you have to engage your
employer or not I know that one of our
resume career coaches over there we had
to engage her employer nine months ago
to make sure that she could present here
and then you can also decide do you want
your employer to know that you're
presenting or are you doing it on your
own and that's your own decision so
we're going to move into some final
thoughts here because a theme today is
sort of underlining theme has been
burnout and one thing that happens when
I did the survey 80% of the people who
said that they do volunteering they said
it stresses them out and what was
interesting is that they said that they
would kill still do it but 80% of the
community says that burnout stress is a
major part of them volunteering it's
back stress it's headaches it's
migraines it's anxiety it's depression
and they still do it so one of the
things that I want Cindy to sort of
touch on is how you look at delegating
your succession and how you look at how
you move on because the one thing that I
will say is if you tend to burn a bridge
in a volunteer situation you are
probably doing the exact same thing in
your career you are probably taking
you're probably going much farther than
you should
and then you're doing the high middle
finger and walking out and trying to
find a next job the other day rather
than planning your exit so Cindy how did
you plan your exit would be site San
Antonio or any other situation
so with b-side San Antonio my first year
there as I mentioned I had a spectacular
mentor Michael Gough was with besides
Austin at the time and he was just
feeding me information hey you need a
time this need to time naive needed time
that so he basically trained me which
was wonderful I with his help and what I
thought was the help of a committee
which ended up not being a committee
even the guy who was only supposed to
get the beer moved out of town and
didn't even find the beer for me didn't
even source it it's horrible so that I
ended up doing that with mice myself
with his assistant so the next year I
had to planned out I knew how I could go
about doing it I tried making a couple
of key people who seemed as passionate
as I was about it
by the beginning of the planning cycle
for the third year I knew I needed to
step back three years doing an entire
conference on your own is exhausting the
stress levels were ridiculous the amount
of time it was taking me to take off of
work I didn't share that with anyone and
I was fortunate enough to have somebody
involved kind of on the periphery but a
lot of that was my fault because I was a
very good at delegation yet that was
willing to take it on and I basically
kind of said hey by the way this is my
last year here you go about a year out
so he had a year to get used to the idea
and a year to object to it so I was very
fortunate in that regard
mm-hmm other scenarios are much more
touchy I think I think you know you're
basically the Wikipedia for your subject
right so for instance here I lead
registration for besides Elvia I ran
registration or been a part of
registration since besides lv2 that's
been a while I've got the historical
knowledge me and three other people are
the oldest tenured staff members here
I've got the historical knowledge how do
I hand that off if I were to say next
year is my last year who do I hand that
off to do you groom staff members and
are they willing to stay on
after you leave you know I mean you end
up building a pretty tight team it's
just like any other organization but
because it's volunteer work it's I don't
want to say it's easier to step back
from but there's more I think it's a
higher likelihood that a team of people
would remove themselves than in a paid
position so it's it's looking at
succession planning and leadership
planning and it brings back to the point
that someone is not responsible for your
career you are responsible for your
career and you are responsible for
having that conversation with your
manager as to where you go in your
company and if you're in a volunteer
position you need to have the risk you
need to be responsible enough to say I'm
starting to get burned out I'm starting
to get tired a lot of us who get
involved in the community say no one can
survive without me I'm going down with
the ship
and that is where burnout happens you
have to say I'm at this point where I'm
tired I'm still having fun and I need to
plan it about two years out and let the
people know don't hold it as a secret
and say oh by the way tomorrow's my last
day I think you know we would all get
shot if we did that or something like
that sorry I shouldn't have said that we
would all have people get very upset so
Kirsten I know you've been involved in a
variety of things how do you handle sort
of succession planning or handing things
off or delegating or do you not do that
I could that's an area where I can
definitely improve and I'll just going
to be honest with you
delegating is also an area where I I
don't want to say I struggle or that I
don't get it right it's part of
Management everyday but asking for help
is something that you need to but you're
like wait on the helper learning how to
ask for help right is it sometimes a
struggle I have a new year's resolution
three years running that I will do less
and not overextend myself and I'm not
going to call out any conference in
particular but there's one there's a lot
of conferences happening the week of
summer camp
and one of them I'm not attending you
can see me here and you'll see me
somewhere else in a couple days but I
just I'm not stepping foot over there
I'm just done it just for me it's
exhausting it's it's it's too much so
you have to you have to that's its
humility - right - to realize when
you've reached your limitations and then
- it's your own time management also
right besides the resources and the
vendors and all the things that you need
you need to manage yourself so you have
to give in a little bit surrender so
this is the last presentation for a
higher ground and before I start crying
because you know this is always a labor
of love do we have any questions about
volunteering or do we want to just have
a offline not videotaped conversation
about this afterwards what's the vote no
questions okay
thank you so much for listening to our
conversation it has actually been
videotaped as well we're going to be
doing this presentation again at Derby
con we actually have all of the
Community Survey data about community
volunteering and career development that
we're going to be releasing there thank
you so much and thank you for being part
of higher ground yeah
[Applause]