excellent thanks for coming everyone
we're gonna be talking about web than
today
so how Docs supports it for second
factor using it next what comes next for
login and generally looking forward to
telling you about it it's first a quick
disclaimer I do work for Dropbox on the
product security team and I worked on
the web on end project is that certainly
informs my talk but all opinions are
still my own I'm not actually here
speaking on behalf of my employer out of
the way let's start with the quick user
story so let's say I'm working on a
presentation perhaps I want to get some
feedback on it could be based on a true
story here
share it with my friend they receive an
email might look something like this
nice blue button to click on go ahead
and click what happens come to this
website use your name password click
Sign In now I can view the file so how
did this website actually figure out
this was my friend my friend had access
to my slides well it's that password
that was really the only secret part of
this and if we start thinking about what
we actually want out of a secret like
this that authenticates us to a website
controls our accounts one key element is
that we don't really want to tell it to
people that's kind of a strong secret
you're not telling it to everyone you're
keeping it really restricted to only
where it needs to be and unfortunately
passwords are not so great secrets since
you're in the passwords track of b-sides
you may be familiar with this but you're
always entering them on websites you're
essentially telling this web form this
website all the time this is my password
please authenticate me so this of course
leads to problems because it relies on
me it relies on all of you to not mess
up to not just once put your password
into the wrong place so if we go back to
our example maybe you're used to putting
in a password if someone shares a file
with you so you can sign in to your
cloud provider of choice so someone else
an attacker can rely on that to send you
an email that you know looks like
someone is sharing a file with you looks
like it redirected you to the right
place but it's of course really
a fishing site so all of a sudden your
password has been told to the wrong set
of people to the wrong server to an
attacker they can compromise your
account that's one problem with
passwords the other problem is just that
you have too many of them and we're not
actually good at remembering long random
strings of letters or numbers so
typically you know you might choose an
easy to remember password which often
means easy to guess so
with that you also end up with both
fishable secrets that secrets and week
secrets now you know some smart people
thought about this and we're like we can
do better we can add a second secret
second factor authentication so we're
probably mostly familiar with this you
have an Authenticator app on your phone
you have a code sent to you ever SMS and
this really helps with this second case
of having weak passwords are we using
passwords because now you have this
second secret that's a little harder to
get at it's it's actually you know
separate for each site potentially your
your Authenticator app has a separate
secret for every single site or the SMS
infrastructure generates a new one-time
code for you on every login so we have
the second secret where the part you're
telling it only works for a little bit
it's one-time use it's you know a minute
long so we've reduced the risk here and
really helped with the second case of
password reuse and weak passwords but we
haven't really solved the problem of
phishing because that part you still
still part you tell still works it's
still working for a whole minute so if
someone can just as easily ask for that
part as well as your password if they're
trying to fish you and go ahead and turn
right back around and once again gain
access to your account the key lesson
here was though that computers can
actually help us to design stronger
authentication schemes so we had this
human problem of not being able to
remember passwords one other solution is
a password manager of course or in the
second factor case we can rely on our
phone to actually remember those secrets
for us and for phishing if we want to
solve that problem
we can see how a browser might be able
to help us with that to your browser
does actually know the difference
between a phishing site in a real site
it might not know which is which or that
one is trying to be masquerade of the
other but it does know their different
origins their different domains and so
we can actually use that information the
TR TP was a pretty good start of the
authenticator apps because you know they
remembered a different secret for each
site for you and the weak link was
really that you had to actually be the
one to enter the code into the browser
and there was no guarantee that you were
entering into the right place instead we
can offer a browser to talk to our
devices directly and handle that for us
as long as we keep credentials scoped to
a particular domain our browser can make
sure that phishing sites can never gain
access to a real sites credentials
because they're just fundamentally
different domains so enforcing that
separation and using our computers our
browser to help us that's kind of the
key idea of what web ovens bringing to
strong authentication and then really
the rest of the talk see you know how
that actually works and then how you can
build on that to have strong second
factor authentication and even
potentially password lists lock in log
in and seeing in general where do
passwords fit end to this new world if
we have strong authentication with web
lock then you can see here kind of a
roadmap for what I just said the rest of
our time here and I'll go ahead and dive
in to a bit more detail on what what web
event actually is so we have a nice you
know technical looking specification
here and this is kind of you know most
specific version of like what is web uh
then it's you know a specification by
the w3c that outlines a set of browser
AP is that websites can use to
authenticate users on the web using
public key credentials a great thing
about public key credentials is now
remember that secret part we want a
secret that we never tell here the
secret never leaves needs to leave the
Authenticator only a public verification
part is sent to the server
of course the other nice thing about
this is those credentials are also going
to be scoped to a website as I mentioned
so if you're looking at this back it can
be a little intimidating and it helps to
just know first you know what's the
overall structure of what what weapon
actually lays out for us so it's going
to give us as you know where us would be
safe server developers it's gonna give
us to operations here we can register
new credentials to a user and we can
authenticate with them and we have three
main parties who we have to figure out
how they're going to talk to each other
and how they're going to behave so we
have this server that wants to
authenticate users it's also called the
relying party as you'll see that in the
spec now the professor mediates
communication between all of these
elements and the Authenticator devices
themselves so this could really be kind
of anything we'll just see going forward
you were talking about like UV keys
hardware tokens also authenticators
built into your laptop maybe a TPM maybe
a fingerprint reader maybe your phone so
this is kind of a wide class of things
but basically anything that can talk to
the browser and actually take out the
undertake this protocol now if you're
looking at the spec or you're just
getting a bit lost if I talk through
things it's helpful to remember that as
a server developer you can ignore a lot
of this and really as a user you don't
have to worry about too many of the
details so it depends which angle you're
coming in from but the spec really has
to describe you know both for all three
of these parties what they need to do so
you can really focus in on especially at
the beginning the party you're most
interested in so in this case it would
be the server developers for and instead
of kind of going more in-depth and like
specifically the messages and protocols
just gonna kind of go it out a little
bit of a higher level of what are some
key elements both of these operations
and that'll set us up for how Dropbox
actually deployed web often and what it
looks like for different kinds of these
options so for registration we're gonna
generate a request for a new credential
on the server we're going to pass that
to the browser call you know navigator
doc credentials dot create this is this
new API that web app in specified the
browser is going to go ahead and
pass it off to the authenticator along
with what origin the users currently on
and then they're going to take undertake
their own protocol it specified some and
web off end the real detailed
specification that looks at this side of
things the browser to Authenticator is
called see tap - so that's the one to
look at if you're really interested in
the hardware side of this in any case
it'll come back the Authenticator will
go ahead and create a new key pair pass
the public key and some other
information back to the browser and the
browser will go ahead and pass it back
to the server where it can go ahead and
parse and save this credential with
whatever user is registering so next
you've registered a credential with your
favorite site you go you want to login
maybe it's second factor or maybe it's
login in any case the server's gonna go
ahead you know generate ourselves a
request call this API again the browser
passes that to the Authenticator again
with that origin so it's only scoped to
that specific origin so if you're on a
fishing side right now the Authenticator
will not see the real site it'll see the
fishing site and won't use the real
sites credentials then the Authenticator
you know signs this request using the
saved credential passes it back to the
browser browser passes it back to the
server or your JavaScript passes it to
your back-end and now you can actually
verify their response so this is of
course a key piece for security you have
to check that it's for the right origin
using the right key pair that a user has
actually the user you think it is
actually it's Gracchus turd with you so
there's a series of verification steps
in the specular both registration and
authentication actually they're most
important and authentication for
registration a lot of the information is
actually not like not signed or not as
important because the real security
comes here where you're checking the
origin and credentials are correct
that's the overview of how this protocol
works but before we kind of get further
want to interject if anyone has you know
been researching web bottom and is
confused by the names out there or if
you do later it can be helpful to kind
of see in an overarching level like how
these different
keywords or organizations have
interacted in the development of this
I'll see you over I'll have the fight or
two project that's Web oven
plus the C tap to spec which as I
mentioned is the piece that describes
the hardware to browser communication
these actually overlap a lot they really
work together but they're kind of a
collection there that was developed by
both the phyto Alliance and w3c these
came out of some earlier Fido specs that
you may have heard of you to f you AF
the hardware parts of those which is now
called C tap one so you can see you know
web Wathan evolved out of basically you
to F anyway F and C tap 2 is the newer
counterpart to see tap 1 where this gets
a little trickier is that you can
actually mix and match these so you can
have the browser API you know you're
calling the web offline browser api's
but the browser is actually talking over
c tap 1 maybe to an old legacy you to F
based Authenticator so there was kind of
a lot of carrot and actually to how
these could all be somewhat compatible
as much as possible what you miss out in
that case is some new features of web by
then only work if you have a seat app to
Authenticator so hopefully that helps if
you see you know someone marketing oh
this is a fight or two or a web app an
Authenticator it's a hardware device
that means it speaks C tap 2 if you see
a website saying hey we now support web
on 10 that means they've moved from the
you to F it browse your api's to the web
on 10 browser api's so for this yeah
sorry let's that's better had not as
loud but yes sorry about that
Thanks yeah great so we kept of this
section before we move on you know if
you were feeling a bit sleepy cat and
hopefully you get a wait cat for the
next section here but in any case that
would connect essentials or just web
authenticate you with some sort of
Authenticator device Authenticator
devices could really be anything that
talks to the browser over this protocol
and can store credentials and the
browser an Authenticator are what's
working together to make sure
sigh it never gets real sight
credentials and I want to talk about
where job box comes in so if you look at
you know 2014 2015 Dropbox had second
factor authentication TOTP SMS and you
know for all the reasons mentioned you
know wants to do better we've seen even
still recently that kind of pitfalls of
like SMS second factor the reverse
resent you know breach credit announced
saying hey you know we had SMS to FA but
attackers were still able to bypass that
wasn't as secure as we thought that's
you know as you know developer at a
cloud company like Dropbox you would say
oh this you to everything seems quite
promising fundamentally u2f is what
actually introduced a lot of the ideas
that I've been talking about so far so
if you've been thinking like what's the
difference we'll get to that but they're
pretty similar in the fundamentals
especially for second factor
authentication so Dropbox went ahead and
implemented that you know announced we
have security key support quite exciting
and what happened well some users did
adopt it they improve their security
this is good definitely encourage all of
you to turn on security keys for
whatever sites do support it
whether it's u2f or both in but there
was limited adoption overall for our
user base it's only supported in Chrome
and later Firefox 58 plus but still
behind a flag not on by default and
generally another key point was that
there weren't that many hardware devices
that users just already had that they
could use for security keys for you to
eff you had to purchase you know go out
and independently purchase something
like a Yubikey or you know any of these
other hardware Authenticator devices and
so this is a big barrier for getting
kind of mass adoption and what's really
hopeful about web offending this initial
effort of u2f and getting the whole
ecosystem one board saying we're gonna
have more and more devices users already
have like their phones like their
laptops have web authentication we're
going to support this protocol in all
the major browsers not just Chrome so
that's really the biggest reason to go
from you know if you have u2f support
and you're thinking about going to
webblock then like that's the biggest
reason is it's the future and that's
where this strong authentication is
going
and you know this might seem at first
like is this just marketing is there
like you know anything of substance to
this like there also is as well but it's
not to be unlike discounted this kind of
ecosystem adoption because that's really
going to be the thing that actually
makes it feasible for users to use this
on a broad scale and actually be like
the commonplace way of authenticating to
sites on the web
it's what's basically connecting
websites to hardware devices in a
scalable kind of mass adoption way of
course we're not quite there but that's
the hope of the future and then there
are also some differences in the
protocol there's some additions and new
features so kind of the two main ones
are that you have more options over a
credential creation than web often so
you have a little more control over what
kinds of devices or credentials users
might use and you can also have
authentication that works without
usernames it works without needing to
say hey these are the devices you
registered before which do you want to
use to authenticate you can just send a
request to the browser saying please
authenticate a user and it will come
back with some sort of cryptographic
proof of some user device that they
previously registered with you including
their user ID so with that in mind you
know you don't have you to F a site
doesn't have you to F it's really time
to just skip to I bought then there's
already more browser and device support
and it avoids some complications we'll
get into when you support both at the
same time so I have a quick video here
just to kind of demonstrate that there
are already starting to be new devices
there which this specifically is going
to talk about is showing like touch ID
second factor on a MacBook Pro so the
new touch ID bar today if you get Chrome
can bethe Chrome and turn on a flag you
can actually register touch ID as your
second factor and so eventually you can
imagine using web offender login as well
or second factor on other sites so this
is a kind of screencast of what that
looks like on the actual touch ID bar as
well as the prompt that came up
that's a pretty exciting thing webathon
unlocks for you you know already coming
up in the next couple months and just
see how to get there and how you know we
had a solid u2f implementation what
really changed gonna go into a little
bit just like what is actually new a
little bit more detailed level so even
if you're not you know planning to
directly do this hopefully it still can
kind of illuminate what really changed
here and what web authenticate level so
in u2f you had some identifiers for your
website app ID you had you know I want a
challenge you know register request so
it has a challenge to make sure that
request is fresh and you had some
registered keys because you didn't want
to duplicate people you know registering
the same device multiple times and in
web Botham you know it's lined up color
coded to be what kind of corresponds
there so you have you know relying party
has an ID that replaces the app ID you
have a challenge you have some
credentials and then you have a lot of
new options that's the part in purple so
we'll talk about some of those a little
later well signing also pretty
comparable now one new option at the
bottom there's user verification this is
a nice addition where you can actually
request that an Authenticator has done
some sort of check that the user who's
using it is the one it expects so if you
imagine like a Yubikey or hardware token
if anyone steals that they can still
just use it and press the button the
button doesn't check that it's actually
you know you pressing it whereas you
just saw touch ID that'll actually look
at your fingerprint so there was some
verification by the Authenticator there
that you are who you say you are if
someone steals my laptop they can't just
use my touch ID Authenticator because
they won't have the same fingerprint so
that's the new option in web life and to
request the other thing to look at is
that you might see the app ID and the
relying party ID are different formats
and this is actually causes some
backwards and compatibility because from
the device perspective since those are
different formats it looks like a
completely different website and since
the protocol is pretty
privacy-preserving across origins and
also to prevent phishing it'll treat
those as totally isolated sites and
won't let you use credentials from one
with the other
so to get around that so people don't
have to all we educate our old devices
there's actually an extension in
webathon called the app ID extension so
you can specify a legacy app ID to use
so users can still keep using those
previously registered devices but that
extension doesn't exist for registration
so if you have a device registered with
Web authen it's not going to be useful
in older browsers with u2f but if you
have already u2f registered devices
those are going to be usable in both
with this app ID extension this does
have a few confusing edge cases the main
one here whereas like let's say you have
a user they had a fight our u2f key
registered and they lost it so they got
a new key makes sense they go in they
register their new key now it's on a new
browser we've switched a web authentic
and you know in this case we'll say they
forgot to delete their old key now a
little bit later say they're at a
library they're at a friend's computer
they need to log in and get some file or
get something out of their account they
log in on an older browser that only
supports u2f so you know if we're using
Dropbox in this example we'll see this
and we'll say hey they have a u2f
registered key so let's go ahead and
prompt them to use that they don't have
any u2f registered keys could send a
separate error message and say hey sorry
your key doesn't work in this browser
but in this case they do have one
that'll work so let's prompt for that
but now the user sees this they think
well I my security key I'll tap on my
new about then registered security key
and okay so what happens now it comes
back and it looks like a completely
different site to that web authentic
cuz the app ID is so is a different
format so it'll say hey there's not
actually a credential registered that
like wasn't found it's not registered
and so if you just present that same era
to the user now it's kind of confusing
they're like I just registered this key
what do you mean it's not found so in
this case you can actually detect this
might be happening you can't know for
sure it's possible they just actually
did you know try to use a key that's not
registered at all but if you think it
might be happening you can go ahead and
give some other error message explaining
this case yes that was something that
Dropbox did for that
as well the other thing to think about
when you're switching from you to f2 FN
is looking at something called
attestation so this is cryptographically
verified information about the device
and u2f it's provided by default if you
have a UTF implementation you've been
receiving this attestation and it can be
useful to see like device capabilities
like will this device be useful in
mobile or also if let's say you have an
enterprise deployment and you've given
all your employees you know a particular
model of Authenticator that you trust
and you only want them to use that one
on your internal site you can actually
use attestation to require that so there
are some uses there and but in on you
know kept broad public-facing sites
there's less need to have it be like
cryptographically verified or to enforce
things like that so it's actually not
provided by default if you're you know
if you look at what Dropbox actually
does here it does request this
information you'll see you like do you
want to provide your make and model of
your key but it doesn't enforce that
it's provided or cryptographically
verify it because there's not a need to
actually you know she wished tricked the
devices users are using it's more to
guide the you know product user
experience around you know warning them
if their device won't work on other you
know a mobile device or something like
that or just providing better UI to show
what devices are being used the nice
thing about Web Wathan you know if
you're even thinking okay this is great
I'm gonna have more authenticators touch
ID you Ricki things like that and you
know do I have to do a lot of work to
actually support these new devices and
the answer is no that's it's really nice
the browser actually does almost all of
the work especially if you don't care as
much about at a station because that is
one area that can differ between device
types the only other real thing you
might have to do is just add support for
a new you know public key private key
signing algorithm so usually that's just
a few lines to like translate the web
and of it to your favorite cryptography
libraries version of it so one example
is pretty recently Microsoft released
you know Microsoft edge in a preview
Edition that integrates Windows hello
face sign-in pen sign in with webblock
then and so this
to make this work on Dropbox was just a
few lines of code to add a new signature
algorithm and then it was ready to go so
if you have a you know preview build of
Windows you can also try this out for
second factor so now that you know we
have this implementation you know new
wrapper libraries that choose u2f and
webathon be stunned by your support
you know tweaked the format's a bit for
each case did all the processing time to
roll out so went ahead rolled out second
factor on both Firefox and Chrome and
you generally want to do second factor
off first
not the registration part of it because
if you already have u2f especially you
can always turn off web often and go
back to u2f but if you have people
registering new web often keys you won't
be able to use those with u2f
authentication or signing so it's not
compatible that way so typically you'll
roll out your authentication piece first
test it with you know some internal
registrations things like that and then
when you're feeling solid go ahead and
roll that out in this case Dropbox
rolled out to Firefox and later chrome
when web authentic real most recently as
I mentioned Microsoft edge preview
Edition is ready to go so you might be
looking at this fancy new web often
experience and see you know some link at
the bottom that says hey like can't use
your device want to get a TR TP or sms
instead and your anything will like okay
that seems like an issue like couldn't
someone just tell me to fall back to
those and I'd still be tricked so the
answer is not ideal I agree
but unfortunately web often isn't
actually everywhere yet so hopefully in
the future you know it'll be able to be
web authentic still pretty difficult to
get it web off and working but that'll
be coming soon you know that'll be
coming Dropbox has a desktop apps that's
its own kind of separate piece of work
to actually integrate web authentic re
still doesn't have support for web both
in as well so you know this is something
that hoping to be coming soon but still
you know there has to be a balance
between this increased security and just
locking people out of their accounts
they need to have access but if you are
determined you know you only need to
know you know use web authentic
you could you know sign up for TOTP and
then just like throw away your tea or TP
seed but this of course is pretty risky
in terms of you would want to really
understand where am I able to use web
offended Isis and where aren't I so stay
tuned here for for updates but that's
the current state no so just to recap
what Dropbox has done so far and then
what we'll talk about for the last part
of the presentation here rolled out web
authentic and factor you know you can -
it's pretty well understood based on
people's experiences with u2f kind of
how this this flow these slurs should
work so generally pretty good there
there's a few tricky parts if you
already have a few to eff with this
backwards compatibility stuff if not
just skip to web off then that's what
Dropbox has done so far and then now I
want to you know kind of okay that's
where Dropbox is now more of my own
opinions of speculating unlike okay what
comes next how do you get from the
second factor authentication to an
actual primary login experience how do
you go password list potentially what's
the future of passwords there as first
just to look at it at a technical level
you know why first you know web
authentic is actually pretty useful for
validating that you want to do web
offense einen because at a technical
level they're almost the same the
specification doesn't actually make like
a hard distinction in its basic
operations of registering and signing
between the cases it's really about
using the options that it provides you
differently in some cases so one example
of this is like in authentication or
signing and the second factor case you
would generally always provide this
allow credentials field because a lot of
older devices to save space would
offload storage of their private keys to
the servers they would you know first
encrypt them with the private with a
symmetric key and that was the only
thing the device had to remember it
encrypted the new private key it
generated and then passed that off
encrypted to the server where it could
store it then the server had passed that
back in the allow credential
field and the device would then on the
device decrypt it and recover the
private key and actually use that the
sign so this was kind of a nice hack to
save onboard storage on these little
Authenticator devices this of course
doesn't work if you don't even know who
the user is yet you can't pass in these
allow credentials but web authentic seat
app to specify something new called I
want a client resident key so this means
that private key is generated you know
on the device and never you know it's
actually stored on the device it doesn't
need to be offloaded in this way to a
server and then if you do that you can
actually receive like a user ID back in
their response that lets you see okay
which user actually tried to sign in
here of course you can still also do
sign in without passwords but with
usernames so ask for username first then
look up the keys and you know if you're
just looking at like taking your second
factor code and like turning it into
login code one thing you might forget is
that in the second factor case you've
already authenticated the user with the
password so it might be okay to like
include something about their account to
like have better UI it might make a
reasonable trade-off and you might want
to like make sure you reassess that
trade-off if you're returning it just
after a username because there's really
been no authentication done that zone at
that point but the spec itself shouldn't
pose a problem here it's just something
to be aware of if you're kind of porting
that 2fa case directly to login yeah but
in general you know these basically the
same registration signing operations the
harder part is what policies does that
that's where it gets more interesting
because you want to balance users choice
and like how they sign into their
accounts what devices they want to use
with their accounts security and also
risk of them locking themselves out of
their account so one example of this is
maybe you've gone to a web often you
know signup flow where you want to say
hey the user doesn't even have to you
know make a password for my site anymore
I'm just gonna use web off then and so
your user goes register as a device with
you registers an account and maybe they
registered you know the touch ID bar on
their laptop well now they're never
going to be able to sign in to your site
unless they have the same laptop so if
they ever go to a different site you
know they won't have the same
you know this is like a platformer
authenticators what it's called they
won't have the same platform to use so
they won't be able to chill a thin 2k so
in this case there's clearly a high risk
of kind of lockout if they lose that
device or they're just somewhere else so
you might want to then say hey you need
to register like a roaming Authenticator
is what it's called and actually you
know force them to register some sort of
like hardware token that can be removed
and moved and moved around between
devices or maybe eventually like a phone
would serve this purpose although right
now most of the phone operating systems
aren't quite there yet so that's one
example there the other is that if you
have a you baqi that's just you know
test of user presence is what it's
called it's you like you press the
button but it doesn't actually verify
the user is who they say you would want
to be hesitant before letting users have
that as their only like authentication
factor because it's really easy for that
to be lost or stolen and in the case
where it's a second factor that's that's
not too bad because they also have to
know the password but here like if
someone you know if you have login
through just plugging in a ub key and
pressing a button someone could go ahead
and like try that on all of the major
sites for like you know common accounts
and just like see what they find and so
it's a bit riskier to have like no form
of user verification at all so that's
those are some examples of policies the
other one I mentioned was like in an
enterprise deployment you might want
more control over say you know if you're
using biometrics maybe you don't trust
biometrics and you want to say okay
actually don't use that or maybe you
only trust you know certain devices that
you've already handed out how their
biometrics work so you can go ahead and
use some of the other options in weboth
in like attestation or some of the
there's a few other registration options
to select different types of
authenticators to enforce some of those
policies so kind of just to summarize -
they're really the two main questions or
do you require user verification I would
tend to say this is you should otherwise
it's pretty risky but you know it's
still something you could think about
and also what sort of restrictions on
device type whether it's platform or
roaming whether it's a specific model or
brand in general for like a large public
deployment
you probably don't want to get to in the
weeds with having to keep up with all
the different devices but you know
they're hard cases where you know
certain categories of devices and
distinctions based on them would make
sense
another example is like on iOS
authenticators like hardware keys you're
only going to work if they're Bluetooth
enabled because right now there's no NFC
support so that's you know so you might
want to make sure someone registers a
device that's usable in iOS but that's
some questions that would be up to
whoever implements it so we have some
you know ideas you got to set some
policies but it's pretty you know it's
understood we're working out what the
best policies are we could get to a
world where there's definitely you know
it'll be possible to sign into a lot of
websites using web off end without a
password so what happens to the password
what are kind of the use cases that are
still hard to like know the answer to
right now or directly get rid of so one
is recoverability what happens if you
lose access to all your devices like
something catastrophic happens there's a
fire or you were carrying everything
that authenticated you to a site and a
backpack that got stolen
who knows you lost access to everything
and how do you get back into your an
account so though thanks thing about a
password is that it's in your head if
you have managed to remember it and you
know it's possible to remember a few
strong passwords even if it's hard to
remember one for every site you know you
it's still in your head you can use that
to log in from anywhere so if you're
without any of your devices you can fall
back to that more easily than you know
what do you do in the web authenticate
around the cyant you know password list
case so there are you know some
solutions for for certain cases here
like you can fall back to your email if
you're not an email provider of course
there's another new specification that's
pretty cool that's being developed
that's called delegated account recovery
so this is something right now that like
Facebook and github support where you
can recover your github account through
your Facebook account and it's actually
also like privacy preserving so the only
thing the two providers know about each
other is that you have an account on the
other provider but they don't actually
know like what the username is or what
account it is
so it's nice privacy-preserving way to
link accounts for the purpose of
recoverability so you could imagine the
future this you know is more widespread
and you're able to kind of have you know
one you know trust account maybe it even
has your real physical world identity
attached to it and you can use that one
to recover all of your other accounts
maybe through actually like showing up
in person you know if it was like a bank
you could show up in person with some
other form of identification or police
report or etc you could use the physical
worlds responses to these kind of
catastrophic circumstances to bootstrap
your online identity as well so that's
kind of one like future looking thing
you could think about it but in general
it's you know well we'll have to see
kind of how this ecosystems evolves but
at first it will at least reduce the
frequency and number of passwords that
are needed because then a minimum a lot
of sites you know you're probably fine
recovering through an email account or
something like that so you could just
have them as webathon only and if you
lose a device maybe you recover it do
something else the other kind of thing
people are exploring in the wealth and
ecosystem is having better ways to
handle like registering say a backup
device that you could keep somewhere
safe and then if you lose the primary
device kind of automatically
transferring all the credentials from
the primary one to the backup one in a
less painful way than having the user
like you go to every single site and do
it manually because that's obviously
going to be quite painful if you're
actually using these for a lot of places
that's another kind of promising thing
that people are looking into but I think
recoverability is one of the biggest
reasons that passwords might stick
around for a while just to have this
ability to bootstrap from losing all
your devices the other area just to
think about is that now that we have
something like web authentication it's a
weak password or something like that
it's not providing much but it's still
it's some additional factor like do you
still need it
is there still a benefit there worth the
usability cost a lot of people it seems
like we're trending towards a no answer
here but I could imagine maybe for a few
like sites you're particularly concerned
about
you know you might make the effort to
invest in remembering a strong
passphrase in addition to your device
or the other way this could go is that
maybe you know instead of using the
password directly on the website you use
the password on your device to unlock it
so you have a very strong password for
your device so that's probably better
long term because then that password
doesn't need to go over the network but
it's still something to think about and
the implications it has is like how do
we encourage users to like adopt weboth
in you know first should they adopt this
second factor authentication or should
we just directly say hey you know use
this to sign in does that answer change
if they already have to FA enabled if a
user already has a totp code and they
turn on web authenticate rid of their
totp do you leave it there do you get
rid of it for them if you just want to
think through and I don't necessarily
have the answers here exactly like how
much security any of these factors
provide when multiple ones are being
used because obviously sometimes it
could be totally redundant and you don't
need both but there may be cases where
you actually want these second factors
us even in the web often world yeah so
now kind of just want to bring it back
to all of you and say you know webathon
has kind of ecosystem support to bring
you know the strong authentication to
the masses like browsers are onboard
harder vendors are getting there but we
still need more just websites adopting
it users turning it on showing that you
know people actually value it so it's
all now on to all of us to kind of push
this forward and push web authentic it's
relatively like easy and well understood
for implementing for 2fa so go ahead and
do it the log in with device you know
password list flows also you know seem
to be getting closer to at least being
tried out places but the best practices
around like usability and policies we're
still figuring that out so you know help
figure those out as well and just
generally we can all look forward to
fewer passwords less fishing and more
account security so all in there if
anyone has questions Thanks
[Applause]
yes thanks I'm curious if you see the
need to either keep track of white lists
or black lists of devices in this case
just given that the devices are so new
if you find a vulnerability in one what
are you guys done about that kind of
thing yeah so so far we we haven't seen
the need for that there haven't you know
necessarily been you know widespread
vulnerabilities that have been
publicized for a lot of these it is a
good question and kind of an example of
why some of that attestation information
is useful sometimes to potentially be
able to do that but it's definitely a
big cost that in general you don't want
to undertake unless you feel like you
have to so so far it hasn't been
something that we've or that you know I
would think is really necessary at the
moment
thank you for the great presentation the
problem spaces that you identified here
are problem spaces that I've
traditionally seen addressed with
password managers right phishing yeah
and you know passwords being shitty what
is the you know how do you see those two
how do you see this working with
password managers like what is the
strategic relationship you envision with
this product yeah that's a great
question because there they do solve
some similar problems often especially
if you look at like autofill and relying
on your password manager to make sure
it's only Auto filling on the right
domain so it's certainly possible to
imagine one incident some people have
talked about this actually is it's not
like necessarily my idea is to have sort
of a password manager but instead of
storing passwords it stores your private
keys for a web and then communicates
over well often and the advantage there
is then you still don't have to have
this symmetric authentication with
passwords you can actually have like
more usable public key authentication so
servers there's less risk of a breach of
a server because now the only thing
there is the public keys so that's
certainly one path that could take to
have more adoption in general and maybe
be easier to use I'm not you know sure
you know how much that'll take off
versus just signing in with devices like
your phone that you already have I think
they'll probably be a mix of both like
I'm sure someone will create something
like you described and it'll also be up
to websites to decide do we really care
if users are storing keys and hardware
versus software and for many websites
the answer is probably no actually like
we're just happy that users are storing
secure things somewhere instead of not
having secure passwords but there there
could be some cases where you do want to
actually still enforce some sort of
hardware security as well
I have a very similar question to that
is you were my business is very
interested in in web auth but our
challenge is the portability of the keys
between devices because you know we have
entire helpdesk dedicated just swapping
out replacement laptops I know this is
more of a higher-level thing but what is
your personal opinion of of how that
portability of these keys should be
approached because I've seen in the past
people have said oh you know we'll just
we'll store it on the device it'll be
hard lock into a TPM or something
and and you'll have to re re register
but you know we have employees that are
probably on you know 30 different sites
and we can't we can't have them locked
to a device like that so I was just
wondering if you could go even further
into into your thoughts on that kind of
problem yeah definitely a difficult
problem there are people doing work on
it now I was reading like a cool paper
someone proposed a scheme to help with
this problem essentially like you said
where basically you could imagine
starting to like sign chains of like you
have the old device you know be able to
sign for the new device and maybe like
have that pre registered or some scheme
like that so the keys can still stay on
each device but you could get some sort
of chain of trust I'm not like
describing this in like great detail
obviously or exactly how it would work
but people are thinking about things
like that to help with it
personally I guess I don't have a strong
opinion on like keys have to be you know
in hardware to have like improvements
over traditional password security but
at the same time I do like when keys are
stored in Hardware because then they're
less vulnerable to things like malware
which is a bit outside the you know main
threat model I've been talking about but
it is still something that's quite nice
to protect your credentials as much as
you can so personally I'm definitely
willing to have a bit of usability cost
to have my keys on like something like a
Yubikey where they're hard to extract
but at an ecosystem level then I would
hope we would be able to develop some
sort of solutions like where maybe you
can chain these devices together somehow
or have it be
bit easier to automatically register a
new device using an old device now you
know I've seen so many times in it you
know the first iteration of 2fa is often
the SMS and I also often see the
websites fallback say oh you don't have
your key you don't have this other fancy
thing I will just have SMS does I know
this it's out of scope but what is what
is the response to to how calm and just
fallback to SMS is when it comes to web
off then yeah I think it's really the
fact that it's it's still new enough
that SMS just has a broader usability
kind of support out there like we have a
phone the cell you know network will get
a text to the user and that's going to
work whereas maybe their phone just has
no way to talk to a web Authenticator
that they have so it's a big challenge
right now to kind of develop things that
are both you know usable in all of these
cases and secure so my ideal would
certainly be that you can enforce you
know web often only you to have only and
it just takes more work to get there to
make sure any users who say opt-in to
that are aware of like what it means for
what devices they can log in on and also
hopefully pushing all of the hardware
vendors or browsers that don't yet
support it to support it so it's not a
problem so webathon will be fairly
ubiquitous and you won't need to have
some sort of fallback like that
it's a quick question really is it
possible to identify if the website is
using you to F or whereabout and because
probably hardware tokens are now you
know available for Volga yes so it's
possible just by looking at basically a
JavaScript API is there using now in
practice you know given how JavaScript
code is minified etc I'm I'm trying to
think there's like a really quick way
you could like immediately see it but
it's definitely it's definitely like
visible to the user because it's code
running on their browser and oftentimes
you can like look in the network
responses and see what you know the
challenge format looks like or something
like that or just search for you know
they're using you to F or navigate or
dock credentials get the other way to
test it is just and actually the easier
way I guess is in Firefox you can toggle
you to F on web authentication you know
spoofing to depending on the site yeah I
don't know if that means I should stop
no that actually means I have a question
Oh excellent yeah you by the same token
you've got about five minutes so is
there a way to like for example and I'm
new on this would it be a good thing if
you could have your hardware token but
also have a way to back up so if your
hardware token gets destroyed you can go
to your vault and rewrite a new hardware
token with the correct data yeah that's
I think that's definitely one reasonable
solution to the problem with the the
caveat that like now there's a new area
to attack on that hardware device right
if if someone if there's some way to
backup the keys malware maybe you can
also do that you know so how do you
prevent that you know maybe there's
solutions here of like putting the
device in a certain sort of like mode
that like unlocks this functionality and
then or like you know pairing them
device to device you know a device could
support that we're like you buy to it
automatically you know pairs itself in
some way and then like after that you
can't pair it again or
like that so I think there are ways to
work around some of the security
implications but in general that's it's
definitely one possibility I recently
read a write-up of Google's advanced
protection and then they have like a
titanium version of that or something
and I think the advanced one requires
that you have two tokens and now that I
know the difference between web
authentic done they're actually
supporting UTF the the original Fido
spec but with Bluetooth so that it
doesn't do the UE key NFC any I guess
the sort of generic question do you have
thoughts on Google's approach to that
and that they're not supporting weboth
and it looks like for that higher levels
account security and yeah just yeah no I
think I think it's great Google advanced
account protection like that is kind of
a u2f only mode I think did kind of make
some good trade-offs around the
usability issues like forcing users to
register a key that is on you know is he
going to be usable by their iOS device
because it supports bluetooth and Google
you know doing the work to add that
support into their apps on the mobile
phones too you know undertake the u2f
protocol from a mobile device so overall
I think it's a pretty good approach
clearly I would like to see it move to
web authenticate more browsers support
on desktop you know just generally for
all the reasons I mentioned I think you
know one of which released web often
wasn't ready to to be used for this sort
of thing u2f was still really the the
only thing to use for that sort of thing
so that is why it started there I think
also if you look on like web offenses
you to have support on mobile there
there are more existing like mobile code
libraries support right now for you to F
it's a little easier to do you to f1
mobile then web authentic that'll change
pretty soon I'm sorry would hope they
were moving towards that
yeah well awesome yeah cool I think
we're out of time for questions so
thanks so much I'll I'll be around as
well if you have more
Thanks
[Applause]