so hello everybody thanks for coming to
hang out my name is Steve Reagan senior
staff writer at CSO online that I'm
getting too close to that speaker so I'm
gonna stand over here we are going to
somewhat use the slides we had in
Washington DC earlier this year but
we're going to talk more about not just
basic media training we're going to walk
you through pitching and getting your
story out and developing a story that
works not just for you but also for the
journalists some of the slides we have
are extremely relevant to that some of
them are not so what's gonna happen is
this we work through this we're just
gonna skip the irrelevant slides yeah
we'll go all the way towards the end
mostly and we're gonna workshop this so
that what that means is if you have
questions where I we're talking raise
your hands so we can get to you right
away and occasionally when we need to
make an example or to do an example
we're actually just going to pick one of
you and we're going to kind of run
through it like a little bit of a role
play the goal is to share information so
to make sure that you get the most out
of this session I encourage you to ask
plenty of questions we're not afraid of
them and ask hard questions we like
those and we'll be brutally honest yes
we will be horribly on it so if you give
us a pitch and we don't like it at least
you're going to understand why oh come
on what break the habit of a lifetime
man what xpk all right so the first
thing you need to have a consciousness
of is that we have goals you have goals
there may be some matching up between
them maybe not you want to understand
what you are trying to get across with
your message and then figure out how to
angle it into what the journalist needs
are for the story so before you approach
someone in journalism you want to
understand why you're talking to him in
the first place and have that in mind
so are you doing it to raise your
profile you need to raise your company's
profile is this a business development
thing you're doing or is there
specifically something that you want to
get awareness out about that relates to
the general community and that may have
person that may have selfish motivation
in addition to your your civic
mindedness but you know that's that's a
good motivation and then you have to
understand that reporters are going to
assume things about you when you come in
to talk to that when you approach them
to talk to them they're gonna try to
figure out what your motivations are
because they're going to either assume
we've got something to sell or you're
trying to do something along the lines
that boost your business or they may
have misconceptions about the and
depending upon who you talk to if you're
talking to something information
security journalism they may have fewer
misconceptions about what goes on in
your profession but people in general
media you're gonna have a varying level
of knowledge about how IT works and how
information security works and if you're
coming into them as an anonymous source
or if you're just coming to them cold
calling them and you're not representing
a company necessarily or even if you are
representing company they may have
questioned whether you are a legitimate
source of information about this Oh real
quick show of hands could you hear me
I'm clear to you all right great I could
put that down how many of you familiar
with the term cold call this is really
important to pitch it all right so nine
times out of 10 the pitch that a
journalist gets is a cold call that
means I don't know you and you don't
know me but man you've got a hot story
you want me to report on it I will
ignore that nine times that attended so
will there because it's usually never
relevant to what I cover it's never
relevant to a topic that I'm interested
in and it's never relevant to something
my publication worries about Co so it's
a security publication so if you're
writing to me about blockchain and why
your new ICL starts I would set your
email on fire if that was possible
fortunately I can't so I will just
delete it but these are the types of
things we have to roll out with so when
he talks about that we'll make
assumptions about you if you pitch me
something completely unrelated the first
assumption I'm gonna make
is you're probably never somebody I've
ever going to want to speak to ever okay
and it's not your fault because you've
gotten advice from a PR firm or a PR
person that says here's how you craft
your pitch here's a media list of a
thousand reporters you just hit
everybody they never taught you actually
how to build a relationship or crap that
email or tailor the template which is
why sometimes just before our essay I
get emails it's a dear first name I
welcome you to conference it's just this
horrible form email that you paid
thousands of dollars for from a media
company and wasted all that money
because that's a pitch that just got
ignored by a journalist another thing
that will be sure to make sure your
pitches is ignored is if it comes from a
mailing list oh yeah and that's a common
tactic a lot of PR firms now do is they
send you ball they send out in a ball to
a list and at the bottom it says
unsubscribe and of course I click yes
he's been asked for his email in the
first place and why are you sending us
an email is not tailored to us and it's
on a mailing list or even worse every
every single person in the world is in
the CC a man called the 300 and the 300
is a group of 300 journalists who all
got the same email from CBS now again
what kind of publication do I work with
straight security why would I need
anything from CES I would that's great
fun I was on a list with 300 other
journalists and we were all in the CC
field and of course the most awesome
thing happened and most of you are used
to this somebody had reply all and said
this is not relevant and it's what's the
difference and don't hit reply all and
this chain kept going for weeks to the
point that we actually created a
Facebook group and we all regularly
communicate more notice than 300 and
it's the funniest stamp thing I can't
even explain it how powerful it was but
this is bad PR
okay now get the company and the company
from the the CES finish in the PR
that said that out yeah that's 300
reporters that will never work with the
video matter who their clients are and
that's a problem for them and if you're
we could be Earthcare client that's a
problem for you which is even worse
so the unsubscribe link you'll see that
for me I have filters based on HTML I've
read all my emails and text so if you
send me an HTML email just ignore it
goes right to a folder and I might read
the emails in that folder once a lot and
you just generally assume it if
something comes in an e in HTML it's a
phishing email mmm well I mean also I
mean I got I did some start analysis for
this talk and I got 218 emails about
black cap and two of those included a
PDF that I was supposed to open with
absolutely no security at all and the
other one was a Dropbox thing yeah you
can download a download a press release
from there
fuck that for gay myself right on that
yeah you know that's that's great I'll
go to I'll use do it via tour from my
burner computer but yeah I don't think
that's gonna happen
but that type of email I will get seven
times a day leading up to a conference
because it's cheap its quick and it's
fast and the PR teams know that you're
paying not just for access to their
media list you're paying for volume so
if they tell you we pitched a thousand
journalists five times about your
product this week pay us what are you
gonna think that's a good thing but what
they didn't tell you was we pitched
eight thousand journalists the email
bounced 800 times 200 journalists got
that email but only one of them actually
ready and nobody's responded to it we
did that five times so we all hate it
but yeah and the thing is like there are
so many different tracking things that
go into these emails that allow them to
know when we've read it that I literally
have a filter now that honestly just
tells you that I read it even though
I've never seen that
it just pains it so before you approach
a reporter do some research about them
understand what types of stories they
write yeah a good feel for whether
they're the right person for you to
approach for the story or not and that's
about 50% of the battle right there if
you have a good understanding of what it
is they cover who their audience is and
what they're most likely to write
stories about then you will have a good
feel for whether they're the right
person to talk to and if they don't seem
like they cover what you want to talk
about then don't contact them it's just
that simple
so how do you know who it is do you want
to talk to how do you know that they're
the right reporter well the first thing
you got to think of is what is it you
want to talk about how many of you have
a product an actual product you would
love to talk to the media is there
anybody entering with an actual product
Wow tell me okay
so think about your products and what
you do at force point okay which one of
us is likely the reporter you would want
to reach out to first so you have Ars
Technica the register
CSO and cio and then Thomas TomSka I
know but everybody else doesn't know
that so okay so I'm number one because
I'm security focused and that's exactly
what they do
Ars Technica and the register because
they have reached right and then you
have the actual technical skills so when
they want to reach a technical audience
they're going to go to Thomas this is a
very common thought habit but the
question is is how do you get the
message across because technically it's
not one pitch for all of us it's a
different tailored pitch for everybody
she gets it and she's done that before
I've got it tailored pitches for CSO and
CIO even though I actually read them
both I don't tell anybody
some of you tailor them to the pub I
love that and it shows but not everybody
knows I see the emails for both sides
there's a reason for that it's because
we actually keep the same bottle account
because it's easier through this way but
you would tailor the pigeons to each one
of us individually because that's the
smart thing to do we can tell when it's
a blast and we ignore those so think
about your product or the message you
want to get out and which one of us you
want to reach in half so what kind of
pitch works good for you um since we
pretty much focus on the consumer end of
things this is for Tom's guide not Tom's
Hardware oh sorry yeah not that that's a
very very common thing I actually don't
record times hardware my friends do they
sell right across the aisle for me I'll
afford them something if it seems to be
in their interest but what Tom's guide
does is just sure ask computer secure I
mean consumer security doesn't get into
the enterprise stuff doesn't get into
the big hardware it doesn't get into the
cloud that much unless it's something
that I think consumer law a person
sitting at home would use so for me if
it impacts that person directly then I'm
interested otherwise I will politely say
I'm sorry we just don't kind of cover
enterprise security I'm gonna say I mean
as a JIT so back in two SEC's
but this stuff American PRS really need
to work on this ship because when a
story breaks and they set high we have
comment from so-and-so on this story it
comes in a day late know what yeah weigh
it or it's basically X what would be a
problem but an TX manufacturer here has
a comment to say about it this is
bollocks we can't use this yeah I can't
count how many times I've got an email
the day after Everton story yeah
somebody's saying we have an executive
you'd like to comment on this story I
mean the story has been written the
story is gone yeah I think I'm gonna be
updating it especially there's a one-off
sort of thing why would I take a random
executive and take a quote from them and
incorporate it into a new story about
something already covered my favorite
thing is when I get a comment or we have
comment through the story it's a story I
broke so not only did I reported first
it's a story I pretty much worked on for
a long time because what I write I have
to
you're telling me about a story I've
broken you're actually pitching me my
own story in Xena it's a classic example
of a PR firm not paying attention to who
they're pitching or wow it's a fly blast
that goes out but like they were telling
you you get these emails the prime
example is here last week just before
the car ready got popped they announced
that they'd agreed so I wrote the story
about 45 minutes after data ended
without some data breach and for the
next two days I'm getting pictures about
the road of a degree there's nothing
more to act but everybody's gonna
comment they want to sit I get that you
want to put your your person in the
spotlight but it's too late now
there's nothing new to add to that story
which whelming the classic cases want to
cry I mean there was almost a dd8 ddos
attack against journalists just like
yeah we'd like to comment about this
we'll come over this well every one of
the fucking world wants a cone about
this give us something new what a story
breaks we have the option to either not
cover it or chase the story it's think
of it ambulance chaser okay and what
happened to let's say let's say Shawn
breaks the story about X well Ian's
energies are gonna say we need to drive
so now these two duck stories about eggs
now you've got a cover story about ax
cos those two F stories and I have a
choice do I cover this story or do do I
chase them and cover the story because
everybody else is writing about it or do
I just skip it and tired I look for a
third option can I add something
relevant and something new to what
they've talked about can you build on it
yeah yeah right and that's exactly so
Dan Gooden and I both cover security
doors
Dan's the guy who covers our breaches
and good solid solid heat and he writes
our daily news I tend to write features
or I backstop him when things overflow
for him but I'm also he's more breaches
vulnerabilities
sort of what I would classify as the red
and I'm more of Defense so I look for
things that are more about defending
against things
yeah what was of German war about
clarification that it's not about only
between the publication is it says
there's also about between the reporter
right yeah
in your example reporters like myself if
I don't make up more securities oh yeah
breaches vulnerabilities attacks like
them and research papers series one
approached me approached me with some
research or some new attack I'm sorry a
new product is not a news story si oh
we've got a great new product well
whoopee fucking Dubai an advert right
listen
so I attend in Iowa between the two of
us dan I would be the one who would be
more likely to cover a product but I'm
willing to cover the product within the
context of a trend in technology I'll
talk about your product is your products
dealing with a specific phishing type of
attack or a social construct within
security otherwise I'm gonna take your
para product pitch I'll read through it
and learn what I know about your product
because then later when I need something
like that and to this point writing
about tools we're writing about the
person in the trenches the administrator
or the support desk person who's trying
to solve a problem or put out a fire if
that tool would help them through their
job I'm gonna write about and in the
context I'm going to write why that tool
is good for this job and how you can use
it to make your life easier
that's the kind of story you create but
just writing because tool s is cool
that's never gonna happen so up to this
point we've talked about various types
of pitching and everything like that are
there any questions about better we
always say hey you want to go back good
awesome
so tits and tricks when it comes to
pitching some of the stuff we mentioned
in the last session but to go over it
really quickly and when you find
yourself in front of a journalist don't
fit just tell us you know a lot of times
we will avoid meeting with marketing
people or spokespeople because they're
salespeople at heart the same for CEOs
everybody wants to put a CEO in front of
a reporter but the thing is the CEOs
goal is to bring value to the company by
bringing value to the shareholders which
means they're going to solve things
that's not news I'm really glad that
mark Peters heard random bird whatever
the guy at Facebook I'm really glad that
he can do some great thing Frankenberg
but if I want to talk to some a at
Facebook I want to talk to their
security engineers so once you build the
products who when this is this is
absolutely key point if you trying to
give us a quote for a story the chief
marketing officer bugger that for again
my soldiers it's not it's no use the
readers hate it we hate it
give us a technical person give us
somebody who actually knows what they're
talking about if someone's got a CMO in
their job title they shouldn't be
speaking to the press you know it's
simple I know that's part of their job
but you know the part of their job is
saying look I'm in marketing I'll give
you a tech person but if you're a
marketing half fuck off yeah III have to
say that the times when a marketing
officer has spoken to me for a story it
has not gone well for them I speak it
like it is and if I'm writing about a
product specifically about a product
because of the type of coverage I do
it's generally not a good thing because
I tend to do pen testing on products I
tend to do lab testing at products I
tend to do analysis of what's going on
in a space and if a particular product
is getting called out it's usually
because there's something strange going
on there like oh they were using fake
virus samples for their tests or
something no names here
[Laughter]
we all know who they are so what do you
gotta remember we're suspicious and
cynical by nation whore we're not cynics
who just time release were realists you
haven't been proved right yeah yeah well
we're honest you know yeah we're gonna
we're gonna make sure you were being
honest too
so a couple things that Paul said
earlier in the last panel he said you
know if you're when you want to try to
communicate with somebody in the press
best to keep it to email if you can to
start off with and that's so that you
have a written record of your
conversation but but a key point here is
if you've got a PR person at your
organization and you're reaching out to
press and they don't know about it
that's a problem okay I love you that's
a career-ending a bit because you talk
to the press with ibrb yeah and so it's
a it's one thing to bump into a person
at a conference like this and have a
conversation with them I mean I bumped
into a guy on a project I've been
covering for a while and he can't talk
to me because he's not press cleared by
his organization
and I know that so just go say hi okay
but if there are other people who on
that organization I talk to you that's
that's a that's a fair game encounter
but if you're going directly to the
press and talking to the press and not
engaging whoever supposed to be handling
your media your organization that could
be bad for you it could be bad for your
company especially in especially if you
say something this may be not true or
maybe you exaggerate this personal
situation that doesn't have the full
context or something like that it's
always best to have a PR person in the
room to help you say nothing that will
get you fired that's basically the main
reason have a PR person in the room with
you is to make you sure should you say
nothing that will get you fired
like um like human resources and human
resources on that just to manage
personnel let's keep the directors from
getting fired if you do a phone
interview and you've got PR it's good to
have PR on the phone with you because if
the reporter asked the question it's
going to pull you off topic or make you
talk about something you shouldn't the
PR person's role is to interrupt the the
conversation right then in there and to
instantly clarify things now a reporter
it's really frustrating with the PR
person interrupts when they're about to
say something
really
that's going to make a sale but that's
their job too
but if you go solo then you're on your
own
and there's nothing worse being in the
middle of the desert all alone and you
have a pack of wolves around you because
depending on where you are that's
exactly what could happen in the front
yeah just be real about it this is not a
game when you are the focus of a
particular story or company is you're by
yourself
that's why PR is good at home and now
we're not covering whistleblowing in the
situation because whistleblowing is a
totally separate situation definitely
right so so everything I just said if
your whistleblower you're just referring
about it well I would say on a few
whistleblowing you've got to be really
bloody careful about oh yes and this and
that's this is a couple other points say
yeah but yes you really be really
careful about how you do it yeah and I
guess down and know I'm really knowing
the reporter before you do it to when
you'd make a pitch make sure that you've
checked all of your facts first make
sure that you're prepared to back up any
claims with additional material if
you've got anything in particular that
you're trying to present as a situation
you want to make sure that you have
already thought of how this story plays
out of your mind and you've covered all
the bases in terms of what this person
they're going to ask you about what
other things that you might not have
foreseen like for example with the pitch
that you got in about the Microsoft
having three 5% quad adoption and not
thinking about the other 60 they were
offended they was really offended and
they'll decide if that wasn't the angle
we were looking for well fuck you need
to think about these things beforehand
red team your proposal okay
have somebody sit down with you and go
through what could possibly go wrong
with this pitch before you make this
pitch how many of you see a face
reports that have come out in the news
where you see something that says 60% of
all attendees will give or all of C
levels will give their password away for
a candy bar how about my feet god those
those fucking things drunk me no so
what's really what that told me is six
people will give away their password
because when you look at the sample size
for the support it's like maybe you know
10 people that we stopped in the subway
coming out of InfoSec your're well
that's nice of you
we've got a sandwich for lunch and you
stop saying random people if I can do
chocolate bar and I have their password
it's six number like I like story when
you see reports like that I want you all
to remember that those reports are very
very hyper unrealistic I mean to hear I
mean two two key things with with
surveys what was the method what was the
methodology and what was the survey
sample size I'm sorry if you're talking
about us the CSO problem you need at
least 2,000 people to actually get a
reasonable sample size and also you
methodology we asked people on the
internet well great you asked people on
the internet who cares anyone could have
could have done this stuff for a while -
yeah lo and behold these reports focus
on a problem that guess what that vendor
has a solution to it's amazing they see
creating a problem and now suddenly they
have a spirit into this problem exactly
I couldn't write better news let me just
jump right on that except my editors
like what are you doing you just wasted
eight hours of your day you're fired
so these stories don't get any kind of
traction but they are useful you know
why because it tells me at some point
somebody in your organization cared
enough about that particular topic to at
least pretend to research so if I dig
around a little bit maybe I can find a
researcher in your organization it was
actually knowledgeable about this which
means that's somebody I could talk to
sources to be like Pokemon I collect
them all I can never have too many of
them and the more I have within a given
vertical
market better off I am because remember
earlier when I was talking I said I have
to have multiple sources verified before
I can write something well if I've got
six researchers telling me that the Sun
is green and only two of them saying
it's blue I'm probably going to run with
the headline that the Sun is colorful
but the point is is I could show you
multiple people saying various resources
so when it comes to pitching I want you
to think of who the reporter is why you
want to pitch them how you're how you're
going to get your point across and this
is where the game theory comes into this
particular I want you to think on the
spotlight this is gonna be fun this is
the interview have a seat gopher I want
you to pick a reporter and I want you to
think of a product you're gonna pitch it
to us I want you to convince us to write
a story about what you're thinking so
instead we will write articles about
products you may not want to know oh
that's not what helped in testing art
sack consumer stuff consumer stuff and
you have like general security but reach
yeah pretty much come on let's go to
czars damn it to adding that's one
segment of my very large beach sink deep
dive really technical security general
really knowledgeable security wide
audience very technical security
Enterprise focused security straight
across the board from all sea levels
down I have an idea I don't know I can't
think of which one would be the best
place to that's right that's that's
actually a good thing because you need
to tell your pictures to the individual
journalists you need to actually read
their stuff work out what they're
interested in and then pitch it to them
directly rather than just spamming it
out on an email list so in this case
just pick one of us at random and start
your pitch will tell you if we're not
the right one I won him in the mindset
of thinking about what's a pigeon town
okay this is one that was first I'll let
you but how about a cryptocurrency
wallet that really doesn't suck okay so
you said a wallet that really does
accept the currency wallet and foolishly
john mcafee has poisoned it like
currency means it kind of knocked
everyone out order the market wallet
somewhere but so okay so you say it's a
cryptic wallet that really doesn't suck
why does it not suck because it is
actually using it uses open source
reviewed software well it uses open
source software that's been very
technically we're very thoroughly
reviewed by a premier software security
auditing firm it uses it uses hardware
that's known to be very safe it is used
it uses standard modes of encryption and
things like that things that it doesn't
do the things that your typical Bitcoin
wallet developer would do such as using
you know a s with the same key over
every single wallet or a terrible random
number generator or you know things like
that there's some props for immediately
not at least trying to save
military-grade encryption you said it's
a premier auditing firm well what makes
the premier who are they you said that
it comes from there was another phrase
you other through there that was almost
very much open-source software
yeah so you said it's audited audited by
who Alliance and why does open source
software matter for that matter what's
wrong with planetary says that's
how's it say the type of questions are
coming here so your pitch is good okay
it's great for a basement but the
problem is you're dealing with technical
reporters at a very nuanced environment
so security it's a small sliver of a
very technical pie and when it comes to
the people who cover security on a daily
basis they're very focused in particular
rooms okay so when you you bring up
pitches like this it's a good pitch for
a basic technical journalist
but it's a bad pitch for anybody that
comes technical security on a regular
basis because it's too open-ended okay
right it's a great car it has four doors
and four wheels in the engine
state-of-the-art the only thing I
haven't told you is this car won't start
because it doesn't run on any kind of
fuel that we could obtain but look at
these tires these tires are better than
the other guys tires because they've
been peer reviewed by guys who make
tires it's a great car on paper but it's
not really anything what you do it's a
fair point but also I just came up with
the idea for this like right on the spot
I could tell you you say so there's one
thing I want to say is you know the
pitch you're making is a product pitch
that crosses several layers right so
it's a Bitcoin wallet I have a reporter
at ours Tim Lee who covers Bitcoin
pretty heavily right just so happened he
drew the short straw he's our Bitcoin
guy today I passed him he also covers
blockchain in general so I passed him a
story today that I was going to write
because I'd have time about the West
Virginia I like internet voting using
blockchain thing because that was a
story I knew he could write competently
and I wouldn't have to worry too much
about the security pieces of it until
later so that's the security pieces of
it would be interesting to me from the
standpoint I cover open-source quite a
bit and I cover security so I'd be
interested in digging into what is the
open source one of the other application
of it where does his open-source come
from what's the community behind it
who's supporting the code things like
that
my drive down and dive down on that and
then you start talking about trusted
hardware and that gets into space where
I would talk about that Peter bright
might talk about that Peter he's a lot
of hardware for us he would look at okay
what is this is this is this TPM are we
talking about a trusted platform are we
talking about some other sort of
hardware that is going to do encryption
on board it follows a standard as
well-established or just something new
what makes it better things like that so
we would ask questions like that and it
might and we would have an argument who
covers it depending on how good the
pitch was whether it was something was
on my beat or Peters beat or Tim's beat
we'd figure out what gets a story so
bottom line especially since you made it
all up that was fantastic
yeah the other thing is I want you all
to give our guinea pig a round of
applause so here's my question who wants
to try it who wants you to try again
somebody else might be a guinea pig
there was a guy who raised us and back
yeah come on we'll be polite up to a
point does he weigh the same as a duck
oh no but I float like small rocks
no okay very so rocks we are marketing a
service for monitoring patch sources for
compliance with Newark sip requirements
to allow energy companies providers
generators transmission and distribution
to comply with the 35 day window
requiring them to check for patch
availability so you know what's really
funny I think of all the standing up you
have the only reporter in here that's
actually written a nurse's stories
excellent I know every
it's almost like we're talking about
that in this track honestly unless the
Blitz these guys have written some in
the past I didn't know I I have never
eaten about Netta Buell way ahead of me
on this one I'm aware of them yeah but
it's not something that I write about in
a regular basis and we do have an energy
reporter yep and there might be some
crossover there where she calls me is it
what is this stuff and we'll have a
conversation there but generally
speaking yeah I don't I mean I only
write about nuclear power plants when
somebody makes something explode when
they spill Pepsi on the console yeah
yeah it's how many people joke that kind
of pitch I would want to know more so I
would tell you to send me the
information but on its outset it sounds
like a product thing which is not
something I would cover
however like he said they have an energy
reporter which that would be right of
their feet so I could see that you know
that would be something I would probably
pass on right attaining this start with
a product that's fine but you see what
I'm saying that would be a pure product
story so it's something I want to know
about and maybe I could find something
in the product to talk about like Newark
steps very unique to the can I try it a
different way well yeah what I was going
to suggest to you is if you pitched it
from the problem perspective first and
didn't even mention this the product
would say you're working in this area
you get your foot in the door I'm saying
hey we have this area this area of
concern and energy that you need we
needed saying these be done about and
and then you know soft sell the product
fine so more along the lines of after
contact with 10 to 15 major names in the
top 20 which we can't necessarily give
because they are private like you don't
have authorization to give you their
names power you would find them the top
Tony Energy lists we have found that
over 50 percent do not comply with
Newark SIP requirements for checking
patches every 35 days because they find
it very difficult to not only get the
information from the vendors but also
because they can't identify what they
have and when they identify what they
have they can't break it out into
software swimlanes
I'm gonna take your pitch I'm gonna
rewrite it for you because what you have
is a very good very good base but
there's a way to sell it even better
I'll take it and the reason why I say
this is this is a story I write ok are
you aware that 15 of the 20 energy
companies right now can't patch within
say three to six months they have a real
problem with that do you know what kind
of problems a typical power plant
experiences when they're out of date
with patches what kind of attacks they
see on a regular basis a few maybe with
that well here's five of them what kind
of problems will happen if one of these
five attacks hits you could build an
entire narrative off of that and the
whole thing is the entire time we're
talking we're talking about the fact
that your product detected all of this
without mentioning your product once
these are the kind of stories you can
build out so you're right along the line
but the thing is instead of going for
you know eight out of ten or 30% or
things like that literally just say look
there are twenty really big companies
that deal with energy but 15 of them
haven't patched their systems in about
six months and here's the type of stuff
they've left open its energy it's two
years but yes building off on that so
that's the kind of things you want you
want to get your foot it you know in
both cases of our examples there was one
key element we talked about we would
kind of touched on it when we did this
talking to you see but it's really
important they got to the point of the
store in the actual pitch within the
first two sentences of the email or the
phone call or everything like that it's
called an elevator pitch anybody not
familiar with elevator pitching so all
you know what that means
great for those of you watching at home
over on tape an elevator pitch means you
can give me the entire snap to do story
in about 60 seconds in the time it takes
go from the ground floor to the fifth
floor I should know everything there is
to know about you or your product or
whatever those kind of pitches get our
attention and one of the point it makes
reading through the emails that we get
hundreds of them a days so simple and it
helps us determine that's gonna be a
story that's not going to be a story
that's good so that the email subject in
the first couple of sentences hook me
I'm probably going to enter you and if
you compel me enough that might generate
a story all on its own I've written
stories based off the subject line of
emails because they were that good and
it's because the story was really that
like
and it was worth it but then I've also
completely deleted emails based on the
subject is named as the source of the
story and he will be happy because
people just what's this company what do
you got a and and what he did what he
did was he reframed it to be again in
the public interest for everybody it
really honors fifteen or twenty nuclear
power plants don't give up the security
it's not about selling a product it's
about making them the public interest
it's it's a backdoor way to promote your
product and that's what we want and
you'll say I think I'm probably the only
personally I spent two two-and-a-half
years doing public relations in the mid
90s it's not something I'm proud about
but hey no I helped launched ActiveX in
the UK but I'm so ashamed I mean as you
saying that in the PR industry it's just
like yeah this job would be great for
them for clients of fucking journalists
but I mean look you need to be able to
every client organization wants to get
their name into the story you need to be
able to do that in a way which and they
here wit actually gets your company into
a good lie and just saying this is a
fucking problem and we've got the
solution to the problem doesn't work you
need to add incisive in intelligent
comment just like we're great isn't it
wonderful
fuck up and remember that you know
you're gonna tell us this this is a
great story but I need to find two other
companies in this space exactly I didn't
talk to me about what's going on in his
space never real simple
[Laughter]
you do that it's because you told me the
sky is blue and the Sun it's great and
people can't patch her than six months
but the person after you says that's a
bunch of bullshit they patch in a few
weeks and here's proof to it to back it
up so now what do I do
and that kind of put you on a platform
or a postal so you have to understand a
journalist is going to verify everything
you've said twice twice and for a lot of
reports and a lot of companies getting
things verify twice it just won't hold
up
so you have to know your facts ahead of
time which is why as we mentioned
earlier it's very important you know
what you're going to talk about free
time it happens a depressingly large
amount of the time I mean we we had this
with with Intel with Specter you know we
we pro the story and then they they
briefed financial analysts saying this
is all bullshit it's not going to cause
a slowdown a process not at all and they
came back to us at well they're saying
this is bullshit and then thank God
Google came through and said actually
it's you know if you lie to do it to
journalists if you try and stretch the
facts you're gonna get fucked you know
it's as simple as that and ours is very
good at this COCs I was already good you
know Tom's is very good at this
seriously just tell the truth
just if something's bad just say it's
bad also I got it start by catching and
telling a lie yeah you go really good on
yeah don't be afraid to say I don't know
yeah
we'll love you for that because that is
so easy to write and later it's easy to
update it is easy to update which means
I've got two stories for the price of
water that makes my week we have a
question over that sorry good
power companies are like poverty
disarmed and pitched and you taking this
like oh my gosh and inspect right in the
the headline V about okay so to repeat
back for the video she's saying that you
know what happens how do you deal with
the fact that people sensationalize
content when you give it to them and
make it into world will end tomorrow
because these things are not patched I
don't know who wouldn't mention
reticular puzzles to do this true
because I wanna close with ground on the
ground above ground communities there so
we knew that it will not happen and I
told them at won't and explain why but
then they reached out to another person
credibly cook from oh yes right yeah
right well that's that's something that
I have very specific experience with
yeah so and and this happens to me as a
source all the time guys so I got a call
from an NBC producer a while back asking
me if a particular thing you know they
want to talk about a particular
vulnerability is this really bad what
can be done with it and all that and it
was something that I had been doing some
research into and I said no this isn't
something average people need to worry
about this is specific to this
particular area and but it is a thing of
concern long term for this segment and
I'll be happy to talk with you about
that more and they said okay we'll get
back to you and then they said well
we're not going to talk to you guys it
it doesn't it isn't like an imminent
threat from your perspective and we
it's basically the line we use it for is
if it bleeds it leads without Frankie so
if it bleeds it leads if it's something
that's gonna cause death destruction
damage
that'll go first and that's especially
true in broadcast media and with
publications that are more in sort of a
tabloid esque format but who is the I
they can't hear you
who was the publication to contacted you
okay so so so you need to you need to
judge based on the credibility of this
of the publication you're dealing with
and that requires you to be a media
analyst to some degree on your own and
that's something that unfortunately this
time in in in our history and it's been
true forever I don't know what it hasn't
been you need to understand the
motivations of the publication's what's
driving them as much as you need to
understand how to deliver the story so
they're on this slide that have good up
you know you go there's a little box off
to the side what's this the publication
driven by are they driven by page views
is their entire business model on making
sure they get the most views possible
sort of like BuzzFeed something like
that or is it you know or is it if it's
television is a ratings same thing well
with vision also you need the visuals
right I mean when you're talking about
pure journalist Peale print journalism
right then the the hard cymatics come
down right but I find the problem with
American television is that and also the
British television is that it's all
focused on the vigil the visuals and if
you don't have a visual story you're
gonna get fucked we're running a little
bit we're tight on time so that sounds
to me like it was a journalist who
wanted this sensational fun story not
the reality that you're doing so how do
you deal with that that is entirely up
view it's it's almost in your interest
not to talk to the media at this point
because they distort whatever you're say
so you have a choice that's actually
something to cover it does is they help
you connect with people to get the real
truth out there even if it means for the
first few months banging your head
against the wall issues like nobody's
listening to you
conventionally big will this and the
truth does get out there the reality of
attack so good state a power grid or
something like that becomes focus and
the sensationalism in the fund goes away
so you have a choice you could stop or
you can stick with it but unfortunately
you're going to find journalists who
already have that narrative in their
head and when they asked you those
questions they wanted you to say yes
certainly going to happen so they could
write the doom and gloom when you didn't
give them that answer they found someone
who did there are always people out
there who will give you that quote I
this is an analyst at I won't name the
company but I called them up about a
story and it was like so what do you
want me to say yeah okay fuck off I mean
there are people who you know will
spread the just ignore them fight
against them yeah but give them give me
if you got the facts that's what makes
the story you know anyone can spread
foot all around but give people the
facts and you can't fight against that
and and you know when you said comes
down to this slide
you know this is a slide we read you
at the end of our presentation in DC the
worst in like journalism is like InfoSec
got good people and you got bad people
though the worst in journalism is just
like the worst in InfoSec you know there
are people who are essentially
journalistic script kitties we want to
go for the easy hill easy kill with the
story and they will define themselves
and you will be able to identify them
and you will have to put danger flags
around them and make sure that you don't
deal with them and that's how you end up
dealing with that it's it's a it's a
hard lesson that's why media
professionals will be able to help you
with that most of the time they'll be
able to say okay well we don't want to
deal with this particular source because
they do this particular outlet because
it's a particular outlet is incredible
isn't gonna help our story no all right
so we're over our time first thank you
to our guinea pig another round of
applause
[Applause]