please welcome Aaron Campbell thank you
so I'm Aaron Campbell and I lead the
security team for the WordPress
open-source project I've been doing that
for a little over a year and a half but
been a part of the team basically since
we started it and we've learned a lot of
lessons along the way most of them that
I'm going over today are not specific
coding technical things it's a lot more
of how our team functions well and how
we are able to run security for that
large of a project I am employed by
GoDaddy to work full time on WordPress I
started doing that about two years ago
basically with the directive to try to
help make WordPress better WordPress is
all volunteer powered but there are some
aspects of a project when it reaches
that size that need really consistent
attention so companies like GoDaddy that
hire people to do that really help us
keep things moving along I've been
leading the team for a year and a half
been on it since we started it I guess
about eight years ago I've been
contributing to WordPress for about 12
years but the story of how I got here
starts even a little bit earlier than
that who remembers this game we got like
one person a couple people this is
guerrillas it was distributed in 1991
with ms-dos 5 I was only nine years old
but I loved this game I played it
constantly which when you look at it
it's kind of strange because the
graphics are terrible and the gameplay
was equally terrible and this was the
same time that the Super Nintendo came
out and I had one of those and it sort
of put this to shame but the thing that
kept bringing me back to
this game over and over was this
gorillas was not distributed to showcase
what pcs were capable of around graphics
and gameplay it was distributed to
showcase qbasic Microsoft's integrated
development environment for the basic
programming language so it was
distributed as source code it was open
source it may not be the kind of open
source that I've sort of grown to love
and advocate for now because that first
line right up there is a copyright but
it really I credit it with shifting sort
of sort of my focus from loving
electronics and computers and just
enjoying them to really being interested
in how they work how I can control them
and how I can make them do what I wanted
them to do and this along with a couple
other open-source things that
nine-year-old me was able to get his
hands on or how I started to learn to
write code from that point of learning
to write code it was about a year maybe
as long as two before I started into
blackhat hacking breaking into systems
back then was drastically easier than it
is now security was not really where it
ought to have been in the early 90s and
it was partially because there was we
were right at the beginning of kind of
this shift where companies were even
caring at all about security we were
having sort of yes we were we were
having this this changeover from sort of
if you had the disks you had the program
to things like activation keys that's
sort of where I settled in but those
activation keys the algorithms behind
them were pretty terrible and it's
because everybody was focused not on the
technical aspects of their security they
were focused on the secrecy of their
security
and that is something that I think has
been tough for our industry through
those years at least from where I sit
where lots of people have focused not on
actual security but on secrecy as
security if if they don't know how we're
securing a thing then they can't exploit
it and this is something that I try to
push real hard against where I try to
open up what we're doing as a project
the struggles that we've hit the lessons
that we've learned the tools that we use
I love to get the chance to sort of
share that with everybody when we
started our team about eight years ago
our goal seemed really awesome is just
keep WordPress secure right obvious
except almost immediately we realized
this didn't line up with our overall
project goals which sounds strange maybe
but the truth is from the very beginning
of WordPress its focus its goal has been
to democratize publishing to give
everyone a voice not to make the
greatest piece of software not to have
the the most amazing code but to give
people that tools so that they have a
voice it was our users that needed to be
the most important thing and so we had
to shift from trying to secure our
product which was already pretty big and
already relatively old and so there were
some challenges there but we had to
shift our focus to keeping WordPress
users secure instead and it's important
to understand sort of this mindset shift
because it really affects all the things
that we as a project including the
security team do and and you won't
really be able to understand why we're
doing some of the things we do unless
you realize that securing the WordPress
code is only one
piece of our overall goal and this was
really the first lesson I guess that we
learned if you will users over software
our users are more important than our
software itself this makes some things a
little bit more challenging for example
a lot of us that distribute products
probably deal with this users that are
using an older version are less secure
when your focus is on securing your
software the solution to this is you put
out a secure version of your software
that was your job you fixed the problem
their job is to use that right it's
that's their problem the users problem
but for us putting out a secure version
was only the first step it didn't
actually accomplish our goal until it
was being used by the users and so we
had this gap that we had to try to solve
how do we actually get it all the way
there in order to accomplish our goal of
keeping users secure well for us that
was going the extra step in upgrading
for them which is how we ended up with
automatic updates automatic updates went
into WordPress 3.7 which is like four
and a half years ago so we've been
operating under this mindset for quite a
while and building automatic updates was
hard and doing them securely and not
breaking sites especially with all the
different ways that WordPress is used it
was a huge challenge but it was the only
way that we could see to actually
accomplish our goal of securing our
users instead of just our piece of
software it made a couple small things
easier on us when we focused on users
when we had that clarity we used to
struggle a lot with figuring out when we
should back port security fixes there
was cons
discussion about how many people were
affected and how big of a deal it really
was and how hard it was going to be to
back port it to previous releases and
there was a lot of discussion and often
a lot of of differing opinions but now
our sort of decision-making flowchart
for this is super simple
does it help keep our users secure yes
back port it and this is tough for us as
a security team but it's a thing that we
have embraced and continue to do all
security vulnerabilities that are fixed
in WordPress are back ported all the way
back to either whenever they started or
version 3.7 when auto updates were
introduced the current version is 4.9 so
when we release a fix we are releasing
13 new versions simultaneously as well
as patching the code that's going to be
the next version it increased our
workload but it helped us accomplish our
goal we also realize though that even
though this one little thing this one
decision was maybe easier to make
all in all securing users was crazy
complex we had this code base that was
under our control when our goal was just
securing WordPress but when we had to
secure users they all use plug-ins and
themes that code is not under our
control but does affect the security of
our users so we have to care about it
users host it thousands of different
hosts in at least as many different
configurations and those are not under
our control but it affects the security
of our users so we have to care about it
the other big thing that affects the
security of our users is our users
themselves who are not very good at
keeping themselves secure as we look
across the sort of I guess we get a
pretty good picture of WordPress sites
that are
compromised by and large the biggest
issue is still poor user practices
usually around something as simple as
passwords users are terrible at that so
we realized if we want to protect our
users we have to secure our software we
have to figure out how to secure other
people's code we have to figure out how
to secure their hosting and we have to
educate them and all of those are
problems that we have been struggling
with and trying to tackle I'm going to
talk some about the solutions that we
came up with in just a little bit but
from the very beginning when we thought
yeah we need to educate users we got to
teach them we know what they need to be
doing we just got to tell them little
bonus lesson here and educating users is
terribly hard they do not listen well
and for us we have tens of millions of
users all over the world and they don't
have to necessarily give us any kind of
contact info in order to download and
use our software so we don't have direct
lines of communication with them but it
was important enough that it's an issue
that we've struggled through and
struggled through and eventually found
some solutions to that I will talk about
again in just a little bit to understand
the next couple things you need a short
quick
I guess history lesson of WordPress
we're old 15 years old is very old for
software projects any software that's
been around for 15 years and is still
actively used and developed has changed
dramatically and I think that a lot of
our change has been driven heavily by
our growth I don't have numbers going
all the way back to the beginning I
don't think people cared to track
numbers as much back then but in 2011 w3
Tech's started tracking estimated CMS
usage percentage of the internet and the
numbers are rough because tracking that
kind of stuff is hard but in 2011 they
estimated we powered about 13% of the
Internet and the end of last month they
estimated we powered about 30 1.4
percent of the Internet and that's a lot
of growth and it looks
very linear but I will tell you it did
not feel that way when we were in it as
you know working on the project that's
because these are percentages of the
internet and the Internet's grown
dramatically as well and if there's
anything harder than tracking
percentages of CMS usage it's probably
counting the size of the internet but I
took some likely terribly inaccurate
numbers and plugged them in anyway
because I think that it gives you a
better picture maybe the numbers are
wrong but the shape of the graph I think
better shows what it felt like to go
through this growth period and the years
are labeled and that's pretty obvious
but there's a few points where WordPress
had to grow up a lot and I labeled a few
of them in mid-2013 was when we finally
got an actual build process for
WordPress it was a little behind the
times when we finally rolled that out
but it was really hard to do at that
time w3 Tech's estimated we were
powering 19% of the Internet and we had
built a lot of tooling around our
repository as it sat and that all needed
to be redone because our repository
needed to be reorganized it was a really
difficult task because it was past due
like it was way past when it was needed
in late 2014 we finally moved to a
reasonable form of communication we use
slack now all the way up until then our
main form of communication was a channel
on IRC on you know freenode IRC that is
how we ran WordPress when we were
powering roughly 22% of the Internet and
then last year is when I think our
security team really made one of those
big growth spurts and that was when we
launched our bug bounty program on
hacker 1 and as part of that process we
redid a lot of our processes procedures
tooling etc but again
it was it was really late in coming we
were supposedly powering 28% of the
Internet and we were running all of our
security reporting for a project the
size of WordPress through a security at
email address that distributed to a
handful of mailboxes of people who were
supposed to handle that and the biggest
thing that I realized through each of
these really difficult growth periods is
that we really should have been
assessing our needs far more often it's
real easy to sort of get set up on what
it is that you need for us eight years
ago when we launched the security team
that security at email address and our
our couple tools that we used was great
it was just what we needed
but two years later we probably needed
something else but we never really took
the time to sit down and reassess our
needs until we sort of hit a wall and it
was impossible to do what we were
supposed to be doing with the way things
were currently set up and that is way
too late to be reassessing growing
iteratively looking at where you're at
every six months or a year if you
haven't done that if you haven't sat
down and said hey our processes are our
tools right for us they were but are
they still do so because these huge
growth spurts they're not healthy and
they're really difficult to get through
I think it was maybe even a little bit
more difficult for us in some ways
because we're an all-volunteer security
team that in general is very hard to do
on any project and one the size of
WordPress especially and about a year
and a half ago as we were sort of
restructuring and struggling through a
lot of that I really was asking myself
is it even possible to run security for
a project like WordPress with an
all-volunteer team because volunteers
are hard now there's some benefits to
volunteers I think and I think
it's important to point that out people
volunteer to do a thing because they
think it's really important or because
they enjoy it and either of those things
brings with it some level of passion and
that path passion can drive performance
and that's that's awesome I think it
also brings us a diversity of input that
we couldn't otherwise get our team is a
little over 30 people and some of them
worked for hosts and some of them work
for security companies and some of them
quite a few of them worked for various
development agencies some of those
agencies focus on enterprise some are
focused on app development with
WordPress as a back-end all these
different ways that WordPress is being
used and our team is actually doing that
so we have all that variety of input and
I think that's really healthy but
there's some massive downsides to a
volunteer team and the biggest one is
that available hours fluctuate
dramatically right people give you you
know they're dedicating a few hours or a
handful of hours to volunteer but when
they have a big project at work or
they're coming up on a deadline or they
have some big life event going on they
just don't have hours to volunteer it's
not that they don't want to they simply
don't have it available and the number
of times that that seems to happen to a
large percentage of the team all at once
is a little bit mind-boggling so we had
to sit down and try to figure out how do
we make this work because all of
WordPress is volunteer powered like this
has felt really normal all along but the
security team needs some consistency we
really do in the past the solution had
always been grow the team if we needed
the number of hours that we were getting
from five people but those people were
busy you could grow the team to 10
people and now as long as only five
people were busy the other five could
handle it
that had been our solution to this all
along in the past but when so that was
my first go-to when we started running
into this a year and a half ago but it
didn't really work this time I think
that we had hit a scale where simply
growing the team was just no longer the
solution the team got so big that it
wasn't that people didn't have hours to
volunteer it's just that they weren't
and it was mostly because everyone said
there's so many of us somebody else is
going to get it right somebody else is
going to take care of it and it
completely backfired did not work at all
so we shrunk the team back down and the
thing that we did successfully land on
is that we now operate a little bit as a
hybrid team we're still mostly volunteer
the vast majority of ours are volunteer
hours but for example I'm paid by
GoDaddy to work on WordPress and a lot
of those hours or sank into WordPress
security similarly there's a handful of
people on our team that are given a
certain number of hours by their company
paid usually it's like a 20% project so
they get like 8 hours a week and a
couple people put that all into security
and a couple people sort of split that
back and forth between core development
and security depending on where they're
needed and this has given us the ability
to sort of reap the benefits of a
volunteer team but also never completely
have no hours available because we need
that consistency our tools are
completely focused on making us more
efficient making it so that we can do
more in less hours because ours are our
most precious resource with volunteer
team we've tried lots of really new
great fantastic tools and what we've
settled in on is actually a really
simplistic set
of tools we use slack as our main form
of communication I mentioned that we
have a private channel for security
we've also got some scripts set up that
let us let anyone on the team easily
spin up a security sub channel that
automatically invites the whole security
team and allows us to ad hoc invite
certain people that may be helpful in
discussing a specific issue but don't
necessarily need to see everything
that's going on we have a couple of
those channels that are actually
permanently spun up that I'll get to in
a little bit that have very specific
purposes we use track some people love
it some people hate it mostly the latter
but the WordPress project has used track
since the very beginning and because
most of us have been around it for a
while we're really comfortable with it
and so while we've tried a lot of much
better bug trackers this one seems to
work the best for us and so we have come
back to it it's a completely internal
facing tool so it's only something that
our team needs to use anyway and we use
this mostly for putting up patches on
things doing code review on those
iterating on them etc etc and then we
use hacker 1:yes to power our bug bounty
program but also as our main sort of way
of communicating with reporters and
researchers and keeping them in the loop
and in this big changeover where we sort
of updated our toolset and settled in on
this and tried a lot of other things the
biggest thing that really stood out to
me as we test it and got rid of a whole
bunch of tools is that tools don't fix
most of our problems
they often help highlight where some of
those problems really are we think that
they're because of our tools but for us
most of them weren't
for example we really struggled when we
used a security at email address to keep
hackers in the loop as they reported a
thing to us and we focused in on on
working on it we often went radio silent
didn't really keep them them updated and
they mistook that radio silence as
nothing happening which is kind of
understandable and it's strained
relationships we had a tough time
keeping people updated and now we
thought as we sort of piloted the hacker
one tool and we saw how amazing that was
for keeping people in the loop how easy
it was no longer were we staring at an
email going somebody else is probably
going to reply to this and then finally
saying okay fine no one's replying to it
I'll reply to it and then it you know
six replies all came through at once
there are all these downsides to this
old tool so we thought this new tool
it's gonna it's going to fix the issue
for us and then we went through our
whole test we we launched on hacker one
and they're still terrible at keeping
researchers in the loop and it's because
the tool wasn't the problem and so the
tool didn't fix it the way we fixed that
particular problem is adjusting things
around so that we no longer assign
issues to a single person we have these
small like three to four person teams
the issues get assigned to so that
there's a handful of people they can see
that someone needs an update but also in
just kind of bringing in some new people
to our team who are focused on keeping
communication flowing well right we had
people who were good at fixing issues we
had people that had historical knowledge
of our codebase all this sort of classic
stuff that you expect a security team to
have but we needed those communication
people that wouldn't get distracted by
fixing the issue and would be focused in
on this thing that we were not
doing well so making those adjustments
fix the actual problem when we thought
tools were gonna fix it which brings me
to one of the sort of biggest lessons
that we've learned over the last year
and a half two years we have struggled
for quite a few years with how do we
take our security all the way to the
users with these these three big areas
that seemed like problems that that were
almost impossible to solve write code
that wasn't under our control how are we
going to how are we going to keep users
safe when they're using code that's not
under our control hosting environments
that are also not under our control and
educating our users that we tried so
many different ways and none of them
really seemed effective and the crazy
thing is these three biggest problems
that we had been struggling with as a
team for four or five years now at least
were actually all solved with the same
basic thing which was building
relationships I think that we often at
least the WordPress team definitely did
we often overlooked the fact that there
are other people that can help us
accomplish our goals no matter what
those those goals are and so we took the
time to sit down we said okay we're
having these struggles if we controlled
everything if we controlled absolutely
everything what would we do well we
would make plug in code more secure so
we need to start building relationships
with the people that do control that one
of our permanent sub channels in our
slack is for communicating with plug-in
authors right now it's just our security
team and the authors of some of the
biggest plugins in the WordPress space
the ones that are on maybe a million or
a few million sites
but we've been working real heavily with
them to try to make sure that their
security works well with ours that we're
functioning well together and that we're
setting a good example at the top
because in our ecosystem
everybody that's building all these
other plugins tens of thousands of
plugins are kind of looking to the top
for either examples or to straight-up
copy code and use we've built a lot of
relationships with hosts
laughs CD ends trying to see where we
can protect our users in ways that we
were never able to before right
WordPress could only when we were just
securing our own code we could only
protect users at that application layer
once they got all the way down to
WordPress and by building these
relationships we've now been able to
when we see a problem that could be
fixed at the network layer or mitigated
at the network layer we can get all the
major hosts and companies like
CloudFlare and such to start protecting
millions of WordPress sites before we
even push out any fix and for educating
users all of these same companies that
we're building these relationships with
have much more direct hands-on
relationships with our users so we've
been able to work with them to help
build some education programs and help
them to educate our users building
better programs through through hosts
building even some things through search
engines like Google and their their
search engine console being able to work
better with them to use them as a
channel to educate our users I wanted to
leave a lot of time for Q&A because when
I throw out talks like this it's always
interesting to see what kinds of things
people are interested to know and
we're really open as a project and would
love to share whatever it is that you're
interested in that you'd like to know oh
and there's a mic to run around I almost
forgot because we are live streaming
fate I have a very small CMS that's not
open-source but I'm thinking about open
source but I'm kind of terrified because
then everyone would know where the holes
are and you know I think I'm smart but I
know that I haven't caught all the holes
is there a recommended path or some RTFM
you have for folks who are thinking
about going down this route so that's
that's really interesting we get that
sort of mentality a lot people say well
it can't be secure because it's open
source and everybody can look into it
and find the security vulnerabilities
and obviously there's some danger that
someone's going to see a thing that you
didn't see they're gonna find that
vulnerability and they're going to
exploit it it's possible I mean you're
giving them a peek into your code but
similarly they may find that
vulnerability and want to exploit it but
somebody else may find that
vulnerability and let you know about it
I think that if you're going to go the
route of open sourcing a thing it can
actually be really beneficial so many
eyes on a thing help find all these
issues that you may not have seen but
only if you have good methods for them
to then report it to you and ultimately
get it fixed I think that that's the
biggest thing if you're going to open
source I don't think that makes you
inherently less secure but make sure
that those channels of communication are
in place so that people can help you
keep your products secure rather than
exploit it in some way that they find
and in general I think that this has
been
great in the WordPress project as far as
we have we as a security team yes we
find issues but tons of other people
have found issues over these 15 years as
well that we've been able to fix and and
when we fix it because they noticed it
it's fixed for everybody and that's
that's a big plus thanks actually wanted
to comment about the lost gentleman's
question there you know in the WordPress
community it seems like we went through
this phase in 2011 2012 2013 where a lot
of vulnerabilities came to light and I
think what might have happened is
WordPress hit a level of popularity
where it became very interesting to
security researchers and so what you
might find is at the stage of growth
that you're at now
it's not super interesting for people to
do kind of pro bono research into
vulnerabilities in your platform but you
also don't have a big user base so
they're not going to be a lot of people
affected by potential vulnerability so I
would say if you open source it now as
you grow you know you're probably going
to find that you hit that hopefully as
you grow you're gonna hit that phase
where now you're really interesting and
on everyone's radar and you go through a
bit of a challenging period and you have
to scramble but but then you get past
that and in in the WordPress space now
we're in a much better place than we
were in 2012 I would say Aaron yeah I
think that since probably right around
2012 or so we have felt like we had a
giant target on our back right like
because everybody was if you were trying
to compromise websites WordPress was a
great way to do it because there were so
many WordPress websites out there and
there is sort of that that rough period
to get over where you're interesting to
people but you don't necessarily have
enough help from other people now that
WordPress is run in a lot of enterprise
sites
you know Disney and and Oprah and some
of these big companies that actually do
a lot of vulnerability testing and
research and stuff and bring it back to
us and help us with that sort of what I
feel like got us over that hump and
there are those awkward growth periods
that I think are just a little bit more
awkward in open-source you kind of got
to prepare for those yeah right
[Music]
yep the the very the very beginning of
just putting it out there and somebody
seeing it it can be scary I've released
quite a few open-source things and it
can be scary but ultimately I've found
that if they continue to grow that it's
been ultimately beneficial for the
projects that I've done that way so
there's a lot of time of course then on
like responding to and fixing security
vulnerabilities that either you find or
other people find I'm curious what your
thoughts are on like the other side of
that of preventing new vulnerabilities
from being written especially when it is
like a lot of volunteer contributors and
like kind of maintaining standards of
code quality including security yes so
as a security team we do a lot of code
review obviously a lot of people are
interested in writing new features and
adding new stuff and that's cool and fun
and neat and shiny but checking to make
sure that what's being added is secure
there's a much smaller group of people
that consider is that fun and even then
that's only some small percentage of our
team right but we understand it's
important so we do spend a lot of time
doing that kind of code review
especially around big new things that
are being added into WordPress right now
a complete reworking of the way the
editor works in WordPress a whole new
system for that is coming in it's a ton
of code that we've had to continually
review and look at
some of the ways that we're able to sort
of keep up is that we've built some
tools to keep things simple things like
code quality and code standards are are
checked with every commit while anyone
can volunteer to you know put in some
some work and write some code and get
some patches up our committers the
people that can actually put that into
the project they you know they have a
little bit better knowledge and can are
kind of the first line there checking
that but yes we spend a huge amount of
time just making sure that what's
already you know secure as secure as we
can make it doesn't slip back into some
major problem well my question actually
can end up an extension of that one but
assuming you've run into friction when
dealing with some feature development
teams in terms of them saying oh no go a
security we don't want to listen to you
what are some of the strategies that
you've adopted to kind of get it to
become a win-win and get them on board
and get their buy-in and have you kind
of shifted along the one longer journey
in terms of like we're just gonna force
this on you whether or not you like it
or not versus a more collaborative
approach so some of the things that
first spring to mind are that we've had
some struggles in the past with when
when these new features want to make use
of other libraries that already exist as
a security team especially as the lead
that kind of handles a lot of those
relationships with other projects I feel
like we not only have to review that
code but we need to communicate with the
authors of those libraries that we're
going to use and make sure that they are
going to work with us when issues are
found right all these kinds of things
and that's been a struggle less that
people who want to use these these
libraries or whatever want us to go away
but more
that they just start their building
they're doing a thing they don't even
loop us in you know we have to really
pay close attention and notice it
ourselves so that's been one of the
struggles is just being aware enough of
that aside from that probably the
biggest actual friction that we have is
this constant balance that needs to be
found between securing all the things
and keeping a product that's easy to use
and flexible right
the the thing that I think has helped
with that actually is really working
with our security team to basically say
look I know that we all want to secure
things as much as possible but if our
goal is to make our users as secure as
we can make them then if we make it
fantastic but they don't use it that way
it doesn't actually improve their
security so we have to find this balance
point which is a real mindset change but
we have to find this balance point where
we're doing as much security as we can
that is bringing those users along with
us and sort of maybe iteratively grow
that and so working with our security
team to say okay sometimes it's not
going to be absolutely perfect because
we have to work with in reality and then
yes having to get that buy-in from the
teams that are like no no this is so
much easier yes but we have to fight
we're gonna give a little but you've got
to give a little too we need to find
this balance point in the middle yeah
yeah and work on another large open
source project and we're kind of at the
stage where we have a product security -
lock channel and a build process but not
a bug bounty yet and there's a lot of
discussion as to having a bug bounty I
wanted to hear a bit more how you guys
set that up from a point of like scoping
like we're talking about to do plugins
get included or not if they're not in
core
and the team the scree team is really
afraid of opening this bug mone and just
being like everybody's gonna be busy for
six months
like so how do you kind of manage that
that type of expectation so I'll tell
you how we manage it now in just a
minute but it's we didn't manage it
enough when we first launched and that
initial if you're a pretty popular open
source project that initial sort of hit
that you get when you first launch that
program is pretty intense we were very
overloaded for a period of time we
should have run longer we ran a sort of
a private test that was invite-only we
use hacker one we found that that's been
a fantastic tool for us but we don't
include plugins we only include all of
our products and projects so we have
WordPress as well as buddypress BB press
and WP CLI other things that we build
and all of our sites are also under that
so our wordpress.org site all of our
event sites all that and some of the
things that we should have had more in
place is extreme clarity you probably
have some of those issues that are
reported relatively regularly and aren't
valid not just real clearly specifying
that on the page but also have some sort
of are you sure kind of trigger system
that warns people because it's not for
us it's not the the number of valid
issues that are being found that's the
struggle and it's not the monetary
expense that's the struggle it's the
noise that's the struggle it's the
number of invalid reports that you sort
of have to wade through to get to the
valid ones and I think that that's
partially just a volume thing but also
it's not fun to wade through in valid
reports and a volunteer
team who wants to volunteer to do a
thing that's not fun right so with
hacker one we helped pilot a program
that they put out called human augmented
signal where they have a team that's
kind of the first line of defense to
filter out the most obviously invalid
reports that come through and that has
been absolutely amazing for us in the
last year of our sort of the well in the
first year only about 9% of reported
issues were actually valid but of the of
the ones that were invalid more than 50%
of those invalid reports were caught by
that hacker one team and never made it
to our team which is pretty great
so looking at things like that that
might help you through that initial sort
of skyrocket in number of issues
reported can be really helpful so your
second lesson was reassess regularly and
what I think is kind of interesting
about that as I'm sure your entire team
looked at all the stuff that they had on
their plate and it was never important
for any given build process security
process or whatever to be addressed
until crisis hit and I've been at
companies that will remain nameless that
have let the crisis point come and go
and then still haven't built the changes
and now are facing a real hard problem
so the question I have to you is the is
there anything in hindsight that should
have been a warning signal that you are
hitting the crisis point before the
crisis point became blatantly obvious to
everybody because everybody on your team
was smart right and everybody was saying
well yeah somebody's complaining that
they need better tools but we've got
something more important to work on
so I think that I don't know the like
those those things that may tip you off
very dramatically right depending on on
what kind of crisis you're about to hit
probably but for for us I think that one
of the reasons we missed a lot of those
wasn't because the team wasn't smart
enough to figure them out or recognize
them it was honestly because we didn't
have a good hierarchy within that team
and so there wasn't a a person kind of
focused on watching for those things we
really didn't have a security team lead
we just had a security team until I
think it was three years ago that we we
sort of said hey we should have somebody
in charge and at that time it wasn't
even in charge so much as it was a
person to to put their name there that
people could go to if they if they
wanted to talk to building in some
hierarchy where things were flat before
sets some expectations that the people
at the top are watching for those kinds
of oncoming things that's the thing that
I take on myself for the security team
and similarly in the WordPress project
as a whole we only ever had release
leads someone that was in charge of the
next release and then somebody else
would be in charge of the next release
I led WordPress 3.6 that was my thing I
did that but I didn't also lead 37 38 39
like I didn't have some long term plan
that everyone was bought into so getting
some of that put back in place I think
has helped us as well to see those kinds
of things coming
speaking of crisis with WordPress being
a platform has created or developed and
there's a largely volunteer team how do
you deal with Incident Response
when there's a huge announcement of
vulnerabilities something came to mind
was like the Panama papers that that was
largely a wordpress part of that was
largely a wordpress plug-in
vulnerability and it got a lot of
attention is there like an incident
response protocol that you follow as a
team
that's a thing that we're in the process
of still trying to build and figure out
right now are our teams a little bit
[Music]
just sort of let's jump to it and all
hands on deck and let's figure this out
and we're sort of assessing each one as
it comes in and figuring it out for that
issue which I don't think is healthy so
we've gone through a lot of these
changes and fixed a lot of the other
things that we were dealing with and
that's hopefully that will be one of the
lessons that I've learned by next year
and maybe I can come back and really
explain how we changed to figure that
out
but right now we don't have like a
response that we follow every time we're
sort of custom building those solutions
each time it's so kind of building a
little bit on that question and an
earlier one multi-party response
wondering if you have any lessons
learned or experiences to share about
common vulnerabilities that affect
multiple companies and how you respond
to those for us one of the I mean again
a lot of this comes down to
relationships right there's um there's
been this long-standing thing where for
example every CMS kind of does its own
thing
WordPress hasn't really worked with for
example like even other open source ones
Drupal and Joomla and stuff in our space
we had hardly ever interacted with them
on on these kinds of levels even though
a lot of security vulnerabilities really
do often affect multiple platforms we
now work pretty consistently with the
security
teams from these other CMS's so that
when those things happen we can do
things like coordinated releasing and
that kind of stuff most of that actually
seems to happen
on our WordPress slack we spin up
channels and bring those people in the
security team leads from those other
projects are on our slack already anyway
because we've been trying to communicate
regularly so that's that's where we tend
to handle that but yeah that's a thing
that I feel like we've gotten better at
over the last couple of years anyone
else
well I'll be around for a while if
anybody else has any other questions
come find me and ask thank you
[Applause]