this is not for that a floor above our
frequent as a metering and yeah he's a
great guy and he our tweet of it that I
say that is going to happen and we see
no stupid task idea possible so that he
consumed every idiot trying to learn to
proverbs and make that this president
this is Arya
[Music]
nice introduction of malk night till all
right um mark burnett um I do security
I've been doing it for her oh all right
right believe it or not I've been doing
it or I would do it for about 15 years
I've been working insecure about 15
years I've been working an ITR working
with you know security related stuff
I've been doing up about 20 years I've
been writing code for about 30 years a
lot of what I do well in last 15 years
I've worked in just about every area of
security a lot of what I do now is code
security developing creating
presentations tonight things like that
but I just kind of wanted to start and
talking about how i got into security
and how I got interested in passwords
and it started off about about 20 years
ago I was working for this company and I
was I was writing code and I go in every
day to work sit down on my computer type
in my password which was you know dog
named Cole numbers my bad work all day
write code all day put in the you know
shut down in the day next big walk-in
type in my password dog named couple
numbers and I do this every day and I I
about every month or so they would ask
me to change my password and so I would
you know being as clever as I was I
would increment it so you know one day I
mean before I was a dog named one to the
next time it was dog named 13 and now
sometimes I would get really clever and
skip a few you know dog named 19 dog
named 25 so that's that was my help
that's what I that was me and so anyway
is the boring job so I spent a lot of
time researching and I got got into
researching security most actually
hacking
and and I was really interested and I
learned a few tricks you know how to
it's just tricks and I got this
reputation around the office being the
office hacker you know because I had
these things that made me look less
smart and I really was one day one of
the managers came to me and said they
had this problem what happened was the
network administrator and the VP got an
argument and the administrator just left
the company but he didn't tell anyone
his passwords now the BP was too
stubborn to call and asked for the
passwords so this manager comes to me
and says you know he wants me since I'm
the hacker you know he wants me to come
it wants me to go and break all the
passwords for the network and I said
yeah okay sure but I got thinking about
like oh no would I get myself into
because I wasn't really you know what's
just few trick I knew so do I spent I
spent a few hours doing this and I one
thing I realized is that people have
really bad password it wasn't with me I
was everyone and nothing I realized that
pretty good at guessing but I went from
one system to another got all this guy
got old path words I mean it was you
know Superman 12 Superman to Superman
123 no wonder woman I mean it's just
really obvious passwords so I went
during got him on I sent him to the vet
asst manager um yeah well next morning I
got up as I walking up the office the
President and the Vice President the
company just happy walking in the same
time I was and I swear they rehearsed
this but as I walked up they both bow
before me open the door and let me in
the office and so I I thought it pretty
cool you know like my honest I'm the
office hacker you know and I went down
side of my desk and typed in my password
you know dog named 59 and that's when I
realized how horrible yeah i was i was
just as vulnerable as anyone else was so
i got into secured I got into passwords
and it kind of became like my life's
hobby really as to as to
learn about Patrick learn how people
choose passwords learn about how the
thought process that goes behind it so I
that that's that's my thing I I've spent
my years doing even though I've got my
day job I I've always been fascinated
with passwords and I think it's great
that we have so many other people here
who are interested passwords thanks for
letting me speak here it's really my
talk is just a big rant so thanks for
listening to my rant never had someone
to do this I never had an audience was
to me complain oil fast work my wife
well she likes me to do it only woman
once you trying to fall asleep at night
you know talk to me about passwords so
yeah they're know that yeah she thinks
I'm an idiot so anyway I get a lot of
emails because I've been doing password
stuff for long time ago I emails from
people they want me to check out their
password solution I know yeah that's
great you know I love looking at new
stuff and just I've worn them though
that if this is a graphical passwords
scheme I'm not going to be nice it's
always a graphical passwords game so and
I'm never nice but um this you know I I
hate them I've done two point where is
really hate them you know I hate hearing
about in my everyday there's new pet
graphical passwords games I also hate
all the biometric stuff I mean come on
logging in with your feet you know
there's so much time so much time you I
know la vie metrics but I hate how much
time is spent and how much effort spent
logging out your knuckles your feet or
you know way you walk or whatever and
it's I think it's just it a huge waste
when there's so many other problems that
we need to solve and that we haven't
solved all these years another thing
that's kind of knowing is seen how many
mobile authentication after are and
they're good you know there's a you know
most of them are many of them are solid
and for this thing is there we need a
thousand of them it owned and each one's
proprietary each one they don't work
with each other and each one requires a
major investment in the company so
that's kind of what I hate there's some
more things I hate press releases the
password
killer no title research paper novel
approach is never a novel approach
article to you the fray passwords are
passe in the title killa password and i
really hate the stock photo is
everywhere I mean you don't see an
article about this anyway stock photo
yeah and sometimes it's red yeah and
sometimes it's reverse there's one
that's reverse so okay so I've got this
uhm tae and i am going to give it away
what contest here if anyone can tell me
who or what or anything about the first
password hacker or when what a story or
guess Holly go way back more Wi-Fi
direct good back in the 60s right you
are correct so you get a passport I so
it started off this guy right here came
up with password scheme the first path
work youth on a computer and you know it
seems time sharing they had a way they
kept on file separate the way they kept
track of the time used on the computer
while the Allen sure that's a Corvette
robot oh yeah yeah and um the allen sure
with one of the students there one of
the doctor says he needed more time here
to used up all his time on the system so
he found out there was a file i see here
grab my thing
you accnt da secret was was a file that
had all the passwords in it and even
though he didn't have access to the file
he they had this system where when you
wound up 11 run a print job and you know
usually took a while to queue at the
print job and get it all printed and get
it you know go ahead and get it yeah you
did submit a punch card with it your
account name the name of the file you
wanted and then you go and pick it up
later so he submitted that file he's a
system account name and when picked up
the password file later in a little
pronunciate all accounts so that's a
first Patrick okay so graphical
passwords graphical passwords so we
spend like I said a lot of time working
on graphical passwords other people
found a long time but you know there's a
okay I pick on graphical passwords
because it's a good example of going
astray and with the way we do a research
and 17,000 911 patents for graphical
passwords and image-based passwords 7m
think about that 17 thousand nine
hundred and low and pat pat I mean I
think we thought that one through all
the way okay I mean we don't really need
any more practical passport scheme
there's about 2,100 us research of
scholarly documents oh the written about
graphical passwords games I mean it's
just we spent way too much time
figuring out problems that we really
weren't really problems in the first
place and really don't need solving so
the flood okay well first of all that
graphical password schemes are usually
there's like just presented several 10
minutes already wow several images you
pick one or two that I got a lot more
ranting to do come on or you that's
right anyone wants to hear any more
round Chanukah okay so when you pick a
picture or you pick some points on a
picture or you draw a shape or something
like that and now the flaws are that
it's a small key space now a lot of
people argue these you see lose these
formulas in the research papers that say
how large is key space is the wrong okay
the it's the T space is small most of
them they're based on visual
interactions okay so you've limited
people with with with with visual
impairments you have issues with if
there's if you don't have a graphical
screen or graphical environment you
can't use it with an API or anything
like that another problem is they're not
exact so they have to be a little bit
fuzzy if you don't hit the right spot on
the screen or whatever or if you do
allow that then they're there I mean if
you're not exact that was a new one is
basically saying you know it's like a
pad for where they let you enter it in
one letter off and they'll still accept
it pay or they're too exact where you
get a lot of false negatives and
rejected for attaching issues a lot of
times the these schemes are based on
giving that you have to debate some
logic where it has to make a decision
whether to let you in or not you can't
just take like a password and hash it
and compare it so there are fighting on
the scheme of our issues on storing the
hash they actually have to store and
encrypted form the actual answers or
open the shoulder surfing less
convenient sometimes they can it
actually easier to type in a past
word then picking pictures from the
screen or whatever moving the mouse
around and there's still a password
they're still knowledge-based and still
have a lot of the same weaknesses of
passwords now the we've got okay so one
of the things we can do it's been 50
years and we've got we really haven't
made a lot of progress on passwords I
mean we've come up with some things
we've come up with some some good ideas
and some of the policies are you know
things have relaxed and we people are a
little bit smarter admins a little
smarter out how to do things I remember
once on a mailing list was about about
15 years ago where I I talked about the
password length is all that really
matters are talking about complexity
character sets all seven I said you know
if you have the password long enough
that really doesn't matter which
characters are in there I got so much
hate mail from that I mean jeez so
anyway it's taken a while just to get
that and you know just the basic things
down I mean we're still having secret
questions where they asking for your eye
color and it says it's we still haven't
really got the basics down let alone the
more difficult problems so I was
thinking that it would help if we had
more standardization give us figure out
really what our problems are what our
weaknesses are and go from there that
way that way we know where we need to
spend our effort authentication
standards there's a number of unk we may
be her the Fido Alliance little midas
security coalition motto and there's all
these competing groups trying to develop
standards of course the phyto alliances
we've got a quite a bit of industry
support but they're also a lot of other
groups trying to establish these
standards but what we really need our
metrics the these alliances are mostly
AP is for communicating but the metrics
are really what tell us what is what's
wrong with our systems verify there are
mechanisms for authenticating really
Oregon working the way we think would
they work its guidance for developers
that helps you when you want to purchase
products and you understand really just
you quantify the strengths and
weaknesses of any system oh come on
there we go so no way okay that's her
okay that this is what happens realize
standards okay so this is a patent I
found one day fingerprints you know
people don't like fingerprints so hey
someone thought have a great idea put a
fingerprint on a device you know a
little fake fingerprints so you've got
you've got a fingerprint but a device
problem is you instead of getting the
best of both worlds you get the worst of
both worlds but so anyway one of the
groups is ID ESG and they have done a
lot of work on standardizing come up
these metrics coming up with these
principles guiding principles for house
authentication to happen it's still
really unorganized it's still really
much very much in sipping see but it's
the one I've seen that has the most
potential I think we we as a community
should participate in that and guide the
the guide that the way the direction we
take on authentication but beyond what
they they've established we've got
accessibility issues I mean my
ten-year-old doesn't have a cell phone
my father-in-law doesn't have a cell
phone would play would not use anyway
there's so you know authentication going
through SMS isn't going to work with him
there's legal issues there's ethical
considerations for example using
biometrics and rolling people without
their knowledge facebook has done this
where they they use behavioral analysis
to see if to understand it's really you
working on work on the side or
interacting the site that's kind of a
light example but the company could for
example take pictures as you're walking
in and use that enroll you basically
into a authentication system without
your thought your knowledge there's also
cultural issues there's also issues like
some people just don't like touching
things
people touched so a fingerprint scanner
may not be a good idea for people like
that so design patterns o mighty no time
okay so another thing we need to do is
we establish well-defined design
patterns we've done things you know
we've said you've got to use a hash
assault with your hash you've got a
certain process as you go through with
your password resets but I mean we're
still having problems with secret
questions all these things token and
attribute whining is another area where
you don't see a lot of talking about
that multiple T factor authentication
people are still doing that wrong what
you have course multi-factor uh there's
an issue here with usability like I said
my father-in-law or my ten-year-old I
mean do we have we don't really have
systems or they'll really work for
people like that who don't really
understand computer very well or who are
too young or may have other disabilities
we don't really have good ways to scale
that though that user bait user base
scalability I have a my key chain has
like 10 tokens on it you know Hardware
tokens because you know i got i like
harbor tokens but come on does anyone
else like hard work tokens so uh you
know that's only going to go so far you
can only have so many Hardware tokens
and to really have that security you've
got us have some kind of way to make
this work on a user scalable basis lost
recovery recovering from losing your
token or the token breaking a token
wearing down and a lot of companies
allow multiple tokens but they only let
you use one at a time you can choose and
they support different methods but they
only let you pick one it would be nice
if I could use a hardware token white
log in my computer home a different
token white login homework and maybe a
different token 1 i'm like a
authentication a Google Authenticator
number
the top be number wherever when I log in
from my phone I mean it would it would
be nice to be able to have multiple
tokens one thing that google supports is
having multiple tokens when you log in
so if you lose one you can have a backup
one to recover so if multiple multi
factors it would be nice table to be
able to have more than one token if we
want it but the thing is that we really
haven't established guidelines for how
to do this and you know that we haven't
really said you need to support multiple
tokens you need a support you know this
this minnow amount of security just like
with LastPass I mean you you log in with
your Ubik hear something like that but
on your phone you just log in with your
phone and it goes you know it lets you
log in with that you don't have to
provide the second factor presumably
your phone is the second factor but you
can lose your phone so well I miss all
my good stories so wound okay here's a
good story this is my conclusion is a
story so I used to play around my kids
and have them tight passwords behind my
back like common passwords and I guess
what the password was so one time years
ago I was I was doing a sales meeting
with a client and the admin gets up and
and I was actually passing a kidney
stone at a time so I was kind of like
this with man but he types in this
password and I recognize it you know
admin 123 I mean I I knew this password
so well sound of it who type it
sometimes it sounds really distinct um
hi set up my shirt password admin 123 it
was like quiet per second awesome the
whole room burst out laughing this admin
turn bright red but yeah good skill to
have um so I didn't get the job though
the thing so anyway I mean we're a world
of Secrets we've got passwords but we
really haven't developed much I mean you
read them these old mailing lists and
they're saying having the same problems
that have the same discussion that we're
having today we really haven't figured
us out and we kind of as a community
need a he
contribute and guide the thinking and
the guide the research and and write
blog posts and and and establishes where
where we should put in our effort what
are the problems that are unsolved that
we really haven't solved yet that's it
ten questions I I noticed that you use
the example dog's name many times
without if we're telling us the dog's
name is it is that because you still use
absolute ass or something some password
you just can't change dog 2015 yeah I'm
when way past that sorry I was just
gonna ask you the name of your dog 15
music there you go yep well I think mark
should stick around for the last walk as
well I could be interesting well since
we're doing light hard questions what
are your views on the use of janitors
key rings for multiple physical tokens
no that's a great idea that's about
where i'm but i'm going to move into
yeah I had one of my son's I he just
loses everything we've gone through like
six cell phones I gave him a toga you
know my kids that you know it they have
to deal with me so I gave him a token to
log into the county he lost it I mean
she's so I put a chain on it this is a
big long chain I'm the next one I gave
him a big long chain and he still wasn't
so I gave up yeah I should have I should
have gotten one of those janitor of
things so mark actually has done a book
on passwords I remember purchasing that
online just how to read it and I wrote
that ten years ago and it's all still
valid much of it still valid today I
mean I I have no better answer than and
then you on like white we continue
getting stuck but one thing I have
observed is that a common thread is when
people start talking about you know how
to get rid of passwords is thing they
always started sinking in the in the
absolute wrong place and making a long
list of what's wrong with passwords if
you want to get rid of them you be far
better off making a list of what's right
with passwords because it gives you a
better understanding of you know I hate
these guys have beaten everyone who's
climbed into the ring
with them in the last you know quarter
century I make a list of everything
that's right with them gives you a
better idea yeah exactly and that's it's
always passwords are broken so hey let's
get rid of them let's replace them and
then the first logical conclusions what
if what if we can log in with pictures
but see the thing is if you're going to
do pitchers you might as well just think
of you know the pictures you know Apple
dog whatever battery and write out the
words as your password if you're going
to have to remember what it was anyway
you might as well use as your passwords
huh what's that okay blue yeah I'll do
that having much of both movies like you
know war games and sneakers and
obviously both you have watched those
movies multiple times and you haven't
shame on you and what's the password
what's the password for dr. Falcons
pro/5 dork that's about Joshua Joshua
joshing I'm okay and then what we
seriously need to do you know a password
population size for trivia help yeah how
about Trinity's password in the matrix
no one Zion Zion with the zero course
you know he's a lead that in here 10
even German Hawker in the cliff Stoll
book at the Cuckoo's egg he's gonna
Benson hodgetts I just yeah do Benson
out you use a jizz on different accounts
nuclear launch codes for the u.s. until
it is shy a 0 s 80 s yep Roger Patrick I
peered everyone days ok so again thank
you much
[Applause]