hi guys thanks for being here we know
this is the last talk you guys must be a
big fan for actually with you actually
so our topic today is the overlooked
tactics for attacking activity actually
first we will do an introduction so my
name is Hao Wang I'm the manager for the
UI cyber security practiced and the
primary focus on attack on a penetration
testing we help present in science
aisaka troopers before hi my name is joe
thin rotten and I'm a manager at the UI
cybersecurity practice primary focus on
tapping pen has been dissent at ers day
and troopers and I'm Josh pretty much
the same thing also focused on attacking
pin anyway just a quick disclaimer none
of the ideas or content opinions
anything in here is shared supported
orang dos endorsed by our employers and
then just just to level set what we're
talking about today
this isn't focused on a specific CVE the
exploitation that we're talking about
within within this presentation is
really focused on a lot of the
overlooked methods that we've identified
as we've gone through the process of
attacking red forest so just up front we
want to thank a number of individuals
that they're probably not here but just
call out a lot of their tools and their
research is actually what's laid the
groundwork for really laid the
groundwork and enabled us to kind of
focus on on utilizing key aspects of
their research in order to to do our
jobs really so the agendas we're gonna
pretty much give a high-level overview
of what a hardened Active Directory
environment really is then a couple of
use cases where we've been able to
successfully compromise an environment
like that and then ultimately
sum-sum enhancement on the backend so
just an overview I I think the term red
forest gets thrown out a lot but that's
really what we're talking about here
it's formally referred to as the
enhanced security administrative
environment this this concept is is
really multi-tiered the first is to try
to provide a hardened administrative
environment that is standalone and then
the second is to try to tear and
segregate Active Directory objects to
try to contain an attacker within a
specific zone so the the primary concept
it's a three-tier model the first is in
interior 0 we're talking about those
that have administrative access over the
forest domain administrators domain
controllers anything that would allow
for forests or domain wide compromised
the tier 1 is is usually server admins
and this applications cloud admins and
then tier 2 is focused on workstation
and minutes administrators all of this
is is privileged segregation this is
focused on the administers of these
different environments and not
necessarily on the specific users within
it so high level overview pretty much
you know if you're in a certain tier you
would have the ability to interactively
administer that specific tier but there
are a series of controls that prevent
you from moving down a tier or moving up
a tier the idea behind this is to try to
contain an attacker so if if an
environment is compromised and it's on a
workstation level there isn't a
privilege escalation up to a server tier
or if it's if it's done on the server
level there is a privilege escalation up
to that of a domain administrator so the
the we've talked about you know
segregating tearing those objects the
other element to this is really
creating a administrative force that's
isolated from the production forest a
lot of this is usually done with in
addition to the forest being creative is
usually done also with network access
control so there's limitations in place
even between the production tiers and
then ultimately with the administrative
force and the the thought is that no
production Active Directory admin or
group would have access to this red
forest and so all all administrative
accounts are really managed through you
know some sort of password management
solution and then a lot of times we see
multi-factor in place and so that that's
really those are the primary tenets of
this model so if you're a pen tester and
they've architected this to limit
communication between these different
tiers or these different zones and you
know usually you're able to get let's
say workstation admin or you're able to
get a server admin how do you ultimately
compromise the domain how do you how do
you get that level of access that
ultimately allows you to move wherever
you need to go within the environment
and a lot of times this becomes an issue
especially if you're targeting a
segregated environment once you've gone
through production and let's say you're
you're focused on an ot environment or a
skate environment how do you go through
the process of actually targeting that
specific environment a lot of times you
need certain credentials within the
environment and domain level compromise
allows allows you to gather some of that
and use that context to move where you
need to go so for this for the sake of
this presentation we'll be primarily
focused on that that tier 0 within
within production network how do you get
to that level of domain admin compromise
yeah so next topic will basically talk
about something called the shadow at a
new account so like first you will ask
like what is a shadow at a new account
right so here we are meaning shadow
atamira are the account that the Union
Network like that are always overlooked
by enterprise just because those are
count don't belong to any powerful
activity Electric group okay so we will
highlight a few things here the first
one is the account who are enough to
make me enterprise admin button they
have something called the DC sync right
or someone can have full control to
either root domain object or admin SD
holder so first DC sync right so for
those of you who don't know about what
the DC sync is so basically this is
thinking essentially allow you to use
impersonate your own computer as a
domain controller to replicate
credentials from other legitimate domain
controllers okay
so to perform a DCC attack within Active
Directory
basically you need the two permissions
the first one is replication directory
change the second one is a replication
directly change at all okay and so just
based on our experience we have seen a
lot of misconfigured applications or
some applications require disease
information we will just like a
highlight of view of Lake issues there
may be a lot we don't want to use time
here to go through everything we will
just talk about sharepoint and either ad
sync service okay so for microsoft
sharepoint so if we want to use your
opponent you actually with you actually
so basically you need to set up
something called a user profile service
account so what that this account do is
going to synchronize all the user
profile change information between
Active Directory and SharePoint
environment so it's a mixture
everything is synchronized so just per
Microsoft the requirement you just need
a replication you actually change
permission in order for this service
account to be fully functional but what
we have
seen in the past people always given all
the food permission to this account
including most directory change and the
directory change on all permission so
it's just create an instance right so
what's the attacker compromises the
SharePoint so we're like out this
service account and I can they can use
that account to do deceasing we retrieve
all the password hash from domain
controllers okay so this is another
example right we we understand a lot of
enterprise they try to migrate their
local ad to Azure cloud right so to do
that technically you need to set up a
azure ad sync service and so in order to
make sure that the service is a
functional you need to have a service
account right and by default Microsoft
will require you gave the DCC
information to that account so just in
case right you compromise that either a
distinct server in your previous domain
then you you can own the entire ad so
like we understand those things has been
covered by a lot of people in the past
so we just want to highlight something
here because I think after this session
we will talk about exchange which would
require a lot of knowledge we are
talking about here
so for the who control fluid domain
object so we just talked about DC thing
right so if you find some account which
has a full control to the root domain
object like domain.com right so then you
can potentially also how the DC sync
arrived to retrieve all the credentials
from domain controller just because the
show
also included the DCC information okay
the last thing we want to cover in this
topic is the atom ESB holder so as you
guys know right so people has been
talking about at me as holder for the
past few years and primarily they use
that as a persistence mechanism to meet
in access and I say what you actually
environment but whether we want to
highlight here you can actually use the
atom est holder object to ask you later
privilege to compromise the entire
domain
yeah so for those of you who don't know
what Adam est
there is basically it is an object
located in the system partition of
Active Directory and that the cool part
is the the ACL of the admin is the
holder object is used as a template to
replicate all the permissions to all the
protected domain group when we talk
about group I think in kuru domain admin
group include the enterprise admin group
so it means if you find a similar
account that has full control to add me
as the holder object you can potentially
add as any other account to the domain
admin group or enterprise admin group so
for for admins the whole they are think
of we come primarily look for three
permissions the first one is a few
control second one is the write
permission the third one is a modified
permission so if you have control all
read permission basically you can you
can either whatever user account you
want into whatever group you want okay
if you have a modified information
there's a little bit of difference so
basically you need to give one account
full control for admin as Adam est
holder and then you use that account to
give other account access to the
sensitive group like we will cover all
the details later so we have a diagram
to layout I know it's probably a little
bit confusing here so next topic we will
talk about exchange okay
so first question how many of you are
using exchange in your enterprise
environment including 65 office 365 ok
so then you probably have issues here ok
so the first thing we want to cover is
like a lot of people are doing research
about the exchange especially for the
past two years and the Microsoft even
released some some notification right
and they are saying there are some
privilege escalation vulnerability or
issues with the exchange and people can
leverage that to compromise the entire
forest and but like it's really hard to
find all the technical details online or
from the website so in this talk we will
highlight step by step about how what do
you need to do in order to ask you later
privileged from a regular to me user
account to to made me okay so as you
know actually exchange user permission
model color row based access control
since 2010 okay so what the role based
access can show that it actually like
more like at least to privileged model
to manage other permissions within ad
and so within row based access control
solo artifact more for the job
responsibilities instead of you how to
create a specific ACL for a specific
user such as exchange 2007 and also from
exchange 2010 there are two new groups
the first one color exchange windows
permission the second one called
exchange trust take a subsystem so we
can call the first one awp and the
second one is ets so just as you can see
from the diagram here and so basically
the parent group is WP exchange of
windows permission and under that that
there is a child group called exchange
trustee the subsystem and under that the
system account of exchange servers are
actually members of flows group okay and
the so in addition to that so ewp also
has a lot of direct interaction with
activity actually object something like
a write permission to some sensitive
object within AD and that the exchange
trust a subsystem basically it managed
all the object with inside of exchange
okay so under this is another screenshot
so once you run that group for those two
group name or within your ad environment
you will find out microsoft to tell you
those two groups have a lot of rice
basically it can modify or change and
they exchange or act to write actually
what you actually object so we did some
research on this so basically we set up
with our testing environment we stand up
exchange 2010 2013 2016 okay and as a
result and so we found the issue here so
the exchange windows permission group
WP always granted with modified
permission for the root domain object of
your domain in case your domains
domain.com okay as well as a child
object so what does that mean okay so
let's say if the ewp has modified
permission to the root domain object it
means there are children like the
members of that group in this case the
system account of exchange servers they
will automatically have those permission
okay so if if like someone can have
modified permission to the domain root
object like we mentioned before what you
can do you can do a distinct attack
right so it means you can use loads
exchange system account grant with our
user account you want with the DCCC
information and then you can you can
retrieve some credentials from domain
controller so this is the tag path right
it's pretty straightforward
so first stab you compromise the
exchange server and you get the system
access on exchange and then you use that
access to grant domain user account with
certain permission you want in this case
we will just use DC sync and then you
carry two password hash mmm so there
article few attack mattered the first
well we want to highlight here's power
view okay so to do this attacker with
how to be under the assumption we got
the exchange server access already as a
local enemy or domain admin as running
as a local added me on that box okay and
so what you can do if you get the
machine account hash of actions over you
can just pass the hash right or you can
use double windows credential editor or
mimic as you can do that then you can
load the power of you module okay which
will be running on the user context of
the NT system account okay and then you
can you can leverage that that rights to
send this information to the domain user
account and the perform that this is
thinking attack so we will have a demo
here to show you how you actually can do
this
so first though we log into it them to
make each other we try to create a color
red team okay it's just like a regular
domain user account it doesn't have any
special permission to the route to my
object
yeah so whatever we are doing here we
just want to show this silicon it
doesn't have any rights and the
privilege
okay then we're locked into another
server which is the exchange of silver
as local item in the account name or the
exchange so it's just like a local
attorney account it's no domain account
it only has the local admin rights on
that an exchange server and now we are
going to use PSA exact to kick off
powershell process and because the
reason we are using PS exact here we
just want to run in the context of an t
system on the on that exchange server
okay so that you can use that and write
to grant permission to domain user
account then we know the power view so
there there's a module within power view
how to get a domain object ACL so you
can use that module to grant disease
information to domain user account in
this case we try to are granted the
permission to the red team team account
we just created
okay so we go back to our domain
controller display we are going to check
if we successfully added and a new
permission for that Red Team account
so we found that the red team account
and as you can see it has all the
replication directors directory change
and the directory change of our
permission okay so it means it can to DC
sync right so just so for proof of
concept right from our packing box which
when to do a DC sync with secured out
with that red team account and as you
can see we are trying to dump credential
from one of the domain controller okay
okay so there's like another attack
method right we just mentioned power
view there's also like a way you can use
the native exchanger PowerShell to
accomplish the same work okay so what
you'll need to do right so you can
either RDP to the exchange server and or
you can use a PS exact and remotely
access to the computer to the exchange
server the point is to get an NT system
shell on that exchange box right and
then what you can do you can use the
building power powershell a displays
Exchange Management Shell to add the
user permissions okay so this way is
very Styles right because whatever you
are doing in here the PS exactly is now
Stiles okay you can use some other stuff
like scheduled tasks right you can be
creative but for the PowerShell script
you are using here it's the native
powershell within the exchange server
okay so it's really hard for him to
detect that and and then you can still
give the permission to ad account and
then you can accomplish your attack pass
right so after you you finish you can
use it like another module within this
PowerShell to remove the permission you
just added to that user cap right just
to clear your your your trees and so
first action 2010 the command is a
little bit different because the
exchange like snapping module you need
to change the name to e 2 0 1 0 we also
leads to the command here so after the
talk we will share the tag you can
retrieve them so we just want to show
another demo for this
okay so it's the same thing that's also
for now login to the domain controller
we try to create some new user in this
case we call that red team one
and we also create another one caller ID
team - so we created two accounts and
they are brand-new and they only belong
to the domain user group there are no
special permission assigned for this
account - the route 80 object
this feather
yeah so we just want to hide up here
there are no permissions for those
account yet and then again we log into
our exchanges over local admin account
exchange again this item is just a local
and in the account it's not a me account
so it only has to look about in the
access of that a specific exchange over
and then we we use PS exactly again to
obtain the ante system alter RT access
and then we will try to use the built-in
PowerShell module from exchange to grant
permission to the red team one with DC
sync so just to simplify the process we
put like the PowerShell command into one
line so just call me need the first line
is is to add one per min permission the
second line is to add any other
permission required a faux TC thing and
then we go back to the domain controller
again we just want to check if we have
successfully added us permission
so the the reason you you see a
different interface here because we are
doing this demo in exchange 2006 the
first time we showed is in exchange 2013
so as you can see the the two required
formation are created
so just for proof of concept we try to
retrieve the credential from the main
controller by using the red team while
account we just carotid disease
information with
yeah as you can see it works so which I
start the hash from domain controller so
before we talk to the next topic we just
want to highlight the process so the the
whole thing is really easy right what do
you need to do you need to get a local
admin access or system ante access 12
the exchange server and then you can
potentially compromise the entire ad so
we found this is really interesting
right so it has this in the exchange
2013 and we found it out exchange trust
a subsystem group actually granted with
modified permission for the admin as the
holder object okay so we only found this
in 2013 but you may find this on 2016
because there's an issue for exchange
right so if you upgraded from to
something search in 2016 the permission
may carry okay so if you have modified
permission on the admin SD holder what
you can do right so just like I talked
before right you can essentially I use
the system account of Exchange Server to
a son like a full control on the admin
as the holder object and then you can
use that to my user account with the
Chotu to add a user into the
domain admin group or enterprise ethnic
group so again like you also can use the
native exchange PowerShell to do this
okay well what you need to do you just
need to PS exact to the exchange machine
to cat it's an empty system shell and
then you can correct the generic all
permission to the account you want okay
and though we can show the last demo
here so again like we try to create two
account from domain controller in this
case those two account are green team
one and the current team two
yeah and again we are just trying to
make sure those account doesn't have
special control on the Adamus dijo
they're object and then they only belong
to the domain user group
okay then when we log in back to our
exchange so we're in this case it's the
same thing we're logging as the Oklahoma
account okay
and as you can see this icon only has
local any access to this box and then
like we did we will I will change our
like approach a little bit so we try to
PS exact remotely from our attack
machine to the exchange server so just
give you a different view about how to
perform this attack and as you can see
we use the built-in PowerShell module
just one line to confirmation to the
current email account so it should have
fook and chose to the Adam est holder
object
yeah so and as you can see so we added
the joke for the Adamus they
hold their object so atomicity if you
have full control to that then you can
have show - to my enemy group so
it means you probably can add another
user helping to Tommy Adam indirectly so
for now is the way we added the green
team wanna come into the exchange server
because we just want to ruin us as the
current my account - to open like a user
management to 2k so now this activity
vector user management toolkit is run by
the current my account with the for adam
EST holder information and then we go to
the domain admin group so quick as i at
the button i know we in this case we
added a green team to account me into
the domain admin group and just to
validate that so we run that group to
madami you can see the Green Team to
account as in the dominant group
okay
okay so there's a third group in
exchange and color organization
management although this group does not
have direct interaction with activity
rectory object but and also but it can
be used to add members to those two
groups we mentioned before the AWP and
the ETS so if in case you compromise
wealth the organization management
account you can add any user to Lowe's
to group just to perform the same attack
we mentioned before okay so just to
summarize we did all the testing from
2007 2016 2 2016 in the exchange
environment ok
and the most of the attack especially
for those privileged escalation attack
work in 2010 2013 2016 the only reason
because it didn't work out 2007 because
during that time windows exchange 2007
was not using the low based access
control and the lowest new group didn't
exist during that time ok people may ask
if we are using office 365 are really
secure job the answer may be yes maybe
no right so but your most of the case
even you have office 365 running in the
cloud you have to have a local action is
over just to maintain all the user
profiles so there are still where we
were a high risk here ok our next topic
here is about leveraging the word
civilization platform in backup solution
to attack the heart and Active Directory
environment
so most organization pretty sure most
organizations implement the
virtualization technology basically
leveraging the VMware or other platform
to variety the server so most of the
server that you have here probably one
of them would could be domain
controllers could be exchange server and
then those administer count within the
worker relation platform they might not
receive the same attention
as those domain domain admin account so
what we like to highlight is the if the
company forgot to treat this admin as a
higher tier as well they could
potentially be used to compromise the
organization so basically if if somebody
compromised and get the VM admin account
they could potentially download the free
emeritus or extracting the password hash
from the operating system directory so
just to show you many organization may
not aware that they have a lot of admin
account in their recenter environment
the the audit may not show up if you can
look at the console there might be a lot
of nested grouping in those account and
then and there's account usually have
access to multiple data center and then
a lot of the the VM deciding within
those data center another trick is if
you need to jump to different tier
environment na Murray usually we have
firewall to segment most of the secure
environment from one another however if
the organization leverage is
virtualization platform the usually
configured network in this environment
so attacker might be able to target the
console to lock in directory at the
console level and bypass that
restriction
similarly this this is the some of the
way we want to show how we how an
attacker go to extract the password hash
from the VMDK at this so basically the
this assumption is the vCenter host the
one of the domain controller image in
the environment the attacker might move
rattori on the network to obtain the VM
happening
then chose so we come up with a
tweetable way you can go and extract the
doors image the first way is to use just
a plain GUI that used for managing the
risk fear or recenter login to either we
have in the face of the client could
browse through a data store rocket the
target domain controller image and those
can particularly guess from the naming
convention or standard documentation
within the organization next is to
leverage the command line so we may also
provide a lot of extensive PowerShell
command line to interact with the
westernization environment so in this
case we can use the same command line
that the admin used to copy out the
domain controller image or other
critical servers however the first two
method I just mentioned it may not
always works if they're they're running
instant it might cause some resource
config so what I've from my experience
on one of the herbal way to receive
images soon whereas some of the
commercial two or three where to
basically create a snapshot of the
target VM and into a lab kit does a vm
directly to the your machine however if
this attack may acid isn't responding if
they have a traffic monitoring
capability on the organisation they
might be able to spot the the bandwidth
spike if somebody download like 100 kick
updater move between swish this might be
one of the attack that could they could
potentially spot on so one attacker can
access to those VM image on that they
need to if they need to access those
file system they have to merge those
files so within the
VMware SDK or some command line that you
can use to merge the file together and
leverage the forensic - such as OSF
mouth-to-mouth those this and then
browse to the file system alternatively
you can also use the command in Linux to
mount those filesystem and gain access
to any es dot did and system hive to
extract the password hash within the
active directory the another way is we
found commonly file this is not specific
to a certain product but some time if if
you you know that target organization
use certain type of backup software to
back up the database of domain
controller or targets we target those
system basically trying to get admin
credential for those system and then
basically try to locate the disk that
the admin use
oftentimes some of these might left on
the NFS or is kasi storage that might
not be pop reset permission so as an
attacker we could potentially leverage
this method to extract the credentials
that way so as you can see from
screenshot is very thorough
once you know some documentation look up
the way to back up then you leverage the
same feature that admin used to steal
the image
excuse me
alright so if you haven't started to
notice the theme in some of these paths
typically we're trying to find any sort
of gray area in terms of the boundaries
between these tiers or areas where a
certain tier a certain tier wasn't
necessarily as protected as there were
certain settings in place that were
overlooked in this case one of the
things that we've we've utilized in the
past is is actually leveraging certain
endpoint technologies so if you have a
tiered model and you've segregated out
these these different machines how does
a pen tester try to move up or how does
an attacker try to target that that
higher level tier and one of the ways
you can do it is through endpoint
products essentially if the tier if the
different tiers are sharing this same
management console be it you know an
anti-virus solution or SCCC SCCM you can
weaponize that in order to try to grant
or gain access to a tier that you may
not be able to interact with otherwise
so in this case one of the you know an
attack example that that we've used in
the past is essentially an anti-virus
solution or endpoint protection was
being utilized on different tiers and
and and that tear the those different
tiers were all sharing the same
management console so the thought was
how do you can we use this endpoint to
essentially push a payload and and use
the environment to push a payload
ultimately to try to execute something
on a domain controller or gain access
that we wouldn't otherwise have and so
the way we go about doing this within
within set
is we we create a hosts integrity policy
and so you'd go through the process this
assumes you have you've targeted the the
antivirus admin and you have this level
of access but you'd create a new policy
and within that policy you would create
a custom requirement for that new host
integrity policy and within there you
can add a function and load in whatever
payload you want in this case we've
typically used VB script and so what we
what we do is create two scripts one to
essentially add a user account and then
a second to add it to the domain
administrators group and then we would
assign that to something on a different
tier so you from them from the
management console you would assign this
policy to a tier that you wouldn't have
access to and ultimately have it execute
on behalf of you in order to try to get
to that tier zero because ultimately I
mean at the end of the day these tiers
are designed to be segregated and you're
not supposed to have that interaction
and so you're just grasping at the
different pieces that may exist within
an environment that would allow you to
do that
just just a quick demo so we we created
a user or we you can see that we did we
do not have a user on that domain
controller and so what we do is we log
in to SAP and then essentially we're
we're creating a host integrity policy
and within that you can see this
vbscript push function and so in here
you can you can we can insert this the
script that we ultimately want to run
the first is going to be the creation of
a user account and so earlier we
validated that account didn't exist
we're going to try to add a regular
domain user account so so once we create
it the the second thing we're gonna do
is then at that point essentially try to
use this an attempt to add a add this
user account that we just created this
Red Team one user account that we just
created to the domain administrators
youth group
and so usually so here we are assigning
that host integrity policy and in this
in this example it doesn't it doesn't
doesn't really matter but we would be
assigning it here to that domain
administrator or to that higher level
tier that we're looking to move up into
okay
and then here we're gonna validate
whether or not that user exists and
obviously you can see that it does exist
that now belongs to the domain
administrators group
okay typically we see SCCM in tier zero
it's very rare that you don't see it in
tier zero but that being said some of
the things we run across are within tier
zero while it may exist into your zero
the network traffic that's allowed to
interact with it isn't segregated and it
isn't restricted to what we deemed to be
appropriate and so while it's something
that is rare and you probably won't be
able to use it another way similar to
the exploitation is to use SCCM in order
to essentially push a payload to a
specific target and so what we do is we
create a connection with SCCM and then
create an application within it and
within this application we would have
that VB script and then we would deploy
that to the specific target that we were
looking to target in this case you know
it may be tier one may be tier zero
there's another way of doing it I I
don't know how many of you are familiar
with PowerShell mafia's power SCCM but
essentially these are the commands that
could cut that could do the same thing
create a connection to a CCM creating an
application to be deployed and then and
then ultimately deploy that application
specific to a tier that you're targeting
so at the end of this what can you
really do I think our talk has been
highlighting the fact that you really
need to know who your administrators are
and who those accounts are and those
groups because any sort of overlapping
between them can be exploited to try to
move up those tiers one of the things
that we that it's it's debated but one
of the things that we see is how network
segmentation should really be applied to
those different layers in some cases we
we see total network segmentation I
think it just needs to be effective for
the environment that you're in a lot of
cases not a lot of traffic is allowed
there's definitely overlaps that we've
seen where something's been applied and
it hasn't they're still allowing some
sort of communication that allows us to
push something up or or interact with
the tier that we really shouldn't we've
highlighted I think through the the
virtualization attacks or the endpoint
attacks that you really need to be sure
what's in your tr0
and what where things should reside the
problem with moving it into you know a
more privileged here is that your attack
surface moves up in terms of what can be
exploited in order to move across that
tier but the the downside with not
moving it in is essentially there are
these these access avenues that allow
for rapid escalation privilege
escalation within the environment that I
sound silly but even as we've we've seen
some red forest environments they
haven't they haven't enrolled their
multi-factor across all technologies
that are being utilized so we simply
target the single the single factor
authentication as a way in and it's
usually a pretty quick way and then
obviously if you're using multi-factor
authentication there's pretty explicit
guidance on having at least one break
the glass account that isn't using
multi-factor authentication but a lot of
times there are there's a credential
reuse or some of the accounts that were
created before it was moved into a
tiered model weren't ever rolled and so
you actually have to be worried about
these legacy advant accounts and service
accounts that haven't been rotated do
you have anything okay I think that
concludes our presentation we'll do we
have time for questions or okay any
questions you got five minutes nope
there's one
in the red in the red forest
environments you've seen have you seen
them start from a good position and then
slowly degrade over time and then in
their hygiene or how do you see red
forest start from a good position but
then degrade to one where you can get in
I I would say in some situations the red
forest environment has been deployed as
a result of something that's happened
within the organization so they're
coming from I've seen the term not red I
think they've used an orange or they
they term it something else but they're
they're coming from and this is probably
everywhere they're coming from they're
moving into a red forest rather than
creating it from scratch there's been a
few places that have created it totally
from scratch but a lot of times a lot of
these tears pre-exists and they're
trying to push those push servers into
the tier and so they're the I would say
it's more defined as it moves up the
tiers but in terms of access but from
from my perspective I I think some of
these access avenues just haven't
necessarily or these these attack paths
just weren't part of the configuration
it was very Active Directory focused and
it didn't take into account some of
these other variables that essentially
undermined Active Directory
time for maybe one more if you need to
all right thank you guys very much