okay so so let's get started so my name
is Martin Vigo I'm a product security
lead
I'm from Galicia Spain you haven't been
there go check it out we have the best
seafood in the world I said that in
every talk no one has gone there yet but
I really like research I like scuba
diving and I like gin tonics
if you guys want ask questions later you
know this is a picture of my sister in
me when I was 9 I believe and that was
my first computer I really loved this
picture it's an Amstrad anyone had that
computer I think it was only sold in
Europe yeah really nice and I'm playing
probably the best game ever written in
Spain which is Laval dia del creaming
it's a kind of anthem where I love the
game if you haven't played and you like
of underwear make sure to download it so
question for the audience a have you
left your phone unattended ever like on
the desk going to the bathroom or on the
coffee okay I knew the audience is gonna
be hostile and I'll raise their hands
okay that's good I'm sure you're in the
live stream so it's like yeah me did you
disable the system in the lock screen by
the way the one on the left is the
Cortana Windows Mobile no one knows
about it it took me a while to find the
icon did you disable notifications on
the lock screen because for example for
in iOS 11 should you use to come by
default now it's not the case so then
there is a question now what can the
system do while the device is locked
which is kinda what this talk is around
what is the things you guys think that
when you say hey Siri and the device is
locked secure encrypted and all that
stuff I can do that you guys think may
be an issue security wise that's the
easiest bypass ever any idea what the
kind of stuff that you could do that you
guys think oh maybe these are some
security consequences phone calls yeah
there could be like you know like
contacts I don't think it gives you I
believe you cannot open a website I
believe airdrop you can activate that's
a good one
another thing that you can do it's a
actually send email thing as a message
so this all started these comes from
like one day I received who uses van
here I guess many of you so I got a text
from my friend we're at a party and he
paid for the Jing so he sent me like you
know he wanted to charge me Brenna
allows you to do that not that not just
that you pay but he can charge it so I
got a text and he was saying hey this
guy wants to charge you 50 bucks reply
to this message with yes or I don't
remember what I had to reply and I was
like interesting because I can do that
from the lock screen right at the time I
had it I could see the preview and
everything so if I can do that if I can
just try to charge someone and answer an
SMS for them then this is what happening
and this is a demo so the device is
locked no there is there is all right so
there I asked Siri Who am I so you will
give me the phone number so that short
code is the one from venmo so what I'm
doing here is I'm actually activating
the being able to pay over SMS on the
victim because it turns out that I found
out the phone so I can reply there and
say activate and you will activate it so
now the victim now I can charge the
victim and I got activated the service
so the victim can pay by replying to an
SMS so on the Left I go to bank more as
an attacker and charge the victim with
the phone number I got in the lock
screen in this case $1 because I don't
have a lot of money so I asked you to
read my latest text so yeah you didn't
have to reply yes I forgot you have to
play with a code yes so I'm replying to
the text
[Music]
that's me trying to be cool and you will
see I will refresh the side and I just
stole one dollar from a device that was
actually locked and theoretically
secured so when I found this out and I
wrote a blog post about it I thought oh
this is very interesting and my website
doesn't have a lot of traffic right I I
write a lot about security but you know
it's not like a top website or anything
and I I went once to look at my Google
Analytics saying this is the top seven
of how the people gets to my site there
is a lot of articles but there is also a
lot of bad people in the world like this
is the top seven people just wants to
steal money and actually I guess I have
the honor or dishonor that if you look
if you search in Google for how to steal
money I think now I'm the third one but
it used to be for one year the first
result in Google if you look up how to
steal money you can test it later so I
guess it's it's an honor so ok so when I
found this out I was like interesting
huh what else can we do right the goal
for me was how can we broaden the impact
and and and help push the the you know
the industry towards like understanding
that SMS is not meant to be a secure
channel for sensitive actions and I
started to look and there is a lot of
things that you can do over SMS you can
reset passwords you can actually
register like whatsapp for example you
don't have a username and password
you've verified that you are the owner
of the phone that you claim by replying
to a text or you can also use it for 2fa
in many services so in this issue with
the SMS I mean I'm not talking about
anything new here so I went to do
searches per year in Google and went
down to 2015 and you see on the Left
2015 2016 2017 2018 always talking about
the same thing we shouldn't be using SMS
for security purposes but no but it's
not that article start there about it
nest itself in one of the drafts then
there was a controversy you guys may be
familiar with it but it was actually
discouraged
or deprecating SMS originally and then
they just discourage it officially and
you probably heard about what happened
with ready that it was recently hack
thing and one of the things that
happened was the two FA was over SMS so
I think there was some sim swap in there
so this is happening this is real we
have been talking about it for years
this happens a lot in security and
nothing gets fixed so my objective now
is to help with the industry to stop
relying on SMS as a secure channel and
this is why I did this talk and I I
wanted to do something that is just yet
another reason to teach SMS so the first
thing I wanted to know is okay I know I
can reset passwords I know two FA is
being used for that I know for
verification purposes so I found this
really cool service that actually lists
all the short codes like you saw for
venmo for services so here I can use
this and try to look at banks that use
it and for what purposes so I can find a
lot of services thanks to this they use
it rather than me just trying to go to
the website set up a username and see
what options I have for two of a
password reset and all that stuff and
this is just a kind of like a alexa top
100 version just a small subset but for
password reset you can do it / SMS in
WordPress Google Netflix Instagram
PayPal Facebook eBay Twitter and
LinkedIn you can do two-factor
authentication the three big ones we
over SMS Microsoft Apple Yahoo you can
do verification what's up in signal
Twilio is a is a VoIP service so
programmatically you can make phone
calls and stuff like that but one of the
things it allows you to do is to own a
caller ID so and you own that caller ID
so basically when you make a phone call
programmatically will display that
number by you verifying that you own a
phone number over SMS and Google Voice
you can have virtual numbers but you
need to tie them to a real number a lot
of scammers use this and you can verify
a phone number you can just start it to
someone else if you do it / SMS into an
attack like I showed with mango so the
conclusion here is there is many
services that use SMS as a secure
channel for sensitive actions and it's
it's used in different
environments for to a verification and
password reset so let's look at that
tack vector right how will it look like
when we try to attack a mobile device
that is locked because in the end this
is what the talk is about it if a mobile
device that is locked that we all feel
like it's encrypted we have the FBI
fighting with Apple because they
supposedly cannot do anything about it
and all this that sense of security that
we'll have when we have a mobile device
locked so the first thing will be to
obtain the victim's email the second one
will be too easy to initiate password
reset in all services because we just so
many of them you can password reset over
SMS we want to obtain the secret code
that is sent over SMS like we saw in
Bergamo and then free leading to the UI
again to complete the password reset and
then we just set the new password and
that's it right so how do we obtain the
victim's email so in this case what we
can do is on a block device we say hey
sent an email to attacker at domain.com
basically an email that the attacker
controls and and you basically will say
that in this case - Siri so we'll send
an email that's how I can get your email
because you cannot get it anymore from
saying Who am I you used to be the case
now it only displays the phone number so
you just ask Siri to send an email and
you receive it in your email so you know
what the email was how do we obtain the
secret codes as we talked about many
people doesn't disable the the preview
of texts in the lock screen and you can
even ask Siri to read the text for you
so you have you have to actively disable
this so you can just see it there so we
have now that if I have physical access
to a locked device I can get these two
pieces of information but we still have
three more which is a we have to
initiate the password reset we have to
complete the password reset with the
codes that we got in the lock screen and
we have to set new passwords so there is
a lot to compromise because we have a
lot of websites that we can compromise
if we have physical access to a locked
device but we don't have we have limited
time may I take five minutes to pee so
if I left my my device on the table
right that's the time you have so we
need automation that's the key
so and that's how I created a wrote a
ransom bot which confirmed ransomware
embalm well I don't have a lot of
creativity that's not one of my
strengths but as you can see it's
basically an app a mobile app in reality
it's a website but I use CSS used to so
you can use it on the on your on your
mobile and the reason is because you may
be walking around and find a phone on
the floor or you want to prank your
friends or you want to just make some
money so you basically what helps you to
do is it automates the entire password
reset process and in this case I started
by using burp and looking at the api's
of like you know Google all that stuff
and it's just very complex because it
changes a lot and the other the other
thing is I was getting hit with captures
all the time because it will kind of
detect that I was doing something not
really in the usual way so I found that
selenium is much better for several
reasons selenium is basically a library
or yeah a library that allows you to do
automation at the UI level and this is
used a lot by developers when you want
to test if I click here here here and
here do I have these CSS buttons with
these colors and stuff like that so this
is super useful not only because now you
don't need to reverse any any api's or
look at verb but it's also super easy
because there is even a plugin for
Firefox that you can literally click
around it record the movement generates
the code for you so it takes me three
minutes to add a new service that I can
that I can compromise to run some bar
because I just use Firefox and I
literally reset a password while that is
recording and generating the code which
is the end all it does is with code it
sells it uses CSS as pointers where okay
this is the text box where you put the
stuff this is the button you click and
stuff like that so super super simple to
make this open-source and just people
can add a lot of new payloads for new
websites so now we have that we cover
all the steps so this is really how it
looks like how ransomware works right we
have on the left side we have the the
victims device which is
locked so you will take that phone or
you found the phone on the floor for
example right you take that phone and
say hey send an email to victims of
ransom at gmail.com which is an email
you as an attacker all about subject
saying content that is just to fill up
everything that city ones in ransom val
is monitoring their email in this case I
use Gmail as a proof of concept and I'm
just monitoring that all the timing as
soon as a new email get it will take
that the others where it's been sent
from and it's fitted into the app
automatically it starts to initiate the
password resets for all those services
using a UI automation so I will start to
see in the victims phone the codes
start to come in so all I have to do is
to read them from the screen enter in in
the UI of ransom bar and click town and
then it will go it will complete the the
password reset process and it will add
the password that you want and now you
just compromised the person's digital
life in two three minutes and now you
can go and demand money for it don't do
that though so I'm gonna do a demo now
and I want to introduce you to Tom
promise
compromise is a play of words of
compromise they Priscilla helped me here
again creativity is not our strength but
basically this is the victim writing
he's a millennial because he uses Gmail
as an email as his email account right
and you know he likes to tweet and he
uses Facebook so he uses social networks
as well and he has a website in
WordPress and you know when he wants to
pay his friends he uses paper and and he
has all that stuff of his phone setup so
so he's like many of us actually
actually I integrated the demo here so
before I started on the right you it's a
simulator that basically it's a
simulator that basically has the ransom
below that on the left side is the
victims phone that is locked
gonna be here so you seeing email it's
gonna show now Tom promise' gmail.com
because the app is monitoring the email
so I only have to click that of course I
can automate this as well so I don't
have to interact with the app at all but
for the demo I want you guys to see what
is going on so you see that now you're
doping a lot of browsers and I'm not
doing anything this is automatic you'll
see it putting the the password that I
want it selects the the SMS password
research over SMS after putting the
email not the password and now I will
start to receive codes and I did that I
did it did that for all the websites so
you see that SMS as I started to come in
and because that person didn't disable
the preview on the lock screen I can see
those codes so all I need to do now is
to go and the tool is waiting for those
10 codes to complete the password
process so I only have to add it there
more SMS are going to come in I'm a
little slow typing better
I just wanted to make sure that in the
demo but obviously you can do this a
little faster but the point being you
see how it works it automatically
started the password reset process
you've received the SMSs the tool is
waiting now for the for the temp codes
and we will just take them and feed them
into into the UI agang and just complete
the password reset with the password
that you see above that is what you
picked so now that I have all of them I
just click one by one again just to just
so that you can see how the tool works
but obviously I could just do this
automatically and you see that it's
doing exactly the same again so I just
compromised Twitter I just compromised
PayPal and facebooking on the other apps
are in the background you just don't see
them but this is how easy this thank you
so and it will suck to get that many
accounts compromised right so losing
your phone now is not really just about
the money you lose the thousand bucks
for the iPhone X I mean if you give me
thousand dollars or keeping my emails
and papers and stuff I probably give you
a thousand dollars and keep my you know
digital life so the thing is a I want to
I'm open sourcing this I'm not creating
a tool that you can go and then start to
compromise people's mode of POC just to
prove the concept right and you can go
there I didn't uploaded it yet I will do
tonight well I will do it these days but
a yeah this week I definitely had it I
just need to touch a little bit because
it's a little bit of spaghetti code but
a so you can play with it so conclusions
a lot mobile device is still insecure
which is kind of not a lot of people
especially not the people in security
has the feeling unattended mobile
devices can be a bigger risk than
unattended computers and companies tend
to ignore this and a lot of companies
you know they force you when you when
you get out to lock the screen and all
that starving and they put locks or no
one can physically take take the laptop
and things like that but mobile devices
is like okay they force it to have a
ping and that's it
but sometimes mDM's they don't force you
to this
the preview or to disable Siri on the
lockscreen so and as I said the
consequences of losing a song are not
only monetary which is the the idea that
people usually has or like when you lose
it it's like oh man I got to now spend
another thousand dollars so now we can
the get in a set in a second part of the
top because everything I told you you
need physical access to the device to
unlock the device but you need physical
access so I wanted to explore the idea
of how could we do this without even
physical access to the device so if we
think about the attack vector there is
two things in which it requires us to
have physical access right which is
obtaining the victims email because I
need to ask the mobile assistant to send
an email and obtain the secret codes
because I need the mobile device to look
at the screen to look at the other codes
so how could we do obtaining the victims
email without physical access to the
device well I just looked at the
previous art and there is several
research that allows you to interact
with the mobile device with a mobile
assistant we actually from distance
right so the first one hidden voice
commands is pretty interesting so
basically what they do is they mix the
payloads like for example hey Siri sent
an email in between noises or garbling
sounds and so that humans may not able
to understand that it's actually sending
a payload to Siri so that's pretty cool
but you know I looked at the demo you
can still tell a little bit but I mean I
was paying attention right if you are in
a casual conversation and you hear noise
then you probably don't realize the
second one is fantastic so these guys
what they did is for example if you have
your device with a with with headphones
on right with that is plugged in with
cable not bluetooth ones a what they do
is they send a electromagnetic signals
that the coil of the headphones you you
saw this right it's really awesome that
the call of day of the headphone picks
up and they do it in a way that it will
trick the phone into thinking that that
signal was coming from the headphones
and in realities payloads to Siri
they did even better a the year after I
believe and they do it now through the
church in Cairo if I believe correctly
because right now not a lot of people
anymore uses the thing but they are able
to do through the charging of is pretty
insane and the third one which became
very popular it's kind of like the
hidden voice command but much better in
the hinted voice comment we hear the the
growling sound right but this what these
guys do they put the palos just like we
will speak it but at a frequency that
the human ear cannot really hear but the
mobile device can so you can literally
talk to the mobile assistant but we
humans cannot hear a lot level I think
it's 20 Hertz I don't remember exactly
hmm 27,000 so and I actually want to
show you how it works so so here they do
the real thing right they have an Audi
on their device and they just play it
and the phone obviously picks it up so
now they plug it into that to the
amplifier and they do it with a
different frequency and you if you look
at the phone now they are playing the
sound we don't hear anything right but
look at the phone so that pedal I talked
to the 300 I wrote emails to them I was
with back and forth with this guidance
from the other two research and they
confirm you can perfectly send an email
with with any of those three research so
we have now the weekend if I'm close to
you but you have your phone on your
pocket I am able to trigger your mobile
assistant to send an email
how about obtaining secret codes for SMS
that is also existing research on this
as the seven attacks probably all of you
have heard already but it is basically
the protocol how the carrier's work
specially when you are roaming and how
they route calls and stuff like that I'm
not an expert on the field but I put
references for you to go watch these
talks that are fantastic and so with
these attacks you are able you could be
able to look snooping into sms's
Shuji done great attacks and the cipher
that is broken the it's used there you
could use that as well and that's kind
of like more a passive attack or
femtocells in Def Con 21 this is a
fantastic talk so basically it's like a
small base station that you can use and
these guys were able to get root access
and compromise it and the way mobile
devices work if I'm closer to you than
they or in reality if I have stronger
signal kinda because I'm closer to you
he would connect to me and not to the
tower and because I have root access on
the on the tower I'm able also to to do
a lot of stuff like possibly looking at
Sam s and then there is the old now that
is becoming very popular the sim
swapping they call t-mobile and start to
tell them some social engineering stuff
and they basically will own your phone
number so the conclusions are it is
possible to perform these attacks
without physical access to the device in
theory because I'm not showing you a
demo and your wishes demand the POC or
get the out right so there is
reasons why I did I don't have a demo
and mostly is because of legal reasons
like messing with GSM it's not it's kind
of not on the border it's very illegal
you can still do stuff but eh but yeah
this actually I wanted to put here in
case you guys think it could be
something worth it what I pictured is a
backpack you know with basically some
SDR or stuff that can you know you can
do this attacks for GSM and also the
amplifier the triggers the thing and you
have an Ubuntu running with ransom Bal
and kind of do that automatically that
will be really cool so another
conclusion SMS wasn't designed with
security in mind in order to be used as
a secure channel online service I should
encourage up based temp codes to FA
whatever and they make SMS opting
sometimes the only way to get to FA is
over SMS it's better to have two FA than
not to have it but they should only
services what I try to help push the
industry like all the research that has
been done since 2014 is that companies
actually adopt this recommendations for
you just to finish don't leave your
mobile device unattended you saw there
is some bad stuff can happen
sable the assistant in the lock screen
disable notifications previewing the
lock screen use apps for two FA and you
and have to obey don't provide your
phone number if not required I see that
in a lot of services you don't have to
and and it's the only way to get to a
faith and do it but you can use actually
a virtual phone number like Google Voice
and you can prevent sim swapping attacks
and even like you know open-source
intelligence like if you go now to ebay
if someone has an ebay account in a
PayPal account you will be able to get
seven of the ten digits because you go
to reset password with the emailing will
tell you should I send the code to a
four one five star star star star star
five three but then you go to PayPal and
it gives you the last four so just an
idea will be nice and I kind of started
to do it just use this automation that I
have which already is happening and just
get those numbers so you can go reset
password' but you don't really are
interested in digesting finding out what
the phone number is just an idea of you
guys want to do it and they check the
settings to disable security challenges
over SMS I think link I think Google
lets you pick between SMS a sort between
SMS and 2fa apps and it defaults to SMS
so that's one of the things that I was
mentioning so in some services you can
actually do this
thank you very much was a real pleasure
I'm giving another talk in Def Con come
check it out it's very cool about
hacking boy smoke systems and what the
impact is is actually somewhat related
to what we talked here about from a
different angle and it's on Friday 1:00
p.m. in track one and thank you very
much
[Music]
and I don't know if you guys have any
questions I think we need to use the mic
you have your questions please put your
hand up there's a question that but no
some talk just wondering in your
experience or your observations when you
take people through this say on a
one-on-one basis how many people have
actually hardened to a pretty good
standard they're they're phone from an
unauthenticated state so I haven't I did
not take the numbers which probably I
should have done first kind of like a
survey what I can tell you is security
minded people like in the audience they
mostly didn't have it but some of them
didn't I make fun of them most of my
friends that are not in the security
industry they all have the preview they
all did
and I for iOS so everything and now with
the iPhone X it will blur e8 and when
you look at it and it is pricey because
it authenticates you so we are doing
better for sure but there is still all
devices that run fantastic thanks to
Talk yeah just learning about the
androids you mentioned the apartment
Siri but about the androids
I'm not really sure Rodney using yeah so
I use server because that I have an
iPhone and testing devices are iPhone so
I know from what questions to my to my
friends and from testing a hundred has
the same issue but I believe at the time
of iOS Tang and whatever was the version
of Android under already had it had the
preview disabled by default so you have
to actively kind of like do a mistake
and activate it while it was not the
case for iOS but this is totally
applicable I mean you have the
notification on the lock screen and you
have 4k Google so it's totally up quick
end to Windows Mobile just in case any
other questions
alright let's go drink that thank you
[Applause]