so let us kick things off first and
foremost I am NOT a data scientist so
please take everything I say with a
grain of salt and feel free to you know
put me down afterwards
hopefully not during my talk and tell me
how wrong everything was that I talked
about but you know hopefully it's not
that bad but so yeah I'm mark Creager I
do
Mallory search at endgame you know
reverse engineering software dev a bit
and I've primarily been working on
ransomware protection research for the
past couple of years so this kind of
dovetails into the research that I did
for this project so just to go over the
agenda for today I'm going to give a
very brief overview of ransomware
current rates more detection
methodologies what ransom notes look
like typically then I'll delve into
talking about exploratory research than
some results that I got from that
initial research that I did and then the
development of a panic
proof of concept framework along with
the results from that and wrap things up
with the conclusion and hopefully I have
time for questions at the end all right
so a very brief overview of ransomware
if you're not familiar with it it's
simply just malicious software that's
going to encrypt files on your hard
drive to deny you users access to them I
just going to tap
typically target common file extensions
so PDFs text files Docs Excel
spreadsheets things of that nature
basically they want to get the most bang
for their buck without file without
encrypting every single file on your
hard drive and making this system
completely useless there's gonna be two
types of output that are produced from
ransomware you know the most obvious is
going to be encrypted files and then
typically it's also going to produce
ransom notes on disk and we'll get into
the purpose of ransom notes in a bit so
the current say the art for detection
methodologies can break down free neatly
into two categories you have static
detection which
they're gonna take place without any
sort of execution of code of the
ransomware so they're gonna be either
more baby kind of typically oriented or
it's going to be based off of here is
six or signatures or something that's a
little more next-gen that's gonna be
based off of something some sort of
machine learning model the benefit to
those obviously is that all data is
going to be preserved and that no code
will be executed but the drawback to
that is that if you do miss that
detection then essentially your entire
host is open to compromise and all that
data is going to be lost in that process
for dynamic detections there's there's a
few things that can take place one
approach is to plant canary files onto a
system and basically the purpose of
these is they're going to be monitored
and if they're modified in any sort of
way that a user want it then that's
going to be essentially their their
triple er to say hey there's you know
anomalous behavior taking place on this
on this host so that's one approach you
know along along that same line is you
know just having something run aah and
run in the background and monitoring
processes searching out anomalous
behavior so the benefit to a dynamic
approach is that you essentially have
you know while the processes are ongoing
you have a chance to detect them the
ring somewhere the drawback to that
though is that in that process you might
be sacrificing essentially a large
amount of the files in hopes of the
eventual detection so how can we improve
these you know two categories of
detections well the easiest way to do
that is to combine them so a static and
dynamic approach a layered security
approach that leverages the the
advantages of both is is the most
Neilsen area that you want you obviously
want to be able to detect something
before any sort of sort of code exists
that's that's the most ideal scenario
but if that doesn't work out you still
want a fallback you know that you can
rely on that that may eventually detect
the Ransom are executing you can tailor
your machine learning model to
specifically classify ransomware instead
of just generic malware there's a
definitely you know a lot of research
that can take place in that and then you
know trying to improve the dynamic
detection methods to pick up on an
almost behavior a little more quickly
and that's that's the goal of the
research site that I sought out with
this project so going back to ransom
owes as I discussed earlier so the basic
idea with a ransom note is that it's
something that is dropped disk in order
to solicit a rat's payment from the
victim of the ransomware so phrases such
as your files have been encrypted base
and will decrypt your files things like
that that's what you're gonna see in a
ransom note there's multiple file types
that ransom notes can take on the most
typical that you'll see is dot txt or
just plain text file
there's also formatted or rich text
format such as HTML and RTF and then you
know there's also images jpg PNG s
things along those lines ransom notes
are typically going to be one of the
first files ever been to disk that's not
always the case but it's typically what
we see and in certain ransomware
families ransom notes are going to be
written to every single directory on the
host and sometimes if not every single
directory it's just every directory that
is going to that sees a file that's
encrypted within it will have a ransom
note as well so essentially you're
trying to be this annoying as possible
just try to get their point across they
really want their money so here's a
example of a ransom note
this one's from cryptolocker this kind
of goes over some of the phrasing that
I'd previously discussed you know that
the first thing you lead off with is
saying your files have been encrypted in
the cryptolocker they tried to just
bribe essentially what encryption is you
know they want you to contact them
they're giving you a certain expiration
date for how long the files are gonna
last they're saying antivirus is not
going to help you at this point and then
they even get into explaining the OAS
for ya here's another example you know
now that you saw the first one from
cryptolocker now you see this it
basically says the same thing all your
files have been cryptid they talk about
specific document types they talk about
decrypting they want you to send Bitcoin
to their address you know and they even
say thank you at the end which is very
nice and there's this one which is
actually a image in this case their
ransom payment is 100 Bitcoin which
currently translates to about $750,000
so not sure exactly who they're
targeting with the specific ransomware
but you know and they're also you know
giving a very specific expiration date
so different approach with that one so
as we've seen you know just from looking
at three ransom notes right in a row how
you can start to come up with a template
for how Ram two notes look your files
have been encrypted by insert ransomware
name sometimes they're going to explain
intricate details in the encryption you
know just to scare you a little bit say
hey is 56 are say to 2048 whatever
they're gonna explain that your files
can't be decrypted on their own they
want you to send a ransom payment to
whatever their wallet ID is you can
optionally email them as well and
they're gonna give you an expiration
date so knowing all this my basic idea
kind of mix around this in my head for a
little bit as you know definitely very
much a data science novice so I wanted
to figure out a way hey can I apply a
data science to essentially detect
ransom notes as they're being written to
disk and can we differentiate them
consistently from normal text files so
with that
mind you know first goal was to develop
familiarity with the data science
concepts and tools that I'd be using and
I'd go out and collect build up a good
collection of ransom notes and then on
the flip side I'd also need to put
together a base benign data set that I
can prepare the ransom notes to and then
determine how suitable rancid notes are
to classification and you know how
solvable this problem really is so a
quick overview of tools I'd be using
anaconda Python 3 do my most minor work
in Jupiter notebook psych it and Spacey
okay so for data sets benign data the
easiest thing I found to use was just
the 20 newsgroups data set and that's
around 11,000 samples that spans 20 news
groups that were I believe that data was
collected you know like in the 90s or
somewhere so so it goes away back
there's the the categories all kind of
listed out there and then the ransom
notes so the way I collected those was
from actually manually detonating
ransomware samples in virtual virtual
environment and collecting artifacts so
that made up a certain portion of the of
the corpus and ransom notes the rest
came from just coming through security
research blog post Twitter downloading
actual text notes when they're made
available by pastebin or whatever or
actually downloading screenshots of the
ransom notes and then using OCR to
extract the text so to get into the
approach that I'm taking for the
exploratory research what we're working
with at the moment or for this problem
is it'll be unlabeled data we'll take
the ransom notes and we'll take the 20
years group's data and we're going to
throw them into one unlabeled data set
and we're gonna leverage k-means
clustering and set it to sort the data
into 21 clusters and they met reasoning
behind that is we have 20s newsgroups
and
we have one set of ransom notes so
ideally what we'll see is the ransom
notes all clustered into one one tiny
cluster and then the 20 newsgroups all
sort out into their own individual
clusters in order to get a better idea
of the data we're working with we'll
also use a bag of words approach with
account vectorizer and then also use
tf-idf to also look at the features so
first things first we need to do a
little bit of data preparation so all
we're gonna do here is strip out any
sort of newline characters are going to
convert all strings to lowercase then
we're gonna actually do the tokenization
and so we're splitting a you know a
large string into just the individual
words and we're going to strip out any
sort of stock words like the a and and
anything that's gonna be within the
Spacey's default soft words list then
we're gonna go from there to only taking
two count alphanumeric alphanumeric
strings and then we're gonna go ahead
and lemma ties the strings and basically
convert them to you know a more generic
form of the specific word so with this
you know very simple sample here what
we're going with is we have essentially
a string that we you know kind of
constructed that was describes a very
basic ransom note and then we run it
through our cleaning routine in order to
clean everything out and what we end up
with is a pretty simple string in the
end file and Crips and Bitcoin ransom
payment and you can see how that
definitely ties you know very closely
with what you would think a ransom note
is going to portray and when we're
taking into account the count vectorizer
and tf-idf vectorizer i
we want to get an idea of what the what
the top words are going to be what what
sort of phrases are we gonna tip ik Lisi
and it kind of hits along the same sort
of notes that we've been that we've been
seeing so far so we're talking about
files Bitcoin encryption decryption
sending payments emails computers things
along those lines and then when you
break it out to buy grams it makes a
little more sense in terms of phrasing
files are being encrypted files are
being decrypted you know they want you
to send in money for a private key
Bitcoin address things along those lines
so it it gives you an idea that you know
there this language is very kind of
tightly coupled together now well
actually yeah that before that was I was
just looking at the buy grams with the
count vectorizer as well now this is the
tf-idf versus the account vectorizer and
so with this we're still kind of seeing
the same sort of words that are popping
up they're moved up a little moved up
and down in terms of relevance a little
bit but generally it's the same data and
so now going back to the clustering the
way things kind of sorted out is here's
you know very you know high overview of
the top I believe 10 terms the top 10
features for each cluster and so our
ransom notes all ended up very nicely
put together in cluster 3 as you can
kind of see they hit the same list of
features that we'd previously seen with
the top words and you know just for
reference the news group 20 categories
or listed over there's the right and you
can kind of you know group together if
you start looking at some of the other
clusters you know which specific news
group they might come from and so
delving into the numbers a little bit
you know we can see that if we actually
the distance from the centroid for each
of the clusters for the particular
phrase that we're going to feed in to
interpret our vectorizer here so we were
actually through a legitimate ransom
note that we ripped from one of our
samples and provided it to the
vectorizer and you know we wanted to get
a idea of which cluster that's going to
essentially attend towards and lo and
behold that was cluster 3 which is the
cluster that has our ransom notes in it
and so if we come up with a phrase
that's similar to a ransom note but
actually is in portraying the exact
purpose of a ransom note
we'll see it actually doesn't you know
sorted into cluster 3 while it uses some
of the same language it's not using in
the same manner so it actually ends up
in cluster number 4 which is actually a
newsgroup for computer graphics so the
results out of the exploratory research
well despite a very small set of data
and you know to go back we only had 173
ransom notes the ramps notes clustered
together very well so they used a lot of
the same language um and with the second
sample that example that I showed there
with the with the subtle different
phrasing there is some nuance in how the
data is clustered it's not just going to
throw anything together that has that
says file and encrypt you know it's
there's definitely more to it than that
so seeing how the clustering worked out
we're gonna say that the data set seems
appropriate for classification you know
and didn't have time for it but ATS any
visualization would have been very nice
for this project but gain ground get a
lot - okay so building a proof of
concept framework so what do we really
need well we need a way to obtain file
change events in your real time and we
need a way to pass those file pass into
a something that's going to read in the
file contents
and essentially determine if the text
comprises a rings our note and then if
we've determined if it's a ransom note
we need to go ahead and suspend that
process and alert the user so since this
is a pretty big problem to kind of take
on you know I want to put put out some
restrictions on you know how this is
going to play out we're only going to
work with English notes we're gonna
restrict things strictly to text files
the reasoning behind this is any sort of
formatted text is gonna require
additional parsing and I believe that
was kind of outside the scope of the
problem that we're working with here any
certain images we're gonna have to use
OCR for that again that's kind of
outside the scope of the goal for the
project here and we're also going to
restrict files to file sizes that are
smaller than 20 kilobytes reasoning
behind that is once you start looking at
enough ransom notes you'll notice that a
vast majority of them are smaller than
two kilobytes and so if you provide a
little bit of you know space there for
some of the larger notes that actually
provide like a you know the whole modus
operandi behind there
you know ransomware campaign and that
sort of thing you know then you have
like some of them bump up a little bit
but but generally they're going to be
very small notes they're just trying to
get their point across that your files
are hosed and you know you need to send
them money so the way we're gonna break
things out is into you know three
distinct components but they're gonna
run within two processes so we'll have a
file change event listener and the goal
of that is it's going to take new file
offence and place it into queue for the
second process process B there's going
to be a component that will handle the
text extraction and also the machine
learning classifier that will retrieve
the events from the queue that process a
is depositing into and the process
mitigation handler will also be in
process B and that's only invoked if the
classifier finds a minutes ago so here's
kind of a you know good overview of how
a detection scenario would play
the ransomware is going to execute and
drop a ransom note in the root of the C
Drive the event listener is going to you
know be pulling for new file change
events and it gets the file path for
ransom note text into the root of the C
it passes that file path to the text
extractor and classifier the text
extractor will read in the contents of
the ransom note and pass it to the model
and then the classifier returns yes back
to the event listener and then the
ransom or bill will be suspended so for
the framework what we wanted to do is
come up with the data set it was going
to be a little more reflective what we
might typically find on a Windows host
and so we took a subset of the twenty
newsgroups data set we're gonna stick
with around 8,000 messages this time and
then also we pulled in you know a little
over 3,000 text files from Windows host
and these mostly come comprises of log
files read Me's and Sawyer files thinks
that nature that you might typically
find on it with us host so we ended up
with around 11,000 files or so and and
yep that's that's kind of what we build
off of with the ransom notes
we essentially doubled the size of our
sample set I was able to find a few more
resources for pulling down ransom notes
so that helped build that up a little
bit and you know despite doubling the
size of the set of ransom notes that so
leaves us you know very you know
outnumbered quite a bit above that by
the benign data and so for for the POC
framework what we wanted to do was try
to address the data set imbalance and so
we're gonna use smoke to generate our
own synthetic data to try to make up for
that so the approach for the classifier
we're going to use tf-idf for our
feature selection use the tf-idf
vectorizer
and what we're doing is we're breaking
this down
to a supervised learning problem we're
using label data here we're distinctly
labeling them into notes this time and
then we're distinctly labeling the
benign data the assignments and you know
we have a binary classification problem
if we're provided a you know a block of
text is this going to be a ransom note
or is it benign data that's all we're
trying to answer and the approach we
decide to use naive Bayes and you know
more specifically be multinomial envy so
here's what our data processing pipeline
essentially looks like we start with our
label data set comprised of ransom notes
in benign text in our pre tokenization
step we're gonna strip out characters
convert all the characters to lowercase
we're gonna do the tokenization done
with Spacey and then post tokenization
we're going to only keep the
alphanumeric strings as before strip out
stop words carry out limit sensation
then we'll convert that set of data then
to vector using a tf-idf vectorizer and
then we'll address the data set and
balance as I previously mentioned using
spoke and then the training will take
place with the naive Bayes classifier so
for testing we're going to split into a
8020 subsets using trained tests split
and you know just to you know is
probably you know might be known by most
see you guys but you know just going
over some terminology here you know for
accuracy score that's referring to the
accuracy of the actual classification F
and the score is a weighted average of
the precision and recall confusion
matrix just provides a overview of false
negatives false positive true positives
and true negatives and in terms of
cross-validation what we're going to do
is it's it's it represents testing the
models ability to predict new data
that's not being seen previously
so the goal of that is that you want to
run multiple runs with different
training and tested test datasets you
know essentially to test model as in as
many ways as you can and for our
purposes we're just going to use Monte
Carlo using a shuffle split so with one
single test we actually ended up with
pretty good results 99.5% accuracy 90
1.86
f1 score if we scale up the valley value
to 100 and with our confusion matrix
results look pretty well pretty good as
well
we have only we have zero false
negatives only 14 false positives and
you know everything else seems to sort
itself out well but a single test
doesn't really show you enough about the
model you might just have happen to come
upon they you know an outlier and since
we're doing the 80/20 split with
randomized data sets
maybe we just happen upon a very lucky
set that's gonna make our numbers well
so with the cross-validation we're gonna
run it ten times with randomized sets
and so the cross-validation as you can
see see Balmer and Bill Gates are still
clapping and dancing up there for the
windows 95 launch release so things are
still going well average accuracy is
about what we saw in our one run f1
score about the same and the confucian
matrix looks about the same as well so I
think what that it our specific case
that confirms that the the data does
classify extremely well here's a
graphical representation of the scores
that just kind of showed the you know
some fluctuation in the f1 score but
they generally at least stay above 85 or
so accuracy it stays extremely high
above like ninety nine point three
percent on average you know as again
that said I'm not need a scientist but
if we believe these are good results
okay so now going back to our event
listener so
essentially what we need is something
that's going to monitor file change
events for us we need to monitor all
processes on the host and what we need
is a mapping of each specific event to a
specific source process and in
particular for our case we want to
monitor file creation events and so
there's a few ways that we could go
about this but some of them aren't going
to hit every single of those three
objectives or they're gonna hit them and
but it's going to be a little more
difficult right so since we're code base
that we're typically using is is Python
you know first the other thing comes -
you might want to use Python watcher the
problem with that is it relies on the
redirect changes API which I believe
only only operates on a specific
directory is a little noisy actually is
a pretty big drag on performance and to
top it all off does not provide a
mapping of a specific change event to a
specific source process and the reason
why that isn't suitable for us is that
we would have no idea what process that
specific event comes from and we don't
know what process to suspend or
terminate in that instance so
essentially if we're using this as a
detection framework the output of thats
gonna be pointless for us we would just
know that there's a ransom note on the
disk we have no idea what stop so what
are we gonna do event logs that'd be one
way of of obtaining events for our
purposes or you can also write up a file
min mini filter driver file a mini
filter driver in the long run is
definitely the best approach to take but
it's also the most time consuming and
you know if you're writing code for the
kernel you're definitely prone to make
mistakes and crashing box so what do we
do in this case well luckily for us
there's syslog and within the last year
or so sis Mon they opened up their
framework for exposing file creation
events that they're gonna write to their
own event log and so with event
eleven all we need to do essentially is
query the event log for file creation
events and we're going to get all the
data that we need so in order to reduce
the noise that Sivan creates because if
you ever installed system on and query
the logs occasionally with just default
settings there's gonna be a lot of noise
in there so essentially that I just
created a very simple stripped-down
config file to just eliminate any sort
of process creation and termination
events and limit it only the file
creation events only to dot exe files
and that's right there the simple
command that you need to run in order to
get system on configured to work with
this framework and then also to query
the logs VW of via WMI you need to
specifically add a event key or register
key to allow event log query so as I
mentioned before what we're trying to do
is pull the event log for new file paths
and we're going to be using the WMI
query language we need to limit the size
of results set in order to reduce
overhead because the event logs can
build up over time and we need to parse
that data from the results and then pass
that to our classifier work queue so in
terms of the process mitigation all we
need to do is like at this point we know
that there is a ransom note on disk we
know the source process and we also know
the source process name so now we need
to determine if that information is
still accurate if there process still
exists so we're gonna grab you know
early active process is to try to
determine if that process still exists
if it is if it does and it's selective
we're gonna suspend it we're gonna
provide a pop-up to the user to tell
them that a ranter no is detected allow
them to terminate or resume the process
and also
if they do resume the process we need to
maintain a whitelist of process IDs and
process names so we don't just keep
alerting over and over on the same
process and so at this point I'm gonna
do a live demo let's see how this works
a lot of confidence behind this okay so
what we're working with here is a sample
of the volcano ransomware and so right
here I have process monitor running in
the background I already have a filter
specifically for right file operations
that are gonna be written out by the
volcano dot exe process and so I execute
this and that was pretty quick wasn't so
what we have here is it lists out the
the file path of the ransom note it
tells us the specific process the the
source process path along with the
specific bed and then it's giving us an
option click ok to determinate or okay
or cancel to resume and whitelist the
process for further confirmation that
this worked 24 - 9 - volcano dot exe
process explorer is telling us that
suspended and if we go to the process
monitor output we can see how fast that
actually took place if the first file
right was at you know 536 55 here we're
gonna scroll down here I can get this
536 56 so essentially one second after
the file writes begin is when our
detection you know kicks off and misses
spent the process we can even drill down
even further into this to see you know
just how long you know it took for us to
detect as soon as we saw a a text file
so as we can see the first ransom note
was written out to the install forge a
user actually just the install forge a
directory or actually that's the one who
that we detected on but they all the
file rights took place within
milliseconds of each other so depending
on how they're they're pulled from the
log you know one might be seen before
the other but but essentially as soon as
they the rain-snow first hits a disk
we're gonna obtain the file pass by
querying out of that log and we can see
things and so if we go ahead and click
OK terminate the process why volcana dot
exe is no more and I'll attempt the demo
gods one more time here and actually do
one more demo here for you I'm going to
run a sample of BTC where I believe I
have the filters all set up
oh actually I didn't that wouldn't
[Music]
so yeah just gonna set up my proc
monologue here just to give us some more
of the output okay so if we want BTC
where and we caught that one as well
so you can see that in this case there
were a few more follow events that took
place before we actually came up with
our detection I mean it's it's
definitely gonna vary from case to case
depending on how performant the querying
of this of the event log is going to
take place you know as I kind of alluded
to before all of our codes running in
Python we're not running our own mini
filter driver we're simply just querying
an event log repeatedly every 10
milliseconds so it's gonna be dragged on
resources and you know you've been doing
some like sort of timing analysis I I
noticed a lot of different you know
results in terms of how long the queries
were taking place so not ideal for some
sort of production ready environment
like please don't deploy this to your
10,000 endpoint network I take
absolutely no responsibility for what
happens but you know for a limited
proof-of-concept
this definitely gets the point across
you can see that process is also got
okay so getting into a few more results
ahead time to test this out on a few
other newer samples so so out nine
samples two of which that I showed you
test for PTC we're in volcano were able
to test and detect those variants of
water samples so for those specific
samples what makes those a little more
unique is that those ransom notes
weren't previously seen they weren't
included in our training set at all
you know that's essentially new data
that that comprises a little bit of a
holdout set now for us in this case
there's also three samples I
specifically tested that have ransom
notes that are in our training set that
we were able to you know test and eject
as well so in order to get a better idea
of what this really you know kind of
brings to the table I wanted to produce
some comparative results I wanted to
compare what the capabilities this
framework are versus you know what else
is out there in terms of free ransom
order detection capabilities so we're
gonna to be doing - very well
unscientific tests here test one does
the product detect the sample to me
that's extremely straightforward so
nothing no I'm not pulling a bunch of
ser tests - we're trying to detect which
is faster the classifier framework or
rival product A or B or C the the reason
with this you know that that it's you
know maybe not the best way to measure
is that there's definitely potentially a
lot of different complicating factors
one of which could be driver altitude
and assuming that most of these products
are going to be based off of foul mini
filter drivers the altitude in which the
drivers installed could determine you
know which driver gets to see the
particular file path first and do its
analysis before it releases its access
the file path you know for the next
driver on the stack
you know don't exactly know how that
factors into things and you know wasn't
perfectly interested and in reverse
engineering all these products yeah but
you know definitely take these results
with a grain of salt
um so without naming names I was told
you avoid that I don't want to cause
anybody any problems here but product B
in our case perform the best and and
also was typically faster than our
framework there was only one instance I
believe where our framework detected
something before it but most of the
other results were either ties or the
ordered product B was was faster in its
detection by second or two but as for
product a and C products C in particular
you know that pretty spotty coverage in
terms of detecting ransomware and even
yeah well when it did it at least
outperformed the framework but product a
in particular yes it literally seemed to
cover all the cases or you know eleven
out of twelve samples but in every
instance about one you know our humble
little Python based framework that's
querying event logs every ten
milliseconds was able to outperform it
so with that being said to bring us back
down to earth you know there are
definitely several limitations involved
here you know despite be you know very
promising results that I just showed you
you know it's definitely a little bit of
a loaded sort of test there it's it's a
lone scenario because we're already
working with samples that we
specifically know drop text file ransom
notes and so at the moment that's all
that we're it's tuned to use is or
detectives text ransom notes so you know
that's one huge limitation but that's
one that we knew at least going in the
there are some samples I don't know any
specific families at the moment because
I've tested so many samples it'll pass
years all the family names run together
but there's some samples that don't drop
in ransom notes until nearly the end so
when they've you know especially you
know encrypted everything on the file
system then they go back and write out
the ransom note so it's kind of you know
would defeat the purpose of her
framework and in that instance there are
some samples that are actually extremely
annoying and will solve some sort of
persistence ahead of time and actually
keep respawning the same process over
and over attempting to encrypt more and
more files
so in that case yeah we might catch the
grantor process over and over but you're
still going to be infected and you know
there's definitely a lot more work that
needs to be done in that case and then
to get into a more wider problem there's
definitely samples that take a different
approach to ransomware
there were two ones that attack the
system in different ways and besides
encrypting individual files some will
corrupt the NPR overwrite the bootloader
they'll do a more full disk encryption
Rob disk based approach or some some are
just simply very annoying screen lockers
which will make it impossible to just
log into Windows on its own without
actually corrupting the files in any way
and then last but not least we're only
working with in English right now
there's definitely ransomware that
targets spanish-speaking countries
Russian countries there's you know
russian-speaking countries there's a lot
of you know other sort of variants out
there but you know outside the scope of
this talk in this feature for this
presentation so future work the the
first thing that comes to mind is we
could definitely improve the datasets we
could introduce much more ransom notes
which would mean that we would rely less
on our synthetic data so we need to keep
pulling in ransom notes as new variants
are discovered and we'd also we could
also do a much better job of bringing a
representative benign text data set from
different installers readme files things
like that so you could use nine night
chocolaty some sort of other mass
installer to
build up a large corpus of text files
that are gonna be written to disk and
kind of pull from there we do this a few
times but definitely porting to a much
lower level languages C C++ something
like that that would yield significant
performance improvements I mean and if
we also tie into working with the file
mini filter driver then you'd have you
know incredible performance and we could
easily at least for those cases that I
was mentioning you know outperform you
know products from you know very large
companies and parsers for other file
types I alluded to before that the image
based ransom notes ransom notes that use
formatted text it'd be great to support
those putting the work in to do those
probably shouldn't be too much work
expanding language support that'd be
great and actually you know finally to
go back to data science experimenting
with different classification approaches
would be great
naivebayes just just will worked for
this particular problem you know is this
kind of well low-hanging fruit because
you know I kind of pulled a couple of
data scientists I work with and you know
they've told me to go in the direction
of using naive Bayes and that's the way
I went Frost the results were good
enough so that's why I stuck with and so
as of now the source code for all this
is available on the endgame github
it is a GPL v3 and it would live this
morning so to wrap things up oh sorry
yep I think I got it into but
all right everybody good okay
so wrap things up with our exploratory
research we use clustering to prove that
the data book was suitable for
classification we were able to determine
the ransom notes do share enough
features across the board that would
make this a viable solution product you
know for this particular problem and you
know we very much realize this isn't
going to catch all the waiting somewhere
but going back to talking about our
layered security approach this can be an
integral piece of layered detection and
improve the time to detect for a dynamic
dynamic detent detection when we do
happen to miss something statically as
we see the PLC does work but there are
many improvements to be made and if I
can do this
I'm sure you guys can do much better
because yeah this actually no data
science it I don't quick what little
plug here for something from endgame
mani right here will stamp your
passports if you guys picked up the
passport cards from the end game booth
earlier if not you can talk to us and
we'll point you in the right direction
so yeah thanks for coming I guess
[Applause]
yeah you don't have questions find me
later yes
in doing this I realize you're using
high-level in-store low-level language
did you do any performance tests to see
like how this would work on a file
server so that you can see the
difference between that huh using Python
or even assembly and doing these kind of
cuts that's really what this comes down
to is you're looking for specific
keywords mm-hmm
file servers are what you're gonna be
worst hit by by ransomware so oh yeah um
yeah I hadn't got around to like kind of
you know doing any testing with any sort
of lower level languages I think you
know at least for carrying out the POC
oh is this easiest to use
you know Python and all the performance
yeah I mean like you definitely yeah I
can easily see how that would be
extremely you know performant for
carrying things out in that way but but
yeah yeah I think that would be you know
kind of next step is to to go down that
path and you know you know write our own
driver you know and do all the other
data science of you know at a much lower
level language in Python 3 do you know
of any the nerves are working on
solutions for masses like NetApp and
integrating directly into their
functionality hmm uh not not that I've
heard of most of the the applications
that that you know that I was kind of
able to discover just once by you know
some some more the main vendors and they
just you know we're kind of tailor
tailoring them just to you know kind of
give people a rough sense of how their
detection works and I don't know if
that's necessarily their full enterprise
support you know what they would roll
out if you you know got big contract for
ten thousand endpoints or something like
that
Cisco all right
all right down with Cisco melis yeah
yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah that that's the
first I've heard of it though but but
yeah I I think is you know as ransomware
you know continues to you know pick up
in prominence I think that right you'll
see more you know specific tailored
solution for those solutions for
different products have you seen any
other os's besides Windows that get
targeted for ransomware yeah um so that
there's definitely a few different like
Mac OS ransomware families but as we've
been tracking them they haven't really
evolved significantly within the past
like couple years or so
I I don't know if any that are you know
particularly successful compared to like
the actors behind Sam Sam or some of the
other more prominent ransomware families
that you hear about but yeah so you know
there are some some Mac OS ransomware
there there's some Linux ransomware but
I feel like you know that's if you are
between and actually the most besides
Windows I've heard about is where the
attack targets of Android systems and
yeah I'm not sure exactly what sort of
detection capable is there are four for
Android right now yep oh it's just in
game ich with no dot now okay I blame
the proofreaders for that kitchenette
all right thanks
[Applause]