thank you very much for the introduction
and for everyone's coming to our
presentation today
I'm sure say tominaga our presentation
today is about how to detect the rotary
movement using a bent rod and we will
show a demo of our tools first of all
let me introduce our service my name is
jose ettan Raja I have been working at
JP sat for five years my primary
responsibilities are to analyze Maria
and EFI yar we have been publishing
analysis of the Bayesian approach we
also develop some tools which are useful
for Mary analysis these are available on
github ok so hello everybody hello thank
you for response to market on you forum
JP start and it's my first B style buoy
and I'm very very excited to be here
with you today and thanks for giving us
opportunity to having a presentation
here and thanks to attending and thanks
to all the staff and volunteer and
beside that we ok let's give up on this
thank you ok thanks and shoot and I and
I belongs to the instant response group
at JP SAR and my primary responsibility
is D F IR
ok so does everyone know JP star no
thank you thank you very much yeah ok I
would like to speak a little bit about
our group we were our group receive
almost 10,000 decent report every year
and coordinate and cooperate with our
partners to mitigate security incidents
also we handle 20 to 30 APD instance per
year and put in a lot of time and effort
to them and today's talks come from the
experience we collected from DF IR and I
wish we would help your DF IR and your
studies
okay before moving on the main topic I
would like to talk about the current
state of the incident response
especially in apt okay as you know when
the incident happens attackers in truth
into the company's network and in fact
many Holliston servers with their
malware using windows default tools in
case the number of the impacted horse
runs up to a hundred and it takes months
is to reveal what happened there okay so
importance of the event log analysis an
apt case Ben log analysis will be the
key factor to identify the compromised
tossed in the victim network so why a
Windows Active Directory records all the
log on histories to the repair log and
we could chase the malicious activity
from them many of the attackers tried to
spread the malware and executed it
remotely with the ad authentications
okay so what's a trend of the malicious
mr. logon method nowadays attacker use
pass the ticket when spreading the
infection to other host passage kit
issues and unauthorized ticket that
grants access to other hot without a
license without additional
authentication and golden tickets
is it granting ticket and silver ticket
is use service tickets so this one
question does Windows System recalls the
past that ticket in the band log oh
thank you so in the past to get user
sister used the system records the same
it will say me been log as a standard
logon and to detect malicious logon from
the Bell law
we need a new Tecna analyzing techniques
or new methods so what's the best tool
for event log emphasis here you like to
discuss option is bamboo it could be the
first often yeah
we could use we depend beer but maybe
everyone knows it's a viewer it's not a
lighter so it's very painful to analyze
this so the next one is the next option
is to export benlloch to the text and
file and use grep or it okay or sets and
yeah it's much better than the viewer
but yeah it's still painful if we have a
large data side to analyze in this very
difficult analyze okay how about see ya
theme is very useful to search logs
their desserts tactical language and the
dashboard is very cool so I love it but
yeah it's not clear where to find the
malicious logs okay so the problem of
the computational methods of analyzing
band logs there's three points and first
it did it difficult to investigate with
the default tools and second is the new
techniques or new method is required to
to detect pasture to get from the bank
logs and finally it's not clear where
where to find malicious logs so today's
goal is to propose a method of analyzing
Active Directory a bit log okay in this
presentation we will introduce our
approach to these those challenges so
our approach is investigate malicious
windows log on by visualizing and
analyzing padlock if we could support
visualizing and analyzing event lock
with stools it will make it easier to
find out malicious activities such as PT
pass the ticket PDT or pass a hash PTH
okay so here's a topic for today's
presentation first we will talk about
the band lock visualization and second
we will show the additional analysis of
the BAM log using several algorithms and
techniques and third we will introduce
our tool logon tracer and finally we
would like to show the demonstration ok
from here I would like to pass the mic
to
suzay so after this right we will
introduce how to visualize an honor and
an irrelevant role how to visualizing
live interact the inventor has multi
multi event related to log on the log
events contains account and host
information the analyze and visualize
dot information in destroyed reached
over all going event IDs these are about
2000 go events for example logo success
is ID f--
you
the answer is no it is possible to
detect Marcia struggle without
monitoring Oregon event or IDs in your
research we know that it is important to
monitor just six event IDs the highlight
event IDs the events that we recommended
to monitor in relation to the success
and failure of rogue on an ethereal and
carriers authentication attempt is also
important the event log is not used for
analysts chrome name or event ices are
different for each review entities and
not all the event ID has the same type
of information associate of the ideal
man
analyzing event roll it is necessary to
solve these problems this figure is a
simple pattern visualizing the event
role by visualizing vm2 asset account
name and the host from the logo event
IDs therefore it is easy to check which
account name used to log on or to a host
this is an example of visualizing logon
event ID based on the previous concept
you
the host and account ratio is one to one
this is an example of Marshall slogan we
can easy find out that many hosts log on
using matter movement
if Masako attempts too much prahasta a
card from account the rogue will be like
this
you
you have a great enough eyesight you
could find master Drago from this video
but most people will find it difficult
to analyze this figure from this result
we learned that visualization is a good
support for analyzing relevant rock but
not a perfect soldier we using that
other approach is needed to analyze in
the event log therefore we saw the
botana cur'us approach it is difficult
to analyze a lot of logs dogs using
visualization but if we can
automatically real suspicious act
account analysis will be similar so we
proposed a new method to automatically
detect emerges wrong
next let me introduce method to method
of automatically inertia's in order to
create to create an automatic detection
method it is necessary to understand
more about lateral movement through our
experience in many case of instant
response we found that attacker normal
conducted lateral movement in the
following steps
this introduces a flow of repetitions
attacker foo infected the host with
Maria correct information or the host
next they collect information to the
host server within the network and this
first infection to other host this
diverse and confidential information
using call service
and saw rust the drugs under credit
files this is an example of a lot of
metal steps executed command by ticks a
taco tick is a cyber-espionage a group
known to target the Japanese
organizations such as a government
agency as well as so is biotechnology
rhetoric as manufacturing and industrial
chemistry the initial investigations
that will fool my command the news mimic
cuts to create accordant yet internal
recon European Command after that use
net command to map our remote hosts they
executed prior to remote host with copy
and eighty command and the final data
files
from our experience of dear file there
are three Co a future in lateral
movement first attack I use not orab at
actors but also windows command and
resume tools
next they use the domain other is
administrator account
finally they use the story account to
repeat to logon biotic is the domain
administrator account no reason for this
example it is possible to log onto or
host on the server using the domain
administrator account the occipital hold
attacker takeover domain administrators
account the most common method is
exploiting building administrator
account many organization use common
password for administrator account to
manage a host therefore if you can still
one account to it infected host they can
easy access all hosts and servers the
attacker use rattle movement with one
stern password password and account as a
result a host that has been compromised
by the attacker will be used for logon
to many hosts with the same account we
are going to many hosts with vow account
is a suspicious activity we applied this
future to automatic automatic detection
we applies a common in the rotor
movement in introduced area to automatic
analysis specifically in the
visualize the event wrong we propose a
method to automatically detect to user a
so how can I automatically detect the
user a from this video there are similar
approach to surges solve such tasks we
use net network analysis to detect
account that log on to many host network
analysis is to hundreds of property of
complex in network is various field
network analysis has two metrics
clustering is a task of grouping a set
of objects in such a way that object in
the same group was similar to each other
than those in other groups we use a
laser matrix centrality centrality and
network analysis centrality indicates
the most important busted bottles within
a group graph in other words it is a
method of cross-training
calculating
regional is connected to the most known
the algorithm to calculate calculate
centrality the most famous our worries
is a Zhang Dejiang is an algorithm years
for Google search to lock the website in
their search engine result I do Falcon
is as follow imported will be page
sorted from many sites so the number of
links will appear our web page linked
from web pages with large number of
links how high important page rank is
also used for ranking others own web
page
pressure can be used for spreaded graphs
such an event raw graph the old original
PageRank algorithm was described by
Brian on page several publications we
calculate centrality using this organism
and the Fondren issue the project for a
controller is Hyosung only one host is
connected this issue is the two hours
ever ever ilysm other than PageRank hard
disk programs so we investigate method
better calculate version we saw the
issue using this method increase the
rank of important to account by changing
the topic
factor for each account the Falconeri
hold that imaginary interactive user who
is around every quaking on the link will
virtually stop creaking the probably any
steps that possibly conduct continue in
that topic factor baristas have tested
differently but it is generally assumed
that the on-field factor will be set
around the point eight five so it has
been proposed that method to control the
rank or with us spawn webpage by
adjusting the at attrition concentration
we also use a method to control the
ranking of the account by controlling
the top in factor the patients that the
change of dumping factor value for each
account is different if by the following
formula D is a damping factor over page
a and the next question is how to
describe the damping factor we
dynamically calculate the damping factor
from the following intervals account
private authentication type unbury
deduction over local controller timeline
Annamarie detection of transition of
local event rolls after destroyed we
will introduce German first element is
account privilege as I said earlier the
administrator account is used by the
taco therefore it is better for the
the other in Saratoga County to rank
higher second element is authentication
type yotaka use pasta hodge mitad ntlm
authentication is recorded so if she
account to use ntlm authentication for
rode on the rank will be higher south
airman is unburied detection of rock
event roll timeline anomaly detection by
counting the number of local event logs
timeline for example a large number of
Rockefellers may be brute-force attack
we use the change find out anomaly
detection change finder is a time share
data change point detection algorithm
that can detect change point in real
time whichever page change finder is raw
computational complexity therefore it is
used for real-time anomaly detection if
change finder detects timeline and body
the rank will be higher
finally animal detection or state
transition of raga event Rock windows
logon has three state transition I can't
not Rogan burger attempt are the Lord o
if sheet shift from not rogue on States
to load our logo attempt and finally
shift to roll down
if it is Marcia's role on the
state-transition baby became anomaly in
case of a brute-force attack or pasta
ticket the state did not with low growl
or roar attempt we examinate method to
detect Armory in this state transition
so we proposed a method to detect on
Murray instead transition using massive
running there are superior machine
learning algorithm to analyze the state
transitions recently recurrent neural
network is mainstream in this field
however recurrent neural network has a
program of Raja Raja computational
complexity the who we analyzed the
inventor of using hidden Markov model
the hidden Markov model is both the most
reported machine running bothers in
speech and language processing this
model is a state transition of the pasta
is a hidden state and the event is
modelled from the output result of the
two states this figure is an example of
the shielding Markov model for example a
thermal pulse of rupees srimant
walk shop and cream the event to be
conducted will depend on the version of
the time however the Reza itself is not
disclosed when you only know the
conductor to event you chasms
current visa this is how hidden Markov
model works we otherwise I paint over
here is a shitty Markov model even these
local event or IDs and the shooting
state not rogue on dog attempt Android
all predict the state of the event ID
time run the hidden Markov model can
detect that the it does not move to
stage one or two so this is a examples
are not as European trope timeline with
hidden Markov model if normal Orem it
will be from state zero to one and
finally move to stage two but in the
case of pasta Hodge it has not shift to
page one Stage one if sister additional
money is detected the lock will be
higher we evaluated the person including
discernment as a result of evaluation
the method we capable of detecting
account using pasta Hodge or Pacific ate
by another anything they repent rogue it
is also probe possible to detect
suspicious Logan
however the case which she can not be
detected the geography is dynamic
damping factor heart problems false
positive if Pluto administrator account
is used for although your host and Sabah
the Polanco of the account will be
higher first negative if
TACA affected only one post it is
decided to detect that the activity this
is a future task
okay thank you for introducing the core
techniques and methods and logon tracers
who say so from here I would like to
introduce our tool logon tracer logon
tracer is a tool to investigate
malicious logon by visualizing and
analyzing event and our Windows Active
Directory event logs
it's a python-based analyzing tool with
web GUI and we use nail for J at the
database and we use the Site escape dot
J's for visualizations and it's open
source software so will be developed on
github and we released the first version
last November and we released the latest
version 1.1 this August okay lock on
tracer has four features first is
visualizing bed logs it makes it easier
to understand what is happening in the
victims network and second is display
important account and hosts and this is
very cool feature and you can find
suspicious accounts or hot very quickly
and third it is no event log search and
it's a preset search conditions for
investigation Active Directory event
logs and it accelerates your log
analysis and forces timeline and you can
make the timeline table very quickly in
this tool and this feature will help
your analysis and reporting instance and
this is web GUI I think it's very simple
everyone how do you think ok I would
like to introduce about the interface so
the upper side is a search navigation
bar and you can set the search
conditions here
and the right side table so the rank of
the page page rank with dynamic damping
factor it's about one of the most
important part of this GUI and upper
table here shows the suspicious account
King and the lower one shows the
suspicious horse ranking so the higher
ranking rank is more more suspicious
here and you can find suspicious or
suspicious or important accounts from
this table and the left side you can
depend log search like a preset for
search conditions you can use drop-down
menu to search account name matching to
specific criteria here's a list of the
additional event log search these search
are very important when you investigate
Active Directory logs in real case I
really do these investigations in
thought
search and dfi are and here's the
interface for the timeline table and
here it shows a summary of the band log
in and the number shows the crowd of the
logs and each hour and colored cell
shows anomaly score so if so the darker
color it the cell has it will be that
the cell has more a higher on all of my
score here and this is a timeline
timeline graph and this graphs show
about a specific user and you could
check the transition of the bandwidth
anomalies score the red line shows an
animated score here okay let's move on
to the demonstration for here so we
prepared a demo boobie and I would like
to show how to use log on tracer
so movie starts okay so first how to
star logon tree
and yes you can find how to start the
web GUI where we are here run start web
application so you can start with
vacation with hyphen R option and now he
running on the local host there with
HTTP and party aoao so access to the bar
from web browser and here's a picture
like this mode if you click all user you
could find all data here and the red box
here is shows the graph visualization
panel so you could customize the
visualization here and right side sorry
the tops at top is certain navigation
bar so you could set the search
conditions and here I'll explain it more
detail later and the right side it is
yes rank of the page rank withstand
damping factor
and the left box here is graph options
view option so you could set a graph
mode or you could change the link link
values here and here's a drop-down menu
for search and yeah it's kind of the
search preset search conditions here
okay from here I would like to show a
little bit about no details of the icon
meaning the blue one is the standard
account and the red circle is system
privileged account and the green one is
IP address or host and the link detail
has how to read the link and this
example uterus madam is traced their
success to logon costs to the host and
yeah very simple to read so from here
yeah and you could check the account
detail by clicking the node like this
yeah you can find a name the privilege
status the security ID and you can
search it by the user names of quick
search and you can find it you can
change the visualization then you can
drag the node so you can clean up the
panel and yeah you can find this account
it's very suspicious because it was used
for it this account is useful for
several hosts logon attempts and you
know you could also search with
navigation bar click search so yeah you
can show the account from here and also
you could add accounts here for example
here you can use your house or IP
address so here it's adding IP address
and click search so yeah you can find
out this here and yet it looks very
suspicious and yeah you could filter by
your event ID here and if you only want
to show two IDs you could change like
this you could also export data to see
its Bowie or Jason or image it's like
PNG or JPEG and here it exporting PNG
based so just click and you can download
it and you can get the file so you can
use it for for reporting instance here
and you could also search users from
right side from example for example here
it will click sis G admin the top one
yes
so here the top line is suspicious so
you can find you with previous account
using here and also these horses you
could click horse and you find it
suspicious like this and from here you
could change the graph mode the default
is grid but you could take clothes and
show all users so it's a you can find
here something something happening here
it's in here so no more nor no normal
logon times and you could also use a
graph more like circles so you could
show the graph like circle and here you
can get a deep L used to link so in this
example in the demonstration it's adding
count and oust names so that's a little
bit small but you can find the
authentication name and the user count
here
okay and now checking with a bent idea
again and so the system privilege yeah
so ap the attacker wants target the
system produced account so you can only
check the system previous that come from
this button and also you could check PLM
remote logon only empty all logins to
check the Hat pastor has I'll pass it
has yeah check domain which which
account where or belonging to and this
feature is useful when certs a minute
certs search if the beaming cut is used
because the mimikatz has need to enter
the domain name and sometimes attacker
miss type it make a typo so you can find
a suspicious domain from this feature
and from here it's showing the timetable
and you could show a click call to show
the timeline summary and yet and the
colored shows are normally detection so
you can find something is happening on
the seventh Tuesday or here and you
could check call so yeah it's very
simple it's very easy to check the
timeline because it's colored
and also you could check click username
to show the detail the timeline so you
could find that the count and each AT&T
IDs and here you can find anomaly
anomaly detection here like this and
also you could add search conditions
forms from shared you can compare
accounts like this so yep and you can
find it upper one has anomaly detection
six and lower land has a separate animal
detection on 7th
and you can switch the timeline mode to
the timeline to the graph going on the
upper side switch and you can search the
specific user here and yeah here you can
find the high anomaly score in the
middle and this score is caused by the
suspicious Coble's
service to get to request ebay 94 7 6 9
here so you can you could you could you
can detect that you can think that it's
a possible over the past ticket here and
you can find the eg pen log count here
and yes this feature makes it easy to
analyze specific user and quick got to
go back to the timeline summary and yep
that's all for the demonstration
okay if you want to know more detail
about vlog on tracer check it out or
wiki on the github and this wiki you can
find how to install log on tracer or how
to store with docker or and how to use
it from this QR code stop now okay
[Applause]