I've known everybody thank you very much
for coming we're going to talk about
something which is of real importance to
pretty much looking after what we care
about prosperity human life and safety
and that's how can we keep the aviation
industry that looks after pretty much
all of us around the globe as safe as it
has ever been it's currently pushing out
some really good numbers on growth and
we need to secure it as we push forwards
with digitizing and connecting I've got
two amazing panelists here and we'll
introduce them in a minute but really
when we're talking about how we do this
then I couldn't ask for a better
panelists it's a really complex topic of
how we secure the aviation industry for
the cyber threats we've got this is the
report that I wrote last year which goes
into a lot of the challenges so so my
hope is that if you want to learn more
about it then please dig into it it's
available online just Google finding
lift minimizing drag it comes up but
what we're trying to achieve here is a
safe and prosperous aviation industry
with resilient trust and systems we've
got to focus on maintaining that safety
because if we look at what we're
digitizing and what we're connecting on
the aviation industry now it's
everything from aircraft air traffic
control airports UAVs all of the flying
personal transport that we're looking at
we've got the supply chain everything
from 3d printing all the way out to how
we look at the satellites for the
communications and then top left in that
picture is actually a remote air traffic
control tower where the people who are
keeping the aircraft safe in and around
the rep or actually aren't at the
airport they're miles away so this is
just a snapshot of how we're digitizing
the industry and what that has done to
the attack surface is make it large and
complex and securing that is going to be
something that's going to take more just
the aviation industry but also tying in
to the amazing research community
whether you're working for a company or
working independently and how we can
actually do that better and faster
together because one of the things that
that you look at when you've got
perspectives of where we are at the
moment is and these are some quotes that
people have said about cyber security
aviation industry
about whether you look at the quote top
left which is we've got a real problem
here and we're going to struggle to get
people to do something about it or it's
not possible to hack an aircraft or we
are secure but it's not possible we
don't want to say how secure we are how
we are secure but if we flip that back
to 1970s when the aviation engineer is
trying desperately to improve its safety
record
you'd get perspectives like it's going
to take a major incident before we learn
how to fix this and improve ourselves
it's just not possible to have an
incident and we are safe but we're just
not going to tell you how we're safe
the industry has matured a lot now it's
a lot safer and we've got to start
moving away from the fact that this will
get better by itself and we'll be able
to cope we've got to be proactive in
making this work across the entire
industry but trying to get the
vulnerabilities understood fixed and
managed when you've got that complexity
and sort of target audience of
stakeholders is something that's going
to be a real challenge and that's why
it's a massive honor to have we've got
Jeff Troy and John Sheehy here so Jeff
runs the global aviation Isacc so that's
not just thought a u.s. one it's the
global aviation highsec and he's got
customers all over the world and John
with ioactive Dave got a lot of
experience in trying to look at
vulnerabilities across the industry so
we'll have a quick chat and go through
the panel and then we'll open out
questions the first question I've really
got is the nature of the challenge we're
facing is is really difficult everyone's
got a different perspective but first of
all to to you Jeff is what do you see is
the nature the challenge we've got right
now well I'd say probably the the first
challenge that we have is you have a
research community that likes to go out
test and try different things and when
you look at the aviation system one of
the pieces of the aviation ecosystem
moves at about 500 miles an hour and
carries a lot of people on it so when it
comes to people going out and trying to
do research on on
on an actual plane that's certainly a
challenge because that's not a safe
environment for trying to do research
and yet naturally when you have people
doing research they find things that
people want to take a look at so so
trying to find an environment where
people who are curious can have an
opportunity to look at things is a real
challenge I think that's a key a key
piece there one good thing I know from
from from the industry from work in our
members particularly very aggressively
thanks to a lot of work that ioactive
and John cheese teams have been doing is
is to know that that the aviation
companies and you've talked about right
the 70s they looked at the number of
accidents that were going on and they
extrapolated it based on how many people
they thought would be flying on planes
and how many flights there would be and
they figured that you know 20-25 years
from from the 70s there'd be an accident
a day based on how many there were a
year and they took the the space for
error and and moved it you know to the
point where you know flying is now the
safest way to travel so they have that
perspective that safety perspective that
is pretty much driving the same adoption
of digital systems onto the plane where
they have a lot of redundancies a lot of
multiple check type processes in place
that pretty much give them you know a
greater level of assurance that those
systems that are protecting the flight
safety are are resilient and and can
operate you know regardless of anybody
trying to attack them thanks to that and
really what what items or hearing the
right there at the very start was how do
you harness that creativity safely in
something which is a safety critical
industry and John with all of the
researchers that you've got across
ioactive and
perspectively you've had on this is how
do you manage that that challenge of
being able to find those vulnerabilities
and actually work on them responsibly so
that's always a challenge there's a
number of issues to be able to look at
cyber physical systems in a safe way and
you really need to understand the
physical impacts of those cyber physical
systems so you can design an environment
where you can safely do that or if
you're operating a live environment know
what the limitations of what you can do
are and know it very very clearly and
that's especially important in an
industry like aviation where if there is
an incident it can very quickly turn
catastrophic you know we've done work on
on ground vehicles passenger vehicles
and if there is an incident the the
outcome of that incident is is
relatively small compared to the
potential for an incident in the
aviation world so those those are key
things that's really understanding what
the acceptable parameters are and it
does take a lot of information domain
knowledge about the particular
environments to be tested and while our
our focus is on the cybersecurity side
we do go to the level of understanding
the physical processes perhaps an
industrial control system or
understanding vehicle operation what
systems are critical to vehicle
operation what systems are not critical
vehicle operation so a a reasonable
prudent risk aware set of guidelines can
be created so that work can be done
safely and do so in a way that builds
trust with the manufacturers and users
of those products and we want to make
sure that we are sharing detailed actual
information in a way to responsibly
bring light to some of the concerns so
that the the representative stakeholders
can go forward to get the resources they
need to address those those challenges
one of the other things that that's
important to understand is sometimes
when you're looking at a cyber physical
system there are layers of safeguards
and and and while our focus maybe on the
the cyber security issues or the digital
aspects of that system frequently there
are
non-technical controls in place whether
the physical or policy or operational
that may reduce the impact of our
particular technical finding on a
cybersecurity issue and it's extremely
important to understand and
contextualize that risk what we don't
want to ever say is we got shell we can
do all these things because that's
probably not the case and you need to
understand for example in an ICS system
in the refinery
there are fiscal controls that don't
allow those systems go over pressure and
having that context and that deep domain
knowledge are critical to being able to
provide a useful outcome of that
cybersecurity research so with the
layered safety aspects they're in in
place in the industry how are we really
going to look at building that that
trust because although the the cyber
security if it's compromising those
vulnerabilities there it shouldn't cause
a critical failure but there is still a
nervousness understandably from from
both the the stakeholder trust and
passengers trust and Industry Trust so
that could be a real blocker going
forward and trying to build up these
relationships so we can be better safer
so you know is that the only blocker
we've got right now or there there are
other blockers that we've got to try and
work through as an industry and says
they called us first and and stay with
the question if you want to so I think
for some of the reasons you talked about
the the aviation industry is a little
bit more insular than some of the other
other industries we we worked with and
so it does take a little bit longer to
build trust and they face a different
set of threats than the passenger
vehicle automobile industry faces the
the automobile industry doesn't face the
threats of bombings and vehicles it
doesn't face some of security threats
passenger vehicles aren't typically
hijacked and and when there is an
incident you're dealing with two to
three people four people rather than 300
400 500 and and so understanding the
context in which they operate is
important to having effective
communication so that empathy is
important understanding the particular
risks and challenges of that industry
of the members and stakeholders at
industry the airlines verse an airframe
manufacturer versus an avionics supplier
is all very important
are there other challenges certainly I
think some of the good of the aviation
industry has been this this really
singular focus on safety what what that
has allowed is these digital
transformations that you talked about
are taking place is there is a focus on
specific aspects but they may not take
the broader look and that's where
engaging the research community engaging
people who have a different perspective
a diversity of thought adds a lot of
value doing so in a transparent way is
also important everyone wants to build
more trust in the operation of the
aircraft in the operation of the
Airlines the way you do that is you talk
about potential problems you you
reasonably categorize the risk while
there may be a digital exploit or a
cybersecurity issue what does it really
mean for safety what does it mean for
privacy
how should privacy be addressed vers
safety and and having those greater
context allows the industry to be more
effective um and on that trust issue
traditionally or there there's been a
lot of cases where the that relationship
between the research community in the
aviation industry has been has been
fraught through - there's been killing
and I understand exactly why it's been
fraught for various reasons Jeff you and
I have spoke about that with the work
you've done to try and increase trust in
all of your customers so you can share
data good data about threats and
vulnerabilities a lot faster is there
anything you've seen from building trust
across your customers that you think
would be able to help bring in the
research community and actually help
sort of learn lessons from a loss or
wider perspective yes so we've had a lot
of success I'd say in the past three
three and a half years now that aviation
ice axe
out there almost four years slowly
building that's that that trust and it
really requires a lot of personal
engagement so we've brought people
together from right now
you know our members are on five
different continents and four times a
year we're bringing folks together to
have face-to-face conversations and then
you know we surround all that with daily
engagement through our our other
services that we have but we have we
have rarely seen a marked increase in
what we term in the aviation I sac as as
wins where people are recognizing
information that was shared by somebody
else and deemed it important that's
that's really how we measure our
effectiveness and you know seeing that
growth of wins occur really helps to
develop that trust when it comes to
product security there's a challenge all
the time between intellectual property
and security and where's that balance
going to be where hey I can't tell I
can't show you this and have you helped
me secure it because if I do then my
secret sauce is going to get weak doubt
to you right so how do I find that
balance so we found many of our members
engage privately with companies like
ioactive and other researchers that that
go out there and they come in because
they're not stuck in the paradigm of the
company they're not from their
engineering group they're not they're
cyber group they've just come in and and
they they do that red teaming on their
equipment so that they can get that
outside perspective and maybe have
somebody find some that was missed well
we do have though is people sharing
processes what are you doing about
quality controls how you handle in
supply chain risk even how do you handle
your your red teaming engagements and
things like that we have a lot more
conversations going on now where people
are sharing those best practices and
that really helps again drive I think
increased security we call it kind of
raising
raising the skills of everybody wait no
all boats lift it up as opposed to just
one or two players getting getting more
skilled as all those players get skilled
also it's not just the plane right I
mean the aviation ecosystem is
everything we said there traffic control
the airport the ground traffic control
the services everything that's being
digitized and analytics and the Internet
of Things devices or services that are
being added you know every every time
you add another thing you add another
risk and so the more that the companies
are sharing the challenges around these
risks the the more that the best ideas
can be shared and people can can get
more secure I'm so in order to make us
more secure in the industry and finding
those vulnerabilities as fast as
possible working on them patching them
yes it can take a while for patches to
go out across industry but that's being
worked on to make that faster but if you
could try and give advice to the
community about how to engage and what
they can offer
what would you sort of and it's all sort
of final points before we open up to the
audience I think there's there's kind of
two points for different to different
parts of the audience and so on the
aviation side as Jeff mentioned having
the right secure development process
having a rigorous repeatable process you
follow to assess the security from
design to implementation and maintenance
is critical from the research community
I think it's very important we work very
closely on rubens most recent research
with the aviation Ishak to make sure
that we had experts in the particular
knowledge domains who were providing
feedback on potential impacts of the
cyber vulnerabilities he discovered that
those are really critical and it's much
more challenging for an independent
researcher to be able to do a
responsible disclosure if you need to
disclose to 20 or 50
more entities even an organization like
ours with significant resources a
dedicated legal team people who are
responsible for coordinated responsible
disclosure it can be very tough to get
to everybody and do so in the right time
and so one of the things that we've
really seen in partnering with with Jeff
and the AI sac is they were able to get
us in many cases to have a conversation
with the right people in a very very
short amount of time so I would
encourage the researchers who are doing
independent work you know to engage with
those right entities and I really can't
say enough about the value of the Isacc
that's fostering trust and communication
and knowledge sharing within the
community the next step both for us as a
set of researchers in the computer
security space and the Isacc is for us
to partner up in a way that will let the
aviation industry get get used to us us
used to the aviation industry and
produce better results for all the
stakeholders just want to say fun also
words on that for now yeah I would kind
of emphasize exactly you know what John
said and I really think this exercise
that we went through in the last
two-and-a-half months or so was a
win-win for both of us
we were we were able to get very
important information there were changes
that had to be made by companies to
secure things but at the same point in
time the researchers were able to get a
little bit more context so they could
better understand what it is that they
had and that's important I think for
everyone because the industry obviously
wants to make sure that anybody that has
found something that they think could be
an issue that that we're addressing it
and that's all that they understand
again I guess that context around it
because there are so many other controls
and John mentioned also in aviation that
are outside of that that just that
digital component that helped keep that
safety resilient system work very much
now I'm gonna up to the audience
stand up and oh just I was curious if
that ever is plays a role in there was a
that sought to secure certain components
of flight control software in a drone
follow those successful things go hand
you'll nodding away don't say this yeah
I'm familiar with it
sure so the question was about what are
the form of methods applied to secure
engineering design of avionics systems
and used within the aviation industry
specifically the asker of the question
asked about hakam's which is a DARPA
project which was focused not only on
applications in the the unmanned aerial
system space but also in other systems
and it was intended to ensure that there
was reliable execution and so it has
buried depending on the systems and then
of specific application within aviation
you're far more likely to see those
formal methods used in military systems
than in commercial and certainly general
aviation systems the formal methods do
you have a lot of advantages one of the
fundamental problems as we talk about
assurance whether we're talking about
software or more complex cyber-physical
systems is it's it's an np-hard problem
and being non polynomial in terms of
time
you cannot necessarily exhaustively test
all the potential vulnerabilities and so
even looking at something like hakam's
that's one component of a broader system
and so his attackers we look to exploit
wall
abilities in the systems even if
particular components are extremely
secure and and sometimes that may be a
human element and maybe you display
information to a human to make them take
an action because that's what they were
trained for that produces in a fact so
absolutely I think it's good that we're
seeing significant efforts made to
improve the component security but you
can't get away from looking at the
overall system or system of system
security and that's one of the beauties
about the aviation industry is that all
of those safety elements are layered so
vulnerabilities in one layer might not
necessarily actually call something
which is critical okay I'll pass it over
for next question yeah go for it we're
trying to smash through the questions as
much as we can because it we don't have
much time basically tackling the weakest
link risks so you have some stakeholders
on this who operate on extremely thin
margins and don't have a lot of extra
money to invest and securing all of
those stuff but they're also some of
your people who are relied upon by all
the other Airmen and in systems just
things right so I'm kind of wondering
what is the ice act doing to try and
identify where those systemic risks
exist and how to shore up those weaker
links it may not necessarily bring and
deliver late the level of revenue
probably more than every year that they
can spend on okay it so the question
basically is what's the ice act doing
really to help everyone because not
everyone's got the big budget right for
security and safety so again one of the
great things about the Isacc is we have
air framers airlines satellite companies
service companies airports everybody in
between the supply chains that are
members and because of the way I sacks
work and the agreements they are able to
do exactly what it is that you're
talking about as opposed to having
monopoly issues and and things like that
because we're not talking about prices
of routes we're not talking about
how you gonna set your seats up or
anything like that or just talking about
the security for everything so having
the air framers in there with the
airline see the operators of that allows
for exactly that type of discussion to
occur the air framers are the ones that
are pretty much doing that from the
design it begins at design then build
and test and operate and the big thing
is as you build all that and you hand it
off right there comes a point in time
where those who have designed and built
have now have to give it to those who
operate and this discussion in the
building of the trust is allowing for in
that free-flowing discussion of what is
it that you all are doing once you've
gotten that part of the issue that's
come up if you get a chance to see
Rubens talk tomorrow has to do with
hands off of equipment because it goes
from someone who's built it to someone
who installs it to maybe someone who
replaces it puts in another type of
system and each of those opportunities
is also an opportunity for someone to
make a security error and so things like
continuous monitoring when it comes to
what's considered a resilient system
have really has really kind of come to
the forefront I think that's probably
one of the biggest things that's come
out of the last couple of months you
can't accept anything as resilient right
we all know you have to do continuous
monitoring and ensuring that that's
happening even on systems that you think
are delivered resilient is is a big part
of that now okay so the aim really is to
try and make sure that we can find those
vulnerabilities maintain the systems
resilient and as profitable and safe as
it has been really across all of those
stakeholders and make sure we can do it
in a way that the the research community
is is brought in in a positive manner I
think we can do it I think that with the
work of the Isacc and and companies like
ioactive and all the other research
community I think we've run out of time
Mac sorry actually what we'll try and do
is
try and make sure that we can actually
find those processes and those
relationships and building trust so he
can take this forwards
I'll give final sore comments to both of
you but they everyone we've we saw will
be hanging around afterwards so he can
answer questions if we miss chief for
example sorry render man and then we'll
hopefully pass over but final words to
the panelists please I would I would
just say over the last couple of months
we've been very actively involved
actually with a couple of researchers so
you know we were mentioned with with
Ruben and ioactive
but we've had other engagements here
where this model of somebody coming in
disclosing something to the aviation
Isacc has helped them specifically
because by by getting with us we were
able to get them connected to the right
people right away which was very
important for both us and them again
context for the researchers and
awareness on the aviation side but the
other thing that I think is really
important and we're seeing it is when
the vulnerability is found in one
product if you go to that one company
and disclose it to them give them a
chance to fix it and they fix it and
then it goes public I think there's
still a lot of risk in industries where
other companies maybe they didn't have
that exact same functionality but they
probably have some similar type of
functionality and the methodology that
was used to uncover that risk
we believe in the aviation industry
should be shared amongst the industry so
all of the other people who design and
build to perform that same function can
make sure that they don't have that same
risk because you know we're talking
again about a huge safety issue a huge
economy and by having everyone be able
to we look at what's going on then and
then making it public I think we've done
a more responsible thing in terms of
safety and security in the industry and
I can I can say for sure that the
information that was shared you know the
companies that were involved in this
thing immediately made their their
Corrections but we know of many other
companies that had shared with us that
it made them relook and rethink and
start to go back and challenge
themselves and that I think is a win
again for everybody so I know we're
we're out of time I would say you know
we work with a number of other ice axe
and the I sac is something that's a
little bit new to a lot of cybersecurity
researchers but it's a very very very
valuable tool for engaging with those
stakeholders are exposed to the risks of
the research so thank you very much for
coming everybody it's a topic which will
not go away and I'm looking forward to
discussing this lots more besides going
forward but please can I speak to us
afterwards and and hopefully we'll
explore this to get it better thank you
[Applause]