hi everyone I am with the CTO and the
father of insular with me is Omri inside
of the research team leader and security
researcher what we'll talk about today
is basically how to bypass the current
mitigations in Windows 10 pretty much
all the mitigations that are currently
there so we'll start with a bit about
current mitigations and state of
exploitation around them and then we'll
cover a bit how memory management works
and how it relates on virtualization
comes in with VPS and km ci is it
required for the rest of the talk move
on to the technique itself that we call
interning tables show demo and
mitigations so over the past years
Microsoft is spending a lot of effort
improving its kernel mitigations and
doing quite a good job about that so as
you can see in the table quite a few
mitigations that were added and
constantly being added as Windows then
progress also they improve some of the
features the mitigations on the one for
example case allow it proved
significantly since Windows 8 and by now
pretty much everything in the kernel is
under mice to one point or another
now also features that depend on VBS for
example AFCI which we'll cover more in
depth later and case efg can control
flow integrity the bottom line is that a
lot of efforts on that and that led to
many new exploitation techniques and a
lot of talk over the past years that
cover how to bypass these mitigations
last year in blackhat there was a very
good talk about how to bypass colon
mitigations
however this
as far as we've seen none of the
mitigation the bypass techniques that
were presented so far also deal with
mitigation such as key MCI and other
various types of mitigations so now a
bit about memory management so pretty
much every modern operating system
nowadays you should use a virtual memory
basically virtual memory is just a
translation form and others to the
actual physical address in memory which
is done by the MMU the idea behind it is
well there are a lot of uses one of them
is if you enable very large other space
when the physical memory is actually
much smaller poster size solution and a
lot of other things we'll cover some of
them in this presentation so how does
the translation actually works so if we
take this 64 bit others for example and
we'll break it down we will see the
translation works pretty much like that
so first you take the caco3 register
control register 3 which points the base
of the page table and add the 9th bit
the 9 bit from the night thirty-ninth
bit in the others pay others to the the
base of the page table and this is
actually a pointer within the PML for
which points to a page directory what's
called the page directory point opt P so
then you take the next 9 bit and use it
as an offset within that table and from
there it points to the page directories
again take the next 9 bit use it is
offset in that directory and again in
the page table where we finally get to
what's called the PT which is page table
entry which points to the actual
physical address which can also be
referred to as a PFN which is a physical
page frame number now so as you can see
the lower 12-bit are not being used in
the translation and this is actually the
page size the offset between the page
which means that the page side is in
this case for K actually there are also
large pages but it's not really critical
to understand the rest of the talk so I
won't go into that so we have pity's PT
is not content not contained only the
physical address they actually contain
other bits that are used by the
operating system to control permissions
on the page and other things for example
the lowest bit it's a bit hard to see
but it's a valid bit so if it's not
valid its points to nothing there is a
right bit which means that the page is
writable not executed and all that they
also built the result for the operating
system memory management as you can see
from the 40s bit from the 52 bit the
width being used by the operating system
to manage memory now because to pity's
can have the same pfn which means that
they point to the same physical address
it also means that the same physical
page can have different permissions in
different memory others as of different
processes so this is essentially how
shared memory works and why it's
possible to make the same page
executable in one process while it's
writable in another process which is
important to understand because it's
we're gonna talk about it a lot later on
so just a few words about prototype PT
is
although pretty is pretty much specific
to Windows in a sense and well the only
thing that's really important to
understand about them is that they what
Windows uses for shared memory basically
each shared PT is a prototype PT which
for example contains the number of time
it is being shared this can be used for
for the operations to know when it can
remove the page and generally control it
and I'll talk about it more later on now
the next thing I'm going to talk about
is copy-on-write and pretty much how it
works so in Windows for example every
DLL that's being mapped is by default so
if you took it kernel32.dll which are
mapped in pretty much all memory in all
processes the the code for example
starters share so they point to the same
physical page which makes sense for
efficiency point of view because then
you don't need to waste much physical
memory for the DLL for the others that
are marked in many processes however a
poses can change the code or read only
data in its own address space and in
these cases the operating system needs
to make sure that it doesn't change the
cost possesses because well that can
definitely cause a problem because if
you change the code in one process in
the facts the code in another process it
can be the source of bad things so what
the operating actually does when the
process asks to change permission on
such page is to for example to make it
writable is not to actually make it
writable but to use one of the software
which I mentioned earlier
in order to mark it as a copy-on-write
page now when the right actually happens
the operating system handles the fault
that happens because the page was not I
type also there was a fault it sees that
it's a copy-on-write page and then what
happens is that the page is being copied
and the PT now points to the copy of the
page and the right happens there so the
change only happens in the specific
process in its private memory and not
globally across the operating system now
when we also have your Chua's asian
involved there is another level of
translation of the second level address
translation and the goal is basically to
make sure that virtual machine cannot
temper with each other memory I guess
it's obvious why we want to keep operate
virtual machines isolated from each
other so there is a what's called a
guest physical address which later
translates by the what's called an apt
to a machine physical address it's like
another level of translation so we
petits how it's called in intelli
processors or npt in AMD processors and
it also adds potentially another level
of optimization because if the
hypervisor control those virtual
machines know that 2 pages are actually
the same it can point them to the same
physical memory so the optimization can
exist in even across virtual machines
and still keep the isolation intact
now as you can also see they also have
permission of those pages so when if it
is if it is being used the actual page
permission is determined on that level
so if a page is not executable on the PT
level it is not executable at all now
Microsoft uses that
with many other things to create the VPS
of virtualization based security so what
they basically did so the hypervisor
manages the virtual the other kernels
virtual machines and each kernel lives
in its own VTL VTL is a virtual trust
level now the least privileged trust
level is the lowest level so VTL 0 is
less privileged in VTL 1 and basically
what you see when you walk on the
computer is the the right end of this
diagram
it's where the regular kernel runs and
all your applications and that's VTL 0
now the secure kernel the skm on the
left hand side is what actually holds
the power and what manager can manage
the apts and the real permissions in the
other side of the less secure world and
that's enables medications like hvc i hv
c i is i provides our code integrity
which is actually split into kind of two
policies one is camp CI which is kernel
mode code integrity the other is um CI
which is the same thing for user mode
and the idea is to ensure that the code
in india with Kensie enabled the code in
the kernel cannot be modified or even
executes unless it was authorized and
authorized actually means that it was
signed properly based on the policy that
is defined so the DLL that does this is
a SK CI it
it's what verifies the integrity and
whenever a new driver or any types of
code is being loaded into the kernel it
must be first validate otherwise it
cannot run it will not get the execute
bit on the apt and once it got the
executed bit it cannot be modified
because as I
and earlier the page would not be
actually writable even if the operating
system marks it as shot as such unless
it is marked to be writable on the apt
as well okay
so to quickly recap all that basically
virtual virtual memory management is
done by both hardware and software I
mean everything that Windows is doing
must be supported by the hardware to
walk for example if virtualization is
not a numbered clearly VPS cannot be
enabled and it's also the basis for many
things like shared memory or the ability
to do flexible physical memory
management but also the way that the
advanced mitigations work such as HV CI
credential guard is based on the same
things and secure memory enclave's and
many other things that microsoft is keep
lending to the operating system ok ok so
now that we covered our basics we need
to understand what we want to achieve
what is our general motivation here so
if we look at every privilege escalation
exploit that is out there right now or
at least most of them at some point in
their execution in their operation they
run a payload in kernel mode which now
becomes a problem because key mci
effectively prevents it as we said we
cannot create new code in the kernel and
know we can modify existing one so we
kind of have a problem here
most of previous publications kind of
assume it wasn't enabled this is because
it wasn't relevant
up until now mostly and proud and
basically our the real goal here is to
able to
to be able to achieve code execution we
test possible privileges usually a
kernel mode but for our for our
intensive purposes we can be good enough
and we can use we can get to a state
that we run as a system user the reason
for that is that at this point Microsoft
does not consider it as a defensible
boundary the quality is taken from a
tool that was released I think yesterday
don't quote me on that maybe the day
before that by Alex UNESCO and that the
released tool utility for whoever wishes
to execute kernel-mode code from a user
mode without any driver being involved
in the process and the only thing you
need is basically an administrator
account or a system account so we're
going to cover our technique which we
named is which we named as Turning
Tables basically we need to understand
what we actually need in order to
execute it so once we found a
vulnerability that allows us to be able
to achieve read and write primitives if
you look at it from a developer
perspective it means that we have
functions that we can supply them with
virtual address and data either to read
or write from kernel mode and do that
from the user space this is very common
in pretty pretty much every mod and
exploit and that's all we need so to
understand the concept and basically
what we are going to do is utilize these
primitives and make a shirt code page in
user mode we're going to flip a bit in
its PT and make it right to go it's a
very
simple operation just flipping one bit
and in that way we will be able to avoid
the copy-on-write mechanism now the
short code page need to be a one that
actually runs in other processes because
it is shared so we want to target a code
that also been used in system processes
next up after we made the code writable
in our own in our own process in the
origin process and we're going to change
the code however we like next we just
need to wait and then we're gonna run a
system it's very it's very simple a
simple concept and nevertheless we still
have some hurdles to overcome the first
one as we mentioned earlier page table
are now randomized and we some someone
need to be able to get their addresses
in order to go through the pts
themselves and we assume you can already
leak the base address for the kernel and
with your right primitive and there's a
lot of material on on on this topic
online so you could just find out about
it and there is a very convenient way to
find the PT base address using an
exported function in the kernel and
Microsoft was very kind to us you can
see that mmm get virtual for physical is
exported though it's undocumented and we
can still use it and the PT base is
marked there it's a bit hard to see the
value but it's a constant value and
which is which changes the every boot so
we can easily walk through the export
table once we have a real primitive and
the end of service address find the
function address and read this random
value now an additional method it can be
can be also growth we can also go
through em I get PT address this
function is an internal function and it
was presented this method
was presented in blackhat last year so
now that we managed to find the pities
for the a code we want to change in user
mode and we need to understand exactly
which code we're gonna change so first
up we need to understand which target
which process is going to be our target
meaning in the end of the process of the
exploit where we want to execute our
code so there are many processes that
run in system for example s be ciosed
which is a generic host for services in
windows win logon and else's which are
always processes that handle login in
authentication and of course pretty much
a v out there and out of the box on
Windows 10 we get a V different Windows
Defender now we don't necessarily have
to target system process on the start
but it will only make our road to a
complete escalation much longer now
another side effect that we might be
able to benefit from is that the fact
that sometimes system processes are
being excluded from a monitoring and
protection of some security products so
we might be able to avoid detection
afterwards so after we understand which
process we're going to target for
instance SVC host you need to understand
which specific DLL we're gonna we're
gonna need to change so target the
target that DLL cannot be a one that is
shared with VTL a 1 because VTL 1
protects every code that is being used
within that so for instance Keanu 32 is
not a very good candidate for that
purpose but because VTL 1 is a very
redacted zone because it has to be more
secure and this attack surface should be
more narrow it doesn't use any UI nor
that it does complex parsing and all
that you or it doesn't use
network capabilities so all of the
relevant dealers for that for those
systems subsystems can be very helpful
for us and preferably and we want the
dealer to or will already be loaded in
our origin process we just save us some
hassle from a quick search we did the
following for the others appear pretty
much in in most processes and our nut
shell with VTL zero and keep in mind the
first one it's very interesting for us
and we're going to continue talking
about it in the next slide so after we
decided which specific DL are we going
to change we need to understand exactly
how we can change it we need to find a
place that is shared but it's not used
obviously because if we make some
changes to it before were really
prepared it will make us a crash which
is ideally not a good thing to do once
one-for-one tries to run in kernel
exploit so for that instance we have
code caves caves in executable files are
quite common basically at the end of
each section of the executable there is
the unused space it's usually because
there are differences in page alignments
between virtual between the file page
size in virtual memory and sector size
on disk so using that these places are
very good so if we look at the code
section and we got a place that is
already shared it's unused
and it's executable so it's great for us
and makes it quite a straight fold well
we're gonna put our first payload so if
we continue on looking on our or a
targeted DLL only 32 DLL as I mentioned
earlier is quite a good candidate it has
over a half a page of code cave which is
quite a lot of space for an initial
shell code so after we decided to write
our shell code we need to understand how
can trigger it because as we said it's
in a place that it's not used so just
try thing it won't be enough so the
target module needs to be used quite
often in the tab in the target process
so our code that we write on we write
there would be eventually executed we
don't want it to be obvious too much
often because then overhead will be an
issue for us and we can also consider
places that may be triggered by the
origin process for instance we are in
RPC some operations from one process
requires communicating with a different
process which eventually may lead to a
path to a code path that will eventually
execute our own code and if we look at
the Alerus as we said we targeted the
DLL entry points for this kind of files
are very appealing
now the invoked on certain events such
as every thread start of thread creation
and haverford exit unless the DLS
specifically opted out from it now on
Windows 10 if you open Rockman for a
couple of seconds you can see that
services constantly create many threads
so it's great for us and specifically
because we target a DLL that Microsoft
built their own version of the C runtime
it's very easy to be to alter in order
to make to make the code reach our code
cave and there is a small jump at the
end of the main block between simply
need to write and change the add the
target address to get our own code in
the code cave so we are at the point
that our code can run but we need to
understand exactly how to build it
now because we write to a shared a page
that code can populate too many
different processes that we don't
necessarily know which which ones they
are and we don't control it so
because we assume that we run in a
limited sandbox process and we don't
specifically know the target process ID
but since we already run code inside the
target process it's very easy to check
the process name and to a very verified
username in which in under which account
it runs and then if it's if it it's if
it's good for us we can simply continue
on running now since we also run in
multiple processes and we don't run our
payload to run only once more than one
section we can simply synchronize all of
the different instances by trying to
obtain a named mutex once we start the
first one with that we'll be able to do
that we'll just continue on to the main
payload now because the code cave is
quite small in size and we need to be
able to do some more complex operations
so we want more code which is usually
larger than the code cave size and we
can either map it and get it from the
origin process or directly read it from
its memory or we can just fetch it from
a remote machine and now that we run
into bleach process it's much easier so
if I need to quickly recap and walk
through the technique with a concrete
concrete example and we have the
hypervisor that protects the kernel we
have hyper-v particular on the right we
have an instance of an SVC SVC host
process that is using oily 32 DLL and
for example and we get a sandbox process
with an instance of edge browser next up
after we leverage the vulnerability that
we found hopefully we're gonna use a
read and write primitives that we
established and make the short code page
is writable in the origin process then
we can write the initial payload to the
code
Jeff which will populate to the rest of
the processes and we're gonna continue
and manipulate the DLL and main entry
point in order to make the code execute
at a certain point then and then we only
need to wait the code is already all the
changes are already done we simply need
to wait for a thread to be created in
the target process and the code will
start running then it will load up the
rest of the payload and do whatever we
like and now for a very nice demo
hopefully so we got here a virtual
machine
it's the latest Windows RS for version
it's updated I think last week to last
week which is the most up most current
and up-to-date and so unfortunately for
us
fortunately kind of depends on how you
look at it and we don't have an actual
working exploit here and there is no
actual volume ability that we can use so
we have to use our own driver in order
to simulate the read and write
primitives that's why we entered the
system into test mode you can see it on
the side here and now if we look at the
at the secure the VBS features that are
enabled we can see that we have the idea
visor and forced code integrity on and
running now we're gonna start our our
simulation
okay it's gonna take up a second okay so
basically we load it only loaded oily
and 32 DLL up until this point we didn't
really actually do anything now if we
take a look at the address on the system
information process that I'm already
touch to we can see it's empty you're
gonna continue on and at this point the
shellcode the initial shellcode was
supposed to be loaded and populated into
the entire into every passes that also
loads up only 32 DLL and we can see that
it's actually happened and the code
actually changed in a process that it's
different from our own so basically what
we're going to look for now at our shell
code does its load up a payload DLL from
C Drive so we're gonna open process
Explorer
it's a bit sluggish the the nested VM on
the VMware doesn't work that fast okay
still no success means that the code
still didn't run in the SVC host process
try and help it a bit with user
interaction that may may cause a service
to actually run and we can see our code
started if we look at the specific
process you can see that SBC host which
runs under system actually loaded up
around DLL
okay so if we just compare it to how it
works versus mitigation so basically
we've shown that by passing page table
and organization is not really an issue
when you once you have a rate relative
so this is maybe a bit of extra walk but
not really hard to do and the other kind
of more advanced mitigations like kernel
control flow and CFG control for garden
is just not relevant because we don't
really need to execute system code we
just wanna run a system in some other
process and the same goes for chem CI we
just don't need to mess with it we just
keep on to the to running a system and
if you compare it to other kind of
techniques that Fork is that don't
require code execution for example like
tokens stealing so there are several
downsides of tokens stealing one to one
a lot of security products so they try
to monitor it on rs.5 windows defender
system guard is also gonna try to
monitor it it also requires a lot
relatively a lot of operation you need
to traverse the processes in the system
in order to do it and in to do it
without a kernel shell code is also
quite dangerous in the sense that it may
lead to a crash and as we've shown the
concept here is relatively simple we
don't do any complex operation to me in
order to make it work
it's just relatively a few simple steps
and it's running another thing is that
usually when you do some kind of remote
exploitation you start off in some kind
of sandbox either at Chrome or whatever
and then you usually want to migrate to
some other process because the browser
process is probably not going to live
very long and it's kind of suspicious
driver telling its system and all kinds
of other reasons so
usually a next step will be to migrate
to some somewhere else and using this
technique you don't need to migrate
because you're already running in in a
process and from our test you can also
target protected processes possible
mitigation is to use um CI which
effectively means that the prototype
pages of usermod processes cannot be
changed because actually generally code
cannot be changed because it's like km
CI just in user mode but this is not
really a good solution because at least
to our knowledge there is not a single
organization that can actually work with
this because it requires pretty much
every code running to be signed so we
don't see that actual solution and other
possibilities to prevent modification to
prototype pages this should be not that
hard to do because VBA so it does that
for code that is shared with video 1 so
at least for the way we implant
implemented the technique in this case
it should be a good solution so even
with all mitigations walking it's still
possible to write a little really simple
I persist to current mitigations
we checked in it's also works on RS 5
and latest insider build and that said
we think Microsoft is doing a job in
developing new mitigations it definitely
makes exploitation harder but still
holds there we suggested some of the
mitigations to Microsoft we didn't get
expunged yet we also think that it can
be useful to even when
mci is not enabled because you don't
need to find useful candle pointers or
function pointers to finish exploitation
or anything like that and it makes it
makes things easier and even if
mitigations like set which is in tells
how the enforced control flow integrity
was working it would still work because
you don't really need to mess with the
control flow you just write your code
and it will work and you can also use
those tricks and other operating systems
it's not really limited to Windows we
just used it on Windows because it was
the most challenging in order to
probably bypassed dis mitigations the
same should walk in linux and our six as
well for example and that's pretty much
it so if there are any questions
[Applause]
first thanks for your talk I enjoyed it
a lot regarding the need for the
synchronization among instances this
isn't a mitigation or but wouldn't the
use of OS level synchronization
primitives IPC things make it an easy
target for an adaptive IDs to detect
that the exploit was going on unexpected
semaphore is being created that weren't
part of the pattern that that was
expected to be seen no just just to
detect that the system is being
exploited and isolated intrusion
detection not not mitigation yeah not
prevention okay there questions there's
one
why can the process running in user mode
right to the table entries and actually
set it to to do the copyrights should
that be protected and only the colonel
during the memory management be able to
modify that yeah just because otherwise
things like this would cause security
boundaries so the operating system uses
it to prevent such things I mean the
copy-on-write is just done to preserve
the optimization of memory
[Music]
now I'm wondering if a viable detection
from user space would be if you could if
you could detect that the page table was
being shared it was not write copy by
may be doing dummy writes in two places
where you know you know you should
receive a write copy your own private
copy in your process I'm wondering if
there's a way to detect this somewhere
there from user mode well we don't have
we didn't have any idea how to detect it
solely from user mode you you can detect
that code most modified if you but the
problem is to know when to check it well
to check it exactly I mean we use the
specific DLL but it can be any other
dealer and you also need to know when to
check it this is not there is no some
kind of notification that you can use to
know when to do it
okay thank you very much for your guys
talk appreciate it