so I'm going to talk about information
operation campaigns on social media that
are designed to disseminate false leaks
and we're going to look at a couple
examples from the past two years this is
a snapshot of a broader research
endeavor on our end so I'm quite excited
to be sharing some of it with you but
I'm also quite nervous and intimidated
about that um so there are three phases
in these false leaks and I think it's
important to separate them and consider
how they work with one another the first
one in so this is when the threat actor
is going to compromise its target and
obtain the data that will later be
presented as leaks it's important that
we use the term false leaks because here
we mean false in at least two census the
first census it's false because it's not
what is traditionally considered a leak
as an intentionally disseminated
material this is material that's being
stolen so the examples we're gonna go
through are gonna be doping uniques DNC
leaks and Mac Points so it's not an
intentional disclosure it's stolen
material and it's false in that sense
the other sense in which it can be false
as the leak itself the material that's
going to be disseminated can be
falsified so it can include fake emails
for instance in the data that's going to
be disseminated citizen lab has coined a
term that I like a lot to talk about
that it's tainted leaks the idea is you
have a forest of truth but then elements
of falsehoods that are included in the
set that's going to be disseminated so
that's the hacking face the second part
is the publication phase and this goes
to how the information is going to be
made accessible to the public
and this can actually have different
flavors and different types of actors
involved who may or may not be linked to
the original thread actors that
conducted the hacking so if you look at
DC leaks for instance it's hosted on its
own website it's it's published on its
dedicated website you can also publish
the material on bite by giving it to
websites that specialize in this so of
course here WikiLeaks come to mind and
in the case of mechanics there's also
now onto the third phase which is
dissemination how information gets
promoted and disseminated and this is
where we're going to be most focused on
today and so when you consider the end
goal of the dissemination phase it's
really two to a more organic
conversation is to initiate artificially
something that's going to end up being
an organic political debate and this is
what gets complicated and fascinating
about false leaks because often the
material is legitimately interesting and
so a conversation that starts as being
inorganic and manufactured ends up being
a true political legitimate conversation
online and so if we look at information
operations assets that are known to have
disseminated falsely comes to mind is
the internet research agency so here
what you're seeing is all the hashtags
that have been disseminated by the IRA
on Twitter and they're organized by
volume on it and verse the other and so
on the top left corner you have things
that they have talked about all the time
but with great consistency they're sort
of like woven into all the messages that
they have targeted at the
english-speaking audiences so news local
right after that actually in the set you
can see it here becomes sports so this
is kind of like the blueprint of how you
go and and
influence America you know news locals
first I was almost expecting to see like
burger out there and on the other side
you have operations so super high-volume
very V in one quick burst I climb in
chemicals who might be familiar to some
of you right this first operation that
they tested in 2015 things that they
really push but in one go
and highlighted in the sets you see
hashtags that are related to false leads
and here you see they're actually one of
the key explanations for that is the
iron was not the only operation and
[Music]
there are two things that are important
on these accounts we see their public
traces but there's something else that
we don't necessarily see which is the
actions that they may have taken not in
their public traces and we know that for
instance they went and they actively
reached out to commentators and to media
for them to be part of the dissemination
campaigns of this leak saying hey this
creates an interesting challenge which
is how do you contrast and disambiguate
organic grassroots spontaneous social
media movements from manufactured
coordinated once fake stuff from real
stuff this is something that we graphic
and along with a few of our academic
partners have been working on for a
little while and the idea is we're
systemically contrasting legitimate
engineering political movements such as
a protest with organized response such
as a counter movement that for instance
would have been coordinated and
conducted by a troll farm now the core
hypothesis that is at the heart of this
work is that and they're going to seek
to replicate the diversity of a big
number of accounts they're going to fail
to do so on at least some of the
dimensions so they may manage to make
believe but if you look at enough
network dimensions you will see now our
Kannamma Lee's that will reveal the
coordination and the fabrication of the
movement and so we systematically study
those alongside three dimensions and the
way the intersect so the network
dimension how are the accounts who
participate connected to one another the
semantic dimension what is the nature of
their language patterns and the temporal
dimension how the it's easier of course
to see this at the campaign level than
it is to see this at the network level
the other thing that we look for when we
look at false leaks is how much the
original actors have blended or
disappeared from the dissemination
pattern are they still in the middle of
the conversation and the target
community is Right the communities you
want to influence are they still in the
middle of the conversation or have they
sort of been marginalized so this was
very abstract like look at how this
looks in concrete on a network map with
a first case study which is doping leaks
it's a some timeline that recaps the
first two phases from hacking and
publication your publication is done on
a dedicated website fenced bare da net
and this is the network map
of accounts who participate in the
dissemination so there's a few things
that are interesting in that Network map
first I can give you a little bit more
context on how we do that and this is on
Twitter this is a social media site on
the Twitter front these are the accounts
who share the hashtag dopey nice or who
shared the link to the publication
website that was hosting the documents
they are here a discovery process so we
make sure we grab the part of the
network that's the more relevant and the
tightly is connected and then by a
rationalization and clustering process
the clustering followership and so
accounts that are grouped together and
off the same color are together because
they highly follow one another which
tends to reveal interest based
communities so if you take one of them
for instance the German right-wing there
are called German white wing because
they are communicating in German
websites and they talk about German
right-wing topics right so they appeared
together as a coherent community from
the network pattern which you can see
remember that network map there was
something in the middle it was purple
and it was right in the middle of the
map and it was weird because it was a
spam cluster it was called spm social
media marketing and spam and I tell you
something I look at a lot of network map
spam clusters are not supposed to be in
the middle of the map these are for
higher accounts these are accounts who
yesterday was promoting viagra and today
are promoting dope unique science taught
today where two years ago but this is a
first thing that's shocking about this
network map is there's still a bulk of
the network that is spam remember things
around spam
there were also weird they were European
far-right communities
and the thing that we're actually
looking for this forest cluster right
the people who should be carrying the
waters on this conversation there's so
different girls with a conversation the
people that you seek to influence there
are really a very small portion of that
there only is when you look for the
media accounts right who are the media
we're talking about this famous doping
leaks that all the spam bots are
interested in they're not in that map
actually the only media of significance
is Sputnik in that map remember the IRA
and the GRU assets right those that we
know that have been attributed we're
able to see where they we're in the
dissemination we have any participated
in promoting disseminating doping leaks
along with 3ju accounts and they're
still very central in the network that
is disseminating these policies this is
really the IRA set that is a bit under
studied these day because it's the
russian-speaking I reset they're in the
Russian pro-government cluster and so
those would not be sort of the famous
IRA profiles and you know of those are
also in the map on the other side in the
pro-trump
us right clusters and then you have a
lot of other spare IRA assets and GRU
assets some in the B's and then some in
the pro-assad clusters who have decided
that suddenly they cared a lot about
doping in sports of course
this shows in the network anomalies
right because you have this very
active somewhat and successful attempt
to masquerade as a spontaneous campaign
but when you look at Network anomalies
you see that this doesn't really fit so
the expected pattern on the temporal
analysis here what we're showing is
these small squares show clusters who
participate in the campaign at the same
time and the expected pattern is a low
temporal coordination between those
clusters some of it is expected a lot of
it is odd the thing that's particularly
hot here is extremely high level of
temporal coordination across clusters
that are completely different in
interest that are not connected to one
another
and that are on completely different
time zones if you do semantic analysis
here we're looking at each user in the
map and we're trying to find their
semantic diversity score and so this is
a fun wrench because humans generally
fall in the middle here you have single
topic accounts so the cats who only talk
about one thing it's actually quite rare
people tend to have semantic diversity
even when they have a very committed
topic so this is oddity on the other
side as the other abnormal behavior
completely random topics this is
generally characteristic of spam just
because they tend to grab everything
that is peeking and so the human range
is generally the middle what you would
expect is to find most of your
participant in the human range here as
you can see we have a huge proportion of
single topic accounts which is also a
network oddity all that to say when we
look at doping lace is very clear that
the competing accounts are still very
visible and that the campaign still
bears the markers of something that's
very manufactured and coordinated now
let's look at the u.s. example with a
few false leaks targeting the 2016
presidential election here it's a bit
complex in
interesting and different because you
have a few actors involved in the three
different stages from the hacking to the
publication to dissemination alright and
we're gonna take DC leaks as sort of an
overarching factor as in these ceilings
the publication websites on which some
of these materials have been
disseminated oh it's interesting and
there's also dissemination on WikiLeaks
as a separate certain publication on
WikiLeaks as a separate publication
website I and the way the those leaks
are disseminated is also different from
the way they're both obtained initially
and published and so what we're gonna
find is different dips emanation
campaigns that are going to come and
push different subsets of the false
leaks the first one we can look at is D
CDs and so DC leaks here is users most
actively sharing that DC Knicks comm
website and the D Series hashtag so
that's a map that I like quite a lot
because it makes a point very clearly
which is that most of the dissemination
here is obviously happening on the back
of a hyper polarized network you see
those two big clusters the Bernie
support cluster in the Trump supporter
cluster we call them course they're very
tightly interconnected accounts they
have connection to one another though
there is one central group that acts as
a network bridge is the pro-russian
conspiracy not recruit so they're not
connected to each other but they're both
connected to this Russian
conspiracy they're really acts as a
network bridge between the two and so
that's the free thing this is a
destination that operates on the back of
the deeply fractured and polarized and
hyperactive network it's not only two
sides that don't talk to another it's
two super structured very well clustered
sides that don't talk to one another the
other thing that's interesting is when
you look at media note remember there
was almost none and openings here we
jump to almost 34% of the map is we saw
in that initial IRA graph of the
hashtags that the IRA accounts did
heavily participate in promoting
disseminating ID CDs the map that I just
showed you was constructed after those
accounts have been taken down so what we
did is a reconstruction of where those
IRA accounts where woven into the fabric
of the initial network that I just
showed you that was disseminating the D
CDs so this answers the question when
you look at this network how much of it
had been penetrated and influenced by
accounts that we now know are associated
with IRA injury and this is the yellow
nodes that you see on the back so those
are the active at that stage now all
inactive and attributed IRA accounts and
the thing that appears very clearly here
is you see how well woven into the
fabric that they were trying to
influence those accounts where
they're not woven uniformly throughout
the landscape so here they're very
central to the Trump group all right and
you see them both in their position in
the network and the size of the notes
the size of the notes here is going to
reveal how much of the group around them
it's following them so this is not just
a measure of influence in abstract oh
its influence in that Network so they're
very influential to that own network
they're densely connected across the
middle as you can see there's somewhat
influential through progressive
independent media clusters but they're
entirely absent from the Bernini group
and that's interesting because I know I
in my field a lot of people suspect that
that group specifically had also been
very affected and targeted by
information operations if that is the
case it wasn't by the IRA or not by
those known assets because they do not
reach into that group how much potential
helps really carry the water and then
to the polar ice let's eat so if we
change to dissipation through this we
can look at the Podesta Deeks
this was someone disseminated
differently you can think about it as
almost marketing this differently where
we did two different group resulting
networks match focus that's much more on
the right wing side of the landscape
this is a dissemination that really
lands on the political right wing part
of the landscape and so you see that
this is really by design and that they
go and they mention and engage the part
of the network that they want to further
engage around the dissemination with the
Podesta leaks is still going to be
Hillary Clinton but here you see that
they're about three times as many right
athlete it accounts that were mentioned
then accounts on the left which may
contribute to explain why now similar
publication point
so DC geeks.com I'm sorry that's a
chronotype so this this shows each group
when they engage with the hashtag the
thing that's quite fun here because
there is fun in network graphs I promise
[Music]
that's not normal
this is a very pulsating slow beat which
means that all the clusters are gonna
engage with the same hashtag at the same
time and at a regular pattern so this
still betrays marks of coordination
soresina interesting same publication
point also ends up on DC leaks
disseminated differently so by different
accounts and with a different focus this
brings in an entire different set of
clusters international clusters this
time still you see the pressure group
here that acts as a network bridge
alongside different communities of
mostly right and far-right groups in
Europe who have little connection to one
another but who are still connected to
the skort cluster there is also very few
footprints of I Ranger you known assets
in some of these network operations that
were later revealed by actors notably on
Facebook as to be part of Russian
operations to I'm thinking the inside
Syria Media Center do appear to be very
popular in some of these clusters so
back to this idea that maybe we're not
in control of the full picture of the
[Music]
that's the same thing
correcto here this tells you this entire
network is really engaged it's not like
the fringe clusters sort of dropped and
pushed it a little bit and dropped out
they remain engaged throughout the
entire dissemination phase
murmuring seventy different story on the
publication don't so what a potentially
comparable stirrer I think firm with
other elements we've seen before but on
the publication firm we have a file that
is dumped on a forum and the this
dissemination story is also quite
interesting so this is high ciders only
which means that this looks at the
accounts who are really committed to
pushing the story out who talked about
it five times or more and shared the
links you still see the central
pro-russian cluster it's written out
there in white but it's really the white
ducks in the middle the thing that's
most surprising and I think that's
surprised most of the people who
initially looked at it is in the early
face of the dissemination the activity
really comes from the US and so that
Trump group u.s. Trump support group in
green accounts for fifty three percent
of the activity in the first phase of
the dissemination of those needs it is
also a u.s. account first post are the
publication website
in u.s. groups and here we have very
little media clusters about 7% of the
nodes or media clusters only 4% is
French media the campaign does display
signs as being heavily coordinated this
one's interesting because the anomaly is
on the other side not a lot of one topic
accounts like we saw in doping AIDS but
a lot of completely random accounts that
suggest more automation more but like
which is supported by other metrics that
we've computed on that front temporal
dimensions same thing the anomaly is in
clusters who are completely different
time zones who have completely different
interests we're not connected to one
another but who really engage exactly at
the same time between all these
different maps something else that's
quite interesting is when we run node
overlaps between all these maps we find
a lot of accounts that are in common in
those dissemination campaigns even for
false leaks that have little to do in
substance with one another so we added
both seven and scope here just because
it's both in the IRA dissemination set
and because of the very high number of
overlaps with the other full sneaks
campaigns that we have seen in that set
you're done soon in science so that wrap
up quickly if you want to do information
operations and disseminate false takes
you really need to have accounts that
are woven into the fabric of the
conversation that you're trying to
influence you can't just you really need
to do this work of having accounts that
are well fell out and well imbedded in
the communities that you're targeting
now the good news in the flip side of
this is that that means that detection
and takedown matter this morning Iko
published a piece of DFR lab on a french
campaign that had been detected and
taken down by facebook who is still in
this audience building stage so you can
see them trying to gather the community
around them try and engage the community
that's seeking to target by talking
about completing inane things in half
and this sort of like early stage of
audience building is really key to
having acids that are later exploitable
and it's really important to be able to
go detect and take down leases the role
of media clusters so we saw from almost
none to doping leads to really heavy
involvement in the u.s. cases - back to
almost none in the French case which
comes with a lot of heavy contacts
because in France at least two things
really shape that map the first one
at that stage had already learned from
the tradecraft that we saw in both
doping eeks and DN c-- so a lot of
accounts have been detected and
deactivated including potential accounts
who may have been pitching to me down
that's one way in which media might have
been involved and the other obvious one
is in France we had a legal framework in
place that prevented media from touching
and covering those my colleagues it was
taken very seriously it's in place 48
hours before the election and the media
action
lastly attributed accounts doing this
research during this investigation isn't
possible if we don't have enough
attributed accounts to understand where
that's coming from
it's difficult we don't have so much we
have the bones we have two GRU ones we
found it really helpful to work from the
set and so carrying is sharing what we
did along with our partners at the
German Marshall Fund is we try to create
a little archive that makes these
datasets not ibly the Russian IRA one
and the Iranian one suing the reddit one
and really as much as we can find and
we're gonna be able to organize and
explain the attribution behind it we try
to make them searchable for others who
want to do this work so that's a
prototype if it's helpful for your
purposes feel free to play with it if
you are sitting on the bunch of social
media attributed data and you want to
share it with the research community
please send us an email right out thank
you
thank you for your presentation I'm
Jason our depart from c4 yes I'm curious
to know on the front end of your
research how you determine which
hashtags become like the bucket of your
study I don't know if they're obvious in
every case which ones they'll pick to
scrape accounts or whatever particularly
with research looking to other
jurisdictions like China or Taiwan where
the alleged influence operations as well
curious about your process might be yeah
absolutely
so in the case of those leaks I'm it's
sort of the most obvious one because we
don't only do hashtags we'll to operate
by scooping around URLs that are
disseminated right so in the case of
those things we know that you're trying
to call attention to set either there's
a very clear hashtag or there's a URL
that you can scope around so that takes
care of that when we do information
operations work we work with network of
partners investigators scholars
companies who each sort of like go after
their anything when we do our own we
tend to you know work on intuition
and/or information it's something like
to add a personality that something that
I personally found very helpful is we
have a part of our program that does
work with civil society I in civil
society actions that are targeted by
information operations a lot of that
work also ends up being quite important
and helpful to understand potential
state-sponsored accounts that later
you know shift to other operations that
make sense how are you labeling your
clusters is that through automated topic
modeling or is that manual effort yeah
so it's both I there's a
machine-learning suggestion that's
trained on every single cluster we've
ever label so there maps that you know
look at topics that we're deeply
familiar with and at that stage to
machine learning is pretty good they
look at features so
most shared words hashtags where the
accounts located and then the normal
process is we work with subject matter
experts that indeed review the features
that are in common for that clusters
most shirt images most certain media
links most certainly do sources the
types of language the types of account
location bios and descriptions of the
accounts and then they make a decision
based on that
for a lot of complex campaigns we really
tend to work with subject matter experts
because sometimes you often like
contextual insights to be able to do
proper labeling it's cool thanks