so just a quick overview of what I'm
going to cover today first some
background on some 2016 internet
research agency activity that kind of
kicked off this whole research effort
and then I'll kind of delve into a
little bit of the difference between
information operations or influence
operations in cybersecurity
give it some background on cyber threat
Intel and then I'll get into our case
study and how we went about identifying
an Associated actor and then building
out infrastructure associated with this
activity so to start off the impetus for
this case study came from 2018 articles
from Wired and The Daily Beast these
articles describes some 2016 internet
research agency activity and some of
their information operations efforts on
Facebook I'm not going to recount to all
of what happened in 2016 that would be
horrible but long story short the IRA
purchased a bunch of Facebook ads and
there were a couple that stood out to us
because they kind of toed the line
between information operations and
computer network exploitation these ads
led the victim to a face music chrome
extension and the landing page for that
series of ads was music FBI info when
installed some users reported that it
began messaging all of their Facebook
friends Daily Beast's review of the
Chrome extension an archived copy of it
rather indicated that the extension
didn't actually compromise an
individual's computer but was rather
used likely used in a click fraud scheme
to generate traffic to advertisements
and so this copy also revealed
communication with another domain X tab
dot info which was almost used kind of
like a c2 server to make the extension
generate traffic to specified websites
so I'm gonna pause here real quick and
just kind of talk to you about one of
the main reasons that I'm doing this
talk and did this research so in this
case there was kind of a cybersecurity
hook the generally information
operations or influence operations
exists tangentially to cybersecurity and
that tangential connection is often
going to be domain and IP infrastructure
defenders generally aren't going to care
about activity visiting propaganda as
long as nothing is compromising their
networks or assets and I think this
disconnect probably deters some
researchers in the cyber security realm
from leveraging their knowledge
capabilities and time against strictly
information operations problems in
reality though cyber security
individuals and cyber threat analysts
are sometimes going to be the best
equipped to identify and build out an
understanding of these influence
networks so my hope with this talk is
that I can get people who exist in those
separate spaces talking together a
little bit more and maybe to point out
some methodologies for those in the
information operations realm to employ
in trying to discover some in better
understand the influence operations that
they're looking at so now on to our case
study where we use threat Intel tools
and capabilities to build out an
understanding of infrastructure with
associations to the internet research
agency so two terms here to know real
quick who is which is a record of
information used to register a domain
that can include things like name phone
number email address etc and then second
passive DNS which is a collection of
domain IP resolutions that you can use
to identify what domains were hosted at
a given IP at a certain time so for this
case study we use the tools listed
right and thanks to demean tools risk IQ
excuse me par site and the Internet
Archive all of which were pivotal in
this research so now given that
background IRA activity in those two
domains music FBI info next ad info here
are some of the questions that we're
trying to answer through this research
who registered the domains and what
strings are associated with them what
else did they register which ip's hosted
their domains and what other
associations do they have two other
domains what a saint can we identify
from those findings and all those
questions are really part of a large
iterative process that we can use to
build out knowledge of IRAs associations
so with that I'll give into the
specifics so I'm going to start with a
who is example and reviewing domain you
as to identify a specific actor now keep
in mind that we're trying to identify as
much about this registrant
as we can and for the purposes for the
part this part of the research we used
predominantly main domain tools so this
is the original Whois record for the
extra info domain so you can see here
there was registered using privacy
protections so that doesn't really get
us anywhere
same thing for music FBI info but if we
take a look at one of the later Whois
records for music FBI info we start to
see some names some other registration
characteristics show up in this case a
stanislav lien of a phone number email
address and an even later record for
music FBI info identifies a different
address for this individual as well as
well as a different name that they used
for the registration
so this is a little bit tough to see my
apologies for that but we can use those
strings that we identified previously in
a reverse who is search to identify
other domains that they've registered
and try and build out our understanding
of other strings associated with them so
in this case we identified two
additional domains emotion frequency
calm and vaccine of bola by virus comm
and these give us a couple more strings
that we can associate with this registry
notably
up there you see a demo graph 2005 that
y and x dot are you and estas bueno at Y
and X dot are you and one of those email
addresses leads us finally to another
domain SEO metrics are you and here are
all the strings that we can attribute to
this registrant based off of that who is
research as well as the additional
domains that we identified now I want to
call out the SEO metrics dot ru that
comes into play a little bit later just
because it seems related in terms of
contents who some of the other activity
this individual may have been involved
with now let's throw all of those
strings up against o sent to see what we
can find
hey Russia so ultimately when we throw
these strings against a sent based on
for the email address Stas bueno at
Yandex are you we see a stanislav
yurievich lean off is or was a student
at the st. petersburg national research
university of information technologies
more specifically he was in the design
and safety of computer systems
department and we also see associated
with that email address a DK account
which is like russian Facebook NW code 2
here are some of the academic papers
that he has been involved with notably
we see some steganography and digital
watermarking related content and finally
here we have some pictures of lean off
and a turn if you like something a
little bit more pensive so ultimately
and I'm going to read this explicitly
because I think it's important we assess
with moderate confidence that Steines
law of yurevic galena of pictured here
most likely registered the domains X dot
info music FB de info in X stat dot info
they were used in Internet research
agency information operations we do not
know the extent of blue knobs
involvement with the IRA and information
operations beyond the registering of
these domains who is records indicate
that glean off did not transfer
ownership of these domains to another
entity which suggests that he was
involved with their administration while
they were used in operations now you may
have noticed there that I included a
third domain ext stat dot info and we
haven't gotten over that yet well
spoiler alert if you thought I was just
going to finish after calling out an
individual just wait till I get going so
now we're going to build out some
associated infrastructure and so when I
went over these first two domains
left something out or I didn't point out
something that we can use to tie these
domains together if we take a closer
look at these Whois records we can
actually see that these domains were
registered through the same registrar
Evo plus limited and they were
registered at about the same time in
fact they were registered about 15
seconds apart to me this indicates that
they were purchased and registered
during the same transaction now this
doesn't always work but I'm gonna nerd
out here when it does
it's really exciting so we can do a
reverse Whois search for domains with a
whose record with the same creation
timestamp down to the hour and the same
registrar listed in this case we get
about six results including the two that
we were originally looking at and we
have to check those others to see if
they were in fact registered at about
the same time so looking at this xtxt
stat info we actually see that it was
registered about the same time and in
fact it was 14 seconds before the next
add info domain was registered so that
indicates to me that this domain almost
certainly was registered by Bleen off
during that same transaction as well and
this domain actually leads us to some
additional infrastructure and this gets
at that iterative process that I
mentioned earlier so if we take a look
at ext stats that info and risk IQ
something notable kind of stands out and
that's these 89 host pairs and if you
don't know what host pairs are they
essentially identify relationships
between websites based on the code
behind those websites so in some cases
that relationship might be with social
media sites based off of links to the
wet to the organization's
social media pages and those are going
to be terribly useful but it can also
identify the use of specific scripts
located at other domains which in this
case was much more useful so amongst
these host pairs we actually start to
see a pattern emerge there are several
news and I'm sorry there are several
news sites that have this script source
parent relationship that means that
there is or was code at these websites
calling out to a script on the ext stat
info domain risk IQ also provides us
with a time period for when that script
was present at the site which we can use
to investigate further in the wayback
machine now these are the 2016 results
for that cube SMI net domain that was at
the top of our results in risk IQ and so
looking at a historic translated version
of this website we see that jef SMI
dinette is an independent online
publication from a kiev community of
journalists they aren't subject to any
political impact and contain independent
views on events color me convinced so if
we look at the source code for this site
and again my apologies this is a little
bit tough to see but this is the actual
link that calls out to a hit hit dot j s
javascript file at the EXT stat info
domain if we take a look at that link
also in the wayback machine we can
actually see the source code for I'm
sorry the code for that javascript file
so ultimately it appears that this
script was collecting user agent info so
the may have been used for monitoring
website traffic to the websites that
we're using the script additionally it
may have also been used to serve up ads
or other shady files there's definitely
an opportunity here for some more
research into both this javascript file
as well as some other files and folders
similarly related with this activity but
most notably the script file at ext
Stata info appears to have been
exclusively used by news websites and
blogs many of which appear to peddle
fake or satirical news such as that Kyiv
SMI site additionally several these
sites have also already been previously
identified in reports on the Internet
research agency trolls
so now iterating on these domains we can
get a better understanding of who is
behind them and what else they are doing
so similar to the research that we did
to identify Bleen oov we took a look at
the who's registration information for
those aforementioned domains this
identified a Nevsky News and a federal
news agency or federal agency of News
notably the federal agency of news just
last week sued Facebook for deleting its
account claiming that it was in no way
associated with the internet research
agency beyond sharing and office space
the use of this script at their websites
in my estimation is another indicator of
an association between those entities
but they're on the right you can see
other domains that were registered using
the same Whois and again some of these
domains have already been identified as
having an association with the IRA
notably Bell and Kat called out several
of the USA the u.s. really domains in
one of their reports
additionally the neva news
or news that never is
sorry funded by Concorde management and
consulting which was listed in the u.s.
indictment of the IRA trow Factory so
finally another methodology that we can
use to build out these infrastructure
relationships are hosting collocations
so for this research were attempting to
identify websites that most likely are
owned and operated by the same
individual or organization based off of
the domains that they are hosted with
and the IPS that they are hosted at so
really what we want to do is review
these domains ip's identify those that
are most likely dedicated to a single
user and identify the other domains
hosted there at the same time as our
original domain so this is an example
using pfaff news are you which was
hosted at the 95 213 148 37 IP from
january 2017 through May of 2018 and
during that same time frame there's only
a couple of other domains that are also
hosted there and many of these I'm sorry
these domains also appear related to the
news so we can with a pretty good level
of confidence say that these domains are
likely related to each other and that
this domain is being used by a single
entity so doing that sort of research
for all the domains that we've found to
this point ultimately this is what we
can identify and you see on the right
there both the IP addresses as well as
the domains and again we're finding a
bunch of these domains are related to
news and blog sites and again some of
these have been identified in IRA troll
reports some of them are still active
but most are not at least for these two
but even for those that aren't still
active I would argue that this provides
some good historical context and provide
some fodder for retroactive searches as
well so all in all we identified about
50 domains that have associations with
the IRA or an organization behind it it
should be noted that there's varying
levels of confidence in those
associations based off of how the
domains were identified in this case I
would argue that generally OPSEC that's
going to be used I'm sorry OPSEC that's
used in state-sponsored information
operations is not going to be as strong
as that which is used in the same States
malicious cyber attacks at least you
know in this case study that was the
case this is notable because it means
that there's an opportunity for us to
exploit registration and hosting tactics
using cyber threat intelligence tools
and capabilities and in doing so
researchers may be able to more
thoroughly identify networks of
propaganda pushers trolls and the
possible goals of those information
operations so finally these
methodologies aren't just applicable to
foreign actors we can also use them to
build out an understanding of domestic
influence operations as well so definers
is a conservative public relations firm
closely associated with the America
rising PAC and was recently in the news
for their relationship with Facebook and
influencer operations efforts
so during doing some similar research
against this entity in this case using a
registrant email domain and specific
Google Analytics account number we can
identify all of these domains and
notably here we see a fake hook campaign
side draft Tim Cook org
a college Transparency dot-com site
focused on maligning Yale and also
something a little bit more questionable
an organization that's bidding to build
the border wall so you know my last
sincerely ran a point here is this if
you're concerned about the IRA and what
they're doing to influence American
minds you should be equally if not more
concerned about domestic organizations
on both sides of the aisle doing the
same thing ostensibly these are
organizations operate legally and can
get away with similar things that Russia
did via its troll Factory and I don't
have a great solution for this problem
but by building out our understanding of
their networks and associated
infrastructure and then publicizing that
information so that consumers can better
understand where their news is coming
from maybe that can insert can serve in
some fashion as a influence or vaccine
so thank you very much hi in your
research have you encountered data
collection from these domains in these
sites
what sort of cookies were used for
example and is there consistency between
those sites in the same cookie being
said and and and the same script being
passed that's a great question
admittedly I haven't gone that far into
researching those identified domains
beyond their association with IRA and
the associated associated individual but
I think there's definitely an
opportunity there for additional
research to build out our own
understanding of how those websites are
working thank you for this impressive
presentation some really fascinating
research in there I wondered whether you
could make explicit for us some of your
internal conversations about ethical
considerations to make an individual you
know named an individual with a moderate
confidence assessment so I discussed
this
with my team at threat Connect we you
know went over the research made sure
that they would come to the same
analytic conclusion that I did and
ultimately our understanding or our
sorry I just want to make sure I think
through this response so part of our
work goes towards showing the
methodology to focus on how
organizations can do the same thing
against their own threats additionally
another part of that is we feel that by
exposing infrastructure exposing
individuals that we believe based off of
that analysis are associated with those
activities that we are increasing the
actors cost and we are essentially
creating a deterrent for them to do that
sort of activity or be associated with
that sort of activity in the future I'm
wondering if you've seen a move since
gdpr if you've seen threat actors moving
into gdpr jurisdictions to avoid
precisely this kind of exposure good
question I hard to say and I wouldn't
want to indicate one way or the other on
that I would say however that even with
GT BR there are ways that we can still
do this sort of research notably like I
showed doing that time stamp research we
can get at additional information taking
a look at start of authority records
that can still get us at a email address
even when there's a GDP are enacted so
yeah hard to say
hey so in respond to some of your
comments about stuff on the domestic
side where you kind of end up drawing
that line between information operations
political
activity and then just kind of activism
like I feel like once you start talking
about domestically like yeah there are
some groups I think pretty much
everybody would agree this is not this
is like a little beyond the pale but I
feel like once you kind of start
emphasizing that domestic aspect things
can get a little iffy sends a lot of
those same information operations really
do turn into politics at a certain point
just some thoughts on that yeah so I
mean immediately I'm not a information
Operations expert you know I couldn't
delineate that very well but I know in
the case of this organization and I feel
like there's I know that there are rules
associated with how PACs and super PACs
work I think that has to be incorporated
into that sort of research and
determining the extent to which you know
a definers or America rising PAC are
actually doing something illegitimate or
against the rules I will point out that
one of the organizations here that is
associated with definers power of the
future I mean they have a Facebook page
with over 70,000 followers and they do
not indicate any relationship with
definers or America rising so you know
to me that seems shady but I'm a
cybersecurity individual I don't know if
that's against the rules
so maybe just use this as an opportunity
to extend on that I thought that
pivoting to the domestic space was
really valuable and I think it speaks to
I think in some ways how resources are
appropriated and that some of the
technical expertise in the room could be
incredibly valuable for a domestic
conversation and so I really appreciate
that you did this I I thought it was
novel and and it was just compelling I
could you talk a little bit more about
what what sort of incentives could be
created in order to get people with your
expertise to be doing more of this to
serve us more of this in the domestic
context how do we get more visibility
into this type of
more activity on a domestic front is a
partnership with journalists is it is it
is it kind of positive and intention in
other ways could you yeah I I'm not sure
that I have a good answer for you I
would say having a partnership with
journalists could be very beneficial and
you know helping to identify what
different organizations might be worth
looking into but for me I mean I was
starting to get really upset with a lot
of the stuff that I saw going on in the
news and so that just motivated me to
take some personal action outside of
work and trying to you know build out
this sort of research in a realm that's
not really related to cybersecurity so
you know if there are other individuals
that you know are feeling that same way
and have a similar motivation then maybe
that is a reason for them to do that
research just kind of a testament what
they said I think there's definitely
more to be done with partnering and some
journalists on some of these findings
and people who are working in the space
I think it's interesting it can be
valuable to find pivots and some of
these nuggets to look into but there is
kind of a danger and saying like I do I
worry about seeing these slides that say
like we know that this is part of this
information operations campaign based on
this one piece of data because of the
fact that information operations
campaigns as we talked about earlier
really proliferate in different ways and
I think that there's it's just a
worrisome danger to start going down
that path of like the pivots and where
this goes and where you find these other
domains and then how do you validate
that as part of the other piece of the
information operations piece I think
then requires like okay you have this
information cluster now you need to look
at where does this actually proliferate
as far as the websites and where do they
show up in other pieces of an
information operations campaign I'm glad
you pointed out specifically that you
saw some of this come back around with
the IRA and the indictments but it I
think there's interesting stuff I have
we can talk about later but about
questions for other domains that
necessarily didn't come up in the IRA
indictment about then how do you assess
confidence
with those of whether they're part of
the same information operation or not
right sure yeah and very fair point
while you're doing this you have to keep
in mind like you have to keep in mind
the Avenue that you took to get to those
additional domains and keep in mind you
know what are the alternative
explanations for why you might see the
same who is across multiple domains or
say the same Google account or Google
Analytics account number across several
domains so and then appropriately copy
out your findings based off of that yeah
so I agree