hi everybody my name is Joe Johnson
working for Katie Katie John internet
service provider in Korea my topic is a
DNS anomaly detection and analysis
system all we've developed this system
then monitor kate is dns server farm and
find out the problem of dns firstly I'll
introduce connect DNS system kernel is
the name mobile Katie's commercial
internet service Cornell has more than
20 cash dns server farms each server
farm advertised the same IP address
using any case drought in each dns
server from servitude to local pub
koonet has a star topology their leaders
central venous overcome in the center of
the star topology essential in a server
farm takes in service your queries for
another server fun when the subform
fills a dns server from consists of all
IPS layout for sweets and multiple dns
servers ichi dns server palm advertise
the true / 32 IP addresses one is the
primary dns IP address and the other it
is secondary dns IP address as i said in
my previous slide we have many dns
server farms and actually we have one
more than 150 gen8 servers on problem or
extent of genius happen simultaneously
from many silver pumps it was difficult
to figure out but problem have happened
on dns before this system
was installed we had to dump Guinness
packets on its dns servers and analysis
the problem it takes so much time and
it's not easy to find out the problem
instantly after this system is third we
can easily investigate which is our firm
has a problem and what the problem is
our system consists top one central
detection system and multiple local
analysis systems all local or nervous
system has been installed pearl dns
server fan bases on local analysis
system attached to 20 dns server pump
through two tabs these two tabs are
located in between IPS and layer for 3g
due to tapping location or we can
analysis thin expected throughout the
stores of the firm that server by zero
basis currently we installed true local
analysis systems there is one local
analysis system in central dns server
from a local analysis system captures
all put fifty three packets to and from
gaining server farms and inspect their
contents with predefined rules and sense
analytical results to the central
detection system the central detection
system gathers the analytical results
from a local analysis systems and then
detects dns anomalies
this is lie the shoulder those systems
user interface actual on this all Korean
characters of this user interface has
been replaced if they are corresponding
English representations main menu
consists of real-time analysis pest
analysis of Ryan analysis local system
control and true self anomaly detection
real-time analysis and pest analysis
have the exactly same sub menu this sub
menus DNS traffic pavan Dara an anomaly
detection your time analysis shows
analytical data present point of time we
can retrieve all the analytical data
from pest analysis menu each cdns
traffic stop menu shows it'll come to
our ratio values on packet analysis each
tab and add a sub menu shows a linking
of frequently used to domain over IP a
source IP addresses this slide shows the
cap the number of capture the packets on
april nine to ten with one mini sampling
rate i will explain this submenu one by
one this slide shows the quarry send
answers of mania with DNS traffic this
graph shows the number of total packets
client queries answered for client
chorus recursive queries and
in search for recursive queries this
script shows many cards at the same time
the user interface provide an option to
select individual carbs this slide shows
the response ratios of manual DNS
traffic we calculate response ratio with
the number of answer pickets divided by
number of Corey packets red curve shows
the response ratio of recursive queries
blue curve shows the response ratio
client queries you can see response
ratios vary from local system to local
system in the normal case the red curve
which is slightly lower than blue curve
this slide shows the response ratio with
primary and secondary dynasty IP address
I will calculate response ratio of
primary dns IP addressing secondary dns
IP addresses separately red corpuscles
the response racial group queries that
comes through comfortable primary IP
address klokov shells response ratio
queries it come through secondary dns IP
address
this is like the Georgia case you hit
ratio submenu this is why the show's
concurrent users submenu red curve shows
the number of the source IP / minutes
blue curve shows the number of queries
per society this slide shows the tcp
station submenu of dentistry p we close
by the tcp sessions as four types only
chlorine time / empty and doom our own
equalization have tcp start can scry and
tcp finishing time / session doesn't
help and it is the people finished
process empty session held tcp startin
to pick finish the process without any
DNS queries
this is lighter shows Cory types of many
of the nest repeat these two graphs
shows the distribution of Cory types
Taipei MX PTR etc you can see there is
there are of normal users in local
system one who generate huge amount of
ppl queries in a normal case the ratio
of taipei curry is very high this slide
shows answer types of many of DNS
traffic these two graphs show the
distribution of answer types type 2
error so fellow named Eric spectrum the
Dover do error time new era answers in
local system one wing called by users
who generate PTR queries
this is lighter shows are normally
Corey's submenu we regard chorus which
violated the premiere constraints of DNS
header is an anomaly chorus these claws
have been generated by malicious users
from now on I'll explain tab indeed a
submenu this is a society submenu the
category field will be changed by
clicking combobox the category
debentures eyed peas are ranking
officers Eyed Peas who generate chorus
happens or cyclist with a highway is a
ranking officers eyed peas which
generate type a query the last column of
this table shows ranking variation newly
lengthy source IP address may be
regarded as a suspicious wizard this
slide shows the coronium plus source i
click the category have been callin n
plus societies or ranking of combination
corey name and source typists applaud
equals source IP generate the same query
continuously it will be rank very highly
tab and corey name + IP the highway is a
combination of qualitative a and source
IP tab and black domain + IP the ranking
of combination of combination of linking
compilation of black domain to a
combination of course to plug domain and
societies this black domains are defined
by korean information secret agency
country the number of black domains are
this slide shows the query name so many
of the tub and data the category tab and
curly q name is Jean ranking of the
quarry name tavern coordinate with the
Thai basil ranking al-bukhari name with
Cory type-a only we also come to cory's
to a third activity in SE servers which
is server recursive queries for root
server je root server is frequently used
because the variscite object is directly
connected to connect we make our ranking
for top-level domain we also make Colin
king for second-level domain n tolerable
that KL domain victory when you Korean
websites have domain names little second
i become the network third rebelled at
KR with this happen second level domain
third level domain ranking we can easily
find out which side popular head
users i will explain anomaly detection
logic briefly anomaly detection is based
on the variation ratio of DNS traffic
basic ideas on detection formula of
pollings you still collect the
parameters of a DNS traffic keep the
limited history of values on each
parameter and football rate on recent
data and then we make this season phenom
only with the threshold
when anomaly detected we check the
details on who our wiring called the
problems with having data pages these
indicators of anomaly increasing number
of athena's packets increasing number of
queries to DNS server farms secondary IP
addresses decreasing a sheet ratio
electron this slide shows an example of
anomaly detection this table has a time
period and nine indicators we use for
one in the velum like green yellow
orange and red the control shows stretch
of the river this warning level red
means the situation is very critical I
will explain two cases of utilizing the
system the first one is to detect
unexpected to increased on MX queries in
Beverly 2007 at the time the traffic was
doubled in response ratio logisys to ten
percent were higher in means both top
client queries are drunk we investigate
what caused their who generate what qui
type there we can announce this result
that multiple source IP addresses from
many server farms kept generating MX
queries it was a kind of berwyn
situation we block the traffic from the
corner to the infecting system actually
it's in USA
the second case is to detect tons of
corazon time that is to that GOP in
barchi 2007 the amount of chorused had
been doubled or tripled at all dns
server firms who investigated what
course they are and who generates more
than 60 personal corazon time that is to
the GOP those source IP address from
some home gateways at the time tunnel
ntp server or Buddhist that GOP what
changed their name is named from time
that list to the Jupiter the other thing
but Korean on gateway still use the name
as NTP servers and they makes this
queries and we advise the dock company
th therefore mirror the plan of this
year is to enter another local systems
to cover all the new server console
connect and we will improve the anomaly
detection watching that it are there any
questions
so more coasters verisign I I really
like this presentation actually this is
one of the first presentations I saw
where cash utilization hit rates was
actually presented and I think that is
we've had multiple presentations over
time from a fruit and je root and so on
terms of the root servers I think it'd
be very interesting and see some more
sort of behavioral sort of
characteristics that are coming from
cashing name service like what you have
put together and I would like to see
that in the future I isaacs all better
from amazon have you been doing any
anomaly detection in the time domain or
has it been primarily based on query
type and response types are you actually
doing time to time domain analysis on
you know response times actually
real-time analysis cannot catch the time
domain parameter like this past time
ring we have main menu offering analysis
today we could operate on a list we can
gathering the information for this past
time Russell but it's not is to keep
Gator time information from your time
analysis sorry one other question about
that was a why do you take the approach
of deploying a server based on tabs or a
collector picking up off the tap as
opposed to a local agent on the name
server um because we have so many DNS
servers there is no tab can you store
between real far sweetie and janie
servers victories thank you
okay thank you very much