thank you so let us define conversions
so if at a certain time you have a flow
that is established from a source to a
destination and at time t1 you have a
failure the connectivity is lost at time
t2 routing is establish again an end to
an alternate path to reach the source to
destination we define T 2 minus T 1 as
the loss of connectivity or the
convergence we are going to focus on
during this presentation and in the in a
previous no-knock we focused on IGP here
it's with conversions related to bgp
reaction so the BGP prefix independent
conversions feature which we call BGP
pick as 2 flavors the co flavor and the
edge flavor so let us first define the
core flavor in the call you can in the
cough Laver we would look at a curved
link or curved node failure so for
example PE 1 in this drawing as
installed 350,000 BGP routes with BGP
next up being p2 in the representation
of the routing table of p1 we see these
350,000 routes as green routes p1 as an
IGP path to reach picchu it is
represented as the yellow entry in the
routing of adding table we say that the
BGP routes depend on the IGP route the
question we analyzed in BGP because if
there is a failure within us which
triggers energy P conversions and we
know from the maturity of the technology
that the IGP conversions will take a few
hundreds of milliseconds so in a few
hundreds of milliseconds p1 will update
the yellow entry with a new IGP path
here pose to the question we are now
looking at is not related to our GP
conversions is related to how quickly
will the green entries the BGP
destination leverage the new IGP path to
the BGP next stop and the requirement
from you is immediately BGP Peco
guarantees that it occurs immediately we
first prove it and then we will explain
how it is achieve
from a technical viewpoint so this is
the the measurements related to the
question II we just described the unit
under test is a CRS running iox 3.5 in
an isis topology of the complexity of
the tier 1 service provider we have 5000
Isis prefixes in this topology and one
of them is the PGP next table that
installed so many BGP routes obviously
it is important so in this case today we
place the we placed it in the critical
list which makes sure that it will be
among the first 500 to be updated upon
IGP conversions it's the typical IGP
conversions chart so on the x-axis you
find the IGP position on the y-axis you
see the conversions or loss of
connectivity measured with real packets
sent to this destination in and the unit
is in milliseconds you see multiple
curves because this testing if it's
reproduced 100 times and we plot the
minimum the median the percentile 90 and
the percentile 100 or the maximum again
the interest is the BGP behavior or our
BGP destination leverage this so we
focus our attention to the right of the
chart at and then we see four points the
first one is the BGP next stop without
any surprise it converts extremely
quickly quickly because it it's leverage
IGP conversions we see in this test sub
100 milliseconds it is not surprising
that's the level of technology achieved
today but the interest is the three
other points the three other points are
respectively the first the middle and
the last BGP prefix that depends or
recurs on it and there are 350 thousands
of them and you see that consistently
through measurements these destinations
leverage the IGP convergence of the BGP
next up it's an image at leverage of the
IGP conversions this is significant how
is it achieved that's the interest of
this presentation to explain how it is
achieved it is achieved through a
vehicle organization of the following
table in the data plane in this
representation you see on the left the
BGP the BGP prefix
the 350,000 BGP prefix I installed as
fib leaves on the left of my diagram
these 350,000 BGP prefixes they have the
comment reachability from a BGP
viewpoint it's the same BGP next up the
BGP LTI is a memory entry in our
organization which in our fav
organization which represents this BGP
connectivity it could be multiple BGP
next up if it was multipath well it
would be one single BGP next up which is
this example from the BGP LDI we have
one pointer that goes to an i GPL di di
GPL di represents the connectivity in
the IGP to go to that BGP next stop
began if there would be multiple IC ecmp
IGP path you would see multiple pointers
leaving the I GPL di box here there's
there was one single path so we see only
one single pointer it is abuse as soon
as you have this hierarchical
organization that as soon as you have
the ICP conversions of the BGP next up
which means that you have a modification
and not to make a modification of the I
GPL di to use a new outgoing interface
that all the BGP dependents leverage
from it immediately it's extremely also
scalable and rubbished from an
implementation viewpoint and under
utilization of the control plane
resources in the past most if not all
rather architectures were built with
flatten it fit which means that when
obviously the control plane always
managed the information in this
hierarchical manner but when it's about
to write it into a dwell flattening is
done it means that each fib leaf is
immediately connected to its image its
outgoing interface the flattening
advantage is that the path the lookup is
easier so you either have higher PPS or
you have simpler outward to achieve a
given DPS the the the drawback it has is
conversion speed because of usually FDI
GP connectivity change and you need to
change the OIF use by di GPL di in a
flattening organization
the line card CPUs now to go and rewrite
all the dependent BGP entries in a
linear process and you can imagine that
if you have hundred thousands of BGP
dependents this extra workload is going
to represent multiple seconds and so the
IGP conversions which is set to hundred
a few hundreds of milliseconds is by far
not the one you would see for BGP
distant traffic which is really what you
care about so here are kicking fib
organization in the data plane for the
forwarding table is as the following
advantage the BGP big curve feature
which is that it the BGP dependents
inherit leverage the IGP conversions of
the next up immediately but it has also
scaling and robustness advantages to
understand the robustness gain thing
about a link flap in your own AES from
an IP conversions viewpoint who cares
it's extremely quick there is no it
doesn't going to await your resources
it's a few hundreds of milliseconds we
download the few IGP prefixes to the
line card and that's it if if the link
comes back up a few hundred milliseconds
later it's the same process and that's
it but if you bundle this with a planet
flatten each data plane architecture
then it means that at the down
transitions you trigger on the line card
multiple seconds if you have 100
thousands of dependence of line card CP
utilization at 100 person to just recopy
everything and so the transition back up
is delayed by these few seconds and so
in total you also have LAN card CPU that
is driven to 100 person just for no good
reason in this case in this case so let
us now focus on pic edge pig edge is a
data plane protection mechanism which is
triggered by AGP conversions upon border
router failure or peering link failure
in order to immediately protect BGP
destined traffic via alternate still
viable BGP next up
it doesn't require any configuration any
tuning any design it doesn't require any
tunnel of what storms to operate it just
automatically don't buy the software so
we're going to explain this topic in
multiple stages first I'm going to use a
very simplified case study I'm going to
report measurements on it to prove it
works and then most important what is
the interest is to explain how the data
plane achieve this how we build the
forwarding table to achieve this
behavior and then we will finish with a
bit more details on what is behind this
technology so this case to d2i speeds
the gray one and the yellow one p at
multiple locations
the yellow is be advertised 350,000 BGP
destination to the grey ISP router r1
and rudder are two set next up cells
rather are three as ibgp sessions with
r1 and r2 r3 is configured for multi
path r3 is going to install this 350,000
BGP destination as multipath entries
with - next up r1 and r2 we're going to
send traffic from the left of r3 to this
destination in the yellow is peace and
we're going to fail rather r1 and we are
going to measure how long it takes for
the traffic to be recovered through the
remaining peering link between the two
high speeds the unit and the test is a
12 K running iOS 3.3 the result is sub
180 milliseconds it is totally expected
because it's the IGP convergence time to
compute with the deletion of the border
router so let us look again at this case
2d in a few hundreds of milliseconds
upon border valve failure it is clear
that our three will conclude with this
simple fact I delete the next stop of
our three of our 1 3 so this deletion of
the next stop triggers the data plane
pre computed
protection mechanism which is going to
push at that time in a prefix
independent manner all the 350,000 BGP
destination via the remaining peering
link we thought any configuration
without any policy constraint in this
simplified example the same 350,000 BGP
routes advertised on the two peering
links but you do not need this looking
at this at this chart
one question that could arise is why is
it that some of the flows that were used
to measure the convergence report zero
loss of connectivity that's normal
before the failures some of the floors
used for the measurements go via the top
peering link some go via the bottom P
wrangling you have load balancing on the
PUF flow basis so obviously the flows
that were routed via the bottom peering
link do not are not impacted by the
failure and so they report zero loss in
this case so again the key thing and I
insisted upon it is that it is a data
plane protection mechanism triggered by
AGP conversions yes the term is BGP
because the one that gains this service
is BGP destination but BGP is not at all
involved with this
this is purely a forwarding table
organization trick coupled with IGP
conversions so when this happens this
exact case 2d with a witness a measured
loss of connectivity of sub 200
milliseconds if you do the same analyzes
but now at the control plane level which
is not what the user would see the
customers would perceive at the control
plane level BGP will take like several
tenths of seconds to converge and so if
you do the same testing without this
data plane a protection mechanism the
experience of the customer is multiple
tens of seconds of this connectivity and
so the impact of this technology is huge
in terms of service expert expressed
experienced by customers
now again what is interesting is what is
the building block behind all this this
is the hierarchical organization of the
following table in the data plane again
so the 350,000 BGP destinations are
inserted in the forwarding table as fib
leaves they are all sharing the same BGP
connectivity it's the multipath set of
two next stop r1 and r2 this is
represented automatically through fib
intelligence it understands this sharing
principle and so they are all going to
have pointer in direction to the same
memory entry which is the BGP LDI
which has two pointer in direction to go
to the I GPL the ID the representation
of the IGP connectivity of the two next
stops and so it's abuse as soon as you
see the drawing that you would think why
was it was it not like this before that
upon IGP convergence it ends up with the
deletion of the top a GPL di and the
only thing that is required is to add
deletion of the LGPL di to check if they
are dependent or children B GPL di and
in place modify them to only use the
remaining valid next stop it's obvious
and simple so now that we have seen how
it works what is the service experience
or the gain and service experienced by
the customer
let us now bring a bit more details to
this there are multiple assumptions that
I met for BGP pic edge to work and we're
going to walk through them the first
assumption is that the trigger must be
an IDP based deletion of the BGP neck
stop it is granted for border router
failure it is granted for peering link
failure if the border router does not
run next up self if the border router
does run next up self then the solution
is simply BGP pick H primary backup
what is BGP pikas primary backup next
assumption the second assumption I made
is that r3 installs these 350,000 BGP
destination
as multipath bgp rounds and you
understand in my example why I need this
multipath entry because when my top IG
PLD is deleted yes I could think of in
place modifying the BGP LDI but it will
only be useful if I have another path
and my multi path assumption it is clear
that you can extend this to primary
backup policy you simply ask BGP to
compute the BGP next up as you have
today plus a backup next up and then we
use the same organization to achieve it
it will be provided in the future as a
software announcement the third
assumption which is that the
communication from R 3 to R 1 or R 2 is
over border rather to border wall
encapsulation it just makes sense this
is the initial way that IGP bgp routing
was designed it was not done 15 years
ago because at that time and caps d-cups
was difficult match her modern rather
support and cap D caps at line right
over MPLS LS peace over IP push and pop
header assume it but I don't see it as a
constraint at port it's beneficial in
this design study but we can list many
other advantages to run an IP network
over IP end caps or MPLS and gaps border
rather to border rather the fourth
assumption I made is that R 3 is
connected to R 1 and R 2 via ibgp
sessions it's abuse for this to work I
need two paths before the failure either
to do multi path or to do primary backup
in the VPN world because people
typically design with unique or the
allocation I don't have any problem for
this assumption because even if I use
road reflectors they will not hide any
path and any border router will receive
all the paths that exist and it will be
possible but in the internet case it is
difficult and most likely impossible to
deploy actually if route reflectors are
you
because the rat reflector is designed to
leak one single path to its clients so
although everything could be done to
have this backup a multipath recovery if
you have only one path you cannot
trigger the mechanism so I'll if you are
interested in this how are you going to
use it for Internet there are short-term
long-term solutions to this the short
term solution is to add ibgp sessions to
other wire reflectors or other border
routers to get the additional path not
sexy but potentially one option the
other options it is to run Internet in a
verse or Internet as a VPN then again
you fall back on the army uniqueness you
bypass the rat the rat reflector hiding
and that's available the long term
solution for this is obvious this is the
ad path capability that is currently
defined that the IDF so this assumption
is not obvious I recognize it in the
ipv4 internet case I listed a few short
term solution the long term solution
likely will be at bath in the VPN world
which was really a motivation for
developing this technology especially to
deal with border router failures which
are catastrophe qu you cannot imagine -
to deal with a border router failure
from a BGP control plan conversions
viewpoint that's multiple tens of
seconds so in the VPN world there is no
issue that assumption is granted so we
we reach the conclusion the real message
or the real of Technology topic that is
behind this presentation is not BGP it
is about how to architect the data plane
forwarding table and that should have
been the name of the presentation but
then it's a bit less sexy less related
to perceived service so we call it BGP
prefix independent conversions but the
real technology behind it is
hierarchical fib organization of the
data plane there are three advantages to
this scaling and robustness and
convergence
especially specifically BGP Pico and BGP
big edge BGP big cog
guarantees that upon curling or not
failures within yo areas BGP
destinations will leverage the IGP
conversions of the BGP next up
immediately thanks to the hierarchical
organization BGP big H is a data plane
protection mechanism which upon border
rudder appearing in failure thanks to
our GP conversions trigger a protection
of the BGP celestine traffic via
alternate still available BGP next stop
many thanks for your attention if you
have any questions they are welcome
Himanshu from Alcatel you said you do
this for VPNs as well yes do you track
the ITP next up or the LSP endpoint I
mean in IDP or the LSP database in this
sex in this example it's obviously the
BGP next stop so it's our one right but
is it is it the LS I mean do you check
whether the LSP label is available or
not or we can discuss it but it's
unrelated because I GP convergence is
going to be triggered has a deletion of
the next stop whether you have an LSP to
it or not it's unrelated
okay and just a side note I mean the
whole whole technology was available in
other vendors for a long for several
years actually I would be surprised that
okay well if we have no more class