hello everyone I'm her char from the
University of Washington and today I'll
be talking about the system called I
plane that I've been building with my
advisors Tom our win then I don't
so the basic motivation for our work is
that today there are several instances
where it's useful to know what exactly
is the performance you get on some parts
of the internet for example in certain
applications such as p2p applications
you like for clients to connect to peers
that are providing good performance on
the other hand ISPs would like to know
what exactly is the performance clients
should receive in the connect to their
customers but the problem is right now
there is no good way really to predict
performance on any path unless you
actually use the path and the reason
this this is a problem is I guess known
to all of you out here is the routes
routes in the internet traverse several
ISPs and so there is no single point in
the network where you can predict
performance between I need to end those
further though any ISP can control
routes going out from it it does not
really have control over incoming routes
and so there's path asymmetry out there
and further both routes and traffic
workloads change over time and you don't
really have any static estimate that you
can make on path performance so to
address this problem given these
challenges we have built this system
called AI plane in that in a nutshell
what it does is it predicts path
properties on the internet between any
arbitrary source and any arbitrary
destination and the way - though is we
have control over a bunch of vantage
points around the internet from which we
continually issue measurements and based
on measurements from these vantage
points we not only predict we predict
the path properties such as latency loss
rate and bandwidth along paths that they
are not even measured and so currently
we have this system continually
measuring the internet daily from
several locations around the internet
and all this data that we gather is
available online at this URL so first
let's look at a high-level overview of
how I plane works so as I said we have
control over a few Vantage several
vantage points around the network so
right now we have planetlab nodes in
around 200 locations as well as around
500 public traceroute servers so from
these few hundred vantage points we
issue trace routes daily to all prefixes
in the internet and based on these
measurements we build up this topology
topological map of the internet and once
we discover all popular links out there
we partition these links into access
links at the edge and links in the core
and separately measure properties of
these links such as loss rate and
bandwidth so this map of the internet
that they build up annotated with link
level properties we call this the
internet atlas and we basically use this
Atlas to predict properties between
hosts that we don't have control over so
let's see how exactly we do that so say
there is some source and destination
between which you want to make an
estimate and we don't have control over
either the source or the destination so
we don't really know the paths between
them through the internet all that we
have is control over a few vantage
points and from these vantage points we
have performed trace routes to some
representative destination in the same
prefix as s and the same prefix as d so
the thing we capitalize on is that by
composing segments of these measured
paths for example in this case by
composing Si and ID you can get a path
that is pretty similar to the actual
path so in this case one candidate path
for the path between s and E is s ID
which though not identical to the actual
path is pretty similar both the
challenge here is there are several
other intersections possible between our
measured routes and we have to choose
among these candidate paths as to what
exactly is the right path between s and
E and the way we do so
by using several properties of how
routing works the fact that BGP tends to
prefer shorter race paths and that most
many people do early exit routing so we
use such properties to infer the path
between any source and a destination so
to estimate the path properties between
s and D we basically used this technique
to predict the forward path first then
predict the reverse path and then
compose the properties of the links on
these predicted paths to infer
end-to-end latency loss rate and
bandwidth so here's one particle example
of how our path prediction works so I
was in Rio last year for the internet
measurement conference and when I was
there I did a trace route from the hotel
in Rio to the web server of the US
Embassy in Romania so the map on the
Left basically shows the actual route
from Rio to Romania as given by trace
route and the RTT measured by the actual
trace route was 298 milliseconds and the
map on the Left shows a map on the right
shows the path predicted by plane
between the same source and destination
so you see that though the path is not
exactly identical it's pretty similar to
the actual path and since it is pretty
similar even our latency estimate is
close to the actual value to evaluate
our path prediction more rigorously what
we did was we considered our atlas of
the Internet to be comprising only
measurements made from planetlab and use
these this atlas to estimate paths
measure from public race road servers
are on final of which we use
so this graph essentially shows how well
our path predictions work the x-axis is
the AAS path this is the similarity
metric which is basically symmetric we
use for comparing to a s paths all that
you need to know is when the metric is 0
both paths identical and the y-axis is
the cumulative fraction of paths so here
you see that for around 2/3 of the paths
in our evaluation set
we're able to predict the a spark
effectively right so given that our path
predictions are reasonably accurate we
then evaluated how well our estimates of
path properties such as latency and loss
rate are given our path predictions so
here are graphs plotting these estimates
the graph on the Left plots the accuracy
of a latency estimates the x-axis is
basically the absolute error in our
latency estimate compared to the actual
latency and the y-axis is the cumulative
fraction of paths the similarly the
graph on the right plots the accuracy of
our loss rate estimates so in both cases
you see our estimates are reasonably
accurate but not perfect and to diagnose
this we further broke down a path path
set into two partitions one for which we
once the one set of paths is those for
which we actually we're able to predict
the a spot perfectly right and the other
for which were unable to predict the s
path correctly so we see that our
estimates for properties such as latency
and loss rate are significantly better
when we do get a spot right so our hope
is that as we improve our measurements
to improve our mapping of the Internet
and also I put our technique for path
prediction our our estimates for restock
path properties will improve further so
now that I've told you that Africa needs
you that there the data that I plane
gives us reasonably accurate how exactly
can you access this data so firstly all
the measurement data that we gather
daily is available online at this URL
and further we also run a query server
on this host which exports two
interfaces one is a Sun RPC interface
and the other is an XML RPC interface so
you can basically issue queries for any
source destination pairs you like for
example suppose you want to determine
what is the performance some set of
clients out there received to your
customers you can basically input though
your those sources those source
destination pairs
as a query and you get back predictions
of what exactly is the pop level path
from on each of these source destination
pairs and also what is the latency and
loss rate estimates along these paths so
currently we have one query server
running on this host and we hope we are
applying to host a few more query
servers that you would have pretty soon
so one interesting result we have found
while doing our evaluations is that our
our estimates of path properties are
significantly better when suppose you
want to estimate the power path
robbery's for some particular source
destination our estimate is
significantly better when we have access
to a few paths from the source and the
reason for this is that there is path
asymmetry out there in the Internet and
the outgoing paths from the source are
not necessarily reflected by the paths
we measure into it from our vantage
points so in fact in our experiments
with public trace road servers we have
seen that by just adding ten paths from
each server we can get significant
improvement in accuracy of our estimates
so it will really help if you guys can
host more trace route servers out there
we can basically scrub the webpage on a
one and include those in our
measurements and give you better data
for to my plane so right now we we also
have a interface by which our query
server can accept trace routes as input
and all that you need to do is upload
the raw output of trace route to a TCP
server and even that is documented at
the URL so in summary today I presented
I a system called I plane that we have
built and in a nutshell what it does is
gives you predictions aprox approximate
predictions of thoughts as well as path
properties between any two end hosts out
there in the internet and if any of you
are interested if you even think this
information to my plane is useful and
you're interested in using it please
drop me a mail and also if there's any
other information you think I plain wood
should provide I would be glad to hear
Thanks