thank you for your introduction so my
name is Bruno quetta I'm with the IP
networking lab and university of leuven
belgium and i will present some work we
have done with a tool called CB GP and
we applied it to to model some aspects
of routing in a nice be and this is a
joint work with the Sebastian told STV
leak and what if available to you so
short agenda first motivate the work
then give a brief overview of the
simulators feature and show how we we
apply it on Jo which is the European
research and education network so why
would you want to to mud on your network
with another tool then current capacity
planning tool well it's a lot about the
nth element traffic and bgp so it's
difficult to to predict the impact of a
link failure or change in your routing
policies or the addition or removal of
the other peering link on your inter
domain traffic another question is how
can i adjust all the parameters of my
network so BGP policies and so on in
order to reduce my costs in order to
increase my performance or in order to
increase the reliability of my network
so these are the question we are trying
to to answer so in my understanding this
is the view that traditional capacity
planning to have of a nice p network so
it's pretty like an isolated island
not really taking into account what
happens outside of your network but the
reality it's much more complex so you
have transit traffic multiple de gracias
maybe a complex ibgp structure in your
network including route reflectors even
multiple levels of road reflectors there
are a lot of destination so around two
hundred and fifteen thousand different
prefixes in BGP routing tables and you
also have the interaction between an igp
protocol ice ice or SPF and and bgp so
understanding what is going on in a nice
p network seems to be pretty hard and
certainly too much for a human brain so
we have developed a tool called see bgp
that is able to compute the routes that
bgp would have selected in an in a
network based on knowledge of the
topology and wrote router configurations
see bgp supports most of the bgp
estrogen process over a local per FAS
path length mad another thing it can be
configured with a different routing
policy so tagging route with communities
prepending aes pass etc it is able to
read BGP route that you would have
collected on your border routers and you
can inject them into the model and it's
it's free it's an open source tool
written in C and we have currently
applied it on three different networks
abilene in general and also a French
tier 1 network
so that our basic methodologies as
follows so first we have to capture some
data onto into the network to build a
view of the topology we also have to
collect information on the bgp sessions
the route maps etc and with that we
build the sea bgp model with one view of
the model we can compute the what we
call the routing state that is all the
route towards all the prefixes in each
router in the model then we can play
with the model we can change the state
of the link in the topology changed igp
weights we can change route filters add
or remove routes and see what other
routing states we can obtain after the
changes and then we can compare all
these routing states in order to to to
figure what's going on in addition with
we are also able to wait these routes
with traffic collected with net flow for
instance this is just a sample of the
output you could get from CBGB so it's
based on model of the abilene network
and command shown here just display the
different steps of the decision process
on a single router towards a single
destination prefix so let's go to the
case today so Jo is a network with pops
in all the European capitals so there
are around I think Fred 23 notes I got
more information here 38 cowlings and 53
peering lengths and among these bearings
links six are with upstream providers so
we have obtained the the general
topology based on an ice ice trays we
are we obtained BG
routing data from a zebra collector
connected with ibgp sessions to all the
routers in jail so we collected all the
the current best ebgp routes and in
addition we also get NetFlow data so at
first scenario i'm going to show you as
a scenario where we in vegas
investigated the addition and removal of
peering lengths so on the example shown
on the slide we would like to know what
will happen to work traffic if you if we
are peering with a new neighbor z and
let's see how the traffic will be spread
over the network and other appearing
links so in the next slide I'll show two
different kinds of experiments one where
we have added a full BGP routing tables
at different locations in the network in
order to simulate the addition of a new
peering and scenarios where we have
removed the routes previously learned
from an existing peering and the metric
here is the distribution of the traffic
over the different upstream the
different links with the upstream
providers so this is a simplified view
of general on the top of a figure you
see the six appearing links that we will
consider with their a load of outgoing
traffic and we are going to remove PR
one to PR four and then add new pairings
on routers are 1 or a 2 etc and that's
the kind of output we can obtain
so on the x-axis you have the different
scenarios the first one is a default
state on the y-axis you see the fraction
of traffic that is that is carried by
the six upstream peering links so in the
default case you can see that the
traffic loads is already highly unevenly
distributed so PR to hear carries fifty
percent of the Geo going traffic so now
in the red scenarios where we remove
appearing link we can see Frank for
example the dell pr2 example here in
this case we remove the the link with PR
2 and we can see that another appearing
linksno carries all the load previously
carried by the link with PR too so it's
something difficult to predict by hand
in the case of the addition of peering
we can see in the case of the addition
of appearing with our van that the the
new peering link will will take all the
traffic that previously went out true
pr2 and well so you can you can see that
four different different scenarios
second experiment we have done is
investigate what will happen when
internal links will sail and how the
traffic will be redistributed also how
many routing changes each link failure
can cause inside my network here we have
classified each routing changing
according to what's shown on the slide
so we have looked at routing changes
that just change the reach
ability of destination so in this class
we will see prefixes that we're
reachable before the in failure and that
are not reachable anymore phn pure
change our roads that are going out
through another AES egress changes still
through the same alias but true and
another egress router and then we only
have in infra domain routing changes so
this is just a summary here on the
x-axis you have all the link failures
and on the y-axis you have all the
routing changes and the colors indicate
the the class of the rotating change so
what we can observe here is that the
single link failure can cause more than
500,000 routing changes so it's
accumulated of our old Rovers in network
that's the first observation and a
second observation is that most routing
changes are changes at the internal
mental level so these are pH changes and
egress changes not only changing between
well think that wouldn't be seen by a
traditional clappers capacity planning
tools so as a conclusion we have a tool
that can be useful for you to try to
predict the impact of various changes or
events inside your network on your BGP
routing or your traffic we have applied
it to three different networks we'd like
to apply it to other networks so if you
are interested in the tool do not
hesitate to contact us and we would like
to
to tell you but I'm sure you know that
many of the changes that are caused and
network are in tellement changes that's
why the modeling tools that that you use
should take into account bgp routing we
have some direction for further work try
to predict the impact on the inbound
traffic but that we need a better view
on the on the internet apology we also
had to the tool support for a BGP mpls
VPN and one way to compute more accurate
failover mattresses that were proposed
by Thomas telegram from caradin so
that's all thank you for your attention