okay it's a 901 so let's get started
most people like they've wandered in so
as I said welcome to bellevue washington
for nanog 40 no not toronto but i'm
still me first and i figure out the
meeting we need to give a big round of
thanks to our host xk el so as I'm sure
you've heard me say over and over again
by now without a host none of this could
have happened we wouldn't have a place
to meet we wouldn't have network
connectivity you wouldn't have any power
at your seats we wouldn't have a meeting
basically so big thanks to exhale and if
you see folks in fact if anybody for my
scales here could you stand up and wave
that is or I probably had others one
back there a couple okay good a bunch of
other contributors in varying roles I'm
not going to read them all because it
would take all day but people providing
connectivity routers just general grunt
work all sorts of things without these
people we wouldn't have much of a
meeting either so thank you to all of
you we have four break sponsors this
time so the food that you had out there
this wonderful breakfast without the big
sponsors we wouldn't be seeing much the
way food out there so thank you to those
guys and please support the big sponsors
during the break still sometimes be out
there with little booths or tables so
you can go talk to them and of course
the big thing is the Bering gear tonight
5 30 to 7 30 it's going to be right
outside in the foyer there can be missed
looks like we have nine exhibitors
tonight so make sure you support them
and while you're drinking our fine beer
and wine and eating our good food I'd
like to give big thanks to the program
committee 16 people plus myself did a
lot of hard work over the last few
months putting this program together we
hope that you'll enjoy it and if you
like it or if you don't like it please
to one of us or all of us or whatever
and let us know what you think and how
we could make things better couple of
receptions already mentioned the beer
and gear right out there is also going
to be a couple late evening receptions
posted by Microsoft at parlor billiards
which i guess is across the way there
there's a little flyer out in the
registration area you can find out about
it that's carefully scheduled so after
all the main events are over after the
Bering gear and after the community
meeting tomorrow you can go and even
party some more I suppose no agenda
changes so far so what's on your printed
schedule is still correct remote
participation I have no idea if this is
still true but it probably is a couple
reminders network security is the big
one of course this is a public wireless
network which means everybody can see
what you're sending so please try not to
use clear text passwords unless you want
people to hack into your accounts do use
and and decryption mrs. H VPN tunnels
whatever pgp key signing off is as usual
going to be during the breaks this time
during the morning breaks in one of the
rooms over to the side there during your
reception I already mentioned another
thing that I haven't mentioned yet is we
have a couple of open seating rooms down
the hallway that way and if you go even
beyond those there's a little patio area
that's been set up for us to use with
some tables so you can sit out there and
enjoy the sunshine when you're not in
here of course in the meeting if you
wonder why some of us have funny colored
badges this is why blue badges for
steering committee members yellow badges
for program committee members red badges
for the mailing list committee members
of which unfortunately we only have one
here today this is time but you'll be
hearing from him at the community
meeting tomorrow night then there's me
mine is green which means that I'm blue
plus yellow together there's also dots
on people's badges green for people who
want to organize peering black or people
who interested in or security and red
for people who like to sign PGP keys if
during this boss I just told you about
lightning talks this is the big hit
since we started it about a year ago
we're going to do 6 10 minute sessions
again this time three of them tomorrow
three of them on Wednesday the only real
criterion is that it has to be on topic
for nanog in other words has to be
technical sign-ups are open URLs here
there's a link also from the main man on
page it says that the deadline is 3 p.m.
tuesday but if you want to be in
tomorrow session the deadline is 3pm
today if you're not selected for today
you'll go back in the pool again I mean
fee not selected for tomorrow you'll go
back in the pool again for wednesday so
earlier is better once the deadlines
passed the pc will choose our favorite
three four tomorrow and then again our
favorite three for wednesday and you
lucky winners will get to present ten
minutes means 10 minutes at the end of
ten minutes we yank you off the state's
physically of necessary informal buffs I
actually forgot to check about this
we've done this in the past where we
have rooms available for people to sit
down and talk about stuff if you want to
reserve a room for that contact one of
us and we'll figure out something there
is an errand booth out in the
registration area again this is old
information so i don't know if times are
exactly right but if you want to talk to
aaron about registration issues or
membership issues go visit them or even
if you don't just go and say hi not only
they're here to help you but they here
supporting our meeting with a lot of
funding to make the AV stuff and the
webcast stuff happened and that's it for
me so now I'm going to turn the mic over
to Mike O'Brien for the next kale
Jeremiah
Oh
okay hi I'm Michael brian i'm working
for x kale your host here today and
welcome to bellevue bellevue if you're
not from around here is a rapidly
growing suburb of Seattle right across
the lake to the west is the big city
bellevue's about 31 square miles just
under 120 thousand population wise and
if you notice when you come in it's
growing like crazy I mean if when you
drove in from the airport or drove in
this morning if you didn't see a crane
you weren't looking up at one point I
think the figure was almost half of the
cranes west of the Mississippi the big
tower cranes were in bellevue which is
pretty well for a city this size and
down here this URL it's also linked to
on the nanog page i think as the
community forum it's got great
information on the surrounding area and
if you find something good you know feel
free to throw it on there it'll really
help people out this is a late night
paint exercise if you can see it on the
screen this oh here is me big blob you
if you look out this side of the
ballroom if you go out these doors and
then go that way there's a great door
straight into lincoln square which then
has a bridge to bellevue square and
those are two of the main places to go
get food do anything around here so it's
a good way to get right into the heart
of the city who are we Xcal we're a
network equipment vendor located down
the street in redmond right near a
fairly large software company may have
heard of which takes up most of redmond
we're on by Cisco Systems co-founder Len
Bozak and lens goals with all of our
stuff is to create reliable easy to use
and deploy and economical systems we're
basically trying to bring gobs of
bandwidth for cheap the DXM product is
actually providing optical transport in
the nanog 40 network we have a room over
there where you can see that here's a
picture of the network it's actually two
different physical locations upper left
is the Seattle area and lower right is
the Bellevue hotel here and they're
connected by some quest dark fiber so
starting with the upper left we have 10
gige handoffs one from NTT and one from
m's EEMA and they're multiplexed via
DWDM on RDX mhm
machines those are then carried over the
paradox fiber from qwest between Seattle
and here this hotel where their
demultiplexed and shot into a pocket
8801 and I'm gonna do some thanks later
but I'd like to thank you know farinacci
right now for helping us get comfortable
with using that rocket 801 in the
network so thank you know after the proc
it goes into a two different networks
the standard nanog wireless and video
network and then also a gigabit wired
network at each of these four front
tables here we have switches right under
the skirt in the middle of the section
and they're all gigabit copper switches
so you can get a pretty sweet connection
if you sit up there or run a really long
cable okay many many thanks lots of
people to thank I will try to go through
them quickly and if I forget somebody
yell at me or hold a grudge but I prefer
you yo erin quinn from qwest really made
the dark fiber happen and Randy bush and
the SC started the contact introduction
so thanks to all of them and roselle
from enzima for providing the first 10
gig of transit and Brian fast and his
team from NTT America for the same thing
Thank Iggy of transit there's company
called optic fusion here in a local area
it's a data center provider and they let
us use their space in the west and for
putting our optical gear and also did
some some great last mile fiber work in
both areas so thank you Eric stock /
optic fusion the Excalibur can set up
team last for this slide but not least
they were here until late late late last
night doing some some power and network
setup so thanks to them Brice Shane
Nathan Scott Eric and Kelly among others
even more thanks Tony capella when we
got this crazy idea to do this super
high-speed nanog network he was a great
sounding board so Tony thanks for that
work dress from the beginning to the
well right now and also Rodney Joffe the
nanog hosting king who has hosted no not
more than anyone ever will
yeah he was great when we first decided
to look into doing this he he graciously
gave us a bit of his time to work
through what he's been through gave us
some tips and honestly we might not be
here today if he didn't help us out so
Rodney thank you very very very much and
I think everyone might say this but it's
true merit makes hosting easy they're
really really good at this everyone gets
a little nervous I got a little nervous
before it but they show up and they lay
everything down and they've done this so
many times of 39 before this to be exact
so merit thank you very much I would
encourage each and every one of you to
look into hosting because you know it's
great for the community you get your
name up there and it's really fun and
Merritt makes it easy so the mayor of
people on site Larry Betty david salle
dawn Rick Jason and Carol and everyone
back in Ann Arbor thank you all very
much and some final notes as of 613 a.m.
today we had 402 attendees all beer and
gear and break sponsorships have been
sold out and just a note exhale
employees were pretty much all from
around here so if you have any questions
about the area feel free to ask any of
us have any questions about anything
feel free to ask any of us and we'll try
to help you up so enjoy nanog 40 and
here Steve