hello I would like to add that I had
this gift in my presentation when I
wrote it several months ago not knowing
that I would be still quite drunk from
last night so as some of you who already
know me know I used to work for these
guys ah we got bought by these guys just
a lot like working for these guys except
sometimes a bit more like this
I do sometimes sleep in a Borg alcove
so aside from work I do other weird
things like things with lasers and
things with old computers I've seen some
things like that
so under Cisco we have this concept of
service ownership which is essentially
somebody who is in charge of a
particular service so I cover off the
primary application assessments but also
Hardware reviews as on Hodler
assessments and cryptography reviews
although I should point out that a big
heavy windows in front of the binary
applications because I don't know
about Linux yeah I'm a windows monkey so
just keep that in mind
so it's service ownership involves a few
different things it means that you write
the testing methodologies for a
particular particular types of
assessment any kind of like checklists
of things that people need to go through
so for example if you were doing a web
app you would be wanting to look for I
know whether it signed you out after a
particular amount of inactivity whether
it you know there's a fuel injection in
the log in whether you can just try and
just put blank login and password and
see if you go through just silly things
that are in a check list that's the kind
of things about end up writing
developing tools specific to doing
particular types of work and doing
research which I tend to be doing more
of recently so the scope of this talk is
some sort of general tips and tricks
around binary applications the common
vulnerability types that I tend to run
into
yeah why they saw how to find them
how to exploit them how to fix them
because if you're gonna be doing pen
testing that last part is really
important for when you write a report
for a client yeah safety and cover your
ass
if you're running a by nap location
that's given to you by a client you
don't know anything about it it's an
arbitrary binary generally you do have
to install it so insulating the VM and
be sensible with the VM configuration
but that also means that you need to
protect the client data so you can't
just you know stick some application on
your host then uninstall it and hope
that all the files run away at the end
of it and then it turns out that you had
a bunch of like production data that it
pulled from the database in a cache on
your hard disk and you've just been
wandering around with it for six months
client ain't gonna be too happy if they
find out about that and log what you're
doing yeah like when you do things why
you do them who you spoke to
it's quite useful to do that just
because if there is ever a bond that's
that's just good advice for any kind of
testing to be honest and limiting the
scope as well so try and cut things down
to just not bloating everything out
everywhere so what are binary
applications basically anything with one
of those file extensions yes fine your
application dot XE it goes to the moon
it's not a mobile app they're the same
thing but they're on different platforms
therefore they're different we don't
tend to at least in Cisco we don't tend
to talk about mobile apps as binary
applications we do them separately
because there's a different ecosystem
and some of the signature security
controls are different you've got things
like intents on Android and things like
that which I have no idea about 99.9% of
what we see is windows behind
applications occasionally we will get
something scoped as a binary application
that later turns out to be an S 400
green screen application and that's
great when you turn up and you don't
have the faintest clue about what it is
so yeah be careful with that because
people tell you things are binary
applications when they're perhaps not
what you would consider to be a binder
application but yeah 99.9% what we see
is Windows we do some of the next stuff
some
Mac OS so most of that tends to be
cross-platform stuff that sits on these
cross-platform frameworks where you bite
one application and deploy it in three
places
sometimes it's drivers and things like
that yeah client applications so they
could we just standalone stuff you know
think of something like notepad there's
a binary application server applications
obviously the other side of this
sometimes we don't we are testing that
kind of stuff things sometimes bond
applications are serving out like some
sort of web service or something and
then handling the requests in a specific
way rather than having for example an
asp.net server they actually write a
custom binding application that has a
bunch of stuff in there and we would be
testing that there's a binary
applications as well and sometimes it's
browser hosted so unfortunately people
still do things with Silverlight in 2018
as I found out recently so if you follow
me on Twitter you will have seen me
being very salty about the fact that I
had to test a Silverlight application
because it's hateful and it makes you
install very specific requirements and
doesn't work on Windows 10 anymore which
is great consider this was a new
application designed for customers
apparently customers that only run IE 11
and not edge yeah so but also Java
applications in the browser as well
unfortunately yes Java applets in the
browser are also still a thing and then
occasionally you get all of the weird
stuff like ActiveX and just they make me
sad and the scope does include
communications if you're testing upon
application and it's talking to
something else those communications that
it does are in scope now whether the
remote server is in scope depends on the
particular assessment and habits of the
scope that's been written out if it's
not explicitly in scope it isn't in
scope you can test the community what
happens with the communications coming
into the application but not going back
out because a lot of the time a company
would be like actually this is shared
across three different production
environments we'd rather you not poke at
it
so if you want to learn how to test
firing applications unfortunately the
first two hurdles is learning how to
read c-sharp and Java if you don't like
reading c-sharp and Java maybe this
isn't for you because almost every
application that I end up testing is C
sharp or Java occasionally it's a
compiled language compiled language
terrible term it's you know something
that can pass to assembly for a
particular machine so yeah unfortunately
C++ and C and v b6 and Delfy and Pascal
are still around and occasionally very
very strange other things that just like
what the hell is this and so yes you do
unfortunately also need to learn
assembly to some level not always
because most things are c-sharp and Java
so you can often get away with it but
yeah unfortunately assembly is also
something that you generally have to
pick up but then again there are so many
good resources on that these days that
it's actually not that hard if you
already know that programming then it's
actually not as tricky as it looks it
just looks really horrible because you
look at it and you're like what the hell
does any of this mean it does it doesn't
have any like formatting it just looks
awful it's all procedural but yeah it's
it's actually not that difficult once
you start looking at it and yeah getting
comfortable with a particular toolset
that you've chosen the great thing about
but application testing is that for
almost any case that you've run into
where you're like I wouldn't I would
like to do this you usually have like at
least two or three different tools that
you could pick I think at some point I
did actually have I think I moved to
slide around so unfortunately my choice
of tools might be randomly somewhere
else in here so I'm guessing most of you
are familiar with the terms black box
some white box test black box test is
here is the thing we're not going to
tell it tell you anything about it go
break it and a white box test is here's
a thing here is all of its source code
here is all in this documentation here's
everything that about how it works go
dig around in it more often than not
actually these days we're doing both
which is actually quite good because if
you spend a lot of time if you're given
the code you can spend a lot of time go
through the code and digging through it
and trying to find vulnerabilities that
way and you might not necessarily think
to try something that's really dumb that
you would have not thought about that
you would have thought about if you were
just sort of hammering away at a black
black box but if you look at something
as a white box you get an understanding
for how it fits together and you can
often it's just human nature to go oh
well that wouldn't work because clearly
this piece of code here and then you
could have missed something so doing a
black box test and then a white box test
is actually quite common these days and
it just gets around that like weird
thing that everybody does which is just
getting stuck in a particular mindset
about something areas focus right so
you're gonna test a binary application
how do you stop well you want to look at
all of these things business logic is
that the big one I'm gonna go through or
app my tools of the trade slide is on
the next one I haven't moved it around
somewhere for some reason I don't know
um yes the business logic is the main
key if this is basically what does the
application do and why does it do it
it's meant to be enforcing or doing some
sort of fulfilling some sort of role
within an organization so yeah if it's
not doing that then actually that's
often a security failure because that
particular role might be who can get a
firearms license if you can bypass the
the the normal restrictions of that
that's a bad idea
so yeah authentication and session
management of course we all know what
that is
logins sessions blah blah blah network
communications who's it talking to why
is he talking to them what data is going
over there how is that data protected
what can you do if you mess with that
data data at rest does the application
store cache data does it do that in a
safe way and what's the impact of the
system if you install this application
does it make your app your
operating system less secure and now my
out of place slide which I accidentally
moved around these are the tools that I
like why shark for networking stuff like
just doing network tracers burp suite
and zap probably a lot of you know off
because of web application testing it
turns out it's also really useful for
binary applications because if you can
route it through traffic through there
in its HTTP traffic it's just like
working with a regular web application I
kind of pay for doing the same thing but
with binary data some of you will have
heard of echo Mirage canapes like the
better version of that coma Mirage
because like a mirage is old and doesn't
work anymore just be compiled as a
toolbar telluric that's fernette
disassembler net decompiling should
point out that if none of you have if
any of you have never decompiled doc net
application before the decompilers are
now so good that when you d compile an
application a lot of the times you can
actually export a project file load that
back up in Visual Studio and the D
compile code will recompile and work
it's that good
JD GUI for doing java IDR is interactive
this is Delfy something so if you come
against the Delfy app that's quite
useful because it dumps like loads of
the class structure and stuff out either
in binary ninja for doing disassembly
debugger why write that there a debugger
of some sort I imagine I like x64 dbg
Ali is also pretty good for a whole
bunch of them also vigeous to do is
actually quite good for it api monitor
that's a tool by Roja tab that allows
you to see all the API calls that are
being done by a process that's super
useful CF Explorer which is basically
just a PE image editor and PE ID which
is good because if you get something
that's packed which sometimes does
happen it'll tell you what Packer was
used and things like that
it's all it also will tell you which
version of the Microsoft Visual C
runtime it was compiled against if it
was
which is quite nice as well so if you've
got stuff that's talking over the
network you want to be able to proxy the
network traffic with a web application
that's generally really easy because
your browser allows you to just go hey
let's just put that through this
property not always so easy with the
binary application because sometimes it
doesn't wanna play ball sometimes in the
configuration files for the application
or just in the applications
configuration it will allow you to
specify a proxy if that ever happens
hooray
because it saves you a lot of messing
around you can also set up your hosts
file so if you know it's talking to a
particular domain you can set up your
host file to change the IP of that
domain to localhost and then you run a
transparent listener unlike burp or
something and just pass it through and
out you can use the system proxy the
number of times that an application
actually respects the system proxy hmm I
would say somewhere around on and then
you've got the the difference between
Sox and transparent properties if the
application does actually support a
proxy being set then you can set up a
socks proxy usually if it doesn't then
you have to use a transparent proxy
which basically the idea is you set up a
proxy that listens on a particular port
you mess with your hosts file or even
edit the application itself to change
the domain that it's trying to talk to
to go back into to go back to localhost
it then the application then connects to
that that proxy on that port and then it
transparently forwards that out to the
originally original endpoint
unfortunately that can be quite a rigid
and time-consuming thing to set up and
it's kind of annoying so languages that
I tend to see see shops definitely the
top Java following shortly behind vb.net
following shortly behind that wrap rapid
application development languages that
just everybody's using these days you
know anything from banks to trading
companies to governments to like ERP
software everything just
is generally now these days written in
c-sharp Java or vim you don't know it's
it's really common C++ follows shortly
behind that unfortunately Delphian vb6
and pb5 are still being either they're
still being written or they're just
still around just Kovan only go away
clipping I don't know why put mine there
um yeah so c-sharp and Java easily
decompile vb.net easily to compile the
same thing with c shop and vb.net in
case any of you are unaware
both of those are front-end languages
that compile to an intermediate language
called CIL or MS il which is the old
term and then they won on the.net
framework and dotnet runtime they are
actually almost interchangeable you can
make them work with each other very
easily and you can decompile one and
then turn it into a c shop and then
recompile it the c-sharp it's kind of
with java again easily be compared
because that's a jet language with an
intermediate language as well C++ yeah
it's assembly and generally you don't
get much out of it more than like if
they left in the original names like the
mangled names of functions and stuff
especially if they're doing like exports
you get a bit of metadata there but
almost nothing it's mostly just assembly
same as C Delfy and vb v and v b6 you do
get some metadata in there and there are
specific tools to pull that data out and
make things a little bit easier sorry
now that I've still giving you an
overview business logic failures user
access controls business processes
regulatory requirements or the sort of
the high level things that fit under
less so for example should this user be
able to access this or let's say for
example let's say you've got an
application that handles financial
transactions for a bank
and the policy is that the court this is
being used by call center workers and
the call center worker can log into an
account and be like right I'm going to
make this transfer if the transfer is
above ten thousand pounds there is a
specific set of logic in there that
record for anti fraud logic and
anti-money laundering logic where that
transaction has to be elevated to a
supervisor who can then approve it and
then it goes away that's a that's a
piece of business logic if you can get
around that such that a call center
worker can make a transaction that's
more than ten thousand pounds without
having to go through this supervisory
approval process that's a violation of
the business process and it's a and that
is classed as a security issue that's
actually one of the biggest things that
we come up against in any application is
it essentially doesn't enforce the
process that it was intended to enforce
and then also the regulatory
requirements for example in that in that
example that I gave the anti money
laundering
thing is a regulatory requirement also
probably the law I think and yeah in
basically things not a deering to those
regulatory requirements again can come
off as a security issue so in order to
find these business logic flaws you just
use the application you modify traffic
to do silly things you might want to
modify the application to do things it
shouldn't if things are being enforced
on the client side but not on the server
side you might be able to do some silly
things there that comes on to a
different phone ability type we'll talk
about in a little bit but yeah sending
direct requests and things like that
essentially you're looking for
processors that should normally be
followed and whether you can skip over
certain parts of it so there might be
for example a specific end point that
that's used to make a transfer but the
client side flags up that it needs to be
escalated and says oh escalate this
transaction sends off this request of a
server to escalate the transaction what
happens if you just submit the transfer
well sometimes you can bypass things
like that
how do you fix it it's specific to the
individual books it's the problem is
that you essentially have to understand
the application in order to do this in
order to give advice about how to fix
things so in general what you would do
is you would sit and look at the user
manual you would speak to your client
contact and work out how things are
meant to fit together and if they're not
fitting together like that you've got to
think about how they can fix this so
that might be a technical recommendation
of you need to ensure that this workflow
that this secondary part of the workflow
can't be done before the first part is
done things like that the secure
development life cycle does help to an
extend with this because it makes
developers think about security at each
step and how things are being enforced
and the last one is a question because
unfortunately despite giving this advice
quite a lot it never seems to happen but
build security into designs from the
ground up
when you're architecting an application
and you're in this the initial design
phase build security in right there but
unfortunately that's not very useful
advice to give to a client when they've
already written the application so bug
number two architectural failures so
these are fun these are things like find
side enforcement if it's security so
stuff that the client makes you do that
the server doesn't make you do so if you
modify the client or just don't use the
client and you can just make it do all
the things applications where the
communications model is it talks to a
sequel server there is no server
back-end is just a sequel server and if
you are a user you have all of the
access that that sequel user has and
that usually means that you cannot
possibly enforce any kind of business
logic unless you're using like prepared
statements in a really clever way and
very heavily locking things down
generally any application you see that
directly talks out to like sequel is a
bad idea because they're the the the the
the way of enforcing the security model
just ends up
almost impossible because you can just
modify anything that you have access to
and insufficient authorization
capabilities so situations where for
example you've got a single single web
service and a lot of things consuming
this web service and they all
essentially operate under the same level
of authorized date the same privileges
because the web service doesn't know
who's talking to at any point in time I
did I wanted to test for a financial
organization where they had a website on
the internet which just did like basic I
think was like a loan application check
or something something very simple it's
like you could put in a an application
ID and it would tell you the status of
the application that was talking to a
web service that web service was also
talking to their call center software
which was allowing people to actually
proceed through processes it was also
talking back to the accreditors but the
web service had no idea which of these
endpoints was who so everybody had every
possible privilege so it meant that if
you pop the web application you can then
do refunds of 10 grand to your account
with no problem because it didn't know
who you were
it thought everybody had the same sort
of authorization so the lack of
implementation of that kind of authoring
authorization granularity and
understanding identity and things like
that if that's missing everything quite
quite difficult yeah so you can't trust
the client even if you're in a sort of
business environment with lockdown
laptops eventually given enough time
with physical access to the machine
somebody will work out how to pop it you
will have an update to the operating
system that breaks a piece of group
policy and somebody will get around
something it's it's always possible you
can mess with the client you could just
not use the client so here's a fun case
study does anybody remember this game
hands up if you remember in maplestory I
found the Nerds great
maplestory it was this game the
it was like an early side-scroller
MMO thing there's a lot of fun but it
had this problem which was that
literally everything was being done on
the client-side your health we're
monsters were things like that so you
could get these hacks god mode all these
fun things my favorite one is this thing
called vac what factors is it transports
all the monsters on the map to your
position back is fantastic it also does
it with all of the treasure and things
like that because the yeah all of the
and this was a multiplayer game and
because the of the way that the
application was architectured from the
ground up though the way it worked it
was impossible for the server to verify
that anybody's state was the one true
state of the application so you could
just have things happen that weren't
happening on the server but you were
still getting the benefits of them so
you could move all of the monsters to
your position and then kill them because
you've now got god mode and everything
you do just like a critical attack hit
then all of the treasure spawns directly
on top of you after you've killed them
and you get all of the level you level
up you get all the XP you get all the
the cache I don't even remember it's so
long ago that I played this game but
yeah like there's still forums where
people are building stuff for this it
was just a poorly designed game and
that's kind of thing also exists in
business applications the idea that
things are the security model relies
upon the client being left alone and
generally you can't rely on the client
being left alone so finding them look at
the architecture I mean how do you find
an architectural vulnerability look at
the architecture but the topology but if
you find things like sequel queries in
network traffic or if it's connecting to
a sequel port also keep in mind that it
might not be sequel might be Redis might
be MongoDB might be something cloud
related Paco can probably tell you about
that yeah exposed funk
in a whistle so if you're talking to a
web service endpoint it might have a
WSDL file was the file which defines the
end point they are fantastically useless
pieces of information if you actually
want to do a web service test because
often they're like oh do you have any
documentation for this oh yeah we've got
the wisdom file great because all that
tells you is the name of the function
and the types of the parameters but no
names for the parameters or anything
else it's it's a so useless and if you
need any kind of special IDs or anything
it takes a long time to stop messing
with them however looking for exposed
functions in the Bristol or looking at
how the binary application might talk to
it or even other applications using that
same endpoint how they might do things
adding that all together might give you
a good idea of some ways that you could
get around business processes and things
like that and find some architectural
failures in the way that things are
exposed and of course reverse
engineering and code review that's the
long boring work but you can find some
cool stuff from it exploiting them
modify the client if it's dotnet if
you're using telluric just decompile
there's a plugin for plugin called
reflexil which allows you to arbitrarily
modify the code of any method and change
whether fields are like public or
private or anything so you can stop
messing with the client in that way
modify the traffic so stick canopy or
burp or zap or whatever in between it
and as the traffic comes through modify
the traffic in a certain way and set it
out you can always write python scripts
and things like that for that that's
quite honestly directly connect to the
sequel instance if it's got a if you've
got an application that directly talks
to sequel you've got the connection
string somewhere in there take that
directly commit to the sequel database
browse around so what you can find and
user queries not intended for you so if
you've got exposed function are on a web
service you can start messing with that
as well
fixing them kind of hard generally the
problem ends up being that if the
application is architectural e broken
you've already architected and written
the application really hard to sort of
jerry-rigged security back into it at
the end reactor we architecting the
application is not something that a
client ever wants to hear and generally
it highlights the need for security at
the development phases and the design
phases it's an unfortunate situation for
a client to be in if you if you find
that their application is from the
ground up just essentially broken from a
security perspective the only way around
it is for example if you've got this
concept if you if you're missing it if
it's an issue like you're missing the
concept of authorization you can add
that in through for example having
unique client certificates for each each
service that then talks in and then you
can work out which one is which based on
those client services so you can add it
that in at that level but if it's
something like it talks to a sequel
database as the full application
communications communications design you
can't really fix that very well the only
way to get around it sometimes is to put
everything in some kind of like VDI
instance or something like that so
things like Citrix XenApp and XenDesktop
idea being that when you go to connect
to an application instead of the
application being installed on your box
is actually installed on a remote box
that you all sort of are DP'd into sort
of so it gets you away from being able
to mess with the allocation sometimes if
you do it right unfortunately they don't
always configure that correctly but it
isn't optional
so man-in-the-middle or cat in the
middle I don't know you can tell that I
like cats and swear tracker so yeah man
in the middling things you probably
already know what that means essentially
you've got some network traffic get in
the middle of it mess with it see what
it does so missing an insufficient
Transport Security is an incredibly
common
vulnerability that we run into you know
something's talking to some service on
some port somewhere it might be HTTP
traffic it might be some random binary
protocol that they came up with it could
be anything and they're just not putting
any form of encryption or authentication
or thecase integrity checking and things
like that on there or if it uses SSL and
TLS the application just decides not to
check the certificate so you can just go
in and just put your self signed
certificate in there and it just accepts
it and so it might as well not have TLS
from the perspective of a man in the
middle attack and then homebrew crypto
because devs love homebrew crypto yeah
like static strings in an application
that they going get ex-ored with every
packet repeatedly and it's so trivial to
break once you know how it works or yeah
they'll use AES and they'll like H Mac
every packet but then the keys for that
are static and just in the binary
application so it's like well now I know
them you have no security
yeah missing authenticity authenticity
records as well so a lot of the time in
homebrew crypto stuff that people set up
for a particular protocol they'll do
something like they use AES although use
rc4 or they use something like that but
they won't actually authenticate the
traffic they just encrypt it
unfortunately due to things like
malleability attacks what you can
actually do is if you know what some of
the plaintext is you can then actually
flip the bits of the plaintext so it
makes it send other things over you can
do things like say for example you know
that there's a I don't know some some
field and it's like admin 0 that's been
encrypted well if you know where the
zero is you can just flip the bit to be
a 1 the encryption only provides
confidentiality it doesn't provide
authenticity or integrity so if there's
no authenticity record you can just
start messing with data so finding well
in the middle problems yeah look at the
traffic like fairly obvious
reverse-engineer the code and then
actually man-in-the-middle it
reverse-engineer the code is actually
optional but it's just useful man in the
middle the traffic
see what's coming through mess around
with it see what happens again burp
suite or zap so HTTP stuff kind of pay I
like for binary stuff there are other
options you can write your own little
Python scripts and things like that
and then just work out what happens when
you mess with things and also just look
at what's in there sometimes there can
be highly sensitive information has been
transferred over the network either not
protected or weakly protected and then
somebody who's sniffing that traffic can
then see see all that stuff or extract
it for TLS certification stuff I
apologize that that looks really weird
so finding bad TLS validation in c-sharp
the best thing to look for is just the
word server certificate validation
callback which is essentially a global
thing for the application using this
thing called service point manager where
you set a callback for every time it
tries to do a web connection out to
somewhere that's HTTP it calls this
function and no end of times I will find
that it is set to this function that
where it just says return true which is
basically accept anything it could be
expired it could be a code signing
certificate rather than a web
certificate
it could be self signed it could be
anything it could be completely in fact
and it just accepts it because it just
says oh yeah that's fine
return true and sometimes you'll see
people doing clever things like pinning
in there well then what they'll do is
they'll they'll pin then they'll forget
to call the parent callback so they only
do the pinning check they don't do any
of the check so that's always quite
funny the pinning check is always about
very often not based on like a
certificate fingerprint it's more often
than not something like is the issuer
this string which is utterly trivial to
bypass just by self signing your own
cert with the same string it's just not
got the validation chain but as long as
that's
broken then you can just get past it um
Java as usual Java makes it really long
and difficult to read I don't see the
word factory on there though so it can't
be real Java code
so while this looks quite complicated oh
it does have the word Factory good oh
yes good get socket factory so there we
go and that's how we know it's Java so
the way that Java does it is you you set
up a yeah this trust manager thing where
it's sort of sub classing the default
trust manager and allows you to just
return certain things so the idea the
way that Java works is it doesn't return
true or false it does nothing or throws
an exception if it does nothing
that's an excepted certificate if it
throws an exception there was an
exception there was something wrong with
a certificate so the way that Java works
is you do all this rubbish down at the
bottom and you're essentially assigning
this trust all certs trust manager to
the SSL context and then when you do a
HTTP request it then check it basically
calls into these methods inside this
trust manager so it says get accepted
issuers so are there any accepted
issuers that you need you need to be
like restricted to check the client
check client truster to check server
cluster trusted so if it's a client if
here or a service service certificate
those get called as they both do nothing
they accept everything so it's the same
vulnerability again it's just harder to
read and if you and again if you're
looking for this kind of vulnerability
you either you want to look for like one
of these obvious strings like x.509
trust map and Trust manager or what's
the other one but there's a thing
somewhere around here that I can see
where is it
yeah set default hostname verifier is
the other ones that you should look for
and more often than not anything that
anybody does with any of these is
probably vulnerable they have some use
for example saying I will only accept a
certificate if it has the the service
certificate if it has this exact
fingerprint so you can pin it down to a
very specific certificate which is quite
useful and really good security if they
actually do it but unfortunately most
people do it the other way and just say
I accept everything fixing them use TLS
enforce certificate checking which is
not hard because you do nothing by not
subclassing or setting a callback it
just works
it uses the system system default
validation routines and it just works so
the solution is to do less than they're
already doing if it's if it's a
vulnerable system and then of course
certificate pinning if you want to add
that in if you trust yourself to do it
sensibly this is probably one of my
favorite gifts on the Internet
that's so good yeah it's even better
when it's got the shooting stars music
over the top of it and socially I
couldn't get that in so handling
untrusted data this is a just a lot like
web application testing it's just a
binary application instead so you're
sticking weird sequel strings LDAP
strings in there and seeing what happens
the yeah look mal forming packets if
you're having them come in over the
network just like mess with them
randomly and see what happens if you can
reverse engineer the packet format and
it's got some like I know like a number
of Records and it's like for changes to
like 6 million and see what happens
you get memory corruption bugs and then
you get all of the remote code execution
tonnage
yeah dots for higher zip bombs yes this
is still a thing there are still
applications that accept like zip files
over a network and then unzip them which
can have amusing consequences and then
attacks on D serialization which I'll
talk about in a minute
they are a great way to get remote code
execution
so finding exporting sequel injection
read a web app book like if you've
exploited sequel injection on a web app
you can do it on a binary up it's the
same look at the code see if they're
doing silly things with sequel
particularly server-side applications
it just needs to use your export
techniques you can more often than not
use what's the name of the tool sequel
map as long as it's not like a weird
binary protocol which makes it kind of
harder but yeah a lot of the time just
finding things is put the silly cat a
pup that put the sequel characters every
what the ones that everybody knows the
signal injection characters the quotes
and all of the silly ones in every field
and see what happens and if it breaks it
maybe got a good idea what's happening
there passing bugs so first of the
parser if you've got some data that's
coming in say for example it might be
Jason might be XML for XML enjoy hating
your life while you're testing it if
it's you know something weird in binary
yeah script some attacks do something
with Python use some existing file pack
a file or packet format forces there are
some really good ones for network packet
stuff and there are some really good
ones for file stuff where you can take a
you can write like a yeah mall camel
file format spec pass it to the fuzzer
and it generates a whole bunch of files
based on that spec and then you can load
those files into the application and see
what happens and sometimes you'll get a
crash and that crash might give you like
code execution or it might just give you
something maybe interesting that's
useful for cases where for example
somebody's loading a file off a USB
stick or something I think actually it
might have been the same one the same
application same financial application
that was doing the weird web service
thing their application also had a thing
where you could take a mortgage
application file which was like a
if you had somebody from that company go
out to meet you and you know have a
meeting with you what they would do is
they would fill out your application
details in this application and then
export but if they didn't have network
access like if you know this was on a
laptop somewhere without Wi-Fi they
could then export that file then when
they get back to the office load that
file back in or just email it off when
they get access and somebody else can go
and go and carry on messing with it
loading that file in it turns out that
there was a bunch of ways that you could
mess with that file and get like a
memory corruption when it loaded it back
in I think one of them was also a zip
format which again you could do silly
things like zip dos where you would open
a one kilobyte zip extract it and it
takes up one terabyte on your disk
that's always fun and then you get
things like AFL which I don't know when
you've heard of but it's like a common
for Zynga library thing but that gets
compiled into the code so if you don't
have the source code in the build
environment you can't really get AFL on
there it's very rare that I'm in a
situation where I actually get to use
AFL but if you do use that or something
like it that's quite useful again look
at the code seems to be why say every
time but yeah look at the code
see what see how particular things are
being handled and think about how you
might go to get around particular checks
there's no end of times when it'll be
like looking for integer overflows or
something and now check for one the
check that they've got is actually
broken and you get around it and cause
all sorts of mayhem in the memory
not so much in c-sharp or Java because
they've managed so they don't tend to
fall into memory corruption bugs but
again did what was a useful yeah
just like about this so anytime your
application takes her dotnet or a zip or
whatever you can just create these crazy
zip files they're like a couple of
kilobytes but when you expand them it
essentially expands to just ludicrous
amounts of data and then just if you can
do that on a server and your goal is to
dos the server it's a good way to dos it
because if it's ran out of disk space
then it can't write logs and then you
get an exception in the log Handler and
then the whole application falls over
and because nobody expects that the log
hand
won't go to write out so often the error
handling is really bad there because
often the error handling is the log the
wrong writer failed to write I'm now
going to write a log of that error to
the log file guess what happens in case
an exception so why is the exception to
the hook file like rice no exception so
yeah it just falls over and yeah you can
sometimes do that over HTTP sometimes
those things where you could like you
can use like a web service endpoint to
upload a file and knock over so Saudi
serialization attacks these are fun I'm
not really going to them in massive
detail I think I actually gave a talk on
them at some point
but essentially Dussehra serialization
is you take an instance of an object in
a in a language like C sharp or Java and
also PHP and you turn it into some piece
of data that you can ship somewhere and
then on the other end they can take that
data and turn it back into an object so
let's say you've got a dictionary object
that's full of strings or let's just
let's say a list object was full of
strings you can then take that object
turn it into a big blob of data this
might be binary data might be Jason body
XML anything and then at the other end
it goes whoop and then turns it back
into a running object this is also
possible for like classes so let's say
for example you've got a customer class
you get an instance of that customer it
turns that into a binary blob of data or
some JSON and then turns it back into
this customer object at the rent that
you can then do work on as if the same
object existed in both places
unfortunately it turns out that that's
kind of fraught with danger because if
you then pass that over an untrusted
Channel and then you mess with that data
well for a start you might be able to
mess with things that had business logic
requirements around them that's kind of
the boring side of things what you can
do instead is you can just change which
type it was so instead of a customer
object you've got then some other weird
type that when you do serialize it at
the other end does something nasty
I won't go into it too much but
essentially yes Acker replaces the the
genuine content with something sketchy
and the side effect of the object being
either created or destroyed on the far
end actually can lead to remote code
execution so here's a quick example this
is from C shop so use this thing called
a binary for matter that's basically a
thing that crater that serialize and
deserialize as objects so you take some
packet from a client's so that let's say
for example it's taking this packet off
the network puts it in this byte packet
variable and then it destabilizes the
packet into this food packet type into
this variable foo so this is this caste
here which because this generates an
object and then you want to assign it to
the left the left-hand side there now
the vulnerability there is not
immediately obvious however this is what
really gets generated so you've got this
binary formatter you get this binary
packet such a bunch of bunch of data now
what really happens is that caste is
then actually split out the evil object
gets put onto the heap of the
application then they try to cast this
evil object to food packet now evil
objects and food packet are two
different things so it's like this is
apples to oranges I'm not going to do
that so it throws the cat a typecasting
exception so this temporary variable
that's on the heap now goes out of scope
because the exception causes it to jump
out of scope it leaves the method the
temporary variable is now out of scope
so the garbage collector finalizes it
now if there's something in the
finalization logic that causes remote
code execution for example there are
some things to do with scripting
environments some classes in the.net
framework to do scripting environments
that when you tear them down you can
have a teardown script and you can
actually pass that inside of the object
so that when it comes through and the
application goes that's not what I was
expecting
gets rid of the object and then the
object runs it runs its finalization and
script and that finalization script gets
you a see so finding
the serialization bugs oh and don't
think that this has to be done manually
I'll explain why in a minute
yeah finding them you want to look for
data from an untrusted zone for example
a network but also files files that the
user might be given over email or
something like that it's really common
in packet parsing in Java and say shop
to find these things you trace the
function calls from where data comes in
from a packet to some sort of D
serialization call and then verify that
you can send untrusted data there and
once you verified that you know that
you've got a bug in c-sharp if they use
any of these there are probably some
more as well to deserialize
trusted user input you can get RT it's
actually not that hard I've been in Java
you've got a object input stream and XML
encoder they can subclass those to do
some decode stuff but yeah if they're
using those again you can get OC and
there's lots of third-party libraries
that you can do that with as well these
two tools are fantastic because you can
just generate the payload that gets you
a shell or runs a command on a on a box
and then just send that and then it just
works it's super simple so you got one
for Java and one for dotnet so yeah go
check this out and fixing them now in
dotnet or a really short time okay iNDOT
net binders are essentially a way of
taking in the writing of function like a
callback function that checks whether
was actually a you have to write class
but it checks whether the type that's
trying to be loaded can be loaded so it
sort of says I would like to create an
object of this type and the binder has
an opportunity to say no you're not
going to do that so you can restrict the
types that are coming in it is a little
tricky to implement but it's actually
quite useful
and it's about the only way to fix D
serialization books short of writing
your own deserialize er that only works
for your particular types of class which
is a lot of headache and gets rid of a
lot of the reason that people use
serialization Java same thing but it's
just suppressing the object input stream
to use the resolved class method so when
it's it calls back when you go to D
sterilize something it calls this
resolved class method and your resolved
class method can say no I'm not going to
resolve that class because it's not
within my whitelisted trust list of
things that I'm gonna take a pot and the
last one yeah I did say like swear track
so Windows objects so there are actually
three NetID three namespaces in in
windows files registry and objects I
imagine a lot of you as you were growing
up thought files with the only thing
that existed and didn't know about the
registry and were like huh where is this
conflict thing stored for this game that
I'm playing and then you realize that
the registry existing you're like oh wow
this is this whole other thing and
there's also another one called objects
so things like driver's devices events
mutexes semaphores Bowl all get put into
this object namespace
what named ones do non named ones you
can get a handle to them but they don't
exist in the namespace there's a tool
called when objects from sysinternals
that lets you browse them and by default
they're insecure if you create them so
this is what when objects like and this
is what the the object namespace looks
like you got all these objects so you've
got events mutexes jobs timers sections
sections are like mapped Maps memory
mapped files or mapped memory loss
shared memory if you're familiar with
those terms in Linux the permissions
model is quite funny so just going back
one you see at the top you've got this
like backslash in the folders and then
everything comes down from there so API
is allow you to pass a ACL a security
context it's called security security
interviews so an API like create mutex
or create
forget all the ones with a book yeah
create semaphore or things like that if
you pass a null it just gives it no ACL
which means that everybody can access it
if the parent directory doesn't have a a
CL that is inheritable the ACLs are
inherited down that tree and the Brut
ACL is null
there is no ACL and Enola yell means
anyway anybody on the system can access
it so by default if you create a mutex
with a name and you don't give it an ACL
everybody on the system can access it
this is quite useful for a privilege
escalation particularly if drivers are
doing this kind of thing because you can
then stop messing with for example if
it's got a shared memory from a driver
to user mode you can stop messing around
things like that or if the driver itself
doesn't have an appropriate ACL on its
driver object you can start calling IO
controls into the driver which might do
things in the kernel that you shouldn't
have the privilege to do if anybody
remembers the Asus UEFI update driver
bug that was around about a year ago
that allowed you to map all kernel
memory that's how that worked I actually
found it before the guy who reported it
found it but then he managed to get
through the disclosure process faster
than me because it took a sus two and a
half years to get through mine yeah
finding the weak object permissions
process explorers handles view is great
because you can see what objects a
particular process has handles to which
great if you're targeting a particular
application you can use win knobs to
then go through and look at them a bit
more you can right-click on any of those
objects in WA knobs and then click
properties and even see all the security
controls if any often it's null which
means you could mess with them you can
also use API monitoring to see what
what's been called and what's being
created when you exploit them the
exploitation is local you there's no
network access to this stuff so local
probe ask at best but cross user is
quite interesting on multi tenant
systems I have found stuff that that and
multi tenant systems do sort of exist
sometimes like on the desktop model it's
total nonsense any vulnerability that
anybody reports there's multi tenant for
DES like Windows desktop users is just
since because nobody's ever logged into
it that concurrently but sometimes you
can run into cases whether it's quite
useful and shared memory is often
interesting so quick case early
application visualization yeah sorry
running late
application virtualization software
might be one that I mentioned earlier
has a thing where applications in
applications that are running in this
virtualized desktop perhaps over more
poor desktop instances share a specific
set of memory so there's basically every
process has this Maps this piece of
shared process because it's loading a
it's loading like a particular DLL for
doing some stuff that allows you to copy
paste it in and out so in and out of the
virtualized environment and things like
that but the memory itself is not
protected because the dacl is no but it
injects into every this this thing is
injected into every process on the
system including ones that run a system
and the memory contains a DLL to the
path to the binary that needs to be
injected so if you just change the path
every process on the system loads this
binary which gets you immediate
professed system although if you point a
non-existent DLL the error handling case
in this was just to continue trying
which means that every single process on
the Box suddenly goes into a spin loop
which hoses the entire instance and
means that the only way to kill all the
instances is to reboot the
virtualization server which was I found
that by accident we copied any
permissions cases 32 Sophos antivirus
had this issue where you could the there
was a bunch of mutexes that were run by
the scanning drivers but they were not
protected you could lock you could
acquire all the mutexes all of the
threat the scanning threads would then
stop and you could basically just halt
the a/v scanning which meant that you
got eventually what happens is it sees
it as a the OS sees it as a kernel
thread hanging and then BSOD is the box
within the time between that which
like I think like 15 seconds or
something you can essentially do what
anything you like and the AV can't stop
you it's quite fun so fixing them pass
an ACL to any of the api's when you're
creating mutexes drivers or anything
like that and you can copy them directly
from your process if you want the same
ACL as what your processes and running
out or you can generate them manually
there are eight cars do that so in
conclusion binary applications are
challenging but also fun there's a lots
of cool things you can find my top five
here is definitely subjective this is
based on my experience of testing behind
applications what somebody else does is
in a different sort of industry vertical
what they're playing with is probably
different if you can test a web
application you can probably test upon
your application it's like the approach
is largely the same it's just different
tooling and different technologies that
you're playing with so it's you know and
you don't need to be elite sport dev you
don't need to be able to you know build
rock chains and bypass SLR that stuff
almost never happens I never look at
meta I think I don't I think I've used
Metasploit like twice in my entire
career so yeah you don't need to be an
early exploit dev you can learn this
stuff quite quickly and there we go
thank you any questions
[Applause]