so hello everybody my name is John I
primarily by day run the engineering
division at a company called mill web
down in Manchester together with my
colleague Jamie who was formerly
supposed to be here
unfortunately he ended up double booking
himself due to the whole take-two thing
he is not in fact my former colleague I
would note he's still employed as far as
I'm aware so both of us have fairly
extensive backgrounds in the past with
security research and the like Jamie
actually presented here last year if
you're familiar with any of my previous
talks you'll know this is either going
to go perfectly fine or become a pun
filled mess within the first half hour
or so so this is Jane Jane has worked
for a non-specific large bank for about
three years and quickly garnering a
reputation as a well-liked and
trustworthy member of staff Jane has
just walked out of this Bank with their
primary trading algorithm and the full
transaction history of their five
largest customers so let's break down
how this happened so Jane gets to work
she tailgates an employee that she knows
through the entrance they let her
through because they know her there's no
CCTV all intents and purposes Jane is
now in the building and no one knows
she's there she then proceeds through to
Bob's desk Bob is away on holiday so she
reads the password on the post-it note
underneath his display logs in and since
she's within the building it's a trusted
network so no multi-factor she then
proceeds through and realizes right I've
got this information now how do i
exfiltrate it bad news this this
particular organization has some level
of endpoint security so USB is
restricted network usually isn't so you
just plug a Raspberry Pi in with a FTP
server and suddenly everything is
hunky-dory it gets the copy destroys the
vow spy walks out with the SD card if
you're going to get really fancy it's in
your cheek or something
and then effectively disappears off
never to be seen again so how do we stop
Jane so let's kind of roll back for a
second and think about how we got to
this point because essentially 80% of
these kinds of incidents are primarily
caused by three things you either have
bad processes you have bad planning or
you have bad tools and in this case I'm
kind of amalgamating like bad setup of
tools into bad planning because in a lot
of cases if you have something that's
misconfigured that can cause and ciliary
problems but yeah and essentially it in
at least from what I found most of these
can be solved either by making these
processes easier or by automating as
much as you can of it because there's
very little that can go wrong with a
properly defined well automated process
as opposed to a human oriented approach
to that on the flip side to kind of
touch on something that Paco said little
earlier if you do have a system where
suddenly it's not that nothing's getting
alerts
it's that everything's getting alerts
and you have 10,000 emails a day and
they are all getting nicely routed
through to a completely different inbox
that you never check then you can get
situations where lots you condition
people to ignore everything which then
causes them to ignore the serious stuff
as well so the first thing that we
really should have had in this scenario
is some form of identity management
right because when you go to any kind of
corporate they are going to have some
type of directory management of another
sort and it is usually one of these
three right so these are the key players
in the first part of our puzzle and yeah
essentially most companies aren't going
to have as much of a targeted or
seasoned attack as this this isn't the
case of like right okay here's your
cupcake ordering service they are not
going to have someone who spends three
years Trojan horsing their way in in
order to go away with your client list
list it's kind of different I'll say
you're going to have different security
concerns
for the kind of situation we're talking
about which tends to be more
specifically oriented around kind of
larger financial services type
corporations so Active Directory the
good old specter at the feast it is good
enough not really I think everyone in
this room can probably pick at least one
active directory exploit that they have
particularly familiar with my personal
favorite is either past the hash or the
whole movie cats ticket escalation thing
pretty much every type of author bar I
think the last three that Microsoft
released has been broken in some form or
another so it's not exactly the it's not
exactly the best thing in terms of
historical detail then you go into right
okay sure this thing is specifically
designed for Microsoft and Windows so
sure let's let's assume that Microsoft
have got this right what happens when
you go and look at Apple's
implementation or any other type of
device that has to interact with this
when you get that level of kind of
diversity across a whole bunch of the
massive kind of ecosystem where I was
only really designed for this kind of
smaller perspective you start to get
deviation which can then result in
larger issues and even companies like
Apple can screw this up as evidenced
when they decided to casually remove the
concept of password authenticated user
accounts a couple of Mac updates ago and
then bring it back again it's also quite
generic which can be a good thing and a
bad thing
it's if you have the time to kind of
really customize it and dig into it it
can be very powerful but with a lot of a
lot of cases people will grab it they
will shove the default configuration on
it and then that's the point of which
really bad things happen without a fair
bit of tweaking you can't really pull in
external data sources to do risk
evaluation on things like logins there
are ways to do this but it's kind of
tends to get a bit complicated and in
terms of the most general UI of it
administrating it tends to take affair
at a time and what's it can be very easy
to just have accounts kind of left in
there
that if you can then we'll sit either
through social engineering or some other
method reactivate them can result in
fairly gaping holes so a couple of years
ago Microsoft came up with this euro ad
which is essentially hey what would
happen if we took Active Directory and
put it in the cloud and it's not quite
like that it's more akin to a kind of
identity as a service single sign-on
kind of thing and it is quite nice it
solves a fair few of the issues who are
talking about before it introduces risk
evaluation in terms of things like IP
address correlation location right
you've logged in from these two
locations in the last five minutes you
can possibly have traveled there
ergo probably shouldn't let you in it
also introduces things like what's it
like external hosted LDAP for
integrating with other third-party
services you can do it single sign-on
that kind of thing I'm sure what set
anyone who's used office 365 is familiar
with that kind of process but at the end
of the day it is still Active Directory
and it still comes with a lot of these
same types of platform based limitations
then we have duo who are I quite like
them they essentially don't really do
the directory portion of it so much as
the identity part they effectively say
right we are going to you federer way
out to wherever you're storing all your
users and then that's it we will
effectively take all of your stuff and
we will then handle the often to build
will then handle the I am portion of it
in front of that so for 80% of IT teams
who effectively just want isn't good SSO
good endpoint security and not much fuss
in front of it you can generally use it
as a fairly solid plug-and-play solution
the caveat being that you really need
either your own directory server sitting
behind it or if you are in if you want
to kind of use portions of duo's own
directory management it's not
particularly complex however it does
have a few downsides things like
things that they're kind of concepts of
effectively kind of access policies are
nice but only come in at the six buck a
month level there is naturally the idea
of like okay you are taking all of your
what said authentication systems and you
are sticking them in someone else's
infrastructure who you may not
necessarily want to trust and they don't
support things like jump for kind of
introducing things like bring your own
device or manage devices that kind of
thing they support to to other providers
but not many outside of that and there
doesn't really appear to be a way to
integrate with them to kind of get that
through you could get around things like
the cloud hosting thing by deploying it
on-site but as they say there's always
money in on stand deployments and
essentially that kind of comes along
with the associated five six figure
price tag I do I will give them a large
amount of kudos for this actually they
have a a free tool that effectively lets
you do targeted phishing attacks where
you can effectively to throw an email
list into it say why I want to spoof
office or Outlook or Google Docs and it
will then go off and build emails for
you send those off and then come back
and you can log in and see lists of
who's actually clicked through those
which is available there but besides
that there's there a good kind of
plug-and-play solution but they're not
going to solve all of the detail issues
that we've got in our scenario right
then there's octa who if you are to
believe the Gartner Magic Quadrant are
apparently the market leaders in
Identity Management but yeah it's not
like they're that influential right well
they somehow managed to get Obama to
turn up as the keynote speaker for their
conference this year so apparently yes
yes they are they are effectively more
complex Enterprise duo in many ways so
they they have things like adaptive
security
which is whatsit which is great because
it's essentially taking all of that kind
of general heuristics view that duo does
and ramping it up a notch so you get
things like what's it proper proper kind
of really looking at where like what IPS
are where they're coming from location
tracking device trust scanning the
scanning the internet for compromised
accounts for example because like yeah
changing random stuff until your program
works is hacky and bad development
practice but if you do it fast enough
then it's machine learning and it pays
four times your code salary
there's the again it kind of comes in
two flavors they do have their own
directory contrary to what's it do oh is
kind of requires that you bring your own
and they have single sign-on integration
with literally everything including
several things that I didn't even
realize existed until I looked at their
supported let's say platforms page and
it's about that's it at least three or
four pages long their pricing seems
quite nice on the outside of it until
you look at the asterisks and realize
that you're basically looking at a four
figure minimum which can be pretty that
can be a non-starter for a lot of
smaller organizations especially because
you may not necessarily have that much
capital upfront to kind of throw out
security then came storm path now storm
path was great storm path was a really
nicely designed easy to use REST API
where you could basically go right I'm
gonna stick this in front of my
directory servers it'll do my single
sign-on it'll do all the rest of it but
then on top of that I can actually bring
my own stuff into it and you can say
right ok so I want to lets it vite vite
something up that effectively checks
whether certain employees have access in
certain times of day for example listen
you could do that and essentially kind
of pull all of that in it so it does
that it can kind of integrate you can
even store your own kind of little
effectively secured storage blobs for
each user with storm paths instead of
having this kind of story in LDAP and
then encrypt it and decrypt it and all
the rest of that
it were all sort of really really nice
pre-built sdk for a whole ton of
different languages and was generally
just the breeze to use I think you've
got to see where I'm going with this
with all the past tenses so octa
acquired them and storm paths
new paths kind of went from looking like
this to a bit more like this very very
quickly the essentially what they ended
up doing was stripping out the entirety
of the API Sun setting it and then
effectively going cool you guys use the
octave API now except the octave API
requires that you pay Akhter style
pricing fees which no one using storm
path I think was really willing to do
yeah essentially it kind of went the way
of the dodo in many ways if you if
you're wondering why there's so many
Arrested Development references in this
talk it's pretty much just our
engineering style but yeah essentially
what this kind of boils down to is the
fact that while all of these have their
place a lot of their solutions kind of
tend to solve these different types of
expected risk in subtly different ways
and much like a Venn diagram you're
never going to quite get overlap that
covers all of your bases within one
thing and if you kind of look at it from
another perspective any company who both
wants to keep their authentication and
security data to themselves and has
these security chops in-house but maybe
isn't interested in paying six figures
for the privilege of having to maintain
infrastructure that they don't own they
don't tend to be many very very many
options within that area we then have
our second problem which is the user
experience of bad security which
primarily tends to go down too right
okay in in in the scenario that I'm
talking about most of your end users are
going to be either ops staff or
developers or people kind of within the
technical space who are going to be
interacting with these systems on a
daily basis they're going to be building
them they're going to be playing around
with them and they need to have fairly
they needs are fairly
widespread access in many cases to in
order to facilitate what they're doing
day to day and a lot of that can
essentially break down to write so we
have these people how are they using our
existing security practices like that
the one thing that I mentioned before
was post-it notes but everybody does
this password post-it notes are a trope
of physical security because they keep
happening even though everyone knows
that it's a terrible terrible idea and
it's not just small-time operations that
have had their security compromised by
the humble post-it know either this is
the agency responsible for that nucleus
care in Hawaii a little while ago who
just so happened to also have one
casually hanging out on there apparently
nuclear FEMA control computer as you do
and there's a lot of reasons that we
kind of tend to put forward for people
not necessarily understanding computers
security are they other users lazy do
they not understand the ramifications of
what could happen do they not care about
the ramifications of what could happen
if someone eventually gets access to
their details and when we're designing
all of these security experiences and
especially when we're designing things
along the lines of plotted policy and
that's it SSO and things that people are
going to be interacting with on a fairly
regular basis we need to assume all of
the above the the best way to figure out
how people are going to get around your
stuff is to make the assumption that all
users are lazy and they will try and cut
every corner that they possibly can to
do things quicker humans are naturally
built to try and optimize things so if
there is a problem right in front of you
and you go right okay if I'm having to
type my password in 30 times a day and
it gets changed every week then I'm just
going to keep adding a one to the end of
that password and stick it on a post-it
though in front of me you're not going
to get this there they are going to find
ways around it even though those ways
may not be the best for your security
policy so the easiest way to solve that
is to essentially integrate the two
together and kind of really
think about just because that's it a lot
of places tend to see early at least
that the kind of corporate level tend to
see security in many ways is an
unnecessary burden let alone the staff
who aren't ranked on how secure they are
and we should kind of us make say right
okay just because users don't know the
ins and outs of the password policy and
all of our compliance requirements we
know them but that's because it's our
job to know them we shouldn't assume
that people understand why these things
are there we have to kind of essentially
teach it to them as everything goes
across and a lot of the time it tends to
be a case that people always assume that
they're not the problem
that no one want no one wants to target
me I'm not interesting there's nothing
that's going to go nothing that's going
to go along here and culturally that
tends to be very difficult to change
because a lot of the time people aren't
going to make that assumption until you
go right well actually what do you what
do what does this person have to gain
from targeting you and really make them
think about it and so the first decision
that we always make when designing these
types of systems is again to give people
as few choice as possible the vast
majority of your users they don't care
about the security side we need to make
them care about the security side and we
need to make them care in a way that is
going to convince them to keep on doing
it regardless of whether it benefits
them or not if it increases the amount
of time that they spend dealing with
something that they don't care about
then that means that they're going to
rush through the process without
thinking about it which means they could
potentially be then making mistakes
further along the line and a lot of the
time I'd say the core thing is to only
necessary when you're thinking of the UX
side of it only make the user do things
that you absolutely require them to do
if you if you if you get situations
where you're kind of going right well we
could throw in these 10,000 options and
make them
what's it configure everything exactly
to their liking but actually if you just
give them some solid defaults and then
let them tweak from there that can often
be far more productive in the long run
as an example of this if you do a search
on the App Store for HSBC right you get
presented with three potential options
here and the first one is a whatsit the
first actually hanging up there we go
that's the slide the first one is an
option for HSBC mobile banking in the UK
right which has overwhelming positive
reviews looks nice and it supports most
of the latest iOS security features it's
simple it's easy to use and the sign up
and login system has very clear
well-defined hours for when you're doing
something wrong the second is for HSBC
mobile banking which has all four
reviews appears to have been updated in
2009 has basically no modern iOS
security and touch ID essentially fails
on every second login with it which then
requires a password fallback which takes
ages to log in which has led in several
cases that I found at least where I've
had what said people I know who've been
using this particular app have then set
very weak online banking passwords
because they're having to enter it so
often you're the the fact that it
becomes such a chore then convinces them
to effectively weaken that and it's a
it's essentially a really convoluted
design that doesn't really tell you when
you're doing something wrong then you've
got on the end you've got the
effectively the same equivalent as the
first one except it's only available in
Hong Kong and if you think about it well
firstly if you pick from this list
obviously to us at least the the correct
option over here would be option a but
if you put yourself in the shoes of the
average user right they've been told to
go download this app from by their bank
branch or by an advert on TV or whatever
and they're wary of downloading the
wrong thing because it's a finance app
and it said they know that that is a an
important thing to do so they go to
Google to check it what do they find
option B the insecure version
additionally what is this that this is
this is a effectively their own
arbitrary what's it mobile first Bank
site again from about 2009 that no one's
really bothered to turn off it's just
kind of there and the fact that if
you're kind of giving people if the
immediate thing that you see is the
wrong option you are in see you are
instinctively never going to be able to
catch like let's say 80% of users are
always going to go for that
every single time and you're not going
to be able to stop them you have to
funnel them in in the right direction
otherwise you do get situations like
this on a similar note right who can
tell me the difference between these
wait wait yep yes that is correct that
is a Cyrillic a these are known as puny
code attacks these can be equally as
messy because if we jump back over here
again potentially I could have two HSBC
movie there that might not even be an
HSBC owned domain that could be someone
who hasn't bought a domain that matches
it uses extremely similar looking
unicode characters which you'd never
really spot unless you actually looked
at the and unless you actually really
looked at the domain or specifically
clicked through it and can lets it
effectively result in some really
devastating or set phishing attacks
purely by way of the fact that we
haven't really thought about the UX
ramifications of it so in terms of
preventing these types of attacks the
core way to do it is essentially to kind
of go along the lines of hey here's some
trusted sources say it with password
managers specifically if you remember
passwords by the actual domain then if
if I if you go to the bottom domain and
I have a password safe Apple com it'll
pop up if you go to the top domain it
won't so that can be a fairly fairly
good way of kind of getting a bit of an
early warning of what is potentially
going on if you have chrome there's a
browser extension called puny code alert
which will specifically ping you if you
go to any domain that contains this type
of these type of symbols
essentially what this kind of boils down
to in the end is that there is a place
in the world of security for software
that doesn't just act well and kind of
easily helps users get where they want
to go but also has a level of simplicity
to it that we don't tend to get in a lot
of modern systems so let's roll back
again how do we stop Jane so the first
thing we can do is use UX as a security
tool so if we make things really easy or
useful for our users then they are far
they're going to be far more inclined to
actually use them right so that's it if
you have a situation where not say you
have your security tool and oh sure it's
a security tool but it also happens to
give you the ability to what's it it
gives you the ability to go and request
access to servers that you may not
necessarily have right so if you so if
you're working as a whatsit if you're
working as a front-end ops person and
you have limited access to a block of
production servers you can go right I
need access to this thing for X reason
and suddenly you start to make these
tools not only integrated with the
processes that your developers are going
through but you can really start to
think about right well this isn't just
this is this is not only promoting
proactive security policy but it's also
making things easier for them yeah
there's a there's a there doesn't have
to necessarily be a trade-off there or
like I said that being able to delegate
access for people in teams without
having to go all the way over to IT or
for example providing one of the things
that we've done internally is that I'll
set as part of our I am system we have
the ability to effectively let's say you
just say right I I need access to this
AWS account and then it goes right do
you have access to the say DBS account
if yes then it goes off to STS gets
tokens and then goes cool I'm gonna put
these in your well so I'm gonna put
these in your environment for the
duration of this session and now you
have access and what's it you
never have to touch or see any of the
Associated Amazon stuff you just go
right this is my employee account I now
have access to the things that I need to
and I'm successfully sandboxed off from
the things that I don't then you have
the human element so things like
physical security things like what's it
named badges with photos on them color
coding on passes that I know this is
something that apples had particular
success with in the past one of the
things that we've been kind of
considering for a while is the idea of
of secure words so the concept being
that you have maybe three or four words
you store that on the lot in in the
direction in the directory with the
whatever else information that you store
so that if someone ever
what's it has it has a badge and tries
to steal a badge and tap in you have a
way of effectively doing two-factor for
humans right without having to kind of
go off to any other two-factor tokens
that may have been stolen at that point
you can go right you don't have the
ability to fake what you can't insert
into a system so if this person happens
to have this badge but can't remember
this specific piece of memorable
information maybe we want to be a heck
of a lot more wary of them and generally
a lot of this tends to boil down to not
training and kind of just generally
making sure that what you've got in your
organization is centrally focused on
making this stuff as easy as possible
without having you don't necessarily
have to compromise upon the security but
if you can explain why people should
care about it it will make it a heck of
a lot easier to then explain to them
what they need to do access restriction
right so principle of least permission
if in any and any organization you
should be making sure that everything
you have is locked down to the lowest
possible denominator the issue then
comes in when you have people like
what's it your Ops teams who are
constantly have and you can't just go
and say right okay sure
developers you have access to this block
of stuff right and
if that's a staging environment or
development environment they might they
may either have blanket access to dev
because frankly nothing's really going
to break there they may have limited
access to certain assets and staging but
if you're but if you have a small
contingent of your ops team who is
working actively in a production
environment you need a system that is
not only restrictive but also malleable
enough to still allow them to do their
job without potentially giving them
unrestricted access to everything then
or at least giving them giving them the
access that they need as they need it so
next we're going to roll into some of
the ways that we've solved this
internally with some of our own internal
security tools so we are currently
working on a a system that we have that
handles some of our what it effectively
some of our single sign-on in terms of
sitting in front of everything as a kind
of duo like layer and one of the first
things that we did with this was to
think about right as a company we have a
large amount of information on the
people that we employ but we very rarely
look at that from your HR looks at it
from an HR perspective we never really
thought about looking at it from a
security perspective so we went right
what can we take from this and then
apply so we realized right well
everyone's got a shared calendar so we
know where people are going to be in
terms of holidays and business traveling
like so we can start to correlate that
movement with where they're logging in
from to ensure that they are in fact
where they are in fact logging in from
roughly where they should be we can take
things like time of day so if they are
generally working in GMT then I'll say
if they are not it's it frontline ops or
the like they probably shouldn't be
logging in at 3 in the morning that
could bump the risks go up again IP
addresses have we seen it before is it
related to a honeypot what kind of stuff
we can get around that Network locations
general patterns of logging time typing
signatures was a fun one we're still
working on that but we are attempting to
see whether we can essentially
get a system that can effectively when
you type your password in we effectively
create a hash of your you're typing
characteristics in terms of how long the
time span is between you between when
you hit certain keys and then
effectively use that to build up a
signature to actually build a hat that
we can then reference back to to say
right okay this is in this is actually
the person logging in roughly with it
with the same kind of pattern it did
have an unexpected side effect actually
when we were testing that in that it
made it extremely easy to lock out drunk
people because as it turns out it takes
quite a lot of effort to type at the
same speed when three pints under so
essentially if we kind of break that
down to the permissions level we then
start to go right so what's it we have a
what's it the user once they're logged
in what they are able to view is their
risk score but from their last X number
of logins so they can see how that's
being calculated to keep a level of
transparency there well most of this
data is computed and kind of sat in the
thing so we have all the stuff that they
have put in we've got all the stuff that
we hold on them and we have all of their
previous other information they can then
go right out it integrations they can
plug in Cal
corporate calendar and the like we kind
of plug in by default but if they have
any other corporate email addresses and
the like they can then add those on it's
it's safe MFA so again we go back to the
whole easy ease of use principle if you
have to go to security every time you
swap out an MFA token that's maybe not
going to result in the best security
posture so what we have is effectively
we kind of combine things like that in
with risk scores so we say right okay if
you're adding a new asset you're adding
in you MFA token and you're adding it
from the office at 3:00 p.m. and nothing
else has really happened with your
account then that's probably not
nothing's really going to act as an
issue there and then things like known
places so kind of like how if you call
your bank up and you say right I'm going
to be going to
Singapore so please don't leave me
without any money at which point they
will then proceed to do exactly that but
in our case it generally doesn't it
contends to kind of let you factor in
decisions like that from an
administrative perspective the bottom of
an administrative view you can see
everything so you get to see the whole
heuristics picture of how all of your
accounts are playing out where where the
kind of hotspots are almost and you can
then go through and say right what's it
if we don't want anybody logging in we
don't have an office in China we don't
have anyone going to China let's lock
out China right or we can then go right
okay
primarily OSU right now is with
two-factor it's with people kind of like
going like hey get on to my account
here's my MFA token so we can increase
the risk associated with l2m
effortlessly to accounts being logged in
within a certain period of time and then
yeah trust crush holds for essentially
going right if you're trying to get into
production that's going to require a lot
more effort than if you're trying to log
in to dev or just take a look at the
wiki so if we break things back down to
our initial timeline let's see how a lot
of the stuff that we have well that
we've kind of taken from this can then
be applied to stop these types of issues
right so initially working CCTV okay so
if you have a camera on your main
entrance
suddenly Jane walking through without a
badge still has a log that she's been
there you may have to go and scrub
through footage but you can say
definitively right well these are people
entering and leaving your building they
may not be in your access logs but they
can sure as heck be in your access video
what's a good security posture so that
employee that she tailgates in what if
they have been successfully told right
if anyone goes in with it without a
badge doesn't matter who they are May us
it challenge them and make sure that
they or sit they actually have the
correct access to be there at that point
in time all right it's it's a simple
simple thing but even even getting
people to kind of do that
proactively especially with people that
they may know and kind of work with on a
fairly regular basis can be quite
challenging so since logins are now so
easy Bob never writes his password down
so he's so we've now completely removed
the post it note problem where
everything is now effectively sitting on
the level playing field where like right
now Jane actually has to put some effort
in to try and get user credentials and
even if that and even if at some point
that does happen Bob's on holiday which
means that that's it his account if
you're trying to log in from HQ Bob is
400 miles in that direction which means
you're going to need some serious
authentication to convince this thing
that actually he's managed to fly back
early in terms of exfiltration egress of
any kind regardless of everyone goes for
USB but network and literally just think
think how you would air-gap something
and then assume that every possible type
of egress is a path is a vector
most people mostly just go for USB and
that's it in most cases that's a ten
point security can be fallible if you're
making the assumption that your endpoint
security is going to let it tell you
right we'll all these machines on my
network all that the endpoint security
is talking back to my central server so
all of these machines are supposed to be
here right it's like you're you're
essentially saying wait okay cool I'm
going to take all of this what's it all
of my kind of security and I'm going to
almost kind of put it on a potentially
compromised machine and think of
thinking from that perspective in terms
of things like MDM can definitely help
as well file storage locations limit
them if you'll use it what's it we used
to have a situation where all of our a
lot of our files tended to be spread
across like s3 Dropbox a whole ton of
other different platforms we effectively
managed to bring it back to just s3 and
Dropbox which means that we now know
exactly where everything is and exactly
where it may go yeah this is we are now
we are now if we've reached this point
we had our five steps along and our
hitting levels of incompetency that I
only thought was import was possible
core facts so segregated access control
here would mean that Bob can only access
information on the clients that he deals
with he has no access to other portions
of the company anymore and the thing
that he tries to modify or source-code
he tries to clone they are either logged
with an audit trail specific to his
account or they are completely blocked
off entirely and if again maybe you
could go off and then modify the audit
trail but if you have someone directly
attacking your identity server you have
far bigger issues I mean you could but
where's the fun in that right so yeah
essentially having gone through all of
those steps and with a lot of the bulk
surrounding it we have hopefully saved
corporate for now so yep if you're
interested in any of the stuff
surrounding this I realized I've come in
quite early so we should have time for
questions but otherwise you can
definitely hit me up on Twitter
otherwise thank you very much
[Applause]
you had to take questions from the world
anything all right perfect
Thanks nope oh the whatsit yeah so
there's there's a I can't exactly reveal
how we do that yet but there's we spent
quite a while kind of playing around
with a few different yeah the the maths
is significantly beyond me
but essentially the way that it the way
that it works is that it figures out the
the people have different time gaps
between how they type different letters
so most mostly based in terms of what
sit where your hands would normally sit
on the keyboard some that's it some some
letters may be quicker to read some may
be slower but everyone has their own
cadence to it so kind of like with music
you can essentially kind of go right
well this is the this is the pattern to
it this is how this person specifically
plays this piece and then if you have
that you can effectively say right well
we can kind of make sure that they are
generally following that pattern with
these sets of what's it sequential
characters yeah so that so the first
couple times they type the password in
it effectively kind of trains the
signature up and then from there it
effectively goes off and just what's it
over time it kind of you make a
successful author quest it adds that
essentially to the model to kind of
improve it over time yeah it's it's a
bit of a it was a it was a completely
unexpected side effect that one actually
the only the only reason that we what's
it founded out was because we were
working on it in a particularly late
night and realized that actually it does
work yep
not yet
we what sir the we do have a couple of
we were actually wondering and I haven't
tested tried this as a couple of people
in the office who have like economic
keyboards so into us in terms of the way
that they the way that their typing
style could potentially change when they
went out of the office and use the
laptop that could be something that we'd
have to kind of factor in but since the
whole I the whole concept that we're
working off of here with risk scores is
primarily based around the idea that
that's not going to be the only factor
so even if you might get marked down by
that they'll still be a level of access
across everything else yes up in the
back well yeah that is intriguing hmm
I'll definitely have to have a chat with
you then that's very interesting any
others yes Center well you can't we
ought to in terms of what's it corporate
passwords the the way that we've all
with things is that let's see you can
but again it'll it'll it'll mark you
down for it you can still use password
managers but I'll - I think I'm
personally of the opinion that with
things like that if you can memorize it
it is much better to memorize it because
if you don't have access to a password
manager and need to get into something
then that is going to be a significant
well we use one password internally so
in order to get in in order for me to
sit my vault on another system I would
have to effectively go and thought it
put him get my vault password get the
actual main password and then go and get
the what's it secret key for my user out
of a safe deposit box so it's not
exactly the easiest thing whereas if I
know that I've got the credentials right
in my head then it turns lot easier yes
so we only ever do it on the login pages
so since we're already getting since we
already have JavaScript in the thing to
pull information like the l-sit bit so
if you're familiar with whatsit Trusteer
but they'll sit there they have a
similar thing where you can kind of
essentially there are ways that you can
effectively have a local agent on the
device
talk to the what's at the jar closet
javascript in a browser so we have it
essentially so that that sends back the
device information and then the whatsit
it's it is it is bad it is very easy to
key log things with javascript funnily
enough I think there's actually a way a
little while ago that you can do it with
CSS now which is even more terrifying
because that's literally unnoticeable
yes yes to mitigate around that not yet
we have a few ideas but since we haven't
rolled this out we haven't went with
yeah it said essentially it is a it's
definitely a problem but since it tends
to effectively be that particular
portion of it is purely confined to that
one login page and it doesn't see
ourself and all the rest of it it can't
I say exercice it can't talk out of that
page it can't pick up key lock key
strokes from
nothing other than if you are
specifically focused on that page and as
far as who aware that does seem to be
the behavior in Chrome and Firefox then
that tends to help us so long as we
basically say right well the only thing
on this page is the password box yes
partially but we have had some pushback
from that in terms of people who use
device lets it occasionally use devices
for access that don't necessarily
support new bikies see also phones so if
any one kind of needs access to
documentation or internal systems on
something that doesn't have a USB port
or doesn't support NFC then it becomes a
little bit difficult anything else
perfect thank you
[Applause]
you