okay I'm glad you're still here I'm
going to do a talk about peekaboo AV
which is a project of mine which I
really love and I hope I can I can
encourage you to love it as well I am
I'm from Germany so if you get the
impression that we've started with a
PowerPoint karaoke already that's
because I'm German like him the peekaboo
AV project that is where's the peekaboo
thing it's an owl and it's cute and that
is weird
okay well you can you can still see the
text so peekaboo AV basically turns
cuckoo sandbox into an anti-virus that's
that's the basic idea behind it most of
you I assume know know what cuckoo
sandbox is cuckoo sandbox was made for
for analysts four-mile analysts for
maybe Incident Response people maybe
forensics people but not particularly in
a way that is 100 percent automate it is
it's so you can you can throw your file
set and look at the reports that are
interesting to you it's not a hundred
percent reliable but it doesn't matter
in that scope but for us it does not
happen so what what what Picabo does it
connects between the mail system and the
behavioral analysis of sandbox we do
queuing we do scheduling we do checks
and then we interpret and we'll make a
decision and that's also something that
Kaku sandbox does not do so in the end
we'll make a decision whether a file is
bad or it's not bad
and whether we pass it on by email or we
do dump something else hmm
so from the from the data flow you can
you can think of an an email that has
one recipient several recipients mail
system takes care of that one email can
have no attachment at all can have as
many as you wish so that's that's why in
every process and I'm going back to that
later we have we have queues we have to
schedule and we have to add information
to what we're getting
cyber is dangerous we have heard that a
lot and you know we're trying to make
world a little bit better and see if we
can we can do that we can achieve that
so this is this is the place for
peekaboo wavy we have the mail system on
the Left we have amethyst which is the
industry standard for dissecting email
messages because the email format is
really ugly if you have ever looked at
it is is really ugly this mime structure
so novice takes care of it it splits up
the the email message and puts it into
in tighten to a directory and hands over
that directory to the antivirus and you
can you can use any antivirus for that
and also it does integrate with piggy
booty which is the the daemon that runs
the peekaboo antivirus and that then
talks to the Kaku system that can be an
EQ system that you're running anyway and
scans the files so I was already saying
a few things about a Mabus and Mabus has
it's very powerful policy banks that you
might know where you can work here you
can also or already exclude files and
say well next suitable is never sent by
email let's just so bitten you can go on
and on and on but then there is files
that trigger vulnerability and you also
want to know about that
but there's no way you can possibly know
that that's why we use behavioural
analysis so I'm always the sex the email
passes it on over the directory into
into the into the peekaboo system and we
had actually to write a patch for a
novice because what amaavas does it
doesn't just put the file into that
directory as with the name of the
attachment because then the attacker
would control the file name within they
within the server that processed that
email so they've named it p 0 0 1 p 0 0
to p 0 to the tree and now and down and
then we we are actually need the
original file name because if we analyze
it in the Windows machine
we need the file extension to be able to
tell which application will open that
that file I will process it so we had we
had to write this patch and I would
really like to see at upstream because I
I believe that other antivirus solutions
might also be able to use it
the best about this project is that it's
license on the DPL the the project is
running since roughly roughly two years
now we have one an open source of world
in Germany for this for this particular
project the set up looks like this we
have a we have a server appliance that's
really good with virtual machines
because that's what we're going to use a
lot we have we've been to running on it
because it's a requirement by
ku-ku-ku-ku say as we run best on on
Ubuntu and we believe them then we have
postfix which is really good with email
but it doesn't it doesn't really matter
what you use then amaavas
we use VirtualBox for virtualization a
lot of python and it's also used in kuku
what we use we use q as well and there
is a nice and shiny installer that
basically sets up everything for you
there is there is more we have a sample
database in the background to know let
me phrase this where we have to two big
tasks within peekaboo that we have to
take care of first one is to not waste
the computing power because there's
there's so many files coming in and
we're delaying that files depending on
the configuration you can have it in
line so the email is only passed on when
it's scanned or you can you can have a
copy sent to the system that's then
analyzed and we don't we don't want to
delay email message as longer than we
have to
so we try to avoid analyzing files which
sounds stupid but it's actually not I
guess and that that way we have this
this database that tells us that we know
this file and I'm coming I'm coming back
to this because we had a very nice issue
a security issue that relates exactly to
this basically if if I send a file and
is recognised by the sha-256 hash which
is pretty good so you you might not find
a second file that is malicious more
malicious than the first one with the
same hash but then the the issue was
that is only saved in the database by
that hash not by the file name so the
first time I sent my malicious file I
put it with a different file extension
and nothing will happen and the second
time I send it with a different file
name it will be recognized that is
already known and and passed along while
it has the actual file extension that
then triggers the exploit within the
application hmm so that was that was a
really nice thing to see
so we cache we cache the results and
then reuse them the the project is is
already in active use so there is quite
a quite a few also companies that use it
it was designed in a way that it can
itself run inside a virtual machine
because we have a server that's really
good with virtual machines so why not
put the entire system into a virtual
machine and we have the benefit that
everything is encapsulated so we can
just reset that will ship machine and
everything is gone so we're looking into
into data editor protection it's all
gone we have an issue we reset the
virtual machine we run the job again and
we have the results that we want without
having to look at anything that's within
an email that we don't want to see also
if something breaks out if something
abuses the vulnerability within a tool
that we use and in fact the virtual
machine is also gone we can we can also
scan files so we don't only support file
input from email but you can also use
them the big setup if you if you've got
one you can you can utilize it at night
time when there's not a lot of emails
coming in you can use it to scan files
from there from the file server or you
can also type in messages and you can
also type in files from from a web proxy
for example or you can extract it from
the network the goal is that the entire
system goes unnoticed until you need it
that's the goal we do have a dashboard
because you have to have a dashboard but
the the goal is that you have the thing
sitting there and you don't notice it
until you need it and then the the virus
admin will receive an email that says
there's a threat that has been detected
and then you can go investigate
I was I was talking about the about one
of the issues the other one was a very
good one as well
and I was I was talking about a file
with different types I mean it has been
demonstrated that a file doesn't
necessarily have to be only one type so
a falcon can just as well be a valid PDF
file and can be a video or can be a zip
file or can be anything else and then we
have we have a whitelist to avoid to
avoid spinning up a virtual machine just
for a text file basically so the issue
was that a sample object within there
within the project has well on an
unlimited basically unlimited number of
my types that it can possibly have and
one of those mime types is the mime type
that is declared with an email message
so it turns out that that well the
attacker does have the ability to set
that mime type within the email message
and it does not affect the the recipient
you can double click it and it will
still open no matter what my type is
specified for it so if you if you put
that mime type as a mime type that
that's on the whitelist that was
sufficient to not check the file because
they the test was the wrong way around
so one of the main types that this
sample has on the white list was enough
rather than all the mime types that it
has have to be on the white list for it
not to be checked for me okay yeah
that's the the final slide because
lightnings are a lot faster in Germany
apparently so if you've got questions
you can you can ask me now or you can
you can catch me anytime and we talked
about this thank you
you