good I am super excited to be here I've
been here like they said to a number of
securities I've had so much fun the
honorary member thing is like holy cow
it's my honorary is my first honorary
anything you know except for some of the
bad words they say down the pub and I
thought yeah say they asked me to to
keynote I mean you got to have balls to
keno to security so I brought balls
little hacky sacks hope you guys are
awake heads up heads up here they come
look up there you go I got a bunch of
these and I want anyway to be awake
because we're gonna do fun stuff and I'm
not gonna throw an entire bag of them
right now you need one hey yeah I got I
got a hands up hands up there you go
alright so we got that out of the way
good morning my name is Paco hope and I
work at AWS right so the cloud so it's
one of the many things Amazon does it's
a lot of fun working at Amazon and I
used to work it digital which then
became synopsis and you'll see a bunch
of the synopsis folks around I'm really
happy to see them continuing to support
I work in a division called professional
services right so it's consultancy like
you might expect and I help customers
who are going to the cloud so they'll
have you know things like we're trying
to move 2,000 servers out of this data
center into the cloud before the lease
ends in October go and you know that I
worry about the security side of that is
the data encrypted at rest is it
encrypted in transit you know what are
the access permissions all that kind of
stuff so I help help customers do that
and I'm going to talk to you about
Incident Response and forensics and your
pyjamas
this is just this is what I wear to work
all right this is this is my work outfit
and I want to show you that even if
you're dressed like this you know you
can still do instant response in
forensics before I get into that though
I think for some people I do need to
define kind of the cloud I was at drinks
last night and I actually had someone
asked me what is AWS and it's one of the
sort of record scratch phones like this
is somebody actually hasn't heard of us
that's okay that was a surprise so cloud
computing you know if you're used to
having like servers in a data center
somewhere right you've got this big
you know room and scott networking power
and cooling and all that good stuff
the cloud is when instead of owning all
that kit and running it yourself you're
renting time from someone else who does
it so AWS runs the physical data centers
with the power of the cooling the
network the people the CCTV you add all
of the physical security and so our
definition for cloud computing then is
when you have on-demand IT resources
right so if you buy that server and you
stick it in your server room you've paid
you're done even if you never turn it on
you pay full price right if you never
use it you've paid for it anyways we're
in the cloud we have this pay-as-you-go
pricing it they're literally like light
bulbs when it's running you're paying
when it's not running you're not paying
which is a totally different model and
it actually shifts us as companies
change how they do technology they
instead of this capital expenditure
that's big massive outlay like every
three years hardware refresh four
million pounds BAM instead it turns into
this like we're renting time on
computers and so we're using X number of
instances per hour and that becomes
hourly a monthly charges and it becomes
operational expenditure I heard from a
big customer in the oil and gas business
and he's like suddenly accounts payable
became part of our critical path because
like if they don't pay the bill each
month bad things are gonna happen so
it's actually a really different outlook
so that's the clout right when you're
renting computers when you're using the
services but you don't have to
physically own the hardware and if I'm
gonna if I'm gonna tell you what is the
cloud wash you probably tell you know
well what are pajamas right you know
we're gonna talk about the cloud we're
gonna talk about pajamas today and
pajamas is loose-fitting comfortable
clothing totally suitable for people who
work from home and I don't know if any
of you have done this yet I have done
the thing where it's like I've got my
pajama bottoms on and have a button-down
shirt because I'm doing a video
conference like I have done that and it
totally works so so yeah you know the
pajamas are fun they're comfortable is
great when you work from home but if you
had to go to a data center we can't go
there like this
yeah I'm lucky the health and safety
didn't stop me you know getting this far
but they sure that got gonna let you in
a data center dressed like this and you
wouldn't want to so I want to tell you
about isn't response in the cloud but I
think we have to cover some ground rules
first just some some basic understanding
I actually had this question asked to me
this morning is like well a few guys own
all the servers and all the physical
stuff who's in charge of security well
that's a great question alright so we
have this whole concept we call the
shared security model another shared
responsibility model rather and
basically on here there are three sets
of responsibilities there's stuff that
is the stuff that we do and you don't
there's stuff that you do and we don't
and then there's a bunch of stuff in the
middle where it's kind of your
responsibility but you're gonna do it
with tools that we made and we make and
tell you how to use so all this bit at
the bottom because this little dotted
line through the middle right all the
stuff at the bottom the compute storage
network all the physicality of things
those data centers that's that's our
responsibility and so the security the
the employment any of the things you
think of traditional security all the
ISO 27001 stuff related to the physical
infrastructure that's our responsibility
that's the the 80s bit at the very very
top you have the kind of customer data
you put some records in the cloud you
know they're in a database theory and s3
objects they're on a server instance
it's your code in a code repository
whatever it is you're responsible for
your stuff and then in the middle you
have all these things like what
operating system is that instance
running is it an up-to-date version of
Linux or is there something vulnerable
is that an up-to-date version of PHP
Python struts Java Oracle whatever or is
it a vulnerable version those are
customer responsibilities that's kind of
your job and then there's like there's
some stuff there the like network
security you know what IP address can
talk to what other IP address so you
know the the routes and the virtual
private cloud
see the subnetting the security groups
which are like instance firewalls and
network ACLs all that is custom
responsibility they do those bids but
they do it using tools that we we made
all right interesting thing because
you're gonna see a bunch of talks today
and they were probably some network
security things I do like to make this
one interesting remark about the network
layer in the cloud there's no layer two
layer two doesn't happen in the cloud so
think of all the things that are layer
two type attacks DNS spoofing ARP
spoofing cache boys and all these kinds
of things that involve somehow like our
ping on the network or confusing a
nearby neighbor doesn't happen doesn't
exist so it's like if you had dot for n
dot five on the same subnet in your data
center
what kind of connectivity do they have
to each other probably a lot right the
probably jacked into the same switch and
in the cloud if you had two instances on
the same subnet dot four and dot five
how much connectivity do they have not a
bit unless you go create a security
group these who are literally have
adjacent IP addresses and can't send a
single packet to one another unless you
go create some connectivity so it's
worth sort of thinking about it's also
worth noting that this is one shared
responsibility model and there are
others not just because there are other
clouds but even within AWS if you use s3
like we're storing stuff for you right
and there's an HTTP interface to that
stuff what servers is it on mmm how many
of them are there mmm well version of
Linux are they running or PHP or
whatever it is but behind it mmm don't
know not your responsibility that's our
responsibility but the data that's in s3
is your responsibility so that just sort
of gives you this idea so this is
important as we start to get into the
security because you have different
responsibilities than we do and I'm
gonna focus on your bits for the most
part now when we think about securing
stuff we think about a couple of
different kinds of security controls we
break it into four and these should look
familiar even if it's not exactly the
same words you use so directive security
controls
are we only use the London region or we
only use Dublin or only these people
have administrative access to this
infrastructure
those are your directive controllers you
guys laying out the the framework and
what's gonna happen preventive controls
are stuff like you know packets from
this IP address dropped them you know
requests that don't look this way
decline them they're the things that
stop bad things from happening and a lot
of your on-premises security will lean
really heavy on the preventive control
give me lots of firewalls give me
ids/ips give me lots of things to block
the bad stuff
stop adds stuff from happening now in
the cloud you really have to actively
manage it you have to be participating
in you don't just kind of set the thing
up and leave it running and and trust
that it's gonna be all right you
actively monitor and manage it which is
why Detective and responsive things are
so important so Detective controls all
the logging all that nonsense about you
who did what and when and all the
responsive controls are like whoa we
detected a bad thing happening let's go
do something about it
and if we're talking about Incident
Response then we're really gonna be down
here right we're gonna be down in this
sort of Detective responsive world today
we're gonna really be focused on these
guys and we're not gonna say a whole lot
about the directive and preventative
bits so if you're in the cloud what
kinds of stuff might you have to run
into and this is a really interesting
incident conversation because there are
some incidents that are common to just
the same kinds of things you're gonna
run into in any other situation and some
of these will be uniquely cloud and I'm
gonna do them from kind of least big
deal to biggest deal right compliance
variance is is a pretty basic like we've
decided all our instances will have
encrypted hard drives somebody has
started up an instance this hard drive
is not encrypted we may not have
actually done anything bad yet right
it's just we intend to have everything
encrypted maybe they've just brought it
off but they haven't even loaded data on
it yet
so we're not actually any real huge risk
but it's compliance variance we should
fix that those are you taking pictures
this thing's gonna build I got eight of
these so you know I wouldn't waste don't
waste the film yet service disruption is
you know we intended a server to be up
we intended this data to be accessible
we intended this database to answer
queries it's not you know these are
incidents that we might have to detect
and and service disruption can be often
it's a performance thing and the
operations team is looking at gosh the
performance is not so good over there
and that might actually be an indicator
of compromise like sometimes the
performance alert is the thing that
tells you a hacker is doing something
I'm part of a team called a zip line
which is kind of a actually had to
change the name but it we're still call
ourselves if line and and what that is
professional services consultants who
can kind of go in and rescue customers
when they they have a really really bad
day and you know you can put me under
contract and and then I'm allowed to do
whatever any contractor working for you
is allowed to do whatever you authorize
me to do we have legal right to do go do
that and so it is kind of like we're
here to help and one of our zip line
cases we have a customer who had
database and really high load on their
database instance and it's RDS
relational database service so it's one
of our somewhat managed services and so
they they they call up our support
they're asking questions why is the
database load so high and will resolve
okay look at them well what about this
auditing plug-in do you need that
auditing plug-in turned on have you
looked at your query performance maybe
there's something you know somebody
pushed a new update to your app and it's
inefficient and I'm like the fourth day
they get a ransom note like we have all
your data and we're going to release it
publicly unless you give some money
right and and so that high CPU load on
the database server that was all their
data going out you know that was that
was you know a bad guy had gotten the
the username and password for the
database that had sucked a whole lot of
data out so sometimes you know it's an
incident because it's a service
disruption for formance issue but
sometimes that's an intake indicator
compromise yeah there we go gotta flick
it a little bit so unauthorized
resources this is a thing doesn't
typically happen in your data center I
don't know how many of you guys have
come into the data center and like
that's for new servers in there where
they come from
most big enterprises who run data
centers run them with a little better
security than that so you don't
generally have stuff just spring up in
your data center but in the cloud this
can really happen right in the cloud you
generally let people spin up servers and
let them spin up buckets and instances
of things so they can learn and develop
and do whatever but sometimes they can
do it wrong or someone gets a hold of
credentials and they spin up things that
they shouldn't
so unauthorized resources is something
that happens in the cloud fairly often
they need to respond to it unauthorized
access and this can happen in a couple
of flavors right unauthorized access is
somebody's got access to my to my
environment maybe they've got my laptop
or they figured out how to do AWS
commands and they're actually looking
around or making changes to things or
maybe it's like SSH login access to one
of our servers one of our instances in
the cloud and maybe they're actually
inside it messing around so now we start
to get into some things that are fairly
serious but also things that you're
familiar with things that you've dealt
with before
certainly inside your instance inside of
Linux inside of Windows privilege
escalation or unauthorized access you're
used to dealing with that privilege
escalation again takes two flavors as a
privilege escalation inside of Linux on
some server some instance somewhere or
is it privilege escalation within the
cloud itself granting someone ability to
create new cloud resources or change the
ones that are out there so two flavors
of privilege escalation or excessive
permissions I call this the steve
problem because i was doing a talk like
this at a customer and they had already
been moaning a whole lot about steve who
apparently had lots of privileges in
their you know cloud environment and
when i put up the thing about you
excessive fruition so everyone just got
looked over at Steve okay so this is the
steve problem right when Steve's that
guy has got all the privileges get all
the passwords got all the access that's
okay that can be an instant that we have
to deal with
information exposure you see on the
front page right this is the s3 bucket
that's open to the world this is the you
know functions that allow you to get
location data out of cell phones without
any authentication authorization this
kind of information exposure is a high
priority incident and then the
granddaddy of all of them you know
credential exposure when you commit
credentials to github you know your 80s
access key and stuff it's a race between
three parties to see who gets at first
you know is it the developer who did it
into and like has to go try and you
know delete it is it
AWS because we actively patrol looking
for stuff like that or is it the hacker
who flies our access keys is ooh let's
see what these can do so these are the
kinds of incidents in the cloud that we
might have to respond to and they
largely fall into a couple of domains if
we had to group them all up
we would say you've got your
infrastructure domain which is stuff
that feels familiar right these this is
the kind of like servers your ec2
instances are are these kind of virtual
servers in the sky and you know
connectivity your networking your VPN
your networking within the cloud or
between the cloud and your data centers
and anything inside the instance itself
somebody has gotten into a Linux box and
they're messing around and we want to
know what happened these are your
infrastructure events and there's a few
others but this should sound familiar
but there's this whole second class of
things which I call the service domain
where everything you're dealing with is
an AWS service natively so AWS identity
and access management you have an AWS
account it has roles and privileges and
rights and and capabilities and if
there's a problem there's no server to
go yank there's no box to go image it
sits up in the service layer and you
have to use AWS api's and AWS logs to
figure out what happened and what's
going on s3 buckets you know they're
very common people store a lot of stuff
in there I was talking over dinner with
somebody who had moved what 670 pad up
yeah was the signal 70 terabytes I think
at any rate a bunch bunch of data and
you know so ask three buckets if that
data gets exposed you know it's gonna be
highly available it's gonna be highly
downloadable and there again no server
to yank the question is do you have s3
access logs turned on
do you have cloud trail which figures
out who was messing with stuff and who
was calling api's do you have that
turned on billing yeah it's it's
surprising how much billing turns into
an indicator of compromise
you know remember how I explained you
pay by the hour or you pay by the
gigabyte for data over the network or
you pay by the gigabyte for storage so
spikes and billing either mean a project
has just kicked off in high gear or
somebody's doing something really weird
and you should go investigate and we had
a customer who you know that was how
they discovered that they had 20
instances Bitcoin mining in Singapore
and 20 Bitcoin mining in Tokyo and 20
Bitcoin mining in Brazil and 20 in
Canada and and it was if someone had
gotten a hold of some credentials and it
spun up a bunch of Bitcoin mining
instances and yeah they found it by
getting a building alert like wow you
don't usually spend this much money and
so yeah building is a really interesting
indicator of compromise and then the
other one that the reverse of that was
that the team that called us up one time
he's like oh my god we're attacking
about support help help and we started
looking and we're like all this all this
traffic looks completely legit we're not
seeing DNS backscatter attacks we're not
seeing any of these sort of things
usually associated with a DDoS attack
and it turns out they've done a Super
Bowl ad and nobody had told the tech
team at all right so they had just never
seen this level of legitimate traffic
and then of course we have lots and lots
of other services and so each of those
will be an important thing that you
might have an incident in and then
there's a couple of things that are
really important like where do you get
the information to respond to incidents
in your cloud and there's a bunch of
really important places you can get
information and the obvious want to be
sort of logging and monitoring there's a
zillion ways to log and monitor day
having said that with gdpr coming into
effect quite soon companies are now
starting to question well what the hell
is in those logs anyways and do we need
to be deleting some of these logs and
you know what what should we be doing
about them so logging and monitoring is
simultaneously an asset it's gonna help
you figure out what happened and it's a
liability you need to only keep the
stuff you really need to keep and you
know I just worked with a government
agency last week who you know had done
this amazing serverless app in AWS
totally native services and everything
and they had turned on full
request/response auditing and logging
mainly for like debugging and
troubleshooting and they had just no
data retention policy or deletion of
anything at two years or like every
requests those things ever done and do
like 14 million a day and so like a
you're wasting money man you're storing
stuff you have zero interest in storing
and be from a liability perspective you
shouldn't keep it let's go figure out
what the data retention policy is and
let's go set up a regular thing that
just delete stuff you might have billing
so billing activity can also tell you
what's normal and you can actually get
super deep because everything in AWS is
an API even the billing is an API you
can go hey give me the all the breakdown
of cost from last month last week
whatever threat intelligence so you know
there's a bunch of companies out there
that sell threat intelligence like they
will give you threat Intel feeds like
here's a botnet these IPS are suspicious
this you know domain is phishing and
that kind of thing
you should have that in any sort of
organization that you run in any kind of
enterprise and you can actually feed
that into some of the tools that we have
in the cloud which I'll talk about in a
second AWS outreach is a super important
source of information meaning that we
can sometimes see things you can't see
and so we might actually pick up the
phone to call and so super important if
you're a cloud company cloud
organization or just an individual
playing around who might make a mistake
sure the records that AWS has on file
are accurate that they that the phone
number that's on file actually rings a
person who would know what to do if we
call that the email address goes to
someone who actually understands how to
deal with it we had the the remember the
github example I talked about you know
where you commit some credentials to
github we had that happen a customer
committed some github credentials and
like I don't know five or six minutes
after the guy did it he's like oh crap
and he deleted them from github but
before that we had detected it and we
were on the phone and we're sending
email and the phone number didn't work
didn't go to anybody that just just rang
and the email went to accounts payable
because most of the kind of interesting
things generally just goes off to
accounts payable because it's probably
billing related and they kind of took a
look at this like you know credential
compromised Bitcoin mining uh-huh
and they they eventually kicked it over
to the tech team so 27 hours after it
was detected then the tech teams kind of
made aware of it they can go clean
things up so make sure that if AWS has
to reach in and say hey there's a bad
thing happening that like it points to
somebody useful I actually found a
customer who they told me that their sis
Amin had left like two months three
months before still had his credit card
down and like his email address like
discussing work for you what do you call
hey Joe do you mind just paying the bill
this month I'm you I swear but we'll get
it changed over soon and finally a super
important thing that I've learned since
I've been at AWS but I always believed
in being friendly as a as a security
person a friendly security front door is
super super important if you're the
security team and you want to know about
incidents you have to accept information
from people that you don't know from
people who may not know exactly what
they're talking about because they've
just seen something funny you have to
accept you have to have a friendly
security front door and I'll tell you
about the security front door within AWS
or we run the cloud so we have
massive security operations and they
literally go around to all the staff
everywhere and they say we have
ticketing right so we have tickets for
incidents you have severity one two
three four five whatever sarah deewan
CEO gets a phone call yes parity two
vice-presidents are like what the hell
is that and who's fixing it when's it
gonna be done and so on and severity
five is like hey gee whiz guys should be
nice if you do this so our security
folks go around telling everyone look if
you're not sure if this is a cell to
security incident it's a safe to file it
file the stuff to ticket if it's not
severity two we're gonna look at and say
oh yeah step four we know what's going
on here we just will downgrade it that's
fine
we want to know we want to get that
ticket we want to get that alert we will
never tell you oh you idiot you wasted
my tiles know where that was no way of
self - they're never gonna say you know
you were dumb you shouldn't have done
that at all you say hey thanks for that
looks like the team is on it we know
what's going on we're tracking it thank
you very much you know so friendly front
door take things from employees take
things from you know security
researchers and external people you
don't know take things from the
development team themselves always have
a friendly security front door so given
all of that we might actually whoops
sorry we'll also have cloud native
sources there's a bunch of stuff that in
the cloud you have these things and
on-premises you don't cloud watch events
for instance can actually respond to a
thing has happened I've noticed this
instance is not responding to HTTP
requests you know what kill it get
another one in there like that's a that
can you can make your infrastructure run
itself by automating through things like
cloud watch events you can have things
like guard duty which will detect really
interesting things happening inside your
cloud and let you know about them if
somebody spins up an instance and starts
port scanning you know guard duty can
tell you hey by the way that instance
over there's port scanning and if you
want to get really drew Kony and you
could say great terminate kill it that
is not a legitimate business use case
here or another fun one that I like if
someone's accessing your infrastructure
they're coming to AWS
coming to you they're not SSH into your
instance they're talking to an AWS end
point something we run maybe something
we run in Tokyo but they're coming
they've got credentials for you for your
account and they're coming from a tour
exit node right this is someone who has
legitimate access but is hiding their
origin they're trying to hide where
they're coming from on the net there is
no legitimate business use case for this
right there there's no business that
does anything with me has a reason for
its administrators to do legitimate
activity hiding where they come from so
for most people that were that results
in an alert and we put it on their
dashboard of like people are using your
account over tor that sounds weird or
again Bitcoin mining if your VPC starts
talking outbound or some Bitcoin mining
sites again not a lot of legitimate
business use cases for that so we'll
flag it up as an alert and guard duty
lots of fun stuff like that so let's do
some fun things let's actually think
about how we respond to an incident so
let's imagine we've got and I'm gonna
start with the infrastructure domain
let's imagine we've got this is a
classic architecture diagram of your
really basic web app right and there's a
few bits that are missing but you've got
your internet you've got this load
balancer load balancers or like
appliances it's just a thing that exists
it's not like a server you can SSH into
it it's just an appliance and it's got
three web servers behind it in a you
know web security group security group
meaning a network firewall rule that
lets web traffic come in and
one of these guys goes bad now many of
you to talk about like what is it I mean
maybe somebody's SSH din maybe somebody
something's going wrong it's issuing bad
outbound requests so we think it's
probably an compromised I don't know
what it is but we don't like it we don't
trust it anymore
we want to isolate this and let's do
some forensics on this guy so first
thing we can do is figure out who he is
and using command lines I'm gonna put a
whole bunch of command lines down here
right AWS ec2 described instance the guy
that's got this IP address who is that
and you know you end up with some
instance ID you know I blah blah blah
blah blah and so then we say you know
what let's put a tag on that guy
environment value quarantine reference
ID we're basically saying we're starting
an incident now we're in a quarantine
this guy and so first starters we just
put a little symbolic tag which so
tagging things related to this incident
now that now we know he's bad he's still
out there he's still serving web traffic
we don't want him to talk to customers
anymore because we've decided he's bad
so we take him out of the auto scaling
group so he's not part the auto scaling
group knows this guy's not part of the
team anymore and again just a couple of
commands you know detach it D register
it we don't want him in the auto scaling
group and we don't want him to part of
that load balancer anymore because we
don't want him dealing with customer
traffic now the beauty of auto scaling
groups of course what does an auto
scaling group say hey I'm supposed to
have three and I don't have three
anymore let me launch a clean instance
so I get back up to three so so implicit
to this I'm not even drawing it on the
screen implicit to this you wanted to
have three and you took one out because
you didn't trust it a third one is gonna
come up in the background you deployed
through whatever mechanism it is that
you deploy these things so and then
we've deregistered him from the load
balancer so he won't get any more
traffic and you can do that one of two
ways you can do that like flip of a
switch he gets no more traffic or you
can say you know what drain the queue
let him finish whoever he's talking to
but no new
connections so you can do it a couple
different ways now not only do we not
want him you know serving customer
traffic we don't want anybody talking to
this thing we don't know what's up with
it yet we haven't done our investigation
so we'll slap down a security group that
says you know what no traffic in or out
zero packets in zero packets out and
again you know it's a couple of ec2
commands modify instance attribute blah
blah blah blah blah and you know put the
security group on it
don't let it terminate we don't want
this thing to die we don't want it to go
away it might have running programs in
memory that we're interested in getting
it might have log files and tools on it
that we are interested in getting so we
need to get the resources off of this
guy so we try to stop it from killing
itself and we try to stop anybody who
comes along and says who that guy's in
trouble I'll terminate it this will
actually make administrators unable to
terminate it without going through some
extra steps cool so we've isolated him
he's not talking to anybody and he can't
talk to anybody and he's been tagged and
so now I want a copy of the hard drive I
want to know what was on that hard disk
and so we have this thing called EBS
elastic block store this is the hard
drive of that instance right it's a it's
a sand that we provide and you can have
virtual hard drives you take snapshots
of them alright so we're going to take a
snapshot of that volume and that
snapshot is blocked for block byte for
byte whatever that thing thinks is on
its hard drive
you got something clever that was
writing in slack space outside the file
system we've got those blocks if you
wrote to that block we have that block
so we're gonna get a complete snapshot
we're gonna roll it off to Amazon s3
which is our you know robust region wide
storage
funny thing about s3 we say it has 11
nines of durability right so you have
99.999 11 nines of durability is
probability that we're going to lose a
byte that you put there
and when I was doing my AWS training
they have you know they put you through
the standard training about all the
services and what they do and they put
up a little slide that says s3 has 11
nines of durability but the voice
actress says Amazon s3 has 99.99999 like
actually read all eleven nine so I was
like no no that's not have we say that
but the point is that you now have a
snapshot in s3 and that snapshot can't
be modified and if you go lock it down
it can't be deleted it can't be changed
it is going to be just what it is and
again it's just a command line create
snapshot on that volume and by the way
let's put that tag on there that
reference ID remember we're tagging all
the assets related to this incident we
all to go get them later cool so we got
this hard drive snapshot now chances are
you want to do some forensics on this
thing right you don't want to you don't
want to log into that instance you don't
pollute the net the the instance you
want it but you need to get some you
find out what's going on right so we're
gonna launch easy to run instance some
forensics instance that we already set
up I don't know this is like Kali Linux
with a bunch of tools on it some windows
box with some windows tools whatever it
is we're gonna launch one we weren't
running it before why would you run one
you don't want to pay for things to run
when you're not using them but it's at
their ready so spin up a copy and again
the great thing about this is that
instance will never work on any other
case there's no danger of polluting
evidence from one case into another case
you're never gonna have this instance
talk to anything except for the instance
the hard drive and the data and stuff
related to the thing it's investigating
right now she gives you some nice sort
of like there's there's no danger of you
accidentally getting data from one case
showing up in the investigation of
another and then we can grant you
basically connect that copy run that
copy that we did at the EBS volume we'll
make a new copy and we'll attach it as
like a second hard disk on the forensics
tools instance so basically you know
your Sidra
your dev SDA whatever that is the
forensics tools that you've installed
that you run and whatever it is and then
dev SDF or the D drive or whatever
that's this copy of the instance that
we're investigating I got a copy you
know what if you trash it if you screw
something up you mount it read write and
you change the data you think oh crap
that messes up our evidentiary you know
integrity here that's all right go get a
fresh copy you don't you just make as
many copies as you like and then we may
want to see the processes they're
running what's in RAM yeah what is going
along this thing I might want to log
into it or I might want to do something
that connects to the live instance
remember I didn't kill it I didn't
terminate it I just walled it off so
it's not going to talk to any any people
I care about and so now I could create a
security group that says you know what
authorized security group ingress let
the forensics tool instance talk to this
thing but nobody else so now I've
actually allowed some ingress and I've
allowed it on every port because we're
trying to figure out what's it listening
on what's it trying to do and I can
actually go now logged into my forensics
instance I can go talk to this guy
running I could install lime for
instance lime as a Linux memory
extractor right give you a dram dump of
everything in the in the instance I
could do that over this this connection
if I want so that's pretty cool
but it sounds like work that's all those
all those commands
that's like typing in the stuff come on
so anything I don't want to do work
right I'm in my slippers or our pajamas
here you haven't seen the pajama party
yeah we've done all this talking about
instant response and I might have been
with a shirt and tie Saturday a computer
anything that I can write is a series of
commands like that well obvious I could
bang that out in a bash script or
something right I don't have to type
those but if I get banging out in a bash
script I could write that as a Python
program that's you know Bato 3 the AWS
api library
so I can write a little Python program
that does this stuff and if I can make
it a Python program I can turn that into
a lambda function and you may not know
what lambda is lambda is one of our
services that's kind of like code as a
service you copy/paste some Python into
a web browser input field and we run it
if you use Heroku some what kind of
thing right we just run the code that
you give us we spin up whatever however
many Linux instances you need to for
whatever traffic you're getting we tell
you what environment that's going to run
which Python runtime which Linux runtime
and so on there's no persistent storage
there's no like if it wants to persist
some data it better write that make a
database connection or put it as three
objects somewhere because it as a
function doesn't get anything and then
we charge you per hundred milliseconds
for 100 milliseconds of execution time
nobody calling it nobody paying nothing
right but if you if you call it you pay
by the hundreds of milliseconds so
that's a great thing so now I'm going to
make that Python program into a lambda
function but if I can make it a lambda
function then I can trigger it and it
automatically in response to like your
Cloud watch events right so I've got my
incident response I'm in my pajamas and
I'm fast asleep so this is what Incident
Response in the cloud looks like
incident response in the cloud is when
you come into work and like oh by the
way there was a thing last night we
tagged it we've put all the stuff away
we spun off your forensics tool instance
here's the IP much log in and have a
look that's you know that's the kind of
thing that you can do when your
environment participates in its own
management when your environment
actually collaborates with you to
automate security now again this still
sounds like work right I would have to
go write that I will write that so I
didn't I don't have to there's in fact
where is my Firefox
so there is in fact this threat response
about cloud if you don't know these guys
this is definitely somebody to go take a
look at threat response cloud sponsored
by the way yeah not just us some Mozilla
and so Microsoft people are
participating as well and you know they
must do DevOps because look at that
beard they have a three really cool
tools they've got a two si R which I'll
show you in a second it was an incident
response thing so all that stuff I said
you could write you don't even have to
write they already wrote it it's on
github
instead of Pony which is trying to do
sort of orchestration right because once
you've got incidents well now you gotta
go orchestrate the incident where's the
s3 bucket the ec2 instance the network
logs that you need to gather all those
things together and margarita shotgun I
love when tools have a really good story
for why they're called what they're
called
remember lime the Linux memory extractor
right lime is this kernel module that
lets you pull the the RAM out of a Linux
instance so you get this nice Ram dumb
if you go see what was running well if
you had to like blast the lime kernel
module into thousands of instances
across your ec2 estate it's kind of a
margarita shotgun there we've got all
these instances full of the kernel
module now so this is really cool and
and in fact we can even look at the what
does it look like when you when you
isolate an instance right so here's a
this is just the output of this is right
off the eight of Si our github oh we got
old men in the room like me
hey let's big mode yes so if you
actually wanted to do incident response
using a to a si are right you have eight
of Si are by the way my forensics
instance is gonna come from this side
arranged so go ahead and allow that and
here's my target here's the IP address
go right well the first thing like where
might that be running there's sixteen
regions in the world
in Korea is it in Australia is it in
Canada where is this thing
and so it searches it finds it and then
you can see down here at the bottom now
let's go do something about it so now we
so okay we found it let's isolate the
host that's that whole security group
thing not talking anybody anymore
tag it snapshot it figure out where the
examiner so the forensics instance
where's that guy gonna be and now let's
start getting round and you can get this
sense of what happens so here's the you
know at 2111 we start marguerite a
shotgun and at 2141 we're done so taking
about 20 minutes to don't ram on that
particular instance and so now you know
process complete it's over here in this
s3 bucket there's all your assets you
know so when you come in you get your
cup of coffee you're like oh there was
an incident overnight let's go let's go
look in this bucket and see we captured
anybody want to do something really
clever you know a lot of times I've seen
people here work with honey pots like
you did you just nail these two things
together right honey pot that just has
this so it's just like automatically you
know trap and keep and and you know deal
with it later
so that's incident response in the in
the infrastructure domain right it's
robots do the work for us we don't do it
ourselves and and that is the key to
cloud scale security you can't scale to
cloud level planetary level if you have
humans do all the work the humans keep
moving up the value chain I had a chance
to talk to our CIS Oh Steve Schmidt
brilliant guy runs security for the
cloud and and I said look Steve we we
must have so many incidents so many
alerts remember heck we also have this
friendly policy of go ahead file this f2
ticket we'll sort it out like this must
be a real problem with alert fatigue
right alert fatigue is a real thing
where people you keep seeing that dialog
box that says you know
was about to lead all your files is that
okay yes oh crap
you know it's uh you know alert fatigue
is a real thing I said Steve we must
have a real issue with alert fatigue
like what do we do to defend against
that and his answer was automation
anything that we see a lot of we write a
function to deal with it like if I'm
seeing the same stupid alert every
morning at 9:00 a.m. because some stupid
job does this one stupid thing I say
let's make sure that we're recognizing
just the one stupid thing and we're
resolving it so if there is an unusual
thing that's not just the usual stupid
nine I am alert I'm still gonna see that
and the whole purpose is anything that's
happening a lot you either you make it
stop happening or you automate the
alerting so the only things that bubble
up to humans are unique they're new
they're the kind of thing only a human
can really decide and and that's how we
avoid alert fatigue if you've got some
Incident Response thing that's just just
filling you full of stuff you're gonna
have alert fatigue and people are gonna
miss important issues because they don't
you know they're just used to clicking
okay a lot so the service domain things
actually a lot shorter it's a lot
smaller they're a handful of things are
really important that you have to deal
with and your s3 bucket policies changes
in i.m permissions credential exposure
these are the usual biggies and and the
answer on that one is again a two F's IR
they do a really great job on this whole
key compromise piece you say here's our
key that got compromised go get it and
so all right we know what we're doing
we'll disable the key we're gonna revoke
any tokens that were issued to that key
and we're gonna gather some logs I'm
gonna dump it all in you know our cloud
response bucket so that's also really
cool there are some other incidents that
you might have to deal with but a lot of
that's just automated for you and so the
last couple things I do want to talk
about quickly is you know how some
customers do it obviously you know you
guys are familiar with the usual
customers like Netflix we've got others
right and so like alfresco these guys
created a thing called Prowler which is
also worth knowing about
Prowler will rip through your AWS
account looking for violations of the
CIS cloud infrastructure security
benchmarks for AWS and so to look for
security violations it'll go all across
your account and look for interesting
things this is really kind of basics
this is kind of 101 like eventually this
thing should start to report nothing and
you still have work to do but like if
this thing turns up anything well you've
got work to do
and then Mozilla obviously they created
the threat response thing and they
contribute to a lot of a lot of this
stuff really important to realize as a
whole ecosystem of people who contribute
so there you go I mean the bottom line
is you can respond to incidents you can
do it automatically using software you
can sit in your pajamas and have coffee
and let the robots do the hard work
right awesome thank you very much I'm
happy to take questions by email or you
have hit me up at the pub tonight or
whatever thank you