hi everyone and welcome to security 2018
take two it's not yeah so quick health
and safety announcement there are no
planned fire drills today however the
unis are doing work in the old college
building so there might be a fire drill
we don't know so if you hear a fire
follow the crew and follow the fire
exits that's it from me
stampede in one direction only right so
I got background for security for those
suits the first time so who's been here
before
the security so like 70% some quick
master and so excuse is organized by the
8th clock in society so we're the
committee a mess on the president Kyle
Declan I treasure our there's not as
hand up declan's the treasure I make
he's a vice president and Holly's Mr
treasurer secretary I'm so a bunch
students who are supported by the a/c
click so up TAC is a Student Association
and who don't get any credit any other
year and they basically support us
massively so they help us a lot of money
booking events between the cater and all
that stuff so without em security it
this will the SA security will be
possible so the other back so give us a
wave AC so thank you to you for helping
us
[Applause]
I know a quick em point of order I would
see so this year we introduced to Kenny
of the hacks Hall of Fame which were
calling honorary members so from now on
every year up to five people will be
elected into our Hall of Fame trainer
who can count this is more than five and
the first year had a lot of catching up
to do right
I've got like seven years of security
and so these are our new honorary
members so we're gonna say a piece about
each one so like make ease up first to
talk about some of the nominated
honorary members so Gavin Hall and was
had some position on the committee for a
couple of years I think and he did a
walk for the society in terms of just
setting up as a serious outfit and and
he's done a walk for probably most of
the students in the room as well and I
certainly wouldn't be where I am today
without him and Graham Sutherland as
well who I believe is with us today
somewhere and he has how the talk
accepted that every security since it
was open to the public which i think is
quite an outstanding achievement
um and the talks are always hilarious
very well attended and and I know
certainly when we go to other
conferences he's always there looking
out for us and getting us unbelievably
drunk um and we love Graham and so yeah
so Cooper has been our videographer for
the past two years and has been an
unbelievable help to us as some people
who have been to secure today before you
might remember that it took I think two
or three years to get the videos for
security 2014 up and last year at Cooper
managed to have the videos up and most
cases before the end of the day so he's
through in the other room but hopefully
you'll get a chance to meet him before
the end of the day additionally Gordon
gray who I think is also here yeah he's
in the back is a
recent alum of Alberta and has always
been encouraging us to sort of go out
with the University and try to get more
involved in external events Haley she's
another one and she is the CEO of the SA
she goes way above and beyond her job
and we love her so much and if it wasn't
for her this wouldn't happen she was a
person that comforted us all when we had
to make the unfortunate decision to
postpone they take one don't mention
that yep that never happened hey and
Kath is the owner of our local the lady
well and I'm sure a lot you know who she
is she's absolutely fantastic she looks
after us all and she makes sure we don't
get too drunk and lastly our our keynote
speaker for this morning
Paco who has been here for many many
years probably before me and it's always
the connect for us for everyone to get
jobs and internships and to support in
society I'm as kind of like a non-member
so we thought it'd only be good to have
him as an on-air member to represent us
across the world in a city which it does
so next sponsors next bags and lanyard
sponsors next so thanks to ICS squared
and couldn't make it today but they
sponsored all of our bags and so your
cool swag bags which is what we'll do
in them and they sponsored those
and redacted firm so freaky clown and
Jessica Baca
most of you will know either in person
or from 12 and they sponsored our line
yards so get those photos in those and
tweet them out I'm sure that'll cheer
them up because it couldn't be here
today so thanks to those guys next
bronze sponsors make it so semantic and
thank you for them and we went out to
Symantec recently as well about six or
seven guys and they were kind enough off
the back of that to give us some money
so that's nice and SPRC as well and
Jerry grant is kicking about somewhere
there is he is the he is the almost the
main man and if you know who man the he
burners you probably all know her and
thanks to them as well yep so we do have
some prizes to get out to the courtesy
of like five so we've got some really
cool swag to give out and more on that
later on
I think yep
so silver sponsors we have a lot of
these we'd like to thank loads MWR
synopsis cybersecurity challenge UK BSI
and ECS for sponsoring us this year and
definitely although it's a lot of sort
of smaller sponsorships we definitely
can make it happen without you guys so
thank you yeah and you can find those
sponsors upstairs in the Center for
Excellence which will probably walked by
on the way into this lecture hall so
additionally we have lizard HQ
sponsoring our bar and there will be
more details on how to access that bar
sponsorship later this afternoon
thank you so we're in the Student Union
in the morning I wrote a wave and I
think for breakfast and then we've got
waiting and talks kicking off about
quarter past 12:00
we've got waiting and talk scheduled
till about half - I want to see so we'll
probably get kicked out of there at 5:00
so we've got a couple of hours free if
anyone wants to spontaneously summer
lightning talk and there's an air table
form for you to fill out just name title
abstract and and that was tweeted out
earlier so if you go to our Bertie
hackers you'll be able to find that link
and please sign up if you have any
problems today yeah there's a bunch of
helpful people and we're in purple guys
goes a wave there we go some of us still
asleep if you have any issues just find
one of them they'll make sure that
nobody's dying additionally for the
first time this year we've introduced a
security helpline so if you phone that
number you will be connected
all four of us simultaneously through
the magic of technology so please only
use it for emergencies but if something
is seriously wrong or if you feel like
you need to raise something in
confidence you can phone that number you
can SMS that number and one of us will
reach out to help you so this year we
don't have a physical program however
postponed so we've recycled the original
programs but instead we have a digital
program available on our website so you
can view that online designed by our
wonderful designer Kari and and you can
also see the schedule online and all of
the talks that we'll be having today in
tomorrow as well so that's it from us
and we're gonna pass you over to Paco
for the opening keynote we hope you have
a brilliant day and you'll hear more
from us later thanks guys
[Applause]