[Music]
thank you
hello everyone Welcome to our session
welcome malware my name is Shulman and
I'm honored to share the stage with
staff Schulman
we will be telling you today about very
resilient botnets that never die
we'll start our session with a little
bit of motivation for our research and
then we'll dive into a short
introduction to botnet and how we are
fighting them today
then we will show you the botnets that
never die and we'll talk a little bit
about further research and some
conclusions
so without further Ado why did we go
after botnets and the reason is that
modern cyber crime at scale requires
botnet whether you want to just ditto
someone or launch a carding attack or a
credential stuffing attack or or even
play an SQL injection and you want to do
it at scale you need a functioning
botnet
so there are organizations and
individuals out there that make a living
out of creating those botnets
maintaining them and either using them
for their own operations or renting
pieces of them for other people other
organizations for their operations
and it seems that these robust botnets
are the key to the success or failure of
cyber crime operations
so
researchers figured out that
neutralizing a botnet is practically
destroying the operations so the
question we came up with is can we build
a botnet that survives neutralizing
and can this resilient botnet be cost
effective
and of course the biggest question of
all can the father and daughter
relationship survive this joint research
okay
[Applause]
to begin our journey I would like to
start with giving a bit of background on
something that is very near and dear to
my heart malware infrastructures
during my day today as a researcher I
happened to stumble upon a very broad
range of different thread actors
utilizing different malwares and
implementing different approaches for
cncs generally speaking I think we can
take all of them and divide into three
main difficulty level of infrastructure
implementations
the very first one is obviously the one
that's most basic and thread actor is
using this level would rely on domain
names they will have to acquire
dedicated domain names or that they can
abuse some compromised infrastructure
they got access to in order to manually
maintain a pool of servers they will
initially deliver these servers inside
victims environment by literally
embedding them inside mild or binary
samples or inside dedicated config files
that will come with these malwares
now for threat actors to choose this
approach even though it's basic they
still have a little bit of range of
motion because they can do things like
update their pull of domains from time
to time but they will have to do so by
relying on an already known and
functioning domain
now the second level of difficulty is
for threat actors still relying on
domain names but kind of wake up in the
morning feeling a tad more creative and
they will usually use dgas now a domain
generation algorithm means that inside
the malware instead of finding a pool of
servers will encounter just one function
and this function will contain a pattern
then a set of prefixes symbols and
characters that will be used to Generate
random domain names during the malware's
execution meaning that we can't actually
predict which domain is going to be used
next
now I believe that the most advanced
practice that we currently experience in
the wild is thread groups that
completely ditch the use of these domain
names and move forward for utilizing
completely publicly available legitimate
services and utilities for their
malicious infrastructures
so we see actors that rely on social
media platforms for creating malicious
profiles in places like Facebook Twitter
or Instagram to deliver their malicious
content using that we see attackers
abuse cloud-based file share services so
things like Google Drive and Dropbox
and we even see a rise of threat groups
that take completely legitimate
utilities so things like Remote Control
software that was originally intended
for I.T Personnel for instance to tackle
thoughts and incidents and abuse its
capabilities for full-blown malowers
so we can really see that this usage of
the publicly available utilities is on
the rise and it's an ongoing Trend
because we see some of the trendiest
stuff like AI powered malwares that rely
on the Microsoft teams platform for
channeling their C2 communication
we even see huge malware Distributors
such as agent Tesla and raccoon stealer
that rely on the Discord CDN to deliver
malicious payloads
now that we've covered the means
available for threat actors today
against us let's see what we actually as
Defenders can do against them
so obviously we can and we should
identify those resources used by the
threat groups we can analyze any
malowers that we get we can enrich data
we've collected and lastly we should
respond and act
how do we even identify those malicious
network resources used by thread groups
well there are the good old traditional
ways so Network anomalies non-standard
ports large packets high volume of
traffic and even registration of strange
domain names like the greatest Google
with a zero
today we even have some more advanced
practices to do that so things like EDR
alerts which allows us to see
communication inside the context of
process execution which helps us gain
some more clever conclusions on what we
see
now if we're lucky enough we could have
captured the actual malware samples that
are associated with this infrastructure
we just tracked the malwares that should
connect to it so when we have a malware
sample we obviously want to analyze it
so we can do anything from the great
basic static analysis onto full very
complex reverse engineering anything
that we can do just to see what's inside
and inside of it we can find additional
domains naming conventions for a CNC
commands supported by this
infrastructure and in case for dgas we
can actually extract the algorithm and
attempt to predict additional servers in
the wild that can match it
now naturally because we are very
curious beings we are researchers after
all we would like to go ahead and enrich
on all the data we've just collected so
we can identify domain registration
patterns and attempt to find more
servers if we see the use of strange
certificates we can go ahead and search
for additional infrastructures that use
them and we can attempt to detect
additional servers that can support some
of the naming conventions for the
commands that we've seen or some unique
and distinct URI past or parameter that
we've seen on the infrastructure we've
just researched
after doing all of these things we now
just have to act
now these days most of our actions most
of our responses to cyber security
incidents involving infrastructure which
consists mainly of iocs now in ioc for
her case can be anything from a file
hash domain name my IP address URI pass
or parameter or any naming conventions
on the server that we found
we can sinkhole malicious infrastructure
so we can attempt to take over
completely unprotected c2s or we can
attempt to register domain names used by
thread groups
in case we have access and we've
identified
accounts used by thread actors so things
like social media profiles accounts used
for Google Drive or Dropbox registration
we can go ahead and get them banned and
removed from the platforms and we can
attempt to identify all infected
machines in our organizations and clean
them up I guess
whoa everything is nice and dendy
researchers are winning the battle
against botnets
because domain registration at scale is
still expensive uh
it is certainly traceable when you do it
on large scale if you are trying to use
accounts on Google or or draw books or
other social media Facebook Twitter well
maybe not Twitter uh
then then this is still very labor
intensive to create the account and
maintain them because these platforms
really try to avoid bot registration and
certainly do their best to remove uh
fake accounts from their platforms
and and once you're confined for example
to specific domains or specific accounts
or folders in Google Docs or whatnot
then then the traffic can unique can be
uniquely identified and then what
researchers do is just capture the
samples analyze them
prevent further infections by that same
malware sample and then create iocs
which gets distributed to the security
mechanisms out there be those firewalls
web gateways so on that look at the
requests coming from the infected
machines and block them
and then when the servers themselves are
taken down there is no way for the new
control infrastructure created by the
attackers and and yes they create the
new infrastructure because that's how
they make the living
but that new infrastructure cannot
communicate with the already infected
machines
creating them useless
but researchers
are still losing
to nation-state actors
those actors have a lot of resources
both in terms of endless budgets and a
lot of head count and using those
resources they are able to Defy Gravity
by creating huge numbers of for example
Google accounts or Facebook accounts or
LinkedIn accounts and maintaining them
over time
so they can keep
the Abundant running for a very long
time even though some of these accounts
are being detected and and now being set
up as iocs in all security mechanisms
now that doesn't seem fair for the
criminal hackers who do not have budgets
and do not have head counts
so we want to give back power to the
people
we want to create abundant
infrastructure for your everyday hacker
and of course it has to rely on public
infrastructure so it should be
indistinguishable from normal Network
traffic
and we want the individual votes to
never die even when the central
infrastructure is taken down
and we want it to be cheap really cheap
so we started thinking of ways to do
that and here are some of the ways we
just crossed out blockchain based
infrastructure for botnet
it's possible but it's very noisy it's
very expensive
we thought of an infrastructure in which
the individual bhagnet would try to
create accounts with the service like
Google like Facebook but again this is
complex this is way too expensive we
talked about how complex it is to create
an account with these services and if
you go to off-brand services
think of WeChat which are easier to
register to
they would be identified in any normal
Network
so let's see if we can do a little bit
better and another idea that we had is
to have a single account
a bootstrap account included in the
initial malware that would be used by
the bot
upon registration to receive an
individual account
from a pool that is created in the back
office of the botnet control
okay and then that individual account
would be used for further Communications
with the infrastructure uh now that
provides us with an easy way for two-way
Communications uh the Bots Will Survive
a takedown of the bootstrap account
because they already have their
individual accounts
they can even survive a takedown of
their own individual account by for
example using a beca account that was
created upon registration
however
once the initial malware sample is
captured that bootstrap account
would be closed and would not be used
anymore and we will have to replace the
initial malware uh
account creation although it's being
done in the back office of the botnet
controller it's still a hassle
and what's worse
is that researchers could actually
attack this infrastructure with an
account exhaustion attack
so they would drive the botnet
controller crazy with constantly asking
for new accounts
well we're not happy with that so we sat
down and say oh we don't know what to do
and when you do not know what to do
you just Google it
and that was our aha moment
or Epiphany if you'd say
we should build
a system in which the Bots do not know
the CNC however the Bots know how to
search for the CNC and they know a CNC
when they see one see
and of course
we have to choose our Search terms in a
way
that they cannot be used as iocs
think cats cute pink
now that we have an idea on how to
become a malware Lord
we needed a guide
to how to do that and the guide for
becoming a malware load starts with
gather your minions
so what we did
is we recruited undergraduate students
from the technion
and explain the system to them
and the system
should be based on a service that
supports Anonymous data consumption okay
so I can consume data without
registering an account
it should offer a flexible and diverse
search functionality
pretty much everyone does day-to-day
and content Creation in the platform
may require registration but the content
itself is not scrutinized so we gave
them these instructions this
specification and said go and find
platforms go and create pocs
they created great things uh they used
YouTube they used Reddit
they relied on comments on content
posted by other people
and uh really within the time frame of a
single semester we're able to come with
pocs on top of these Platforms in the
meanwhile
we took a different platform which we'll
show you today
so now I am really thrilled to introduce
you with the POC that we've executed
SpotBot which obviously is a bot
communicating over Spotify
infrastructure
now why we specifically chose Spotify
for this demonstration was really a
no-brainer
it's because Spotify is just the perfect
match to all the criteria we've
mentioned and said that is absolutely
crucial for the success of this
infrastructure
all types of media that are available on
Spotify can be consumed anonymously
Spotify also offers a great abundance of
Search terms and modifiers to be
performed on said media anonymously
and the most important thing when
creating and hosting a malware
infrastructure
is that for Spotify podcasts all data is
not scrutinized in any way nor for
copyrights or for offensive content
so if you've ever found yourself
wondering of how can one start its own
Spotify podcast then Wonder no more
because delivering podcasts via Spotify
is relatively easy all you have to do is
register to a thing called a Content
distribution platform we've used one
that's named castos and it costs less
than twenty dollars a month which is
quite cheap and then into this platform
you upload your podcasts content so
episodes images titles transcripts and
descriptions then simply go to
podcasters.spotify.com link it with this
distribution platform and
congratulations you now own a podcast
now that we have a brand new podcast
started live and on the air let's see
how we can actually utilize it to send
CNC commands and so the first approach
we can take here is to encode data
inside the podcast audio streams or the
images that are associated with it and
to do that we'll have to encode and then
decode the data on the other end using
something like an OCR or a naughty
modulation program
now the second approach that we chose is
to encode short data messages inside
podcasts episodes descriptions now
you'll be surprised with how much you
can fit inside just one description
so for instance we can put their short
short command we can put URLs for
fetching further payloads we can insert
the ID of an additional Spotify object
in our malicious chain
and we can even fit a 64 by DSA digital
signature inside the description
now that we covered how the spotbot's
controller side can look like and can
operate let's see how the spotbot's
client so the victims themselves can
create their initial contact with the
Spotify C2
and to do that will rely on those Search
terms we've mentioned earlier it's
because each SpotBot distribution will
be packaged with a set of keywords
referring to the malicious podcast name
upon initial execution SpotBot will
search Spotify for these keywords
receiving back many many results
including podcasts episodes songs
playlists artists and essentially
anything available on the platform that
can match either of the keywords
poor SpotBot now has to determine which
of these results is the right one and to
do that he will attempt to match the
description of all of the results with
an additional set of either keywords or
patterns that are embedded inside the
malware
note the right episode with the right
description
shouldn't only match spotbot's keywords
and patterns but must also match
spotbot's digital signature because
we've said that we can fit one inside
the malicious description
Now using the signature helps SpotBot
verify that it got the right content
while also helping us make sure that our
infrastructure and our Bots are not
being sinkholed
so as you can see inside the description
we can put things like commands to be
executed on the victim's host machine or
that we can put their the ID of an
additional episode of our podcast that
will eventually lead SpotBot to things
it has to execute
now let's all assume for a moment that
the absolute worst of all that happened
in a researcher happened to track down
the links to all of our episodes
blocking them even getting them removed
from Spotify in an attempt to defeat us
and disable all the Bots
well in this case
we'll just simply upload new and fresh
content into Spotify because we're still
aware of the keywords that are embedded
inside spot but distributions and
SpotBot will forever continue to look up
their keyword in case they received no
additional command leaving us and a
researcher playing a very vicious game
of guacamole with Spotify content and
SpotBot Reviving
now we want to present just a quick demo
of how spotbot's execution can actually
look like so on this side you can see
the console output of a SpotBot
execution so what a bot is doing what is
he looking for in Spotify what did he
find and attempting to do next and on
this side you can see the actual content
on Spotify that the bot is consuming
so
we can see that
the boat is attempting to start it is
not starting
to simulate the boat
he's not working
so it was evident that we could easily
create
a running functioning bonded
infrastructure on top of various
Platforms in
a very minimal cost
and it was easy to deliver command from
the controller to the bot
on this infrastructure but as you've
noticed
it's not that trivial to do the other
way around so of course we could use
some of the commands to for example
include temporary links or URLs to
servers that we've taken over and can
now be used for a limited time by the
Bots to upload their content but this is
still somewhat inconvenient so in terms
of further research we've tried to find
a way to make this channel
bi-directional
one of the methods we thought of was
looking into the analytics that the
platforms offer think of YouTube
analytics who's watching the movie where
are they coming from and so on who's
listening to my music and podcast on
Spotify and what we try to do was
to insert information
into HTTP headers for example in a way
that would show up
in the analytics screens
alas we're not very successful with that
there was anecdotally one thing we're
able to do with YouTube so we're able to
see which language
a movie was consumed in
so we could have
different Bots trying to ask for
different language versions of the
podcast for example or of a movie and
and and then you know track them a
little bit but
not a lot of information could be sent
that way uh so that's that's certainly
one area that deserves for the research
another idea that we looked into was
instead of the
bot searching for their controller have
the controller find the Bots and the
best infrastructure for doing that
is ADS based botnet
think about all those services that
just know that you're planning a trip to
Kenya or all those
advertisers that just happen to know
that you were talking about a new car
you want to purchase okay so these are
very powerful Platforms in terms of uh
targeting machines targeting individuals
uh so definitely an idea to look at and
of course one of the most obvious ones
that deserves attention is how can we
use existing accounts on the inflected
infected platforms
to communicate with our botnet
infrastructure
so I think that we've proved that many
public platforms provide the opportunity
for attackers to create a very resilient
botnet That Never Dies and all these
platforms
can be easily put to work because of
their apis because of their simple web
access so the cost of maintaining this
infrastructure alive
is dramatically dropping not only that
because you are not losing the
individual Bots when you're being
detected at one place
it becomes even more cost effective
so what's the conclusion of all this the
conclusion is that the current Defender
toolbox
is no longer doing the work and it must
change the generic defenses that are
based on ioc's applied
to the traffic going out of the boats to
the controller
just fail to protect us
and we got to the point where you can
achieve cheap and simple construction of
this botnet however it's a very
expensive and complex process to
dismantle them
and it seems like we need a new breed of
tools here that are able to look at the
content delivered by the platforms and
at the same time be somewhat platform
agnostic
and until we have this breed of tools
we'll keep losing the game of guacamole
thank you
[Music]