everyone everyone hello can you hear me
excellent everyone welcome to b-sides
Orlando 2018 thank you for being here
so as the screen comes down and we get
our slides up my name is ian mayer and
the president besides orlando or other
board members are raucously running
around making a conference great for you
guys right now so we really appreciate
you being here on a Saturday morning
basically we want to give you a little
history of Aesop's for those of you here
new here the b-sides framework started
in 2009 so if this is your first
conference we hope you have a blast and
we hope you check out more but the
b-sides frame workers are on bringing
communities together getting people who
maybe might not be able to get to a big
security conference involved bringing in
new voices getting students involved and
it's grown from 2009 it's grown
throughout the world 20 events 30 events
throughout the world and then besides
Orlando starts here
so we're ahead with this as ours what's
6th a year now this year we're expecting
about 550 people here we're gonna be a
checking account later so that's amazing
and we can't thank Full Sail enough for
having us
so everyone give them a clap here so
it's not cool this is like blackhat
level stuff we came in last night and I
got to give credit to the guys in the
back that came unless anything like are
you sure this is OK do you like it I'm
like are you kidding this is amazing so
wonderful so a couple updates a couple
things to keep in mind here a hacker
tracker if you guys downloaded that we
got some comments there's some
scheduling issues on there we apologize
so check the schedule on the website
besides Orlando com of 2018 /schedule
that schedule is up to date the career
hall there's a 9:30 resume review that
has been moved back so if you are here
to get your resume reviewed by some
really quality resume reviewers that's
gonna be a little later in the day and
then we've got our soldering station on
the map it's been moved forward a little
bit so if you see the soldering station
you're trying to go the other tracks and
you're like oh I've going to where am I
walk past it and someone will be able to
direct you so let's thank our sponsors
of applause for the folks that made this
happen with some monies please go see
them these are people supporting our
security community they see besides is
something that's important so go support
them find out what they're about see how
you can get involved we want to thank
our shirt sponsor these awesome hack the
planet shirts Florida cybersecurity
Center they've been a partner for a very
long time so we want to thank them and
of course our afterparty sponsored our
diamond sponsor ally quest is well a
wonderful partner will talk more yeah
somebody from Alana question sure so so
a little map thank you to Heather for
this you did an amazing job on a lot of
these graphics and full sales pulled
them together for the visual I'm just
thrilled to be up here so if you haven't
seen the map yet check your programs and
your bags but we are where that star is
right now registration track one when
you leave this room if you don't stick
around for the keynote which I highly
suggest you do but if you leave this
room to go check out one of the
workshops you're gonna leave out the
front go through the side doors and
follow around when you see the tent for
the soldering station keep going around
and go through the doors there and
you'll be able to find the other tracks
the vendor Hall etc so sunshine CTF
who's here to compete in the CTF anybody
see some ants cheers come on I see I see
UCF folks in the back yes how you doing
yeah so yes of course they heard of
Cammy the CTF so go check out sunshine
CTF these are people who I consider you
guys pros I mean to be honest you guys
are amazing so that people are competing
from around the world around the world
many competitors and our local
competitors here will be announced as
the local champion so we'll do that at
opening ceremonies hopefully it's one of
you fire talks this is a new addition
for this year in track two we will have
fire talks um Jeff will be over there
running that during the lunch hour
you got something you want to talk about
you got a short talk ten minutes stop by
sign up talk that's it
they'll be limited slots available take
about ten minutes first-come first-serve
so if you've got something you
particularly want to talk about about
security you brought some slides you got
whatever we're here for you
right there we go so food how many what
to be said Stampa Cheers I like
everyone's hands hands very good so
Bethune's has drove up from tampa for us
if you like Bethune's they are out there
cooking up the barbecue for us $10
plates of barbecue cash and credit
accepted and you don't have to leave the
security perimeter which is fantastic so
however if barbecue is not your thing
you've got some food allergies or you've
got some different dietary preferences
there are multiple options on campus
just keep in mind when you do leave the
security perimeter you have to come back
through the security perimeter and we'll
talk about that a little more in a
minute so career track how many you here
looking for jobs want to get into cyber
security more hands yeah good this is
what this conference is about we want
you to come in so cyber SEC jobs has
come out they run higher ground out in
be size of Las Vegas the mothership
they've come out they're going to be
doing they're gonna be doing a whole
talks panels there's gonna be a
presentation on doing better PowerPoint
slides to really get your point across
this is great stuff and if you're
looking they have bracelets I believe we
have them at registration if we don't go
over the career Hall they'll be there in
the career hall room career track
they're basically I'm hiring I'm looking
you have those bracelets in some way so
say my company's hiring what are you
interested in strike up those
conversations that's what this
conference is about meeting people
connecting with them building building
things out so solder stations this is so
cool so Heather and John really some of
our staff and board members really kind
of went into this in your bags there are
lanyards you may have been given a PCB
board badge please one thing I was just
noted you do have to have your badge on
while you're outside so if you haven't
put it on yet getting your bag get your
Lantern
get your little PCB board put it on for
me please Full Sail Security's wants to
see that to know that your you're
supposed to be here but we have a tent
over there where there are electronic
parts there's LEDs these badges do stuff
and if you've always wanted to learn how
to solder
we've got people over there they're
gonna walk you through it
lockpick village without tool Orlando
out here doing a lockpick village so
again if that's your thing and you've
never picked a lock before come out
learn how to pick a lock this folks I
cannot tell you how cool this was so I
had an opportunity to go out to Wild
West High confessed
Black Hills information security hosted
that out in South Dakota they actually
put together hands-on labs hands at
keyboard playing with software-defined
radio decoding firmware pulling that out
all that stuff that you go I want to
figure out how to do that but I never
have the time they have short demos you
can get your hands on the keyboards
right now and learn that stuff we can't
thank them enough for bringing that out
it's just amazing we also set up
something that honestly it was late one
night and I'd said to the team I'm like
should we do this and they said yeah do
it
so I bought about three hundred dollars
in garbage IOT gear just junk just just
Chinese Wi-Fi junk and it's just over
there so please wreck our stuff we leave
it there for you we look forward to
seeing what you make the little Wi-Fi
controlled remote camera car thing I
bought do so please do that after party
so Miller's Ale House we literally have
our after-party next door so a really
great what's gonna be from 6 to 8 it's
sponsored by realize everyone give a lot
less another cheer first goes who
doesn't like after party yay so stick
around if you're gonna stick around for
closing we're gonna give you some coins
we all sent around said yeah tickets are
kind of cheesy what can we do so we
actually got like little plastic gold
coins maybe you think that's fun I
thought it was fun we'll give you some
gold coins that you trade in for drinks
over there if we hope to see you silent
auction we have a really awesome silent
auction over there with some fantastic
prizes hacker boxes sent us full like
lab kits we've got some know starts
crust gift certificates we'll take cash
and credit card some of the items will
be shipped to you either through email
or whatnot from no starch so go over
there bid all that money goes into
putting this together for next year and
we can't thank the people that sent us
gifts off for that so do want to talk
about some rules rules so most of you
would have seen we have a code of
conduct I'm actually very proud of this
we want to be a
inclusive community and one of the
things we want to do is bring in voices
and people that haven't been in this
community before because we need them so
if you haven't had a chance to read the
code of conduct we think it's great we'd
love to hear your feedback and how we
can improve it so the security perimeter
we had some questions about that this is
in my mind actually a fantastic thing
our venue cares enough about your
personal safety to make sure that the
people that are in here are supposed to
be here and with some of the events that
have happened in our home state
especially on campuses I personally am
thrilled that they're doing this so you
know we're happy to take feedback and
things like that but know that this I
think it's great I think they did a
great job getting through people through
you're all in here I think we've cleared
the line I think we did great
no unsolicited penetration tests of any
kind
we brought stuff for you guys to break
we are guests here I know that no one
would ever do that because you're all
good and kind and strong and brave
people and I love you all for it but
just that is a reminder we've got gear
for you guys to break don't touch any of
Full Sail stuff I know I don't need to
remind you but I'm reminding you because
I work in compliance now and that's what
we do so we're guests here right we're
hoping to make this our permanent home I
mean look at how cool this is we want to
be a part of Full Sail and we hope that
they're gonna ask us back to be part of
their family
so speaking of Full Sail my what you
guys might not know is I have the
privilege of being an adjunct professor
here teaching information security and I
would like to invite my boss to the
stage J Boehner he is the program
director for the cloud technologies
program here at Full Sail he's going to
give you just a little couple minutes on
full sound some of the stuff we do here
and I will hand it over to Jay
that's right thank you so much my name
is jay bondrock I'm the program director
for the cloud technologies program here
at Full Sail University and what a great
what a great event I mean we're so
excited to host besides on campus here
and looking forward to all the great
workshops there's a lot of cool stuff in
stores so a little bit of history about
full sales so for about 30 years now
we've actually taken kind of a creative
approach to education and we first
started off in a lot of you know
recording in media industries and things
like that and recently and in the last
several years the last five to ten years
we branched out into game design and
simulation and tech you know
high-technology types of degrees and so
cloud technologies is one of those
degrees and we wanted to have some
opportunity to to give a first-class
conference experience to students as
well because a lot of students don't get
to experience this until they're
actually working in the industry so so
when I share a little bit about the the
school and kind of tell you some of the
cool types of things we're doing so I've
got a real quick demo video we're gonna
show you thank you
we have a lot of technology being
introduced and in I think all of the
disciplines at Full Sail are connected
to technology in some way it's this yin
and yang where you have creativity but
it's not enough to just like want to
build something or want to create
something you have to want to keep
creating something and you have to want
to make it better you have to have a
creative elements that process and you
have to have a critical element to that
process and that's true of any
discipline and what we call the creative
class I think which includes not just
what people traditionally think of as
visual artists but it also includes
engineers and and folks who come up with
solutions to problems I'm just a
lifelong maker this is just my heartbeat
but this is like a crazy amazing time
for me because I get to teach in this
amazing Fab Lab we have here and it's
putting the hardware skills with the
student software skills it's essentially
like merging with the emerging
technologies so getting to put these
symbols for a tech VR all that together
because it's a great time to be involved
in all of this that's being driven by
people with passion for this and if it
were saying is maker is somebody that
that makes things and it's the age of
the maker because now with the
technology so advanced and we've gone a
long way that people are empowered to do
projects that require 50 people back
there or 10 people now you can do it
with one person and that is something
that empowers you and we're starting to
see all of the boundaries pushed and
broken apart sometimes and just how
quickly everything is changing I think
what makes our curriculum different as a
university is that that foresight will
allows us to take risks that other more
standard curriculums aren't able to do
and sometimes with technology it's not
about who's been doing it longer it's
been who's been doing it better
we've got this stuff we've got the
hardware that the students get to put
their hands on if students learn tool
sets throughout the different courses
that attach themselves to other courses
and that really fosters creativity
that's synergy of the students so it's
not really if the gadgets it's not about
the gadgets it's really how do we
empower the students to synergize with
each other and now she creates something
better like they bring their labs done
to lab time and then during the lap time
they're bugging the instructors about
like I'm working on the side project has
nothing to do with your class I already
finish the work for your class I'm
working on this other thing and if you
could help me figure out this one thing
I can make this one thing better right
and when you have people come through
and they look and they see what you're
teaching and they go
these are employers out there going we
want what you're making like we want
these students this is an important like
set of tools that we want students to
know what do you think isn't that really
cool
so our simulation visualization program
actually has we have a Fab Lab in the
air VR labs and things like that that
you saw up on the screen if anybody's
interested in a tour of those this
afternoon we're out in the lobby is a
full sale table we're going to meet at
11:45 you know right at the start of
launch break so if anybody's interested
on on tour of that just join us out
there so I appreciate it and welcome to
Full Sail and I'm gonna hand it back
over to you and thank you they took they
took my Britney Spears mic I will not
dance for you so those of you who are
here for the ICS track we have a
waitlist this is a super super popular
thing and we cannot thank security
matters enough for coming out and doing
it so unfortunately it's a long class we
actually asked them to trim it down so
that you could be here for the opening
ceremonies and closing ceremonies this
is generally an eight-hour class that
they run that is very expensive and
they've offered to come here and do it
for free for you so if you're one of the
people that are in that class now it's
probably the time to start walking over
you can exit through the back if you
need to once I'm done talking we do the
transition over to our keynote speaker
that way you can get over there and make
sure you've got your seat if you are
registered there is a waitlist there is
a 20-person waitlist and if you are not
in your seat 15 minutes after it starts
your seat will be given away we
apologize but we're giving you fair
warning so we just want to make sure
that everyone who wants to get in that
class does we have a nice full class and
the instructors get the benefit of
having a nice full class so proceed on
to the workshop map or on the on the map
2d workshops so coordinators I'm looking
at everyone in this audience if you
leave here today inspired if you leave
here wanting to be more part of this
community there is a team of people
wearing red shirts right now and I've
got a slide thanking up there that
worked dog idli to make this happen for
you we would like you to be a part of
that team email info at besides Orlando
comm with the subject I want to be a
coordinator about a month after this
what's basically once we all
an app will start reaching out to people
just like the volunteers with some roles
and see what you're interested in we
need someone to manage social media we
need people to manage on-site logistics
we need people to be permanent local
security we need all kinds of stuff so
please if you like what you see and you
want to be a part of it be a part of it
and thank you I I there's this slide
could honestly be like four miles long
and I couldn't thank everyone that needs
to be thanked but if you see someone
wearing one of these red shirts thank
them they've been up all night for weeks
working with people to make this happen
and we hope you enjoy it because we just
poured our hearts and souls into it I
want to sit a special thanks to the full
sail team one of the reasons that we
really wanted to be here is obviously
you've seen the production value is is
amazing but Danielle and Jay who you
just saw and a myriad of others Jacob
who I think's in the back somewhere
there he is hey he's on camera hey Jacob
d-iii Tom who's on here trying to keep
me and my mic and I'm an unruly person
who walks around and waves his hands too
much so um anyway thank them as well
they've put in a monumental amount of
effort to just bring this up to a next
level and we can't can't say how much we
appreciate it
so social if you do the socials with the
Twitter's and the apps Twitter at
besides Orlando Instagram besides orl if
you're tweeting stuff out if your
instant stuff out I'm an old man I got
too much grin my beard now hashtag
b-sides Orlando and then I've also got
hash tag in there IOT dumpster fire so
if you hack some of our stuff that we've
left over in the hands-on hall show us
what you did tweet it out we want to see
all that Chinese junk do cool things and
I have an extra note here down here that
Tom's gonna yell at me if I don't read
it you guys can't see it but a very
important the mics down here at the end
when we have speakers that have QA at
the end and you need to ask a question
or want to ask a question walk up to the
mics and just get line and as we have
the ability to answer questions we will
time permitting and they'll get it on
here so everyone can hear you and
whatnot so just walk down to the mics at
the end and you'll be good to go and I
was also asked please please please
please please make sure you get your
badges on
so if you haven't done it when I first
said it make sure you do it so the
morning keynote we are absolutely
thrilled and you're probably tired to
hear me talk so we're gonna do a little
handoff here but I had the pleasure of
introducing AB need a sigh of shellman
and company she is an EVP for them and
she comes from an ethical hacking
background she's seen the whole gamut
from being a penetration tester to
working with executives to finding out
what it means to go from being hands-on
keyboard all the way up to working with
executives and new companies this is a
person that you should listen to because
they have the experience to show you
what the career arc looks like and what
yours can look like so it is my pleasure
again to bring on Avenida site
[Applause]