[Applause]
you've got a crowd of hecklers only it's
my pleasure for to introduce here this
evening this afternoon - Chad see my
internet dumpster diver
DDoS researcher hunter of botnets
diddler of malware in senior Security
Response Team engineer at Akamai
presenting with him is Rory Smith
computer and caffeine addict pocket
ninja log crawler and first line of
defense against large-scale web app and
DDoS attacks targeting your favorite
companies also known as the senior sock
engine specialist at Akamai
hey guys thanks for having us the talk
we're gonna give today is the wire X
botnet and how shady apps lead to hot
pockets and we'll hand it off to Rory
first alright hey everybody
pretty much here we have a nice and
interesting attack to kind of bring in I
wanna just at the timeline bring you all
into the sack you're gonna become one
with us you're gonna feel our pain
the pressures on every point of this and
pretty much show you how we work through
it so if you've ever worked in a sock
you're gonna feel like this is another
day in the office if you haven't well
just get ready you're about to get
strapped in and engage so on August the
17th we had pretty much a slew of
attacks right and it targeted all of our
hospitality customers so what's
interesting about this attack is that
you know you're working in a sock you
get to know someone's infrastructure you
get to tune it accordingly you want to
protect them proactively we always want
to go towards a proactive solution but
in this case normal mitigation methods
didn't work none of our proactive
solutions worked what was also
interesting is that even our detection
methods didn't work right so and then
after that for some of our customers you
know have advanced mitigation methods
depending on the solution that they have
and those also failed so now we're
missing a lot of information now we're
unable to detect it we're unable to
mitigate it proactively and that's what
we walk into starting a day so what's so
special about wirings right so what
we're looking on is 70,000 unique IP
addresses right so 70,000 infected
devices connected at one time and I
think there's still being a bit modest
because we saw quite a few more but
we're gonna go ahead and just hold it at
70,000 and these addresses they result
primarily to mobile networks not always
cuz you know you may have your phone and
it's connected on the Wi-Fi it's not
necessarily always mobile but one of the
trends that we saw with it later on is
that it
definitely mobile networks
geographically
no that was completely dispersed again
we have a hundred countries here however
actually being there on the ground
looking at it we saw 172 plus so
definitely more and it bypassed all our
standard security anomaly detection x'
that we had in place it bypassed
proactive control methods and it also
even bypassed our basic JavaScript real
browser challenges so whatever this bot
was it they knew what they were doing
these attackers knew what they were
building on what they were targeting and
then now let's go back were in the sack
and we're finding the mushroom cloud so
the title says it all because you're in
you're sitting down your phone rings and
the first call is we've gotta save one
critical business infrastructure is
impacted websites down right now we're
making no money here's a bridge get on
it
we need your help now no warning you
know you love those blind calls you're
going into it blind you get on and you
know you're we're all seasoned sucks now
so we're going through our lives what
can we see what can we find right so
we're looking on let's say we have our
mud security rules we've got our snort
rules we've got everything engaging
we're checking no triggers we've got
rate controls no triggers so at this
point it's hey did somebody on your site
do some maintenance maybe open maybe you
tried contact a system team did they try
to update something and bring down your
app we say that a lot but maybe that's
what's going on so we said ok while
everybody is engaged and doing their
thing let's actually go on the traffic
side what does traffic look like usually
someone's network operations made up
made perform those tasks since you won't
really go to a sock and just say are the
traffic so we know that business is
impacted and it's going down so if there
was an attack capable of bringing in a
down we must be able to see it in
traffic right so we started looking on
let's say the hits per second to the
site now fairly popular sites so it has
its usual 250 to 500 per second logs
usually
and then immediately we see 20,000 right
so that's 20,000 per second millions are
logs per minute now being filled and
some customers to their benefit they
were actually able to stay up their
server logs were 70 percent 80 percent
their CPUs and other customers they were
completely down so now whatever this is
it can do twenty thousand per second and
at the same time not trigger an alert
that's weird
on the security side so I decided let's
go ahead and look on your valid traffic
let's see what's actually in those logs
right now not really any is a task from
our side since from the security
perspective we want to go ahead and what
we do is we tag it as malicious and we
get we want to preserve those headers
because just if you go into your Apache
log you're gonna get some details
headers aren't preserved right so once
we get that going maybe on your sock you
may have a TCP dump that you can open it
and see it live we see that pretty much
the traffic looks fairly well with the
exception of the user agent looking on
that user agent we can see 26 characters
randomly strung together right so when
you're in the logs it's clear as day
now when IDs is looking at it it's a
unique IP and a unique user agent so
it's treating that as unique traffic
right so nothing to see here maybe it's
just a marketing campaign and that's why
their traffic doubled right so now we
can we can identify it that's no problem
let's let's build some more profile
around it right so we've got get floods
post requests and get requests we
already identify the user agent and that
the IPS were all unique now the rate is
interesting they're getting brought down
however looking through the logs we have
a lot of IP addresses we were clocking
it at maybe three requests per second
per IP address at near its peak no
that's definitely territories where if
you go rate control you're going to hit
legitimate traffic so from there and
I'll go into the next line a little bit
later because the attacker appeared to
be actively monitoring which will call
over in a second and overall the volume
traffic was high enough to him to impact
your infrastructure right so these are
what we know now fairly easy we've got
26 character user agent we've got some
pretty decent regex skills going on so
let's just drop this one right this is
basic right so we're just saying a to Z
26 make sure you put that dollar sign in
the end but for some mitigation
appliances some of our clients let's say
they don't just have one domain right
they have maybe 10 15 domains and that
is really popular domains you don't want
to just use reg X that can be
computationally expensive so you don't
want to be inspecting on everything we
just want to cut that traffic first so
we figured out the domain from the locks
before and we already saw that we had
get and post requests so let's just make
a rule pretty much those are the
criteria is there and pretty easy
now attack mitigated beautiful everybody
is happy right so attacks mitigated
servers our back CPU levels are great
websites stable customers know awesome
and ready to get back to business
and then the cycle is down again and now
we're wondering hey what's going on this
is weird
so then we'll start looking on the logs
again we're already mitigating some now
they're playing with the length and then
taunting us noscitur like oh you know
what we've got ahead and throw digits in
there - what are you gonna do next
right so again we know what good user
agents look like we know what bad we
know what characters to expect or
characters not to expect and we can go
ahead and start making more reg X's now
after that every time we made it they
change it and then of course they went
over - what are you gonna do when we hit
you with legitimate user agents right so
now we're getting legitimates so now
this is this is ours going now because
we've got whack-a-mole going now we've
got pretty much you know legitimate user
agents which we can't just make a custom
rule to drop so now we've got to get
more proactive because at this point we
have a case where our customers are
saying every time you make a rule you
fix the problem but between each of your
rules
were feelin impact and it's getting
really bad so at this point again you
know our advanced mechanisms they're not
working because this is whatever this is
it's currently bypassing those so we've
got user oldies but goodies and we've
got a pretty much just lower the levels
right so we had to use multiple controls
after this right we have geo blocks
aggressive rate controls network lists
and each of well combined it definitely
mitigated the problem individually each
had their own set of problems so let's
say we start with a blacklist in this is
hospitality so some of our customers say
hey we've got a global presence people
buy tickets from us all over the world
people want to stay in hotels and they
come from all over to book we can't just
go on black countries randomly you're
gonna you're gonna cost us money so
those this wouldn't be a great option
right but for other customers they're
like hey you know what most of our
income is coming from the US or Europe
right now I've got $0 coming in let's go
ahead and block everybody else then we
use the aggressive rate controls was
said over overall we're seeing three
requests per second right so on average
three requests per second so legitimate
users can pretty much trigger a three
requests per second easy however do you
expect it to sustain over five seconds
do you expect it to sustain over a
minute or two minutes so should a
legitimate user be doing three requests
per second for two minutes that's
definitely not expected at that point so
we could get more aggressive with our
rate controls tune in accordingly and
from there for some of our customers
that resulted in some legitimate client
impact others of course had no impact so
this was definitely a good one but again
if we have two customers getting dropped
as opposed to everybody being unable to
access a site this is effective and
acceptable to them and then we had
network lists right so network list it
was great at the start
you need something immediate you need to
shave off some of those top talkers and
get that sight a little less load but
this was exhaustive super exhaustive
when you're pulling loads and you're
pulling loads then you have 50,000 lines
of code with 30,000 different IPS you
can imagine how exhaustive that must get
to even add them to a list and even when
you think about it we did see this as a
mobile network so if you think about
your drive here your flight here you may
have changed IP addresses 10 times right
and conservative so 10 times in which
case one infected IP could do 10 IP
address attacker from 10 different IP
address this was super temporary but if
they're feeling impact were engaged and
of course we're using every tool at our
disposal so from a combination of those
three we're able to pretty much mitigate
the attack make our custom rules as well
and tunas needed if they called in and
said hey our customers are impacted then
you know we would go figure out a way
maybe increase the threshold a bit and
make sure that the load that they're
seen on their side isn't too much and
pretty much just go on and from there we
got them through the hard part of this
attack right so now that that's done we
just go ahead and call our cert team or
Chad here and I'm like hey Chad this is
a button it it's super annoying and
we've been dealing with this all weekend
interesting thing looks like it's coming
from mobile networks go ahead and check
it out this is where I come in love
botnets the best I always love finding a
new botnet it's always a good day it
sucks for the internet but it's a lot of
fun for me
so this sounds especially interesting as
soon as I get any details from it and
I'm just like give me the data give me
what we need let's start digging now
before I go any further there are some
things that led up to the discoveries
that we'll talk about that I can't talk
about just as supposedly Napoleon said
never interfere with your enemy when
he's making a mistake
the develop
of the malware made mistakes I want to
talk about those mistakes but they are
eventually what led us to finding the
apks and everything else that found the
botnet or made us uncover the botnet so
one of the mistakes resulted in some
random characters ending up in some of
the attack traffic that looked fairly
unique unique enough that when you drop
them into Google you found apks
associated with them hosted on these apk
marrying sites now if you're not
familiar with a became airing sites
essentially they just crawl the Play
Store and they snapshot everything
pulled down the apk files that would be
hosted there copy the descriptions copy
the developer pages everything and serve
as a backup if you will kind of like an
APA apk archive so if your favorite app
gets pulled from the App Store you can
probably still go find the apk and then
load it from an unknown source directly
from here they also if they push a new
version everybody was all up in arms
about the new snapchat well you could
have went and got your old snapchat back
from these guys probably stuff like that
so that's what therefore this turned
into quite the rabbit hole we had a
couple instances from the attackers
mistakes that led us to a couple pages
which in turn led us to their developer
page as it was captured by the mirroring
sites which led us to the other apps
which led us to more apps and more apps
and more apps I don't think you can
really see it in the screenshot here but
like this google is for tubemate two
point two point nine snap Tube YouTube
downloader are and you find that we've
got listings from apk pure we've got
listings from eight one APK dot CEO and
there were a bunch of others so it was a
lot of just going and hopping from one
of those to the next and grabbing all
the apks we could find that seemed
relatively unique so now we've got all
of these apks
and I am not an Android developer and
I've never reversed anything on an
Android device so now the hunt begins as
to how can we start to handle this and
this is where apktool comes in thank God
for apktool it is amazing and if you are
looking into malicious apk files or
malicious Android applications you
should definitely look into it this is
straight off its website a tool for
reverse engineering third-party closed
binary android apps it can decode
resources to nearly original form and
rebuild them after making some
modifications it also makes working with
an app easier because of the project
like file structure and automation of
some repetitive tasks they also have a
disclaimer that please don't use it for
piracy because you can totally use it
for piracy it's that good we we don't
know if the developer that launched this
malware used this but I wouldn't be
surprised if he did because it allows
you to basically decompile a nap and
then recompile that same app from the
decompiled source that you got from the
first D compilation and you can modify
it
hence piracy if you want to find more
info you can just google it if you're on
OSX you can literally install it from
brew super easy it's also available in
most of your package management stuff on
all of your favorite Linux distros so
it's awesome so this is a quick example
of using apk tool you can see here we
have T TWD LP H key GQ whatever that is
one of the apks that was pulled down
obviously from apk pure comm and this is
just a basic D compilation process it
couldn't get literally any easier
apktool D file name and the result is a
directory named after the app so we go
into that directory and there's a lot of
files in there there's 2422 files in
there that's quite concerning
considering it's one tiny apk and the
the big problem is that we have to dig
through this stuff to figure out if
apks this is one apk at this point I
think we had close to two dozen and each
of them were producing thousands and
thousands and thousands of files so the
important part here is that apk tool
produces a folder called smiley although
these smiley files are text files which
becomes important for the next steps now
the problem is if we look at how many
lines of code we actually have from
smiley across our 2,400 files and
directories we have three hundred eighty
thousand lines of code also a nightmare
I don't want to dig through three
thousand three hundred eighty thousand
lines of code trying to find to figure
out if this is a malicious app or this
is just some guy doing piracy so that's
a lot of hey how can we find some
needles first thing why is there so much
small e there's so much small e because
apktool doesn't know where your app ends
and the android core libraries and and
everything else begins so we can see
here you've got Android support
annotation Android support v4
accessibility services Android for
support animation app view then we have
v7 app internal widget so there's all
this stuff that comes out and a lot of
it is just junk that you can ignore
safely the good news is is because this
stuff's written in Java and Java
utilizes proper namespaces for libraries
and everything else it does you the
favor of saying hey this is all the
Android stuff from the Android namespace
and this over here is all the other
stuff from all the other namespaces in
this case we know the app was called T W
DL whatever and if we look in the actual
small e structure we see a comm and then
we see a TWD lph whatever and then we
see an app now if you're actually
writing Java you probably are familiar
with import comm dot your library name
dot whatever path you
go down so when's apktool does the D
compilation it actually like they say it
maintains a same application structure
for your project for recompilation and
management purposes when it does the D
compilation it does the same thing so
looking into just these folders or this
folder where we suspect the primary
nefarious stuff is happening because
it's very unlikely that he's back
dooring stuff into the Android libraries
it's possible I guess but it's unlikely
we find twenty four hundred and fifty
one lines of code so sorry 24,000 lines
of code so much more manageable than
three hundred eighty thousand so what is
small e like a pirate no not like well
it can be used for piracy so maybe a
little bit like a pirate small e
slash back Somali isn't a similar
disassembler for the decks format used
by dalvik androids Java VM
implementation syntax is lui based on
Jasmin's detects or syntax supports the
full functionality of the dex format
including annotations debugging
information line information etc I don't
know what that means either
so what does this really mean in plain
English you can take Java Dex dalvik
bytecode it will process it and it will
convert it into this small e language
which is basically an ASCII
representation of Java bytecode so if
you've ever thrown a binary in something
like Ida and and you start to see the
the actual functions the move functions
and all of the pops and the pushes and
everything
same thing for Java essentially and just
dump to ASCII so it's really good you
should definitely get to know it here is
some sample code in Mali we can see the
first line we've got class public hello
world this is creating our hello world
class we can see super java.lang object
this is basically a hint that we're
extending the generic Java object class
if we were writing code this would be
hello world extends object if we declare
a public method main static returns void
we override that main function we're
gonna have two values that we're going
to store two registers we have V 0 V 0
stores are reference to system dot out
you can see java.lang system arrow to
out the actual second value is the the
the object type of that so in this case
it's a java io print stream then we
store in v1 con string hello world down
below we see invoke virtual we see V 0
which we know is system dot out and we
see V 1 which we know is our string
hello world and then we see that on the
print stream we're using the function
print line so invoke virtual is
basically just a function call and now
we see down below and comments I've put
a little sample as to what that would
actually look like system dot out dot
print line hello world return void and
method so that is your crash course -
this is small e
we're gonna look at some more of it I'm
sorry so we're still looking for a
needle we've got all of this small e
it's interesting but there is way too
much of it now we don't know how this
thing communicates with its c2 we don't
know if it's binary protocol if it's
HTTP it could be using something funky
all we really know is that it's capable
of attacking HTTP services so let's
start looking at HTTP or let's start
looking for HTTP as a token within the
code because you never know maybe you
know this thing decomposes or D compiles
and includes annotations and notes and
other things maybe somewhere buried in
there we can find HTTP and start to pick
away at this what we didn't expect to
find and found immediately where two
domains ax click dot store you and dot G
so if we look at where those strings
were found one is called exploration
activity small e
not too suspicious the other is found in
services /r why iidr XC j MF b which i
don't know if you're familiar with
malware naming but that seems nothing
like malware right totally legit so
first thing first let's poke these let's
see what they do if we hit u dot ax
clicked that store just simple curl we
get a 200 ok response blank never
changes we can hit it a thousand times
we always get a blank response to the
200 ok if we hit G ax click that store
we also get a 200 response this time
there's HTML the HTML content is mostly
blank except for there is a single title
tag and in that title tag is a string
and that string changes every time we
hit the server so this is an example of
what you would see HTML title HTTP slash
slash gobbly gook HTTP slash slash so
certainly looks like we've got at least
two URLs here we can tell that the
second URL starts because we see the
first HTTP and we can obviously tell
that it starts to HTTP now if you look
at this a little bit closer something
else jumps out of here we also see s any
W X WRI is repeated so that's pretty
interesting because given the
randomization of that string it seems
kind of weird that you would see repeats
like that if it were truly a random
string so then we start to come to
conclusions clearly the first thing is
URL we don't know why but we know it's
URL the second string that is repeated
we're now assuming as a delimiter and if
we break up this title on that delimiter
all of a sudden those magical mix of
characters in the middle are 26 Alpha
characters sounds a lot like the user
agents we've been seeing in the attacks
so we're starting to
confident we found the apks for what we
thought was a mobile botnet in there we
found URL that points to a site and in
that site we've now got a title tag that
contains URLs and a random 26 character
string so feeling like we're definitely
honing in on the right the right place
side note if anybody has ever used the
wire X but Bitcoin app I'm sorry that
this happened we had no idea it was name
that we named this wire X because of
shuffling of the letters in this
delimiter file or at this delimiter
value there are some way more fun names
in there but we weren't allowed to use
any of them so you can imagine you can
imagine alright so now we've found a URL
in a file that was interesting we found
that that file is named very
suspiciously we've confirmed that what
looks like the user agent is coming out
of the title tag
now let's find how this delimiter is
going to be used and where and
potentially how these values get used if
this is indeed a delimiter as we suspect
it is we grew up for that delimiter and
now we see our same two files show up
again we see exploration activity
there's four versions of exploration
activity and we'll explain that in a
second
this new adapter thing is new the comp
file is also new but the services we see
are very suspiciously named service
again so let's look into that service
file what we find in there is and
actually what we find in there and a lot
of places which is why we see so many
files here is we find a function that
uses our delimiter as the first part of
its function name we see public s anew X
W R I and then CC now I don't know how
familiar you are with verbage relating
to malware and botnets but CC is command
and control so to see a function with
our token and then CC at the end
that feels pretty good because now we
suspected this thing was communicating
with the CC in the first place based on
all the observations we made thus far
and the guesses that we've made so let's
see what this thing's doing will will
only focus on the blue lines just to
save time and energy
the first thing where you see it do is
that it is spinning up an Android WebKit
web view then it is using that webview
to get the settings object from that
settings object its setting the cache
mode to two if you look up the value for
what that means it's a constant means
don't set cache then it is setting v1 to
the value of one and clearing the cache
using that value it is clearing the
history on the webview then we see that
actual reference to the gix click store
this is the URL that we suspect is
giving the commands we see it load that
URL here's where it gets interesting we
see a new instance of services our same
filename with a dollar sign - at the end
we see the dollar sign - at the end
version a knitted and then we see it
passed in you can see it's stored in v1
and then v1 is passed into the webview
as a set webview client so what's the
deal with the dollar signs
when apktool decompile is APK files
you'll find there are the cases where a
file you're looking at may have multiple
named versions of itself delimited with
a dollar sign sometimes multiple dollar
signs what's going on here is
essentially when I'm writing my Java I
can put multiple class declarations in a
single source file before compilation
and what apktool is trying to do for
sane management of my project is take
those multiple classes and split them
out into unique classes for management
and
organization purposes so instead of
seeing this massive wall of text for a
single file all of my subclasses get
spun out in this case what we're
observing here is that the developer
declared their webview client class
inside of the same source file it was
compiled and then Wendy compiled it gets
split out to its own thing now we don't
know that it's a webview client yet but
we can make a pretty educated guess
based on how we're seeing it used in the
decompiled source you know we see dollar
sign two in it and then we see it
immediately set as the previous web
views own webview client so what is a
webview a webview is basically a
headless embedded browser instance it's
part of the Android OS if you've ever
used an app where you know you install
the app and then you click on the little
icon and it just loads the website
that's basically a webview what is a
webview client a client is basically a
programmable interface for catching
events and having programmatic hooks
into a webview that has been declared so
just like in JavaScript you can create
an object and then you can catch the
onload or on page load or whatever
events this is the WebKit class for
hooking into those events so if we
actually look into that dollar sign to
file where we suspect the webview client
is indeed being used we confirm that
there is one being used and the magic
happens in the on paged finished event
hook so this event hook fires when a
page is done loading obviously that's
very handy if you need to process the
page so what's going on here
important to note is the first parameter
passed in p1 is a webview this is our
webview that was just loaded with the c2
page we see that that webview will then
call get title if we have a title tag we
will continue we will call get title
again now we see our delimiter our s nu
X WRI is loaded into V 2 and then we're
checking with a string contains that
that string that is stored in our title
tag contains our delimiter if we do find
instances of it we continue we get title
again we trim it for white space on the
ends and then we split it on our
delimiter exactly what we expected
perfect so all of our all of our wildest
speculation and dreams are coming true
so we found our C 2 for sure all of our
guesses
most of our guesses have been correct so
far we know that our initially suspected
delimiter is indeed correct now we need
to see how these values are being used
so this is for sure the C 2 but we don't
know which of these URLs is the target
what is the other URL for we have no
idea at this point at this point though
we had already begun tracking that C 2
and we had have without a doubt observed
that URLs we were protecting and were
actively under attack from these
attackers were showing up in this C 2 so
this is the s new XR III whatever this
is the attacking function if you want to
know how a DDoS is this is where all the
secrets lie
the first thing worth noting is the two
declarations for x64 that's in hex it
comes out to a decimal 100 I had to
strip a lot of this out of here to try
and fit it onto slides and even still it
spreads across like three slides so
there are parts missing just know that
this was running in a loop you can guess
how many iterations it had so we spin up
a new web instance sorry web view
instance from that web view we anit it
we're also creating a new hash map the
hash map is interesting because it's
basically the object type that is
expected if you plan to override HTTP
headers in a web view object from there
we see map put but first we see the con
string refer so here we can figure out
that we know that the three values
passed in here you see L java.lang
string three times up there in the
public function header declaration for
the the function itself the method and
the peas map exactly to what you're
thinking there so p1 p2 p3 so we know
that the third URL in this case is being
shoved into the referer header of the
web view that's going to be used for the
attack we see X requested with which is
an interesting header this header is
used by the app it's built in and what
it basically does if you're using an
embedded web view the X requested with
header ships with the name of the
application that's doing the request we
can see here that the bad guy had
thought about this
he blanks it over written next we see
the request to get settings for the web
view that we're about to use and we see
it enables JavaScript to make sure that
we can bypass our real browser checks
next we're setting the user agent
we see here that they're setting v12
ptoo ptoo we know as the user agents the
second value in the the title that we
showed and we know that has been split
into an array before being passed into
here or not splintered an array but
chopped up and passed accordingly we see
that he clears the history not sure why
exactly I guess if you're browsing on
your phone and you look in your history
and all of a sudden there's all these
sites you've never been to and there's
thousands of pages for it you might be a
little suspicious he clears the form
data also not sure why but he does
clears the cache this one's obvious if
you're performing a DDoS attack and
you're getting cache hits on your local
device you're failing don't do that well
actually do do that
do do that then he clears the web view
database from the local device he wipes
the web cache DB from the local device
finally he sets the cache mode to no
caching and then he loads the URL for
the target and here we can see he's
loading p1 into v1 so we know that now
we can absolutely positively confirm
that the order and use for those values
are what we thought they were first one
target URL second one user agent third
one we now know is the referer header
that will show up in the HTTP headers
for the attack traffic creates a new
instance of same file name dollar sign
three we won't go into that it was
basically just an empty skeleton to
catch errors and fail gracefully without
throwing errors in the users face
because something went wrong and then we
see a dent and he increments v-0 so
essentially we're in a loop and what
we're gonna do is we're gonna spin up
100 web views we're gonna load them up
with our target using the user agent we
requested with blank requested with
headers and a refer that we've specified
from the c2
and send all that traffic at our poor
poor victims so there we go
this is what we've we now absolutely
positively can confirm is coming out of
these malicious apps this would be the
pseudocode based on the decompile stuff
that we just discussed if you were more
comfortable looking at it and something
that resembles a real language attack
command parser extends web view client
on page finished page title get title if
it contains our delimiter continue trim
it split it pass it into our DDoS attack
service and ddos attack service looks
like this target user agent refer get
your webview headers overwrite refer
blank your ex requested with header spin
up 100 instances of a webview and an
array loop over and inject your new web
views into your existing array make sure
you override the settings and do
everything delete all your files
everything between sessions continue
onward so now that we know how this is
being used and this step like I said
already happened but it was still fun
basically we just begin tracking this
situ non-stop and we did it over tor so
if you blocked us you know we'd be back
in 5 minutes and this allowed us to
capture a lot of attack traffic confirm
attacks against our own customers as
well as monitor real-time attack traffic
against other people that we didn't know
so while we can say hey we know this
thing's attacking us it was also fun to
say hey this thing's attacking them and
they're down ok they're starting to come
back up and now they're changing stuff
so it was pretty cool to watch I guess
would be some Freud or it was fun to
watch but it was painful to watch at the
same time
yeah phone when it's marrows yeah it's
always fun when it's not us so what did
we learn from watching the situ for a
considerable amount of time we managed
to capture over the course of well first
of all the timeline of this was it
attacked us on the weekend and by the
next weekend it was down or it was in
the process of going down and in a
little over seven days it was completely
down so 386 thousand attack commands
were observed over that course that it
was still up and running of those 386
thousand attack commands 17,000 of them
targeted a unique domain and path
combination so just like we said if they
are active they're actively monitoring
you and they're actively seeing if their
attack is having impact these guys
attacks 17,000 different things and
thousands of those same things or
different things were across the same
people you know if you were sitting over
here and they're hammering your cart and
you start putting some kind of
mitigation in place that's protecting
your cart and it starts to work all of a
sudden they start hammering your
customer service form or your ticket
system or anything else that they think
might cause impact to your your
organization of those 17,000 unique
endpoints there were only 61 domains
that were targeted
so they attacked 17,000 things across 61
organizations the targets included
travel which we know from firsthand
experience ecommerce a very large
e-commerce website named after a jungle
which is hilarious if you think about it
yeah let's attack them they have so many
servers that they give half of them away
I'm sure we can take them down with our
botnet file-sharing torrenting stuff
prawn always a hot target governments
gaming
just I want to say these things but I
can't say them so okay they they had
36,800 unique user agents overall that
were used in their attacks this includes
the randomized ones we found that if you
hit them they were basically just
shuffling that you would always get a
new unique one even if they were hitting
the same target so it was like they had
a randomization script or some kind of
function in the situ but more
interesting is that if we omit all of
those and we only look at ones that look
like real valid user agents we observed
eight thousand four hundred and ninety
two user agents that looked super legit
like it would be opera coming from
Windows XP it would be Firefox on
Windows seven it would be FreeBSD
running chrome like super legit you
would never suspect that they were
nefarious at all
the attackers were very very active in
pivoting they appeared to be just as we
were monitoring it appeared that they
were monitoring too and as soon as they
had impact and it that impact started to
go away and the the target recovered
they would pivot and start to make
changes how did this happen so basically
this happened because they were named
squatting on the Play Store there are
apps that you can get for apks or you
can get apks for that are against the
Terms of Service of Google's own Play
Store and therefore they cannot be had
so what they basically did was grab
these apps decompile them shove their
backdoors and upload them to the Play
Store under a very similar name that
would hit on a search for an ignorant
user that ignorant user would install
this application and until Google caught
on it would sit there infecting people
and then once it was pulled that was it
it would stay on that users device so
long as they did not install it how many
go look at your phone right now and you
tell me how many apps you got there that
you installed like one time you've never
looked at again that's one of these guys
so yeah that was pretty much it they
would trash their accounts they had
multiple very shady accounts the
developer names were always just like
ten character alphanumeric random and
people still would just be like I'm
gonna install this this seems good here
are some of the apps also interesting we
tried to test these in the Android
virtual device the AVD stuff and they
didn't do anything need to actually go
out buy some crappy burner devices throw
them on ADB and load these apps over ADB
via unknown sources and then once we
spun them up we were able to actually
get them to go from there we were able
to spin up throw them on Wi-Fi and
control DNS then we could trigger replay
attacks of previous attack commands and
test moving fields around changing
values seeing what this thing could do
if you looked at the permissions
required it needed full administration
permissions which what could go wrong
and it would spin up services in the
background so what does this mean this
means you got hot pockets they ran in
the background that so it didn't the app
didn't need to be running for this thing
to run as soon as you launched it the
first time it spun up a service that did
what it needed to do and that service
ran forever it would connect or attack
using whatever connection it had so
you're in your car you're driving to
work you're hopping across multiple
wireless towers you're getting new IPs
you're attacking all that time you get
to Starbucks you're ordering your coffee
you're on their Wi-Fi you're attacking
all that time you get to work you're
sitting in the conference room you're
bored you're looking at your phone your
phone's hot you don't know why you're
attacking all that time you go home
you're on Wi-Fi you charge your phone
three times a day battery's still dying
you don't know why it's a tagging all
the time so this is part of the reason
that we saw so much traffic distribution
and a lot of stuff coming out of this
thing also if you haven't tried
cheeseburger lean pockets they're
delicious do it
uh I went the wrong way take down like I
said the once we had figured this thing
out and could absolutely positively
confirm that it was an attacking source
we notified Google Google was super
responsive they began taking stuff down
immediately they identified lots of apps
they identified over 400 apps from the
same developer or at least based on
trends related to that developer and
they were able to remove those apps from
the Play Store and get them out of there
using the new Play protect features on
some newer devices they were also able
to remotely uninstall the apps from
infected devices and the really cool
part was if anybody else tried to
download them and install them from apk
mears or anything else you would be hit
with this right in the face
app can be used to perform denial of
service attacks against other systems
and resources yadda yadda yadda
please don't install this crap after we
went public it was discovered that there
were also UDP attack capabilities which
we did not see in some of the samples
that we had found upon the discovery of
that from 360 cien we did go back and
look at our 24 somethin samples and like
one or two of them did have these
capabilities we just missed it because
there was so much other stuff if you
want more about that Google that goo GL
/ - you BTR X there's a full write-up
there same deal
picking it all apart analyzing the
source code this was not just a kamae it
was a team effort it involved Google
team Comrie risk IQ CloudFlare Oracle
flashpoint Rory and they all deserve
high-fives some of the all the guys in
blue are some of the Akamai researchers
and and resources that helped including
this man right here Dave McEwen who's
too afraid to get on stage so I'm
calling him out
[Applause]
in red is miss miss Jaime Cochran she
recently passed away she was an amazing
researcher and you should definitely
google her name she was also an epic
troll a troll that was so good they
brought her on talk shows to troll
people so that's it we've got 30 seconds
Q&A go yeah
molly code why did you not use like
dexter jar JD do something so you could
actually get it back were they doing
some type of authentication are we
trying to do something that was
programmable easy to do that across all
the apps sir to be honest for me I had
never really picked apart an apk before
and when I started looking into it
apktool was the first thing that I found
and it did exactly what I needed on the
first try it got me visibility into the
source code that I wouldn't have
otherwise and that was good enough so if
there are other tools I should
definitely look into them but it was
just the first one I found and it worked
well enough for future reference so you
can feed in the apk tool to get a small
e then use Dex to jar to get a jar and
then you can get from a jar file you can
use JD GUI and actually get full Java
code although you don't have to write
your pseudo code you could actually use
these nobody should just turn that into
a single tool they should just make a
script you just do that and it grabs all
the depths and does it all yeah but
still awesome stuff thank you yeah thank
you anything else all right I think
we're all set
I made it in time did you go all right
thanks guys guys
[Music]
[Applause]