test justice justice justice justice
it's a noise you're definitely not one
to talk test hallo justice test test
test test test justice
all right yeah I mean we'll just roll
with it if it gets fixed cool it's not
no big deal all right hey guys I don't
know if the speaker is working out there
so we'll just talk really loud
sorry about that we'll try to talk loud
this is a talk that we just finally
named right before this called red
teaming the Trap House this is actually
a little bit of a background on this
this is an extended version of a talk we
did at Derby con that was called the
Trap House making your house as paranoid
as you are we've actually added a lot
more stuff to it because we kind of
realized a while back that we were going
back and forth on talks there were
essentially red teaming or blue teaming
a modern home so I'm Dave wrong meeting
we both got a bunch of certs on that fun
stuff we both work a place called R'lyeh
quest in Tampa we do manage sock
services a bunch of engineering if you
need any of that or if you're looking
for a job we are hiring yada yada yada
so now so how this whole thing started
to come around is that I made the
unfortunate mistake of buying Phillips
hue light bulbs and if you know anything
about Phillips hue light bulbs they are
literally crack right but the problem is
is that I'm in the info ii industry and
that tends to make me extremely paranoid
especially when you start talking about
IOT devices so I started to think how
can we use these home automation systems
in order to not only make our lives
easier and cooler but can they can we
make our lives more secure my can I make
my home more secure by repurposing these
systems so the basic approach to this
concept is that all devices should be
repurposed right hey if I have motion
sensors that trigger my light there's no
reason I can't use these same motion
sensors to detect motion so another
example is like smart speakers think of
your Google home that can totally double
as a siren right if you have speakers
placed all around your house
why shouldn't you use that in order to
broadcast and alert the problem with
that is that you need to have some kind
of approach to centralize all of these
different components Philips has their
own hue eco system
Samsung has a smart things eco system
Google home and Amazon have their own
API is for able to access these things
so you need some kind of central
platform to manage all of these and wait
right but the thing is is that none of
them really integrate nicely with each
other you know wink only supports
certain protocols and things and you
know you can't you don't have the
extensibility of setting up really
complex integrations with them
so I did a lot of discovery and the
platform that I settled on was home
assist and this is probably my favorite
of all of the platforms that I was
playing around with home assistant can
literally integrate with anything it's
ridiculously easy to set up I run it on
a Raspberry Pi 3 and it's easy and the
advantage I can repurpose any of these
devices sure they can completely serve
their own normal function but I can
repurpose them so this is a this is kind
of what the home assistant interface
looks like so you can see here you've
got the nav on the left hand side and
then I've got these about different
zones set up for all the different
devices in there so I have a garage
sensor in the air motion sensor in the
garage and whether or not the motion is
activated you know that's that switches
from a zero to one device tracking for
all the different devices that are
normally identified on the network and
then just different management things
for the lights I built a really ghetto
floorplan with a custom SVG editor but
you can kind of get the idea of how you
can separate your room since different
zones and then just have different
things you know have that change out so
to talk about the different components I
mean start out with the centralized
brain ready to Raspberry Pi model 3
maybe 35 dollars maybe add an extra and
20 dollars for the SD card might
a few light bulbs which I spent a
ridiculous amount of money on motion
sensors and you know the use case there
was that hey I want to walk into a room
without having it's such a light let's
also use this as motion sensors for the
home security and then you know sorted
Google Homes for Amazon echoes so that
you can you know walk anywhere and into
the room and have more Martin Gabe turn
on so for a 1600 foot square house this
is about you know what you you might run
cheap better best and really it just
depends on what kind of life you wanted
what kind of speakers do you want but
the goal is is that anything you set up
as long as it has api's and integrations
you can use whatever for notifications I
use pushover it's five dollars per
device type really simple so there's a
few core principles for building your
own IOT security system number one is
that you need your CFO buy-in that's
your significant other they need to be
bought into this because no one else is
gonna be happy about this and the prices
tend to add up quick but when you say
honey don't worry we can use this for
multiple things yeah that might not work
but so so easy to manage right you need
to be able to be accessed remotely you
need to be able to quickly view and
manage the status through mobile device
I'm not gonna sit there and teach
someone how to SSH to a Raspberry Pi
restart the services right there's
there's really no point in that so the
simpler you can make the management of
this platform the better support sending
your notifications I shouldn't you know
if someone's breaking into my house I
should be able to see that on my phone
while I'm at work right there's no
reason I need to be on the same network
get that notification be aware of people
inside the home and you know this is
kind of touches on the principle of
presence detection and how what can we
do to identify whether or not someone
that's normally and expected to be
inside the houses home or someone that's
not expected to be inside the house have
an audible siren you know that just
because I know someone's in the house
that doesn't mean that my neighbor knows
someone's in the house but once all the
noise starts to happen
they might know and then it can that
goes back to that CFO buy-in if it's not
easy enough for everyone in the house he
use it will just not evolve the way you
want it to go so his crack is still up q
bulbs my crack is this stuff if you're
in the hands-on work station stuff
they've got some SDR things don't do it
because you'll go and you'll play with
it you're like oh this list you aren't
think it's only twenty thirty bucks or
something that's what starts that's that
free he'll from there so presence
detection will get into slightly better
if you want to throw in for a seven
twenty two n a little bit better
distance for Wi-Fi stuff it is you'll
spend a little bit more money these
little Cena Bluetooth adapters are
fantastic again it's one of the rare
Bluetooth adapter you can early crazy
this is what I would personally
recommend I believe I updated the final
cost thirty one which is a USB dongle
it's received only
Cooper - one for all your bluetooth
needs the SDR games in the yardstick 1
the yardstick 1 is Michael Hoffman the
guy who does that you Bertie hack ahrefs
sub Hertz radio it runs code called RF
cat which you guys may have heard of a
guy named Alice of doom did which
basically is Python libraries do a lot
of fun stuff things and then once you
just firmly embrace that you're addicted
and you have no choice here's some other
great stuff and again you know this talk
is intended for both sides so if I'm
looking at the house as a modern day see
full time things am I going to be what
makes a particular home good target
obviously the first thing that I'm going
to look for is a thief is are there
valuables inside the home the cost of
the valuables that I'm going to be able
does this house have like a you know
sign in the front yard protected by XYZ
security that tends to kind of you know
you have to understand that I mean
there's all this
[Music]
so this is just going over some examples
of stuff people might see I did this
because a lot of times I found people
just look at Wi-Fi access points only
put much thought into it so some
examples like the top set there you
wouldn't be interested in if you're
trying break into a house because the
last couple are clear these are all cars
and the ones a bus so not too helpful
the middle one second ones there those
are actually ones that are connected to
a service provider so while that's
probably not necessarily helpful
depending on narrowing down you can
sometimes maybe know someone where they
are from geography wise like say you
know BHN secure obviously as Bright
House Networks and if you're in say New
York and see that probably it's not
someone who's local next one obviously
is hotels that makes you know that maybe
they travel a lot and then the last one
there is again some other more corporate
or larger scale access points so you
probably want to attack those like the
ruckus the ubiquity some Bluetooth
examples this is helpful both for if
you're trying to attack someone or
you're just trying to detect someone
itself these are pretty obvious what
they are like Nintendo's and stuff like
that but then if you're actually trying
to detect someone from outside this is
also helpful because for example the
scaler Rider one
those are headsets for motorcycles so
you may be detecting someone actually
outside of your home at the time if you
don't normally see that but if you kind
of look at all this information little
thought into it you can really read a
lot more info out of it and another
suggestion we've had actually in the
past is you may even want to record the
MAC addresses of your devices is almost
a secondary serial number in case your
stuff's ever stolen can't hurt you no
listing of the devices that are inside
the house but as blue suddenly you have
you're able to collect all of the
devices that are inside your house and
have an asset inventory of them based on
their MAC address some more examples
like we said as he mentioned if you see
like a lot of ZigBee you know someone's
probably into a lot of home automation
and you can pretty much assume they've
got some money so killer beez excellent
program lets you see devices in there
you basically this is a snippet of some
stuff that we found in one home that's a
bunch of automated lights z-wave well
most people think it's probably the same
is ZigBee it's a lower frequency
slightly different but you usually find
it typically more in industrial stuff
but starting at use born homes again
this is actually an alert from a door
sensor opening and closing that we
recorded so presence detection scoping
out a house kind of how do I know
whether or not people are home because
if I break into a house that people are
home this goes from burglary to armed
robbery kidnapping and I suddenly am
looking at a lot more years behind bars
so the it's important that when I break
into this home that no one's home
that being said to flip that around
managing my own you know internal IOT
network it's important to know whenever
people are home that are you know normal
users of this so that I can set certain
schedules and have certain actions
trigger like let's say whenever I come
home I have my Google homes welcome me
and cuss at me and tell me what a
terrible person I am but they do say
welcome home which is important right
but I don't want that message to play
when my significant other comes home
because if the Google homes are yelling
at her then
it's not gonna be pretty so my point is
presence detection is extremely
difficult if we rely on motion detection
it's already too late from a defensive
standpoint right because at that point
you're looking at post compromised at
the same time a motion detector doesn't
necessarily differentiate between
individuals it just says someone is here
someone's here
a typical homing traitor will probably
have a cell phone on them like let's
think about the sophistication of the
people that are freaking in your house
they probably parked in your driveway
they probably brought their cell phone
in with them and they probably are
broadcasting SSID probes they're
probably broadcasting Bluetooth probes
and if you're collecting all of that
information that's something that's
going to be useful for later so as far
as
you can also work we have that's the
great part about the package he was
showing you earlier so how did they
connect people I threw together some
scripts that basically work on top of a
program called woods by Tim tomes
essentially all you really need to do is
the stuff that would have is the stuff I
mentioned earlier mostly Bluetooth and
Wi-Fi the goal of breadcrumbs lets you
set up people to track where it can
alert on if you see a pro for certain
network or a certain MAC address it can
also do this for Bluetooth stuff as well
I ended up just using blue Hydra another
program for the Bluetooth stuff because
it was a lot passed with no code I had
written another thing I had for a while
there just for giggles cuz people get
paranoid about cells getting intercepted
is I actually have it monitoring local
cell towers just it will alert if a new
one pops up or something has changed
like that nothing's happened but hey we
live in boring times I guess so as
mentioned breadcrumbs basically woods in
blue Hydra to collect Bluetooth and
Wi-Fi probes the origination of this
really comes down to a few years ago
Jonathan and I had a boss who was
actually based out of Canada the hell
you want it's delightful but then we
kept showing up and boom he there figure
out some way to find this out that's why
I end up digging into this and it kind
of exploded into having a web interface
that shows you updates stats so you know
how that goes
I'll update the github with this newer
version but literally we wrote this at
first to get an alert so on our drive in
we knew if our boss was sitting in the
office at the time waiting for us that's
the complete reason we did this in
context of this so as far as actually
detecting people using using as an
attacker I don't want to tie anyone up
and in the state at the same time I can
use these exact same techniques to
identify whether or not neighbors are
home as well right if I take an
inventory of all the devices that are
there at say midnight and then compare
that to an inventory of all the devices
that are there save
em anything that's missing may or may
not be an indicative of a neighbor and
this is really fairly simple to do I
mean we've all done different aspects of
this I'm sure but it's just a matter of
combining this all and using it using it
to get more context and then that kind
of goes back to different ways to detect
general house uses your pattern if we
don't want to just rely on Wi-Fi there's
some other techniques that we can do for
this so one thing that we found that was
kind of fun is a lot of environments
nowadays at homes residences whatnot
have connected power which means it
could either be a device that sends out
information about your power usage so
your power company can just drive by and
collect that information or there's also
more modern ones they're getting rolled
out to some environments that are
two-way that then have abilities we need
to track your power yourself turn off
and on certain things
so am I started really surprising a long
time ago it was like I said made for
drive by meter readings a lot of I
always thought that those projects would
cost out of electric company their
statement was a lot of times meters are
in places like behind fences where there
may be dogs work hard for you to get
access to it that results in those
estimated bills that eventually get
reset and maybe get a crazy
bill so am ia MRR is the one way am I is
the two way again remote power
management alarms leak detection that's
starting to get rolled out over in Tampa
I honest I'm not sure here in Orlando in
your own area so of course you know
we're still in Florida if we went they
rolled this out about 2013 they did a
bunch of public health studies the
public service corporations the arm of
our government appeals fist up bunch of
companies utilities came in presents it
on health impacts cost and everything
and everything was great and this is if
you go to the Public Service Commission
right now this is what's on their page
talking about the data they're trying to
keep you from getting scared about it so
to me the interesting ones were these
that basically say smart meter data is
is not sending out any customer
identifiable info and it's encrypted and
sent in a way that only the utility
companies can read that
I'm not sure if that's really correct
it's very least with AMR anyone with one
of these $20 $25 RTLS jars can pick up
everything this is actual data that I
picked up as you see a little before
Christmas last year from around my house
and I'm in a multi-storey counting so if
I go up high and put an antenna I get a
couple hundred of these so I'm getting
power meters so the main company that
makes these power meters basically say
yeah the data stare but it's only what
you would see if you went and actually
read the meter as for personal
identifiable information if you just
walk by the meter once you can easily
see the meter ID the type in the model
models not hopeful for what we're doing
but walk by someone's house wants to get
that new tidy consumption rate okay so I
picked a random target I don't know who
they were near my house and their power
turned on more power than this map to
show me very simply so if I was a bad
guy what could I look at this data and
possibly use it for I know when I can
break in apparently aspersions on around
during this time print so that is on to
other stuff not getting busted this was
detecting people detecting meter this
will be quick because you guys probably
read about this by someone posting this
on TV their user blog and they responded
back and they're like well you know it's
very unlikely it's highly sophisticated
these guys did pull these things open
pull the firmware off it did a lot of
stuff that average you know bad guy the
Robie probably wouldn't do they're
saying they have it hurted
got any reports of anyone attempting
these attacks not aware of it happening
anything and other people use the same
maturity what interested me was a
comment that's one responded to that
saying that hackers have to know if you
have anything worth stealing
obviously for what we value
so and also about the whole thing with
it being really hard
my coxswain again mark I am amazing STR
stuff
he basically redid all these attacks to
the point of being on the collect like
the pin network just engaged the alarm
with this yardstick one so he dug into a
big-time faring out how it worked and
everything was okay obviously but they
have FCC it's not there but it's there
so we actually picked up one of these
motion sensors just to play with it we
found the frequency band well without
getting as smart as my costume and we
brought it up and walked in front of it
and looked and it starts hanging out so
we see it something some information
that sees motion and this is it's on the
frequency it set if you want to get
really insane this is a great tool
called the universal radio hacker that
lets you record stuff and try to
what's their but the problem here is we
didn't even really need to do this
because we see exactly whenever
someone's moving so we could tune in to
motion sensors at Solon's home and see
if we see any activity and know if it's
moving mind you this could be someone's
house or dog right so that was a little
bit of an older system and this up a mr.
John this is the story of us two nights
ago getting together to finish up it's
funny because someone actually just
mentioned the wink oh look out
I I did by a week look out and I was
like oh hey maybe I can start
integrating these different things
because what I was missing was door
sensors and I needed you know I was I
wanted sensors to notify me every time
the door open and every time the door
closed that I can monitor the state of
the doors so some wireless alarms can be
detected and bypass and found this out
the hard way
usually these types of things are gonna
be self install kits I mean you can pick
them up simply save has them linked has
them there's a lot of different ones
that exist but be more commercially
installed systems say one that ADT would
put out instead of they're moving a lot
more recently towards wireless systems
just because it's easier for them to set
up they don't have to run telephone wire
all around your house you know it's
really easy so going off of IOT alarms
like I said I bought a wink lookout I
was really excited for it released in
2007 it actually got released and I
think October so this is fairly new I
think it sells for I think I bought it
for maybe 100 but it basically comes to
door sensors a motion sensor and a siren
wink operates entirely on the V wave and
it comes with a hub each set up and then
can talk to all the different devices
now z-waves on 800 to 900 megahertz so
we looked at the system and tried to
figure out whether or not it's
vulnerable in the same way using the
killer killer Z we were able to capture
some of the packets for
different actions that were happening on
here so every time we open the front
door you can see that we captured here
and there's three separate z-wave
packets that are being broadcasted you
keep capturing these over and over again
and none of the data is actually
changing the same thing for capturing
the actual clothes now
killer Z and killer B both have really
nice features where you can actually
replay these packets you have a view
wave device I think yeah the yardstick
one does work for transmitting these
packets as well and it works very very
well so you could actually spoof opening
a door right let's say that you keep
replaying this over and over and over
and over again and you can kind of mess
with the state of the actual application
itself so you see on the right that I
have my mobile app here the door was
closed and I'm sitting there at my desk
and then suddenly I identification with
my front door opens and you know I run
down and try to check it out but
nothing's going on the door is closed
but my phone clearly says that the doors
open now imagine that you're going to
work you open your door you close your
door start walking out and then you get
a notification that your door got opened
well I got to run to work so I might
spend maybe 30 seconds debugging this
your doors open all right I don't have
the time to deal with with this right
now so I'm just gonna go ahead and go to
work now we can also spoof closed door
notifications as well right so what we
discovered is that you can actually by
sending these replay attacks you can
attack to the state of the actual wink
device so if you start spamming door
open right before you go to work then
that person's probably not gonna be they
already have it in their mind that the
system's acting up so if there's another
door open notification that happens say
later that day when someone's robbing
the house they might think about that
less now we discovered during our test
that if you spam door closed
occasionally in the right direction
winds right and the temperatures right
and you know butterflies are flapping in
Japan when you spam the door close state
you open the door a notification has
never generated if you can overpower
that device
so basically robber opens the door no
notification door still says it's closed
they close the door and now they're
inside the house and you're none the
wiser so that's really where you want to
go defense and death
right don't rely on any one component of
your system they should all be trying to
back each other up as far office layer
another thing to mention quickly about
the wink test that we did is one it
screws up the state excuse up the state
of the app so if you are that person
leaving for work you open your door you
close it if someone's there watching you
and can quickly Vince them another door
open and you look at like door open and
you look back and the doors closed I'm
going to work if we've been breaking in
your home and open the door it doesn't
generate another door open that the
person got so that last door open it
thinks it's open so it stays there until
it gets the door closed back so that's
another angle of the attack there um
this what we wanted to do is a little
bit of system defense basically we want
to protect our systems we want to know
if maybe someone is screwing with the
systems themselves the fun stuff we put
in and we want to try to collect some
data at just in case this was a brief
thought that mostly started with I
thought this would be fun to put this on
the internet and see who screws fit what
if someone's already on your network why
not model a honeypot after an IOT
devices and the great thing is the IOT
devices have a small footprint so you
don't have to get too fancy what I have
at home is an echo B thermostat so I
decided to model one after that
there's so little information that these
things that give out essentially if you
can have some honeypot that spits back
the right MAC address everything that
really an echo be another angle is
something I'm working on and it's not
even anywhere close to putting up on the
well you know we have woods for
collecting probes there's a lot of these
things that can result in a spike of
traffic and we see these attacks so if
we're already collecting y-pipe Road why
not do something similar
obviously I have no creativity so I
theoretically calling it's after 10
films thing I'm collecting all traffic
and kind of working on ways to make kind
of a historical model of what's usually
there and if it starts seeing anything
out of scope alert on it because a lot
of times really really loud but you're
not really gonna see another thing is
we're talking about
devices so we always get that up in the
slides so another level of distraction
was that these signals can get replay
for why these alarms like we show you
with the link and there's the mic
awesome inversion will simply say it's
really easy to get around this so my
thought was what would be more fun is I
can take the stuff out of my house and
randomly will you play that so someone's
outside of my house they can have alarm
there seems to be like oh god
and then he could get signals off of my
house and do the same yes but the
problem is the same method of really bad
this could result in your bill being bad
this is very illegal and it also be very
bad and the trigger makes the
unfortunate mistake of breaking in my
trap house based off all of the
automations and integrations that we've
set up in the house it should go into a
very defensive state right and what
happens during that off-site collection
of data should be pushed more frequently
so you could probably stand a really
small micro instance up in AWS or
something and then whenever the it goes
into defense mode
start shipping logs over there
immediately the thought with that being
is that if this intruder for some reason
discovers your platform and disconnects
it that's the brains of your operation
and if he destroys the device you've
suddenly lost all logs so you definitely
want to start shipping that data off
immediately we already touched somewhat
on all the different paths of collection
that you could have you could be doing
for that right so start scanning the
waves for any of the MAC addresses of
any devices that are there get the SSID
probes from all that and for all of
those devices get any Bluetooth
information does he you know if they
parked the car does that car have a
radio in it that it has a has bluetooth
can we pull that MAC address and pull
the device name from it can we pull the
device name via bluetooth of the cell
phone and we I don't know use Wi-Fi
pineapple and force them onto a network
where we can do work intrusive scans and
that's where we go into our active
collection right
the active defense if he makes the
mistake of coming into our house and
he's broadcasting SSID probes or let's
say he has a cellphone on the AT&T
network and robotica asking it were
called apt Wi-Fi
nobody would ever do that and they join
that network then you could go ahead and
port scan it start logging all the
traffic and just try to gain more
contextual information about your
attacker of course start sending alert
notifications to whoever manages the
platform or just different members of
the house so that you can start to
reacts much more quickly what I have set
up is that I have the wink siren going
off but in addition all the Google homes
turn on their volume to maximum and then
they blast out this really obnoxious
police siren and while that's happening
all of the Philips hue bulbs are
alternating between red and blue lights
and it turns into this like weird police
themed rave so Robert starts to walk in
motion sensor goes off and immediately
all the lights start flashing
red-and-blue and you hear sirens you're
either gonna be you're like really
freaked out or really intrigued either
way it's good for me there is that I
suppose that's what we need right now
you could totally do that though right
because what I was thinking was all
right now I need to wallet well the
sirens are going on I'm gonna layer in
the sound of a shot gun being cocked
rater there's just some like dogs
working any anything you can absolutely
do just to I mean you know don't get
slaughtered
so as far as different ways to notify
you I mean you know home assistant has
really really simple integration do all
that example of what look like hey
shooter got detected in your home and
I'll say recording started I'm a huge
fan of pushover because it's stupidly
easy to setup and very simple to use and
this is an example of what it would look
like on the house and then you can have
you extra set up callbacks so if you
want to take additional action and
as you can see it's actually very
straightforward to set up on the home
assistant side example with doing like
generating a message with raw curl and
this is an example of what the actual
what this notification looks like
there's other ways you can do that too
you could have a few voice calls if you
set up an Asterix server you'll need a
SIP trunk there's a bunch of providers
available I think Google Voice yeah
there's some onyx $5 set up gateway and
dave actually wrote a call some someone
say something which is just a simple
script to generate a voice message call
the number and play it mediate you need
the configured SIP trunk but let's say
that you I don't know set up your own
stingray and some reason this person's
device connects to it while they're
inside your house you just call
something someone say something called
the only phone call any all of the
phones that have connected to this
network start playing messages to it and
you know they're getting phone calls
while they're inside the house the
lights are going it just is a confusing
situation for everyone involved and
that's the goal right so there are some
off-site considerations as the attacker
and as far as like enhancing the
lockdown state of the home these are
just different ways that you can
repurpose some of the different devices
if you have a smart thermostat create
the temperature up if you're in Florida
or crank the temperature down make it
unbearable to be inside you have smart
walks start spamming block messages
block messages and signals to every door
in the house right so it's not really
gonna do much it might waste a few
seconds of their time but that's all
precious time they need in order to
start collecting more contextual
information
[Applause]
I had a I had a someone breaking in what
my brother's home and he stole a a wii-u
he made the mistake of taking the WiiU
back to his house and logged into the
logs in Netflix which had the IP address
and then cross-reference that and got
everything back that was fun but that's
kind of it you know that kind of tells
you a lot about if you could just if
you're just collecting this information
you can use that
we'll have that published some points
actually
that really doesn't yeah someone might
be able to jam one component but as long
as you're layering in as many different
things as possible that's really what
you want to go for now that's not being
said that as attackers you can't use
these exact same technique that we're
doing to smokescreen for yourself right
so while I'm breaking new house hey I
got a Raspberry Pi with the radio inside
my pocket that's broadcasting out a
whole bunch of junk a society's the
whole bunch of is that realistic for
most attackers probably but you know
right right you got bigger problems with
people like that are attacking