destinations
acting speaker there is no speech
impediment
last sentence so uh... colwell and that
you are and we have a twisted pair
pasadena co-hosts
environment now colleen when she's
supposed to be approved
but i'll tell you know i've just outside
of the league of twisted every year dot
com religiously affiliated with
incidences hundred
and just listen to her
response we are
now regroup rivers coming from hong kong
notes eleven size leon
it was legally rear
we've got eighties we show we talk about
what show wicker show gilroy
disorganization
anyone print campaign managers
without warrants visiting atlanta
pesticide
well friends everyone has a restaurant
hopefully at the same totally because i
like it you know
but uh... we've got a great let this
year so this is a second annual
helen fahey myself and
accidentally
however is that we have basically yes
the first night seven p m twice
separate fish for every
alter-ego tomorrow and then we do have a
lot more sophisticated instruments nice
weather
alabaster brightest unrepaired remind
every few days ago and agreement
addendum recommends the long-sleeved
rank in the courtroom friends right
buttoned shirt support
so uh... jetliner unfortunately another
reporter in others and of all the other
hand
their there is less
but uh... we have to move things around
a little bit quiet riot was
unfortunately attack
in captured by indigenous
the parking lot of the a_n_c_ is you've
beside her skeet shooting
was usually against inflation this
humanities
skeet shooting the assets that you know
that
uh... but anyway they processed here at
a_b_c_ any names a hit me back year but
uh... the important is that we receive a
bit so settlers are unsatisfied houston
he's using opens up for a separate space
about
immigration sprang to the ground is
actually a flip book here are my india
to brown
anti cyclones bonanza
yeah
uh...
so you might wonder why
redress of recently
and we want to have a little bit of the
not u_s_ fifty-one forces the enemy was
false
we want to preach to huntsville there
are so much the bridge
as well
we want to have
i think this year but going global
so i think our government and we talked
about taking it easy to learn here
and continue to move forward and
teaching other people
we're going to be easy cigarettes you're
on there
belize and how's everything to market
so commodity russell
says he wants on the google we want to
do make sure that you know things that
you do
affect everybody house and senate tit
for tat issue
but every piece of bad code that you
write that shit that java applet that
you wrote
there is some time one person it is a
killer and it's really the right now
that albany street gallery that you
wrote
handed back it's your fault he hasn't
been updated hostility return people all
over the world
non-western carousel scar tissue native
everyday
because you don't have right now
so
one of these are a number is that
global think local think how can you
take the things that you learn
and things that you know
and how he knows that
global change global change kristin
thoughtful person
it's your testimony so far is is our
show
please let me jump in and back
uh... yes if you know
but honestly was well
buster shows i think what we're really
nine sixty senate breath that
under the internal corporate
beginning this and communicate are
coming to remember or convert some of
the same newsletter and the bacteria
they see anything in your our prime
teams so let's hear after ara minister
couple weeks later repair or
presentation
allied candidate from seinfeld narrator
is always says seven thousand dollars
thirty did a presentation that might
help us understand that it can be
so little couple unearned remember
remember
police you
can really understand the internet
so that there might be a sentence with
practices just you're not going to get
there
that's hurting her
that's that's a lot of really know
not only three hours it yet krithika is
still a bad idea
woods but yene with their india ltd dot
was very nice com inaugural week
behind the witness
trendy