[Applause]
all right thanks everybody my name is
Gerry Hargrove I'm gonna talk today
about from zero to dev sack ops in 60
minutes now obviously I don't have 60
minutes to give this talk so I'm gonna
expedite of it I'm a Solutions Architect
at Rackspace I work with a lot of
customers who are building out new
infrastructure in the cloud in
particular AWS you can see my my twitter
handle is AWS geek my website is AWS
geek calm so you can you can tell what
kind of background I have so and I don't
have a picture of me up here you'll see
a picture of me in just a few minutes
I'll put one up there for reference but
today what I'm going to talk about is
dev sec ops and getting there very
quickly so my background is as a
developer so I was happy to see that
there were probably about 50% of people
in here who raised their hand when the
question was raised previously who's a
developer then I also saw that when the
break come about half the people in the
room just left their laptop sitting on
the on their their desk and walked away
and the other half packed them up and
secured them so I'm not sure which half
did what but I'm assuming it was us
developers who just left our stuff
sitting out so I'm gonna talk about I
have a particular perspective I'm
looking at today I'm going to go a
little bit deeper than some of the
previous talks so I'm gonna talk less
about the the why and the what and the
who and the wind although I am going to
cover those briefly and more about how
so a very practical or pragmatic
approach to devstack ops in particular
for those of you who are working in the
cloud this is based on my experience
that I've had with AWS customers as well
as a juror and GCP so before we get
started though quick show of hands how
many of you are building or securing
applications in the public cloud
so we've got about 50% of you how many
of you are doing this in a private cloud
and how many of you on-premise no cloud
at all so we've got a few so mostly
public private cloud so most of my
discussion today obviously AWS geek and
OBS geek got Tom I'm going to be talking
about AWS and practical application of
that but as I mentioned I'm not going to
leave out Azure or GCP I'll talk about
them too and give you some equivalent
examples on on all of those platforms so
let's go ahead and get started so the
question about when comes up about when
should we be doing this obviously we
should be doing this yesterday we should
all be worried about security and dev
sec ops in general before today but I
wanted to give you an example here how
many of you are familiar with this
company code spaces anybody anybody
actually work for code spaces will work
for them code spaces was a cloud-based
company a few years ago they opened
their doors they provided services for
companies you know hosting code and
project management
one day code spaces customers woke up to
this message and it was code spaces is
down and you can't you probably can't
see all the detail in that message but
effectively what the message was is
someone gained access to our account
credentials got into our AWS account and
started deleting our customers data and
then getting rid of s3 buckets and
destroying our databases and before code
spaces could react they obviously they
didn't have some best practices in place
to protect this before they could react
code spaces put this next sign up so
they were unable to recover from this
they didn't have multiple backup they
didn't have backups and different with
different vendors in different locations
they were unable to recover from this
they were unable to recover technically
because they lost data and they also
lost the trust of their customers and so
my point of this is
coming from a development background or
a developer's background I often think
well we're just being paranoid but just
because you're being paranoid doesn't
mean there's actually not somebody
they're actually coming after you so
it's good to look over your shoulder if
those if you are familiar with AWS and
AWS and ns3 you've probably seen some of
these next it's a little bit of a delay
here actually this has got a lot of
graphics in it so maybe that's the
okay so if you're familiar with AWS
you'll you've probably seen or come
across some of these new dark news
articles recently about AWS users and s3
buckets and leaving s3 buckets publicly
open and available so either AWS users
have created public buckets that they're
using for websites which is perfectly
acceptable but then inadvertently stored
sensitive information in them or they
have a private bucket that they're using
and storing sensitive information in and
inadvertently someone makes it public
and so we see these stories quite often
actually just in the last week that last
one with FedEx was just a few days
before I came here and so these these
types of incidents and breaches are
actively going on and so the next
question comes up is why well some of
this goes back to the discussions we
were having this morning about increased
security exposure through the evolution
of our software and best practices and
for many of you who have been around for
some time you and it's been mentioned
this morning that many of our systems
have evolved whether it's architecture
moving from monolithic systems to
service-oriented interior architectures
to microarchitectures or whether it's
actual systems going from bare metal
systems in our back room to VMs to
containers to functions and our
methodologies Waterfall agile C ICD all
of those have allowed us to progress and
deliver software to our customers much
more quickly than we were able to before
say 20 years ago back when I started
writing software we burnt software to a
CD we sent it off to a manufacturer they
mass reproduced it we got someone to
print the manuals we put it all into a
box we shrink-wrapped it we put it onto
a truck and then shipped it out to a
store this took six months nine months
12 months so there was really no rush
for security to get involved in too
we can actually turn software around in
a matter of minutes and so what's
mentioned earlier with that type of
speed some level of automation needs to
be in place and I spend a whole lot of
time on this but you know any time we
talk about well DevOps in general we
talk about people process and tools and
the same applies to dev Sec ups the same
fundamental changes need need to happen
as a matter of fact I think if you're
not already implementing or have some
form of DevOps culture in place that it
can be very difficult to automatically
move to dev setups so what I'm going to
talk about today is mainly on the
right-hand side of that screen so mainly
automation and tools we've we've come to
a point now in software especially when
we look micro-services architectures
container based architectures the
complexity of these systems are such now
that we can no longer do this without
automation and and so we look at what
types of things to automate and I'll
just iterate over a couple of these real
quickly auditing of systems what kind of
systems that we have out there what's in
place what our response is going to be
so automating responses in particular in
the cloud we mentioned earlier about
containers how many systems are
ephemeral now I mean just in the cloud
in general our systems are ephemeral and
so we need to be prepared to deal with
them in a way that doesn't involve
actual manual intervention analysis of
systems so looking at forensics and log
diving these are all candidates for
automation remediation as well as
reporting now I'm going to talk a little
bit about sort of response and isolation
and things like isolation and tagging
more post activity than pre activity
there are a lot of different ways to
approach this in the cloud I'm going to
focus mainly on things that we can do
after the fact detecting that something
has occurred there are ways and methods
of preventing these activities from
occurring that's a completely different
discussion about identity and access
management roles and responsibilities
user
and rolls on on your cloud provider but
where you guys start ultimately depends
on you and and your system in your team
what your budget is we've talked these
were talked about earlier today what
your schedule is what skill set your
team has what risk-averse you are what
type of risk you're able to take on and
your priorities and then ultimately the
culture of your your system the next
thing I want to cover real quickly is
who but before I do that I usually never
do this but I want to call something out
that today this week is actually my 30th
anniversary and my wife who never comes
to these conferences is sitting right
back over there in the maroon dress we
were here just just a few seconds ago I
leaned over to her and said you know
we've been married 30 years I've
embarrassed you a lot is there anything
that I couldn't do that you wouldn't be
about she says no I've seen it all so we
were actually here 30 years ago in
Singapore and now we're here we both
look exactly like that too we have not
changed a bit so I'm sorry dear I I
really wanted to do this in public too
because you know that if no one sees me
after today what happened so the the
hopefully about my wife and I but that
you know the team whether you're you
have a veritable army of roles or actual
people associated with security on your
team or you're an army of one ultimately
it all boils down to your business what
we do as developers and what we do as
security experts affects everybody in
our business and in our company like
with the code spaces example yes there
were some security issues that are
probably some development issues but
really it took the company down it
wasn't just it wasn't just the
developers and the the security team
that was affected
so I have a couple of sort of stopping
points along the way today that where I
put up questions it's really matter you
know for me to catch my breath and if
you have any questions while we're going
we could probably take time to answer a
question or two if you don't have any
that's fine I'll just roll right through
it no questions so I'll go ahead and
keep on going
again it's an opportunity for me to
catch my breath grab a drink and if you
have any questions along the way so this
is really what I came here to talk about
today and sort of the meat of this
discussion and that is how do you do
some of these things in the cloud and
specifically on AWS so I'm going to give
you some examples talk about some
services today I'm going to go at
probably another level deeper we're not
going to write code I'm not going to
give any demos but I am going to give
you some ideas for things that you could
do when you leave here today ultimately
my call the call to action at the end of
this is that you have enough information
to go out and make changes in in your
environment or do something that you
might not already be doing so this
probably dates me to how many of you
remember the Gang of Four and design
patterns all right I don't feel too old
mid 90s
so design patterns in in software
development are a way for us to sort of
amortize the cost of certain activities
or code it allows us to speak a similar
language when we're talking about
specific problems so if we're having to
redo things over and over and over we
can build a design pattern around it so
when I talk to somebody about a visitor
pattern or a facade pattern in software
development if they're familiar with the
Gang of Four doc look they could
probably that we can talk the same
language and so today what I'm going to
introduce is a simple design pattern
many of you are probably already
familiar with this it's event-driven
software and I'm gonna introduce that in
the context of security and adding some
automation to our environments so
event-driven software is really similar
you may be familiar with it and you know
maybe it's called pub/sub or you
have some other name with for it really
involves three different components
right a producer a channel or consumer
and these may be called different names
depending on where you work you might
they might be called subscribers and
publishers event managers etc ultimately
though it does really interesting in
software it allows us to decouple one
end from the other and that means that
we can vary both of those so if you
think about you know micro-services
architectures that's a lot of what
that's about is decoupling these
components so they can vary from one
another so you can have different
development teams different languages
they can scale differently so an
event-driven software imagine in a an
event or a message occurs that one end
the producer produces it hands it off to
a channel the nice thing about this is
the producer doesn't need to know about
the consumer on the other end so it
doesn't have to worry about
subscriptions doesn't have to worry
about retries doesn't have to worry
about exponential back-off some case of
failure the channel manager the event
manager handles that and can deliver
that to the customer so that or the
consumer so the consumer can subscribe
to producer events very easily this also
means that it's very it's super easy to
broadcast that out to multiple consumers
again the producer doesn't have to worry
about any of the details of that and
this translates very well to
event-driven security we can use this
same type of model in public cloud and
as a matter of fact the providers all
provide infrastructure that allows us to
do this very easily so in an
event-driven security model say for
example we wanted to do something like
this on 8 FS what are some of the
components that use so on the producer
side AWS provides a whole laundry list
of event producers if you're familiar
with AWS services you probably recognize
some of these all of these can be become
part of an event-driven security system
and produce events that you can act on
one in particular that
I'm going to spend some time on today is
AWS cloud trail so for the AWS users in
the house how many of you are familiar
with cloud trail no your arity with it
good so I'll talk about it briefly I'm
not I won't go into a whole lot of
detail that's that's really not the
point of this session but just to get
you somewhat familiar familiar with it
for those of you who aren't familiar
with AWS so all interaction with AWS or
for that matter GCP here as you're
ultimately goes through an API so you're
making an API call to individual servers
or services in that cloud platform in
AWS specifically whether you log in to
an AWS console online through your web
browser or you write an application that
uses one of the AWS SDKs you've got a
ruby app or you've got a go app or what
have you or using the AWS command-line
interface if any calls in to the AWS
system that interact with your resource
go through that it results in an HTTP
request that then goes through API Cloud
trail is responsible for capturing all
of those API events in AWS so you can
imagine this big bubble around all of
your AWS infrastructure for anybody to
gain access to it or make any changes to
it they have to make an API call cloud
trail is there to capture that now so
just kind of walking through what
happens a user logs in say to the
console they make a change they go to an
s3 bucket and change the permissions on
it that ultimately results in a call to
an AWS API that event that API call as
long as along with metadata associated
with that call is captured by Cloud
trail Cloud trail then takes all of that
information and aggregates it all up
into a log file and pushes it over to
and s3 bucket it's important to point
out here that that this is not a
real-time activity this is very commonly
used on AWS for doing you know forensic
analysis of events or something after
the fact this can take on the order of
minutes to to get that information into
s3 once it's in s3 anyway not familiar
with s3 I should ask that question first
I said sometimes it seems so it's AWS is
object storage system in the cloud once
it's there though you can use other AWS
services like Athena like Maisie
redshift all of those to actually look
at that data and look at those log files
and start doing forensic analysis or get
extracting information from it a cloud
trail event itself might include
information like this that information
includes the event source so what
service generated this event in this
case ec2 elastic cloud compute the event
name was start instances so someone
tried to launch a an ec2 instance in the
cloud and there's the region it came
from and the source IP address of the
person who initiated the request now
there's a lot more information than that
included in an event but just to give
you an example of what one looks like
JSON data structure very very
straightforward and simple to process
so now that we have a producer
identified in the form of AWS cloud
trail let's look at what sort of the
channel is on AWS on any of you at that
channel is AWS cloud watch events so
that's that component that sits in the
middle of producers and consumers
manages you know ingestion of events
manages subscriptions by consumers and
then delivers that event down to those
consumers so near real-time event stream
I call that out because none of this is
actual real-time that there is this is
an asynchronous operation this is this
can happen much quicker than pushing it
to an s3 bucket and reading it after the
fact but this gives you much closer to
real-time than than any other message so
AWS cloud watch events routes those
events to the subscribers to it and as I
mentioned previously you can have one or
more multiple subscribers to these
events so if you wanted to daisy-chain
or do things in parallel based on a
particular activity in your system you
can do that using cloud watch events and
just a little more detail to the
previous slide about you know what's
included in a cloud watch event here's
another example some generic information
that's included in all of them for
example the account ID the user name
associated with it
so you can imagine using this
information to go in and say give me a
list of all of the AP API calls made by
Jerry over the last 24 hours so it gives
you a real keen insight into what's
going on in your system and what a
particular user or users have been doing
so that was pretty straightforward we've
got cloud trail set up on AWS we're now
going to use cloud watch events so when
cloud trail produces an event we're
gonna set cloud watch events up cloud
watch events it allows you to filter and
say okay I want this EC I want this
particular service and I want this
particular API I want that to trigger an
event so what's actually going to
consume those events who's the consumer
on the right-hand side on AWS another
laundry list of AWS services that can
consume these events you may recognize
many of these Kinesis ec2 code build
step functions you can send this off to
any of these services to do a lot of
different things if you just want to
send a notification out you can use
simple notification service if you want
to queue events up in a queue for later
processing you can do that one of the
things that's super interesting in an
event-driven architecture is AWS lambda
so a DFAS lambda is AWS as functions as
a service offering so it facilitates
serverless computing allows you to very
easily write code and have it executed
when you run it executed but you don't
have to deal with all the overhead of
spinning up a VM or an ec2 instance
maintaining the operating system
it simply executes syour your code in
response to an event and you only pay
for that when your code is running as
opposed to spitting up an ec2 instance
and sending all these events to peers
paying for that ec2 instance as long as
it's up and running serverless computing
allows you to only execute code and be
charged for it when when that code is
actually running
alright so that was easy
AWS we've now got a cloud trail
generating advanced we've got cloud
watch events taking those events
filtering them and then for to them off
to consumers in this case AWS lambda so
that's our AWS version of an a simple
event-driven security system and the one
that I'm going to use to show a a couple
of examples going forward before I do
that again if anybody has any questions
or comments happy to feel a couple of
short ones now if you have them raise
your hand if you do go ahead and we'll
bring a mic over to you okay go ahead
I maybe use I didn't hear you very well
so you might have to use the mic sorry I
was
I was just gonna ask it looks like a lot
of setup based on the number of tours
you presented and the number of
different types of events you'll have to
process would your recommendation be to
use a tool on top of these event streams
I you definitely could I think that once
you grow beyond a couple of simple event
events that you want to handle you may
want to have something else in place to
orchestrate all of those and there there
actually may be tools that do some of
this out there already but I could
definitely see as it becomes more
complex you know beyond looking for the
couple of examples that I'm going to
show today then it becomes you know just
managing all of that infrastructure and
again having a tool or some way to
automate management of that is going to
be beneficial so I think I think the
answer is yes once you grow beyond a
simple two simple examples all right
cool all right thanks any others
all right so let's let's actually walk
through an example and here's a simple
example really some a real clear
specification notify somebody when cloud
trail logging is disabled now there's
some context here that I want to give to
you out trail is the service that we're
going to be using that's capturing API
calls on AWS cloud trail hasn't always
existed as a matter of fact it was only
introduced on AWS just a couple of years
ago and by default it is off and so it's
super important and because cloud trail
is such is so useful in any type of
security system that you're building
that cloud trail actually be up and
running
now the reason AWS doesn't turn it on I
should say doesn't turn it on by default
for accounts it's just for backwards
compatibility for new accounts that new
AWS accounts that are created as of
probably six months ago it's turned on
by default but users still have the
ability to turn it off and so one of the
things that we want to protect against
someone coming in and disabling our
prime method for gathering security
information API calls now obviously as I
mentioned before the first way is to
prevent it from happening in the first
place so setting up users and roles
Identity and Access Management using
that to establish lease privileges so
that people can't actually turn an off
button you may have a case where you
need to have somebody with that
permission and you want to be notified
when they do it so let's look at an
example that shows how do you use the
system to do that all right so walking
through this step one somebody a user
logs into the system that could be an
actual user going through a UI or it
could be an application with a set of
credentials that has access to this
system that interaction with the cloud
trail API so that user is going to
actually go to the cloud trail service
and say execute the stop logging
function
that interaction with cloud trail is
going to be captured by cloud trail
itself so cloud trail is going to
capture that event and then is going to
send it off to cloud watch events
because we have set up a cloud watch
event source and this is probably a
little hard for you guys in the back of
the room to see but setting up a cloud
watch event source is really as simple
as saying ok I want to watch for events
associated with the cloud trail service
in this case and specifically I want to
I want to be notified when someone
executes the stop logging function so
you see at the bottom of that section
aide there we set that up next
once that event is captured by cloud
watch events we want to execute a lambda
function and I've got a real quick
sample of a lambda function here it
could be really as simple of this as
simple as this here's a python function
that gets executed each time one of
those event occurs and you can see at
the top of the function I'm grabbing
some information out of the event in
this case just the region and I want to
put that into a message and send it off
to a slack channel for example and so
I'm this this could be as simple as it
is right we want to do this one thing we
want to do it well we're going to send
it off to a slack channel and notify
somebody so once we've got that then
we'd go back into our cloud watch events
we've set up the source of the event now
we want to set up a target and again
probably a little small for you guys in
the back but setting up a target is
really just a case of selecting that
lambda function that exists and saying
whenever this source event occurs send
that event to this lambda function and
you can send the event in a couple of
different forms depending on what you're
going to do ultimately though you can
send the entire event the entire JSON
data structure and your lambda function
can do what it would like with that
extract
whatever information now I go in or my
user or application goes into the cloud
trail sort of stepping back in time a
bit and disables cloud trail I went
through the UI here that then triggers
the function we walk all the way through
the chain it triggers the lambda
function lambda function gathers all the
information from the event packages up a
message to send to our slack channel and
voila there we see this in our slack
channel hey somebody disabled cloud
trail in u.s. West too and I did just a
simple example here just to demonstrate
how you could do it it's not any more
difficult than that you could you know
package up whatever information you
wanted you might need to go out and pull
in some context about the events and
metadata about the event but this is
really a real simple example just to
demonstrate how you would do it
I mentioned earlier the use of simple
notification service as one of the
targets for an event and symbol
notification service is a pub/sub
messaging service provided by AWS act in
in my developer so right now I work as a
Solutions Architect now as a developer I
worked at AWS and this is the service
that I worked on so it allows you to do
pub/sub messaging so you can set up
topics you can have individual endpoints
that subscribe to these topics you can
do massive fan outs with this service
mobile notifications at cetera but it's
also another interesting way to capture
events and send them out so we change
our event-driven security architecture
just slightly replacing lambda on the
right side with Amazon SNS and then we
walk through almost exactly the same
steps as we did before and you'll see
this pattern occur in a couple slides
again so it's very similar garde --less
of where we're doing this so again we go
in we set up an event source for cloud
watch events configure it with the same
event information then we want to send
it off to SNS so we go back to cloud
watch events we set up a target in this
case instead of it being a lambda
function now we specify an SNS topic I
did I took some of the event and pulled
out in this case the user and the region
and I'm going to send out a simple
notification via email to whoever
subscribes to this event saying hey
jerry disabled cloud trail in this
specific of eat in this region so go
back disable cloud trail through the
console or through the api and an email
gets generated the SNS is notified with
that event it pulls that information out
packages it up into an email
you know in a matter of seconds I get an
email notification in my inbox jerry has
disabled this region so I'll stop right
there that's a quick example of what you
can do on AWS with cloud trail with
cloud watch events and with lambda
anybody have any questions or comments
anybody actually tried or done any of
this before all right I don't see any so
we're gonna go ahead and roll right
through
so this is what our event-driven
security architecture looks like on AWS
it's cloud trail it's cloud watch events
its AWS lambda this is a pretty well
proven architecture I've used it other
AWS users that I've worked with have
used this simple architecture it turns
out that all of the cloud providers
provide similar service because they've
matured to the point when I say all I
mean the top three or four if you
include AWS GCP as your poly Baba - to
some extent all of them provide these
basic services the functionality that
allow us to very easily build the same
architecture out regardless of what
public cloud that we're on if we look at
GCP Google Cloud they provide a similar
set of services to the ones that I
described you know as opposed to Cloud
trail we have stackdriver log where we
can extract API calls and information
about user interaction with the system
we can set a cloud pub/sub to establish
and act as the the manager in the center
so it will manage all of the
subscriptions ensure events are
delivered to consumers and then we have
cloud functions so that's GCPs functions
as a service offering and the
architecture then this you know it's
almost as though I just replaced icons
and names in here because that's exactly
what I did it looks and behaves almost
exactly the same on GCP as it does on
AWS you have stack driver logging acting
as the producer you have cloud pub/sub
acting as the channel and ultimately
cloud functions as the consumer so in
this generic architecture it looks very
much the same so let's look at a quick
example using GCP then so going back to
our first example let's send a slack
message when
an event occurs using GCP now this is a
little bit different than the AWS
example in the AWS example I wanted to
know specifically when a user had
disabled cloud trail there's no such
there's no cloud trail in GCP as a
matter of fact you don't have the
ability to turn off exact driver logging
so this is just a generic event on GCP
how you would do that it turns out it's
almost exactly the same as on AWS so a
user interacts with the system one of
the Google Cloud api's that in turn
generates an event of some form that is
captured by SAC driver logging we can
set up filters that then send filtered
events and messages to cloud pub/sub
cloud pub/sub then you can configure to
deliver these message to consumers in
our case we're going to deliver it to
cloud functions ultimately then we can
do whatever we'd like they're sending
messages is a simple example you can
send this notification out to your
existing applications or software
whether were there on-premise or off
prevalence in the cloud or off the cloud
you can send it wherever you'd like in
our case I just wrote it quick
JavaScript function that did a
notification to a slack channel exactly
the same on AWS so you can you get the
same types of information and can
the same types of notifications our
regardless of the platform that you're
on or execute the same you execute
arbitrary code in response to a
particular function so end-to-end it
looks like this cloud API stack driver
logging cloud pub/sub cloud functions to
slack this is the GCP version of what I
described earlier in event-driven
security for AWS so looks exactly the
same just the names have been changed if
we sure we see something very similar
very similar services very similar
functionality in replace instead of sack
driver logging or cloud trail now we
have a resource manager which is what
you interact with to administer your
resources in Azure and that captures
those activities that you take with it
you can then pipe those activities over
to Azure event grid this is something
that's actually new in the last couple
of months with Microsoft but it helps
glue all of this together you can do
pub/sub you can do fan-out whatever
you'd like with Azure event grid you can
send those events from resource manager
event grid set up subscriptions to event
grid and then send all of that out and
then you have Azure functions which
allow you to exit code execute code in
response to an event again very similar
similar that you know I'm going to show
you this the the high-level model I'm
not going to walk through another
example because they all end up being
very similar there may be specific
events or events that are particular to
the platform that you're on whether it's
AWS or GCP or or asher but it all looks
very similar so before I go on I've got
another example I wanted to show real
quickly but any questions or comments at
this point I can probably answer one or
two on the way
all right cool we'll go right through it
so early on one of the things I showed
was s3 so this is this is a particular
pain point with me in that in order for
these stories about s3 to occur someone
has had to have done something or taken
some action to make their s3 buckets
publicly available or changed an
attribute on them and it's very simple
for you to detect number one that that's
occurred and then take some action using
this simple architecture that I've that
I've shown today and oh really it looks
just like this it's very similar to what
we've already talked about on AWS
someone interacts with an s3 bucket or
an object in an s3 bucket ultimately
they're going to call the put object or
put object Akal API calls on s3 that is
captured by AWS cloud trail so anytime
anybody interacts with those services
cloud trail captures it we can set up
cloud watch events specific to that s3
bucket can be specific to resources
within that bucket and have it trigger
an AWS lambda function just like the
other examples it's exactly the same the
configuration is the same the details
about what you want to do are what
ultimately is different so in this case
we can actually tell AWS lambda to take
that API call if it's in a bucket of
interest to reset the permissions on it
such that it's not publicly available
and then potentially notify somebody
again this is happening after the fact
so it's reactive you'd still want to put
other practices in place to prevent
somebody from doing this initially but I
more often than not this is happening
accidentally someone with permissions is
making the change exposing the bucket or
they're putting a an object into a
bucket that shouldn't have been there
anyway
so to kind of step back and give you
sort of a big picture I wanted to stop
and summarize here and and go over the
things that we've talked about so
event-driven security on this slide I
show all of the different permutations
of it depending on whether you're on AWS
or whether you're on GCP or whether
you're on Azure each of the cloud
platforms public cloud platforms has
similar infrastructure and similar
services that allow you to to do very
similar things on them they've all
matured to a point now where you can't
actually do these very simply no longer
do we have to whole four events prior to
these services being in place it was
common to see us polling for activity in
our public cloud and then once we saw an
activity occur taking some action based
on that now all of the cloud providers
provide some form of event source that
allow us to react to these changes and
we can use these services that I've
described here stepping up and looking
at what we talked about this is really
the high-level view of the activity that
I walk through today users interact and
specifically in specific to AWS users
interact with AWS through an API of one
form or another every interaction goes
through an API that API can be captured
by AWS cloud trail you can do a couple
of things with cloud trail you can by
default that information goes through an
s3 bucket I didn't talk a lot about what
you can do there but other than to
mention there are a lot of tools and
services that you can use on AWS to
actually mine data out of that bucket
who's been using what API is you can run
it through machine learning you can do
all kinds of AI on that information to
mine data out of it you can use tools
like Macy or or redshift but you can
also send that information and set up
custom activities based on those events
so we set up cloud watch events to
filter these activities and then we set
up
consumers of those events whether it's
SNS to send out simple notifications
when an event occurs or lambda2 execute
code when to execute custom sets of code
to interact with internal or external
systems this is a super flexible system
that allows you to really get your feet
wet really quickly and it's really easy
to set up so to close I want to leave
you with a couple of items number one
for those of you who are AWS consumers
and I don't think I've broke it out how
many of you of those who are in public
cloud how many of you are using AWS how
about GCP Google how about a sure so
that's roughly the what I would
typically see you know the majority
using AWS then GCP in the nashor but it
really varies greatly if you're using
AWS then this is this is really for you
if there's one thing you take out of
this talk today is is go back to your
office and make sure cloud trail is
enabled if it's not enabled on your AWS
account and a breach occurs then you
really have no effective way of doing
forensic analysis on this unless you
have some other system already set up
number two
based on you know what's been in the
news lately for you get this specific
day WS go back and check your s3 buckets
really make sure that if you have a
public X s3 bucket and there are lots of
reasons to have public s3 buckets you're
hosting a static website put it in a s3
bucket and make it public you have to do
that but make sure that number that
you're not storing sensitive information
in that bucket also look at buckets that
are designated as public and make sure
that you're not storing sensitive
information in there third
regardless of what platform you're on
even if you're not in
a public cloud start looking at building
out an event-driven security framework
this allows you to begin automating some
of your infrastructure and it makes a
leave for many companies especially
those who have an army of one focused on
security to jump in and start automating
some of this infrastructure finally and
this is my hope that after this
conference I don't have to update that
slide with new news stories stay out of
the news this is this is really the big
one because it's it's as soon as there's
an s3 bucket that's exposed it ends up
in the news and I don't want to update
that slide anymore so that's it for me
today I appreciate all of you coming and
sitting through this talk the questions
and I'd like to open it up now I don't
know how much time we've got left one
minute one minute okay
so anybody have any questions on what I
presented today any comments you're
using it already great stuff raise your
hand we'll bring a mic over to you
I don't see any I saw one right here
so it's a no-brainer if you don't secure
your s3 buckets right as you shown so
can you give you an example of the
skillet you're running these queries
probably the events which will ensure
mean Rackspace or anything how are you
managing the you know notifications
let's say if you have a big
infrastructure you were born to get a
lot of noise and then how you are
managing that noise yeah so I this kind
of goes back to an earlier question I
think where it's once you get to scale
this this works for sort of that one-off
let's get our feet wet but once you get
up to scale then you have to have
infrastructure around that to start
managing it and and you're right
false dealing with false positives all
of the same types of topics that you
would deal with normally so this allows
you to get in there and start
experimenting with it and start using it
and and what I found and and where I
most often see this type of architecture
is when I'm working with AWS customers
who are who just don't have anything in
place right it's like I don't have
anything I I could barely secure my
application now you want me to secure my
infrastructure as well so this at least
gets them moving in that direction but
here you're absolutely right once this
scales out you have to have some sort of
infrastructure or some sort of tooling
in place to manage all of that
any other questions
well I'd like to thank everybody who
came I'd like to thank my wife for
putting up with me and thank all of you
and the presenters thank