[Music]
and I brought my candies so questions
after this talk you get a candy he's in
charge he's got them except this one
okay so this talk so welcome back I hope
you had a delicious lunch oh my god the
food here is amazing
I can't even believe how well had been
said anyway okay let's talk about the
talk so pushing left like a boss so I
wrote this talk so I was a software
developer and then I switched into
security and I wrote this talk because
this is all the stuff that I wish
someone told me four years ago at the
beginning I had to figure this out had
to figure out what the activities were
that you could do as part of
applications security I am I felt like I
was kind of stumbling around blind in
the dark and so I made a talk that is
just this is the foundation of app sack
this is the stuff that I feel we should
all know this is the stuff I wish every
developer knew and so let's start okay
so first of all I'm gonna explain what
pushing left is and I feel like you'll
already know but I really want you to
know it when you go home so if you
imagine the system development life
cycle or sdlc as I like to call it
written out on a piece of paper the
further left you go oh no the further
left you go the earlier you are and
you're the earlier you are let's let's
do my little there we go
the earlier you are right so security
would like to be invited to the party a
little sooner in fact I would like to be
invited to every single part of your
SDLC so the security is addressed the
whole way through I'm sorry is my hair
touching the mic
so I put it up this morning okay
we're gonna come back to the slide later
because I've heard you need to hear
things three times to remember it and
you already heard it at least once today
so we will come back to it but I just
wanted you to all know so I'm gonna
refer to pushing left over and over
again so you know what I'm saying
when I used to go see talks they would
always have this Who am I slide and I
never understood why they had it until I
had to write one the reason for this
slide is to try to prove to you that I
am qualified to give this talk it's a
please please please consider my ideas
please listen please consider doing them
at your office so with that as of Monday
I am a senior cloud advocate at
Microsoft and I'm so excited to be there
and I'm an application security
evangelist I really like talking about
apps tech I will bore you to tears with
it if you let me I'll just go on and on
I'm the chapter leader of a wasp and
Ottawa and I also started an open source
a wasp project called dev swap with my
friend Nicole Becker where we make
crappy DevOps things and then show
people how to hack them and show them
how to secure them so it's kind of cool
so far we have a bunch of vulnerable API
it's but we're planning all sorts of
interesting things for the future
and I've been being paid to be geeky for
over 20 years I started developing
software at the young age of 16 and
basically the point is is my goal is to
try to make software like to try to make
IT the easiest way to do something the
most secure way to do the same thing I
want secure to be a lot easier
so let's talk about this the first
couple slides are going to be a
refresher for most of you so it's the
state of affairs as we see it and the
reason why I'm doing this it's gonna be
like two three minutes long it's really
short but I'm doing this to make sure
we're all at the exact same level
because well some of you are experts and
have worked in apps like forever some of
you this might be your first app tech
conference this might be your first
foray into this and I don't want to lose
anyone in the audience so please be
patient with me for the next two minutes
so you've been hacked we are hearing
about this constantly in the news
constantly constantly but like someone
else said this morning up to 90% of all
of those breaches are caused by
vulnerabilities in software and this is
a serious problem and we aren't focusing
our energies on this as I feel we should
so I don't feel Security's looking the
wrong way I feel like they're just maybe
not doing the 360 I would like I feel I
see a lot of teams where they're
focusing on the perimeter and they're
doing an awesome job at it will really
go with firewalls now they're focusing
on patching awesome extremely important
they're doing enterprise level security
like taking away all those fun
permissions like your admin on your
desktop to lock things down and make
things more secure and all of that is
great but I feel like a lot of security
teams are missing knowledge about how to
make secure software and if you work
somewhere and they are making software
we want to be secure
so what is application security or OPSEC
for short so here I have it's the art of
making software secure I joke that it's
something that the security team wishes
the developers would take care of for us
and then it's something that the
developers it's the security game which
developers would take care for us and
the developers are often unaware of they
don't have time for it's not part of
their actual job responsibilities
officially there's no spot in their
project where they're supposed to be
doing this and then we end up with it
being kind of in the cracks in between
and that's where application security
comes in so we are that part in-between
we're like the bridge between the
developers and the security team so that
we actually make secure software another
thing I see so as someone who did some
consulting doing penetration tests I get
called in at the last minute they've
been making this app for eight months or
nine months and they call me in the
right tanja could you come in next week
and do some tests because we're
releasing in two weeks that is not when
you want to call me you want to call me
away before I mean I look cool don't get
me wrong so I come in no one's looked at
security the whole time and it's like a
shooting fish in a barrel I look amazing
like I found a hundred things but I'm a
lot less concerned from a professional
standpoint with looking cool as I am
with like actually making sure you
release a secure app because if I find a
design flaw right like a logic flaw in
your app like things need to change you
can't do that in a week or two you know
I need time to do the testing anytime to
write the report I can't come to you the
night before and then make you stay up
all night fixing it like it's gonna be
bubble gum and duct tape it's not gonna
be good right so I see a lot of
penetration testers being called in at
the last minute and I have also seen
some places aren't doing any security
testing like places that you use their
websites and they're just like oh we
don't have budget for that we didn't
have time to do a scan like they just
don't even do a scan and they just
release it to the Internet and they're
like I hope it's okay this is not a good
security plan so let's continue so who
knows what this is CIA this is the
reason why the security people have jobs
confidentiality availability and
integrity of your systems and your data
right this is why if we get paid awesome
when I give this talk to developers no
one puts their hand up I feel like if
you like security people are really good
at being discreet we're really good at
keeping secrets and hiding the things
that we should but when we're supposed
to promote things and tell people things
and share that that's a weakness for us
because we're so used to trying to hide
everything and the fact that I give this
talk I've given this talk at least
thirty times if not 40 and I am so lucky
if one or two or three software
developers put their hands up they need
to know why we're bothering them this is
why I hustle you if your application has
all this under control I will not bother
you I will be your best friend right so
I feel we need to learn to communicate
more what developers what we need from
them okay so with that one more time
pushing left is when you start security
earlier specifically riah at the
beginning and all the way through I'm
gonna give you an example to explain why
pushing left is important so it cost
less and you will do a better job of
security if you push left let's say
you're building a house so you and your
spouse you've been saving up forever
and you're building your dream home this
is really great
oops I had a timer set but I paused it
Mike how can I be at sixteen seconds so
you're building a house you and your
sweetheart you planned it forever
and you know they're just at that the
finishing phases they're putting the
handles on the cupboards you know
they're they're putting in the windows
you're gonna put up drapes soon you're
really close to being done and then your
spouse says oh honey maybe we should
have put in more bathrooms we only have
one and we have seven kids mmm you
should have thought of that threat model
that's a lot of bladders with one
bathroom to share this is a design flaw
right so this this isn't a bug which is
like a problem with the coating that
could be changed later this is a flaw
this is your design so what are you
gonna do maybe you're gonna sacrifice a
walk-in closet and turn it into a
bathroom and it's awkward because you
have to go through someone's bedroom to
get to it right maybe you're gonna have
to lose a whole room for this but if you
had done this at the beginning you know
you're mapping out the house and you're
like you know what maybe we should get
three bathrooms because we have so many
people and then you could plan it it
would be better it first of all would be
way cheaper right your project would
actually show up on time and it would be
great the design would be good instead
of duct tape on the side right so this
is why we should push left so now you're
probably like okay so we're going to
push left so what is this like a boss
part if you want to push left like a
boss in my opinion you need to start an
application security program you need to
formalize your steps so let's talk about
when application security program can be
so I really like food I guess I've
already mentioned food once so far so I
organized my slides into food so that
you understand what I mean so in the
following slide I'm gonna explain to
what I feel the main courses the things
that you should be able to do if you
have a formal AB SEC program if you work
somewhere and it's a smaller place you
know you only have ten people on your
whole IT shop maybe you can't do all of
this maybe you need to hire out
sometimes you don't need to do all these
steps for every single app but if you
work in an enterprise I really feel you
should have the capability to do these
things or hire out for these things when
it's important so let's look at the main
the main tours Bulmer ability
assessments and scans so I would like to
explain right now that a vulnerability
scan is not the same as a vulnerability
assessment and I've had to fight this a
lot in my city where they're like oh
could you just go to a VA in the next
hour like do you want me to run a scan
is that what you're asking for because I
can run a scan in the next 20 minutes
for you but if you want a vulnerability
assessment I mean I need some time so a
vulnerability scanner is an automated
tool that will go and find all the
low-hanging fruit for you in your app
but it won't find logic flaws it won't
find weird obscure things people
estimate that finds around 30% of
problems you need to fix all of those
things because vulnerability scanners
are really really easy to use and that
means any idiot can find it in your app
so you need to find it and then fix it
well vulnerability assessment is where
you need to use your noggin you need
someone with some security experience
and background to go through each of the
different things in your app to make
sure all the security controls that are
supposed to be there are there and that
they work correctly to make sure it's
the business logic can't be abused so
that's doing the opposite of what it
should be
etc threat modeling
I'm gonna go into each one of these a
little bit more as we continue the talk
but threat modeling in my opinion for
developers anyway is a brainstorming
session between security developers and
the business about what the risks are
that face your application and how you
can make sure that you've defended
against them we'll get into this a bit
more oh wait wait
secure code reviews and or static code
analysis so secure code review is a
manual type of effort and it can be
coupled with static code analysis which
is an automated effort where it purses
through your app and finds things that
things might be a problem code review is
important I know that it's not fun it's
not going to make me popular to say but
it's really really important for quality
and the last one is penetration tests
which again are not quite like a VA a
vulnerability assessment you're going to
find what the vulnerabilities are but
with the penetration tests you want to
exploit them you want to see how far you
can get you want to see if you can
actually steal all the stuff from the
database but with a VA I'm just like I
injected some SQL I paused your database
I'm sure that this worked I don't need
to seal the crap I can get in the
damaged I can do it prove there's a
problem let's just fix it
penetration testing is so great if you
want to shock management into agreeing
to sign things for you there is nothing
like sending a proof of concept like I
have definitely sent an email before
click on this link boss you've won an
iPad and then it might prove of concept
is in there it's not a good way to get
popular make friends but it is a good
way to bring attention to why you need
some changes in your organization all of
these things apply to not only custom
homemade apps but it applies to cots
products so if you're gonna do this huge
implementation of SharePoint awesome you
should test it and make sure it's
properly hardened because just because
the product is good does not mean all
the things you did to it it's still good
right so please don't think because it
came from
like an awesome company that it's always
bulletproof you definitely want to check
that it was put in the right way and
changes haven't been made that are
damaging okay so who knows what this is
this is the Canadian national dish yes
it's pitting so this is we take hot
fries and then we put cheese curds in it
and we pour hot gravy so that melts the
cheese curds into the fries so that you
can have 3000 calories in just one city
it's so delicious I really like it it's
a really good on a cold day we have to
put on weight and winter will die but
seriously I will I love gravy and so
these are extra things that you can add
to your application security program so
that's even better
right so above above just the main stuff
so you could start a developer education
program right like if you have a
knapsack team with five people maybe one
of you doesn't mind public speaking or
is willing to endure it right give
lessons on things that there are
problems with like we heard this morning
if you could get some metrics on what's
going wrong like if you see a law of
cross-site scripting do a deep dive into
cross-site scripting it's awesome they
will definitely appreciate it right you
can also do like workshops on things
bring people in for lunch and learns
just educate your developers some of
them won't show up but some of them will
and it's so great when you get their
attention
you can also do
secure coding standards so tell them
what you want tell them what you need
tell them what you expect from them you
know like if you're if your app has a
file upload here's the list of things I
expect from you you know first you need
to obviously scan it from malware I
don't know if you saw but the Canadian
government released a free tool to scan
your files from malware and then they
take a sample and add it to our base so
that we can warn other people about it
it's free it's called assembly-line if
you want to try it so if you're if
you're gonna upload it to something
maybe you should scan it with that right
and if you have a paid product scan it
with both like make sure it's okay and
the list goes on file uploads are risky
risky business but tell them what you
expect from them and then you might do
it responsible or coordinated disclosure
program I know a lot of places do really
really fancy versions of this but in my
opinion this is a lot like the the thing
in airports where they say if you see
something say something right so give
the public and give your employees
especially a place to report security
issues right give them just an email
address if you find a problem please
send it to us great and then make sure
you read it and you look into the things
90% of the things that are reported are
gonna be crap this is the fact or it
won't make sense and you'll you'll feel
like you're wasting time but that's 10%
where someone's like oh by the way I saw
your data for sale on the dark web for
$50 it's really good to know these
things right and if you don't have a way
for them to report it to you people will
do things like send it to your info at
your company name dot whatever and those
people will look at it and not
understand what it is and probably
delete it probably won't get to you or
it will in six months or they'll post it
on Twitter or reddit or someplace like
that and embarrass your company there's
so many
different things and I would so much
rather someone tell me instead of
telling the media so I can fix it the
last one here is creating a secure code
library and or other reference materials
or creating custom tools for your
developers I I heard about this app set
Kali this guy was talking about how they
didn't want people to use the md5 hash
anymore because it's insecure so they
put a wrapper on it
so whenever a developer used it it would
rename itself to really insecure md5
hash function usage went down by 95
percent just being passive-aggressive
I've worked at places where we make a
secure templates oh it's so great I
didn't have to think I just used it and
we had a secure coding library of
snippets that were secure coding things
that we'd already had pen tested really
thoroughly examined so I know it's a if
I could just yank it and drop into my
code it was awesome sometimes I told
security people about this and they're
like great I'm gonna go in the code
library and do this stuff and I would
like to inform you that the code library
is like a woman's purse you do not put
your hands in it without permission it
belongs to the developers so you need to
ask them their permission to make an
area for you don't just be like we're
gonna do this we're security this is
gonna make you enemies it's a woman's
purse you ask permission or ask them to
put it in for you ask them to take care
of it that's even better and then you
can give them examples of things that
you can put in it okay let's go on to
the next slide this is the desert mmm
this is extra special things for extra
special situations they're not going to
apply to everyone you might not get to a
level where you need these things or you
want these things but they exist and I
want you to know what
so one bug bounty programs so we hear a
lot about this and I want to make sure
everyone knows what it is
so who here seen one of those many many
many Hollywood movies or TV shows where
the people escaped from jail and but
bounty hunters go chase them down grab
them bring them back and then they get
money they get a bounty this is kind of
like that but for security bugs so you
essentially allow hackers to hack a test
version of your site and they report all
the things they find to you and if they
find something and no one else has found
it yet you pay them and you say thank
you instead of suing them big companies
like Microsoft like Google like Shopify
from Canada they run their own bug
bounty programs they're huge and they
can do that a lot of smaller places you
hire someone like bugcrowd hacker one
and they'll run all this for you they
will reduce a lot of the noise do triage
it's fantastic not everyone needs this
right not everyone needs to have this
level of security but if you want to
have 20,000 hackers look at your
application this is a really amazing way
to do it although I would advise unless
you have done all the other steps first
this could be very expensive if you do
it this way that's that's the end on bug
bounties so the next one is my favorite
thing ever capture the flight contests
so this is like a hacker contest we put
up a vulnerable system a whole bunch of
people gather and they attack it as they
solve security challenges or puzzles
find vulnerabilities they get flags they
turn these flags in they get points and
whoever has the most points at the end
wins this is in my opinion the absolute
funnest way to learn about security
I've ran these for my own chapter every
year this is the first year that I'm not
running and I've passed the
rains off to my friend Jen it's so
exciting is so fun
III went to CTF and I made this
all-female team and we went and I
brought all these developers with me and
I was showing them how to hack things
and one of them you know the first time
she got something she literally jumped
up and she was screaming and dancing and
our full team was really excited this is
what happens when a bigger full women
get together we really didn't fit in at
the event but that's okay if you ran one
of these for the developers where you
work you will get their attention when I
showed all the developers on my team how
to do SQL injection and get past the
login screen I just blew their mind when
I showed them you know with a web proxy
you can just go right behind you can
just go right behind all of the
front-end validation and that means if
you haven't revalidate on the server
boom I'm in there just like oh my gosh
I'm like do you need to run back to the
office now it'sit's such a good way to
learn and if you want to build better
relationship with your developer team
this is a great way and the last one is
red team exercises so in Canada for the
government we have a red team a lot of
places like big teams they have big
companies they have red team and what
they do is they will attack your
production applications during regular
hours or off hours but they'll attack
your real systems and they won't
necessarily tell you what they're gonna
do like there's some scope but they will
attack you so that you can see how
resilient you really are instead of the
paper exercises like threat modeling you
now have facts right so sometimes people
hire out a team to come in and test and
the reason why they do this is so that
they know where they stand like if you
hire a red team in three days later
they're like we got nothing like you're
doing great but if you hire a red team
and five minutes later they're like
would you like to know your password
because I know it you need to make a lot
of changes
and this is a real this is a way of
knowing what's actually happening within
your network they'll definitely go for
your legacy apps first just so you know
you definitely want to make sure that's
all cleaned up before you hire a bunch
of people to do this how am i doing for
time 20 minutes oh good yes okay so I'm
hoping by this point in the presentation
all of you are like oh my gosh this is
amazing I want to push left please
please tell me how good cuz that's what
the rest of the presentation is about a
bunch of these things I'm gonna give
might seem like they're things that
developers need to do but these are all
things that as security people
you can enable developers to do because
I believe the security team is meant to
enable the rest of the the rest of all
of IT to do their jobs securely right
that's our job is to enable the business
in this case developers to get their
jobs done securely and do them at the
end have security so how can we push
left you can test your code so if you're
on the security team you can test code
if you're a developer you can test code
if you're on the security team you can
make sure that there is time in the
project for developers to do testing
during the development phase and again
at the end you can give so how many
people here have taken security tools
away from developers yeah you're not
raising your hands I have had the
security to you so many times try to
take my tools away instead of trying to
take tools away what if we give them to
them and train them how to use them
properly and give them safe places to
use them this is my opinion so if you're
gonna do security testing on a web app
you can get a web proxy you can get an
automated scanning tool there's free
ones
there's not free ones there's cheap ones
there's expensive ones there's ones that
are absolutely you don't need any skill
to run and you will get a smaller amount
of things and there's ones that are much
more complicated to run definitely need
a human with lots of
but they will find everything with it
right the way it works is it sits
between your browser and your
application and everything goes through
this proxy and it listens and it plans
its attacks and scripts that's going to
use against your app and it makes a
report for you of things that it's found
right if if we could enable developers
to use these things so where the
security team we have all the power I
don't know if you know that but we have
a lot of power and if we tell the
business this is a thing that we need if
we can get developers scanning during
the development phase by the time it
gets to us it will be so much better
caution
security scanners can cause damage so
when you give developers these tools
when you give some time you need to
train them you need to make sure that
they understand that you know if they
they come in at 9:00 and then they set
zap at insane mode and point it at their
dev server and then they go get a cup of
coffee they've just essentially DDoS
their whole team and they're not going
to be popular right so you want to make
sure that they use them properly so that
your name isn't mud so another thing we
can do is threat modeling so you can get
really in depth with bat modeling you
can do attack trees you can do so many
huge things and I know all the threat
modelers that I know want to go in-depth
and they get really upset with me when I
say this but it doesn't have to be that
complicated if you don't want it to be
great if your company's never done
threat modeling before just start with a
meeting with the business and the
developers and security and just have a
chat explain I want to know what you
think the risks are like if you were
gonna attack your app how would you do
it right if the business like what are
you worried about like what could happen
wrong like if there's a let's
an email money transfer application you
know what could go wrong what would what
are the risks well people want to steal
the money
right that's obvious right but what ways
right like if I can transfer you money
can I transfer your negative money can I
transfer you like a trillion dollars I
don't have when you talk this out take
notes then go make sure it's not
possible so here's all of that again
sometimes I talk through the picture
because I don't want people to read
while I'm talking because I can only do
one at the same time listen or read but
this is you know then you can take a
picture of the slide if you want I'm
gonna share all these slides after on
Twitter immediately they're actually
already on the net if you want them I
always share everything it's my pleasure
to do so so feel free to take pictures
or grab them later reviewing your code
so do you see this woman do you see how
chilled out she looks she looks serene
she looks confident it's because someone
reviewed her code she knows that's good
so
I think reviewing code is important when
you review someone else's code and you
see a mistake they made is unlikely you
will ever make that mistake again if
someone points out a mistake to you that
they found again likely you're not going
to make that mistake again
I tell developers that a secure code
review is so much better than a regular
code review because you only have to
worry about the security parts I don't
know if that sells it better but
basically you want to look through your
application and look at all the places
they're supposed to be something to do
with security and then make sure that
it's there make sure it's working
properly right have someone else look at
it you also want to look for your threat
models so remember that meeting that you
just had with the security team and the
business and the developers go look and
see if those things are possible
right like you can find a lot of things
with with your eyes looking at the code
that you can't find with dynamic
analysis and vice-versa so I think
they're both important there you can use
static code analysis which are these big
tools by many of the companies that are
here today thank you for making those
makes code review a lot less painful and
it purses out the app and looks at all
the different things and then gives you
hints as to where it thinks there are
problems I feel there's a bit of a
problem with static code analysis tools
not with the tools itself but the fact
that after management bought it they're
like oh well just you press the button
and then you have all the answers right
so you just press the button what's
taking so long like oh it's not it's not
telling you the answers it's giving you
hints it's telling you we you know
there's 20,000 lines of code we found
what we think could be 200 things and
then you review them and then you
actually found 20 things and
20 things I'm like this is great instead
of reviewing 20,000 lines now I'm
reviewing 200 lines this is awesome but
in the meantime management's like this
tool sucks
it gave us 90% false positives like no
Oh anyway so you might want to explain
that to management when you get this
that it is not the Silver Bullet that
makes security happen it is a thing that
helps you get there okay so this is the
picture slide and next okay so this
slide I've had some people tell me that
it feels a little condescending well you
could just write better code that's not
what I mean if you see a professional
athlete do you think of that person
after they practice they go back to
their host they sit on the sofa put
their feet up they eat Cheetos and watch
TV for the next four days no they do not
the best people on their teams they
practice they watch themselves to make
sure they can do better they experiment
with new diets new different ways of
doing everything new tools new they talk
to experts in the field they ask other
people's opinion they continue to
perfect themselves and you can do that
too no matter how good you are at coding
you could still always do better and if
you have made an app and it is beautiful
it's fast it's efficient it's everything
the client asked for but I can get into
it in ten minutes it's not the best
right so let's talk about doing even
better you can
trained yourself on secure coding I know
this sounds hard but there are actually
so many free tools online and free
videos and all sorts of things I can't
believe some of the stuff has given away
for free and like this is so good
there's paid stuff there's courses
there's training there's all sorts of
things you can do you can ask to do them
right if you are a security team what
you can do is you can provide this to
the developers right like there's I
don't want to name names but there's so
many great trainings out there that you
can either you can bring someone in they
give the training you
you can order like pure based training
whatever provide this tool and
developers might use it but make sure
that their managers will actually give
them like an hour a week to work on it
it doesn't it doesn't work if you buy
subscriptions for everyone and no one's
actually allowed using it another thing
so the so so this is the biggest thing
so when I as a developer I'd be at my
desk coding drinking coca-cola that's
what I did and at some point I'd be like
I forget how to do that I would
immediately go to stack overflow we all
do this all of us do this and then I
would look up how to do whatever the
thing is and then whatever the top thing
is I'd look at it I'm like yeah that
looks good copy-paste compiles perfect
continue coding if you can just convince
developers instead to so whatever is the
top thing on stack overflow you better
believe it is the least secure way to do
anything because when you remove all of
the security everything works better so
if you can convince them instead to go
so there's this new pair of Stack
Exchange called the security part you
can ask them to look there instead or
ask them to look up the most secure way
to do something so instead of taking 30
seconds I want you to take two minutes
and do it the secure way instead right
just look up how to do that instead this
will make a huge huge difference in your
code base
and another thing that you can try to
encourage developers to do is become
security champions so I have people that
will come to me they're really excited
about security and they want to learn
more and then I teach them stuff and
then they go show other people and it
propagates and it's like investing and
then your money grows but better when
you have someone come to you and they're
interested spend time with them it's an
investment and it will grow it will be
worth it especially if they're chatty
and they want to talk to people and
they're excited they will tell other
people and all of this will grow and
propagate for you you as a security
person so from what I understand the
general ratio is 100 developers to 10
Ops people to 1 security person right
that's not really great odds you don't
have time to train every single person
but if you can spend time with 3 or 4
different developers and have them go
and spread that to 12 other people each
like it just it propagates and it's
really great and if you can encourage it
it's awesome I'm gonna talk about wasp
again it's happening I'm sorry this is a
free resource that all of you can use
right we volunteer for them or a
nonprofit organization that's
international there's a chapter here
there's chapters all over the world
whatever country you're from if there's
any English speakers you probably have a
chapter hiding out somewhere it might be
sleepy you may need to wake it up and
tell it you need it but you can use some
of their products which are all free you
can use their tools you can read their
books they actually have books that you
can order they're free you can download
the PDF or you can pay to have it
printed you can have a physical copy if
you can get your developers into this if
you the security team can get into this
oh it's going to be so good and
have a new project about cloud security
yes and they're getting more and more
things like a bunch of their tools can
be integrated into your DevOps pipeline
it's such a good deal I'm looking at the
time guy he hasn't even showed me
anything yet yes anyway if you can get
your developers to join a wasp in the 10
meetings and learn stuff if you do it
you will stand out from your peers ray
if you're in application security like
you you really have to be a part of this
but if you can convince your developers
and other areas of IT to come to 200 ask
they will learn a whole ton of amazing
things and your security it'll just go
up like this like all all the stuff is
free it's such a great deal anyway next
with that I'm going to ask if anyone has
any questions
oh and we have candy for you I know the
audiences are shy sometimes but I was
really nice to the people ask questions
in the morning
you sir mm-hmm you have a chapter I
think you have to Oh
it's changed the culture yes no how can
we talk into the management that we
should lift shift to the left not to
change the culture is also cost more
budget than before so how can we like
talking to the banishment to ship left
so the first time that I managed to
convince management to do this I'm not
gonna say where I worked but we had a
bunch of security incidents over an
event we were doing and I made her a
port I'm really really anal retentive
I'm really obsessive about things so I
made a report about all the different
incidents we had and I grouped them into
sections like here's this huge section
of application security related problems
that we had all of these were easily
preventable like all of these are such
low-hanging fruit like I can I can
definitely solve all of this in like the
next nine months before our next event
like just just let me just let me and
because I showed the metrics and I
explained the risk and I showed them the
bad things that happened they're like
you know what Tonya you know there you
have like five months left on your
contract just give her just do it and I
got all the developer scanning the SAP I
gave them lessons I did all these things
are so exciting and we saw all of the
codebase just go like this is so magical
stats are is a really good way like
metrics
okay I know this sounds bad but create a
pretty report with pictures and graphs
executives like this don't make like
don't make bull make real real numbers
right and there's this thing from wasp
which is free called defect dojo and it
will suck up all the results from all
your security tools and then make these
beautiful metrics and make reports and
you can make management style reports
that are just great also I work
somewhere once and they wouldn't fix any
of we had a we had some external pen
testers come in and they just shredded
everything and I could not get the
developers to agree to change any of the
things and I was new to security and I
was like but I was hoping he would fix
this and it just wasn't working
no one's giving me any to any attention
so so this is a stunt so you should not
do this every time but I wrote up a
report that explained the risks of
exactly what could happen for each one
of the things and then I sent it to the
chief information officer and the
departmental security officer so the
person that's in charge of all the
physical security and IT security and
then the person in charge of all of IT
and I was like oh could you sign off on
the risk for this because I need you to
accept all of this this risk that it's
okay with you that these things are
happening with our brand new biggest
piece of software we've ever built and
then departmental security officer calls
music tanya was described I'm not saying
this this is horrible we can't put this
out there Zak well bill
you know maybe I could I could tell them
that you don't tell them bill sent you a
mic okay and I'm like um well bill said
and then everyone just like what bill
said and and then everyone fixed
basically everything it was awesome
so I basically one of my directors told
me one day if because I was all upset I
was like we need to do this and they
voted no and I'm like I don't understand
I was like I wouldn't say howdy I would
go that far
and he's like Tonya you didn't explain
the risk properly if you're this upset
about it you certainly didn't make us
that upset about it it's like what's the
problem and so then I explained to him
and he's like you need to go again next
week and you need to explain the real
reasons the real things that can happen
and why you're really worried and why
you're like we can we can set this
security project aside and we really
need to do this one so it's a lot about
communication because if they don't
understand what the risks are or if
every single thing for you is an
emergency you know what I mean like
after a while they stop listening to you
so if you can clearly explain and
communicate which is hard it's hard for
techie people to communicate I know
thank you for your question
the left course of a software
development life cycle is the
requirement in your experience what how
how do you deal with requirement that
when you look at it that and and know
that or they don't think about security
at all so I used to work for the
Canadian government till Friday and we
have this thing called itst 33 which is
painful and what I did is like I wrote a
thing kind of next to it so all the
things that apply to software and then I
just reworded it in security manure
words instead of security words and then
basically like oh you're doing an app
you know are you doing file upload boom
I need you to do those things we're
gonna add that to your project cause
you're doing file upload oh you're gonna
do this boom I'm gonna add that now to
your list of things I need you to do and
so then I could just reference that so
when I looked at their requirements you
know there's some that are always there
so like the Canadian government has this
HTTP only thing so all of the websites
are we're gonna do that right and so
that automatically is in there so
they're something like automatically in
there every time and then and that's
just like oh are you doing this okay you
need this it's like a shopping cart and
I had like thirty three things and you
have some of you have like six for sure
and then you might have more and then
I'm just like could you could you do
these things thank you I'm so that's
that's how it worked that what works
best for me personally like coming up
with this list you might need to have
language specific things so for instance
if you're doing Java D serialization ah
right so if you're using Java
I also need these things from you right
if you're using a framework I need you
to use the newest framework like things
like that so if you can come up with a
list of things and then you just do your
check boxes and you just you tell them
those few things that you need oh my
times up thank you very much for your
question thank you for having me if you
have more questions just come see me
later I love talking I'm very friendly
and I'm more candy
[Applause]