so check mic check
okay so hear me okay maybe a little
louder we're good
mic check okay so reasons to pay
attention one is I'm a little delirious
from lack of good sleep for the last
couple of nights I don't know how many
other people are severely displaced from
their home timezone but I may make bad
decisions so that that should make this
entertaining
another thing is I've got two live demos
that I haven't gonna attempt and the
last couple of times I tried them they
didn't work so that should make it
entertaining too because that's always
it's like going to the racetrack you
might see a crash so so we'll try and
keep this interactive here's my bad my
bad jet lag joke what's the definition
of jet lag
I'm sorry what were we talking about
thanks thanks for laughing for that so
my name is Jodi I work for cyber-ark
cyber arks and almost 20 year old
company focused on privileged access
management that is people with root
passwords the things with root passwords
now and so traditionally that was people
but more and more it's processes it's
tools and so the gist of this
presentation is how do we secure that
automation how do we handle these
privileged actors and then there's
something called the secret zero problem
it goes by other names auto-enrolment
but how do you bootstrap identity so
that you can authenticate authorize and
audit these things that are doing doing
work but to just kind of do a history
lesson and I'm noticing some themes here
so I won't dwell on some of the slides
that I've seen you know the topics kind
of covered because I think you know
we're seeing a lot of consistency which
is good at you know everybody's on
message even though we're not
collaborating around this but eight
years ago when DevOps was a new thing I
used to use the graphic on the left to
try and explain what it was to people
and just say you know really it's about
change at speed and in development it
had developed ways to introduce change
using outs of development and things
like that so they used to be the
constraint that constraint then moved to
operations operations wasn't ready and
had s LA's they had to meet had really
good reasons for saying hey whoa slow
down and DevOps you know there was a
wall of confusion between dev and ops
but it was fast forward about eight
years and and it's not you know we can't
we can't call victory yet but techniques
have been developed to do change at
scale and speed dev and ops have gotten
together and done things like blue green
deployments dart deployments feature
switches and just a lot of new
techniques have been developed to
introduce change at scale and speed and
now we have the situation that you see
over there on the right where there's a
new constraint and that is how do we do
it securely how do we do that in such a
way that it
be authenticated authorizing the audited
and this you know this is why we have
this conference right so everybody who's
probably read the Phoenix project or the
goal and probably knows something about
the Theory of Constraints and what
happens with constraints is sometimes
you just work around them and so this is
part of the challenge here and I had to
point out and in another presentation
with this this is not a real book though
you can't go by this anywhere this is
this is supposed to be a humorous
attempting and it's documenting you know
kind of a true situation and that is you
know like we had with shadow IT if there
is a constraint the tendency is to try
and work around it and so this is what
we don't want and I appreciate if France
was called to to collaboration because I
think collaboration you know
fundamentally that's what Davin ops was
or DevOps was about and so this is what
we need need to do now because this is a
report from Gartner that I think you can
get on Sunnah types website that and if
Gartner says it it must be true right so
that's why we put Gartner quotes in our
presentations but you know top top you
know complained her top thing to get
right in 2018 is DevOps collaborating
with the security team so collaboration
is number one but it's also number seven
and it's also number eleven
collaborating with a compliance team
collaborating with the audit team so
DevOps has gotten real and it's gotten
mature enough where now they're saying
okay you know great you can do change
it's scaling speed now you need to do it
securely and it's not the applicant just
the applications it's not delivering the
secure applications it's delivering
applications securely and that's what
I'm really talking about here is
securing the pipeline not securing the
contents of the pipeline it's not
application security its DevOps pipeline
security so if you look at the the
personas that are involved here there's
really three major personas there is the
security team which needs controls and
to prove controls are effective and this
that's the basics of compliance is so
it's not enough to have controls if you
can't prove that they're effective do
you really have control so you
can't prove it's like the tree falling
in the forest right the DevOps team you
know they're all good a change of scale
and speed and they're generally on board
with the concepts of security so in our
experience it's not that the DevOps team
is cavalier even though you know that
that book is kind of funny they're not
cavalier about security they just they
have it's just that the security team
hasn't caught up with it the way that
operations wasn't you know ready for the
changes that the dev team was
introducing the security team hasn't
caught up with this new reality and so
you've got this wall of confusion going
on so the third of persona here are the
developers and developers generally
speaking one is little to do with
security as possible and we kind of
don't want to put the onus of security
on them I don't know if anybody was that
AWS re-invent but Verner Vogel's was
saying security is everybody's business
yeah yeah it's important but it's not
really everybody's business and and the
less we the less onus we can put on
developers to be responsible for
security the more compliance will
probably have make the right thing to do
the easy thing to do that's a that's a
thing so there's our personas if we look
at how DevOps has the risk to change
it's by reducing the quanta of change as
the speed has increased the quanta has
has shrunk and so as we've gotten new
technologies first with virtualization
then with containers and now with you
know server lists and micro services
ud risk change because the size of the
change is smaller so and it also enables
other things like parallel development
parallel deployments that enables a lot
of other capabilities but the point is
now we have a lot more things to keep
track of and a lot of these things need
access to databases and services and
other things they need they need access
to the secrets and the credentials in
order to get access to these services so
how do we provision these things how do
we keep track of them there's two
for people to keep up with anymore and
that's why we have so much automation
and we all know DevOps isn't automation
but you can't really do DevOps without
automation right so so now we have these
privileged actors in the network we've
got truly robotic system administrators
that are provisioning servers
configuring servers deploying
applications these are your system
administrators in many ways now and they
need to be we need to keep track of what
they're doing we need to know what
they're doing
we need to authenticate authorizing all
the other activities so so especially
these automation tools that are doing
that but but across the board now
scanning scanning is typically a very
privileged process because it has to
reach in and see what's going on
everywhere in the network and so that
that is a very privileged process so so
this is this is the general problem that
we find today and and to the DevOps
team's credits people generally aren't
embedding secrets in source code anymore
that's kind of the first step you know
the first step is get your secrets out
of source code I'm not gonna ask for a
show of hands but if you have secrets
and source code get them out find a
place to put them because the first you
know many of the breaches that you hear
about today who burn things like that
these secrets were harvested out of
github they were just there for the
taking and so that's that's the first
step get your secrets you know who
you're abetted secret's out if a secret
is embedded in source code it can be
rotated and rotation is the first first
order of Hygiene for for any credential
the sooner you know the more you rotate
the less valuable that credential is
because it's likely to be no good when
somebody goes to use it
so so for a lot of reasons you want to
get secrets out of source code so a lot
of DevOps teams say hey we're using
puppet puppet has you know hire a
database and encrypted um oh we'll put
our secrets there and then there's
another team that's using chef and they
say hey chef has data bags will put our
secrets there and another teams using
ball and another team's using AWS and
another team is using PCF we will put it
in credit hub so you now you've got
secret sprawl this is this you know
you've heard of image sprawl there's
different kinds of sprawl now you have
secret sprawl and you've got these
secrets cashed in all these different
places many of which really aren't
secure so they're they're a place to
store the secrets and you know they're
not a source code anymore but now you've
got this balkanized fractured very
exposed sets of secrets spread across
your your operations so this is what we
call islands of trust the other so again
it's it's better than you know but this
is the next step of maturity okay now
we've got secrets here but now we've got
this this fractured security space we
don't have good consistent practices we
can't really audit these things the
security team is saying what you know
the security is like we got to get these
horses back in the stable help you know
and so a lot of times we come in and we
have meetings with the DevOps teams and
the security teams in the same room and
it's like marriage counseling it's like
most like no see the DevOps team is
adding value to the business and
insecurity so you don't DevOps you know
they need compliant because the auditors
are going to come calling and they you
know so it's like it's trying to see you
know everybody see it things from their
other point of view the other part of
this is even if you unify all of this
even if you get one secret story for all
your DevOps top but it's not integrated
with your enterprise security processes
you still got a problem you still don't
have coherence and and unity and that's
really what we're trying to get
so factors that increase the per capita
cost of read so this is kind of a funny
graph this is the bottom part of it the
top part was you know things that that
decrease the cost of you know so reduce
the cost of a breach and there was a
good practices these are the negative
practices so a negative decrease is an
increase and so so this is and per
capita means per compromised record so
what this is saying is that there's a
strong correlation between compiled
compliance failures and extensive cloud
migration and an increased cost of a
breach to the tune of 14 US dollars per
compromised record so if you have 30
million compromised records times 14
this is this is the the negative thing
and you know we are not seeing devops up
here but there's a pretty strong
correlation between cloud migration and
DevOps they're not you know completely
orthogonal they're not completely
correlated but people that are tend to
be doing cloud or to give us but at the
very least compliance failures if you
can't show compliance if you can't show
you've got good controls in place then
then we're seeing this correlation here
so anyway so here's a question can you
be a hacker if you're not wearing a
hoodie is that it's like you know mr.
robot you know it's like when I'm at
home I have a hoodie I was like look -
my wife was like look honey I'm hacker
now I'm a hipster now I'm a hacker but
so you don't think that's funny anymore
anyway so this is this is these these
credentials that are stored in the
various places are ripe for the picking
and this used to be kind of a
hypothetical you know we know about
github and things like that but I hadn't
seen any really intentional targeting of
these systems until literally last week
a friend of mine sent me a link to this
video on YouTube from Def Con in October
and it was a guy this is a white hat
hacker so this is this is a good guy but
he was documenting how to exploit
continuous build system through
continuous integration systems and he
was not only documenting him he's got a
framework on github that teaches you how
to do it and it's adding to editing so
so this is you know so the first order
of business is you identify the exploit
and then you figure out how to defend
against it so he's doing the right thing
but he's calling attention to the fact
you know that before word was kind of us
going hey this could be a problem it's a
problem it's a true problem
and he makes some really good points
here which which I just love because
they vary they dovetail very nicely with
my presentation but you know here's all
the good things I don't know anybody can
read this at the back so I'm just read
it to you good frequent release cycles
are fabulous good faster code
deployments equals quick remediation
good decoupled systems reduce single
points of failure compromise the one
service doesn't always made full
although ownage bad fast release
sometimes mean hasty oversights you know
you're doing things too quickly to
really do them right automated
deployment systems are checked less than
the code that they deploy so this you
know so much focus on app second
security scanning let's not forget that
the things that are deploying these apps
are privileged processes
and they bare looking at and the last
thing here which is really the thesis
statement of this whole presentation it
is identity management so so the point
I'm gonna leave you I'm gonna tell you
that what I'm gonna leave you with now
and then I'm gonna you know through the
rest of the presentation but I think
identity management is the common ground
that DevOps and security can focus on is
a common language it's a way to say what
is the identity that this process is
running at what is the identity of this
Jenkins executor what is the identity of
these you know what who needs to be
running this playbook and in ansible and
so if you can start focusing on identity
and the roles that these identities need
to take then you can start getting
developing a common language look you're
a few the hacker you're a hacker
really call alright so in any way that
this if you want to go see this video
it's pretty entertaining
um there's your link there your bit so
anyway so we talked about that oh and
there's the link there too
guy goes by space box that's a capital B
zero so we've got these challenges we've
got the security teams not collaborating
effectively explosion of automation
deployments inconsistency and secrets
for all lack of audit and compliance
broaden attack surface let's call it
what it is it's dead
its technical security debt and this is
going to grow the longer it goes
unaddressed so it's really pairs you
know you really need to start thinking
to taking a look at it and saying okay
what are the privileges that these these
processes need how are we going to
control those how are we going to audit
them and show show compliance with our
policy so let's look at just to put some
nomenclature around this we're seeing a
very high Duty this this almost
everybody relates to this almost
everybody Zuzu Jenkins for build and a
lot of people are more and more people
increasingly are using ansible or
deployment some people use chickens for
deployments you know and that's one of
the challenges of our job is no.2 DevOps
tool changes of the same and certainly
know workflow those are the same so the
firt our first step is always just
understanding what the workflow is but
in general you've got these these
privilege systems they're building the
applications and they need access to the
secrets to be able to pull code from
from
to deploy to the doctor repo for testing
to deploy the artifact repository for
staging and then ansible similarly needs
secrets to pull from the repository to
deploy the application
similarly the applications also need
access to secrets to do their work so
we've got two sets of identities at
different times identities in the tool
chain and then identities at runtime the
point is all of these things in order to
get access to these credentials need to
be able to pull secrets from some
secrets store and and preferably they're
authenticated and authorized and audited
in doing that so that's set this up for
let's talk about identity when let's
talk about it any of these that aren't
just people let's talk about machine
identity or service identity or see see
the term now work loved identity this is
these are the nonhuman identities that
still need to be authenticated
authorized and audited
we want to do it all the code we need to
do it very efficiently because we've got
thousands of things coming coming and
going so this has to be a very efficient
and
a dynamic process so so this is a
taxonomy of different ways of doing
authentication and it's it's my work as
you won't find a reference for this
anywhere it's just based on my
experience so it generally we've got two
classes of authentication techniques one
is credential base which is your classic
username and password hostname and API
key you know so everybody is familiar
with that I won't dwell on that too much
but there are differences in the Machine
space because these things come up and
they don't you know the enrollment
process is is it's not well established
you know think about the human workflow
of an of identity you go to you start a
job they know who you are you get
assigned an account you get a password
you remember the password hopefully and
so you have your own built involved so
you can remember your password these
things don't apply to machines in
general they don't know their own
passwords and they come and go at such a
furious rate that that you really need
something that's very very efficient for
doing that so there's pre verified
machine identity techniques and then
there's dynamically gratified techniques
I'm gonna do a demo the first demo I'm
going to do is this more statically
define identity where we we assign an
identity and there's a privileged
process that issues the API keys and so
we'll show what that looks like
god-willing at the demo
the other thing is attribute-based
and so this is is a new if so think
about biometrics the human analog here
is you know when you go to open your
phone you don't you don't use a code you
don't type in a code you just use your
thumbprint so it's it's something about
you it's not something that you remember
or submit and so this is getting into a
more advanced way of authenticating
these non-human entities but it also has
some limitations and and it's it's these
limitations are kind of spelled out here
we actually do this one of our typical
products has been doing this for over
ten years but it requires an agent be
collocated with the application in order
to do the verification but it can do
things like use view certs or md5 hashes
to to authenticate the applications
verify it is what it is without the
application submitting a password so the
the other here in the demo I'm going to
do second is using kubernetes and using
the kubernetes runtime to verify the
attributes of a container requesting
access to secrets so this is the kind of
bootstrap process you have to
authenticate in order to get access to
the secrets once you have access to the
secrets there you can get access to the
databases and the services that you need
we all good with that every any
questions
all right so let's see what happens this
is gonna be the fun part Oh
nevermind I let me let me just step you
through it let me show you what I'm
going to show you then I'll show you
so credential based pre verified
identity so the workflow here is that
there's an admin process that issues the
API queue to application container so
it's going to launch the containers and
then it's going to assign each of these
containers an API key and they're all
gonna have the same API key they're
going to share the same identity so the
the applications will retrieve the API
key from his shared volume just running
in a docker compose environment and then
the credential is deleted from the
shared volume after five seconds so it
only exists for five seconds and this is
where you start saying okay thinking
like an attacker how could this system
be compromised how could somebody get
access to this API key because when they
have that API key then they can retrieve
that whatever credentials that identity
is authorized to retrieve so so this is
a way of distributing the API key pretty
pretty securely it's a shared volume
that's only seen by these these
containers and it's deleted after five
seconds here's a graphical depiction of
that same thing so the the issuing
authority or the credential issuing
authority is this script and it's going
to be logged in as the DevOps
administrator so it's a privilege
it's a privilege Authority it has to
have the privilege to be able to rotate
the API key the Sony's thing so it's
going to pull the API key from the
secret store actually rotate it
distribute it in the shared volume yeah
applications pick that up so that's
probably enough ado about that now let's
see if it actually works
so I'm going to run to containers and
they're going to sleep every five
seconds before they fetch that database
password so this anybody used we scoped
we scoped makes makes demos a whole lot
more interesting because you can
actually see what's going on as opposed
to just watch text scroll so this this
is my my conjurer environment conjures
our secrets management product for
DevOps we're close we've got a booth out
there and here's my two containers that
came out web app one web app - I can
open up these containers you know get a
shell in here and pop this out and just
watch as it retrieves these passwords so
I'm going to just tail this this a log
file that it writes to and watch so we
can see that it's got the API key it
echoes the API key to the LA hug and
it's retrieving the password which is
unimaginative to leave the database
password so all well and good I mean
that's that's great right it's so what
so let's do something here now let and
this is what I'm going to do is just cat
this this script so this is the script
that's going to cycle or rotate that API
key and so rotation again this is like
this the fun most fundamental security
hygiene practice you can have as soon as
you rotate a credential anybody that has
the old credential is alan they're
locked out no matter where they are it's
like it's like an EMP for credentials
you rotate the password and all those
old credentials are dead so what this
script does is rotates the API key and
if I don't give it a an argument then
it'll write the new API key to the
shared volume and the applications will
pick it up and they'll go on about their
business and so we'll see that happen in
real time here
rotate the API key the application you
know it
it failed authentication went back to
look at that shared volume picked up the
API key and then the script deleted it
so so that's that's cool and then you
know here's just the other example where
if I add an argument it's not going to
write that that API key back and the
applications are locked out and because
all these applications are sharing the
same identity you know which is arguably
what you want because they all have the
same privilege they're all instances of
the same image they all have the same
authorization requirements so you don't
need to create unique identities for
every single container so these are
sharing very efficiently a single
identity and when I rotate that API key
they're all locked out so that's just
you know kind of getting into some of
the the semantics of identity for
inanimate things you know this is not a
human thing anymore and these cycles
these life cycles you know are very
dynamic but you know the downsides to
this is we have this very right now the
identity that's used to issue these keys
is a privileged administrator and if we
had lots of different types of
applications then you get into well how
much privilege does this thing have and
does it become a liability because now
it has access to issue credentials not
just use credentials but issue
credentials which is a very powerful
thing and if you're aware of general
exploits using Active Directory one of
the most powerful things you can do is
the golden ticket hack where you you
take command of the of the author you
know the identity issuing authority and
therefore it can give yourself any
privilege that you want so we want to
avoid that and this is the kind of you
know critical thinking that needs to go
into our security models and and so you
know all the good for the old principles
of zero trust lease privilege
non-repudiation role based access
control you know these these all still
apply it's just that now when they need
to apply to these non-human actors so
that's that first Dylan let me let me
just stop these things so I set up for
my second demo
any questions any gonna is all of this
clear and straightforward semi
entertaining
so I'm going to shut these containers
down and we'll move on to the kubernetes
going so that's that so so now we're
going to look at the attribute based
authentication so not using a password
the containers are come up and they
initiate the verification of their
identity so they submit a request
basically and the workflow really is
submitting a certificate signing request
to now the Secret Service so there's no
there's no administrator logged in here
this is all fully automated where as
soon as these applications come up and
they could be launched by whatever
automated process but they're not given
an identity to start with they request
verification of an identity through a
CSR that CSR is validated with
kubernetes so basically we're we're
trusting we're using kubernetes as a
trusted third-party to say is this thing
what it says it is is it truly at this
IP address does it have this name is an
instance of this of this image and if
that all checks out then we'll issue it
a certificate and that certificate
becomes its credential that it can use
to authenticate so that's the process
that we're doing here here's the
graphical representation of that so this
is using ton in order to hide complexity
from the application remember that if
we're trying to make the developer
experience as seamless as possible we
want to shield them from a lot of this
the mechanics of doing this
authentication and certification these
things like that so we're using a
sidecar here
which is a very common pattern now
service mesh architectures as a way of
encapsulating complexity so as this
sidecar container is is actually doing
the authentication dialogue back and
forth with the conjurer server and it
gets back to certificate not directly
over the requesting channel but through
a side channel so we're actually it's
it's again so we're kind of a two-factor
authentication where the final check is
even if it's not where it says it is
we're writing the cert back to where it
says it is into the container using the
the kubernetes runtime so if it
successfully spoofed us every other way
it's still not going to get a certain
test sir so that's this demo and let me
just run through that real quick it's
very similar to the one we had before in
that we're going to deploy a web
application it's going to come up it's
going to first get authenticated and and
usually by the time everything pops up
here it's authenticated it's already
started retrieving the database password
so that's the if you saw those lines get
created that was why after it got
authenticated now it's contacting the
Secret Service to retrieve the database
password pull this up here and it will
start seeing it echo the
password so that you know same thing
there it got authenticated got access to
the database password yeah everything's
good so let me just show you one last
thing here real quick because I want to
show you what this certificate looks
like and and then talk a little bit
about some some developing standards
that are that are happening so to use
whoever have context
control
so
live demos are all the rage at the
conferences these days I'm just happy
mine so far I don't want to jinx it so
far it's worked pretty well so I'm gonna
exact into this container and we're just
going to look at that that cert go quick
so I'm in the in the webapp container
happened to know that it's that the cert
is written to the conjurer ssl directory
that's here so here's a certain the
private key that it can use for
encryption and then I'm just going to
going to parse that cert real quick
it's an x.509 sir
this text
okay so final proof point we've got a
cert here and if we look at the the just
the the common name here it's got the IP
address encoded in it we look over here
we can see that that's the same IP
address that the container is at so the
cool thing about certs is you know
they're they're they're pretty
open-ended we could put a lot of
information in this cert and it's
stateless we're not keeping track of
these certs anywhere ever they don't
have to be looked up so it's very very
scalable we can issue these certs
they're there they're secure they can be
tagged very specifically to this one
container they can't be used anywhere
else it certainly can't be used outside
of Cooper Cooper Nettie's but they can't
be used by anything else that doesn't
have that information in it so the thing
that we find really gratifying about
this but you know besides just being
incredibly technical is that it is very
similar to an emerging standard coming
out of the cloud native computing
foundation the same organization that's
overseeing kubernetes is is kind of
sponsoring this it's not a formal
project yet but it's it's a project
called spiffy secure
secur production identity framework for
everybody so this is a generalization of
that process that we just looked at
where a requester asks for verification
of its identity the identity is verified
through various means
but generally but through a trusted
third party it gets back this especially
formatted 5:09 certificate which can be
used as a general way of authenticating
to other processes and so this is called
workload authentication it's it's just
how do we authenticate these things that
aren't people anymore and so this is a
general framework that's being developed
for that for these highly scale of
container and dynamic environments just
a foreshadowing so you know attribute
authentication and the spiffy standard
are pretty cool but what if these
applications never actually touch
credentials this is some some
foreshadowing and some research work
that we're doing and it's based on a
product that the cyber-ark has for human
administrators where a sysadmin can
login and and never see the root key but
get a root session on a target machine
and that session is audited but they
never see the root password and so this
is a much more secure way to to give
access to give privileged access to
something and so what if we could do
that for these non-human actors where an
application simply gets a connection to
the database and it never sees the
database password
we think that's a much more secure way
to manage these things it's also much
simpler for the developers so that's a
bit of foreshadowing you know that's
another presentation for another time so
just to wrap up strong identity enables
collaboration so I think that starting
to talk about the identities of these
processes which ones are more privileged
than others it gives you a way to have
this common language that that devops
teams and security teams can start to
use to understand the concerns of each
other you have an over privileged
process that is a bigger target it's a
more of a liability and so we want to
mitigate that risk we run over you know
risk is is probability times impact so
if that over privileged process if it
has access to tons and tons of Secrets
or can issue identities that's something
we really need to focus on and raise
this level of importance in terms of our
strategy and remediation as opposed to
you know just some application that
needs to connect to a database maybe so
it's a way it just gives us a common
parlance where security and operations
can focus on solving these problems as
much as possible keeping development out
of the literature so just a call to
action collaborate collaborate
collaborate focus on you know further
security teams focus on outcomes this is
how the marriage counseling slide focus
on outcomes recognize the value that
DevOps is bringing to the organization
be practical and making trade-offs
between perfect and good enough you know
it's we just a case in point you have a
customer who's security team mandated
that all jinkins jobs will be
authenticated and anybody that knows
Jenkins knows you can authenticate the
executors but the jobs are data you
can't authenticate data you can sign
data you know there's other things you
can do but you can't really authenticate
data so they issued a nonsensical decree
that the dev ops teams have no way of
complying that so avoid doing that
devops teen show you understand security
principles that you believe in those but
you know be open to change recognize
that they're required to show compliance
with regulations use established systems
of trust where possible so tie into the
enterprise organizations established
systems for authentication for you know
for those things and then both Identity
Management is a common objective it's a
way of talking about privilege about
over privilege about often you know just
being able to to control access to these
credentials and preventing them from
getting in the wrong hands so thanks I
don't know how I'm doing on time do we
have time for questions or is there five
minutes all right any questions Hey
usually there's somebody in there
another company yeah but what you did
there that could be you know anybody
all right great thank you
[Applause]