mainly in the latin america and
caribbean region since the majority of
our members in the united states broke
down that geography a little bit more
for you as you can see by this pie chart
more than fifty percent of errands
members come from eight states in the
united states those are states for
California Texas New York Virginia
Florida Washington Illinois Maryland and
you can see the total numbers of the
members we have in the other states
notice we everyone has a member in all
50 states and also one member in the
Washington DC area or in Washington DC
next I'd like to give you some
information about our ArrayList number
registrations over the past two years as
you can see here I provided the
information for 1998-1999 also you can
see that there has been a substantial
increase over the last two years in the
number of a s number of registrations
there are a total of 915 s number of
registrations in 1998 and it increased
to 1685 in 1999 something else that also
increased over the last year were the
number of ipv4 requests Erin received
1999 we received a total of 1480
requests for IP address base as opposed
to 900 in 1998 currently the average
response time for response to requests
for ipv4 address space from Erin is at
one day or less and another note here
twenty percent of the requests received
a Terran do not to achieve approval
status you know there are many reasons
for this three of the reasons being the
requesting organization did not meet the
request criteria or the requesting
organization requested
walk smaller than Aaron's minimum
allocation size of a / 20 and it's in
many cases organizations submit
incomplete templates and when we go back
to them and we ask for for that
additional information be provided they
just do not respond and they allow their
ticket to expire after 90 days this this
next slide here gives you some
information on the cider block sizes
issued in 1998 and 1999 you'll note here
there's there's a line for other an
example of other are those allocations
that are made off the cider bit boundary
an example that would be Aaron
allocating 96 / 24 s to an organization
from something that may have been held
in reserve for them but you know do keep
in mind that those 96 / 24 s were
contiguous with the previous allocation
so that puts them back on the bit
boundary this next slide shows you how
much ipv4 space was issued by Aaron in
1998 1999 measured in / twenty-fours in
1998 Aaron issued 50,000 903 / 24 total
and in 1999 80 4839 substantial increase
also I'd like to give you share some
information with you about Aaron / 20
allocation history as most of you are
where Aaron reduced their mental Malik
ation size from a / 19 to a / 20 in
February of 1999 and you can see the red
line here on this graph to show you
where the minimum allocation size was
reduced and you can see the number of /
20 s issued increased beyond that time
this slide here gives you some
information on the box that Aaron
currently administers currently we're
making our allocations out of the 64 / 8
network
and a visit to ICANN's website which
will link you to the iono website will
show you the / eights that are currently
listed is reserved now currently listed
is reserved here from the IANA website
pulled this information from there a 105
/ aids or listed as reserved and that
accounts for approximately 41 percent of
the total ipv4 address space also like
to share some information with you about
Erin's ipv6 registrations during the
year of 1999 Erin received three
requests for ipv6 address space two of
those requests have been approved and
allocated one of those requests have
recently been approved but not yet
allocated Aaron's initial ipv6
allocation size is at / 35 reserved from
a / 29 and if you'd like to find more
information about Erin's ipv6
registration service you can visit the
URL listed here in red our largest
volume template Aderyn is the swip
template as you stood by the numbers
here there was a substantial increase
again of templates processed in 1999 /
1998 we had 238,000 in 1999 that's over
137,000 in 1998 it's an increase of
about a hundred thousand registration
transfers in 1999 Erin completed 121
registration transfers those are IP
number registrations and a s number
registrations as opposed to the 70 that
were completed in 1998 so the transfer
traffic also increased and also we do
run a help desk at Erin know many of you
probably called it before we do our best
answer on a first or second ring but the
amount of phone calls were received in
did go up much from what were the
numbers were in 1998 we received just
over almost 16,000 calls in 1999 as
opposed to the 9000 in 1998 like to give
you some information also about Aaron's
routing registry Aaron currently mirrors
the routing registries listed here on
the slide and we currently have 314
objects in the a.m routing registry if
you'd like to find more information
about using aaron's rattled registry or
just general information you can visit
the URL listed here in red and at this
time I'd also like to invite everyone
here to participate in Aaron's mailing
lists we do have met many mailing lists
that are open to the general public and
that those mailing lists are listed here
and I'd like to invite you to visit URL
listed here and read to participate and
ends up in the community and the policy
things discussions that are going on and
things of that sort at these mailing
lists also like to at this time invite
the public to Aaron's upcoming public
policy meeting on april three in april
four and members Aaron members to
Aaron's member meeting be held on april
five the meeting is going to be held in
calgary this spring april three through
april five and the sponsor will be Sean
communications additional information
and registration can be found after you
are all listed here in red also like to
share some information with you about
the ASO council representatives in each
region Aaron's elected representatives
or a Cathy wit book for a three year
term David Meyer for a two-year term and
removed abeka for a one-year term also
listed here are the elected
representatives from the AP neck region
and the ripe NCC region
like to invite everyone here to attend
the Aaron micro allocation bought this
evening it will begin at seven thirty
p.m. this evening and it is scheduled to
last until nine-thirty p.m. and this
bath will be moderated by a kathy wipro
of the errant advisory council and
before i close my portion of the
presentation today i would just like to
let you know that the following ER and
staff are available in analog 18 for
remainder of today and all day tomorrow
to answer your questions Kim hovered
Michael O'Neill Sam Kurtzman and I and
before we close for lunch as President
Kim Hubbard has some information that
you like to share with you all bets
thoughts you are going to have to hear
from me today didn't you okay and if
you're anything like me the last thing
you want to hear about is another
meeting but I really do want to
encourage everyone to attend the Aaron
public policy meeting coming up in April
and Calgary Canada we have a lot of
interesting I p times ahead of us and
it's important that all of you or your
organization's at least be aware of
what's going on we're going to be
starting on contract negotiations in the
near future with i can i'm sure you all
know better i can and it's going to be
um it's going to touch on on issues such
as you know the future of aaron with
with regards to our cannon and whether i
can should follow the same IP policies
as everyone else or whether they should
be allowed to directly allocate address
based without following the policies so
it should be very interesting along with
topics such as micro allocations and all
the other policies it's and I you know
the question is that's going to be
coming up in future with the ikea
negotiations is whether
when it does in and the other registry
will do any other registries obtain
their authority from and we believe that
it's a bottom-up we believe that it's
from you you're determined policies
global and local visual registry
policies but but to do that you really
have to be involved I just want to make
sure that you all keep yourselves aware
and understand what's going on with with
IP in the future and it'll benefit all
of us if if you do and that's what
that's all I have to say if you'll have
any questions before you're going to
like Sean dala not a question it's my
usual question okay narrating the
registration database is between AP Nick
right and Aaron how's that project
coming along our engineering group at
erin has been in communication recently
and of course over the last couple of
months with the other registries and
there has been some significant progress
in it but quickly we really are working
on it we want to wait talk to them that
y2k problem was on her way but now that
you know we're okay and you're okay
we're going to move move ahead with this
the end of any other questions yes what
we call it that a question but um with
that of the loyalists are mode on
website as an archive feel only lists I
think it'd be a good idea forget it
people to play with the content of the
novelist or to Alexis up through hell
archive okay great recession thank you
very much any other questions
all right thank you thank you