this my name is tim Griffin I'm going to
talk about some work that I've been
doing at bell labs sounds good okay and
I know this floor has seen a lot of
talks on bgp I and under these aspects I
think this is probably the first part of
the metaphysics of BGP how's that okay
here we go okay so I want to ask what
problem is bgp solving and of course
it's solving the interdomain routing
problem but here's the way I mean it in
here maybe I should tell you why I
started thinking about this problem
because i was writing some code on top
of the are a tool set and I what I
wanted to do was pull in our psl
policies from from databases and then do
some analysis sort of end-to-end
consistency analysis or check for
certain kinds of routing anomalies and I
was having a hard time because I didn't
really have a semantics for bgp you know
what I mean I wanted to one of them
first of all simplify things a long one
one dimension I just wanted to get rid
of that whole notion of dynamics of BGP
so I can you think of this think of a
collection of routing policies as some
some system of constraints that I wanted
to solve okay and then then I want to
take it to simplify it along another
dimension
so they sort of get rid of all of that
complexity of the interaction of
policies along along a path of things
like that so and I wanted to use this in
in designing algorithms for heuristics
really for analysis of our psl policies
okay and it turned out that the we came
up with a simple model and it was also
useful for other kinds of analysis of
BGP that I'll talk about toward the end
and also some design is useful in the
design of some extensions an analysis of
proposals for btp and I'm not really
going to talk about some of that stuff
today because it's kind of research IAM
what I hope to talk about is what I hope
you get out of this talk is some sort of
fun way of looking at VG p and also some
framework that makes it a little easier
to discuss certain kinds of routing
anomalies that can happen with bgp okay
so what I want to do is we all know that
there's this shortest path problem out
there it's very simple you can describe
it to anyone so any math geek for
example will understand this problem I
don't have to know anything about
networking it's a very simple problem we
have a graph some weights you want to
find shortest paths in that okay and so
that problem underlies these well-known
protocols rip ospf and is is and those
things are fairly complicated
distributed algorithms for solving the
shortest path problem okay so I want to
find an X a problem that is too bgp as
the shortest path problem is to these
these I GPS okay and I want it to be as
simple as possible okay so for example I
want it to fit on two slides okay so
here's what here's the problem that we
came up with here's a way of stating it
we call it the stable paths problems and
again you know forget about all of the
complexities let's say
p in the dynamics i'm just going to give
you a very simple graph problem and the
problem is you have a graph with labeled
nodes and there's a special note labeled
zero and everyone else all the other
nodes have a collections of paths to
that node 0 and it's some some sub every
node has some subset of all pop you know
possible paths from that node to the 0
node and these are called the permitted
paths that node at that note so for
example node 3 in this diagram has just
one path 30 and no 2 has two pounds to
the origin okay and each one has a
ranking on those paths so and I've
listed it so that they rank the highest
rank path is on the top of the list so
for example no.2 likes the path to 10
more than it likes the path to 0 okay
now that's it and so you know if
intuitively the idea here is that 0 is
some let's say some is announcing an
address block and what we're looking at
is is sort of the the Distilled policies
how everyone wants to get to that
address block okay so I'm only looking
at 11 address block at a time here and
I'm not going to get into the
translation from let's say a set of our
psl policies to an instance of the
stable past problem because it gets
really messy especially when you're
dealing with ibgp for example so
intuitively we can think of just as a
first cut that each node here represents
an Aes okay and it's a little bit
simpler than thinking about it that way
because these paths represent a s has
fine but in general when you have when
you deal with ibgp you're actually
dealing the paths actually our paths
between routers and these nodes
represent represent routers okay well
I'm not going to get into the messiness
of the translation okay everybody
understand what an instance of the
problem is okay now I want to tell you
what a solution is okay so solution well
how do I solve
pass problem what I do is I come up with
an assignment of paths to nodes okay so
the two things are true I don't don't
try to read that stuff I'll just tell
you what it means one thing is it's a
consistent assignment and that is it's a
treat you know that the assignment of
paths induces a tree rooted at zero okay
and the other thing is that it's stable
every path every node is stable in the
following sense is that it couldn't it
has of all the paths going through its
neighbors that are consistent with their
assignment it has the highest ranked
path possible okay so let's look at this
the underlined the red paths here
represents a solution to this particular
stable path problem and for example 2 is
not terribly happy it has this path that
it doesn't like as much as to 10 but it
can't have to 10 because that's not
consistent with what is assigned at one
okay for for example couldn't be
assigned for 30 because of a stability
condition because it can it can adopt
the path given the assignment that's at
2 it can adopt the path for 20 which is
better than 4 30 so it's going to take
that path okay so it has to have that
path and a stable assignment given what
given what is assigned that too in this
case okay so is that clear and also we
can we can have a node like five here
that doesn't get anything so in general
with stable path problem is not a
spanning tree and it's also not a
shortest path tree in general okay so
let's just look at another example real
quick just a first of all this
illustrates that there can be multiple
solutions to a stable path come here i
have a problem where yet one prefers to
go through to win
prefers to go through one I call it
disagree because there are two solutions
here illustrated and somebody always
loses somebody always has to take their
their the path they prefer less okay and
in this case just to illustrate what if
it was stability is if you assign a 10
and 20 you know the direct path to each
node well then that's not a stable
assignment because each each of those
nodes can do better by going through its
its neighbor okay so I want to
illustrate in the net you know these
things start aren't directly if you look
at this it sort of looks like well one
and two or maybe doing something strange
right and that could be the case but
let's look at how our psl might map down
to this i'm going to show you three sets
of our psl policies that that the actual
are via of BGP policies have mapped down
to the same stable paths problem they
all map down to that problem disagree
and the first one is sort of a direct
encoding of what you see at those nodes
is that is one just prefers anything it
sees announced term to so it sets a
higher local preference which happens to
be in our psl or lower pref so okay it's
just sort of a direct encoding I'm just
going to use a little preference to do
that another encoding is very different
one says okay if you send me a certain
community value I'll prefer it more and
that's community 1 1 and a 2 says well
if you send me community 21 I'll prefer
the route more and what strange here is
that the 0 the origin is sending out
announcements and it's sending up to
when it sends an announcement at the one
it's attaching the community for to
choose preference and one sends up the
announcement that to the two it set it
attaches the community for one's
preference and so that ends up inducing
those those preferences that you see in
the stated path problem at one and two
but it's
really there it's not one in twos policy
exactly it's the interaction of the
announcements from one and the sort of
generic policies that wanted to okay and
finally it was sort of a combination 10
pads out on the 01 link so that one
likes things coming from too and that
too has a has local preference set so
that it prefers things from one okay now
you could sort of get a sense here why
you know this this kind of model helped
in writing some code to do static
analysis of policies because you can you
can sort of boil down all of that in a
complexity of interaction down to kind
of a very simple canonical form and then
do some analysis there okay so that's
what's going on here okay so let's look
at how just this fact that there can be
multiple solutions to a stable path
problem how that can explain or model a
sort of very common routing anomaly and
I i'm calling it without triggering here
i'm not sure if that's a well-known term
i got it from alec your dev but it
basically means you you have a primary
link in a backup link and you don't want
any traffic going over your backup link
fine you know and so your primary goes
down all the traffic the switches to the
backup link and then what happens is
your primary comes back up and you still
got traffic on your backup link what
happens okay so here's a really
simplistic model where we're looking at
you look at node 0 that all the traffic
is coming in on the primary link and
then that relate goes down and we have
another solution to the simpler problem
and now you can imagine link comes out
but pay its there's nothing to prevent
it from adopting a different solution to
the stable path problem okay and there
we see that both 3 and 1 have routes
directly to 0 ok now I've sort of you
know I've gone this far without really
talking about dynamic semantics at all
okay so we can sort of imagine a simple
protocol for the stable path problem
where every node is just listening to
announcements from its neighbors about
what path they have and then making
their decisions based on what's what's
the best possible path is right so it
really simple simplified version of BGP
okay so if we think about that protocol
well well you know the end what happens
if there's no solution to the stable
path problem I can turns out the finest
table pass problem has no solution okay
so remember what i mean by solution it's
every somebody everybody's happy not
necessarily happy there their content
they can't get any better given what
their neighbors have so if there's no
solution and all like if every node all
they see is is their neighbors well then
somebody is always going to think they
can get better somebody's always going
to be changing their their path and that
the protocol can't converge right if it
converged we'd have a solution but
there's no solution so it turns out that
that this is sort of a simple model of
how how bgp can diverge and this is a
this this observation was made in 96 how
many people are familiar with this
possibility the basic idea is that yeah
there's no guarantee that the the bgp
routing policies of a collection of
autonomous systems is consistent in any
sense that there is a solution that
there is some static routing right so
bgp can actually diverge just exchange
routing messages forever okay so that at
the bottom picture is just sort of the
state of stable past problem where
you're looking at that and it just says
yeah if there's no solution at all well
you have to diverge but it turns out
those cases where there is a solution
and you've hand over diverge also and
I'll give an example of that okay okay
so here's here's a system that has no
solution
it's called bad gadget and basically the
idea is that everybody prefers a one or
two hop a two-hot counterclockwise path
to the origin okay it's fairly simple to
see that there is no there is no stable
assignment for example if one took that
direct path in 20 well then because if
we're assuming the assignment is stable
that implies that too has to take 210
okay and that implies that well for
can't take 420 so that implies that
three is taking 30 but if three is
taking 30 well if it's a stable
assignment then one can't be taking 10
it has to be taking 130 because that's
the best it can do given the assignment
at three a contradiction so you can go
through taste analysis like this there
is no there's no solution so if we think
about those three different sets of our
psl policies that map down to that
simple system disagree we can come up
with a dozen policies at the bgp level
that could map down to this system and
whether or not they're all sensible in
any way i'm not sure but then there's
always a the possibility of Miss
configuration right but there you go so
one way of interpreting that observation
that broad net all made is that is that
while the system this problem that's
being solved doesn't necessarily have to
have a solution now let's take this a
problem here and add a link between 0
and 4 and let's make for prefer that
most so that's a the system called
surprise and it has a solution the
underlined the the red assignments is a
unique solution to this problem so for
takes the direct path greats and
everybody else walks in on another route
the problem with this is that you can
have a stable routing right and boom
when that 04 link goes down it becomes
bad gadget okay so what this example
illustrates is that everything can be
great but lurking in your never tested
backup policies is a problem that you're
not going to see until some link goes
down okay another another problem this
is a kind of like this lie just looks
nice this is an example where you can
there is a solution but you can also
diverge okay and so on the right hand
side is that disagree subsystem right
member it has two distinct solutions and
we have over here on the left hand side
something that well if one picks the
direct path to zero then everything is
okay everybody that sort of locks into
three and goes it takes that path
however if one locks into the 120 path
then boot that the left-hand side
becomes a bad gadget and there's nothing
you can do it will never diverge I mean
never converge after that point ok so
now notice notice that's in these bad
gadget kind of examples there's always
several autonomous systems that are
preferring some longer path over a
shorter plane right actually it turns
out that that's always going to be the
case but that so you would like to say
that if I can figure let's say all
routers in the world are configured so
that they don't use local pref okay so
in other words basically the decision
process is picture this a s paths and
then do some tiebreaking you'd let use
that it's sort of a baseline for
analyzing let's say proposed extensions
or whatever to bgp because you say well
let's start from that safe world and see
if we can get into trouble by adding
some new feature or whatever so here's
an example so the idea here is suppose
every what you're in a world
where there's no local press but we do
have Confederations can we get into
trouble if within a confederation you
take when you're measuring a s path
length you take member a SS into account
ok it seems like you could code that up
yourself if you wanted to worry good if
your vendor could provide a knob for
doing that kind of thing and here's just
a simple example where you get a bad
gadgetus out of that so the big blue
circles are Confederations and they each
have tues member a SS and so for example
q the router Q has three paths 20
they're all of length 2 from the
perspective of its a BGP table let's say
and it so it just breaks breaks ties
using some maybe the IP address of Z and
RNA okay and so it broke ties preferring
to go through three and now everybody
does the same kind of thing they they
just break ties going to the left and
boom you've got a problem okay here's
another example this is just again
suppose we're living in the world where
there is no local preference but there
is so we know that world safe now let's
add the prefer me global community okay
so here's an example where in the grey
boxes are sort of the bgp level policies
everybody's doing same things nothing
weird about it and pads are being equal
length paths for example at one and
three are just being there's tiebreaking
going on there so they just happen to
pick this counterclockwise path and then
five here is announcing prefer me up to
two and so what we're seeing in tues
policies in the s in the so it's in the
BGP world it's just saying hey I'm doing
shortest paths basically but in the spp
world we see that this one path is for
over the other and then you get this bad
gadget now this isn't saying that the
prefer me is bad or it's not saying it's
good or anything like that it's just
saying it's very powerful okay it's just
saying in a world where everything is
okay only 11 insta one use of this
attribute is enough to get you into a
situation where they won't convert okay
so perhaps there are some guidelines
that need need to be followed when using
these kind of things or use them
carefully something like that okay so
what's to be done here about this
particular problem well what approach of
course is to put the problem really I
was originally looking at was well how
do we pull out our psl policies out of a
database and check them for consistency
we want to say hey there's not going to
be any problem here or there is going to
be a problem potentially this link goes
down website and we've done some
analysis on that and again this is kind
of research II stuff but it turns out to
be really hard even if you had complete
information about psl policies it turns
out to be an np-complete problem to
identify solvability and that kind of
thing so that doesn't mean that it's not
worth while still to you know come up
with some heuristics that work pretty
well in practice and I think that's
definitely an area that we're going to
do some work in okay another approach is
to you know just recognize that this
uniform like this recognize that there
is a possibility of BGP divergence and
try to come up with let's say
recommendations or policies and how to
identify that and how to address that
one thing would to do with it would be
fun would be to you know with 11 prefix
let's say to actually set up in the
backbone some exec you know between
lodge tier one isp set up set up an
oscillation like this intentionally so
that we could use the kind of
infrastructure Craig talk about to
measure what it looks like what does it
look like when this kind of thing
happens and then maybe use that to come
up with some
recommendations or guidelines okay
another approach is a dynamic approach
some sort of dynamic brake on bgp
oscillation nao out flat dampening
doesn't solve the divergence problem all
it does is make it run in slow motion
okay so what will happen is let's say in
a bad gadget is you'll just slow it down
it'll never stop okay and and we've done
some experiments on that and but so one
thing and again this is sort of a
research II topic we've we've come up
using that spp formalism we've come up
with an a proposal to actually extend
the protocol with extra information
where you can dynamically detect a
policy-based oscillation and recognize
it as a policy-based oscillation and you
can see all of the AES Pat I have the
autonomous systems that are involved in
that that policy conflict ok so again
it's that's sort of at the level of this
spp very low level now it's kind of a
research problem right now to bring that
up to the level of bgp and you know is
it scalable is it robust things like
that so some shameless plugs on some
work we've done it again this is sort of
in the academic community we had a paper
in sigcomm this year last year showing
that and that static analysis
essentially of our psl was very hard
okay we also in ICMP we had a paper that
sort of used this spp model came up with
some sufficient conditions for a safety
sanity things like that and then in
infocom coming up next month we have we
use that model to develop this extension
the safe extension to to a simple it
simplified bgp protocol okay the sitcom
paper and the infocomm paper available
on online at the FSA common infocom
sites if you want the icmp paper paper
send email a recent paper that's going
to appear in sick metrics by leash inja
cow and jennifer Rexford
sort of uses some of this formalism and
shows that well if we make certain
assumptions about the world and how
routes are exchanged then they can prove
that everything is always going to be
okay okay and so the question is are the
assumptions valid and how well do they
model what's really going on the
complexity of routing policies really
out there today and of course they
assume that there isn't going to be any
miss configuration there and if you're
interested in that paper I suggest
sending mail to Jennifer at ATT labs ok
questions for Tim
Shaw island I'm interested in in your
opinion using the current tools that the
operators have available to them is
there any intervention they can make
that would stop this oscillation if they
detected by some other means well I
think I think the big problem is when
you see this kind of oscillation you
know from one path to another you don't
really know what the source is you don't
know some flaky interface somewhere or
there's no way of telling right now by
looking why this route is flapping okay
that's a that's why I suggested that I
know if that's what I was suggesting
that maybe some experiments be done so
that we can get a feeling for what it
actually looks like when it happens
right so maybe perhaps it looks a little
different than than the kind of flaky
router flapping that were used to seeing
okay yeah maybe I just wasn't paying
attention close enough but it looks like
all of these examples of problems depend
on piers redistributing routes learn
from other peers to each other which is
currently knocked the case in the vast
majority of the large backbone routers
you tend to only originated the routes
that you are receiving from customers to
peers not other buyers right so that
eliminates a lot of those cases of
problems yeah and I think that's
essentially the bit the idea of the
leash ngao and Jennifer rexburg papers
is that kind of model right but then
again it's already implemented right but
we don't you know the thing is that
these are sort of this kind of a
worst-case analysis write that as the
complexity of BGP policy becomes sort of
unmanageable and you look at the
interaction of policies between peers
and also throw in things like Miss
configuration right and the fact that
link failure can can can you know
activate policies that might not be so
obvious at first right I think you know
it's there's reason to concern here I'm
not saying the the sky is falling or
anything like that obviously I just
think there's reason to be aware of the
problem and to be somewhat concerned
with it well I'm not saying that we
shouldn't be concerned and I'm not
knowing these problems aren't real but I
think we need to be aware that the
default configuration or providers and
what people are recommending and
requiring of their peers is a condition
where these types of failures are not
going to be epidemic now obviously I've
seen plenty of misconfigurations where
you'll end up with something very like
what these problems described happening
with continuous route looping and the
only way to clear it is to pretty much
shut down everything related to that
path right but the default configuration
is that you're not redistributing routes
that you're not originating to other
peers and a common exchange right ah for
lots of very good reasons okay
if you this is a sort of a related
question question about this
presentation and a question sort of for
Craig if you're looking from the
perspective of a number of different
providers and only some providers have
these conflicting policies then you have
you ever seen have you ever looked at it
from a perspective of saying well we see
these prefixes churning but only in a
few different a s is not globally you
know looking past the BGP dampening
window so maybe there isn't actually you
know the t1 going up and down causing it
maybe it's some sort of oscillation or
at least you have that data so you could
run that kind of analysis so after the
fact that would be a great thing to look
for and all of that data that's being
collected out there but obviously you
lose if it's the SS transiting someone
that are right you know having this
problem but as as was pointed out
normally those a esas aren't transiting
each other also although sometimes that
happens right I think all that makes a
lot of sense the difficulty up till now
has been it's been so much junk in the
BGP streams that any type of rational
analysis on trying to find patterns has
been a bit nonsensical but because we've
gotten rid of some these pathologies I
think and things really are being
deployed and new router oh yeah so
hopefully in the future