ok so I'm how coming loose I work for a
company called Blue team you may have
met yesterday given here i'll talk about
large-scale mail architectures so now
we're up at layer seven but still will
be some routing by large-scale I mean
mail server installations with from a
couple of hundred thousand users and
upwards so basically three feature or
distinguishing distinguished features
from for any kind of ASP application not
just mail that sets them apart from from
enterprise systems one is the kind of
scalability scalability require neither
is high availability since these are 24
by 7 systems per definition and the last
one is the ability to do management on
the system while it's in operation for
the same reason it's a 24 by 7 system
and the right in this picture you can
see I try to illustrate that ok people
know the best practices in the industry
is quite advanced on how to build
scalable systems scalable web system
scalable mail systems also have a fair
understanding of how to build high level
high availability systems not cheaply
but but and we build them but also
extremely low maturity in how to build
nan actually systems that can be managed
wireless while the traffic wireless
services up and running without
disturbing traffic so I'll talk about
all three of these or talk mostly about
well kinda how all about scalability
since that's the most understood of
these problems
so the challenge here is really to build
a scalable hi Val abilities system which
is not too expensive that is easy to
manage while the system is up and
running without disturbing traffic ok
the basic we have three base
architectures for email system one is
the simplest possible one where you have
one mail server either a single
processor over multiple with a huge male
storage because this system is doesn't
first it doesn't scape what you can't
you're comparing a bigger multiprocessor
about your sooner or later you hit the
hit the roof the scalability none other
serious problem here is of course crash
recovery you either need the journaling
file system or something like that to be
able to quickly recover from a cash in a
system like this so this is quite
uninteresting when we talk about
large-scale systems next step up is
shared storage architecture what I mean
that you have several mail servers you
spread the load for the traffic among
them for example by and level 4 switch
or even dns round-robin but all all in
this case 3 service share the same male
storage so my mailbox can be accessed
from any server which is the reason you
can use simple load balancing gear in
front of it trouble with the with this
kind of architecture is is the middle
storage it's what most you see down here
a couple of alternative universe sequel
database some fiber channel system and
common theme of this is that either they
don't work very well or a very expensive
or they have both of these problems
okay so what I will focus on is is what
you see at most big ice piece when you
look at the remains systems it
distributed storage architecture but
where the mail store is partitioned
among a large number of mail servers so
my mailbox resides on a particular
subject and can't be accessed at all
from another server and in this case the
storage can be what she could be local
disk typically it's a DBM database
something like that berkeley database
database but are another of bunch of
interesting problems in an architecture
like this so the rest of the slides
vessel discussion will focus on on this
okay so let's start with scalability
this is the first slide again what
scalability for architecture like that
is we can divide that into the three
problem areas basically load balancing
and you'll see what I mean with load
balancing in this case queuing mail
queuing and message routing for smtp and
session routing for either pop or imap
depending on how you read your mail so
start the load balancing when we have an
architecture lipase a balanced load
means that you have an even distribution
of mailboxes on each server because the
number of mailboxes on the server
determines the load on the server so
load balancing is basically a manual
operation of moving mailboxes between
servers man oh man preferably automatic
in some way and you sure need to do that
for for a number of reasons one is that
if your typical eyes PU you go quite
fast so I need to add more servers and
then you have to do a rigid
redistribution of your mail accounts
from one one server to the to another
and also you might have customers that
themselves are going so you have bottle
domains that
quite fast okay so this is what load
balancing a monster in an architectural
art is and a naive way of doing for
moving mailboxes would be to just copy
them from the server to another which is
of course not working you'll see if this
mailbox is accessed while you do it you
risk losing mail so there's a simple
simple algorithm for doing that okay so
the task here is to move mailbox from a
server a to server be redo is that you
first create the new mailbox and lock it
and then change the basically the
routing tables for mail transparent
session routing to the new mailbox which
me and that one is locked which means
that the Pope user cannot access his
mail at this point and the smtp incoming
inbound mail is cute okay Danny move the
contest on all my box the new and annual
unload the new mailbox than your up and
run so you have a short outage here for
four pop users which is how to avoid in
in an architect Lucky's ok next problem
which has to do with the scalability is
one of probably the most serious problem
for a large male installation which is
skewing and the problem is basically
that that suddenly you've got large
volumes of a cubed nail mail to queue
for some particular domain typically
some big and slow domain there are a
number of them as you might know could
be number of courses for that will
happen one is that their mail servers
are down it's impossible to connect turn
narrow is that they you can connect to
them but they just disconnect which
means that you have to queue it and try
to resend it yourself later
or they can be misconfigured either
because they run some strange mail
server software from from some
particular wonder or or that I have what
what they do basically is that they sent
temporary error codes when they mean to
send permanent error codes and temporary
votes means that you have to queue it in
your system and one other happens you
can actually get floated by stuff you
have the queue which can happen really
really quick so this is a very common
situation at the big I would guess any
big ISP and it has to be handled and the
way to handle that really is to first to
detect the situation very quickly so you
need to have an alarm system that
actually monitors the queues nothing not
only the size of the cubes but also the
contents so they can say that whoops now
we have grown but very quickly and the
the reason we are going is that food
calm has seventy percent of the males in
the queue so what we should do in that
situation is somehow to create a new
cube for that problematic domain either
on if our software allows it on the same
host or dedicate a real a machine for a
particular domain so that's that's how
it should be handled very often at least
what i have seen it's not a way it's
handled because well
it's it's really not supported in quite
a lot of common solutions okay next
thing that's that's important for scale
abilities is messed message marketing
and session routing and here the main
issue is actually how to handle virtual
domains should have quite a lot of if
your own big isp you can do that in a
number of ways one ways to for example
allocate the separate IP address for
each word of the main you host which is
probably not a good way to do it because
it's not very scalable and it's hard to
to maintain sort of the Sun my way of
doing it is to have a particular for
example my you see here my real email
address and the ISP rear ives it either
actually rewrite the smtp come on to to
my real name or keep that knowledge in
internal instruction system to some
internal address that points to the
server male 3 this example where my
mailbox resides if we have a rewriting
scheme like this we can actually move
the whole blue tail bertil domain by
simple reigate matching between between
machines rather of course other
addressing schemes we can use so example
solve of systems that support is is son
may leave the alias file and what you
use the table for doing stuff like that
and there's also an alch dropped for
four message marketing based on
l-dub directors but if you do that for
inbound smtp you better do it for pop
and imap as well otherwise the
alternative is that you handle the
inbound smtp quite well but your pop
users are bound to connect directly to
the mail server that the pop server
where their mailbox is residing which is
not at all a good solution for number of
reasons one the most important one is
that it's very hard to to re relocate
that mailbox because it would require
changing client software which is a bad
thing for an idea okay so typically end
up with a architecture like this that
you have a two layer architecture the
bottom layer here is the actual mail
servers but that's the end point mail
servers and the first layer the two
machines up here are that's a real a hub
basically which where you do routing and
also hooking all kinds of spam filtering
you want to do bodies checking stuff
like that and that's the the the the
address you publish in DNS so the MX
records for for all bottle domains point
to the routing hosts here one good thing
without is that the IP addresses of the
the bottom layer mail servers here are
not visible we need not be visible on
the internet so you can actually run
this on a private network behind the the
robbing houses okay so
this is very common I mean most most
lice big guys peace have something
similar to rat okay then you also have
to handle both both outbound smtp and
pop/imap in a similar way so you see
here what we what should do in that case
is basically to to extend the
responsibility of this routing layer the
first topmost layer to also handle
directly handle outbound smtp and pop
proud can I map rally which this picture
illustrates the Pope client goes not it
goes with one level of interaction as
well exactly as the inbound smtp
outbound smtp you connect your
smtpclient to their to the message
routers and they decide what to do and
then of course they have to know that
your client is to be considered to
belong to the local domains you can
relay from from that client so here you
end up with an architecture basically
where you do all message routing or pop
IMAP routing or spam filtering in the
first layer and the second layer is
basically reduced to two pop servers I'm
observers and local delivery so you
don't even need to run an full-blown
empty a like somewhere in the second
year here so this is sort of the
state-of-the-art scalable mail
architecture there is the one big
advantage disadvantage with its
architecture and that is that each tier
tier two server here is singing point of
ever which means that you cannot
wipe out the entire service but if one
of these boxes go down say if you have
ten boxes ten percent of your clients
cannot exhauster their pop account until
this machine comes up and inbound smtp
is less of a problem since it gets
queued outbound smtp is not a problem
since it goes in the in the Tier one
layer but ok you have an outage for some
fraction of your users when it comes to
pop access so to handle that situation
you basically has to have a situation
like this where you have a hybrid
storage solution solution that your
pairs in in the volunteer here you have
some pairs of mail service sharing
common storage which is easier to handle
I multi-home disks or or some low so
low-tech solution you don't need a full
blown fibre channel store shyona Puerto
to handle two machines but it's also a
matter of cost it's not really serious
that then ten or two percent of your
users can lose access to their pop
accounts in knowledge maybe but if that
series this is what you end up with
doing okay so this is
basically a quick overview of of state
or out in in in scalability and what you
can do to to improve high availability
to the point where you don't get any
outages at all visible to fit outside
and the lost issue here is it's the
toughest one which is in service
management so what you really would
expect in a 24-7 system is basically
what you have been used what people have
had been used to for public telephone
exchanges for lost twenty years but you
can reconfigure it in a running system
without disturbing traffic that you can
upgrade the software in it without
disturbing traffic in a distributed
system and that you can redirect traffic
to other points while you need to
replace some parts of the system and I
mean here we are extremely far from this
thing in most installation providing a
noticing in most commercial products
honest very high-end products so I think
this is the challenge to actually build
a really if you want to build a big
really big mail server from the
challenge is actually to to combine the
scalability solutions which are quite
well understood with with a good storage
solution and finding some way to solve
this problem of of managing it all in a
in a rational way
well I've done it so I have some time
for questions some questions / con
and maybe you have a light thanks
thank you how Kyle