that'll so I am rocking on Ubuntu and
this Windows computer doesn't like so I
missed his my own
computer a.m. the hello my name is
really
I was really seems swell there was
journeys during twelve you
and now I am cybersecurity analysts
scene so since 1 year
a me I'm always a but i won
learning and learning and learning and I
love to collect $60 k/ mo Dame
through them to Sheedy countries where
they cut
internets a in other people can connect
and can communicate again I am so
participate to non-profit provider
and I'm so friends a
you know how you can recognize the
French people I'll see
that the one who say sorry for my bad
english
so away from people but not too far
sorry for my bad english so
so with lots of journalists a
lot of people who are thinking about
what journalist
up doing but even if you are
in a safe and democratic own country you
can have
problems and people can take you know
that that's even
if you are email is safe n democratic
and country you can be spied by
NASA all what its so hard to protect
yourself
just knowing you're tours a
against to write to don't have you that
does with you
that's important to protect sources and
after that beginning
who really big nightmare to a ing
to be better and better and better with
security
in France a do look pretty girl
and cool country
you there is a new new low it was a
project when they could just slide
the to reload now a me
they would eat a few days ago now
intelligence can monitor everybody
communications without judge permission
that means
when you add to list they come no who
are your sources
who are you going to you hook who'll you
are calling
sorry who you are writing to and maybe
open using
you remains if you don't think a move to
communications
they say okay maybe
maybe that's because of terrorism all
his for terrorism
they try to to spy you every time that's
because of terrorism
but in france in 86 we heard an attempt
it fayed but it was in
18 86 internet doesn't exist
so this terrorism stories at just
witty if you don't know how you computer
rocks
hull how you can be sure you protect
your data
if you just
up in something a to a two-run program
and you don't know what this problem is
doing how you can know
Eve this program don't take your that
does don't
a don't open your five doled
send you five to
someone there's a distance lol something
like that and if you don't use free
software
how you can know watch a computer is
doing
yeah maybe you you can know because you
are technical
high-level but no more people come no
whether the computer are doing the first
step
ease to use free software
second
civil way the lady is
hosting a sting is
losing your data when you're so nice
okay that's good but they don't know how
to
run a server on something like that so
first you learn how to use go online
we this time so okay you have to learn
about security on your server
having a is this SK and stuff like that
bookie but where I can put the server
they had to you 28 is first in a data
center
civilian enough friends home
with his home computer depends on what
you
do you want to do is friends that's good
because you can learn a lot of things
because so one's here when you have a
question
Burnham something like that but
even is a really good friends
you don't know if she comes excesses
that us
so that's again
problem I love my friends but they have
to protect my sources
and that is most important so you can
who died in a data center and maybe
asking friends to help you to
reeled the security abusive that is a
first step
so first you don't come online second
your own server
after it's time to play when I was in a
deep
the during during and after I'm about to
leave their
I really love to use F think
good month nothing is really good
because you don't love you
your stuff is your in your computer you
as the girl you just
send everything to
see other does ever can be everywhere in
the world
and you have nothing with you so it was
really really good day love
housing was my favorite command but
was again aboard every time you fix a
security problem
a new problem the PO because
or is recalled in but his story
so what is
bash is da business on a bombshell
that's your problem with the US your
poll than a little you can share lead
you say should but shown it is illegal
for you to believe you been
you notified now the food was unique me
sorry system being used to Cedar should
prolly for the mic with exceed 80
but this week those thought apology
sequin
you don't understand that no mothers
infants but
the problem is I am friends and they
don't understand at all
so when you are Germany's knowing
nothing about computer yet thank you
wanted
you can rowing lot a.m.
okay so you have again to us
some friends so too has some hikers in
France we have some hikers space
so you can go on ask question to people
so
another thing you have to learn what is
bush what these measures story
in how to manage with that
you know the a but she story
don't recall you think a month because
its authority
take your computer don't find documents
and see
in the bushes story you made ever think
to a silver
to send you that does you have the
problem because they can connect to the
server
and find it at that so so you have to
ask to your computer
okay dolt recalled 1i sent
is that does okay that's good
but what about my flesh keys MySQL
that begin problems deleted
there's just sheets because you
all know a everybody can
find that as you did it from you is to
get out
with Wii really useful tool so
everybody can fide so you have to cover
and cover uncover and cover your
your jobs are you flush keys or maybe
make a shred
with is the reserve list he's so yet
a new command to know ok it's another
go to say okay that's a good sayings a
sensor data
they don't see the I
cover every to axe so I'm lookin I can
go to the wall
and having no problem was intelligence
okay but if you open you fides
the again it may if you open your fights
before to send
to your 80 20 arm
someone is a newspaper you work for as a
parent is
when you open the file in the memory of
your computer
you that does in the minute as
can be stocked so that's begin a problem
if you clean
all really good if you send all your
cell
and he was a fun with that doesn't that
doesn't your computer
it's again a problem so you
to learn heart to how to
did these tracks the other problem
ease USB a flashed his because when you
going
Breast Center a everywhere when you have
country runs a those places for
journalists
and they put on lots of lots of cash
keys we speak to you
rules and information earns and you see
%uh joins the
good news and they put on the computer
just take the pic to exam permission to
20 years as good
I have everything to write not secured
and that's good
day is as good you have everything and a
man were
knows the solution ease
to never blog a flash your computer
first without knowing and I am
I trying to I'll to check email my
resume RBI
Raspberry Pi a I don't know
if you lose a best way I'm doing that
like you're like a brother one in my own
a me I'm using raspy
rest but Raspberry Pi sorry to move
create an easy though
and verify if is a price flash key is
a there is no a hidden
a dot eggs if I'd because sometimes you
can open a PDF
open a GPG fight in that a
that the name the file any run a mile
away you can't
a you can't open exit side wheeze a
reserve free software reserve hoping to
so is as good if you don't use window
that's a good thing this is it's
not every time every time every time
every time you learn on a new security
solution
every time you discover new problems
reading
so that's good to connect to a server to
put you don't own it
but if you just gonna make we got
business it's security they can
find a terrific and I hope so they can
monitor
0 and the kids find your data and your
sources and I was sick
so filth connect with this is it's
on UAL sever
but didn't rip did for does an improved
its orders in a group that for girls
where they lived in there every grow in
my computer on my server
I every time the puts
the aerobic the inserts
fall a bus routes was a bit upset
engineering
a imogene eaves a find me and the beats
me a lot
a after I well then I will know in
detail why
i would tell my purse world and there
with days ago
okay your mother is a cow and he was
just nothing that my bus world
that's the let the CD way but that's a
good way to protect
sometimes your folder another thing
stuff
you don't know secretary Len and ticking
for the permissions
because you can rights when you want to
sell you know that's
what's when you'll join his you don't
you don't check the sort of stinks and
sometimes
if someone else access to your cell and
can
modify your documents yen
a overseeing all you can
lose everything because you don't have
anything on your computer
home om these issue disputes everything
on the server begin for to check the
mission and
the question is who can access to the
server that's another question about
Asian
but
but but but if you don't want to do all
of that
things can be easy
she States it's time you through you
need to transfer data
you can use
I'll think my favorite command you can
connect
through 20 you can
have no information in the rd's
so that's
a good solution if you don't want to
a mmm to a mmm
to welcome a lot I know the difficult
and I'm learning
already I'm already learning
and they will learn in two years and
three years in five years
a to be more and more below but
only understand when you are young to
let is to just go outside of school
you want to go to the world in order to
make big stories
and a you don't want to
to do I love that you can just please
you stay
because yeah maybe you can be alive
because of that
so that's a good idea is one other night
you can sing too mobile phone more but
for because
you know a now because I've snowed in
fines
we know because I was up there with do
you look at his Asian
there is with baseband the
some intelligence can year what you're
doing
colicin so year that's applauded when
you go to interview
to meet some activities to meet some
political
a important people and there is just one
solution
it was at the microphone that's better
if you have an iPhone you can't do that
and the conformal everywhere every time
if you have another phone
you can be free beat but to get you good
to meet
can do that too a.m. again monday was
teaching
Louis teaching your some security for
journalists and again Tony
0 have to take my password for Gmail
every time on my computer my telephone
yes because if someone take your
telephone and can
access to your emails professional
inmates
can access to your sources can exist to
you work
so maybe maybe your sources can be in
danger
yeah bed typing my password every time
is bothering me
yeah but you can change your job if you
want
that security
he is not so hard when you understand
just litem sings of every day
if you just tried to type every time
your bus routes
could be better
if the one take your computer
or your terrified Eve
you try to use names to
to protect someone that does it would be
better to use nothing
in you will begin step by step and
step-by-step
and maybe better after enough to inlets
there is
some other questions I'm rocking on it
now
a using private chiapas for as is lame
using to use looks to
to to stall some documents but is it
good to start private keys
I him is it better to moan to flash key
on the live distro
all on the Raspberry Pi and
yet that's more and more complex
every day you should try to lay down a
that's complex but but
protecting sources is not a
in france you have lot of janet was a
okay we
use sings when they will create
useful tools okay
but you have to put the justices and no
one that so
so some tubes exist throws
mature put two fingers owes outside of
your us
without a keyboard and try to ram try to
protect your sources
and if you have a problem some people
can help you to fix it
but things exist and
but they still sees is not someone
that's a responsibility
israel's thank you
Leadership Summit mission they
on to questions first one is how long
did it take you to lying
I'm I don't know much about your
background so I'm curious how long did
it take you to get to
this level of proficiency you know you
pop Michael
quite the Savvis is that mean not like a
your average journalist
and and the second question is I will
learn new things everyday and we
we understand that we did something
wrong usually and
until we learn to do it better secure
hospital and I'm curious
when was the last time I mean what was
the last thing
that you learned your doing wrong and
when
was that exactly because you know I just
learned
that having an iPhone is bad and I
learned this today so I'll probably
switch to
a author Jim phone okay so
for the background I leave a I leaves
one year nineteen agents
the between 2009
and mean 2011 a leave desserts
EN a in Tunisia
I was in Sudan I went to say at the
beginning of the revolution
and saw and heard some problems
in my bag time in a jeep people
following you people know you are
giuliani's
the
he had policemen around me was a okay if
you steal ur making interviews and stuff
like that
we can arrest you so I was mobilized to
learn
this stuff so the
at the beginning I just had friend got
good
and try to find some things and after I
met some people
blow girls a Blugirl activist in Egypt
who helped me to secure my my first it's
and after that I just learn then learn
in more recently a help some
I was unit seem to help Syrian people to
communicate
between them and Louise a
with Peabody as a in the world and so
I was between the technical
guys speaking English and some Syrian
people who speak Arabic
in just are a bitch I have a bad Arabic
when I speak Arabic that's like your
world
butts a if I wanted to
the exam to explain them how to protect
themselves
I most lemme
from the technical team so
I don't like that's step-by-step
unstable that
and fathers the second question I'm
trying now to use
a.m. token you know token and it's
really really hard
so I am trying because I want something
in the
they will something great in the so
maybe it's too hot to do for me but I
think it will arrive
maybe we'll see mom so
maybe more the
butts i think im in love and yet you
gonna fail
every day but leads us to fail make they
would be better
it to someone to
in someone here did you
use need to factor to cation
in in your system so far sometimes but
not
or and I A can do yank them
ok I
so arm have used like world
operating systems that are made
specifically for journalists another
non-technical people like bagels which
is bail on the Knicks
Orem I know the Electronic Frontier
Foundation
they maintain a website to you a lot of
information for journalists
and easy to use tools because I mean
Dom I don't want to I mean don't get me
wrong
the information you presented is
interesting
mulberry maybe another interesting for a
lot of people here because they're very
technical consulting
I'm a journalist for example but
I mean didn't offer main the
user-friendly solutions right i mean you
could have included some
actual examples of tools that are out
there and
journalist can use use or maybe storage
secure storage sources
store with operating systems like tails
maybe password managers with two-factor
authentication that about 20 knowledge
model
and includes the vault locally or stuff
like that which
Tim obviously be be useful for on thank
you
this is not this is not a nightmare this
is dream so her
you can find that and it's really easy
mermaid duckworth after that
when you try to go a when you try to go
after using after using SysTools is from
the tubes
what you can do what you can do to be a
mall secure
a but it is good you know maybe
reporter with the border else they give
days
skis to two people are they held them to
install the PM
ideal told about the VM like
a like you
the actual books and stuff like that but
is good too because
the big problem when you have some
julie's ease
they are afraid to change their habits
like
like every well because oh I don't know
with that and I don't know how how it's
working so yeah I'm afraid and I was
like that is beginning
and I you tried 12 in the
the actual machine during months and
when I was ready
i James I tried saw
on the mutual machine at the beginning
but they because he was afraid
a about words this program I didn't know
a ok im doing my computer in
the main problem is people who are
afraid but
when you make the friendly to run
as so when you you tops the
you can help them with that and helps
them to
photo n have the neck that their
questions
how your securing your in government
mine you're in the moment
security what you internet yes how US
securing you're in the moment
okay I depends over depends on what
applications connection since using VPN
yes a use them sometimes the AM
using days the depends on the moment the
Bengals the country because
in some countries a yes I include my you
made in France
and that's good because lots of not lots
but be tough people
improved this that you mates if you're
in a good three
where no one encrypt emails and you are
alarm to encrypt your email a you will
have problems
because they we did the you are a
problem
so depends on the situation depends on
where you are
difference of what you want to protect
there is no
the magical solution have you ever used
ver true or heard about it
but with birds true how you are that is
its spelled the II are to you and it's a
solution to increase your emails
and send them securely and see
the recipient received it and if I
you misspelled the recipient address
again then revoked email
revoked Aki associated with your email
it might be a good solution
if you're corresponding with and trust
that person's no I just use pgp for
for a min yes I don't love to you
whatsoever
but never true is a free extension for
Firefox and Chrome
is open source is free and it doesn't
require for recipient to have anything
is sold
so it might be a good solution for you
okay
thank you I would try we have time for
one more question
now
okay yen thank you thank you