ah hello everyone
hello
i know this is the harder one
but
i'll try to stick to my time and uh
deliver
you know a good talk
so
topic is context-driven security i'm
excited to be talking about this topic
i've been researching on it for the past
three years
in different
under different research
agendas so what i'm going to be
presenting today is one of the research
interests that i've pursued
so context-driven security need for a
critical shift in threat intelligence
it's the year 2022 wake up
january has come to an end it's february
and we can comfortably say that internet
has is now only present
everything is connected to the internet
patients have sensors on their bodies
smart homes
healthcare education transportation
finance insurance electricity education
again
manufacturing cyber attacks have
targeted every single sector
and i i know that this crowd doesn't
need to be convinced about the
importance of security and that it needs
to touch every single sector that i just
mentioned
uh but
out of curiosity i wanted to look up
which is the you know the top most
the the most important threat vector
which impacts all of these industries
that i just mentioned so i'm gonna take
a minute and show you the dreaded
histogram
malware continues to be the most
effective
attack vector across all the sectors i
mentioned i'm not going to show you what
the rest of them are they're not
important for this talk
for us research researchers what is also
important is that
the topic that we are pursuing like
malware research in my case
we also need to get data
to
you know help
with evaluations to support uh you know
the reason that we are doing so
therefore malware research was an
interesting topic for me
so let's center
the malware threat impact on enterprise
networks
for the purpose of this talk but the
impact of this research is across
sectors
and
as we all know machine learning has done
an outstanding job with both defending
and preventing against cyber attacks
emanating from this specific threat
vector
in fact an ai visionary arthur samuel
defines machine learning
as
the ability to learn without programming
without explicitly programming and with
data because machine learning uses data
and learns from it so
this um i know many of you have a
background in machine learning but not
all of you
so the training phase uh is you know
when you train the machine learning
model with this knowledge that you've
gathered from the data
and machine learning
because machine learning algorithms so
there's data there's algorithms and
therefore models
the algorithms can can reason
the properties of previously unseen
samples because they've learned from the
data
in malware detection
uh a previously unseen sample could be a
new file that
will be uh that will be you know
testing this model that we just learned
uh and you will find out whether the
the network was indeed protected against
this new file this malware file so it is
important to emphasize the importance of
uh the the importance of
the data-driven nature of this approach
and uh so
like in the training phase a model
created for malware attack detection and
prevention uh it depends on the data and
it has seen during the training phase so
that's an important concept uh that
needs to be kept in mind uh so that it
can determine
uh
which
features are statistically
significant or relevant
for predicting if the file was actually
malignant or malicious or benign so the
statistical significance is very
important and that comes from the data
that the model has been trained on
so that's
uh something to keep in mind while i
continue with the talk and most
companies have used machine learning or
are using machine learning um
to us to to some degree in their
intuition detection and prevention
systems but machine learning has its
limitations obviously because machine
learning is hard that is the topic of
this this uh this panel and we are going
to be talking about those limitations
and the circumstances where these
limitations
are more pronounced
so we are increasingly recognizing
recognizing these limitations and some
of these challenges
come in the form of false alerts false
alerts uh false positives false
negatives false negatives happen
when a model mistakes a malicious label
for a benign file and false positives
happen
when harmless file or url or an
indicator
that is being scanned in the model that
we just talked about the trained model
uh that i just talked about
that model incorrectly identifies it as
malicious that's false positives so
together they caught they're called
false alerts
and they can't
carry um serious consequences for users
you can imagine that right so you will
continue to see benign files and if
they're tagged as or labeled as
malicious
somebody needs to take care of that
those those people are sock analysts and
uh
you would say that we can impose higher
requirements on the model
and both you know the machine learning
model and the matrix that are defining
uh you know the thresholds whether this
will be
labeled as malicious or benign you can
increase
those thresholds or
you know impose higher requirements for
your models
even then
even then it is it is very difficult to
get rid of
uh you know false positives and false
negatives in fact uh
i was looking around for some specific
uh
data around this and top companies the
the products that they build
uh each product sees terabytes of data
every day and even if a fraction of that
is false alert you can imagine the
amount of time money
goes into uh
analyzing why are we seeing these false
alerts and they can't just let pass
those alerts and what they cause
because of the amount they cause
alert fatigue the analysts
is not able to
manually
analyze those alerts
after a point
so
problem
now we've understood what we're going to
be targeting let's talk about
let's shift gears
uh towards solutions
so um that's what this this research i'm
going to talk about is focus towards
but breaking down the problem into p1 p2
p1 is lack of enough representative data
to test rules and that's why i was
emphasizing on the training uh
aspect of the the learning model that if
there is no representation
in the machine learning model it will be
very challenging for the model to
actually uh to find that
uh
you know to be able to label uh a new
file and then the other problem is
deluge of false alerts that i just
talked about the too many uh to be dealt
with even if you have prioritized them
from low medium-hardened focusing only
on the high ones even then they're just
too many
so
for problem number one lack of enough
representative thera
one solution that
we have
in with that that we are pursuing is
continuous learning uh
and then add most recent data so
new attack vectors new vulnerabilities
keep coming in
uh they're
they're more they're
the way they are attacking those attack
patterns also keep changing uh the
vulnerability might remain the same but
the but the attack pattern might change
so how do we include that into our
learning model
well you increase the data that is being
used to train the model
and i'm going to talk about that in in
the upcoming slides and the other one is
triaging alerts how do you triage alerts
how do you prioritize even the high
priority
alerts
this is this talk is about context
adding context to security so
the direction that we have taken is that
you provide context to your alerts
focusing on the first one first
continuous learning uh add most recent
data
so
continuous learning how does that happen
uh
we found that
so enterprises are constantly you know
uh analyzing their internal telemetry is
coming from logs uh network data
host-based data all of that is getting
analyzed
there is an additional source of data
that can be included in that analysis
and that comes from the internet there
are lots of open source threat
information
that is easily and
from what i have seen freely available
to a degree there is noise in the free
version but that's what i was able to
access
so free freely available open source
open source threat intelligence
written by
sorry i should have moved that moved on
to this one so open source threat
intelligence uh aggregation is what uh
we are
we are we are pursuing as a way to
increase the the learning of the models
uh by increasing the data and this data
is most recent and how do we get that
i'll talk about that so these uh the
open source intelligence actually uh
covers is written by researchers
on trending attacks and what are the
defense mechanisms against those attacks
these might be opinions these might be
blocks these might be actual threat
reports and at the same time these might
these might exist in the dark web where
people have recently encountered uh
you know a new payload or uh
a novel way of
of using an existing vulnerability so
all that getting discussed we can
aggregate that data and that's what open
source threat intelligence
aggregation means and these can be very
useful although unstructured
so i want to show you what i'm referring
to this is more of a
more
you know official and a a better version
of what threat reports are and threat
intelligence looks like uh from mcafee
and this is on uh the sunburst trojan
and uh
so what they basically uh
the the information that is included in
the in these threat reports is
uh how the the attack was discovered uh
the the pattern the attack pattern of
that specific malware uh the
vulnerabilities that were used uh the
indicators of compromise
and
attack patterns and so on and so forth
so although these are unstructured
reports uh these are essentially
opinions written by security analysts
who have varying degrees uh of expertise
and uh and you know also based on the
information available in hand at that
point of time when they wrote that
report so
this is an essential source of new
information that we can gather and you
won't get this from uh binary and you
know from from binaries by static
analysis or behavioral analysis or
dynamic analysis these are written
in uh human you know understandable
language and covers context which
otherwise wouldn't be possible to
capture in code
so that's the advantage that we see in
using this kind of threat information so
our
research uses knowledge graphs to
capture this kind of information
and it's a significant endeavor
it's the data is unstructured how do you
know what to capture how to capture how
accurate that
uh that
that the data is that you've captured
from these unstructured sources of
information
uh and it requires
multi-disciplinary expertise uh in uh
you know
in in the domain in machine learning in
natural language processing information
extraction
and uh of course about security
so let's first talk about how do we
generate a knowledge graph so first i'm
going to show you what a knowledge graph
looks like so for i know it's a little
small
but i'll try
so these are small dots which are
vertices of a large graph
varying in sizes and these are connected
by edges and these edges are essentially
a relationship between
between two uh
between two of these vertices which
means that these two vertices have a
relationship there is a context which
exists between this
circle in this circle so this is
different from a generic graph that you
might have studied in maybe a graph
analytics class or graph theory class
and towards the right of this is
actually a legend
this was generated using neo4j and what
this legend is uh so for example the the
beautiful orange colored circle is about
manware so these orange circles that
you're seeing are malware uh which was
recognized or
the data about it was extracted from the
reports that i just showed you
the light colored ones are the light
oranges malware family and then there
are there is location-based information
where was this where was the impact of
the malware uh found uh what
vulnerabilities were used to compromise
the platform
and so on and so forth
i believe it all of this was captured
only using threat reports and this was
uh from 25 threat reports
and and basically uh just a handful of
malware information was collected
um and then there is another one just so
i can make the uh the concept a bit
clearer so there is all of these are
malwares which are connected to one
another or they're aliases because not
every security company will be using the
same name uh so you need to capture the
aliases so so that you can capture other
details and then combine them and form a
knowledge graph which can be used for
excuse me use for further analysis now
now let's pick one example so flubart
malware has picked up again
it's been around for the past three four
years uh hard to tell when
um because there is always some report
which says that oh a version of it or an
alias of it existed a year ago so i know
it's a small one so i decided to zoom in
now what you're seeing in front of you
these dark colored oranges is one of
them is flubot and the others are
aliases of flu bot flubot malware
and then there is you know same
information location when what when was
uh this flu bot uh you know detected in
a certain location
uh and and name of the the uh different
countries
uh and the impact on devices and so on
and so forth but what is really
interesting are these blue colored
bubbles what these blue colored bubbles
are attack patterns attack patterns
which were captured from these threat
reports
and combining these will give you from
multiple threat reports combining these
can give you the entire kill chain of
this specific malware and that's what
the biggest
takeaway or biggest advantage of using
knowledge graphs is that by using this
unstructured information written in
indian language understood by humans you
can capture this kind of
details about that malware and
extrapolating that consider many such
malwares as part of a very large
knowledge graph
all of this combined can tell you uh
attack patterns or infer attack patents
with little information
as in when a malware threat is evolving
that's the advantage of using knowledge
graphs and that's
what this research is pursuing
okay now adding context we talked about
uh
gathering data from the internet uh
and how do we add context so that
essentially we want to help the stock
analysts right
uh so problem number two was adding
context but to get context you need to
add context to your models if you're not
adding context how will you get context
as an output
so uh
provenance reasoning and trust these are
some of the ways where context can be
added and the the areas that i pursued
so far
um so provenance can come from wiki data
wiki data is an is a very reliable
source
of
information what can be done is the
knowledge graph that i just showed you
those bubbles if you click on one of
those bubbles
we have connected that to the to the
concepts which have been described in
wikidata you click on it and it will
show you the description
of a specific malware or a location
and that's
automated it has automatically been
connected to wikidata now you would
wonder why is it important and i'll tell
you a very interesting example
so there was this
um attack on google a couple of years
ago aurora
you might have heard of it so
when you are extracting information
which
is called aurora
the extraction models will not
understand that aurora was actually a
campaign
it will call aurora as the northern uh
northern lights in i think in ireland
somewhere
right
uh so that's that confusion is uh is
obvious and we want to minimize those
kind of uh those confusions when we are
automating our systems so
wiki data essentially was able to
easily uh you know give us that uh
definition of aurora and the campaign
not our the northern lights
the other one is open source threat
intelligence uh sources so these threat
reports are coming from somewhere
right and that somewhere can become our
um anchor
many of these reports come from
prestigious companies kaspersky
microsoft security reports uh mcafee and
so on and so forth uh that can be tied
in fact we have tied that to the
knowledge graph and that provides
provenance and and for a security
analyst it's important
uh to at the time of analyzing
false positives where did we get this
information from
it's it's a very quick way for them to
go back and look at in fact trace the
alert to the source of the information
so that's why provenance is important
reasoning comes from knowledge grabs and
ontology we we followed the ontology or
taxonomy based approach because um
because we created knowledge graphs with
certain questions in mind and those
questions can be answered if you give
them a structure
and structure comes from
classes classes can be
can be defined in ontologies so i don't
want to go into that because of the
limited time we have and then there is
trust that's an area that i'm still
pursuing how do you add trust to to the
models which are extracting data as well
as to uh to the source of information
uh so how do we get from how much time
do i have one minute okay okay okay
so how do we get from here to here i
think that's a valid question i already
talked about ontologies and then there's
in information extraction models named
entity recognition and relation
extraction
so it's it's a multi-disciplinary
research uh
where you need in uh
well nlp
and then there's disambiguation core
referencing and deduplication
with this large corpus of data comes
noise there's there comes duplications
there comes pronouns so you need to
clear them all up so that your knowledge
graph has minimal noise
uh this is the
architecture for the first malware
knowledge graph that we created i don't
want to get into it but it mostly talks
it mostly covers what i already talked
about
so how do we use this knowledge graph
we have a case study in one of the
papers
so you pose a query to this knowledge
graph like
there's an indicator of compromise
coronavirus themed attacks and the
relation which is the line that
that that is connecting these these
circles targets so you have a query
corona wise streamed attacks targets and
what it will give you is a set of
results
and these are the options that are
potential answers
and you get that with a confidence score
and along with that also the data source
from which
uh
this information was extracted so this
is how we are adding context to the
results
of our predictions uh if that data
exists and if that data does not exist
then it becomes inference
so parting notes
end of the talk is we need to go beyond
measuring the performance of models
using accuracy precision f1 scores we
want to be able to help
analysts by inferring with confidence
and context
and then
that's the research frontier it's
triaging at scale and automation
so i'll be happy to take questions now
thank you
you