hey everyone i'm radha mashagba from
yukon
in this talk i will tell you about
supporting the privacy for payments as
well as arbitrary computations on
blockchains i will tell you why this is
challenging and where we stand with
respect to the current and potential
solutions that we have
imagine a world where we can use bitcoin
to pay for everything
so we have the blockchain which is
simply a public immutable log
of all the transactions that happened so
far in the system this blockchain is
maintained by the miners um each of
which is holding a full copy of this log
and working on extending it
let's take video on demand as an example
so in order to pay for a video uh the
user's wallet will issue a transaction
to transfer coins from the user's
address to the vendor's address and it
will broadcast this transaction to the
network
the miners will validate uh all
transactions they receive uh and they
will package them uh in blocks
uh and then they will compete with each
other to solve a mining puzzle
only the winner will get to append the
new block to the blockchain
at that time the transaction will be
published on the blockchain and then the
user the vendor and everyone else will
be able to see it
which implies that the payment has been
refilled
this model unfortunately has two or
suffers from two main
limitations the first one is
functionality related uh bitcoin is
mainly about currency transfer
and it has a limited scripting language
so it doesn't allow the users to ask the
miners to execute arbitrary code and it
doesn't allow them to build
sophisticated applications on top of its
blockchain
the second limitation is about
privacy uh
so remember the blockchain is public and
anyone can read its content
so yes we use random looking bitcoin
addresses that don't require real
identities
and yes we can be extra careful and
generate a new address for each new
transaction
however all these techniques
support only pseudo-anonymity
several studies uh have showed that
transaction linkability or have showed
that transaction linkability can be
utilized to link these addresses back to
their real owners
so back to our example uh everyone will
be able to uh tell that this user has
purchased a video from this specific
website or a specific uh vendor
addressing these two limitations started
almost in parallel and initial solutions
went different directions
in other words they either uh improved
the privacy of the bitcoin model or they
extended its functionality but remained
public
let's explore uh both directions
starting with the functionality one and
see if we can achieve both of them at
the same time
ethereum was born to address the
functionality uh or the limited
functionality of bitcoin by allowing the
users to execute arbitrary code on its
blockchain
and it pioneered this movement
naturally other systems inspired by the
ethereum model
have emerged such as algorand and
cardano
in this model the miners form a global
virtual computer
users can write arbitrary programs and
deploy them
on the blockchain as smart contracts
anyone can ask the miners to execute any
function
in these contracts
so
a user
when invoking a function will provide
inputs
the miners will perform the computation
over these inputs and produce outputs
and then update the blockchain state
accordingly based on these outputs
this builds a model for computing on
demand uh it's powerful and it has or it
found numerous applications uh such as
decentralized governance and
decentralized finance or defy and many
others
on the privacy side uh initial solutions
targeted the bitcoin model uh with uh
with the goal of mainly supporting
private payments
this resulted in several academic and uh
industrial initiatives such as z cash
quiz quiz monero and many others
and
the general paradigm behind these
solutions is
hide and prove
so
instead of sending a transaction in the
clear to the network
hide it inside a cryptographic
commitment or simply encrypted
and to allow validating this transaction
uh to make sure that it is correct
without revealing its content uh
generate zero knowledge approves uh
attesting uh that the hidden transaction
satisfies the correctness requirements
uh as
stated by the system
so uh again back to our example um a
transaction will be translated into two
components
first the user's wallet will encrypt the
transaction and then it will generate
a proof
uh this proof uh simply states that uh
the users or the
which is the hidden transaction
satisfies the correctness requirements
that minor uh usual or that miners
usually check
at a basic level these include uh
that or attesting to the fact that the
user owns the coins that she or he wants
to spend and uh they are not spending
more currency than what they are
this proof is publicly verifiable so the
miners and anyone will be able uh to uh
verify that the hidden transaction is
correct
um in this paradigm anonymity is
achieved using what is called anonymity
sex
so the zero knowledge proof will also
attest to the fact that uh among a set
of uh private coin addresses the user uh
owns one of them without revealing uh
the address itself
but remember
bitcoin is still public
applying uh core changes like these that
we just described to the network
protocol will result in a hard fork if
not all the miners accept the changes
uh such hard forks
will result in two or more blockchains
and it partitions the network and the
mining power
for this reason uh private pay or
privacy preserving uh payment solutions
uh produced new systems with their own
blockchains and native currency rather
than uh being updates uh to their
bitcoin network protocol
so
we have systems that improve the
functionality of bitcoin such as
ethereum
and uh we have systems that improved the
privacy of bitcoin uh
such as zcash
and the question is can we have it all
in other words can we have privacy
preserving smart contracts that operate
on private inputs and produce private
outputs
more initiatives have emerged towards
addressing uh this question such as
zether zexi smartafacci kachina and many
more
the
solutions or these solutions uh adopted
uh
two paradigms uh the off chain and
on-chain
the option paradigm uh yeah and it comes
like which paradigm they used it depends
on where the private computation is
being performed
uh in the off chain paradigm uh
the
users or maybe other parties will
perform the computation of chen meaning
locally while in the unchained paradigm
the computation
is performed by the miners themselves on
the blockchain
in more details um the off chain
approach uh performs the computation
over the actual inputs locally then it
encrypts the inputs and the outputs and
provides zero knowledge proofs that the
computation has been done correctly
several
systems
have adopted
this approach such as zk and xc to name
a few
so
the users or the end users themselves uh
perform the computation over their uh
inputs then the users also encrypt the
inputs and the outputs and generate zero
knowledge proofs
while
the
miners only role is just to verify the
zero knowledge proofs and apply any
state changes to the blockchain
resulting from the computation such as
transferring currency for example
so most of the heavy lifting work is
done on the user side
and we no longer have the computation on
demand model so now the users themselves
they have to coordinate and perform the
computation rather than asking the
miners to do that for them
i should note that there are uh
other offchain solutions where they let
the users delegate the computation to a
trusted third party or trusted hardware
instead of having the users do them
but i'm not going to discuss these in
this talk
on the other hand
the unchained private computing paradigm
extends uh the
paradigm of a private payments that we
saw before
uh in the sense that we don't only hide
uh or encrypt the inputs and provide
proofs that they are correct we also
let the miners uh perform computations
over these uh encrypted inputs and
produce encrypted outputs
uh smart she introduced this idea where
it combines fully homomorphic encryption
and zero knowledge approves to build a
privacy preserving smart contract
scheme
in particular
fully homomorphic encryption allows us
to uh compute or operate over encrypted
inputs so we have two operations
homomorphic add and homomorphic multiply
that
allows us to add or multiply the
ciphertext of uh inputs and get a
ciphertext of the actual results which
is the actual sum or the actual
multiplication
having these two
basic operations allows us to compile
any computation into a privacy
preserving format using these operations
and again we still need the zero
knowledge approves uh to uh a test or
can
provide proofs that the encrypted inputs
are correct and valid
uh so um
using these operations a smart contract
can be compiled into a privacy
preserving uh format or version by
involving homomorphic add and multiply
instead of the regular uh ones
users can invoke
any function in the smart contracts and
they provide encrypted inputs zero
knowledge approves for them and then the
miners will execute the computation over
these encrypted inputs and uh provide uh
encrypted outputs
uh these outputs can be only decrypted
by the key owners uh of the uh
under which the inputs or the original
inputs were encrypted so only those
users will be able to decrypt the
results
uh this uh builds uh
a model for private computing on demand
because as you see uh the heavy lifting
work of the computation is done on the
miners side and users can simply just
submit requests to have the computation
being performed for them
so
is the problem solved and it is just a
matter of selecting a solution flavor
unfortunately no
private computation over blockchains
introduce several challenges that need
to be addressed before having any viable
solution
concurrency is a huge problem with when
dealing with accounts changing the state
of an account will invalidate all
pending zero knowledge approves tied to
the original state of that account
and this in turn will
invalidate all transactions tied to
these proofs
the current solutions that we have rely
on locking these accounts and delaying
any currency deposits until all pending
zero knowledge approves
are verified but of course this creates
an availability and usability problem in
the system
another issue is dealing with inputs
belonging to multiple users
so
for the on-chain model this means that
we have inputs encrypted under several
public keys
an idea here is to use multi-key for the
homomorphic encryption schemes that
allows us to perform computation over
inputs encrypted under different keys
however the decryption process for these
schemes is interactive and requires all
users to get together in order to
decrypt the results
uh for the on for the option paradigm
to
it's like operating on inputs belonging
to multiple users increases the burden
on the end user
themselves because these users they have
to get together and coordinate the
computation
uh over their private inputs using for
example multi-party computational
protocols and uh produce the output
and these protocols are usually
interactive uh and computationally heavy
efficiency also is a big problem uh
privacy preserving uh
solutions for blockchains usually rely
on advanced cryptographic primitives uh
that
incur
high computation and storage costs
uh for example uh generating a zero
knowledge of proof uh to attest to the
correctness of even a simple computation
can take the user more than a minute
while this takes only a few milliseconds
for a private payment
on the storage side a single homomorphic
multiplication operation
can generate a cipher text of a size
exceeding 100 kilobytes
and this is compared to just uh less
than one kilobyte which is the size of a
private payment
this adds to the efficiency problems
that permissionless public blockchains
already have and trying to solve
in my opinion
the path forward doesn't necessarily
mean that we have to be on one edge of
the spectrum
i think having a hybrid solution is
better in the sense that we reduce the
amount of computation to the minimum or
which is the unchained computation to
the minimum level required for
coordination while doing the rest of the
work of chen uh perhaps on a secondary
temporary chain uh managed by a subset
of the miners for example and of course
optimizing for efficiency is a key uh
such as developing
more efficient fully homomorphic
encryption and zero knowledge proof
systems
this will also promote
the
privacy preserving
applications and techniques when applied
to blockchains
so
bottom line
privacy is a critical
for the future of blockchain systems
especially those
employing or supporting smart contracts
and yes lots of work has been done
but this is just the beginning more
efforts are still needed on both the
research and the engineering sides to
address the challenges that we still
have
thank you so much for listening and i
hope that you found this talk useful
thank you