so that's a wrap I hope you enjoyed the
event no matter how chilly it got at
times or how pitchy it got at times
so thank you so much for attending I
know some of you flew abroad and some of
you walked a lot and some of us talked a
lot and annoyed you so thank you so much
for staying
and I don't know how to use this but I
hope I'm using it right
um
yeah so thank you so much for attending
the con and it would not have happened
without you we did this for you and we
if you enjoyed it and share us the
opinion and all the yays Or Nah that'll
be great so thank you so much and I'd
like to now go ahead and thank the
sponsors we have our Diamond sponsors
Red Hat cystic updates and VMware tanzo
we have a platinum sponsor appearo and
we have our gold sponsors as well so
thank you so much we would not have been
able to do it without you
and we also have our wonderful program
committee who were here to cool at all
the wonderful talks that you listen to
and and provide you with the right
agenda right content so we were right on
top of it for last few months so thank
you so much for everybody and there are
a lot of members that are not mentioned
here be the CTF team or the events team
or anybody who really advised us and got
us moving thank you so much
and now I will now hand it over to James
and Andy to wrap up the CTF
thank you very much
um so the last couple of days we've been
running a CTF event here yesterday we
ran a couple of introduction workshops
and today we had an all-day event just a
couple of numbers on screen uh we had 50
clusters 80 Flags 11 hints
560 total points possible and 74 flag
submissions
puppies thank you
so we can see it was pretty tightly
fought event which is really good to see
we actually had a lot of collaboration
uh this year
which is great lots of people working in
teams
and the top four users
were
Adrian Nick Mata Hertz and Alex so
congratulations
[Applause]
so thanks everyone who played
um we welcome any feedback and if you're
interested in the solutions please come
and talk to us
thanks
excellent and thank you to metahertz for
choosing a genuine hacker name in the
context of the rest of the individuals
right
let's talk briefly if you haven't heard
it before about tag security who we are
what we do and why we care so much about
trying to raise the bar for cloud native
security
we have a repository everything we do is
GitHub driven we are modern developer
flow focused we come from a practitioner
background instead of an abstract
ethereal security deployment stopping
background and really we're looking to
work with projects to enhance their
security and dispel some of the latter
old security practices which involve uh
perhaps floods fear of deployment
instead we prefer to deploy regularly
and enshrine modern development
practices
so what does that mean it means we are a
voluntary and community-based
organization of course the Linux
Foundation runs kubecon we are under the
cncf the cloud native Computing
Foundation but we operate with our own
editorial Independence I suppose from
one perspective which means that we're a
collection of uh a raggedy collection of
voluntary individuals as you can see
enthusiasts is probably the strongest
defining commonality
many of us are lucky enough to do
security for a living we also welcome
people from an educative or academic
background as well as researchers
hobbyists there is no minimum bar to
entry we're thankful for anybody who
chooses to spend their time with us
goals really this concept of
strengthening the ecosystem tax
Securities mandate is under the
technical oversight Committee of the
cncf to ensure the products and projects
that are looking for that stamp of
approval looking for access to the
marketing budget looking for the
reflected associative Glory that comes
with being in the same Foundation as
kubernetes one of the fastest growing
projects in the history of Open Source
plus the Cavalcade of other projects we
have with us
are appropriately hardened that we don't
miss the foot guns that we don't ship
things that do not have that minimum
standard of technical security quality
we identify gaps this is part of our
threat modeling process that we will
talk about education is really important
thank you for arranging and running the
CTF today James
part of the points of running those sort
of things is enshrining the adversarial
mindset in defense of security
it's only really possible from a Sun Tzu
perspective to know your enemy and
defend against them with a full
understanding of The Suite of
capabilities an attacker or adversary
may have
I hope that we're the kindest
approachable Security Group in the
history of security uh you be the judge
we do meet regularly and have very open
discourse there is no nerd sniping going
on here
fostering maturity this is part of our
mandate to help grow the projects in the
cncf engaging more communities we do
this intrinsically by virtue of those
organizations coming to us as part of
that Toc mandate and stepping up through
the levels advancing hopefully to
graduate
we're there as part of that path and we
look to collaborate and work in tandem
with the project themselves
finally nurturing growth and
participation it is a high pollutant
goal
we really want as much contribution we
are the product of or we are the sum of
our parts really we are the product of
the contributions that people make to us
and we're nothing without the community
that builds and supports us so thank you
to everybody who has contributed and
please do throw your hat in the ring if
you would like to understand different
security mindsets and different ways of
approaching problems there really is no
finer community in my humble opinion
our Charter protection of cloud native
systems this is our goal the Advent of
all this new technology brings a rush of
developers as we saw at the Advent of
the cloud native Renaissance
the people who are delivering code were
writing golang
golang is relatively exclusive in terms
of language penetration in 2013 there
were not many security Engineers writing
that language and so we see incredible
utility afforded to developers and
operators with some attenuation of
security Focus because again of the
complexity of penetration of dealing
with a language with concurrency
Primitives I suppose
what about rust we ask ourselves the
Russ Foundation is uh is interested
we're yet to see a lot of rust turning
up in the cncf perhaps you can correct
me but uh yes as it advances we will
also be looking for Rush security
practitioners because that is certainly
somewhere that we do not currently have
strong representation
it is exactly the same problem the long
tail of
uh the short entrance
to uh
The Humble brag from Mr cattle's that we
have two implementations of the update
framework one of the First Security
projects to come through tag security
with uh published security properties
and a known attack and defense surface
but yes please anybody interested in
helping the ecosystem we are raising the
bar of security universally
we have next helping developers meet
security requirements these are the
abstracts sometimes security
requirements that developers find hard
to reconcile with genuine
implementations this is where we can
provide value we've been through this
process multiple times and we look to
minimize the friction involved with
implementing
again these abstract security properties
and common tooling for audit and
reasoning about system properties
we have provided some organizations and
a reference to spiffy Spire threat
modeling work here especially with very
detailed security properties that can be
given to adopters so the systems that
they build upon these security tools
and we're in a space where we know that
rolling our own security tools is the
method of Last Resorts that write your
own cryptography do the minimum you can
try and Implement other things but when
there is a gap in the market where there
is innovation when there is the bleeding
edge instead of allowing adopters to be
cut on that bleeding edge we provide
them with for example in this case
a matrix of compromise an attack Matrix
what happens when an attacker has this
level of access to your system these are
the security properties that still
remain these are those that you should
mitigate with other controls I advise
you if you're interested to look through
that work as an entry point to
understanding
the capabilities of some of the people
that I'm lucky enough to work with
with that
thanks to my co-chair Brandon Lum who is
here today aradna who also spends a huge
amount of time working in the team
we're lucky to have an active and vocal
Tech lead Community we welcome Mr Justin
kappels back after Hiatus very pleased
to have you with us again we have Andres
here push cars in the room I hope
somewhere or at least was and is around
and uh we we have uh of course uh then
Michael Liebman who is also our
interface into the open ssf and into the
salsa steering committee and then I'm
lucky to be joined on stage by Marina
and Ragga who have joined us recently uh
we also have uh Matthew who perhaps
isn't here but is working actively
on a complex threat model dealing with
Argo CD this is how modern git OBS based
deployments occur we also have as we'll
see coming up work with flux and githubs
in general cert manager
um again huge thanks to the team and I
will pass over to Marina all right thank
you
um so I'll talk a little bit next about
a couple of the projects that the tag is
currently involved in
so here's a quick
highlight us some new projects some
things that just finished so there's the
cloud native security white paper we
have a version two of that white paper
that was recently released as well as an
audio version of the white paper that's
available online for folks who prefer to
consume it in the audio format another
white paper that was recently released
was the supply chain security white
paper so that's also available these
slides will be available when they have
links to all of these projects they're
also available on GitHub and the other
breaking project is this Cloud native
security controls catalog which is a
catalog and GitHub where you can access
all of the controls and
and go through those some other upcoming
projects these are some ink progress
projects this is a great place to get
involved if any of these have your
interests and have open issues on GitHub
to track all of the different progress
this includes the lightweight threat
model threat modeling project the
version 3 of the cloud native security
white paper because security is always
evolving and so we need to keep making
versions of this white paper until we
capture everything in perfectly which
will never happen and then we have the
cloud native security controls mappings
there's a couple different versions of
that mapping the cloud native security
controls to existing standardization
efforts
and we have some security assessments so
lots of ongoing ones here I think what a
couple just completed some some link
there that are ongoing or upcoming
and the zero trust white paper is also
an in progress project another white
paper explaining Focus this time on the
zero trust architecture for cloud native
and
um the V2 of the audio for this Cloud
native security white paper that covers
the V2 version of the white paper
instead of the V1
so that's kind of what we have ongoing
and again links to GitHub if anything
catches your attention with lots more
detail about all these projects so I
encourage everybody to get involved and
join us in whichever version of this
whichever project seems the most
interesting to you
and I'm going to pass it on to Raga to
talk a bit about where you can jump in
and some kind of quick calls to action
for getting involved today
I missed one thank you which was I've
been eyeballing him about the spiffy
work but of course thank you to Andres
Vega who is also our Tech lead for this
piece of work and everyone else was
called out already
cheers
okay so now that we've established we
are the kindest hum list and the most
welcoming Community here and there is a
ton of work for everybody and a recent
study astonishingly says that there is
only one security engineer for every 100
developers which is a really really
really less amount of numbers so we need
you we need you to come join us
collaborate we're really friendly we we
are not at all scary and we're not scary
as our vulnerabilities are so come join
us and how you could help immediately is
by
joining and sharing the survey
responding to the survey and share
whatever you know how supply chain is
affecting you so this really helps us in
driving our roadmap as well as derive
some key insights on where we can
improve so take a time take a moment
scan this QR code please respond to the
survey and we really will be benefited
out of it
I'll pause a moment so you actually take
your phones out and scan this please
yeah
all right
and we are active on a number of
communities if slack is not your cup of
tea then go ahead check out our GitHub
we have GitHub as our single source of
Truth we maintain everything via GitHub
there are a ton of issues last I checked
it was more than 130 so feel free to
check out all our issues wherever you
want to get involved just drop a message
or drop a comment there and we'll get
back to you
we are really active in Twitter as well
as well as our mail mail lists are
active as well so whichever platform you
favor you can go ahead and get involved
and we meet weekly uh on Wednesdays in
two different time zones in APAC as well
as U.S time zone so feel free to join us
whichever time zone you are we have a
room for you
and if you are sometimes like me Miss on
Zoom meets there is always a YouTube for
all our recordings so feel free to go
back check it out and whatever you're
interested in come join us
and more importantly we are going from
Colo to solo so we need your support
check it out and the cfps are open so
submit and we look forward to seeing you
here again in four months miss us maybe
but we'll be back in four months thank
you so much thank you from our raccoon
[Applause]