welcome to this talk about building
separate things thanks to God fuzzing
my name is Jeremy I'm an application
security engineer at grafana Labs I
joined six months ago I used to be a
back-end developer a long time ago
mostly coding for security products in
Java and some.net go is not my main
language but I like the design decisions
they made from a security point of view
uh started in graphernal labs in March
2022 so that's further new
uh so we are on the beginning of the
security Journey but because grafana lab
is all about transparency there are
things we already wanted to share
and you will see in their presentation
there are many links they point to
GitHub repo that are public and all the
PRS and all that so you can
follow up on that and see that it's real
data
uh what we will start doing is like even
though we're as good secure defaults
we'll see that it's still possible to
server password
and we talk about the fuzzing trying to
and I don't know we can help like
detecting past reversal then we will try
to First Mark complex
see that
writing predicates that are needed for
filling
can
be that easy
and then we'll follow up with next steps
and like once you have good feeling what
should you do next to like the more
value out of it
so
because
girlfriend I love is all about
transparency we share first or first
zero day that took place in December
2021 so I was not yet an employee but I
discovered a lot about the context
thanks to public blog posts and then
public purpose one of the issue was
fixed by that time the security team was
only one member the size of Thomas Owen
uh
and basically what happened a security
researcher responsibilities closed
across traversal in the code of grafana
on December the 2nd
it was rather bad it's called as high
because it allowed to basically download
uh
any files running as a graph funnel
process from the server
and out of excitement this researcher
tweeted that he found a press Traverse
wall another not the specific place in
the source code that was vulnerable
reduce that he found one
and a few days later we identified on
December the 7th that well this
vulnerability was actively exploited
making it to zero day service other
researchers when they are there but hey
there's a past traversal in this code
they could find it because they they
knew that if they look for something
they will find it
it was also fixed on December 7th uh the
question like you may be asking now is
yeah but even go supposed
to have a really good standard library
with safe defaults and then
why did it happen
well in fact the
method fivepas.pin is tricky let's see
why if you just tweet the documentation
quickly you just like somewhere with the
first sentence and say yeah it cleans a
clean returns a shortcuts fast
equivalent to pass so it looks like a
really good candidate
to filter any side paths you could
receive as input and to get the camera
nickel from out of it and then somehow
You can conclude that you will be saved
but if you read in details and I don't
ask you to do it now because it's it's
kind of really confusing there are
several steps and it's not easy to
understand each of those and all that
and
that I'll try to make a recap it's just
like
if you just use Simple wall
papers.fin will remove any dot sequence
which has a sequence that are dangerous
from the past 12 also point of view
because of the other one that can allow
you to
jump to uh top level folder so it will
remove all of the all those those
sequence in all the Inner Elements and
also on the first element if it starts
with the Slash
which means that if the first element
does not start with the slash it won't
filter it
smoke proof you just go to the go
playground uh
and you give
an input that dot slash data and then
you see that what
it's not clean as expected to
the function is doing what it says in
the dock but the developer may be
expecting something else
so now let's look at the vulnerability
in detail so
aetv is using two lines first thing we
were doing we were cleaning a web input
so we received a file pass
and we were just executing five plus dot
field and thinking that we will get the
uh canonical form out of it and then we
join this file pass to plugin directory
and so somehow we were expecting that
all the files or would be content within
this plugin directory and which was not
the case because of this uh let's say
unexpected Behavior what's really
interesting if you see
the source code a few lines below you'll
see that we have a comment uh that's uh
a word
or the security Linker goes like that we
are running
and the developer said that well it's
safe to ignore gossack warning his g304
since we already cleanly requested five
plus
uh so somehow like it could feel like
it's a bit of pity uh because
with
like some other two let's put it
something that could be dangerous and
then we reached a conclusion that well
it's not and if you read the details of
this uh goes like warning kind of like
awkward
thing is that there's a recommendation
you need and that said yeah well you
should just use bypass.clean so let's
say any reasonable developer we will get
this warning we'll look at the
corresponding Dock and say well now I'm
fine I'm using fightpass.clean
but it's not
because we have this past traversal so
how did we fix it well somehow
try to an easy way uh which just
add a slash
in front of the file price we received
so that's now somehow we are making the
key method PF as we expected it should
have been
and uh one unit test has been added to
check those relative past stuff and
making sure that we don't get outside of
the plugin directory yet you could
say that here one unit test may not be
enough
also sharing for transparency
site descriptions we had on this topic
and well three different proposals
one of them was
normalizing all the URLs so that in a
business logic you don't really get
toggled slash so you somehow you do the
filtering before it happens in your
logic another interesting comment was a
way to silence this concept group
but it's clearly it also clearly said
that yeah we have the risk of getting
blind to this issue because maybe it's
not fixing it it's it's just tricking
the uh goes like tool
and the last question which would be the
last point which would be really more
interesting for us a point about like
making a security help a library out of
it so that other developers don't get
tricked by that uh and then yeah
question you can ask yourself is okay
but
how are we confident that
only adding a slash
in front of it will fix all the possible
plus traversal issues we have
uh so that's why now we will be
discussing about your fuzzing
so first thing in a few words uh the
goal is to extend unit tests
by predicate predicates are somehow
General truths and Tamil we want to
extend the uni test
by predicate that say that those kind of
things should never happen like for
example for the plugin stuff you say hey
I never want that the resulting file
pass is out of my uh plugin folder
and then what does filling do uh well in
fact it's uh it's uh it's an engine that
will generate a really big amount of
pseudo random inputs and test them
against those predicates
so
now it's available natively in go from
version 1.18 which is really good
because you don't have to depend on the
external tool that is not augmented that
is hard to use why you need specific
config files to every training and all
that and that what's really nice with
the goal integration is by default as
soon as it has if it finds something
that breaks the predicate it will create
the corresponding test data test data
and then as soon as you relaunch a unit
test this test data will be including in
it
the default implementation is a
never-ending Loop because you are
generating random inputs well in fact
they are kind of there are deterministic
permutations on inputs uh
but it's it never ends because you you
have so many like possible inputs of
course you can configure it and say yeah
you can stop after a given the amount of
time and with the assumption that if you
don't find something quickly it could be
safe enough it smells is traded uh you
could you can choose a number of workers
and CPU course you you want to use
uh so there's a rather nice tutorial but
we will just use uh the past traversal
which been discussing about
you so
what has been done is in this GitHub
repo
that is a really simple example uh well
team paths where the validation logic
has been extracted into this really
simple method where we choose to slash
Plus or parameter and we clean it
and so what do you have to write to have
the threading test working uh I won't
focus on all the details just on the
important points
first thing you are declaring are test
cases so that this is a list of inputs
there are four
three sorry here uh
and those somehow correspond to unit
tests and what's really nice with the go
implementation is that if you run it
as is so without like launching the
phasing engine those will be considered
as regular unique tests
and then
really in the specifics of the first
method you you're telling which
parameter you want to First
then use for your parameter in the
helper Library
and then you write the predicates so for
this example there are two the first one
is yeah while you expect expect that the
clean output starts with a slash because
with really adding the Slash and if we
are we don't have a slash anymore it
smells bad it means that somehow an
escape has been found
and then the other predicate is making
sure that we don't have any past
traversal sequence a new pastoral
sequence is slash dot slash which means
that somehow you are able to move up uh
One Directory
all you have to do is either you just
launch this really small clip but what
you have to do is make sure you have a
correct conversion
run the regular unit test because of
course if the few inputs you've already
provided by activity tests it's not
worth launching a b engine crunching
millions of input
if there's already something
that you know that break some predicates
and that if you really want to start the
fuzzing loop you just have to add a
minus minute first and the name of the
test you want to First
so it looks like super easy uh
but fighting the predicate is not
straightforward it's a bit more trial
and error at the beginning if you will
write predicates that are not totally
correct and fuzzing will find valuation
but in fact there are valid outputs
uh and then searching will also identify
counter cases where it's really hard to
decide if it's a valid or invalid output
but it's worth closing is really useful
because it forces you to make
requirements more explicit and because
there will be less ambiguity you will
have less vulnerabilities because you
you will know what you would be the
behavior of your software under let's
say world word conditions
so for example when to be totally honest
I didn't get the correct predicate first
so I saw that I would want to check this
press 12 also looking at the dot slash
because for me it was enough to say hey
we are with this character sequence I'm
able to move up uh directory level and
then you just learn fuzzing on it and it
really quickly finds a violation and it
provides you the input
and the output and it's really hard to
figure out if is it a legit input like
if you receive other five pulse
something that's called 0.0
and is the corresponding output valid
well it starts with a slash
but does it make sense does it
cannot pass troubleshold with that and
here you will have the question about
like should I be more strict on input
validation and do not trust that or
should I try to do something in my
validator to get rid of that
so that's why now we will be looking at
more complex helpers
so
I took this
example uh
and I
somehow extracted your source code uh we
have plugins in grafana and plugins are
used to add features and they are
positively just uh
a zip file that you unzip in a folder on
the server and what we don't want of
course is that within this folder that
there are Sim links that point out
outside of the plugin directory so for
that we have a helper method that's
called uh is seeming relative Tool It's
rather artery so yeah well go is not my
main language even though I have to read
it three times it was a bit hard to
figure out what it was doing so it's
doing a clean uh
then it's going it's calling the fight
pass the trail you know if it's a
relative pass or not and then it has an
uh return condition well that's
basically looking for DOT slash
which is just like the sequence I was
choosing before that uh
well a predicate I was using before that
was not really okay
so when doing that code review I was
just yeah well uh maybe fuzzing can help
decide if like this validation logic is
doing its job or not so for that I had
to write the first test
uh
and then it became obvious that the
predicate is not straightforward so
somehow are too extract it into a
function called expected result and then
in the fuzzing logic the only thing we
are doing is
Ed output of the helper difference from
the expectation from the predicate and
if so we found a violation
and then the predicate experimentation
here well uh when you need to express it
then you quickly realize that somehow
you have to re-implement the logic of
the validator and it's important that's
quite common in unit testing either
you're just looking at an input a and
you say you get B and input C and then
you get D or you try to be more generic
and somehow you have to do
implementation number two and compare
implementation number two with your
original one so it's what I'm trying to
do here with the naive implementation
looking if it's like if it looks like an
absolute pass
trying not to use the Google standard
library to be sure we are fully covered
and then doing a naive John of pass and
all that
and then what's really interesting there
uh and then as soon as you launch fading
a violation is identified something like
some parts that will be dot slash dot
dot
where the validator says yeah yeah it's
it's legit but then I will my code is
expecting
that it's rejected
and then when I found that it was
unclear to me what
what should be the behavior so we
discovered that in this PR and then the
conclusion was that yeah we don't want
to accept it so the fix has been made
again if you look at the fix
doesn't seem obvious that it's the let's
say
a perfect solution for it so then
filling is again useful because you
first the new implementation and then
you get no violation in a reasonable
amount of time and then you can conclude
that the future will be good enough
uh yeah so
writing predicates can be hard uh
because uh as we've seen here it was
rather straightforward for for the
example one where it's just a one-liner
uh so if the emperor is small uh
and you can you can easily express
predicates with sentences like should
not content this character or sequence
but if the
helper gets bigger you will need this
complex validation logic to implement it
and of course if you just copy paste the
original implementation in the first
test it's useless because you are
comparing
output from the expected output and if
his expected output is always the output
because it's a copy paste of the
implementation you are doing just
nothing
uh so you need to write your
own implementation and for that you need
not to get biased by the existing one
because otherwise again you would be
just comparing similar things and maybe
a corner case is missing and you need to
think about it
a team of complex question I faced was
there were two extent should I draft the
standard libraries because we saw that
flightpass.fin was tricky
and so for that I wanted to share the
list my lessons learned when I was
trying to validate the file storage API
of grafana so it's a new API that will
allow to do file uploads on the on the
server so of course password is a big
concern
uh and there's a rather complex validate
path function in this API so add to be
implemented
and it was really time consuming
uh I did not identify any violation
which like somehow is good because it
means like the current validate pass
seems to be doing the job yet I'm not on
100 confident that I did not miss some
Chrono cases because it was hard to
re-implement this complex logic
okay so next step we still have some
phasing for it and all that so it can be
useful so what what can we do to
are getting more value out of phasing
well first uh yeah as we said you should
make security helper as simple as
possible and then one is done you can
easily include trading in the cicd
pipeline so you make sure you will not
have any regression so let's say in a
few months some other developer decide
to refactor this example to logic uh and
it breaks it like uh an unfolding could
find a violation quickly and and we can
realize that yeah the validator is not
doing the job anymore
of course once you have those uh
security helpers like you can that you
can consider trusted because they are
first
you should communicate about them so
that like more developer uses them
uh and then if you want to make sure
that they are really used you could use
some uh static analysis tooling like Sam
grab
so that you can check if like in your
web processories
if those security helpers are really
used instead of the dangerous features
thank you
so to wrap up uh so
yeah you've been warned that five past
can be tricky when you try to protect
from Pastor reversal uh
I hope that you are convinced that
phasing can be useful in real life as it
improves your automatic testing coverage
and it's identity
to identify Corner cases that would not
be obvious
uh and in the end it should make you
more confident with your security
outdoor libraries and we've also see
that yeah well go fishing is easy to use
and really nicely integrated and it can
be really efficient as long as your
target simple functions
and now I would be really happy to take
all the questions you have about that
thank you