tomorrow we have the edition of a
capture the flag experience those of you
who have been here before may remember
uh dread pirate Captain hash Jack and
his nefarious goings-on
we also have a selection of workshops
they will be happening outside of this
room and we will continue with our
content in here
we have drinks receptions both tonight
and tomorrow they are on level two of
this building
and
with the greatest pleasure and again the
warmest and brightest of thanks to
everybody who has helped to make it
happen but we have a standalone security
con happening in February
this is all the same spicy Cloud native
security goodness that you have come to
know and love from tax security and from
these colos but independently
standing by itself
same content different location and we
will uh
look to learn from
this event and hopefully continue add
infant item
there are a couple of pre-recorded
sessions today oh there's one today and
three tomorrow
you can identify
from the schedule
they'll play in the room and speakers
will hopefully hop onto slack so that we
can get some feedback and Real Time
Communication and questions
and as if it wasn't clear enough to us
all already
supply chain and open source security
be so hot right now
over 90 percent of packages equaled from
open source package libraries have a fix
available we are installing old broken
software and that has a ripple effect
repercussions for all parts of our
structure our build systems our end user
devices
keep those tariff statistics in mind as
we progress through our content for the
next couple
there are plenty of Open Source
opportunity to remediate these things
and importantly as an open source and
voluntary
participation-based community
there are plenty of places for you and
your organizations to get involved not
only in tax Securities work but also in
the projects that we help to assure and
also more broadly of course over the
course of this week everything under the
cncf's bright shining Banner
talking of banners we have a CTF a
practical Banner
the way that this will be played is all
through a terminal
we kick it off tomorrow in the room
across the way room 333 but for those of
us who have not played a CTF before
we'll run through a workshop today so
instead of this being a deaf style
malware reversing binary exploitation
kind of CTF we are looking to help
people understand kubernetes security
contacts sorry Concepts and contexts of
course
so this is an educative ETF there is
still a competitive element
but it's not designed to uh mangle the
Swede as we might say in the UK or
similarly twist the brain
learn how to
poem clusters and pot shells
we'll do an introductory Workshop today
and this will guide you through one of
the previous CTF
scenarios that we've run before
points of doing style of CTF is to help
internalize the adversarial mindset and
then give us an opportunity to
understand where to apply controls
ultimately helping to raise the barrier
Cloud native security
there is also a companion website
as I say we'll start with a workshop
today and then three workshops will run
throughout tomorrow running through
three increasingly complex scenarios you
are advised to turn up for the first
session if you are not feeling overly
confident if you pop in just for the
third session it will be slightly more
difficult
and of course we have the cloud native
goose chasing us throughouts
this is the website and of course the
protocol Captain hashtags black flagged
vessel
as I say everything is run through the
command line
and
you can prepare for the CTF there I hope
that has
suitably
ensnared some of your interests okay
what do we have coming up this morning
we have Keynotes and into our first talk
we have Michael Foster from red hat with
crossing the kubernetes network policy
Castle
then Jeremy Colvin from upticks why
develop a laptop security is key to
securing your cfp pipeline
again those open source statistics
coming into shop
the kubernetes
coffee break
of the next two days
a huge thanks to our sport who have
helped to make everything possible
uh cystic upticks and VMware tanzu some
long-standing supporters of the security
community in there
are some sponsor apparel
and gold tigera and veritas much
appreciated thank you for the supports
and that slide has spectacularly failed
to load big thanks to everybody whose
faces are supposed to be here
who helped on the program committee who
have helped again volunteering their
spare time in order to schedule and
manage an event like this it is a
non-trivial process so huge thanks they
will also appear on the closing slides
so they have a second opportunity
um
also a huge thank you to everybody
involved in tag security again these are
voluntary efforts with people's Spare
Time organizations putting funding
behind the open source security
thank you once more to the incredible
effort we've seen
from these individuals
and of course it would be remiss there's
another
uh another missing image
you remiss not to remind you that should
you have the spare Cycles the
inclination or just the interest to join
what tax security does we meet every
week
we have an emir time zone meeting we
have a U.S flavored time zone meeting
they alternated
good things like Shoring projects cntf
are looking to help graduate we're
working now with cert manager flux Argo
CD these are again critical projects to
the sanctity and safety of production
deployments and
the expertise required to go through
some Assurance practices and threat
modeling
experiences uh it's it is a high bar
success and so
it is much easier to do with the
help and the collaboration of friends
and colleagues in the open source
Community it's a great way to learn how
things are done in other organizations
and it is a hive mind a fabulous Melting
Pot of intellect I very strongly urge
you
interested or with the Cycles to come
and join us
jump on Slack
and come and attend some of our meetings
with that
we are ready to start the day
so the first keynote is starting in a
couple of minutes thank you again for
your attendance and supports and I hope
you have a fabulous time at cloudnative
security con
[Applause]