all right I'm gonna go I don't know if
they do intros in this room I'll just do
both
hi
welcome to uh
security con Cloud kubecon this is my
first time ever talking one of these so
what could go wrong right I got a lot of
moving Parts I'm trying to warm this
room up for probably better things to
come
no
okay you say so
I have already learned that walking
around on this stage may not be the
safest thing I should do
uh this is pulling the CI and I'll just
dive straight to it
uh the story behind this I was asked to
research this because this happened to
our open source project checkoff we got
a pull request one day from this guy and
I'm going to just highlight that
because there's a little re return to
that earlier because this this talk it's
more interesting as time goes on because
weird stuff keeps happening to us
but you can see there's a name up there
says am young 34 just remember that by
the way if M young 34 is in this room
I'm sorry
because this is not going to reflect
positively so this is what the pull
request was
it was delete everything useful in our
build yaml and replace it with a PS and
an m on our self-hosted runner
so obviously we didn't accept this PR
almost did
but that would have been bad because our
cell phone surrender has also some
information on it both in terms of
environment variables see my processes
are running these are all bad things
so I was then rcto BRAC said can you
just like dive into this how bad could
it have been for us
so I did and that's this is kind of
result the first thing of course was I
had to break the news to him that
generally running self-hosted Runners on
open source project is considered bad
um but of course if you look out in the
world and see how many people actually
use self-hosted Runners on public
projects
all right let's just forget what best
practices are and just go with the
actual reality of what's really
happening
uh and I have a link down there
you don't have to take photos of Links
at the very end I have one one slide
that has every link that I use so if you
just want to go click and
look around then you can do that
this is the obligatory me slide where I
inflate my ego the cloud native security
Advocate I work for bridge crew Bridge
crew is bought by prismacloud which is
Palo Alto networks it's like it's I'm
not sure who I work for somebody I've
been writing code since the 19th
and doing a lot of security thingies if
you're ever in London England
uh ping me and come to our Meetup we run
a meet up in London called devsecops
London Gathering every month I have a
lot of wonderful guests on there and if
you ever want to kill an hour on a
Friday around three three o'clock
uh there's a show on Twitch called c9k
it used to be called something quite
profane turns out YouTube doesn't like
that
so we had to change the name
there's a perfectly innocent QR code go
ahead and scan that so
get imagine workflows hands up if you
use GitHub action workflows
great
so I can speed through this so I do a
lot of grabbing the the actual text from
GitHub because their own help
I found kind of takes you down the wrong
path sometimes uh but this is just what
it says it says you can create workflows
to do what three things build your
application deploy your application or
do just stop like add a label to an
issue uh you can sanitize an issue Etc
I'm going to be doing some of these
things live so if it all blows up in my
face
that's what it's going to do today
the fundamental problem generally is
that if you submit a pull request like
this person tried to do that is in the
GitHub workflows path
it will try and execute the workflow it
doesn't know the difference between a
pre-existing workflow and one that
you're sending in is the commit which is
weird
the other thing is that a lot of the
creation of workflows is generally done
by people who weren't appsec
professionals and they don't quite have
the mentality of sanitizing your inputs
yet so you've got things like issue name
issue description the list of potential
inputs is actually pretty big and
particularly if you use things like
workflow run triggers where you're
feeding one workflow into another then
it really complicates what is considered
input our user controlled input so a lot
of people aren't doing that and there's
a lot of things that can happen as a
result of that and the last one of
course that workflow directory it
doesn't have special permissions you can
add permissions to it but by default
anything anybody can submit anything to
it so that's not great
so as a result of that there's a few
things that can happen across all of
these so if you're not sanitizing inputs
you can do some kind of command
injection into there if I know that
you're using something to build or even
deploy then I'm assuming that you might
have some access to credentials on your
self-hosted Runner so what can I do to
try and Achieve acquiring those
credentials and execute some form of
supply chain attack so this is this is
what I was challenged with
what I found kind of confusing down to
the box is some of the reactions GitHub
has when you are a new contributor like
the first one up there let's just do
this this is exactly what happened to us
and actually
if we uh
go here you can see I've got two people
here I've got this
a malicious person called Loud Canadian
and then I have
this nice person over here called
eurogig who's just trying to maintain
this wonderful application
and I've submitted a pull request and
sure enough I have my approve and run
and this is what happened we just didn't
click this
which actually I am going to click now
because I don't mind just to kind of
push things along I'm going to merge
this pull request I'm going to confirm
the marriage fabulous
awesome so now this person
is a wonderful contributor
so what happens in GitHub is you don't
get these instructions on the top you
just weren't there this is from the help
and that does warn you that if the
contribution is in the GitHub workflows
directory be alert
fantastic
what could go wrong if you have no
workflows whatsoever
it kind of scolds you and says hey why
don't you have workflows come on man you
can you could use this to catch bugs and
enforce style workflows are a good thing
for security
okay
the default for outside collaborators is
that you only require approval for the
first thing you do
which I just did
once you've done that
you're an Insider awesome so it's far
easier to become a malicious Insider
just by changing a readme or going to
the good first issues
and doing something really simple and
then you've bypassed this whole workflow
conundrum
sounds a little too good to be true
so I have just submitted something
here's the first thing I'm going to play
with now which is unsanitized inputs to
workflows
here's an and this is me looking around
for how do people do this in the real
world so I look just look for GitHub
event issue title I found this one which
was pretty cool somebody's creating
generating blog Pages based on issues
that are submitted
that's kind of neat so what if I create
an issue with a title
that has a bunch of HTML in it that
might fish for information when someone
goes to that blog page
there isn't any real Auto sanitization
of what the issue title can be
that's kind of up to us
the other more common one and this was
like there were thousands of these just
people logging issues or PR titles or
anything that's like an input user
controlled input as they're arriving so
that there's more visibility again
sounds like a good thing
then when I just submitted a moment ago
here
we can take a look at the files changed
is that one
that is designed to look like a positive
contribution I'm checking the input
GitHub event issue title to make sure it
formats to a certain way and I look like
I'm contributing to the project in a
positive way
which is great
and that's it there
it's great unless
if I create an issue and you probably
would think surely GitHub won't let you
create an issue
with this weird title surely right there
would be something that would stop that
from happening
so
this is where you get to see all the
funny things that I've got going on here
so this is the this is the good area
I've already merged this pull request I
go to my code
I've got workflows here and I've got my
issue check
which is cool it means anytime an issue
is opened it should run this it should
live in my actions world
so what happens I go to my issues so
here's my battery I would I'd probably
get my friend to do this for me because
I wouldn't mind doing myself right that
would be
too obvious I'm a hacker
I'm not going to go to my ridiculously
tiny notes
here
I'm gonna grab exactly what that said
I don't use a back tick
everybody knows what a back dick does
fabulous
because the even if I see equals or I
assign the value or do anything and I
get a workflow it happens in a batch
script basket basket seeds a backtick
and it's like cloud formation sees a
dollar squiggle it tries to resolve the
meaning of it before it does the
assignment
so I hadn't really screwed this up so if
I create this issue
issue
seemed happy with it
I go there and look
it's oh hello
go back to my web hook site
and so I now have all the environment
variables from that particular Runner
by the way if you ever use webhook.site
it's awesome just for testing things
it's also good for messing with people
but
it was kind of that easy so that was
like the first thing ever was like all
right so any of these sites that are
doing any kind of input sanitization I
can now just
vacuum out all of their environment
variables in a much easier way than what
was attempted on us
so that was interesting thing number one
but there's ways to protect yourself
from this like there are Environmental
Protection rules and environmental
secret rules that already exist there's
a link down the bottom so if something
you're watching that you're going oh
maybe I should only give certain
workflows certain access to certain
environment variables and secrets you
should
the link will be at the end it looks as
simple as
environment name the environment Etc so
it's a really really simple things to
implement
generally I found that you should nearly
never have like hard-coded credentials
even if you think they're stored as
Secrets you'll find out later why about
that but it's not a good thing
short-lived tokens are important if you
use self-hosted Runners it can be an
advantage because you can create lists
that and
make sure that your only certain IPS can
talk to certain IPS so that cell phone
supporters can be an advantage
um in AWS reporting is important openid
connect GitHub actions does use oidc it
doesn't use spiffy Spire unfortunately
yet but if you can make sure you use
that to access any kind of cloud
provider definitely do that instruction
specific or Amazon are down there and
also just generic ones for github.com so
when this happened it was really
fascinating because our own repo wasn't
as secure as we really thought it should
be
number two
I'm not going to show this one but I
just find it fascinating maybe I will
show it later
so this brought me to Branch protection
rules you should always have your branch
production turned on what was amazing
about when Chekhov first started we were
a startup and we didn't know how popular
it was going to get
so it must have had a thousand stars
before we had Branch protection turned
on it seems crazy but we were and we
were inviting collaborators like anybody
help help and that when that turns into
a SAS solution you become a startup and
you're like
maybe we've got to go back to the
original effort that we could have
quickly uh sped ahead on
if you turn on Branch protection
you should almost have everything ticked
nobody ever does if you do tick by
default the first thing require a pull
request for emerging which you should
you require approvals which you should
a lot of people think they're done but
the default down there of one is kind of
where it gets a little dicey because
you can approve yourself
so over here this changed in April this
year this year
the default this is what you should have
for workflow permissions this is the the
good thing read repository content is
permission in a workflow this is what
the GitHub token should be able to do
that's not the default though
the default is that
there was about a day or a week or
something where the default was the
correct default for new repos and
everybody freaked out because they
weren't expecting that to be the default
and so they went back to that
so just to know that's there so if you
create a new repo the GitHub token if
you will have a way more access than you
think it's the difference between these
that middle column that says read only
and that column there which you probably
is as far from least privileged as you
can imagine
so I hope it's not too small I'll show
it again later but
to do a curl but little workflow
I was surprised to see and by the way if
anybody from cider security is here this
is their research not mine
um
you have everything you need to do a
curl command you've got the GitHub
repository you get the GitHub event
number which is the pull request you've
got the secret GitHub token like you can
just assemble a command
you can't approve a pull request
so you can't merge a pull request but
you can certainly do that and you can
approve your own thing and so that whole
thing you did to have approvals is
suddenly irrelevant
that's not all you can do there's a lot
of things this is just going to get your
imagination going
all right so the last one
fingers crossed the works this is the
one that I tried to submit because I
thought this is the how bad could it be
section
so zooming in on there
I thought all right so I can get the
environment variables how can I get the
secrets I got to get the secrets in two
lines by doing Echo sequence to a file
because the secrets are only available
in the workflow they're not environment
variables but unless I push them out to
a file
and then curl that out to the same bad
URL in which case now I have all the
secrets they're not encrypted they're
just there
and then I want the GitHub token I'm
like well how long can I the GitHub
token be alive for
the GitHub token dies at the moment the
job dies so I stick a sleep in there and
now I get a GitHub token as well and the
secrets and the environment rows cool
and then I was kind of feeling nasty so
I did this version
which I thought all right well what if I
could do a reverse shell
and then send that out to myself and
then that would make everything persist
for as long as I wanted
so I thought yeah I'll do that one
so let's do that one
so there's a few things I still have
this sitting here
I still have this
which is cool
what I'm going to do now I'm going to
make myself a contributor I'm going to
do the all the things you shouldn't do
this is a bad example of how to be
secure
I'm gonna do a collaborator I'm going to
add me so I can commit Direct
I've been such a good
person in this project that there's no
reason why I wouldn't add myself
I just got an email telling me I'm at it
yeah
also
add to main I'm going to turn this on
there we go now I should have a lot of
this stuff turned on but I don't know
why anybody would turn on
do not allow bypassing why is that even
there there's some weird stuff in Branch
protection
nice so I'm all set up there I've got
code
I've got this running
and oh yeah
I've got that running
okay it seems like it should work I've
got everything going I'm going to go to
code
when my workflows
and so now I'm not in my own Fork
anymore I'm actually right here I'm
going to add this file create a new file
I if you're going to add something dodgy
don't call it pone.aml
that's that's a dead giveaway that's a
little tip for you
budding hackers out there
is my file now the difference between
this one the one I just showed you is
this actually has the audio approvement
as well just for kicks up here that's
you probably need a telescope to read
that but
here we go
okay
so I have my little Auto approve in
there which should
in theory work
I should be able to propose this new
file which is fine
I'm going to create a report request
to merge back
uh I need to fix able to merge
oh I can't read it I know my class is on
oh one second one second
uh Canadian patch one hold on sorry
about this
I'm a little
phone actions
ah there we go
so I have my GitHub token now that
worked
and I have a reversal which is not ideal
and given the amount of time we have now
this
is unlikely to work because I got my
naming around but there is another step
here where
because of the path I'll leave it up
there there's there's a step there where
I can start to change what I what I just
did via the runner thus I can cancel the
pull request delete what I've submitted
and change the actual person who did it
because I used an unsigned commit
and so I
so it's the things I can do while here
are actually
pretty terrible
um I realized I'm
a little short on time because by the
way this is normally a 50-minute talk
another thing I noticed on most Runners
is that
Docker is always installed by default
so while I got access to the runner as
the ID Runner
you could use Docker just to create an
auto pop-out shell and upgrade yourself
to root so now I'm a root on the runner
as well I'm kind of there as long as I
want
and of course I use that value everybody
see the Falco talk
I thought that was Brill so they should
create rules to stop people from doing
stuff like this
so that's kind of like
the idea behind why this is all bad
the idea of getting a being able to run
things in shells is one thing
but to be able to destroy evidence of
and be able to have full access to the
repository that I just took over make
changes to pretty much anything in the
code
change the adjacent code if it's a
shared self-hosted Runner and even turn
off the pull request remotely so that I
can stay on the self-hosted runner
independent of GitHub now
so what can you do with this
if you're in if you're taking part in
the CTF
pretty much all the things that you want
to do on the CDF I can start looking for
AWS information that might be still as
environment variables I can change the
logging level on the runner that I'm on
right now I could get it to report back
to me I can I can add my own SSH token
so I can come back directly to the
runner with all of this staff I can look
with processes the network I can look
for access to S3 buckets so much I can
do
now the next thing I want to say is
important information
I'm saying don't be a bif you recognize
this from
Back to the Future don't be a Biff with
this information
the thing that started all this this is
where it changed a month ago
this crossed my path in my mass network
of information that comes to me via
newsletters and whatever this came in
and I was like oh Zucker punch abusing
stuff was good I'm running to Facebook
that's what my talks about that's pretty
cool I'm gonna read this and I I hadn't
even scrolled down yet and I went M
Young
that's interesting
that's the guy
I looked at what was happening here
he says Facebook actually was Pi torch
which is Facebook which is now Linux
Foundation
and he goes through all of his he's kind
of bragging about everything that he did
all the way through
and really it turned out Ollie was was
after money
he's calling it a bug Bounty there was
no bug Bounty but he just went through
and was like using this thing but now I
realized we were part of the whole
scatter gun approach to trying to find
people who had misconfigured GitHub or
insecurely considered GitHub and I'm
like you could have really messed with
us like if we'd clicked that that would
have really bad for our own because
checkout is what powers our commercial
solution and that would have been not
cool
and so
my little comment on that is that
I don't think it's pretty like I love
bug bounties I think they're a great
idea they make us more secure but if you
know how to do things like this don't do
it on Open Source projects that are a
gift to the world like Pi torch
um do it on actual bug bounties that
just I just thought the behavior was
terrible
the good thing about his article is that
because he was actually doing this to
real people he got observations that I
couldn't get
he did find out that many self-hosted
Runners did have access to S3 buckets he
did find out that many had access to ECR
without ecr's immutable tagging so he
could change the images while
maintaining the tag thus supply chain
attack
a lot of self-hosted Runners were
internal and were not on a VPC so the
efforts like I don't like what he did
but I like the conclusions that he got
so I added it to my presentation
all right ounce of prevention
well I'm just gonna blast through these
because I got five minutes
be careful when adding contributors even
if you're a new startup it's bad because
people like me might be added to your I
mean I'm just a terrible programmer so
that's bad either way
self-hosted Runners and public
repositories are being targeted I mean
uh Branch protection is important more
than one reviewer but there's lots of
things inside Branch protection you
really should read every single one and
make sure you understand what they are
um don't run workflows unless you're 100
sure Environmental Protection
um short lifespan tokens of any kind but
preferably open ID connect if you're
connected to the cloud
GitHub event logging and code owners
code owners is the thing I mentioned
where you can add a code owners file put
someone's ID in it add it to your GitHub
directory and then that's the person
that can review it doesn't end up just
being any old person or yourself by a
curl
and then the last one which I didn't
show you and I'm so sorry but I'm I'm
running out of time sign commits
that there was a bit in that script that
just had me sitting my git config to an
email address and it was Linus torval's
email address
if you do that try it on your own
repository set it up yourself use his
email address and do a commit
GitHub goes and finds his Avatar
and we'll pop it in as the author of The
commit
you can be anybody you want with Git
unless
you're not so you don't have to be you
it's way too easy
to be somebody else in this world
awesome tools you should be using if
you're not already
open ssf scorecard anybody using that
yes it rocks
uh it'll check so many of the things
that I just talked about Branch
protection contributors from at least
two different organizations which I
thought was funny because I did that in
order to become a bad contributor but I
really like the avoid dangerous coding
patterns I did a lot of playing with
that to see what it would find and it
was actually pretty good
um declarative I mean that's not
everything it does it does awesome all
sorts of awesome things just checking
the security of the repository and the
way it is tested in general
that's a definite use it
the other one I would be remiss if I
didn't plug the own project I work on
but the reason we did this was to add
rules to check off that look for the
sort of same sort of things so we've got
strange patterns that look for many uses
of curl inside of workflow anything
that's doing what I did with Secrets all
the different possible reverse shell
things like anything at all like that is
in there and plus we have some of the we
have some overlap with the open ssf um
as well because we do scan the apis and
we look at Branch production being
enabled and they'll also things like
that so there's a bit of a Venn diagram
there but using both certainly would get
you a long way to stopping me doing
anything like I just did there
and that is the end and these are all
the links I used so if you're curious to
read you can go for it
question
yes
uh there'll be eventually a gitlab event
edition of this bitbucket did not
but I hated bitbucket
so there we go uh that's the end any
other questions I have three minutes you
have a three minute sign that's an odd
number to choose
you can do
dialysis
in my organization apply this policy to
them and then Auto fix or open issues if
it doesn't provide
cool All-Star everybody get that
it's like open ssf but like huge
yeah same makes sense
awesome thanks for watching that if
that's it
great oh well again
I mean thank you for asking questions
I don't know it's a good question I'm
looking at it asked me next year when I
do the get lab version
foreign
cool
thumbs up all right thanks