thank you Jeremy for the keynote
um I'd like to take a brief moment to
thank our amazing sponsors without their
support this security con would not be
possible
so thank you to Red Hat sisdig Optics
and VMware tanzu for being our Diamond
sponsors and also thank you to apiro for
being a platinum sponsor
with that we are ready to begin the
General Sessions for the day and first
here we have Mohan atriya from Rafael
systems Mohan will be talking about
securing the kubernetes infrastructure
using kubernetes zero trust principles
Mohan thank you um am I am I Audible
thank you good morning everyone
um great to see so many people here
so I I'm going to talk about a pretty
interesting area uh this is uh this has
been something that we see a lot of
users attempting now when it comes to
kubernetes and I hope I hope at the end
of it you'll walk out with some
interesting insights and if you have
some questions after the session I'll be
around so just look me up and happy to
chat more
um
so um why do we think we wanted to talk
about this topic
um
a lot of you here are very technical
but there's a vast majority of people
out on the out in the world who use
kubernetes a little differently
um
if you've seen some of the reports
recently like from Shadow server there's
nearly 380 000 kubernetes clusters open
on the internet think about that open on
the internet right that's not good and
we kind of play in this space so we've
been kind of talking to people why do
you do this and a lot of people say it's
just too hard if I have to go another
way go through a secure tunnel or
something like that
so with this backdrop of why so many
people are out there with open
kubernetes clusters on the internet I
mean think about it your API server is
the way by which you interact with your
clusters right like as a user it's open
on the internet anyone can touch it not
good right so we ask people what do you
do
um typically right and then maybe
there's a better approach
so what people are typically done and
this must be very familiar for you uh if
you've been in the in the uh industry
for a while uh they put up a Bastion if
you go to a security team they probably
will say maybe you should use Sebastian
right kubernetes is new to them
so what did they do
um they go set up a Bastion there's a
um you know you'll end up doing um a cue
cuddle right from uh the Bastion onto
your clusters in in your VPC or
something else and now you have a
problem uh the problem is well there are
two problems first is from that Bastion
you can see everything in that VPC all
right if I'm an attacker that's a juicy
Target right and number two
me and my colleague getting out of the
Bastion using the same Cube config most
likely right so that's not good now you
can't tell who did what so this turns
out to be a problem okay way to start
you'll end up having problems
the second thing that people do is they
land up saying well this Bastion thing
is not working for me maybe I'll put up
a jump host in front of it right I put
up a jump hose now the user or the
developer in this case is really really
ticked off because now you're asking the
user to go through two jumps right now
you may you may start thinking here at
this point of time some you know gears
are probably churning in your head
you're thinking how is this any
different from VMS you've done this for
VMS for hundreds of years uh why is so
painful the problem is in the old
monolithic world the typically the only
person doing this was the Ops person
right in the kubernetes world is every
developer when you have 100 micro
Services the poor Ops guy doesn't know
which broke what broke where so many
developers access right to help out when
you want to resolve issues ETC so when
you have hundreds of users attempting to
do this you're on a real real painful
situation right this is what people
encounter in real life
the last thing that we see people do is
they plonk a VPN in front
um not bad right except if you can
afford it
um these vpns do cost a lot of money and
if you have three four data centers I
mean it's game over from a budget
perspective right you have so many VPN
concentrators but the good thing is now
every user is using their own cubeconfig
and they doing it right from their
laptop
life is a little better right more
secure
um the the primary thing is cost of
course this does not remove the attack
surface problem which means if I can VPN
into my VPC I see everything inside the
VPC right
um not good right
Audible
now we talked about how can I access
stuff
um
now let's talk about the second
actually a very important aspect
if I'm accessing kubernetes
um not have some kind of operation
a developer I have the same kind of
access administered that's a no
cluster-wide privilege every developer
came over
what people do
end up having for example
stand up saying that hey are all the
Developers
of this application an Acme name have to
be in the Acme namespace
stop the orange line
tap
you want to make sure that the developer
um uh who doesn't need access to
cluster-wide Privileges and only access
things by the namespace but if I'm an
operations person allow me Pastor wide
privilege because I need that
so you guys know this fundamental logic
this hardback built into kubernetes
after you use it the way by which you
control your blast radius
hello
better
all right sorry guys
um
so I'll just go back to that previous
slide for like two seconds so the The
quick summary there is there's something
called rbac or role-based Access Control
in kubernetes really important for you
to understand that because you do not
want every developer who does not need
access to the entire cluster you want to
make sure you use our back so that they
can only see what they want to see
really really important
uh so uh now what happens at scale now
we have one user or maybe one cluster
not a big problem right you can do all
of this manually
what we see customers struggle with and
users struggle with is when you have
tens or hundreds of clusters
and typically like when I talk about
microservices when you have hundreds of
micro Services you have hundreds of
developers who constantly move from one
theme to another
now your problem is magnified you have
hundreds of users hundreds of developers
and you have many many clusters now how
are you going to manage all these rbacs
and even keep sense of them really hard
right so essentially
if you are looking into a model by which
you're doing this manually you're now in
an impractical zone right is this not
possible to do this
so this is where
um uh the processes fall apart and you
need some form of automation to make
sure that the wrong people do not have
access to the wrong things or the uh
more things than what they need
so now let's look at let's look at how
can we solve this problem both of these
problems in one Fell Swoop right
so let's look at this from maybe a
requirements perspective if I'm a if I'm
an operations person and I have hundreds
of developers that need to access stuff
and I need
um to support tens and hundreds of
clusters running in data centers in many
many regions in Amazon Etc the first
thing I need to do is I cannot afford to
put my clusters open on the internet
that's I mean everyone agrees to that
the next thing I need to do is make sure
that I don't put my developers through
this complicated Bastion or VPN based
user experience which everyone hates
right none of us like that experience
so what you really really need is to
leverage what's been out in the market
for tens of years I mean if if folks
have heard about companies like zscaler
and all these companies they've been
like very pervasive they all do this but
for web applications why not for cube
CTL why not for cube API after all runs
on https right so the first thing you
need is a way by which you can access
these clusters
even though the Clusters are cloaked
behind a firewall can you do that yeah
if you can do that with zscaler why not
the next thing you want to do is you
don't want this R back to be permanently
injected inside the cluster you want to
do that dynamically just in time why is
that really important
you don't want credentials to be
permanently sitting on clusters right
you want to remove them after the
session is complete so the automated
ephemeral are back really important
all user access need to be strongly
authenticated given right and then
finally this is a question that people
struggle with from a governance and
compliance
if I come and ask you hey what are the
cube CTL commands are ran against my
cluster or rather Johnny Ransom commands
yesterday what did he run people have no
idea right there's no way to reconstruct
that what if there was
right so these are the four things we
see that organizations need to have a
sensible practice around making sure
that you run things at scale with your
clusters where you open up access to
your developers give them a fantastic
experience and and make sure that you're
not running insecure
so um
so what are we going to talk about now
I'm going to for the remaining part of
the session I'm going to do two things
I'm going to talk about an open source
project that that
um that we announced sometime back
called perilous
um it's actually based on something we
noticed about three years ago in the
market you know about three years ago
you know we all started working from
home uh because if uh the pandemic right
and we had coincidentally introduced a
zero trust access uh capability in our
platform and that took off like a rocket
ship I don't have the charts here the
show but you know it was almost like you
know a curve like that and it's because
people are working from home everyone
hated vpns no one who wanted bastions
and everyone wanted instant access to
the Clusters so you're going to see that
in action with this open source offering
we open sourced it because we felt that
it's really important for the industry
to kind of move a couple of notches up
from a security perspective right like
everybody should be able to do this you
should not be requiring a commercial
offering to do this so let's let's talk
a little bit about parallels is open
source Apache license so you can pull it
down and use it right and if you are
using something like digitalocean you
have a one-click experience just go
there search for parallels click it
install it use it please participate in
the community right like we would love
to see how we can improve this we love
to have contributors and then like you
guys are all you know pretty aware of
how the community is so important to
make sure this this projects are
successful so help us out let's make the
industry more secure
try and participate in this project
so how does this work now you kind of
heard about the zero trust let me kind
of show you
architecturally then I'll show you a
live demo I'm sure it'll blow your mind
right so the first thing you have is you
have the access manager panelist access
manager this is a proxy it's a cube CTL
proxy or cube API proxy on the internet
right
it's got these an agent running on every
one of your clusters and notice the
arrow is out outbound right the agent
dials out on Port 443 from your clusters
behind firewalls to the perilous access
manager and runs a long running control
plane session
right it's a it's essentially keeping it
alive the connection
now when the developer who is sitting at
home
can access the perilous access server
they don't know any different they get a
cube config they say Cube CTL get
namespace or something like that right
they don't know if they're touching
perilous or the end cluster they don't
need to know they're hitting the proxy
right and the proxy authenticates them
it's a two-way Authentication
with digital certificates is very
strongly authenticated of course
everything is encrypted it's https right
and not only that
anything the user types is now audited
right so if I type some funky commands
you can reconstruct the whole set of
commands and from a compliance and
governance perspective this is really
important
right and once that authentication is
complete it's just basically on The Wire
the commands are flying back and forth
between the client and the server now
before that
the downstream APS server at this time
has no idea who you are it has no R back
for you on that cluster so remember at
step two when the user authenticated
with the perilous access manager
they're also indicating I want to access
the cluster on the top and our back is
generated on the Fly and a service
account is injected into that cluster
right this is all happening in
milliseconds right milliseconds or
microseconds right
so the API server is the one that's
actually controlling everything behind
the scenes perilous here is nothing more
than the main gatekeeper it's just an
access proxy that's pretty much it it's
access proxy authenticating you
generating the r back injecting the
service account on that cluster
sounds fascinating right I'm sure you
guys want to see a very quick demo of
that I'll I'll do that right now
right
um so let's see that
so what what you're going to see here
is uh
um I have the perilous access manager
setup it's running in New York in
digitalocean
right I'm now here in in Detroit
and hopefully my internet will work and
uh you'll see me
attempt to run a cube CTL command and I
can run this against three clusters what
I've done is like I've simulated a
typical environment any small company
would have a Dev environment a staging
cluster a production cluster right and
what I'm going to do here is I'm going
to show you if I log in as an Ops person
I can see everything because that's what
my access rules are
and I'll have cluster white privileges
but if a login as a developer
I will not have access to production
because that's the rule I set up here
right now this should be like easy right
like how do you do that
um uh why not see it in action
so let me
um very quickly
is going to be complicated because I'm
holding the mic and doing this at the
same time so this is a perilous access
server so what you're seeing here are
three projects I have a Dev project a
prod project and a staging project
inside that I have a cluster a Dev
cluster and if I want a cube CTL do it I
mean I don't know where it's running I
don't need to know and I can say hey get
namespace and I get the thing now the
key thing here uh uh you know you don't
even see the the service account being
dynamically injected on the cluster so
now what I'm going to do is I'm going to
flip to another cluster Just for kicks
and I'm going to show you live
let's go inspect the service account so
when I run this
um
let me type this out I can't talk and
type at the same time
yeah there's also autocomplete thank God
so when you go look at that and if you
look at this service account for this
user
it was generated about two hours ago
when I was just practicing and
rehearsing for this demo now what I'll
do is I'll log in as an Ops version and
we'll see this being generated live
right so what I'm going to do now is
going to log in as an Ops person
I'm going to authenticate as John
right and if you look at John
the the company the Central Access
manager said John has access because he
belongs to the Ops group I have access
to the dev prod and staging this mapping
is done automatically based on my group
membership right
then I go into prod and I'll do the same
thing
and I'm hitting the same cluster and if
I look for the same thing which is a
secret service account minus n
perilous system you'll see that Ops John
this email just 10 seconds ago the
service account was dynamically created
on that cluster right just 10 seconds
ago and when I log out that service
account will be flushed which means
nobody has keys to the kingdom all the
time every time I access I need to
authenticate really important so
tomorrow I change my role today they
move me from Ops to Dev
I will not have this level of access
anymore everything is automatic right so
that level of federation really
important
now let's log in as the dev
all right so I'm going to log in as
Sally
Sally is a Dev in this company
and when Sally logs in remember Sally
um because she belongs to the developer
group the company had decided Sally and
developers don't have access to
um the production environment so as you
can see here there's only Dev and
staging clusters visible now Sally also
Belongs to Only One namespace called
Apple
right there's a namespace called apple
on the cluster she only has access to
that
let's see if Sally attempts something
smart
and attempts to see anything more what
happens but before that let's see you
know I'm just going to try
typing in
um you know
I'm listing all my pods in my Apple
namespace everything looks good now
Sally says you know what I really am
curious I want to see who else is
running what on this cluster and I type
A get namespace and you notice access is
forbidden why is this forbidden because
the r back for Sally that was injected
under that cluster is constrained down
to the Apple namespace so you can only
see the Apple namespace nothing more
right imagine doing this for hundreds of
developers who are constantly moving
from group to group or hundreds of
operations people everything is
automatic
right you add people to the right group
our back follows them right that's the
power of Parallels for you
so
um the last thing I want to show you
here is is the audit Trail
so if you remember
as a user I was typing a bunch of things
[Music]
as a company if I'm an auditor I can go
in and look at every command that was
run by without a Sally here or John here
or the admin here whatever I did
everything can be tracked right so from
a governance perspective people can
rewind back and say this person did this
these are the sequencer commands what I
see users tell me now on forums is
fascinating we initially built this
assuming they will use it for security
purposes what people are saying is
they're using this to automate run books
now like you know this is really sharp
engineer who knows how to run the cube
cuddle commands in a certain sequence
they capture that and say I'm going to
bottle this up and I'm going to use have
other people follow the same sequencer
commands so very fascinating set of
feedback from organizations
so in summary
we encourage everyone in the industry to
do three things at least three things
please do not put your kubernetes
clusters on the internet
cloak them
make sure that people have zero trust
access make sure your developers get
access to your clusters from anywhere
with the right R back
make sure the rbac injection the service
account injection is done dynamically
which means only right level of access
is given at the right time
and make sure you have an audit trail of
everything right this this in summary
would get you to a point where you're
running secure operations for your
kubernetes environments I think that's
all I had if there any questions I'll be
around at the back or outside
um I'll also be at the booth Raffia
Booth later this week so stop by I think
we'll have something about perilous
there thank you
do we have time
go ahead yeah yeah we have the mic
so what is the current stat state or
status of parallels can it be used in
production and second question is the
performance hit like what kind of
performance hits are we looking yeah
yeah very good questions so two
questions there what's the stage of the
project
as you all know at cncf there's a
there's a pecking order right you
eventually want to get to a graduated
stage we are now in sandbox right we
submit it for sandbox so we really have
been looking for the community kind of
help us you know we need the right kind
of sponsorship from the community to
move up the ladder right so help us out
there we're right now in sandbox getting
in the sandbox application for sandbox
we had a we had to climb up that ladder
right it takes sometimes years to climb
up so that's the first question the
second question is what's a performance
hit so
um there's typically a
about a when you saw the whole thing in
action right me typing in the command as
a user is imperceptible but you can
measure it it's typically in
milliseconds it's in milliseconds for
the first time when the user is
authenticated
and the service account is injected on
the downstream cluster that's about a
millisecond needed that is to
disorchestrate that but typically the
user never notices anything
uh by the time you think about the
command you're going to type it's all
done right so and you can run these
proxies anywhere in the world so what we
see organizations do is say hey I'm
going to run my perilous access server
closer to my clusters because really
comes down to distance you can't beat
the loss of physics right so if you run
the perilous access server closer to
your
clusters or closer to your users I think
that's the decision you got to make
yeah yes
right thinking that perilous proxy node
has to have
admin credits to all clusters so that it
can dynamically generate the buyback and
if so is there any roadmap
yes good question I'll repeat it because
I'm sure others couldn't hear
um so there are twofold questions one is
uh does the perilous access manager need
cluster right privileges to do its job
and number two is is that a plan to do a
third party pen test the answer is yes
to both
the the third party pen test kind of
happens naturally as part of the cncf
process every project is put through a
microscope right as it happens I think
that's why we encourage every project to
go through the cncf you know governance
model
yeah yeah perfect thank you any other
questions
yeah reach out to us on slack we're
pretty active on slack
um uh I think I just look for parallels
I'm sure you'll find it
thank you
[Applause]