all right thank you um thanks everyone
for coming so yeah uh what we're going
to be talking about today uh lightning
talk so super fast is source
attestations with a project called get
sign uh so a little bit about myself my
name is Billy Lynch I'm a software
engineer over at chingard I'm a
maintainer for the get sign project as
well as some other supply chain security
projects tecton chains and I also make
contributions to the rest of six store
and tecton as well
um so Source out of stations so the
first thing we starting to talk about is
what is an attestation you might also
hear another word called Providence so
what's the difference so the two terms
here Providence we're really talking
about sort of the who what where when
why so these are metadata about the
artifact where did it come from what's
in it why is it here why do we care
about it
uh an attestation is the metadata itself
isn't necessarily enough because that
could be populated and produced by
anyone so an attestation is really
trying to say is it coming from someone
that we trust is it from a trusted
developer is it from our CI pipelines
um so really the difference between the
two is provenance plus some identity uh
is is what really makes up an
attestation and when we talk about
identity uh usually this is where
signatures come into play and if we're
talking about signatures then we're
going to be you know one of the things
we're going to be talking about is
sixstore so six store is a project under
the open ssf it its goal is to make
signing uh software artifacts easy
whether this is images git commits
anything part of your sort of software
supply chain we want to make that
signing easy and one of the really cool
things about sigstore is it has this
process what we call keyless signing
which allows you to basically generate
ephemeral keys to sign objects and
artifacts using a certificate Authority
called fulsio
um and to produce signatures and
attestations and put them into a
transparency law called recore and what
this lets you do is sort of offload the
complexity of managing Keys uh to six
door tooling
um so that you know all you need to
worry about is like making sure that
those things are signed and not having
to worry about managing gpg keys and
rotation and stuff like that
so one of the tools that people are sort
of most familiar with just because it's
been around for a little bit longer is a
tool called cosine and cosine is really
focused on container signing so making
signing oci images it can also do blobs
stuff like that very easy so cosine has
a really Nifty command called cosine of
test where you can actually attach
provenance data to an image and sign it
to make an attestation that about that
image right so you can attach s-bombs
you can attach hey like hey we ran this
check on on this image and you can
attach it in and upload it as in the
same registry so you can see at the
bottom here
uh there's this dot ATT file that
actually has the same sha within the tag
that references the image that it's
attesting to so this really Nifty trick
What it lets you do is store the
attestations in the same location right
so if you have the ability to go fetch
this image you also have the ability to
go fetch this attestation
so that's a really really useful tool
really really powerful so one of the
things that we were sort of thinking
about for git sign is you know we have
this Behavior with cosine we can add
attestations to images but oci images
are just one artifact one part of your
software supply chain
git commits are another part right the
source that goes into your CI the source
that goes into the images that you build
are another artifact that you might want
to add attestations to right
um so the question is how what can we do
there um you know how can we add
attestations to repositories and make
that easy for users
um so as I mentioned in the beginning
one of the projects I work on is called
git sign so the original sort of goal
for git sign was to make git commit
signing easy so traditionally you'd use
a gpg key or an SSH key to sign your
commits but with Git sign you can
actually use the full six store keyless
flow and we were thinking hey can we
apply the same sort of principle of
cosine a test to git sign and that's
what I sort of want to show off today so
we have a really quick demo
I'm just going to hop over to the GitHub
repo here so this is just a sample repo
that I put together so within the get
sign repository we have um
uh it's right now a separate binary
we're working towards Upstream into the
git sign binary itself a tool called git
sign a test right so it's very much
mirroring what cosine a test does and as
an example here I have a few GitHub
actions that are producing attestations
some some things that you might want to
attach to your Source commits right so
this could be an s-bomb you know what
are the transitive dependencies that are
part of this repo that are going into my
builds I'm going to hand wave a little
bit here salsa source satisstation so I
was talking right before this
um one of the things that if you look at
the in Todo docks the salsa docs sort of
the concept of two-party review and have
all my changes been reviewed by by
someone I trust can we generate
attestations for that and add that to
the repository things like scorecard
static analysis and you can extend this
even further right fuzzing have CI tests
ran against this what were the results
of those CI tests these are all things
that you might want to attach to these
commits and put in a discoverable
location so that other tooling knows how
to find it and then can take advantage
of it
so as an example here here's the the
s-bomb tool that ran so we're just using
the kubernetes bomb tool so it's pretty
simple pretty straightforward we're just
checking out the code installing the
bomb tool installing git sign a test uh
we're generating the s-bomb and then all
we're doing here is
um adding this attestation making an
attestation Associated commit so all
we're doing here is we're running get
signed a test we're giving it the file
we're telling hey it's type spdx and
what this is doing is it's actually
storing the attestation in a special ref
space within the repository itself right
so just like branches and tags we can
actually push and pull these custom refs
if you're familiar with Git notes this
actually works in a very very similar
mechanism but this is sort of a
different carved out space where you
know our goal is to really make this a
space for uh to put attestations into
attestation data and so what we can do
with this is just push the Repository
and if we cut over to the repo here we
just have you know simple repo we can
actually go fetch the attestations this
isn't actually going to do anything
because I already have it cloned locally
we can do full get things with it so we
can actually check out uh arrest
attestation's commits
and so this is going to dump us into a
folder that looks pretty gnarly but it's
actually just structured
um
sort of format for hey here are all the
commit Shaws that we have attestations
for so if we do if we just get the
commit Shaw for whatever's that means so
we have this a4a
uh so if he's CD into a4a
here's where we see all the prominence
data and all the attestations right so
each one of these files they're sort of
up here here
um it's it's storing what is the
prominence data that that we added uh so
in the case of the s-bomb
um this is just an spdx s-bomb uh and
then the corresponding signature
is the signed data of that s-bomb that
we produced using this extra keyless
flow so this looks pretty gnarly because
it's a b64 blob of the the provenance
data that we had before and we can do
this for for the other things as well so
like for the the review thing
um here let me just pipe this into JQ so
it's a little nicer to see so for this
just for the demo I just sort of spat
out the pull request data so for this
pull request you know I I reviewed it I
approved it and we can actually store
this data in in the git repository
itself only using git protocol so you
don't need to you can do this in sort of
a git repo agnostic way so it doesn't
really matter if it's GitHub gitlab
anything like that
um and then the other thing is so here's
a Nifty UI that we use for just
inspecting recore log entries so this
corresponds to the S bond that I
produced before so you can see it was
issued by six door it's a short-lived
cert
um I ran this three days ago and what's
really cool about this is because the
cert was issued to the oidc identity of
my CIA my GitHub action CI you know we
can use the certificate in in this
attestation to say hey no this came from
ICI it came from like a known Runner it
wasn't just a random developer that sort
of produced the status station uploaded
it to the repo things like that so
that's sort of the value that like Sig
store can add to a process like this
so this is a lightning talk so we
unfortunately don't have that much time
to go into the specifics
um but yeah so I just wanted to show
this off it's things that we're working
on it's things that we're actively
thinking about
um you know the things that are on our
mind is Source attestation data
um like I mentioned before right it's
another part it's another piece of the
software supply chain uh we want to have
attestations so things that I would like
to hear from everyone from everyone if
you want to grab me during lunch or
something is like what kind of data
would you like to see in attestations
um you know obviously I think there's a
lot of value in having this data present
next to the commit
um yeah so we want to see how we can
grow this I am definitely interested in
the like the in Toto salsa spec for like
the two-parter review stuff like that
um but yeah I think it would be really
interesting to see how we can apply this
for for other things
um yeah so uh thank you that's all I
have a really short talk if you're
interested in get signed here's the link
for the GitHub repo and if you want to
come and chat laughter more than happy
to so thank you
[Applause]