thank you so much
thank you all for joining today in
beautiful Detroit
um
So today we're going to talk about why
machines deserve rights rethinking
automated infrastructure access with
open source teleport machine ID
so
this is what my terminal looked like at
an internship I did many years ago we
had this command we had this little file
living there called secrets.text
when we open that up
we get these
some long-lived credentials that our
team used to access automated worker
nodes that would frequently break
these lived in AWS and we had them
stored in a password Vault but because
of the frequency we needed to access
them A bunch of people on the team just
added them to local files on their
machine
and this was a terrible terrible but
common practice
and this is still a problem today
one in four employees still have access
to Old passwords and 41.7 percent of
employees admitted to having shared
workplace passwords along with
credentials AWS Keys SSH Keys Etc
and this brings it to a security breach
every security breach has two things in
common a human error for an initial
infiltration an attempt to Pivot to
maximize the blast radius
human error
six million of these credentials were
leaked in 2021
uh this is according to a git Guardian
study that they did these types of
secrets that were committed were you
know Google Cloud Keys awsiam Azure API
Keys join tokens that's a two times
increase since 2020 and this is because
more and more companies are scaling with
their Cloud infrastructure thus leading
to more and more of these secrets
and more of these leaks and you might
say but we're not open source so we'll
never do that well 85 percent of these
corporate leaks came from developers
personal repos they would Fork the repo
and it was public and then they would
merge it back in once they were done
with the pr
the next step is to maximize the blast
radius you get into a slack workplace
you get access to a server get into a
server you're going to escalate those
privileges from there you do what you
want and then profit uh 50 50 your
results May Vary you'll either be on the
beach or someplace a little bit less
nice
so some more numbers real quick 26.8
million active software developers
there's supposedly 45 million by 2030.
there's around 8 000 data centers in the
world with 50 000 physical servers per
Center this varies widely depending on
the size but this is the average
400 million of those physical servers
which means billions of virtual servers
trillions of containers uh you know the
numbers are incalculable how many
virtual environments there are open to
attack the attack surface is immense
and all of these virtual servers all
these physical servers are all running
software written by humans
humans who make mistakes
the problems with machine access
people make mistakes writing code a
misconfigured file here there is the
difference between a secure setup and an
embarrassing hack
access problems are not limited to human
developers we need to stop thinking like
this machine to machine communication
operates on outdated security principles
security principles such as static
credentials SSH Keys API Keys shared
creds when keys are used by different
services
and perimeter security
only the network boundaries protected a
VPN is simply not good enough anymore
and we also have siled access policies
for humans versus machine access
so what can we do
treat machines the same way that you
treat your developers
give them rights
provide each piece of automation with an
identity from a microservice to a VM to
any worker node in your environment they
should have an identity exactly like
your human workers do
and eliminate shared credentials
entirely
every machine every automated service
every node should have its very own way
of accessing the resources it needs to
replace them with short-lived
certificates
this way that there's no cred to lose
and enforce best practices by default so
this eliminates the need for these you
know costly and expensive uh
configurations where it takes you know
hours and hours to make sure you get it
right and I missed comma here there or
an inconfigured service account is going
to wind up in trouble
and tear down those access silos so you
have to think about the way you handle
access for your machines with the same
care that you do for your developers
to minimize the blast radius say worst
case scenario one of those machines is
compromised you have to be able to
eliminate from your network immediately
without letting it be the skipping point
to the rest of your infrastructure
and keep it simple the most secure
solution also has to be the easiest this
is what we saw at the beginning where
um those credentials were ended up saved
to these people's workstations is
because it cut down on like developer
time accessing these creds through some
Vault ended up costing time and was very
annoying so people circumvent your
security methods if you let them if it's
more complicated
so this brings us to open source
teleport machine ID
machine to machine access so what open
source teleport does is it handles four
key pillars of access authentication
connectivity and audit
Authentication
so for every service for every node you
generate an identity in the form of a
short-lived x509 certificate
for the microservice and tie that
identity to a role managed by teleport
so teleport has its own concept of rbac
that you can assign every machine
directly to so you can share rules while
at the still at the same time
maintaining that um
you know maintaining that accountability
for these machines
authorization
you need to be automatically able to
approve or deny access requests to a
range of resources like servers
databases kubernetes clusters
microservices and CI CD systems
and connectivity we're going to come
back to this diagram in a second
but it also needs to handle the
connection it needs to establish a
connection between the microservice and
the requested resources using reverse
proxy tone from the teleport server to
the resource this communication is all
encrypted and secure eliminating the
need for vpns or you know traditional
Bastion hosts and the like
foreign
extremely important for any compliance
and any standard you're trying to reach
any security standard you need
accountability and you need to be able
to review all the actions that were
taken by both your human workers and
your machines
so this is kind of the high level
architecture this is an example for
teleport configured with ansible and so
what you have is this orange teleport
cluster over well I guess you can't see
my cursor but this orange teleport
cluster
um that has two parts it has an off and
a proxy service the proxy service
handles all the traffic inside and out
of the cluster
and then the auth is a separate service
that handles uh your logging it handles
your um you know authentication and
handling all those rbac roles
then you have this ansible control node
and this is a separate node on in your
cloud
and so when you
create a new node or create a new worker
you're going to onboard that to the
teleport cluster once that teleport you
can do this in two ways you can do this
with either an ephemeral token or a
dynamic join token like an AWS IM
um and once you do that then the machine
will refresh its credentials every 20
minutes or that's configurable you can
set it every five minutes every 30 every
hour
that way there's no long-lived
credentials and there's no secrets that
can be leaked
um this then will go through the
teleport proxy and access your host VM
in this case this is a VM hosting a
kubernetes cluster from there you'll use
the SSH protocols to actually run Cube
cuddle commands directly on the VM from
your worker node
and you can do this in another way as
well
um where you can access the cube config
directly through machine ID it'll
actually populate the cubeconfig with
the machine's R back rules baked right
in and then you can just run the cube
cuddle commands from the node itself
without having to go through ansible or
any SSH
so let's see it in action
this is going to be interesting
live demos
let's see if I can type
on the screen
do you let's get rid of this
close perfect
no email bad get rid of this
okay
okay we can see this
I'm sorry
oh okay
um
all right so let's begin
um so what we're going to do today is
we're going to do we're going to see
both of those examples from the two
architecture diagrams I showed you
um and let's see can I make this bigger
oh
okay
can everyone see this okay or should I
try to make it bigger
did that do something
oh no you can't see the edge
uh
okay wait let's just let's let's do this
instead
that I didn't do that I was like
okay can you see this no
yes perfect
okay
so
we're going to have three Windows here
three terminals we're going to have our
ansible control node we're going to have
our Kate's host here and we're going to
have our teleport post
so first what we're going to do is we're
going to create our role for our bot
and this is the role that teleport is
going to use
when it's assigning that role to the
machine
and so let's go ahead and log into our
cluster
this uses GitHub to authenticate as an
SSO
and we're going to log into our teleport
cluster
so we're logged in now we're going to
actually SSH onto our teleport host
perfect so now we are in our teleport
host so now what we're going to do is we
are going to create our role that our
machine is going to use
so we're going to go ahead and this rule
looks like this
we have our name the machine ID Cube
demo this is going to be the name of
this is so tiny oh my gosh
a little bit better
okay
so we're going to have our name here
this machine ID Cube demo this is going
to be the name of our rule
um and then we're going to give it
examples we're going to give it
kubernetes access
and we're going to assign it the
kubernetes user Alice
and so let's go ahead and make our roll
here
great so we got our roll now and next
we're going to go on to our kubernetes
host
and we're going to create a kubernetes
role to that we're going to mirror with
our teleport rule
again very small
great
now we have uh our kubernetes rule
and then we're going to create the role
binding of course
got that and then we're going to go back
into our teleport
uh control node here our teleport host
and we are going to actually onboard
this bot into our cluster
so we're going to run this command um
tea cuddle is a CLI tool that allows you
to interact with the teleport cluster
and we're going to go ahead and add our
Cube demo bot with the roles of machine
ID Cube demo which is the role we just
created and another access rule that
we'll use for our SSH
perfect so we have this role
and we have now this token this bot
token here this is what we're going to
use this is only valid for 59 minutes
we're going to use it to onboard our bot
to the teleport cluster and like I said
there's two ways of doing this you could
also use an I uh like an AWS Dynamic
token as well
um perfect so on the ansible Node here
we're going to open up
this uh t-bot config here
whoops
sorry got a SSH onto our ansible node
first
I love
um live demos
perfect we're in our ansible node so now
we can do our sudo Vim
at ctbot yaml and this is what we're
actually going to use to configure
um our t-bot service which is going to
do the credential refreshing
so we're going to take this token we're
going to swap it out for the token that
we had before that we got from our
teleport host
so we're going to give it this token
and this is what we're going to use to
onboard our bot
so next we're going to actually
initialize this bot
and so this is going to take in our
config file we specify the directory
that we want all of our credentials to
be written to disk so this is the this
is the directory that all of our SSH
config and our Cube config it's all
going to be written there and refreshed
at a regular rate
uh we specify the bot user these are the
Linux users and then the reader user
which is over here which is going to be
the user that our service is going to be
imitating
great so now we have this so if we go in
here
we can see all of these files that were
created all this directory we just
generated and all these files right now
are completely blank and what our t-bot
service is going to do is it's actually
going to instantiate those files with
the credentials from the teleport host
um great so now we're going to create a
service using system D to actually run
the t-bot service in the background
and it's going to look like this it's
pretty simple and it's just going to
tell our systemd to start up the
teleport t-bot service and then we can
start refreshing those credentials
so this looks good
we're going to go ahead and start up
that service
using system cuddle start machine ID
demo
and let's get let's check the status
okay so we can see that ignore this
error that's fine we would successfully
renew the impersonated certificates we
persisted the new certificates to disk
and we're starting to watch for the ca
rotations so this will persist every 20
minutes
and let's take a look again now at our
files that we had so if we go back in to
our
directory that we specified earlier
whoops
let's go into here and we can take a
look at some of these files
so now if we cat our Cube config yaml we
actually see that we have a whole Cube
config and this was generated from the
teleport host
and so if we
export our Cube config here
to this
[Music]
um
opt machine ID Cube demo
now we can actually interact with our
cluster
whoops
Cube config there we go and now we can
actually interact with our cluster
from the worker node
all going through the teleport proxy
service
and we can go in to and actually check
it out we have a web view here
and we sign in with GitHub
and we can see if we go into our audit
log
we can see all of the activities that we
were just doing so we can see that the
kubernetes request we can see
all of the metadata from here all of
this can be fully fed into like anomaly
detection tools or other you know log
aggregators
and we can have we can see our active
sessions here so we see that our we're
logged into ansible we see that we're
logged into the control node
and we can see
our session recordings as well so all
the sessions all the SSH sessions are
actually going to be recorded here
if this would load and then you can
actually play them back
and these aren't actually videos
um they're just a collection of commands
um that will run
perfect
um and so the last thing we're going to
do
is we're going to show the ansible
example
so in our ansible node here we're going
to look at our ansible config
and see that our sshrs are actually just
set to our machine ID directory where we
get those SSH configs that are refreshed
on a regular rate so this way in the
past what you do is you'd manage SSH
Keys which were long-lived and become a
pain both for rotation and just for
security vulnerabilities once those keys
were leaked they're out there but with
teleport's machine ID these are
refreshed every 20 minutes every on
whatever Cadence you want making it much
more secure and easier to deal with
so we have this so now if we go in to
our other directory we go into our demo
folder here
um and we can try to actually run
our Playbook here and what this Playbook
is going to do
is that it is going to actually run Cube
Cube Kettle commands on the SSH node of
the that's being hosted that's hosting
the kubernetes service
perfect so we just have to change our
key permissions here for ansible
and then we should be able to run
it's a little Playbook
and Playbook Dot yaml
uh
ansible Playbook
playbook.m
and so we should see here is that this
ansible control node is going to copy
nope did that is not correct
um
okay that's fine so we're going to
change this permission again
Cube demo
and now
we should see
perfect
so now what the ansible control node is
going to do is it's going to access our
kubernetes host
it is going to upload the Pod yaml and
deployment yaml configurations that we
have written here and it's actually
going to create a pod and create a
deployment on the kubernetes cluster
and we see that the Pod engine X is
created and we see that the nginx
deployment was created so if we actually
say Cube cuddle
get pods Dash name
namespace equals uh demo name space
let's see where are these guys
um so we see our nginx pod in the demo
namespace along with our nginx
deployment replicas
and that is uh the end of the demo
um so let me go back
to the slides
but
and we can skip to the end here
Maybe
if we are cooperating please
okay well I mean you get the picture
um so thank you all so much thank you
for that's a Teleport machine ID
[Applause]
and we also have our slack here we're
also going to be at kubecon at Booth p13
so if you want to come chat more I'll be
around as well as our CEO and some other
folks so come hang out and then we also
are hosting a happy hour we still have
registration spots open if you like beer
and chicken so
thank you
any questions
hey so I I liked your talk um thank you
one of the kind of core kubernetes
things is cattle not pets
and I know also like kind of if you
Spire which I'm a lot more familiar with
also kind of with the way it does keys
and management of identities and other
things like that also has somewhat of a
cattle view sure um and I may have just
picked up on something on your slide
without really understanding it so I'm
just asking
um when you talk about all machines have
identities is this more in the pets
category or the cattle category and
maybe you can also explain what I mean
by pets and Cattle yeah so
it certainly Falls more to the the
reason that you give it an identity
um is to
um you know treat it with the same
accountability that you would like a
human so
um it's not like
like a pet in that like you can do this
also for like just an ephemeral
um like worker nodes
um so it's it's all about just kind of
consolidating access rather than like
making it something it's not it
certainly is a cattle and we're still
viewing them just as like worker nodes
um and they are can be completely
ephemeral
um so it's just all about way of like
consolidating that access rather than
making them like more special than they
need to be or something like that
um which I also forgot actually is in
the future so a lot of like a core of
this product
um in the use is like a CI CD workflow
way
um so that you can handle this access
without having these long lived
credentials that then get leaked in a
GitHub repo for example
so in teleport 11 the next release we'll
actually have GitHub action support so
that you can interact with teleport
protected resources directly from these
workflows without need for secrets in
GitHub even for example
um and we also have Kate's support for
automatic service Discovery so you can
have a cluster running this service and
anytime you create new pods or new you
know microservices or new nodes those
will automatically be added and
onboarded to the teleport cluster
without doing that whole setup that we
just did so right now we have that
support for SSH nodes like in eks for
example but we don't or um sorry not eks
uh
whatever it's called Uh or yeah eks
um but uh that'll come in teleport 11.
so this is like the kind of the core
value here is this CI CD workflow so you
don't have to have these persistent
creds
um in your infrastructure and that's
kind of the idea
does that kind of answer your question
yeah
another one over here
yeah absolutely yeah so uh great
question
um so yeah you can do it by tags or by
labels
um and as soon as there's a there's a
match that will be that uh node will be
onboarded to the cluster with its own
unique identity
um so this identity will be generated
again from its own x509 certificate
um and
it will have some like configurable
naming convention that you can give it
and you can differentiate them while
still grouping them under the label of
whatever you know like worker node or
whatever like service that you're
employing with them does that make sense
perfect
great oh over here as well
um use your identity in terms of like
I'm sorry a developer laptop yeah no
absolutely and that's like so that's
more of like the human use case but
that's also like a core teleport service
is that like machine ID is just one of
the offerings
um but what people typically do is that
it'll integrate with like your SSO like
OCTA or GitHub or whatever
um and then you can do all this for like
a human developer or like a even just
like a developer laptop like you said
um so you totally can do that yeah
and that's kind of the core business
right now of teleport The Wider use case
is for engineering teams that need
shared access to different resources
um they use teleport instead of like
using a password Vault or
um you know like juggling a bunch of SSH
keys or something like that
but yeah thank you guys so much again
and I hope to see you at the kubecon
booth thank you
[Applause]