Welcome everybody. This is the
diversity in information
security panel. I am going to be
shuffled off to the right a
little bit. So we're going to
clear the air before we turn it
over to the panel real quick
about a lot of different things
about this panel. There is
obviously a lot of strife to get
something like this in. Should
it be here, Does it need to be
here? Why is it here? There's
not problem…There is a problem.
All these wild things of why we
shouldn't do this and the simple
answer that I have for all that
is we should do it because we
should do it. Just get it out of
the way and do it. I don't have
to explain why we should do it.
You are all here because you get
that we should have done it and
your presence here says that's
the right decision that we do
this. It's a lot of warnings and
this is cheesy sounding and
everything, for a simple matter
of appeasement we'll use the
trigger words, yadda yadda
yadda. You're familiar with what
this is, this panel may not be
for you. This is for people that
are not really in that scene
that already get it. This is for
people that are just curious. I
don't see a problem. People keep
saying there is a problem. Can
people just be frank with me. In
here, there is no witch hunt. We
have these microphones. You can
ask something incredibly weird
and strange whether it's women
in technology or minority. I
know the audience maybe
cringing, we did a very small
intimate 35 person group last
year in this format that went so
well that people are like I know
you're going to judge me for the
rest of my life but I have to
ask this one thing. This is that
safe place to ask that one
thing. Maybe somebody in the
audience doesn't like this at
all is going to be twittering
and we should find out who he is
and attack him or her. But in
this room right now we're not
going to judge you for it. >> --
I have to go through --
(inaudible) I don't need a mic.
Please, ask the questions. We're
(inaudible) He is being a
dick, don't be a dick. That's
all. >> If you're not on the mic
you're not on DT TV. Good. Less
people for evidence. And all of
you in you rooms playing along
from home, we're trying to be
open and honest. We want you to
have the same courtesy there.
Other things to bring up. This
is a very, very widely diverse
panel and we're going to start
with the not so obvious ones and
move to the obvious ones. The
obvious ones is we have people
here that work at fortune 500
companies and premier companies
and wonderful and well respected
educational institutes. And a
lot of them are well-known
people having done a lot of
reverse engineering, a lot of
research. These are the doers of
your industry. And along with
the doers these are the up and
coming people that are quickly
becoming doers. It's very
diverse, just people getting
into CS, computer science to
people in it for a long time and
just crushing it. Well you're at
the beginner side. Do you have
imposter syndrome? >> Well I
work for the Gov and I am now a
section chief, so I am not
innovative or anything else >>
So that's the not so obvious
thing just by looking, all of
these people, you know, they're
very active in the info -- all
are active at DEFCON and all
have been here two years. Some
have been here since the very
first one. You're getting a wide
range of people that understand
the culture and understand
DEFCON and the good, the bad,
and the ugly that have come and
gone throughout the years. There
are gay people on this panel.
There are black people. There
are transgender people. There
are minorities on this panel.
There is -- we'll get to that.
He is handicapped. Handy
capable. There are just very
young people, there are much
older people. So you're covering
everything. Ageism, sexism, you
know, fear of transgender. All
that -- it's all here and
they're all sacrificing their
plight to take these questions
and talk about this stuff. So
with this, one of the obvious
things that people love to
Tweet, let me get this straight,
you have an entitled white guy
as your moderator of the
diversity panel? Yes. Well, I'm
from California. As of this year
I'm a minority in California.
But, that's just a small joke.
You need to see me as the
moderator, as the API. You're
all the people, you're supposed
to be able to say, hey, I get
it. I'm trying to translate
this. I know what it is to be a
white guy and be a married to a
minority. And have a daughter
that all she wants to do is play
with Legos and stuff like that.
I'm seeing it from a perspective
of other people, I'm white and I
don't see the problem. I've seen
quite a bit of it over the years
and I'm trying to be an API --
succinct and to the point about
things. He doesn't cut corners.
When it comes to this he wrote a
very great response on Bruce
Schneiders blog about the
accusations of harassment alt
DEFCON and how we handle those
things. Making sure that DEFCON
is a safe place to be. He is the
go-to guy. He is not a minority
in the traditional sense but he
is here as a representative. So
we can get that stuff out of the
way. This doesn't look like what
I thought it was. This is what
we're setting up for you just so
you understand. >> I have been
on public transportation where
you wouldn't believe the crap
that you hear in those
languages. I do want to
reiterate at the beginning here,
we have a zero tolerance. It is
not allowed. Period. Full stop.
You should feel safe and free to
approach anyone with a red badge
or red shirt at any time. If you
feel you do not get the
appropriate level of response or
the response was inappropriate,
find me. I am here from 8 in the
morning until 3 or 4 in the
morning every day. It will not
be tolerated. It's not allowed.
One of my personal pet peeves, I
do a lot of standing outreach.
There are not enough -- like I
said -- woman and minorities in
the STEM. And it's so
frustrating to walk into a
classroom where, oh you're so
pretty, don't be smart, you're
so pretty. And have that girl
ask a question. I just light up.
Someone said she's smart. >> I
swear I'm going to pass it over
to you but one plug. This panel
was organized and put together
by -- 2.0. They had a fundraiser
party last nights. Part of the
national center for women and
technology. We're the largest
organization pushing for women
in information technology in the
United States. We're the only
information security group
representing there. So it's, we
feel it's our responsibility as
stewards of the information
community for you to give us
feed back so we can get feed
back to them. They're focused in
education and foreign 500. They
have soft spots in information
security and we feel it's our
job to hear from you, hear your
responses even if we don't agree
with them, pass them straight
through and say these are things
that people bring up of concern.
Keep that in mind afterwards.
Come find us and we'll be happy
to facilitate that. Emily you
wanted to add something? >> Yes.
NCWIT I spoke at their summit a
year or two ago. NCWIT has a
high school competition for
girls 9th grade through 12th.
It's a scholarship opportunity
and award. If the girls go to
the state level they have an
award ceremony. They get a
trophy and cash prizes and
scholarship for college.
NCWIT.org. And look at their
scholarship. >> Now we'll kick
it off. I want to start with
mouse. We should do
introductions. After that I
would like you to kick off the
panel. Scott, we'll start with
you. >> Your name, your industry
or where you work. >> My name is
Scott. I'm a gay man who has
been working in the industry for
almost 20 years now, information
technology and IT. Working for a
multinational company, foreign
500. Working for -- industry
now. It's really interesting to
see what we've had happen. >> My
name is little jinni and I'm
half way through schooling for
informatics. I'm going to
combine the big data initiatives
and layer in information
security to that. It's kind of
interesting to layer that in.
I'm also Mexican and I'm also
female. >> I'm sandy Clark known
as mouse. I'm an adult that is
getting a Ph.D. I'm at
university of Pennsylvania.
We'll talk more about the
ecosystem later. >> I'm Jolly.
I'm technically homeless
although people say that doesn't
count. This is going to shock
you but I have a turban. I know.
I know. I just thought it was a
built in pillow. I left my magic
carpet at home. Other fun things
I have a slight addiction of
conferences and I mean in 2012,
I went to 26. I've probably done
more this year and also dancing
and CTF's. >> I'm Emily. Working
as a college student trying to
build a company that focuses on
educational technology. I'm
working just to increase better,
more open source, educational
resources. >> My name is Vyrus
I'm probably the most defensive
person that is going to grab the
microphone today. This is my
12th DEFCON. I'm part of a group
called DC949 we invented Open
Capture the Flag a while ago,
now it's been passed off to
another group who's doing a
crazy job. I work at a security
firm. I previously worked at
other places and break shit.
Hackers are now a minority at
DEFCON. >> I'm Kristin. I'm a
hacker first and foremost. I've
been presenting at DEFCON for
many years now. This is the
first time I've gotten up on
stage since I underwent a gender
transition about three years .
This is slightly bizarre for me.
I hack all kinds of things.
Internet companies to cell phone
companies to car companies. We
try not to. So yeah, Hi. >> All
right. I'm going to stand up
otherwise you can't see me. When
we have a podium you can't see
me over my computer. I'm going
to tell you how I got here. This
is an origin story. I grew up in
a conservative religion and had
a very well-defined gender role
and my entire future was planned
for me. And I went to my
church's university as a premed
student. And I spent my entire
childhood doctoring up every
child in the village. I imagined
myself in a lab coat. I was
going to do research and cure
cancer. And my first semester at
this university, my adviser
called me in and said you
shouldn't be in the premed
program you're a girl. I dropped
out and spent the next three or
five years trying to figure out
what I was going to do. I took a
computer science class buzz all
my friends were taking it. It
took me 10 to 15 years to break
the chains that were around my
brain. When you're firmware is
slashed with something, you
don't question it for a long
time until somebody glitches it.
And then you might start to
question. So when I broke free
and I took a couple years to
believe that I wouldn't be
punished for trying. I came to
my first DEFCON and it was
DEFCON ten and I was scared
shitless. I didn't know a soul.
I didn't know how to do
anything. I was terrified. This
was the community that I wanted
to be a part of. I walked in and
you guys found me, I don't know
how you -- but you did, but
suddenly I found a family I
never knew I had. Things, this
place, if you make it so, if you
get over the fear of -- because
it's -- well it's a bit harder
for you than it was for me
because it was much smaller
then. You will find that this is
the safest environment you will
ever be in to be who you really
are. We are not easy people to
be around. Because we won't do
things for you. We expect that
you're going to try something
and you are going to fail at it
a lot. And I'll get back to that
in just a second. And we will
help you but we won't do it for
you. Whatever you are, whatever
is inside of you, we will accept
that. Because the people who
don't, are not the people you
want the respect of anyway. My
advise to you as new bees is the
advice that the things that I've
learned from these guys. The
things that my adviser is
constantly telling me, I want
you to fail well and I want you
to fail often. And I want you to
get up and try again. I built a
couple 3D printers and this last
one I built kicked my ass. And I
spent an entire year taking it
apart down to the screws and
putting it back together again
because I couldn't get a decent
print. And because of who I am I
thought what the fuck is wrong
with me. Of course you blame
yourself because everybody else
is smart and they know how to do
it. Turns out that on one of the
forms after an entire year, this
was a full year, after --
someone said you know my nozzle
was the wrong size. I printed
something out and measured it
and it was too big. I measured
it with calibers and my nodule
was .7-millimeters and I thought
it was .5. One software change
solved all the problems. What I
mean by fail often is it's going
to happen because you don't know
how to do shit. But you don't
give up. You don't doubt
yourself and you don't stop
trying. The answers will be
there and these people, here,
have a lot of the information.
Once you try and then you ask.
And everybody will help you.
That's what this community is
for. I'm going to pass the mic
to someone else? >> Thank you
very much. We have about 25
minutes left. So thank you very
much. And this is something we
specifically wanted to make sure
mouse was out there. We talked
about it at a in the pre-meeting
, we felt she had the best
representation about how we
think of DEFCON and the people
and the friends that we make
here that continue on throughout
this industry and hopefully
these are good stewards to bring
people here or take this
attitude to wherever they go? >>
Her story is not unique. All of
us on this panel felt the same
way. This is our new family. >>
I wanted to do something to
shake up the room a bit. First
put your hands in the air and
get the energy going. It's like
a Ted talk. The next thing I
want to do is if you do not have
a college degree, please put
your hand up in the air if you
do not have a college degree. If
you were qualified for the job
and they told you that you were
exactly who they were looking
for and you still didn't get the
job because you didn't have a
degree, keep your hand up.
Otherwise put your hand down.
Ever. If you never had a degree
and knew exactly what you're
doing and said you're 100
percent qualified and we really
want you to have this job, too
bad you don't have a degree.
Look at this room here, how did
you feel about that? How did you
feel when they told you you're
100 percent qualified? There you
go. For you people, how you felt
there, you had to think other
people that -- it's easy for us
to say it's never happened to me
or hasn't happened around me. I
don't know if this is a real
thing. That was a real
experience for you and how you
felt then is how other people
feel when it's, you know, you're
a girl, you're not supposed to
be here. Or you don't fit what I
think an American should look
like. We're not going to hire
you. Or I'm homophobic and stuff
like that. And it's still
prevalent everywhere. That is
how they felt. I did everything
right to be here and you said I
did everything right except for
this degree. Imagine if you
couldn't fix it by getting a
degree. They can't be not a
minority, be not black. You
know. I don't know how to
articulate that but I think you
get what I'm saying here with
that example. I want to open it
up to the panel at this point
and say, do you have any good
success stories where something
negative happened and you found
a way to turn it around
positively? >> I used to be in
administration. I didn't have a
degree and I fell into that
right after retail and
restaurant worked and I excelled
at it. I worked my way up to
executive administration level.
I hit a point in the career
where I wasn't making enough and
wasn't getting the respect
enough so I put my resume out
there and got a call back.
You're amazing and wonderful. I
know your previous job and who
you worked for and the fact that
you survived more than a month
at that place just blew my mind.
They went through 26
administrative assistants within
one year before they hired me
and I lasted three years there.
That in itself, they're like we
need you in our office. I said
okay, what can you offer me. So
they gave me a figure. And very
typical what they always tell us
is you're supposed to counter
that. I countered that and said
I would like a little more. And
she said I'm not going to do
that. Why not? Because there are
people with degrees willing to
do it for less. And that was a
big just like choke back for me.
And I had to swallow that. I
said let me think about that for
a night. And thankfully I was in
a wonderful situation where I
had a husband that sat with me
that night and we sat up until 3
in the morning and went back and
forth. I had to get out of the
office I was at but those words
kept ringing my head. And we
looked at our finances over and
over and said go back to school.
What do you want to do? That was
an interesting point where I
said, listen, I love computers,
I like this but I don't want to
commit to that. He said what do
you like. I said I like society.
And I like working with people.
I like the intricacy. I can get
a career in anything. It's like
psychology but without a career
map. I don't want to help people
and fix emotions because you
can't do that. So he looked at
me and it was like that
lightbulb went off and I'll
never forget that moment in his
face. He is like informatics
where you use the sociology of
people and society and then
you're using information to
really combine that. It's a big
thing and it's like going places
now. Everyone heard over and
over, big data. And then as we
go more and more into this and
now we're getting into the 1 or
2 o'clock hour and he's telling
me because he is in information
security about these loopholes
and issues. And I said why isn't
anyone layering this together?
And we looked at each other and
that lightbulb went off. I
started looking into local
colleges and started building
that degree and found a local
college that worked with
information security and
informatics. Had them both. So I
started a career path of my own.
That is what I'm working in.
That was about the time that he
brought me into DEFCON. And it
blew my mind how incredibly open
and welcoming everyone is.
Interesting anecdote is one of
the first conferences that I
went to and it wasn't DEFCON but
close to that. And I remember
sitting outside and there was a
smoking section and I ran into a
girl and she was like what do
you do. I said I'm in office
management. She said Microsoft?
I said, no, people. And she
turned around and walked away.
It was shocking. She was a girl,
too. That was more like -- if it
was a guy I think I would have
passed it off but it was a girl.
And until DEFCON where I ran
into this same person again. And
we got into that exact same
conversation. And she is like
what do you do? I hesitated. I
said I'm here as someone's
girlfriend. She was like no. No,
you are not just someone's
girlfriend and nothing stung me
more. This person I hated for an
entire year and I resented her
became one of the biggest
mentors of my life and that was
here at Defcon. That was turning
a very negative into a positive.
>> What do you guys want to say
about the boilerplate? It will
be very clear once you hear the
question. Twitter is just like
this hyperbole of complete
nonsense especially when it
comes to misandre and misogyny
acusations. What do you think?
So the loaded question is,
because you're very active on
these conversations what do you
think we can do better or is it
something we have to turn off?
Or just start rambling after on
your thoughts about the
situation in it's current form.
>> I start by just hitting the
fucking unfollow button when I
don't want watch what somebody
else is saying. I don't know. My
intro to the community was
different and more hostile than
most. When I came to DEFCON
there is a lot of talk now about
DEFCON being an openly inclusive
place. When I came it was a ton
of fucking thieves. Like an
electronic gun conference. It
was a lot of people that liked
tech and scared a lot of other
people and that gave them power.
That scares people. Our history
is we have our blinking boxes
out there and we want to be
engineers. So we built our own
parties and called it DEFCON.
And now those people want to
come here, they want to look at
our tricks and buy your bugs and
pretend like we did it to teach
them. If you have a badge and
you're here today and you don't
hack stuff and you're here to
observe, that's great. But
understand you're a fucking
tourist. We built this place to
be safe for us. Not radically
inclusive. Ours. And ours means
that the thing that matters most
when you're here, not what you
look like or smell like or have
two arms, but what you do. What
is in your head. If I hand you a
problem and I don't help you
solve it, what do you do with
it? This is a bunch of people
that have unique approaches to
that question. And nothing else
matters. And you're so so
contingent is just as much as
anybody else. I'm just as free
to use racial slurs and you're
free to use racial slurs. If I
want your bugs, I should
probably be nice to you and if
you want my bugs you should
probably be nice to me. But you
don't have to do shit. I think
it's important that we keep that
mantra. Because as soon as we
become the PC police and back up
for things other than our hack,
we don't have our hacks anymore.
Thanks. We're going to start
doing some Q and A so if you
want to line up here and have
questions, this is your live mic
to do that. While we wait for
the people to come up and ask
questions, Kristen maybe you can
speak about if you've seen any
changes, if any in the Black
Hat, DEFCON, tour Con, those are
the big cons here? >> The
biggest thing that I've seen
change over the years is myself.
A few years ago when I was
coming to DEFCON I was living a
lie essentially. I knew I was
female. I was identifying as
female and forced to live this
male persona. And I was the one
not letting me fit in at DEFCON.
I could come and present
research and never felt a part
of the it because it was me not
letting myself be a part of it.
So I come back this year and
these kind people are awesome
enough to invite me on the panel
and I come and do stuff and it
feels like a family reunion.
DEFCON is a giant hacker family
reunion. I feel at home in this
place. You have no idea. And
it's been an odd realization for
me that, like the clothes and
the hair and the lifestyle
changes that I've made, makes me
feel safe in the real world.
What makes me feel safe in
DEFCON is this. It's the fact
that people here know I hack
things and I solve problems and
I build technologies and that's
the only thing that matters.
This is -- it's such a welcoming
place if you let it. But you got
to let it. >> Thank you. >>
We'll take the first ... >>
People are going to hate but for
something no matter who you. Why
not be hated for who you are
rather than who you're not. >>
Yeah. >> We'll take the first
question. >> When I came to
DEFCON as opposed to black hat,
these my people is where I feel
happy. I myself have changed in
the last genders in the couple
of years while working in the
industry. One of the things I
notice is we're very tolerance
of difference but at the same
time we have these ingrained
prejudices. So in my case people
don't care that I'm trans. I'm
seen as a woman. I have to prove
myself. So I do and I smack them
down. >> We see you as
Australian. >> No, you're wrong.
It's okay. >> May I respond? So
the thing is that this isn't
just DEFCON. We get that kind of
thing, I have a very recent
example with U.S. congress
people where they would not
listen to a female voice. And
everything had to be repeated by
a male voice before they would
listen. This is not exclusive to
DEFCON. This is a problem that
right now the only solution I
can think of is to do some
awesome hacking. Rub their
fucking noses in it. At least
here for a lot of its history,
about 30 percent of the
speakers, the people presenting
the cool stuff have been female.
While it may not meet your needs
and there is still no line at
the women's bathroom which is my
metric yeah. Some things here
are better than they are in the
real world. >> Really quickly,
we do a survey where we -- all
the conferences and all of them
generally say between 6 percent
and 12 percent women except for
DEFCON. DEFCON is between 28 and
38 percent. The uptake of women
in information security is about
16 percent, 16, 17 percent. So
we're double the actual industry
as far as our speaker
representation is concerned. Of
course, everybody can quickly
look and say there is 51 percent
of women on earth so shouldn't
there be equal representation.
That is true but it's a path
we'd like to get to. But just to
point out we're more than pacing
at DEFCON. If you know our CTF
process you know it naturally
bubbles up that way. >> I don't
want 51 percent in here. I don't
care if your transgender, a
woman, a man. I'm looking for a
good piece of mind. If you have
asexual, trisexual, or a neuter,
I don't care. It's not important
to me. If you are a brilliant
mind, that's what I want to see
here. I don't want to see 14
percent Vietnamese and 30
percent Caucasian and 15 percent
women. I want smart people here.
And get over yourselves. Get
over yourself. The only way I
can be more handsome is if I
shave my rear end and walk on my
ends. Everywhere I go with my
shaved head it's a hate crime.
Because I'm the big ugly white
guy. Who cares. Don't be a dick.
Don't put hand on people you
can't put hands on. And Going
back to your original point, as
virus said the original
community was a small tight knit
community, i've been here since
DEFCON 5, so 17 years I watched
the kids who came to five are
now here just starting with
their grandkids, our demographic
has expanded from that. They do
a much more diverse homogenized,
corporatized, marketized
community. We're seeing that
bleed over into this. Just
listening to the crap about New
Zealand. The scariest thing I
ever saw was when we played the
University of Hawaii and they
did the Haka, I swear I thought
they were going to eat us. It
was cool. It was great. Cause I
can do that, I'm comfortable
with that. Who cares. Let it go.
I'm not an ugly white guy who is
an asshole. I'm me. Don't carry
it with you? >> One of the
things that I took away with my
experience at NCWIT -- is
there's this thing called
unconscious bias. You're not
aware of what you're doing.
Because there's so many white
men in the information security,
people, everybody, doesn't
matter what race or culture you
are or sex, you start to be
build expectation of who fits
that model. So I'm 100 percent
not for affirmative action. I
don't think there needs to be
percentages or quotas. But as
individuals you need to break
that mold and not expect the
white man to be the hacker. It's
an interesting, people aren't
aware. So if you're thinking, oh
yeah, that is not an issue. No.
You are that issue. You have to
stop -- I've been guilty of
that. It's interesting. I think
it's -- whether it's your sex or
your skin but we are guilty, I
think by fixing those numbers
just a little bit. It's not
about 50/50 or meeting a quota
but understanding there is no
quota? >> It's about
opportunities. The opportunities
for someone who is interested
regardless of age or whatever.
Whatever characteristic they
feel comfortable. You've seen
the always commercial recently.
If you haven't seen it, it's
very interesting example of
unconscious bias. Because they
asked a bunch of small girls,
like under 7, what it means to
run like a girl. What it means
to throw like a girl. And so the
girls race across the room and
throw the ball as far as they
can. And then they ask the
adults what does it mean to run
and throw like a girl and then
you get the classic stereo
types. And then they showed the
adults what the kids said. And
the adults realized they had a
bias. Sometime between 7 and
wherever they were they
transitioned from a girl can do
anything to a girl has to do it
like this. I don't think it's
just related to females. >>
Question to females in the
audience. First, this is your
first DEFCON speaking as a
female. does that mean you're
going to take a shot? >> That
means someone has to go get
that. >> Doesn't sound like I
can say no to that. What's your
next question? >> Well, that
depends. Technically I'm three.
My question for all of them,
I've interviews females on
occasion, talked to them on
occasion and asked them
questions about women in the
workplace and how I can
contribute and make it more
comfortable. But I get responses
as far as when I ask them, they
prefer working with men. The
typical girls are crazy, I don't
like working with them. How am I
supposed to help if they don't
even want to work with each
other? >> That is a very good
question. We have the same Bias.
>> If you'll notice, men, boys,
are cultured from an early age
to work in teams, we work in
teams. We play football and
baseball and basketball. I'm not
a psychiatrist. Girls, girls
play individual sports. They
swim, they play tennis, they're
thought from a very early - hear
me out. They're taught to
compete with their peers. If you
think about that as a general
rule, they'll play in the dirt.
>> So there has been interesting
research on educators where they
asked little girl -- they ask
teachers if they treat their
girl pupils different than their
boy pupils. And this is not just
U.S., this is also been done in
Europe. And the standard answer
from the teachers is no, we
treat all the kids the same
until they are videos. And then
they show, when they ask a
little girl a question and she
gets it wrong, they have nice
and kind and say that's the
wrong answer. But when they ask
the boy a question and gets it
wrong, they then work with him
to get the next answer. So if
you think about it like this.
They coax the answer out. Girls
learn young, you get one chance
and if you fail you don't get
another chance. Girls try to
make things perfect. I went to a
conference recently that was
specifically for minorities in
security, an academic conference
and it was 99 percent female.
The idea was to get a group of
young security researchers to --
in a conference where they can
see people doing interesting
work. Not talk about gender
insecurity but talk about
research being done regardless
of gender. They made every one
of us talk for 2 minutes about
our research specialty. And
every woman spoke passionately,
intelligently about whatever
they were doing. And I thought
it was so cool. And then they
sat in the audience for the next
three days and said nothing.
Five of us had this interactive
conversation. And we were eating
communal meals and I was going
from table to table and talked
to people, you are doing such
and such, this person speaking
is doing such and such, why
didn't you talk to them? I was
afraid to make a mistake. I was
afraid to say something. It's
from the cradle because the
consequences of failure are so
much harsher that is one thing
that male mentors can do is give
the females, your females
proteges a safety net. If they
make a mistake you don't fire
them. If they make a mistake
it's okay? >> I have a very
quick answer directly to your
question. If someone says I
don't like working with women
because they're crazy, whether
it's a man saying it or a woman
saying it, they're being a dick.
>> Further to that, I noticed in
the workplace a lot of people
are often being dicks. And
sometimes the people are present
and sometimes they're not. What
responses would you like to see
when people are being dicks.
When these comments are made?
And if -- >> You don't say that
at a job interview though. >>
Personally I don't always have
the courage to speak up when I
see people being a dick. Can you
offer any advise to people in
the room about how to step
forward or do you think that
should be something we're doing
when we see these comments being
made? My immediate thought is I
have to think hard about that
person that you're interviewing
with. If they're asking
questions that are dick in
nature, do you want to work for
them? >> Those questions are
illegal. They are not allowed to
ask questions about your
marriage or your sexual life or
your personal life. What is on
your resume, that's what they
have to go on? >> This wasn't
about interviews. It was about
workplace interactions. >> In
the regular workplace Ive found
it very important to really sell
what you're doing and show off
your skills. Regardless of
whether you're black, white,
whatever. What you do is why
you're there and you do it well.
>> And one school of thought, it
can be tough for a lot of
individuals to follow along. If
you know -- and I said nothing
and then it goes on and on. That
is a powerful quote because you
as an individual, you're like
hey, I don't know if I'm
comfortable saying or not
saying. And by not saying it,
it's sometimes worse. That means
I may have to look inside myself
and do something I'm not
comfortable with to speak up.
But not speaking up can have
some dire results as well. I'm
not demanding that you do that
but it's food for thought that
if we don't speak up, we don't
speak up? >> What if we do
experiments. If we do, what are
the results. Try it and see what
happens. >> We're going to take
the next question because we're
short on time. >> Quick. You
don't have to have a big
explanation. Just say, don't be
a dick and then move on. You
don't have to say anything other
than that. It's just being a
friend and reminding them. >>
Next question. >> In general my
life, as a queer person is kind
of weird, and whatever you know
I would have expected given what
I've been taught. To have had
bad experiences in general. But
no one here has given me a bad
experience. No one has
discriminated against me. And I
feel like I don't slash our/
slash men's rights threats. But
how do I like, how do I say,
like, actually I've had positive
experiences. I know other people
haven't and I respect that. But
there is a lot of people out
there who have treated me very
well. And that's awesome, and I
want to give positive
reinforcement to the people
who've been doing that while
simultaneously telling people,
no, there is no sexism in the
world. I don't get it. I've been
very privileged. >> I only had
one negative comment the entire
time I've been involved. >> My
girlfriend is watching on TV
right now. Hopefully I'm not
flirting with you too much, or
just enough. >> Anyway, I wanted
to say that as generations like
ours, we are coming into the
work force, I experience less
bias as days go by. And in
generations like mine I'm used
to seeing people who are gay and
transgender and hanging out with
other people. This is my normal.
When I went to school, I went to
Purdue and they have the second
highest international rate. And
I think that we as our younger
generations -- will be able to
deal with more diversity and
teach those who are older to
deal with it as well and
experience it and work with it.
>> Jolly do you want to expand?
>> I often struggle with the
same question. I had that
progress and change over my
life. I remember me growing up,
junior high, elementary, where I
obviously stood out. I was the
different kid and I got teased a
lot for it. If I look at my
precollege identify, it wasn't
fun. If I look at me today and
look at my life, I think my
diversity, and my life is
fucking awesome but -- >> And
you're Jolly. >> But exactly
this' it. I think now I get
massive benefits for being
diverse because I'm the dude in
the turban named Jolly dancing
at a party and everyone
remembers me. I get on so many
work calls and introduce myself
and say I'm Jolly and they know
who I am and I have no idea who
they are. >> Do you think that
is privilege, I feel like that
the people I work with, I have a
benefit because I have really
nice tits and they enjoy looking
at them. That is some privilege
in the community. I feel like I
should check my privilege. >> I
have a lot of friends that are
-- that're white guys are
glasses. >> I'm not saying I
won't. I will honor my
privilege. >> I honestly don't,
it's challenging because I don't
often know how to react because
I have substantial benefits for
who I am versus my white male
friends wearing glasses and
black T-shirts. Try finding them
at a crowd at DEFCON. >>
Quickly, I think we need more of
those stories. It's not like ha
ha, shame on you. I have the
upper edge. We need more
positive stories. No shame. No
double edged sword. We need more
of this. I hear so many negative
stories and I'm done with it.
That is exactly why I pursued
this panel. >> We're going to
move onto the next question and
then wrap up with closing
statements. >> I mentioned to
priest earlier in response to
the girls are competitively and
boys play football. I played
defensive tackle. I was the only
woman in my league. I spent my
entire life invading male spaces
being told I don't belong
there. And I'm like, fuck you,
I'm still here. How do we
counter having to have that
attitude because there are a lot
of brilliant minds out there who
don't necessarily have that
attitude, who don't have that
strength and there are also a
lot of organizations who are
claiming to advocate for these
folks and doing so in a really
underhanded and back stabbing
way. So how do we make the space
open to those people who don't
necessarily have that same
temperament without throwing
them to the wolves of these
various organizations claiming
to advocate for them, and will
not? I think the answer is
mentorship. Be a mentor and
reach out to that new person in
the scene. Don't be afraid, yea,
it's only my second year of CON
but I'll be happy to show you
around. That is where you get
that change. You're no longer
the only girl on the team. Now
there are two of you. You proved
your point? >> Anyone here know
this symbol? Do you know where
it comes from? There's priest
(inaudible) they can take -- one
by one ... But they can't take
us all together. It's stand
together. >> We're wrapping up
and everything. We're going to
make quick closing statements.
Thank you to the panel for
taking the time. We initially
talked about going in a
different direction and these
things have a way of being
animals and going wherever they
want to go. I hope everybody on
stage had the opportunity to say
their piece and I hope they were
able to get through. And so, I
thank you, everybody. And you
guys see their faces here. One
thing I wanted you to take away
before you leave, these are
obviously people you can
approach off this panel. Come
talk to them. They want to talk
to you. It's a positive
experience and we want to keep
it a positive experience moving
forward. Finally, numbers,
people coming in, blew us away.
Not official DEFCON but looking
at the demographics. This year
is the first year there are
notable chunks in the pie chart.
This is a big year for you to
actually seek out people that
you have something in common
with. So why not talk to
somebody, you're like hey I've
never talked to that person
before, let's go and say hi.
It's hard for people to approach
random strangers but this should
be a good place to do that? >>
DEFCON is that one environment
where you can. Grab me in the
hall. I don't care. I will stop
and talk to you for a half hour
before I realize I was supposed
to meet somebody somewhere. >>
Okay. Well thank you all very
much and I appreciate all your
time. And we're -- a lot of us
are hanging out in the contest
area so if you want to go over
there, that is where we
generally are. >> I would like
to make one statement. With
current industry trends, by 2016
you're only going to have
one-half of the industry jobs
filled. If we don't start
increasing the diversity rates
we're going to fall. We need to
increase diversity. Encourage
people to come to DEFCON. Find
the people who are broken. Find
the people who are put down and
help them become what we are.
DEFCON is one of -- I haven't
felt at home like this since I
was at Jcon. It's fantastic? >>
If you want to talk to me about
not drinking in a world full of
alcohol, come and talk to me. >>
And also, also if anyone wants
to meet me for dinner I'm going
to the American bar grill thingy
and I'll be standing there. Just
join me and we can talk on stats
on diversity rates and can
answer any questions that were
not answered today. >> Perfect.
Thank you very much, everybody.
"This text is being provided in
a rough draft format.
Communication Access Realtime
Translation (CART) is provided
in order to facilitate
communication accessibility and
may not be a totally verbatim
record of the proceedings."