So, you'll hear people refer to
me as Anch, Unch, Inch. I
pronounce it Anch. Technically
it's a form of Unc but I'm Anch,
and you guys are here to listen
to me ramble on about man in the
middle attacks or monkey in the
middle attacks. And we'll, we'll
play some traffic it will be a
lot of fun. Uh, so, just a
little bit about me. This is the
slide that I normally introduce
my wife because she's here but
she's not here. That's her on my
way. I'm sure you're going to be
four minutes late. I'll
introduce you guys when she gets
here. I have a lot of experience
in penetration testing and
hacking and funny story -- funny
story time since I have time. A
penetration tester, the job
title penetration tester is the
best, best title to have at a
party. [Laughter] People walk up
to you, what do you do? I'm a
penetration tester. And they
look at you funny like, Huh?
[Laughter] And they're like, so,
what do you do exactly? They're
expecting something like, well,
I test the lighting in porn. But
then I explain to them what I
do, and they're like, oh, that's
actually really fucking boring.
[Laughter] So, uh yeah. I have
got over ten years experience
doing this. I like to do this,
and I like to teach people how
to do it. I'll take a little bit
of a survey, how many of you
guys are first year DEF CON,
first time. Wow, I got a room
full of noobs, that's awesome.
By the way when I say noob it's
not an insult, honest to God not
an insult it is a compliment.
I'm a noob at things, I can't
reverse engineer for shit I'm
teaching myself to do it. I'm
total noob at reverse
engineering but I'm really,
really good at the other stuff.
So, being a noob is not a
problem it's actually really
awesome. How many people in here
are penetration testers right
now? Ok, how many people in here
want to be penetration testers?
Good. That's awesome. That's an
admirable goal. How many people
-- How many people actively
exploit boxes? As a penetration
tester? I got one. I got two.
Charge, I didn't save those
seats for you. [Laughter]
Actually really I didn't. My
wife is coming down so just save
her a seat she's got one more
with her she'll probably sit on
the floor it will be ok. Well,
You know it's important that I
take care of my wife. So, yeah,
so uh, that's a little bit about
me. Boneheadsanom is my Twitter,
tweet me if you want me, it's
all good. Did that not actually
cycle? There we go. So, why do
we play in traffic? Traffic is
really, really interesting. By
the way I put funny stuff on my
slide so feel free to laugh.
Don't be like -- It's quiet and
stuff. You guys are the quietest
audience I've ever had, When I
walked down here and I asked you
guys if you were in line for the
talk you were like -- anyway.
Traffic is interesting stuff.
Yeah, thank you. It gives us
insight on to how things work.
When you're looking for
something on the network that's
misbehaving the first place I go
is the traffic. Oftentimes it's
something simple like a miss
configured switchport or I'm in
the wrong VLAN or I'm pushing
things to the wrong address but
the traffic will tell me that.
And if you know how to read
traffic and you know how to look
at it and you know how to
capture it you can actually do
some pretty cool stuff with it.
It allows us to gather
information on a target, really
valuable information on a target
actually. Tells us the source
and destination, Mac addresses,
tells us what ports the traffic
is -- the target is talking on,
so what ports are open.
Sometimes you can't get a port
scan because you got a fire wall
and it's just sitting there and
it's like empty. You know you
run M Map and you're like, it
comes back, nothing. I know that
host is alive so if I can get
the traffic I can tell what
ports are open on it and maybe I
can spoof the traffic in order
to get in to that host. There's
a lot of fun stuff you can do
with traffic. And it allows us
to change things as they go by,
I know I get in to some fun
stuff you can do. You can really
prank your friends with some of
this especially when you're at
home your friends get on the
Internet they're like, why --
why are, why is all the images
upside down? We get -- Hi!
Everybody, this is my wife.
[Applause] Yeah. I saved you
seats. And uh, yeah. Have a
seat. She supports me in
everything that I do and I love
her very, very much. And so she
deserves a great big hand.
[Applause] So, being able to
play in traffic allows us to
change things as they go by and
make modifications to stuff that
may or may not allow us to get
in to things that we're not
supposed to. And that kind of --
that kind of power is great
because people aren't looking
for it. IDS looks for it a
little bit but if you're smart
about it you can actually bypass
IDS altogether. And by like, oh,
yeah, that's the traffic that is
supposed to be there. Good I'm
actually getting you --
chuckles. That's good. Most
importantly it allows us to
prank our friends. And honestly
allowing us to prank our
friends, we have to have fun
with this job. We can't just --
we can't just -- just do the
work to do the work. If it's not
interesting to you, you are in
the wrong line of work. You
really are. What was that? We
have to laugh. It is all about
the roles, you'r right. We have
to laugh, we have to have fun.
And you have to be interested in
doing this stuff so you'll
actually learn it. Otherwise you
go to work for 10 or 15 hours
out of the day and you come home
and you get stagnant because
you're not learning new stuff.
You're going to -- you're
applying what you already know
but not actually picking it up.
And if you love it, you'll go
home and you'll read about it or
you'll play with it or you, you
know, you'll mess with your
friends, your neighbors.
[Laughter] Interesting story
about my neighbors. I actually
-- I did something for Aruba and
they were kind enough to give me
an access point to play with. It
was one of their new 80211AC
access points and I set it up at
home and I'd been having
problems with interference on
stuff and the Aruba access point
comes up and it goes, oh I'm
seeing interference. Let me take
care of that for you. All of a
sudden all of my neighbors
access points go, oh I'm going
to get quieter and turn down and
now I'm the king of the
mountain, pretty awesome. All
right. How do we get in to the
traffic that we want to play
with. There's a lot of different
ways to do it. And I don't have
my presenter notes up here, so
just remember to always wear a
helmet. You want to -- you don't
want to really mess anything up
so you got to be real careful.
Playing with traffic, playing
with network traffic in general
you're not going to permanently
screw something up but it can
definitely have unintended
consequences, I'll get in to
those here in a little bit. When
you mess with things, the
systems have checksums and ways
to figure out that you're
actually messing with them and
they'll toss it out. You can be
like, oh, I got the transparent
proxy in place I'm trying to
create the all important
Internet. And it's replacing
these images but it's not -- the
images aren't coming up and it's
probably because you're not
injecting them right. We'll talk
about that a little bit later.
It can be dangerous. You can get
caught. It's a noisy thing. If
you get caught and you're not --
well if you get caught and you
don't have permission to play in
traffic, by the way, get
permission first. No means no.
If you don't have permission and
get caught, the consequences can
be dire, you can get arrested
and go to jail. That's never
fun. But, it can be dangerous,
it can mess stuff up. It can
mess your traffic up on your
network, I've done that a couple
of times. My wife calls me, the
Internet is not working. I'm in
Oklahoma I'm like, sorry, I left
that on and I didn't mean to. It
does really mess with the
network especially some of the
tools that we'll talk about here
in a little bit. It can take
entire networks down and like
big networks. Or entire segments
of a network down. When you're
impersonating a gateway or
directing traffic to your box
and that gateway is normally
handling 10 gigs of traffic and
your box has a 100 gig card in
it, it tends to hurt a little
bit. It can really, really mess
with the networks. And you can
really be -- you can really be
-- put yourself in a position
where you are taking something
critical off line. And as a
tester we never really want to
do that. We tend to get smacked
for it and it makes our jobs
even more difficult. And like I
just alluded to your host might
not be fast enough. You might
not be able to process all the
traffic that you're getting.
You're going to drink from a
fire hose and when you do that
it tends to fill your mouth
pretty fast. And switches will
alert on things, if you have a
client that is particularly
intelligent and has their
monitoring and alerting set up
it will throw an alert and they
will catch you and they'll be
like, ha. And you'll be like,
okay, you caught me. And IDS
usually does catch it. There are
ways to get around that and
we'll talk about that in a
little bit, but it usually does
flag on things when they start
to change. Your IDS is set up to
look for normal and you're
creating something abnormal or,
you know, yeah -- looking for
somebody abnormal and you're
creating something that is not
kosher on the network. And so it
will usually catch it. For those
of you that can't read this, it
says a giant tool and he's
carrying a wrench. So we're
going to have a little
discussion about tools. And how
to use them and what they're for
and the best ones to use. I'm
going to go through the stuff
that I normally use and normally
put on a network in order to get
in to traffic. And tell you
there are pitfalls and the goods
and the bads. So we're going to
talk a little bit about arp
spoofing and when to use it
which is almost never. And we're
going to talk a little bit about
DNS poisoning and spoofing and
when to use it, which is a lot
because it's a whole lot of fun.
We're going to talk about DHCP
snooping or spoofing as well,
basically telling -- answering
faster than the DHCP server for
an address and making yourself a
gateway. We're going to talk
about transparent proxies which
is where all the pranks come.
Those are the most fun. And
those transparent proxies are
what you use after you get the
traffic to your machine.
[Laughter] I'm glad that got a
laugh. Because I have run in to
so many people that are like,
yeah, I use Kali Linux I'm a
hacker. No. That doesn't make
you a hacker, I'm sorry. Let's
talk about the most dangerous
option, arp spoofing and arp
poisoning. The tool is Arp spoof
and it's provided as part of the
Dsniff suite of tools. If you
haven't got Dsniff installed,
install it. There's a lot of
really fun stuff you can do with
the Dsniff suite. You can Arp
spoof, you can DNS spoof, you
can do traffic discovery you can
do a lot of stuff with it. It's
really, really, really cool. It
is easily, easily, easily
detected on the network. So
basically what you're doing with
an Arp spoof is you're answering
-- everybody know what Arp is?
Hold your hand up. All right.
For those of you that don't talk
to your neighbor afterwards they
will explain it to you, just
kidding. Basically an Arp is a
way to tie a Mac address to an
IP address and a switch holds
the table of these ties that's
best way that it can route the
traffic, the layer 2 traffic, in
the switch. From port to port.
So what you're doing when you
ARP spoof, is you're saying, no,
I'm really the gateway address
it's me, you're flooding the
switch with answers to Arp
requests for whose got the
gateway, whose got the gateway,
whose got the gateway. And
you're like, me. Me. You know,
it's me. And basically you're
injecting yourself in the middle
and becoming a gateway. Now, if
you don't have your machine
configured right what is going
to happen is you're going to get
all the traffic that's going to
have nowhere to go and whole
network is going to come
crashing down and you're going
to be like, um, Oops. When your
machine finally crashes because
you're drinking from that fire
hose the network will go back to
normal. But, until then you just
brought your client down and
that's never a good thing. But
for the most part IDS will catch
this as you're doing a
gratuitous Arp, IDS will go, no,
he's not really the gateway. He
can like to think he is but he's
not. And it will catch it. It's
one of these things that lights
IDS up like a Christmas tree. I
just alluded to, if done
incorrectly it will take down
the network, and it will, I've
done it. I'll admit that. I've
done it at home. I've done it at
work. I've done it at work, at
home. Starbucks. [Laughter ] You
need a fairly powerful host to
keep up with the traffic. These
days we're looking at gigabit or
multi-gigabit connections. Your
host needs to be able to process
that. So your little Wi-Fi
pineapple or your little Linksys
box that you can do this with is
not going to cut it. It just
can't process the traffic fast
enough. Laptops, Mac minis,
small commuters, they're going
to be able to keep up with the
traffic as long as you're at a
gigabit or better, I carry a
secondary network card,
lightning network adapter in my
bag just for this purpose. So
that I don't have to route
traffic in and out the same
address I can pull it in one and
route it out the other. Setting
it up basically your setting
your box up as a gateway and you
got to be able to route the
traffic through the machine
without actually slowing it
down. You're going to slow it
down a little bit, just one of
those things, but you want to
slow it down as little as
possible. [Laughter] I told you
they were funny. Yeah. So DNS
poisoning and spoofing a
slightly less dangerous way. It
is slightly less dangerous, Cane
is one of tools that is able to
perform this function amongst
others. It's actually pretty
damn good at doing what it's
supposed to do. And it's the one
that I prefer, yeah it's a
Windows tool and I know Windows
is bad. What's that? InnoVM,
Absolutely. People look funny at
me because I have a Mac, and
actually I see a lot of Macs
now, used to be one of those
first people to actually hack on
a Mac. They're like, you run a
Mac, I'm like, yeah, it's a
great platform. I can run
Windows on it still. It may
still require you to Arp spoof
first. You're going to send
replies to DNS requests, to
point traffic at yourself. So
you have to become that DNS
server. You may have to Arp for
that one specific address and
say, I'm a DNS server, I'm the
DNS server instead of I'm the
gateway. And it is always used
in conjunction with other tools.
It doesn't -- it can't actually
handle the traffic itself. And
so what you're going to do is
you're going to reply with an
address pointing that particular
-- that DNS answer back at
yourself or someplace else in
order to capture the traffic
going -- in order to get the
traffic to be redirected. And
the great thing is, is with DNS
caching, is you may only have to
answer once every five minutes.
Or once every two weeks.
Depending on how the cache is
set up in DNS. If you have to
answer once every two weeks,
that's pretty awesome. Because I
can stand up a box, answer once,
poison the cache and take the
box down and go home and I'm
still getting that traffic. It's
really pretty cool. Unless they
figure it out and they flush the
cache. Like I said it provides
your IP address the answer to
the DNS queries. You're saying
I'm really this -- I'm really
Google, it's me. I'm Google. I'm
going to -- I'm going to send
you my search results which may
not necessarily be kosher. I'll
let you read this. Cause it's --
I thought that was pretty funny,
too. Still a little bit less
dangerous, we're going from most
dangerous to least dangerous in
this particular category. DHCP
spoofing, you're going to
provide answers to DHCP
requests. The ever famous
Ettercap who in here has heard
of Ettercap it's a tool, it's a
long old, old tool. It works
really, really well it has for a
long time. And it's really well
maintained, it's awesome. But
Ettercap does this function
perfectly. You still be able --
you still need to be able to
sniff the traffic, you still
need to get the traffic coming
to your box somehow so you're
still going to have to do
something. Either have a span
port or, or one of these. Last
year I did a talk on my bag of
dirty tricks. Zase's mom came up
and said I really like the Ninja
throwing star. This is what
she's talking about. This is a
Ninja throwing star LAN tap. You
guys have probably seen these I
think they're available in the
vendor area. As kits. They're
really, really cool. It allows
you to get in the middle of
traffic and, you know, scan it,
play with it and inject in to it
and, hey look, all my friends
finally showed up. I'm going to
embarrass you like I embarrassed
my wife. Bill, wave hi to
everybody. Everybody turn around
and wave hi to Bill. You and I
need to go talk to Priest later.
No. But I want my T-shirt.
[Laughter] Now he's laughing.
[Laughter] Yeah, you can
actually get in the middle of
traffic with one of these, you
have to be physically there, you
have to be able to plug in to a
wall jack between a machine but
it will let you scan traffic and
provides both transmit and
receive and it's pretty cool.
It's a passive device, you don't
need power, it's really, really,
really awesome. Wow, are they
loud or what? We're going to
take a real quick break we're
going to do something here to
annoy the other guys. Okay? I
want everybody -- I'm not going
to make you stand up again. I
want everybody to scream and
clap for ten seconds as loud as
you possibly can. Ready, one,
two, three -- do it. [Cheering
and Screaming] Perfect!
[Laughter] They put us in these
small rooms with these thin
walls and you know that's Sky
Talks over there and there's no
recording we just probably
really annoyed the speaker
because he's right behind that
wall. [Laughter] That's a lot of
fun to do. I'll have to look and
see who was speaking and go,
Hey! [Laughter] Switches can be
alerted to check for and deny
this type of attack. Especially
in situations where you're
relaying traffic to one DHCP
server. It can be -- the switch
can be configured to actually
send these packets directly to
the DHCP server and send the
responses back, if that's the
case this isn't going to work
for you. If they're really,
really well configured and tight
on this, this attack is going to
be tough to pull off. But it is
less dangerous than an Arp spoof
because you're not -- you're not
going to interrupt all the
traffic, just some of it. And it
is also used in conjunction with
other tools, we'll talk about
those other tools here in a
little bit. So, we're going to
talk about proxies but this
image might be a little bit hard
to see, hard to read. It's the
whole, what my friends think I
do, what my mom thinks I do.
Yeah. My mom knows I'm a hacker
but she does think I work for
the Geek squad sometimes. And
I'm not a chick even though
that's a chick in what I think I
do. And we all know what we
actually do. The government one
I thought was the funniest,
cause I'm sinking the Titanic.
You need to actually be able to
do something with the traffic
once you get it. You need to be
able to have a way to change
things, the easiest way to
change it is to set up a
transparent proxy. In this case
we're talking about HTTP or
HTTPS type traffic or web
traffic. There are some other
tools that you can do that do
other traffic like SSH. You can
do actually do SHH man in the
middle and it is evil and it is
fun and [Loud Noise] [Laughter]
Why? >> It's so heavy. I love
you softly. >> Guys, this is
Crypt. He's pranking everybody.
All of his friends. [Laughter]
>> Hey Crypt? >> Yes. >> Why
don't you -- Oh. [Laughter] >>
You have any Def Coin on ya?
Uh-huh. Oh, that's nice. >> I
only have -- I have four left.
>> You have four left? Can I
have them? Of course I did. All
right. [Laughter] >> I am
amazing. And I'm a good sport am
I not? >> You're one of the
smartest guys I know. >> Yeah,
awesome. I've got 400 Def coin
here and I'm going to do some
questions and answers. And the
best questions that I come up --
that uh, that you guys ask me
I'm going to give a Def coin to.
Who here has DEF coin? I know
you guys do. Of course you do.
Who here wants DEF coin. Good.
At least I've got something
that's valuable. The paper it's
printed on is worth more than
the actual coin. So, multiple
tools provide this service.
We'll talk about SSH man in the
middle here in a little while.
We'll talk about HTTP and HTTPS
first. Who in here have heard of
Burp, the Burp suite? Who have
actually installed the Burp
suite? What was that? Pro? I
don't pay for it. The features
that ask, it provides, they're
not valuable enough for me to
pay for it. And the free version
is awesome. Who here has
actually used the Burp suite for
something? Good. Good. You know
what I'm talking about. It's
fun. You can actually examine,
and look and change traffic, web
traffic as it goes by. You would
not believe the number of people
that look at me funny, when I
say, you know what, I've got
your password. How did you do
that? You sent it in clear text.
What do you mean, clear text?
Yeah. Another tool I'll talk
about is Malory. This is one
that fewer people have heard of.
Raise your hand if you've heard
of Malory. Raise your hand if
you've got Malory to
successfully run. It's a
difficult tool to actually use.
But, it's infinitely more
powerful than Burp. You can do
so much more with Malory and
it's fast. And it's not Java
based. That got you. But it's
really, really hard to set up
and use. The documentation isn't
very good, not very well
maintained. I don't think -- I
didn't see anything since like
2011. It hasn't been maintained
very much at all. So most people
that use it and use it
effectively maintain it
themselves. I actually have a
private GetHub repository with
my version of Malory in it and
it's because I've had to make so
many changes to it to keep it
functioning over time that I a
want version control. I can't
just -- I'll lose the tar ball
if I lose the machines. And then
there's Squid. People look at
Squid as like a good regular old
proxy but it can actually do
scriptable changes. It's fast,
it's efficient, it runs as a
service and it's really, really
good at what it does. We'll talk
about Squid here in a little
bit. So let's uh -- Yeah. It is.
Passwords any more are
ineffective unless they have
spaces. Remember that, put
spaces in your passwords. People
don't think about spaces. Spaces
at the end of passwords when you
crack them they show up as a
blank space, right? So you're
like, I don't understand why
this password isn't working.
Well, it's because it's got a
space at the end of it. Let's
talk a little bit about Burp
suite. You guys know, it's Java,
it runs on almost anything. Runs
really well on almost anything
and runs really slow on almost
anything. Java is one of those
things that we wish we didn't
have to put up with but we do
have to put up with it. But it's
good, readily available, the
free version is more than
effective for what most people
need. Unless you're doing some
really serious heavy, heavy,
heavy application testing and
want to know some automated
stuff and some automated
certificate stuff. My arrow keys
just aren't working well. It
just works most of the time.
It's like an Apple computer, you
know. Or iPhone. Just works.
Your 5 year old can probably
figure it out, it's pretty cool,
it's got a real good GUI. It
sets up requests and posts in
such a way that you can actually
change them and see what's going
on. I'll be honest if I'm
looking for something quick Burp
is the first thick I grab. If I
don't have time to play with
Malory and get it fiddled and
setup, If I'm just looking for a
quick, you know, two-day
engagement I'm doing a pentest
on application I'll pull up Burp
suite and go through it that
way. It's really, really good at
what it does. It grabs cookies.
It will hold gets and posts for
you, it will sit there and fake
the server out like, yeah, trick
on the data to you, just on a
really slow connection and let
you change things and it's
really great to escalate
privileges because lot of people
don't think about -- developers
don't think about the cookies
that they're setting, you know,
they set this cookie and their
like, yeah, you've got user
level. It's like user level
zero. Like, okay. What happens
when I change that user level
one? And all of a sudden I've
got admin access it's hilarious,
are like, how did you get that?
Well, I just changed it on the
way. That's Pyro. Is that Pyro?
No. If that was Pyro we'd really
mess with him. And it's not Pyro
so I'll leave him alone. It can
change cookies, variables and
HTML responses on the way back
to the server. This is a
client-based tool. You're not
going to actually change the
traffic going from anything but
your client to -- or your group
of clients that you've
configured to use this proxy to
the server. And so this is a
really good way to get in to
things, Tomcat and stuff like
that on the server side. Speaker
goodness, interrupting me, I'm
just giving you a hard time. It
has some very powerful SSL
options. SSL is only as good as
your user training. I can
present you a fake certificate
as long as you are trained to
click on, yeah, give me that
fake certificate, I've got all
your traffic. Our social
engineering efforts are vastly,
vastly, vastly successful
because people have gotten used
to, oh, that looks odd. But,
hey, I've got an okay button I
don't want to call IT I'm just
going to click okay. You know.
Google chrome has gotten better
that it's presenting a yellow
screen, full on yellow screen
now but it still gives you the
option to be like, yeah, I
understand what you're saying,
I'm going to go through. Used to
be red, the red screen really
freaked people out I think they
changed it to yellow because
they were getting too many
calls. Yeah. This is really
kinda what Malory is all about.
I'm the best Hacker ever I
downloaded this thing on the
Internet to do it and Malory
it's tough to use, we'll talk a
little bit about it. It's
really, really, really powerful,
though. More powerful than Burp
and much more -- much faster.
It's got very, very good SSL
options, it will just like Burp
it will auto generate
certificates but if you have the
right type of root certificate,
like a fake root certificate it
will generate these valid
certificates with the valid
information based on the
certificate it downloads from
the actual site that you're
attacking. So it will actually
fill everything in like it's a
real certificate from Google.
Like Google, HTTPS, and you'll
look at it and it's Google
incorporated. This is the date.
Just been self signed. You
actually examine it if you have
a user that is actually going to
examine the certificate and look
at it, it looks legit. And
you're like, oh, okay, Google
just made a mistake and put a
self signed certificate up there
I think I can do that. And I'll
let it through. And then you've
got all their traffic and it's
very, very good. Very
configurable and almost too
configurable. Linux and macro OS
are easiest way to get Malory
working. I actually have a
virtual machine that I keep just
for Malory. And it's because it
takes so many different
libraries, it has to be massaged
just in the right spot, it takes
a certain configuration of IP
tables in order to actually
work. So I just keep it all set
up on a VM that's ready to go, I
boot up the snapshot I start
Malory I'm ready to rock and
roll. I know that I can make
changes to the configurations I
need to go. It has a chrome plug
in that will allow to you look
at cookies and do injection of
-- change of injection of
cookies and things like that
it's not very effective it
actually kind of sucks. And it's
really difficult to understand.
It's a great tool, try it out,
go download it. I've got the
link somewhere on here and it's
actually in the presenter's
notes which are on the
conference CD. It can be very,
very, very picky. It really
doesn't like -- what the heck is
going on back there? That is
really, really annoying. He's
going to go take care of it for
me, I love you, man, thank you.
It can be really, really picky
about the environment it's set
up in and it can be really,
really, really tough again to
get working. And there's not a
lot of prebuilt tools for it
you're going to be building a
lot yourself if you can code in
python or C you're going to be
set up and ready to rock and
roll. But you're going to be
writing a lot of your own
plugins and a lot of your own
tools to get it working, there's
some real advantages to that. In
the fact that you can write your
own plugins and your own tools
and so as you do that, you'll
get your only personal suite of
tools and plug ins that you've
got around Malory that will do
some really, really cool stuff.
I don't share mine that's
probably really, really bad
thing. I should probably start
doing that but I am possessive
of my Malory stuff because I
don't want people to find out
about it, and be like oh, yeah,
got you. And it's not
maintained. Hasn't been
maintained since 2011. It hasn't
been a new release since then
and I think it's just due to
lack of popularity. So if more
people start using it we can
start to maintain it we can
actually make it a solid stable
and scalable tool. Disgusted cat
is questioning what he just saw.
Squid. The squid proxy is a
staple of Linux proxies, UNIX
proxies, really. It's used in
everyday use for a normal
caching proxy. In fact I used it
for a caching proxy for years at
home when my Internet connection
was slow, cause it sped things
up so drastically and it's
really, really, really good at
that. It's very good at doing
the caching stuff. But it can
also be turned in to a very
nefarious tool with IP tables
and PF. It can actually be
completely transparent to the
user, I can redirect the traffic
in to squid without having set
up proxies on the -- proxy
configuration on the browser so
I can sit there in the middle of
this traffic and be modifying it
all day long and you would never
know it. Man, who did this
PowerPoint anyway? It's good for
fast and static replacement, if
you want to replace images or
you want to put a header at the
top of a certain set of
webpages, captive portal type
stuff it's really good for that.
And lots of modules and lots of
support and it's very, very well
maintained. It's more or less a
commercial product and people
use it all over the place. And
so picking those products and
then being able to twist them to
your own uses is something that
is incredibly valuable. And it
is the best thing to prank your
friends with, it's readily
available at home, there's lots
of resources on the web to do
what you want to do with it and
it's a whole lot of fun. So I
was going to do an SSH monkey in
the middle here, I booted my VM
this morning and I got set up to
do it and as always, the demo
Gods are not in my favor today.
So -- >> I would just like to
say that those guys -- >> Oh,
wow. It's a flying Dick. We'll
set that there for the next
speaker and he'll wonder what
the hell happened in here. It
will be a lot of fun. But
instead I'm going to do some
time for questions and answers
here at the end because they
didn't give us any Q and A time
after our talks this year I
wanted to be able to answer you
guys' questions. So, I'm going
to take the ten minutes I set
aside for that and do that
instead. The other thing I want
to talk about is the all port
Internet. Redo. I like that
image it was so much fun. I
actually have something in my
bag that is -- batteries are
dead, and it's a redo of
something that was done back in
DEF CON 17. And these guys got
up and talked about what they
called the all port Internet.
And it was an access point you
could attach to, and it would
replace all of the images with
random porn. It's a great prank,
a great example of what you can
do with a proxy. Battery is dead
in my box, in my bag right now.
But it will be up -- I'll go
upstairs and charge it and it
will be up and I'll be walking
around Con, and you'll see an
access point that says, all P
Internet. It will throw you in a
captive portal and it will
actually ask you about your
preferences. [Laughter] And so,
I'm non-discriminatory I want to
make sure everybody gets -- not
my brand of porn but what they
want, and so it will ask you
about your preferences and it
will present you your
preferences of pornography and
every image will be pornography,
I'm sorry. But it also gives you
the option to join it or not and
I'm not going to force it on you
because I understand that that's
not for everybody too. No demo,
but it will be available. I
won't force it on you. You have
to ask for it. It's gender and
preference neutral. With that,
let's open the floor up for some
questions. Let's see what kind
of time I've got. I've got 20
minutes left or 25 minutes left.
So, yeah. I haven't played with
it in a long time to be honest.
It's one that I will put on my
list certainly to check out. You
got something that you've done
with it that you want to talk to
me about, come grab me a beer
afterwards we'll do that. Yeah.
There's actually a tool, if you
Google SSH man in the middle,
it's part of the DSniff suite it
will actually present a fake
public key to your client.
You'll get a message, a key
warning, the public key has
changed, I have mine configured
to where it won't connect to a
changed public key but most
default and limitations will ask
you if you want to replace it,
yes or no. Then it will sit in
the middle and decrypt the
traffic and record the traffic
for you as it's passing the
traffic to the next host.
Because you just changed the
public key to the one I
presented you to, it's
decrypting that traffic. It's a
whole lot of fun. It's not a
whole lot you can change with it
but you definitely get passwords
from it. Yeah. You'd be
surprised. Presenting somebody
with, are you sure you want to
do this type message, will
almost always get a yes answer.
I do it. You do it. Come on,
admit it. Do you answer yes to
that kind of stuff just because
it's convenient, yeah, I'll be
the first one to admit that I do
it, too. I've gotten caught by
my friends they are like, got
you! I'm like, oh, man. But,
yeah, everybody does it, it's
kind of human nature you get,
are you sure you want to do this
yes or no, and the answer is
almost always, yeah, I'm sure I
want to do this. Yeah. The best
proxy to use for SSL stripping?
What I would actually do is just
something that you're trying to
do quick. Use a tool called SSL
strip and Burp. And that's the
fastest way to do it if you're
just looking to strip the SSL,
and get the credentials. If you
want a little bit more
complicated version, Burp
actually does do some
certificate generation. You can
set it up to generate fake
certificates and send them back
to the client and get the
message. The other way is to use
Malory and actually generate
some really, really good
certificates. If you can get a
fake root certificate on to the
client that you're attacking,
then you won't have the issue of
the certificate as bad type
stuff. It's really, really
powerful and cool. But, yeah,
SSL strip and Burp are the first
go-to. Out in the cloud? It's
gonna be hard to do out in the
cloud if you want to prank your
friends get a little -- Yeah,
okay. My wife is telling me to
repeat the question for
everybody because they can't
hear you. [Laughter] She's
right. She's a teacher. She
knows this kind of stuff. He
wants to know what the best
service, cloud service to set
this stuff up in to prank the
cloud. Or the best way. I
actually do it at my gateway my
home gateway. I run PFsense
which gives me access to VSD and
PF you can do a lot of fun stuff
with that. There's a lot of plug
ins for it. If you're pranking
your cloud -- your friends out
here just carry a Wi-Fi
pineapple or something in your
backpack with a battery on it
and connect it to the DEF CON
network and away you go. That's
how the thing in my bag works.
It is, just a Wi-Fi pineapple
configured to connect to the DEF
CON network and funnels traffic
through there but it changes
everything coming back and forth
to it. No, I'm not. Yeah. VPNs.
See I'm not going to keep the
Def Coins to myself, that was a
really good question. The range
about VPNs, VPNs are actually
pretty well protected. Although
most people are switching to
like a SSL or TLS version of VPN
you can still use all your SSL
based tools for that and
actually get access to the
traffic. The problem being is
that when you've got a VPN going
you often times tunneling
traffic inside tunnels, at least
I do. You are going to have to
not only man in the middle my
SSL VPN but your also going to
have to man in the middle my SSH
and if I see one warning for VPN
and then another warning for SSH
at that point I'm going to be
like, okay, something's up.
Somebody didn't misconfigure
something or I'm not an a
network that is in the middle
already. I'm actually being
messed with. You definitely get
a Def Coin that was a good
question. Yeah. Yeah. So that's
actually a very, very good
question. What he's asking is,
when you get that yellow screen
from chrome and it's a site that
you've been to you know but
you're still getting that yellow
screen how do you verify that
it's okay. There's actually a
small link on that screen,
there's like, get me out of
here. Or then there's advanced
or everything is okay I know
what I'm doing. Are really the
kind of three options there.
Under the advanced tab you click
it, it will give you all the
certificate information. So what
I look for when I look at that
certificate is, is it really the
site that I'm going to. What's
the issue. Is it the company
that I'm expecting to work with.
Am I sending my data to some
place that I actually want to
send it to. Is the URL correct
-- what's that? Yeah, you'll see
the CA. The certificate
authority. And the certificate
authority I can put anything I
want in that field, it could be
kind of fun, I'm generating my
own root so I can be like, oh,
yeah. What's that? You really
shouldn't trust it. Just click,
get me out of here. That's the
best option. Then if it's Google
or something especially if it's
like a big name company or your
bank it's like, oh, it's been
self signed. Don't trust it. If
it says it's expired, don't
trust it. Chances are if it's a
big company and their SSL
certificate expires they're just
getting ready to put in a new
one anyway so wait 20 minutes
and go check again. Just on an
independent network, that's a
good one, too. This is for you.
Yeah. His question is have I
ever tied one of these tools
into like a beast attack or a
crime type attack or a
renegotiation type to decrypt
the SSL. Yes. It works very,
very, very well. The crime
attack, until they patched it
has been amazing. Yeah. Time to
wrap it up. One more question.
Yeah. Right, Right. It would
have. They have since fixed
that. But yes it would have. It
actually worked very, very well.
That's all I got for you guys.
[Applause]