>> I'm technical director, Matt
Hastings, one of our
consultants, both of us has done
response investigation at
Mandiant, for myself upwards of
five years,for matt upwards of
three years. Apologize if we
sound horse. I have been in
Vegas since Friday of last week
teaching and presenting. This is
last of my voice that's left.
Hopefully it will carry through
the hour. Thank you for coming.
We will talk about investigating
power shells attacks. Not blue
shell. If that's what you are
looking for in the wrong
presentation. The reason we did
this research ‑‑ we continuously
are seeing attackers adopt
interestingly novel approaches
to compromise and persist an
environment. We had seen an
increasing power shell in some
targeted attacks we investigate
starting about 18 months to two
years ago, very sporadic,
nothing consistent, nothing I
would call a trend at the time.
Earlier this year matt and I
worked the case, targeted
compromise of the fortunate 100
cases, spent four months
investigating in this
environment. This victim VPN
space have been compromised for
over three years. Attacking main
administrator during that time.
They had free access to the
majority the environment, but
the way they have conducted the
majority of their of command and
control when we were watching
was from their own originating
attacker system through the VPN,
targeting the victims work
station and server using a
combination of stuff we see
often, like schedule tasks and
stuff not seen quite so often,
power shell remoting and copying
and executing power shell
scripts on the target systems.
This turned out to be
forensically challenging. You
don't get to see what's on
attacker's system. When you
conduct attacks like power shell
remoting over the network, it's
difficult to see what was done
on the host on the end point
side if it's in memory. This
lead down the path of doing
research and that's why we're
here today. Of. We're not going
to go into a power shell 101,
way beyond the scope of this
talk. Suffice it to say power
shell is powerful. A command
line and scripting environment
in Windows takes the
functionality see in batch
scripts or other scripts Windows
supported and rachets it up
another level. You can interact
with Windows API and registry
and you can do cool stuff access
the entire dot net frame
workload and reflectively load
and execute DLL and memories.
This makes it useful for system
administrators and developers
for using it legitimate
purposes. It also means
attackers can use it and do neat
stuff witness. Developers have
built penetration testing and
attack frame that use power
shell. PowerSploit is probably
the best known written by a
number of guys, Bell, Joseph,
Mack who works with us at
Mandy FRI. PowerSploit does
recognizance, remote code
execution,its got a module
called invoke Mimikatz that will
take the mimikatz code and in
memory run it on a remote system
without ever touching disc and
do what mimikatz does and other
modules. Other tools like
MetaSploit which has power shell
based modules for over a year
now, veil power view, more and
more attack framework are
integrating power shells are
integrating power shell into
their tool kit. Targeted
attackers learning how to use
it, attack and testing tools
using it. Mass malware use power
shell. The first power shell
mass malware was shortly after
the creation in 2006 called
power worm. A proof of concept
didn't do much but now mass
malware use power shell. Trend
lab has reported a couple
examples in the last 12 month. A
classic ransom where sample that
encrypted all your file and
demanded payment. The bottom
line attackers of all
disciplines are learning how to
use this stuff. Instead of
coming up with an investigation
methodology specific to one
attack frame work or cool or
malware, we took the lowest
common denominator. What is the
fundamental way to interact with
a system and forensic impact
does that have? The three
scenario exercise executing a
power shell local host, using
power shell remoting feature
which using a protocol WinRM,
Windows remote management
interact with a remote host and
persistent power shell, taking
power shell code and configuring
system to automatically execute
upon log in or boot time. Each
scenario you run test case what
impact on registry on file
system event logs, memory and
monitoring the memory, network
traffic. A few assumptions, the
fist that we make is that the
attacker has local or domain
administrator access to the
target system. You may be
thinking, isn't that cheating,
what we're dealing with, when we
look at this is post compromise
scenarios. I don't care about
the initial exploit, I concern
has a foothold in the
environment and achieving
mission, moving host to host,
doing recognizance, stealing
data and whatever else brought
them to that environment in the
first place. Almost every
Windows environment the attacker
gains administrative permission
quickly. You can find the other
stages without getting
compromised and kicked out.
That's the context we will be
looking at all these
environments. A quick version
reference, there's a lot of
different versions of power
shell. I think 4.0 is current,
5.0 is in the work. in most
Enterprise environment, you will
see 2.0 because thats whats been
installed by default in Windows
2007 and viSta late and Server
2008R2. Windows 8 power shell 3
by default, Windows 8.1 includes
4, but we dont see corporate
environments adopting either of
those platforms for quite some
time. The down side is cool
things in power shell 3 that
myself and Matt will talk about
later, won't be available by
default and therefore won't be
installed in most environments.
You have to apply an optional up
date in the Windows management
frame work to gain access to
later versions of power shell
and Windows version of Windows.
Let's begin by talking about
memory analysis. In some ways
this is the worst case scenario.
An attacker interact with
targeted host, use power shell
remoting. Worse case scenario
because it's volatile, the
session end, come back to system
in minute, hours days, and based
on a lot of factors we want to
understand what would be left
behind assuming the system had
not been shut down or rebooted
and how long could you find and
recover that and how much could
you get out of memory. To
understand this, we need to
understand the process hierarchy
that power remote using. What
happens myself as client
initiates power shell remoting
on target systems memory? The
way it work lets say i use the
power shell command like the
invoke command to run evil .exe
and presumably evil.exe is
already on target system.
svchost.exe service hosting
process that is running the
decom launch service an
instantiates an instance of
wsmprovhost.exe and then that
instance of wsmprovhost in
turns, executes evil.exe so
evil.exe parent process will be
wsmprovhost and svchost will be
that wsmprovhost's parent
process host. In contrast, If I
use power shell remoting to
execute power shell native
command, in other words, just
command or code that is solely
resonant within power shell
language based, what happens is
wsmprovhost spins up again. You
don't see a child process power
shell dot exe spawned. The power
shell code runs in context of
wsmprovhost. You don't see a
child process when you do
remoting like this. So what's in
memory? If you go to memory and
you dump memory right when a
power shell session, remoting
session occurring on victim
host, you can reconstruct almost
complete command from the
wsmprovhost memory space. The
problem with that is it
terminates at the end of the
session. Meaning if I do one
power shell remoting command,
the moment the command complete,
that wsmprovhost terminates, all
the cool evidence is totally
gone. From a practical
standpoint as an analyst or
investigator you will almost
never get to the system in time
to recover that process memory.
That kind of brought us back to
the drawing board to see where
else in memory does this stuff
hang out? What we found is that
another instance of the service
hosting process running the
Windows remote managing service,
broker power shell remoting,
contains remnants of the soap
objects that power shell input
and output martial-led into when
you do remoting. This may
persist after the end of a
remoting session maybe up to
reboot. We found bits and pieces
of the same data persist in the
kernel and the page file. We
suspect that that is probably
artifacts of page, tools and
memory and therefore not
something you can reliably
expect to always find. We will
not read this in detail. We put
together a table here of source
of evidence in memory and how
long you can find stuff after
the fact on the system. Your
best bet is the winRM instance
of Svchost. If you dump memory,
assuming that the attacker is
the only one thats interacting
the system through remoting, and
assuming that the system hasn't
rebooted, you can recover input
and output from power shell
sessions. It look like this. I
apologize if the colors are hard
to read. Here's an example of us
running through remoting of
power shell command that does
echo test string PS session
through output file. Amidst this
giant blob of ugly xml, you can
see an RSB command tag and the
full command we submitted in the
command line. We were able to
recover that from memory many,
many hours after that already
had executed. A more interesting
example used the power sploit
invoke mimikatz madule again for
remoting. We used the technique
where you download through power
shell the script over the
Internet, and then dynamically
execute it. So nothing touches
this memory on the victim
system. Again, we can see in the
inset a complete command line of
everything executed to pull and
run the invoke mimikatz Power
sploit module. It's possible to
use this. Yes, this is painful.
This is kind of like worst‑case
scenario. You can recover
evidence. Will you have to work
for it. The biggest problem is
since we're looking at fragments
of the soap and the power shell
remoting protocol, xml objects
used when do remoting, not like
well structured objects retained
in memory because being actively
used. It's portion of memory no
longer actively allocated. The
bottom line you can do string
searches. You can find RSP
command,RSP command line the
strings and hone in on the
commands. You will have to sift
through a lot of garbage. In
summary, timing is kind of
anything, everything rather,
that's always the case with
memory analysis but especially
with this because there is no
proper place at which in memory
all of power shell history is
retained forever. It has to be
constructed from what's left
behind in the Windows R M memory
space. Taken then things like
system up time and memory
utilization can impact how
likely you are to recover these
types of art facts. I will turn
to Matt? >> You look at similar
scenario Ryan talked about
attacker interacting with
system, and we also looked at
logs in power shell locally.
Each scenario try to answer
three questions. Which event log
specifically are activity? This
will be event log that are
directly writing power shell
activity. What you will see in
the next slide is event logs
that power shell writes to
directly. It doesn't necessarily
cover the event logs that may
contain data. For example in the
remoting example, an attacker
logs in, you will expect to see
a log in. That wasn't covered in
research. As looking for each
resource, logging detail,
ideally get full command history
of everything executed on the
system. What will we see?
Specifically some of the
distance between power shell 2
and 3. So we identify five
specific logs that may contain
power shell commands or may
contain some relevant
information related to power
shell execution. The next two
slides will walk through what
happens local versus remote
scenario. Starting with the
power shell event log itself, we
identified two event ids for
104, three contained some bit of
relevant information. Not ideal
if you are looking to fully find
out what was executed. but in
the EID 400 seeing the engine
state changes from none to say
available, indicating that power
shell started. Looking at
generated time of event, power
shell was run on the system at
this time. then in EID 403, done
running. You can two times and
command between X and Y. The
host name consult host indicates
a local session versus a remote.
We will show you what a remote
session looks like in a
following slide. A power shell
operational event log and power
shell 2.0 doesn't contain any
information. We did find one
that contained the same
information that power shell
starting up. You can get that
from the same event he spoke
about previously. Power shell
3.0 and greater, it write for
error messages. A script failed
to run, we get the full path of
the script. In a remoting
session session, if looking at
remote host, you can get the
host name and I T address of the
system attempt together be
accessed. For power shell
analytic logging, those not
familiar, analytic logging is
disabled by default. Debugging
purposes and not for long‑term
retention. We did enable it and
find that power shell contain
relevant information. You can
see here in the 79, 37, the test
dot PS 1 scrypt was run. We can
see a power shell script run.
You can run a native within the
same event I D and finally, a
dropper I D. Run that from the
power shell console, that will
be recorded here as well. What
you don't get from here is any
command or argument, you kind of
get like half way there and then
you want to know how were these
configured and there's better
ways to record this information.
An analytical logging in this
case is probably not worth it.
Moving on to remoting section
here back to the power shell
log, EID6 the accessing system,
we can see that the WS man
session is starting. Looking at
this, you can say from the
system of remote session
starting connecting to another
host. And those not familiar, W
Sman manager protocol used by
win R M which is what power
shell uses for remoting. On the
access system, we have E I D 400
and 403, in this case we see the
serve remote host as a host
name, which indicates that this
is a remote session versus a
local session. In the remoting
situation you are using the
winRN service, specifically here
in EID 169 you can identify who
the user that logged into the
system was, if you don't have
logs going back that far. The
security protocol that was use
Ford authentication. Similar to
the power shell log, the time
frame of remoting activity, the
client request for the shell and
the delete shell. That appears
in multiple event logs. Now
going back to the power shell
analytic log. As far as 2.0 is
concerned, which Brian
mentioned, it is probably
prevalent. I got to pause.
Yesterday a mispronounced
prevalent Back on track. In the
analytic, way of capturing
command execution and responses.
Now to problem is, and well will
get to this. The actual content
written in hex encoded format.
Looking at the log itself
doesn't give any information.
What you will find is that every
piece of information, and
everything that is sent back and
forth between the two host will
record it. The initial protocol
is recorded in the log hex
producing format. You have to
dig through it if you want to
find what was run. Here is an
example of the event log. Here
an object was received on
company man, again, it's in a
hexing encoding format. You
can't tell what happened. If we
decode it, you can see here that
the lines here. You can see it.
The command get char item in the
script, no, not, you can see the
argument pass. You can see ‑‑
Looking at the analytic log now
with a response that is sent
back, a single response that's
sent back to the request in the
system. In power shell we run a
built‑in command, everything
that comes back is in the form
of an object. Each object
returned from this command is
written as a single event in the
event log. If you run this get
trial, it will create enough in
the event log to mass the number
of items within the C directory.
It generates a ton of events and
you have to parse through
individually decode and map back
to what was run and what was
responded. In 2.0, it's not
practical to do this. There are
some other options. The first
one is some of the profiles that
power shell has. Power shell has
multiple profile options where
you can configure code to be run
at any time that power shell
locally starts up. Here an
example of global profile. You
can start record transcript
command input and output. You
can write out to an event log
format if you prefer. We have
seen some companies put together
custom codes overrides the
default prompt so anything typed
in spit out to a file. Some of
the limitations here are like I
mention, this is on for power
shell execution. It doesn't do
anything over remoting. Also,
you can launch power shell by
saying no profile flag, so none
of this codes are run. Again,
it's a solution not the best
answer, but it is something that
can help you out. Also, if you
are using app blocker, it has an
option for enforcing scripting
rules. You can see here, okay, a
script was attempted to run at
this time. Here's the path to
it. Even if not enforcing, it's
another option if you are
running app blocker. Moving out
of power shell 3.0, the best
option we found is module
logging. What it allows is to
get that clear text specific
command input and output in
clear text for anything being
run through the shell. Both
locally and remotely. We will
show you in further slides. Here
we ran a more complex command in
the past. We said get trial item
of C attempt directory
recursively only filter back
files with the .text extension
and do a basically a select
screen in power shell for the
same pass word. The top item
here, you see we captured the
command sent to the system and
have all the arguments being
parsed out and available in a
clear format and at the bottom
you see the response or see the
file that it hit on and the line
where it found the file, found
the hit. Now, this can be
slightly problematic when you
run a script. Each line and
script, each command in the
script will generate own power
shell script. We ran the invoke
mimikatz module in power shell
and doing over 1200 events in
the event log. A large number.
We can't parse through. When we
got to the actual response, we
found it written in clear text
mimikatz output in the event
log. so you can see all the
password hashes here clearly
written in the event log. >> For
this last bit were gonna focus
on, we wanted to talk about the
ways in which power shell code
configured to automatically run
in the system. Attackers like
persistence, if you are look
doing something like back door
or key stroke or car data track,
or track recording, anything
continuously execute on a system
and survive reboot and shutdown,
you need to find persistence
mechanism. This is understood.
There's numerous techniques that
Windows provide well‑documented
from registry, auto start point,
window services, thing like
recurring schedule tasks, use of
the start‑up folder, if you
think about it, persisting power
source, making power dot exe run
with argument of the script. All
of these techniques very well
understood. We will not spend a
lot of time talking about them
because folks have done plenty
of research on that in the past.
What we will spend time on is
per these tense via window
management. One of the reasons
nor that is the power sploit
tool kit includes this as one of
the mechanism that you can use
to persist the code of your
choice. We thought that made it
a target. We seen a packers use
W M I persist, not necessarily
power shell but other things
like C script or J script, the
other built in scripting
component in Windows that
similarly running native and
code. W M I is friendly for that
scenario. To understand that, we
need to step back and explain
how W M I works. This is a big
mess. I will give you a high
level. It's this inventing
infrastructure. It has this
notion of event filter,
consumers and binding between
the two. An event filter is a
query continuously run against
the state of the system. When
it's satisfied, it fires the
consumers that bounds ‑‑ and the
consumer runs something. All of
these things can be set with
power shell using set wmi
instance command. And also as
we'll show you later enumerated
power shell. Event filter, as I
said is the thing that causes
the consumer to trigger. Written
in Wql. Has a simple example. We
have an example of wql that will
fire when the system up time
between 240 and 325 seconds;
basically, a roundabout way of
saying, fire upon startup. The
next one is an example where
instead of relative time, it
says at 12:00 exactly fire. So
that will satisfy the filter.
Two different ways to basically
achieve the same thing,
continuously run something on an
agreed upon interval. The
consumer is what runs when the
filter is satisfied. In this
example we're going to execute
power shell. The trick is
execute power shell to load
what? Where does the evil code
come from? You have a few
options here. The thing that
power sploit does by default is
it puts the code in system wide
or user profile. As Matt
mentioned earlier, load
automatically when power shell
executes. If I create a system
runs power shell without any
options, it loads the profile.
By virtue, it loads the
malicious code. Simple technique
and works nicely. The other
thing is add your malicious
power shell code to argument
supplying to power shell exe and
build into the consumer's
command line. In that case only
limited by the command line
length limit Windows enforces
something like 8,000 characters.
That isn't too bad of a
constraint. The example shows
you can run compressed power
shell code and decompress and
execute on the fly. You can fit
8,000 characters. The easy
solution to find malicious wmi
filter and consumers that run
this is through the use of power
shell. The get wmi company man
lets you filter consumer and
binding between the two. We do
investigation in a lot of large
environments. We pulled 50,000,
100,000 environments to get an
idea of what is and what is not.
What we have seen is that it is
not common to have event
consumers that execute power
shell. That doesn't mean in your
environment it may not be
legitimately used for
administrative purposes. The
bottom line is base line
environment easily and determine
what consumers and filters and
legitimate and look for
anomalies. The other thing you
can do is look at the file
system at the host which this
occurred. This is difficult
because wmi is stored in the
wbem repository. This directory
C Windows system 32 wbem
repository. The files that keep
all of the wmi objects in event
filters and consumers, mainly
objects.data is the key file. It
is this undocumented proprietary
format no documents whatsoever.
Some engineers looked at
briefly. A big ball of hurt.
They don't want to get into. The
bottom line is if you had a dead
disc image from a host, there's
no good way to host it purchase.
You can do strings against it
which can kind of good. Strings
will give you the event filter
and consumer names. If your
attacker was foolish enough to
create my bad ass event filter,
you would be able to find in
object data. You get the command
line. If you discover on a host
this technique is in use, the
attacker is referencing power
shell with arguments, you can
see that in strings in
objects.data. If you are looking
at things I'm examining a
system, did these files get
modified in the time frame
attack activity? It will not
work. Windows is up dated
constantly. They change all the
time. Finally, you should
definitely review all the
profile .ps1 file on a system
that you suspect has been hit.
In most environment, you will
have an empty file. So quick and
easy to check the profile. You
might as well look at it.
Anything in the profile will
automatically execute unless you
supply the no profile argument
to the power shell command line.
Why not check it for malicious
code? Finally, the registry,
this was kind of disappointing,
like many thing in Windows
creating a wmi filter, a
consumer lead to some sort of
change for registry forensically
examined. That was in this case.
The only exception was depending
on the filter you used to create
the condition to fire consumer,
registry team might be created
to a provider that satisfied
that query. The long and short
is the example power sploit uses
run this on this exact hour and
minute, it was like 12:00, in
the example. Creating that
filter registers this key for
win 32 clock provider, by
default this does not exist in
Windows environment. You have to
create a wmi filter that uses
that as its provider. From all
the enterprise scale
investigations done, I have not
seen this key except when an
attacker is using this
technique. Of course there's a
hundred million ways you can
create wmi filters that don't
use that specific provider. This
isn't meant to be comprehensive.
It was an interesting part of
the fact of default behavior of
PowerSploit itself. Other
sources of evidence, if you use
the system internal tools, which
are fantastic, auto runs was
updated a month or two ago.
Version 1d will enumerate and
displays all wmi filters and
consumers in an easy to read
format. I suggest checking that
out. In memory, we didn't spend
a terrible amount of time
examining this. That was mainly
because the memory space of the
wmi relevant processes are
noisy. We didn't find any
reliable way to recover evidence
after the fact. Event logs do
have some wmi, so you can enable
wmi trace logging. If an
attacking register a malicious
wmi, it would generate an event.
Windows does this stuff behind
the scene. The one event will be
buried amongst thousand events
during system up times and roll
off the log quickly. >> Just to
wrap up. We didn't cover every
source available. We have
released a white paper now
public, in a draft format. The
final version out next week. It
has more detail and some of our
research and findings. A few
other places if you look, if all
the other ones we have gone
through turned up nothing,
looking at Windows work station
and a power shell pretext file
created, that can contain
information on either a power
shell scriptures line or power
shell certain files of interest
to you. Now only caveat only for
local execution of power shell.
No remoting here. Also, there's
a single registry that I
wouldn't say relevant, the
execution policy setting. By
default power shell doesn't let
you execute unassigned scripts
this is just to prevent people
from double clicking bad
scripts. Everything else in
power shell, you can bypass
command line with the execution
bypass flag. One situation, the
attacker modified registry key
to allow unsigned scripts rather
than bypassing on the command
line. I don't know if tired of
doing it, they did modify this
key. Network traffic analysis,
since power shell using the win
rm service, looking at the winrm
port so port 5985 and 5986 use
http and https respectively. The
pay load for power shell is
encrypted regardless if its
http. If you are using http, you
can pick up header information
power shell version. In that
case, mentioned previously, the
attacker is using a different
version of power shell than what
they use natively in the
environment. They actually wrote
some ‑‑ did some network
monitoring power shell based on
the version in the headers. And
then looking for anomalies.
Really, lessons learned and
recommend upgrade module logging
possible. Move to a power shell
a version 3 or later and
implementing module is the best
solution. Beyond that and
looking at high level, base line
legitimate powershell usage
usage can be key in identifying
anonymous and malicious
powershell usage. What is
execution policy setting and
does it change? If so, why? How
do you name the power shell
experiment and where do you put
them and looking for other
directories that may not match?
Do you use remoting? Is remoting
enabled by default or only on
certain system and base lining
that usage? What users use it
and from? Is it only admin or
serve admins and work from
similar sub net and base lining
and saying this is what good
power shell looks like in my
environment and looking for
anomalies through the method we
described earlier. >> The bottom
line exception of module loggng,
no perfect solution. There's a
lot of attackers continue to do
it. Taking that step in advance
before an incident understand
how being used can save a lot of
leg work in the future when you
may have to respond. The thing
we find is during your
investigative process, power
shell isn't the lead. It's some
other artifact activity on the
system. As doing forensic and
time line analysis and see these
thing we presented today, you
may get indication that attacker
was using power shell. If you
didn't node to look in these
places and memory, you might
completely miss that's part of
their tool kit and therefore
they might be able to
successfully use it without
being detective in post
compromise. We want to
acknowledge Matt, co author of
powersploit, done a lot of cool
work on attack research with
power shell. As has Joseph,
Chris Campbell, Microsoft has
reached out. I want to thank Lee
Holmes. The folks at Microsoft
are aware of folks using it.
It's under the context of
attacker who is already in the
administrator on system. All
bets are off from security
standpoint. They are working to
make it more audit friendly and
easy to monitor. There will be
some cool stuff coming down the
pike make it easier for those
running in their environment. I
think good thing will come out.
Thank you for your time and
attendance here. If you have any
questions, it looks like we have
a couple of minutes. Step up to
the microphone. We will answer
them. You want to talk to us
directly, catch us after the
talk or email us or hit us up on
Twitter. At this point I will
stop for any questions. Sure.
Could you go up to the mic
please so it gets caught in the
recording. We will repeat it. >>
AUDIENCE MEMBER: [Indistinct
speech] >> The question
recommended powershell 3, not up
date to 4? Not that I know . You
can just as well update to 4.
They don't make it automatic.
There were a couple of things
that were deprecated between 2
and 3 ,they're exceptionally
minor, for the small pool of
people using power shell for
exchange event management, you
may not want to break things. I
would check whether the thing
you are using in 2.0 not broken.
2 to 3 was the major change.
Does that answer your question?
ANNOUNCER: Yes. >> Any other
questions? Once again, if you
want to talk to us directly, we
will be here. You can reach out
to us via email. You guys were
great. Appreciate you having us
here. (Applause)  [End of
session]  "This text is being
provided in a rough draft
format. Communication Access
Realtime Translation (CART) is
provided in order to facilitate
communication accessibility and
may not be a totally verbatim
record of the class." PAGE PAGE