hello everyone i will try to keep it
interesting since you just came back
from lunch
so talking about nation state actors uh
first some definitions when i'm talking
about nation states i'm talking about
intelligence agencies spy agencies
all the countries have them and in this
talk i'm not going to separate them it's
military and the civilians since it's
going to be more abstract around how
they operate
typically national states
are there to do the dirty work for
governments and military what i mean by
this one is that
there are certain things that
there are two big components of what
they're doing the first one is
collecting information to answer
questions
the way they do that is typically using
means that are illegal outside their
country
on the other hand in many countries not
in all of the countries they are also
doing
operations
for example in the us they call
covert action in russia they call it the
active measures in some european
countries they call it the special
intelligence operations
there are main names in summary it is
not only understanding
the threats but changing
the outcome for instance it could be
influencing elections
it could be
participating in some paramilitary
operations supporting certain insurgent
groups it could be bribing it could be
all sorts of activities even going as
far to assassinations or
yeah like
actual genetic operations so for
instance where cyber fits into all of
that
how many here are uh familiar with the
jamal castro djs from 2018
okay
a few people so for people that are not
familiar in 2018
that person a journalist was
assassinated in 30 and that was later
attributed to the saudi intelligence and
you would say okay what this has to do
with this talk well later it was
discovered that both his mobile phone
and his family's mobile phones were
compromised and we don't know if that
was part of the operation but
we can assume that maybe it helped plan
this operation
okay so
having given this general introduction
of who
of what i'm going to be talking about so
why am i qualified to talk about this
that's a good question because i have
never worked in any intelligence agency
and that's probably also the reason why
i can talk about these things like i
never had any clearance which means yeah
i'm just talking about open source
information here
and so i have been working information
security for some time i started from
the offensive security vulnerability
research and exploit development and
then i switched to the bluetooth side so
i know that some of the work that i
initially did ended up being used by
nation states
but yeah a leader switched sides
so some of you might know me from a blog
that i have been running for more than a
decade and the initial it was most again
about exploit development and then more
around uh
intelligence topics cyber espionage and
so on i have also talked about lots of
different topics in the last few years
on cyber experience some more technical
some less technical like this talk is
not going to be very very technical
and also for the last couple of years i
started a youtube channel called the spy
collection where i'm sharing some of the
things i have acquired over the years of
researching that area some are physical
some are digital
and i also started this year a
newsletter which called spy news and
here is the interesting part with this
one
every week there are multiple stories
about espionage around the world
but what we see it is only two kinds of
stories either stories that are
intentionally out there for instance an
agent might want to pass a message so
they are control leading that
information
or things that went wrong so an
operation that didn't work as planned
now all of us work in different areas
and probably all of you understand that
when you do your work you are going to
make mistakes at some point and this is
probably what gets in the news of
the spy news let's say
but on the other hand also probably all
of us know that when you work i don't
like probably 90 95 of your time you do
your job right nothing goes wrong so
that means what we see is not even the
tip of the iceberg it's like probably
the
the snow that is getting blown on the
tip of the iceberg
this is what we see when we are reading
about espionage stories still it's
pretty interesting but keep that in mind
that what we see is a very tiny portion
of what's happening out there
and you see that emerging cyber
and espionage since like in the case of
djs and other cases i'm going to be
talking about
there is a very strong relation like for
nation states what they care about is
the outcome
and in many cases we have to combine
multiple disciplines to get to that
outcome so
we have to be aware of both worlds it is
not just
cyber espionage
now as you can imagine probably you saw
in the previous slide that working at
booting.com so
very unrelated topics this is my
personal research it has nothing to do
with my employers so
just be aware you have it's all personal
stuff and i will also not accept
questions for my employer since i'm not
presenting anything related to
booking.com here
okay so starting the first i will start
with the assumptions that i had for
making this presentation then i will go
to the private sector since especially
the last few years we hear like
since i'm doing the spy news i know
every other week we have some news about
nsf group international group is not the
only company that's doing that and it's
not the only company that's offering
services
that are related to nation states
once we cover the private sector i'm
going to go to the main area with the
public sector
and then some key takeaways so the aim
of this presentation is mostly to give
everyone food for thought and raise a
little bit the awareness of what's
happening that yeah it's not only
fishing that we hear every day i'm not
saying fishing is not happening i'm just
saying there are other things that
happen
that
we kind of ignore
so on the assumptions the first one is
that uh
all of the big apts that they
historically we have been very impressed
on how they did their operations
probably they never stopped doing
operations we just
stopped seeing those operations
the second one is that the not all
nation states are made equal and you can
probably imagine that when you have
organizations like a
russian gru
thousands of people a lot of resources
then you have other countries like very
small countries but maybe the whole
population is like two three million
apparently they will not have the same
capabilities and it will also not have
the same resources then we have agencies
like for example in the us that they are
having a global focus they want to know
what's happening all over the world well
you have other agents another place that
they only care about the regional space
so not all nation states are made equal
both on resourcing and capabilities
vary a lot
then what i'm assuming that you are all
here and also the important in the live
stream
because you are interested in this kind
of topic that you understand facing it
does happen it's
really high volume but there are other
things that might be happening out there
and you might want to be protected
against them especially if your threat
model involves protecting against nation
state
level threat actors
and lastly
we have some anecdotal evidence of this
one that nation states learn from their
mistakes but it's really hard to say
that conclusively for all of the nation
state actors for instance in the vault
seven in uh wikileaks
there is a wiki page that it was from
the cia and then there there is even a
full page when kaspersky managed to
attribute a lot of their activity to the
acquisition group where they are doing a
retrospective and they are looking to
okay what could we fix to avoid those
mistakes in the future we should change
this this and that it's a pretty
interesting read to go through that but
again that is one instance
most likely this is what happened in
other agencies as well
and we can also see that a little bit
from the development of the implants
that it changed over time and the evolve
so
most likely when we release some
research to the world that research is
going to be received also from those
nation state actors and they will take
steps to make sure
that they are going to fix those issues
in the future
okay so moving to the private sector
the main three questions so that again
this mostly make sure we all speak the
same language of what we mean when we
say that
why do they exist
what are they targeting and how big of a
market is it
the first one is pretty simple
considering the assumption they exist
because there is a need for that not all
of the countries have the capacity to
build all of these things of their own
not all of them have the knowledge and
experience to develop those things so
they have to rely on somebody else and
this is why the private sector provides
almost anything you can imagine to
intelligence agencies
however
here for the sake of presentation i have
to
let's say limit it down and put in some
package
i know this is not conclusive but i try
to put that in three areas and i'm going
to cover them the first is
infrastructure level signals intelligent
solutions
that are covering things like
telecommunication providers isps and so
on
then specialized seeking services let's
say vulnerability research reverse
engineering and so on
and lastly
tooling to be able to provide small
groups of people so we're talking about
either individuals so either maybe
dozens of hundreds of people maybe a
couple of thousands but not anything
beyond that
there are way way more things i'm very
happy to discuss them afterwards
yeah i even have an inventory in my blog
with lots of these companies that are
offering the offensive cyber
capabilities i think it's like 140 that
they have so far so it is not just an
iso group
and yeah that leads us also to how big
of a market is it
it's a multi-billion
dollar industry and the reason is this
and they are offering anything you can
imagine from
telecommunication level solutions all
the way to zero days then very tailored
solutions for their customers
most of the information we have is from
leaked contracts that leak over time for
instance uh it was i think last month
that we had a contract click from intel
alexa that was an 8 million contract
last the month before that we had one
from the thai cover government a
contract agenda costly so from time time
we get to see
how how much those solutions cost so we
can make an estimate i can guarantee you
you will never see anything that is
below a million
like i have never seen any contract that
is cheaper than that
and the interesting part is that here is
a very tiny subset as i mentioned there
are hundreds of companies like that you
might recognize some of them so i don't
want to blame any of them they're
literally offering a service i'm not
saying anything against those companies
i'm just saying it's a huge market those
are some of the bigger names out there
and it is heavily based on trust and
professional relationships
here is an interesting exercise if you
want to do that pick any of the big
companies around this space you can even
go to my blog 140 of them
and then see the people that work there
just go do some oh center them you will
see people that are marketing on sales
and so on most of them
come from the government sector and then
they switch to the private sector
and this is cheap because a lot of them
are heavily based on having these
translations like you couldn't imagine
intelligence agencies going in the wild
and luckily asking hey i want to buy a
zero they just reach out to me they need
to have those relationships
and of course there are some conferences
that are closed for this kind of
audience that the intelligence agents
and these companies are going together
and they are presenting the tools but
most of the time it is
heavily based on professional
relationships and trust
also in some countries
they are not even allowed to have an
online presence if you want to sell the
service to a government agency you are
not allowed to have a website like a
domain nothing at all you you should not
exist on the web
that probably also gives you an idea
what we see again is a very tiny portion
of everything that's out there on these
companies
okay so now probably will unders have
the same understanding of what i mean
when i say private sector in this
context
so let's go a little bit on the
infrastructure level which i would say
is the most innocent because you can
find tons of information about this for
what i'm going to cover here but still
it's not very well covered topic that's
the ali system the lawful interception
systems
so
every country that they have research
has these things installing their
telecommunication providers of course
including this country but
like any country that i i have a
research center that is a lot of them
like more than 20 30 countries
how they work is pretty simple they
demand by law the telecommunication
providers to install them in their
networks they are tapping on the network
traffic and then through a legal process
that is different per country they are
allowed to
issue an li request which means for that
person we want to intercept everything
that they are doing
and here is something that is not widely
communicated this is not
intercepting only voice which is what
you'd assume like okay phone calls like
wiretapping traditionally it's
intercepting anything that this
telecommunication
provider has access to including data
including metadata including
in some cases they have abilities to
track sessions so you can build sessions
from so you have have easier experience
browsing the collect information
um
they all support next-generation
networks nowadays so
many different capabilities and that
exists everywhere
you could say okay i trust my government
i will never abuse this technology maybe
it depends
um but then there are other versions of
this one so there are many different
models out there and the one that you
might hear if you start looking to that
is the russian version of it called
storm system for operative for operative
investigative activities
technical speaking is
almost identical to what we call in the
west lawful interception there are
really minor differences and there are a
few others as well but i mentioned just
those two because we start looking to
those two
you will get into a rabbit hole and
you'll find a lot of information
especially actually the russian
initially was built for the fsb the
federal security service in russia so
that they can use it for investigations
but then they started also the companies
that build it also selling it outside to
other company other countries that are
let's say
friendly to russia
then we have another part of the private
sector that it is not so
innocent let's say
i use this example because it is easy to
find information about it but there are
many similar products out there
it is from finfisher a product that they
call thin isp
and again a government can install it to
telecommunication providers and what it
does is similar to the lawful
interception in terms of wiretapping the
traffic but it's online and can also
inject traffic so it can do many
individual attacks and you might be
asking yourself why would someone do
that well because this way you can
compromise systems almost transparently
you can
inject exploits in a session of a person
and they will never even know that this
happened
again from country to country it heavily
depends on how those are used or abused
there are entire legal frameworks around
those but as with any law
yeah and the intelligence agencies that
operate in this really gray area
there are countries that are pretty
strict on how they operate them and
countries that are a little bit more
relaxed
on how they use them
so some considerations for
those systems the infrastructure level
seeking solutions
first of all we all think that hey i
fully trust my government they will
never do anything bad with those things
it doesn't matter that they have them
installed
well okay but what happens when you
travel somewhere else what happens when
you talk to someone in another country
or your traffic their communication goes
there what happens if your internet for
whatever reason is routed through
another country
it is not only your country you have to
be careful of there are other players in
this
and the another area is that
you now imagine you are a nation state
actor you're in a signals intelligence
agency
it could be really awesome having access
to a foreign country's lawful
interception system
pretty cool right you would have like
all your interception already in place
you just have to enable and start spying
on people
and the last
actually on this one yeah
it did happen in 2004 the us did exactly
that in vodafone in greece
and
the vodafone at that point was using a
system from erickson for lawful
interception and the nsa had developed a
rootkit using the language of that
system that was called plex
and you like i just the question is how
they managed to install it well here's
where we go back to the combination they
recruited a network engineer working in
vodafone the most uh let's say sad part
of the story is that when this leaked
and became a scandal and that happened
because the olympic games were happening
in general when you have international
events like a spy magnet you have lots
of people going there and of course by
agencies have an excellent opportunity
to reach all of those people at once
but the sad part of this story is that
that
engineer was
found
he committed suicide at least this was
the initial
assessment when this scandal became
public but later on i think it was 2017
or 18 the court decided that was a
murder
so again it is this where you see the
cyber meeting
the real world
okay but that is like almost 20 years
ago an isolated incident we could say
but when snowden did his leaks
we found this lideck this is from the
nsa and says exploiting foreign lawful
intercept round table
you can check out the slide deck if you
want it's a public on the internet i
think the intercept linked it
and
in there it has like a whole inventory
of like 10 12 countries that the nsa was
doing exactly the same thing so it
wasn't just greece
another thing to remember even if your
country doesn't abuse
the systems they have maybe some other
countries abusing them for them
and the last part i mentioned about the
thin isp or similar products that can
many in the middle and inject traffic
now
you might say okay yeah they cannot
inject anything like we have https we
have a like a perfect trust a perfect
secrecy and everything is working nicely
based on most statistics only 89 percent
of the internet traffic is https and now
think for yourself like in the last
couple of months didn't you have that
time that you
browsing something or you did it up in a
not secure site
now if you were part in the target list
that's the only time that was needed
they could inject in that http response
and exploit it and boom they have access
to your device that's it
and um
actually from snowden's click we even
know that they were building automation
around this thing so they didn't they
were not doing these things manually
they would just have the target list and
the moment they were able to
get some unencrypted connection of
course it was far easier back then they
were immediately injecting the exploit
and it was getting back to the system to
feed all of the data back to the nsa so
it wasn't like a human doing that was
full automated
so okay that was pretty saddening
if opponent part so what can we do
first of all let's accept that we all
operate in very hostile networks
the second part is encrypt everything
and not just enable encryption but
research what are you doing like doesn't
make sense for what you're trying to
encrypt
and
yeah don't rely on the defaults and the
last part if you if you have any
researchers here that are going to look
into that look at the network-based
attacks like make the middle tampering
with network packets can you find any
injections
there are lots of areas that you can
look into that level like the network
level of
exploitation then we have the more
straightforward part of the private
sector that the offering service is like
okay
can't you find a zero day in the target
platform can you build as an exploit for
this vulnerability that we have
or we got this to exploit but we don't
know how to make them work in a nice
production already exploit chain
or
we have this a very obscure device that
we try to hack because of x
adversary of ours is using can you help
us reverse engineer it and see how it
works or we managed to capture this
malware and we want to reuse it for our
own purpose can you help us figure out
how to make it work so those are very
common scenarios in this space
and
here again we have to consider could we
do anything around this to protect our
hardware and software
and that goes back to a lot of the talks
that also happened uh today and
yesterday about ethical hacking how can
we make ethical hutting more more
appealing and reverse engineering
adopted in a wider way so that people
don't have to go to that route and we
reduce
the
the amount of let's say good
evaluability researchers the reverse
engineers that those companies get
some considerations and uh
how can we defend adjustments again
encouraging ethical hacking we should
not be assuming that anything we buy is
secure no device should be assumed that
it's secured because someone said so or
it has a stamp of some sort unless you
have stamps like the ones you see there
which like it has been reviewed by the
german intelligence the swedish
intelligence the european union
intelligence but i guarantee you most of
things that we buy as let's say private
companies they will not have the stamp
synergies
and um yeah the other thing is that the
maybe we should switch our focus and
instead of trying to
to protect the whole platform can we
protect the whatever is running on the
platform
the
workload
the thing about this let's say the
network's compromised the platform might
be compromised
how can we make sure that whatever we
deployed in that system
is not getting tampered and no one is
touching it in any way or form because
if we do that we don't really care about
anything else we can assume everything
else is compromised that attached a
little bit on the zero uh zero trash
architecture which is like a big thing
nowadays but
it's a nice consideration to think of it
this way
and another area is if you have
especially in the ocean enthusiast is
to look around what all of those
companies are looking for when they are
hiring people for instance we have one
of the let's say
very well known companies that are
acquiring zero days for nation stages
that are from time time they put things
like that it says we're temporarily
doubling our bounty for chrome chains
remote code execution and sandboxes
shape to 1 million
well how you can read this is like there
is a customer out there in nation state
that pays a lot of money for this
and in some cases they are saying things
like that for very specific software and
hardware which means researchers maybe
we should
shift our focus there and see okay do we
see any active exploitation do we see
anything going in the wild around the
space
and even more interesting is job
listings
here is another one i removed the name
of the company apparently because it is
not just a single companies all of those
that are doing that so
this is why i really don't like all of
that blaming a single company whether
this is
i'm not going to create energies so if
you read this like it looks like normal
advertisement let's highlight a few
things i will read them for you because
they are tiny probably the top says
possess an active top secret sensitive
compartment information clearance or
above or an ability to update a
clearance the second one is experience
performing vulnerability recent and
exploit development for desktop and
mobile and the third thing i have
highlighted is ability to take unknown
hardware and or software systems from
initial trios to reconstruction of
system architecture through reverse
engineering efforts so this is a nice
advertisement how i read it is that
they want someone to be embedded in a
u.s government agency give them some
obsture hardware
and try to find a way to hack it
again it can give you a lot of
indication especially some listings are
even more detailed than that on what
they are looking for
okay now we'll go to the probably the
most popular area that is all over the
news exploitation frameworks there are
so many out there apart from pegasus i
just named a few and added a few
screenshots of some of them
now what is the selling point of those
it is at the point the click solution
the operators that buy them they don't
need to know almost anything they go
through a very minimal training a few
hours of training and then they learn
how to use it
those things basically they say i want
to hack this person here is the mobile
phone number and
if it is a more if let's say it's a zero
click they don't do they don't need to
do anything else if it's in a one-click
exploit they might need to add like okay
what message do you want to send to that
person
and everything else is happening on the
background on the platform
you can realize that
this has a very specific market
for instance
let's say really huge agencies like i
mentioned like the gru or the nsa in the
us
they probably care more about the
exploits that are being used rather than
the platform because they probably have
way better solutions than that but when
you're talking about smaller urgencies
that they don't have this capability
they would love to have something like
that
how those are charged typically is like
a cost for the platform per year
subscription plus additional module for
anything that people buy per usage for
instance you could say okay i want to
have a zero day for
ios okay it's going to be plus that
amount of money per 100 users
and and so on and because of that they
are very limited in use in terms of
you cannot use that to spy like in a
whole country you can use this by dozens
people hundreds maybe thousands but
after that it's not something beyond
that space
again all of them are a multi-million
subscription fees and series interest
part almost all of them are cloud-based
nowadays so you if you look carefully
you might be able to find some of those
in the wild
now what we need to think about from our
side is that uh yeah those are four
small groups of people they are not for
anything else that uh almost all known
case that we have like anything from
citizen lab amnesty international from
uh washington was like there are lots of
things that have happened over the last
just this year
they involved some zero day either one
click or zero click which again shows
there were a few very very few cases
that was like traditional fishing but
that's the exception i don't have the
exact number but
it is
way less than ten percent that it was
facing almost everything was zero days
and the other thing is that a lot of
people get
really obsessed with ios however the top
target is android in all of those
platforms if you see what's the top
demand is android apparently because
more people use android but again it is
not ios
so what can we do as defenders first of
all awareness training and teach people
operational security personal security
measures like when to use their phone
when not use their phone
what they can say in their phone where
they cannot say on their phone all of
these things
and of course uh there are a lot of
things that we could do on the
protection side like for that thing to
work on the phone think of it yeah it
could be a root hit it with kite itself
but still
it will need to do some operations
can we see those operations for instance
like one thing that's usually referenced
the battery lifetime do we see a change
in that another one that i find more
efficient is the data usage those things
need to accelerate a lot of data so that
should be visible somewhere
also if you have some sort of wi-fi
interception and your phone is using
wi-fi and then it's you need to reach
out command control servers to send data
you might be able to capture those
things
and yeah as i mentioned those are
cloud-based so with a little bit of
research you might be able to find them
online
okay now move to the public sector and
does anyone know this person andrew
busamante i'm a fan of him
no okay
so he's a recently retired cia
clandestine service officer and he's
doing lots of different interviews and
podcasts so i took two quotes from him
from two different podcasts here so the
first one is this one
the us military has something called
cyber command their job is sole cyber
warfare so not only does it happen not
only does it happen frequently but it
happens frequently and nobody even knows
it's happening that's what makes really
professional intelligence work happen
that's why we call it clandestine
going back to what i mentioned the
meeting about what we see in the news
it's a nice addition to that and the
second quote is about the targeting side
that we're talking here that once you
become an intentional target then your
security apparatus they will create a
dedicated customized way a vector of
attacking your specific security
apparatus and because security is always
after there is the leading advantage and
the trailing advantage when when it
comes to attacks the leader always has
the advantage because they have to
create the attack before anybody else
can create a way to protect against the
attack
i guess it's common sense but still i
found an easy transition from the
private sector to the public sector and
the connection to what we see in the
news
so public sector is relatively see
easy why it exists to inform the
government and military of what are the
threats
and there is another nice port cast here
from my former jsoc member talking with
a former military intelligence analyst
that in during the discussion they
estimated that from their side that it
was well their site was killing
terrorists so it was a very nice area in
the intelligent side but still 70
percent roughly of the actual
actionable intelligence that we're
getting it goes from signals
intelligence
and that also explains why all the
governments are putting so much effort
there
since it provides value
compared to compared to other
disciplines this is also why we see so
many cyber activity because cyber falls
into sigint i will explain that shortly
so what are they targeting anything of
potential interest to that specific
government or military and this is why
monitoring geopolitical news matters if
let's say a politician comes out and
says oh really disagree with that
government's position and we're going to
take steps against it i can guarantee
you in the background intelligence is
already working on that
and there is also a let's say slightly
difference here of culture change
especially in the last 10 years before
it was really like that like very
targeted and specific
what we see in the last year is that the
many governments especially in the
european union because another place was
already happening uh some degree they
started moving more to okay let's
collect everything and then filter from
that and i will give just a few examples
since we have limited time
for instance just last week in the
netherlands the regulator of the second
agencies of another of the netherlands
resigned
because his name is a bird hubert if you
want to check it out because he said
that
there is a push from the agency to tap
on all of the traffic all of the
internet traffic of the netherlands and
then filter out whatever they see as
interested based on an ai and
smart let's say rules that they filter
out whatever they consider relevant and
of course this is not let's say the best
approach but um yeah this is why he
resigned because there is a push for
that
similarly in germany it was 2018 i think
that the bnd the german intelligence got
access to the frankfurt internet
exchange to do the same thing
and
well very recently also in the last year
or so in denmark we had the military
intelligence scandal that came out with
the nsa that i'm not going to the
scandal if it was a scandal or not the
scandal or it was a secret agreement or
whatever but the important part is that
through that we also learned that they
had full tap on all of the traffic of
denmark and they were using that to
to collect intelligence
and how big of a domain is this uh it
goes back to i mentioned not all of the
apts are equal
it really depends on what they are after
if you are talking about someone like
the u.s or china that they want to have
global reach of course they will have
way more of these things happening
compared to if you talk to a smaller
country they don't like a small country
let's say well in india we understand
like small countries that may care about
what's happening in the region and not
so much anything outside of that so that
heavily depends and uh yeah just give an
explanation hopefully that shows up yeah
with the colors
this is like a purely semantics in the
practice doesn't mean that much but
signals intelligence in the western
world typically we split it to elite
which electronic intelligence you can
think of it like emissions of device
like let's say you have a spy plane
flying over and they can identify oh
this is a tank of that version oh this
is an anti-aircraft system this is that
and then you have the communication
intelligence which what which are about
which is anything that has to do with
transferring information
and of course computers fall into that
so we have like what i mentioned that is
called bulk collection or in the new
smart surveillance so the things that
look like wiretap everything
then we have
what is called international cno
computer network operations so that we
can
well it's network operations we're using
computers and the two areas that we hear
about in this talk is the cna computer
network attacks and those are
destructive or disruptive operations
think about let's say nation say doing a
denial of service in another country's
communication network and actually
in
2018 or 19 blackberry threat
intelligence did the black hat talk that
they found the ddos botnet that belonged
to the chinese government so
also governments do the u.s it's not
just
activists
and
the second part is the cne computer
network exploitation which is what we
can bundle ask what most of us
understand us hatching is how do you
exploit computer systems to get access
into them
and then you have the more traditional
voice interception like intercepting
mobile phones uh traditional phone lines
and so on so this is the space that we
are moving in this talk the common
second part
okay so
the bread and butter of second agencies
is cryptology
encryptology is the combination you have
cryptography encrypt analysis making
crypto and breaking crypto
so
has anyone ever heard hearing those
things firefly key exchange high
assurance internet protocol and crypto
and rush back
encryption anyone
okay
well probably even if you did you might
not feel comfortable saying that
so those are um
encryption algorithms used today
by nation states that are classified and
that completely trusts is the whole
point that we have the cryptograph has
to be public and everyone needs to know
everything about well not if you're a
government
if you're a government everything you
use is classified and it's not publicly
knowledge and those are some that you
might be able to find some information
in the wild
but there are many more that there is no
information out there
why is this happening oh actually before
we go there did you know that gchq had
independently discovered public geo
encryption asymmetric cryptography but
they kept it a secret
anyone okay a few people yeah it's a
pretty interesting story
it was discovered roughly the same time
but they kept the secret because they
thought it's such a big advantage
compared to the adversaries that they
don't want anyone else to use it so they
can spy on people but they cannot get
spied upon and this goes a little bit on
why governments decide to use their own
things
is it because this way they can let's
say they find the flow in some those
first of all those are not like entirely
new algorithms that have nothing to do
with what's used they are typically
optimized or modified versions of what
we use
in the public space in the let's say as
private people
so
what they did let's say they find the
flow they can immediately fix it on
their site so they know they're
protected and then they can start the
discussion okay should we fix it in the
actual algorithm maybe we should not
let's do a third assessment or it could
be oh like for this specific
communication system that we have we can
really optimize the crypto if we do this
this thing that but if we release it to
the general public they might find out
that okay
this is not the best approach the way
they do descriptors so okay let's not do
that so
it is not like some super sort of it is
like a big secret for or how they do
crypto but i mean it is not something
extraordinary it is optimizing more or
less what is out there and of course
there might be other things that i'm not
aware of that are fully customized that
have nothing to do with anything that no
they might exist
this based on open source formation so
you never know
i really like this this is the second
intelligence from australia and their
motto is literally reveal their secrets
protect our own
i found this the best description of why
cryptology is so important those
agencies this is later the bread and
butter not from now even if you go back
to world war ii this is what those
agents were established to do
so going to the modern world what does
it mean
again a snowden slide on the top right
that it is from an office that existed
back then in the nsa it was called the
office of target pursuit and the
specific team that did the presentation
was called the vpn exploitation team
pretty self-explanatory the whole
purpose to pick up vpn solutions find
flaws and find ways to exploit them so
that if at any point anyone in the us
government wanted to hack a system they
had something already available to use
that you can see like what they were
doing is provide vpn vulnerability
analysis engage network security
products convey meaningful feedback to
customer customers anyone that might ask
them for a hatching solution basically
develop and sustain exploitation threads
when possible suggest alternative
approaches if passive exploitation is
unrealistic
and oops
sorry and of course decrypt the crypt
decrypt which means if they have only
find a way
to bypass some vpn they might be able to
decrypt the traffic
the second screenshot that i have is
from 2014
from cloudflare that we still don't know
if it was the nsa behind it which goes
back to the deniability why those
agencies do exist to be able to do shady
things and not being able to easily
attribute it back to them and if you
want to research for that just search
for the
dual elliptic curve
deterministic
random beat generator
this is what they try to introduce which
to this day
it is still unclear if it was a backed
or not but it seriously looked like a
bacter from the nsc
then we have the biggest case of all
that was like 50 years of continuous
back dooring devices the crypto gjs that
the german bmd with the cia and some
support from the nsa they acquired a
vendor that was providing encryptors for
lots and lots of governments around the
world
and they did something super smart they
were
picking specific customers and they were
either changing the manual so they can
set the device in an insecure manner or
they were making a slight modification
that it still looked very very secure
but they had a way to reverse it and
break it and they did that from 1950 all
the way to 2018.
at some point b and d pulled out of this
deal but the cia continued on their own
still a very interesting case
of the combination of cryptology and
also
supply chain attacks
so what uh what they are doing these
agencies those are a few examples they
are doing of course intercepting traffic
the
all of the second agents i was able to
research they have cryptologic units
that they both verify that the solution
is secure and also try to break
solutions of their adversaries
and um we even now have a few private
companies that are doing that which is
great we should have more private
companies that are picking up solutions
they try to find flaws in cryptos like
yesterday there was a nice talk from uh
unciphered that they do these things uh
in a different scope because of
cryptocurrencies but still they try to
break crypto using
very traditional methods like what we
see in this case here
and some considerations so
let's assume based on that that hardware
appliances might not be as secure as
advertised or we don't know if they are
secure unless we check them
also in when you do encryption did you
just enable whatever is recommended or
do you do your research what could work
best for your case for instance
depending on your data flow your
hardware on your
kind of communication
one type of encryption might be better
than the other or a cypher sees a
specific cipher suit or settings in that
cipher suit
and the other thing that i'm not sure if
people take as seriously as they should
is that encryption is the ultimate
security control think about it the
network class is full compromise the
device is fully compromised someone can
read everything that we send over
what can
protect us well if someone reads
everything but they cannot understand
what we're sending
and
what should we do about this
first of all never assume something is
secure unless you have some assessment i
know like none of us is sending a
cryptanalyst expert that can do this
work but there are some
trustworthy vendors out there that can
help in that part
the other is
research what you are going to be using
for crypto
this the third point is probably the
most important
your ways for margin cryptographic
team the team management for
cryptographic material should be like
the most secure thing you have in your
organization like nothing could even go
remotely a security
this is what is achieved to your castle
and of course governments take this very
seriously but private companies i'm not
sure if they are taking it as seriously
and if people are interested in doing
research of course finding flaws in
algorithms is pretty hard unless you
have a team of cryptanalysis
mathematicians and computer scientists
but the finding flaws in the
implementation is far simpler
something to consider most of the flaws
that we have seen so far it's in the
implementation
then we have
yeah security appliance that might not
be so secure so this will be pretty
quick it's about the leaks that are have
been out there so vault seven it was
mostly used by the cia 23 projects were
leaked and the code floor is widget used
by the cia
no references to fishing
anywhere actually if you search there
will be like a couple of references but
if you open them it is not from the
widget it is a report that they were
attaching from vendors like crowd strike
fire and so on so their own content has
zero facing reference nowhere
what they have is a lot of
firmware implants lots of them
then we go to shadow brochures a few
years after 2016
mainly used by the nsa
zero reference to fishing what they had
tons of zero days remote code execution
local privilege escalation lots of zero
days also many of them for vendor
appliances specifically network devices
i listed the top ones that were
exploited
and email gateways
lots of those
again areas that the to the best of my
knowledge most companies are really not
really putting a lot of attention on
security
because we assume we buy something and
this is secure
and snowden leaks that it is uh the
harder to search because it is documents
it is a 483 documents
in total that have been released
zero reference to fishing
so what we see over there if i had to
abstract all of these documents it could
be
the targeted collection which is where
they have teams like the vpn
exploitation team or the taylor tax
operations that are going after a
specific target developing something
specifically for that as uh
using the quote from andrew bustamante
and then you have the bulk collection
that it is okay how do you wired up like
entire internal lines and people always
talk about prism but prism is not that
great because prism they have the legal
agreement with those companies to get
the data
not that exciting but upstream is more
exciting because they were tapping on
the fiber
far more interesting and basically all
of that goes to some different database
that they have big data solutions and
then they have lots of analyst tools
that they use on top of it with the most
popular being xg score that nsa did such
an awesome job that they even offer it
to partners
i'm not sure if swedish intelligence use
it i know other neighboring countries
are using it
and uh lots of european countries are
using xg score you can think of it like
a you have all of these databases how
can you say if i ever see something much
in this pattern please alert an analyst
or please do this action more or less
like a yeah an analyst quitting tool at
least it used to be like that until the
last week we had that was 2018 i think
on a manual development manual for xg
score
or xgs xjs
here is another interesting
part of the this leak i will just call
this part this from an internal nsa
communication says
this is about router hatching for this
post i'm not talking about home adsl
router i'm talking about video routers
such as cisco's junipers huawei's used
by isps for the infrastructure cutting
routers has been a good business for us
and our five is
five eyes partners for some time now but
it's becoming more apparent that other
nation states are honing the stills and
joining the scene
that is also going back to lucas talk
from
yesterday on the cisco switches
it looks like yeah other nation states
are holding the stills event to this day
in this space
yet on our side we do not pay a lot of
attention to that space
and this is a remember i mentioned about
finn isp how they were doing man in the
middle the nsa had their own tools they
were calling it quantum
and it was a similar approach it was
tapping on the network traffic and it
had like automated list of who are our
targets and when picking up a target it
was immediately injecting some code to
redirect them on what they were calling
fox ac server and
think of it like an exploit kit
and from there they were getting access
to the system
we know that this was used at least
until 2016 if not further because
slingshot that was a jsoc operation to
hack some people in somalia and africa
in general it was using that to inject
malicious dll updates on microtech
routers so if they were seeing people
trying to update the routers in that
specific part of the world
they were installing they were pushing
malicious dlls
in the updates
okay so attacking appliances i already
briefly covered it so hard to detect
pretty easy to implement because those
things don't have a lot of hardware
security they are pretty basic
and highly represents them because no
one is checking those the downside very
specialized limited system resources
they have they do not have a lot of ram
cpu and so on and you need some really
good reverse engineers to figure these
things out because there is not a lot of
documentation
recent cases
2018 the case i mentioned about the
microtic
2021 iranian servers were wiped with an
ilo ios like the bmc to manage the
server firmware implant
interesting case we still don't know how
this got in there
they just bought some new servers and
they came with this
wiper pre-installed
maybe a supply chain who knows
other recent cases it is also raised
yesterday from truesec they did a pretty
nice presentation it's the wipers that
the russian gru used to target ukraine
most of them were installed by insiders
and some default credentials but still
there are a few that we don't know how
they got in
interesting case as well
this year this this is a cyber security
infrastructure security agency released
three zero days on firewalls and a voice
device that they are used by nation
state actors and the conspiracy found
two uefi based routes that the chinese
actors are using
so as you can see lots of things are
happening in there but
we are not always seeing a lot of
activities think like in the whole year
i'm certain that there was way more
things than those happen
supply chain we are in this space so now
pretty hard to detect because we depend
on lots of suppliers
again highly persistent and it provides
extensive access because typically a
supplier has multiple customers so even
if initially your target is one customer
by getting access to this single
supplier well now as a bonus you get all
of the other customers
the downside is that it's highly
targeted like how it works you can
identify which supplier is used by all
of your targets and then go after this
specific supplier so
if that supplier has higher security
standards it will make it a little bit
harder to get into so more high cost
more complex but high reward as well
of course i have to mention the svr
changes the solar winds that they
compromised
tons of companies those are the ones
that were listed in reuters but i'm
certain there are way more than those
interesting part of the solar which is
that i'm pretty sure people are familiar
because it's very recent
all of the reports that we have today
even the government reports nothing
mentions how the initial happen the
initial access happened to solarwinds
it would be good if anyone knows please
let me know i couldn't find it anywhere
and then on the ukraine side
when the invasion started the russian
invasion started
we had like 70 or 80 ukrainian
government websites getting defaced and
putting like pro russia messages
how this happened is that they had
compromised a company that was offering
october cms and another active
development company called kidsoft that
they were maintaining all of those
websites so they didn't target one
website at the time they just
hacked the supplier of all of them
and of course this is not that new but
that cnn chinese pla operation aurora it
is such an amazing thing if you want to
research that area and basically what
they had done is that they compromised
rsa that at that point is producing some
key photos for key fobs for two-factor
authentication called secure id
and the only thing they install is the
seed so they can get
all of the customers
to a token then they use that to hack
into lockheed martin
like a lot of commerce there is a big
list and they stole lots of information
pretty interesting chase of supply chain
also cia has a venture capital company
i'm not sure if you know them it's
called inquitel it's officially cia it's
not like i'm matching this up you can
look it up they say that
and they maintain a list which is the
software supply chain compromises that
they document
this is the trend line but i'm not sure
i saw lots of things missing from there
so i'm not sure how they define supply
chain attacks
but yeah this is uh according to cia's
in qtel what they see supply chain
now
an interesting consideration
we all know all of the news that okay
china could use huawei anticlock to spy
on us because they have access to this
equipment
what happens if
let's say for instance the crypto eg
example that i mentioned that's called
operational rubicon for 50 years they
were spying on people do you know how
only three people in cryptog actually
knew about this
how because the people from bmd the
german were not going as hey where b and
d they were going as employees of
siemens
and the employees of the nsa were they
were not going hey where the nsa let us
build this crypto device no they were
going in as contractors from motorola
does this mean that anytime we use
motorola we should ask him the us
government has access to it
i don't know just some food for thought
also remember in 2013 snowden leaked
some very also by the way it's not the
only companies that i'm mentioning
anecdotal uh evidence like in the uk
raccal was the same with gchq so there
are many such companies
yeah i don't want to blame specific
companies for that
snow then leaked in 2013 a photo of uh
nsa employees in the customs in the u.s
opening tamper-proof packages of cisco
routers
flashing the framework and repackaging
them that they were going to specific
customers
maybe this is how the ilo implant got to
iran who knows
another thing in
in this space is a very interesting case
in iran that
it's called the tenor space if you want
to check it up so those were some
engineers that the cia recruited
to sell certain parts to iran because
iran couldn't buy those because they
have all of the embargoes in 2008-2010
and of course those parts were faulty
and they caused like their nuclear
systems to fail and break and they had
all sorts of issues and then the swiss
government figured out and they tried to
proceed to those people so it's an
interesting case
but what i want to highlight this one is
that supply chain is the bread and
butter of spy agencies they have been
doing that for
several decades
it is not yeah of course now we sit in
the cyber space but it's not something
new
they have been building fake companies
they have been buying companies to to
target their customers so
it is not anything new
both for hardware and software
so why do we keep on seeing fishing and
not all of these things
because first of all this is what we're
looking for we have such good telemetry
detection tools everything for fishing
that it is almost impossible to miss
like a
i would be impressed if people can evade
like modern email security solutions out
there it's pretty amazing what what they
can do
the other is that of course nation
states do use fishing
of course we have attribution we can see
that but the question is when do they do
that
for instance they might say okay
let's have this operation running all
the time it's a low risk even if it's
discovered it's us it doesn't matter or
for example in russia they are in war so
of course they are going to lower the
standards in terms of risks like yeah
they know it's us it doesn't matter
let's go after with everything we have
so
and also agency doesn't mean that they
have like all of the super hackers out
there they might have a team that they
are super capable and they might have
another department that they are not
capable and because of bureaucratic
reasons they might not be collaborating
so it might be that one unit is using
something that is not so sophisticated
but the question we should be asking is
when why do they use fishing and that's
not something from all of the previous
examples that i showed
the other is uh
because this is what we can see and what
i mean by this one imagine the case of
uh let's say government a wants to hack
this specific
company in a some country i don't know
like
in some place in the world and they only
target 10 specific routers in that
company
unless we have sensors in all of the
internet in that country in that isp we
will never see that
even if it's super noisy even if it's
not ideal
we do not have the telemetry to see that
and then most of the cases of these
operations that we are talking about
they are either passive which means they
are catching things on the wire and they
are not modifying anything or they are
very targeted
so it's not only it's not happening it's
we cannot see that they are happening
so closing
focusing on the right threads and what
could you do the first is
take the things that i mentioned here
like network-based attacks supply chain
zero days script analysis
think like a nation state if you were in
that position you had all of your those
tools in your in your toolbox in your
your arsenal and you wanted to target
your organization
what could you use how would you do it
to be as deniable as possible so even if
you just discovered you cannot say who
did it
the other part is that do not trust
third parties that they say provide
secure solutions find a way to verify
them whether this is
having your own people whether this is
hiring a company whether it is going
through some very
exhaustive compliance uh verification
not just a checkbook clicks not just a
checkbox
find a way to do that don't assume they
are secure because they have a stamp
the other is that the
i think by now it should be pretty clear
signals intelligence is one option but
it's not everything and in many cases
having an insider might be easier
quicker and cheaper
for instance this week
marge did the hearing in the us congress
and he mentioned that
india had agents in twitter china had
the interest in twitter and we know from
the department of justice in 2020 that
they they managed to dismantle a whole
network of saudi intelligence agents
into iteration so maybe it's easier for
instead of trying to hack twitter just
hire someone inside and call them and
tell them hey tell me who is doing that
or that
all
they are all the other cases i mentioned
that uh
yeah having an insider might be easy
just to install something so that we can
bypass all of the controls
or you could use both
and for people that want to do research
first of all what nation state and i
mean intelligence agents hate the most
is public exposure they are designed
they are everything around the culture
of intelligence is operating in the
shadows
i have talked with lots of people former
people in agencies
this is what like
they don't even want to consider going
public so
what should we do anytime we find
something like that go public talk about
it
and also push for change if you see a
vendor that they are not working in this
optimal way or they are not letting your
people poke in their device for whatever
reasons of like tampering their device
don't work with them make it public the
defender is not working in a secure
manner
also there are many areas that we are
not touching a lot like a network
tampering integrity well i mentioned
them here you can see them mobile phone
certain analysis script analysis
and uh blind spots on the internet lots
of blind spots every time we use a
thread feed from a vendor
remember that this vendor gets this from
ins the response and sensors they have
deployed in the world most likely there
are many places in the world they have
no sensors and no instant response
and that was it thanks everyone
you can contact me in any of those i
will also be around because i don't
think we have a lot of time for
questions but we might have some of them
uh yeah thank you very much we do have
some uh
questions from the audience to start
with
and first of all i would like to ask you
because nation state
has been a very like
term that have a very broad meaning when
especially when you read the news do you
feel there is a misperception what's
actually nation staged and state
sponsored and do you have any comments
about the terminology yeah there is a
whole categorization actually the use
government has like a state sponsored
state
what is it
state supported um like they have a
whole subcategorization but here i'm
talking about the actual intelligence
organizations that are belonging to the
government or the military not uh let's
say auxiliaries or proxies they could
use
during those activities
um okay the the next question was uh all
of this leak how this affected your work
i mean working before snowden with this
research and and
all the leaks that happened how has that
affected your research and do you think
there is a wider acceptance
the
housing i think it is easier to talk
about these things not only with snowden
like with all of the clicks that happen
all the time snow then of course it was
a big bunch of licks but shadow browsers
wikileaks
also from time time like a vice releases
the intercept they keep on releasing
classified information so it is nice
because you can let's say for instance
you might know that these things are
happening you might have an idea you
might have indications but you get the
full picture so it
let's say it helps you complete the
puzzle of how things are put together
um another great question like like is
there a government we can trust
i have no idea i wouldn't trust any
government
mainly because governments are people
i'm certain all of governments the
majority of the people have very good
intentions and they want to do the right
thing but there will always be
things that like people that will try to
abuse that and also
again from my limited experience or
research all of the governments put
government first and people second and
all the military puts military first and
people second which means if they have
to choose between
okay should we do all these things that
might not be that great for all to all
of the people or
should we not do it because it's going
to violate their human rights well
they're going to do it most likely
um okay and and a question about your
closing comments which was like to to
open source and always bring out in the
out in the light but should we be
worried that that open source reachers
this is presented at this conference are
weaponized and actually put into these
programs and absolutely i am certain a
good example is lucas talked from
yesterday that was released as a zero
nights talk initially and then lukas
figured out that some government was
already abusing it to hack hotels in
sweden so
yeah of course the same way that we
learn from all of the companies
yeah nation states are also learning
okay uh thank you very much for
enlightening presentation uh and um yeah
we're gonna have a short 50 minutes
break
and be back here a quarter past
two thank you very much