all right
um thank you all for coming out
um today we're going to talk about the
new uh bug class called prototype
poisoning
which we found almost a year ago
um
and a little presentation about us
um my name is Christopher Jacoby I'm an
independent security consultant I work
with penetration testing and I work with
change in security and trying to improve
organizations
um I have a Twitter account and it's a
cook official
you know this guy he also has a Twitter
account from today
I saw them at it right now but let's
show it later in the slideshow uh but
I'm I'm Anton I'm a independent security
consultant at Intel squirrel uh mainly
focus on security testing for mainly for
web applications I'm really big into OS
open source intelligence
um I'm also a really big fan of
JavaScript which is the language we're
going to speak about today uh love
building application uh still do
all right so
this whole thing started when I had
become an independent consultant I did
some some subcontracting for a
stockholm-based security company called
xpd that's probably around here
somewhere and they asked me to do a
black box test or one other clients
and in that test I found a bug in a
server-side schema validation service
that means that the input I was sending
into the service was not validated
appropriately
and I was attempting to do something
called prototype pollution based on a
tutorial I'd found online
but ended up somewhere completely
different and when the job was done I
had to reach out to Anton here who is a
great JavaScript specialist to get some
help because I could not for my life
understand what was going on so I could
not even write a bug report about it and
this is the story about how that went
so
I could see from the output of the
application that it was running a
library called Joey Joy is an open
source JavaScript library that validates
the input and checks that I'm using the
right type of boundaries and the right
type of format for the inputs that I'm
sending which means it's really really
hard to hack that application because
everything is strictly checked it's
written by a guy called Aaron Hammer
who's a well-known security researcher
who also wrote oauth 2 and that means
I'm screwed right and
turns out there were holes in it
and the way Joy works that with the
scheme of validation that you you create
your own schema so for example here uh
we have the username and the password
and the username it's a string it should
be alphanumeric at least three character
and maximum 30 characters and has to be
uh present
um the password as you can see you have
a reg export
um so no super
difficult and then you pass uh you use
the validate method and you pass the
object you want to validate and in case
everything is fine which it would be in
this case uh it passes so you would have
the the object itself
uh if you would add something extra like
I've done in this case and that that's
what we mainly did when we uh tested a
application and saw something was weird
that we added something and we got back
400 bad requests and extra is not
allowed so we're not allowed to add
anything more to the object we're
sending in right this is by the way the
message that made us see that this is
probably Joy going down yes because that
message is pretty unique to that Library
so we identified that this is a library
being used and we could start model the
same type of thing ourselves yes exactly
it was a black box test we didn't have
any code to look at but we asked it was
the Orion it was
um but then some when we're trying to to
send in a lot of different stuff which
you usually do and you fantastic uh we
realized that when we send her in uh the
Proto key with the extra everything was
fine
so we really didn't understand what what
is actually happening here because we
can't send the extra parameter uh
immediately that we can send it when we
wrap it in the Proto
and it only works with the word Proto
yes
and
what this means is that we are somehow
changing the input object type prototype
and
so the bug was already reported after
the assignment we figured out what was
going on we sent a bug report to the Joy
project where we contacted them and we
found out that there already was one so
there was no point in trying it was done
in 2019
and they had labeled the issue and won't
fix so it means that this packet is
still vulnerable to this exact thing
that we showed now you can still do this
thing today and Aaron Hammer who's
obviously super smart said the bad news
is that there is nothing nothing to
blame other than JavaScript itself it's
much harder getting it fixed this means
that
this is not just the problem with this
Library it's a problem with how input
validation works or how how structures
are handled in JavaScript in general
so some background about happy and joy
and who Aaron is it could be interesting
to know so
every Autumn coming to Winter there is a
holiday called The Black Friday where
people buy
sheep stuff and and and fight over
getting into stores but if you do this
online
going to Walmart you're meeting a web
framework called happy enjoy happy was a
really really fast way of building web
applications pretty cool Joy was an
add-on to that to do input validation
for security specifically and still it
was enjoy that we found the
vulnerability so
Aaron had received a bug report just
like ours back in 2019 by a company
called LOB
lob engineering is developers but
they're sending a pretty nice bug report
to him explaining that this bug we're
seeing right now can actually be
exploited to cause a lot of trouble in
happy not just go past the input
validation but actually cause execution
issues you could actually change how the
program was running inside of it
uh and um if you have access to these
slides afterwards following this link
leads to blog post by Aaron about how he
tried to fix the problem how he failed
to fix the problem and why they decided
to do nothing about it in the end
um he eventually wrote another library
to to handle the issue but uh it's a
pretty tricky problem yep
and
I mean we really want to get to the
bottom to what is actually happening and
to understand what is actually happening
you have to understand how JavaScript
works so
um just the basics of JavaScript uh to
create you have different ways of
creating an objects which I am in the
top but this is the most common this is
an object literal
um and what I'm doing here is that I'm
creating an empty object and still I can
call a method called tostring and that's
quite weird I mean how am I supposed to
do that because it's it's an empty
object right
um but the way that works is that
JavaScript uses something called
prototypes so
compared to to Java and SQL plus uh it
doesn't have a true class it uses
prototypes instead and the prototypes is
just a way that JavaScript can share
methods and values and properties
between objects that's how you do it so
you create a property uh sorry a
prototype and then other objects can
inherit from that
and automatically when you create a new
object and an empty object a prototype
is being assigned which is the global
object
and how it actually looks for for
properties uh when you look for
something is uh it starts by looking at
your object the properties in your
object if it doesn't exist there it goes
up to the Prototype itself and it will
Traverse up through the chain until it
reaches null because then we're out of
prototypes there's nothing else to look
for so in this case if I look for a
property called known non-existent in an
empty object it will start looking in
the object which is it's nothing it will
look in a prototype and in this case
we'll referring to the global objects
prototype which is inherited from the
global object so it sits on the object
um and it doesn't exist there and then
in the end since we have no more uh
prototypes it's returning null and then
we're out and that's when we get
undefined
because we're out of something
and a way to reach the Prototype uh uh
in JavaScript there's something called a
dollar Proto
um which is just an excessor to to get
to to yeah to access the Prototype
itself and
uh it's not when you create an object
it's not actually it's not a property
itself it's just a prototype an
accessory to that prototype and in this
particular case where we're sending in
the Proto uh the donda Proto property in
the in the object in a payload and it it
did go well so uh naturally we thought
we had something called prototype
pollution turns out we were wrong yeah
um pretty much and what's actually
happening here is that we create an
object and directly with setting a Proto
so we're setting a prototype on this
object which has a property called Foo
and the value bar
and what we realized we're we're
controlling the the object's prototype
in this case uh but we're not
controlling the global object prototype
which is something you want to do when
you Pro you want to pollute the
Prototype of the global object
you want to change something you want to
change meters like a two strings but we
were only able to to access our own
prototype
um as an analogy that means that we can
only poison one individual object and
not other objects poisoning multiple
objects is polluting right yeah
and so I thought okay but if I change
something if I change because if we go
back to to this slide if I chain it I
say proto.proto which is something
pretty common when you you want
prototype pollution
um so I'm sending another Provo and the
results were just I was going further
further away from the object I really
wanted I was so close which is one step
away
so but I couldn't reach it was
impossible
um
so what we understand then that
um we're only able to mutate the input
objects prototype that's it and we
couldn't mutate any other prototype that
was being used yeah
and uh what we figured and that what
what might be actually happening is if
you create an object with the Donna
Proto property which something like the
extra and the payload in the beginning
if you actually get the proper type
properties of that object it will return
an empty array it's not there
but if I actually call it it's there
so this is something uh we understood
this is built in in the JavaScript so it
always allows you to create a prototype
when creating a new uh object
so right now we're talking about bug
classes we're not talking about how to
perform the attack we have definitely
not talked about impact
but these are different ways to mutate
prototypes
or other
input objects to alter how the flow of
the program goes so if you have
prototype pollution in a client
application that can lead to cross-site
scripting
and many other things
if you have product prototype poisoning
you can replace individual properties in
that object and that's called property
injection there is another bug class
called hidden property abuse
and the research behind this bug glass
is pretty brilliant I think
the problem
that we're facing right now is it's very
hard for us to describe how bad this is
because these bugs can all be shown
together so if you find multiple bugs in
one project of these kinds you can chain
them together and you can pretty much
control the input of the program so you
have three different weapons that you
can use at once against the target
application and this is where this gets
a bit complex
I'm going to try to explain the
briefly try to explain how hidden
property abuse works because the people
or the guy who made that type of
research or that research explained a
lot of attacks in such a way that it was
inspiring for us
for this research so it was it was
something that we thought that we might
be able to do as well so think Chao is a
guy who study at um in an American
University and he found a way to inject
properties into JavaScript to alter
program flows and during one year 2019
to 2020 he found 15 CVS using a scanning
method where he is doing symbolic
instrumentation or looking at the
execution flow of the 100 Java Script
projects and from that he got 15 CVS
ranging from remote code execution and
there was input validation bypassed
denial of service and a lot of SQL
injections and we think that we also
have the same type of impacts in this by
class and it's even worse if you combine
them
so the way hidden property abuse works
is that
when you send input like the input you
saw before with username and password
imagine that you simply add without
having property Proto involved at all
you just add one more field called
Constructor and in there you define name
this will be inherited when the program
runs in such a way that it overwrites
the Constructor for other objects that's
being merged with this one it's very
rare that it happens
but it does happen often enough that if
you start scanning open source projects
just keep seeing a pattern of programs
that are vulnerable to this and you can
start altering Pro program flow and do
really really nasty stuff
what he didn't know when he did this was
that simultaneously there was research
going on with prototype poisoning and if
you combine these two it's starting to
get a bit scary so app specific
attribute manipulation is a method
within HPA not hacking freaking energy
Anarchy it's hidden property abuse
this attack method means that you create
a
a property like a debug colon true or
something like that and it's being
inherited through the program so that a
Target object now enables debugging and
that changes the outcome of things it
could be authenticated it's true or in
this case is overwriting the proper the
prototype by having a legitimate object
object property called constructor.name
with some given content and by producing
different types of uh failures and
execution flows he is
altering the flow of the program and
here's an example because this is quite
conceptual right now
this is SQL injection in a library
called Taffy Taffy is a library that
does mongodb database queries
so the database looks like this it has
ID gender username password Etc it's
just an example of a database what it
could look like
if you have an input query that happens
to have an object name called underscore
underscore and then this long
predictable string you can start looking
at other fields that you weren't
intended to because ID underscore
underscore ID is a private
um property member that is being used
much much later in the program it's
being inherited all the way down into
the program and it's being called and
referenced and when that happens all of
a sudden you can start picking out the
username and password field of other
users this is pretty messed up and
finding this is pretty complex but what
uh Feng did was to write this tool to
scan for these we think that it's
possible to write a scanner that
combines these type of attacks to scan
for
prototype poisoning vulnerabilities in
combination with these where you can
create flaws to disable logging and at
the same time for instance do SQL
injection or extract other type of
information
all right so
we haven't talked enough about what
prototype pollution is so in reality the
distinction between poisoning and
pollution is that with poisoning you're
only hurting one person usually with
pollution you're hurting the entire
environment
what happens with pollution is that
you're able to overwrite a prototype
that's used by multiple different
objects so say it's used for input and
output writing and suddenly you're
messing with the member functions inside
of the object for output printing
and in this case you have three inputs
it's key one key two and value those are
user controls so imagine the first value
is now Proto the second one is polluted
and then the last one is true then
all objects that use this prototype will
be polluted and now have a member called
polluted equals true
it's one where you're measuring this
I mentioned before that all these three
can be chained together
we have seen indications that you can
create prototype pollution
vulnerabilities on the server side from
prototype poisoning
and this is something that's starting to
scare us a bit yeah and to talk about a
bit more what prototype poisoning is
which is not prototype pollution so
you're only able to mutate your own
prototype you're not able to mutate any
other shared prototypes at all just
around because you're creating your own
prototype so in case in in this example
we have the object we actually have two
prototypes in this case because we had
our own prototype and then we have the
global objects prototype but we're
mutating our own prototypes so in case I
would run
um
object.2 string it will be null
this is actually what's that that's
basically what's happening so as
Christopher said we you you can only
hurt one person you're only hurting
yourself but this is bad enough because
when uh you're selling that object
somewhere else you still have those
properties on it because they're hidden
so we started looking for other exploit
channels that were related to this
vulnerability but not coming from Jason
so Jason was the input format we looked
at before with the curly braces
you have probably made a post request or
a get request to a JavaScript or Express
server at some time
the library that received that request
and parsed it is called query string
query string is a parser that
understands that input
that Library had a vulnerability that's
now fixed since q1 in 2022
where you can overwrite the Prototype of
the input object into request body on
every single post and get request
in every single application out there
in JavaScript I mean this is all of them
this was this bug was in every single
program
everyone uses this library and this was
obviously not a good thing I'm not sure
everyone has patched this yet but I hope
they have
so what we want to achieve now we've
been babbling about how it works and
stuff but what we want to achieve as
attackers that's what we're going to get
into now is we want to do we want to
bypass input validation of course we
want to remove all kinds of obstacles to
to check our input or control what we
are doing because we want to be free
inside the application then we want to
do injection attacks command reaction is
the best coding action second best and
then SQL in action on the third place
that's something we want to be doing as
attackers right we want to avoid logging
so the logger we want to crash that
maybe even call step
to break somehow we want to bypass
authentication so we want to reach
functionality that requires
authentication and use it otherwise even
though we're not authenticated if we can
we want to overwrite default methods so
methods that are used for things we want
to make them break so
um
yeah we'll get to that and we want to
change the outcome of conditional
statements so
things that check if this is that we
want to change it to something else we
want to control of the program
essentially right
so let's look at the attack tree of this
where what it can actually lead to and
this is where it's starting to become
speculation for us we've seen other
attacks so we've read a lot of code and
fixes of a lot of code to come up with
this list but we think there are
multiple ways to bypass authentication
multiple ways to course SQL injection
that you just saw before
with the app specific attribute
manipulation techniques that means we
understand the node app so we have the
source code for the Target application
we know the library we're hacking then
we can cause denial of service by doing
infinite loops
I'll show examples of that you can
create recursions by making function
call themselves and that's really really
bad in JavaScript we can change the
control flow of the application and we
can do or we want to do arbitrary code
injection where we send our code into
the application if we can if there is
the evaluation somewhere
we also want to achieve prototype
pollution because that means we can
overwrite any object
anywhere inside of or multiple objects
but preferably any object because then
we can start controlling the entire
application exactly what it's doing
and avoid logging and do all the other
bad things and if we want to be stealthy
we want to pass hidden members past the
input validation and do argument
injection which is a another new
technique that I think Anton was first
too yeah find and this was actually what
we found in the joy Library you had
something called hidden members and when
you create an object
um it's it's not really being shown
because you you hide it in the Proto in
the Prototype so it still works with the
Prototype shame because when you chain
up it's still there but it's not in the
object itself it's not a property on the
object and
this is
um we saw this in in multiple uh schema
validation libraries as well
um that they they look for the keys in
object but that's it that that's the
only thing they're looking for and a way
you can bypass this for example if um
uh
you would have yeah as we showed before
you create an object and you override
the the string method to for example to
to console log one uh when you're
running the object to string this is
actually what will be run so if you uh
are possible it's possible to inject
that payload itself into that object
well then anytime that method will be
run for this object uh you will have a
console log one and of course you can do
whatever else you want to do
um same with xss
this is client side by the way
yeah this this is a pretty pretty nice
line uh what What's actually happening
when you're running uh when you're using
a template literal so you create your
string and used uh input whatever you
want in the first string you actually
I'm just inputting an empty object
but the string method is actually called
so what you can do in this case that you
passed a prototype for this object and
you set the tostring method to something
like alert one so in this case uh when
the line would be run with your object
you would actually have a prototype
intuition mutation or prototype
poisoning attack in xss
so all you bug bounty hunters out there
make notes
so
there are
limitations there are plenty of
limitations frankly one of them is the
input format so the input format the
channel of exploit matters a lot to what
you can do imagine that now we talked
about a body where it contains Jason
then we're confined within the format of
Json you cannot in Json Define
functional code for instance you can
overwrite to string if you want to yes
but we cannot override it with code that
executes
we can all write with nil or null or we
can override it with a string that does
something but it will always crash if
someone tries to run the function to
string
unless there is base64 decoding involved
or you're using a more generous input
format we've been looking into a format
called Beeson which is part of the
mongodb framework that's a binary
version of Json that has code as a data
type by the way so it can actually
execute the code that you put in there
might be an interesting vector
also potentially you can do things with
the web sockets XML files
well there might be more yeah
this is an example that I gave before
but it's for posterity it's worth
mentioning again so now we're going
through examples of inputs that you can
send into JavaScript application and it
might change things so here we are
enabling debugging
potentially in an external feature that
has a check for debugging that it does
but it no one is has set this prototype
it's just something that is being read
by a third-party application at some
point
maybe it's not necessarily a bad thing
but if we can control the control flow
of the application it could result in
something that would be relevant for us
later
here's another one denial of service not
so funny for the bug Bounty people but
funny for the rest of us
the number here on length is two one
four seven four eight three six four
seven is the maximum integer in the Json
format if you change length to this and
now
request.body.length will actually be
that value
that might make this Loop very very slow
if you make the request multiple times
you can block the worker thread of that
application and and have it die same
thing if you change the data type of
length to true you could maybe make that
while loop go on forever potentially
here's an example that I brought up
before as well but the ice
authentication bypass ideas simply
defining authenticated or setting it too
true saying that yes I'm authenticated
you'll have to Define what username you
used somewhere else but this could
potentially be one target that might
turn out to be interesting because
um
a lot of times in JavaScript the input
is merged with a state object so the
input which is usually called
request.body is merged with the object
that's used for handling your state and
this is where you now overwrite the
Prototype and also that state is now
authenticated set to true
and get some pseudocode I put together
but this is something that
quite I quite often see that you have
some kind of method and if the the
property exists like in case email which
you shouldn't run but sometimes you do
um it will it will be run but before you
do that you actually filter something so
you filter uh if the the the the object
you send in has a property called eval
well it should just return don't run the
the method itself but otherwise if if it
doesn't exist on the in the property of
the object then it's fine run the method
right
and if we hide uh for example the evil
in the Proto uh a prototype of the
object well it's actually there so this
will be run this is something you can
bypass so sometimes
um and that that's usually what happens
when you have a scheme of validation you
you think that the object after the
validation is secure right because
that's why you set up your your schema
um but it's not you you have properties
on it which is not it's it's quite
hidden but still there uh so if this
will be run well then you would have a
remote code execution for example
um moving into patching this is where
the story turns a bit more sad
because
well we have this patch in inquiry
string which is great because that saves
the body parser which is like the most
essential part of all Java Script
Express things but
the JavaScript Express framework has an
ongoing conversation about this
vulnerability starting back in 2019 and
it's still ongoing
that means that no one has found a
solution to this issue because the issue
is the language itself I mean there are
other JavaScript like languages like
Dino for instance that have patched this
essentially by removing the dunder Proto
string name completely from from the the
specification but in the ekma JavaScript
this Still Remains and the issue does
remain
and this means that very very few
projects that have this reported
actually do something about it it just
turns into discussion and dice
uh
and that's means that the bug class is
still at large in the language I mean
it's it's still here some people know
about it but many people don't talk
about it and
as a community we need to start working
on Solutions here I think
yep and a quite easy way to identify or
uh
uh if if you're able to send in a Proto
object this is the default methods you
have on an object so you can set
everything to null or can you set the
product null and it should actually
throw back
a Thai power and if it's not handled you
you get a 500 back uh usually but you
can look for that type error because it
would say well uh if you would try to to
run for example the tostring method it
will say well this is not a this is not
a method so it won't be able to run
um so before we move on this is the time
to take a print screen all the pen
testers everyone in bug Bounty if you
have a Json structure that is you know
is valid append this Json structure to
it
that's what you need to do you can take
either one of them but preferably the
lower one because it's simply matching
everything in the Proto and makes it
null which means that nothing is
executable anymore of these functions or
whatever functions that happens to be in
there the top one is for the default
ones but
you might be able to destroy something
else yeah
um and also another way the the way we
actually did it how we found out this
this vulnerability is you send in uh the
pro to object in a schema validation for
example and if everything is fine then
you know that something is fishy you
shouldn't be able to do this at all
yeah the application to stop you from
doing it
so there is another way around this
and going back to this guy Aaron so
Aaron didn't leave this completely
uh to the world to exploit so he wrote a
library called born
and born is a library that scans the
request body or whatever you tell it to
scan for the word
Proto and removes it from the input this
is a really really shitty solution
really no offense I think he agrees but
it's the best shitty solution we have
that's that's the way to do this right
now so you before you start working with
a request body if you have an
application
scan it for the string Proto and have it
removed there's multiple ways to bypass
these type of scanners born is pretty
clever about this so for instance you
can use one of the many of the Unicode
methods to bypass these matches by
having character flip around things from
the Arabic language for instance those
things tend to bypass but Aaron thought
about it so I think he's
pretty it's pretty safe to use born to
parse your inputs or to scan the input
prior to sending it into your real input
validator but considering that we chose
this language and shows these libraries
and Frameworks because they were fast
this feels like a pretty shitty thing to
do you have to scan them like three
times before they reach your application
just because of a quirk in the language
it's unfortunate but on the other hand
they're also pretty good performance I
mean in this it's it's pretty well
written code so that helps yep
let's do it
so
we need you losers please help us
we need you to get in touch with us and
actually contribute to Resource we are
on the key base uh which is an encrypted
chat Network sort of we're called kyog
and soft sopa and we also have Twitter
we've made a blog post detailing how to
do this gave away all our secrets
completely for free we haven't made any
Bounty money or anything like that yet
but we are ready to work with you if you
want to
figure out Solutions if you can bring up
similar findings stories anything
related to prototype pollution might be
interesting because it's so related
we're trying to build a community around
these type of bugs because we first need
to understand them completely and teach
others about them especially developers
so that we can find ways to or clever
more clever ways to avoid it
all right
thank you thank you
we do have time for questions right yes
we do I think
are we allowed to have questions
uh there's a question
what sound is asleep
yes we're getting the money sorry
all right thank you
um so obviously they didn't fix it in
the JavaScript language because uh
backwards competitive I guess
um but in other tools like SAS tools or
in IDs do you see it fixed there or like
warned about there
I haven't seen anything yet uh I mean no
this this is quite hard to
um yeah I think what the community is
fixing right now
is what Joy is trying to do to just
remove any other type of input that's
not there that's essentially fixing the
bug called hidden property abuse where
you just append real
user control things that's the bug that
the community is working on right now
not this one necessarily in total and I
think it's because people don't remind
them that this is a thing
do you have any other questions there
yes over there
I'd like while you walk I'd like to
mention also that it wasn't easy for us
to find this it wasn't easy for us to
find their previous research
and I think that's an issue that's
limiting people from understanding it
too
great talk I've watched half of it so
sorry if you answered my question
earlier in this so JavaScript poisoning
prototype poisoning Etc it's an error I
see a lot
and it's one that developers are having
like the less awareness about let me
rephrase developers are falling into
this error all the time without like
realizing with arrays being implicitly
defined Etc I would love to know your
insights your your idea your opinion on
why this happens all the time in terms
of developers why JavaScript prototype
poisoning is still such a big thing when
people are writing code
I mean it's the question white actually
exists like white White's still there uh
because developers kind of know about
prototype illusion is that the question
so my question is why is it in my
opinion one of the top uh things I see
in JavaScript written in code all the
time without realizing that it's a
mistake yeah I I think what where we are
right now if you
remember how it was back in 2001 with
the SQL injection this is where we are
with prototype related bugs right no one
knows how the developers hackers are
getting to know it and right now a field
or a Mason Labyrinth is opening up and
we are sort of rush in there and squash
things fight dragons and monsters
why not just fix it in the
um Json parser like I know that doesn't
fix all the problem right but like make
the default Json parser if it sees the
Prototype keyword
triple Escape it or something like that
you could and they actually kind of
fixed it uh not really but it kind of
fix it in in Json Parts uh but still you
have I mean what if you get input in
other ways like you get it in XML or or
query string or uh for example like
Beeson that we're uh about to
investigate that you have you have the
the issue is in JavaScript when you
create a new object you're always able
to create your own prototype for that
object
um so yes you could but it doesn't
really stop everything from there is
also another reason and this is a bit
unfortunate but people are actually
using the dunder Proto string invalid at
real applications it's actually being
used in communication between front-end
and back end in applications so if you
break that
and that's why Joy didn't fix it because
they had users of that library that
deliberately used Proto
it's like a real question over there
right
yes
so you were talking about the solution
using Proto filtering strings
what I'm wondering is kind of to use
replace the Prototype object with a safe
prototype object when you are creating
the object itself
right so that means so what he's
suggesting is that you overwrite the
Prototype on input you had this idea
before we talked about noddling the
Prototype right yes I mean you you uh a
way to I mean to protect yourself from
prototype pollution is to create a null
prototype in that I'll say you create
object start crate and unknown but the
issue here is
um uh you since we're sending in a new
prototype even though the object has a
null prototype you're creating the
Prototype yourself
so
um
it's it is hard to protect against this
um not sure if you have any commenting
uh I think it might work in some cases
to do it uh
I think one issue is that uh
still
um
if you don't check the input you can
still alter the Prototype unless it's
frozen right so you can always alter the
Prototype if it's merged with another
input object at some point somewhere one
structure that we didn't mention during
this talk we're thinking about is that
the HTTP header itself is a structured
format
that could contain a prototype you could
have a header called underscore
underscore Proto underscore underscore
colon and then
a list of something
I mean that's another one
do we have any more questions before we
end this evening
hmm
yeah so my question would be on the
server side is the Purdue still being
checked or can you still inject uh like
arbitrary code to execute on this other
side
like on the server side you should check
for Proto case or like I mean if you use
expressed or with node.js for example
and I sent some
JavaScript code
and then also inject some
[Music]
arbitrary code in the Proto object how
would the server handle it as of now uh
I mean if for example if you're able to
send in a function as a key and that
will be around later then you have
remote code execution but that's one of
the limitations with Json for example uh
when you send that you know user inputs
uh I mean you can't really send a
function right you can only send a
string or like Boolean or uh integer but
um
uh I mean
it is possible to have a remote code
execution with this you should always
look for the protokeys and you any
anytime you have user inputs I mean you
should ignore the Proto case always uh
it's not really nice that a user should
send in a prototype for for the object I
mean even though you would have like
microservices architecture it's it's
really bad to to have I mean Services
sending prototypes to each other in that
way and so Express and node will not
filter or limit any of these attacks it
would rather actually help them slightly
so getting getting the data in there is
right now not the problem uh as an
attacker though getting into execution
is a bit tricky because you need to
reach a function that does evaluation of
what you're typing as a string so string
evaluation into code that's what you
want to find and for us as testers to
find this brute forcing is not a good
option what we need is a symbolic
symbolic execution scanner that scans
every possible input with every possible
dangerous function that we would want to
reach like eval or system or whatever
thing you want to hit and doing that
over a large code basis that's the
solution to start identifying where
these bugs are so some might be
vulnerable to to rce as you suggest some
might go into SQL injection or something
different you also need a hacker's
mindset and I to see which one is which
because you will get plenty of false
positives trying to do this and in a lot
of cases overwrite really shitty things
to do basically nothing
so you will get requests where the
service has 500 error crash lots of
times first
do we have any more questions we have a
little more time
thank you foreign
did you do it uh in practice
so if we combine this with this
realization we'll start the question no
yeah you mentioned that uh during uh
digitalization Zone format some code
evaluated in the mongodb driver or
mongodb package have you exploited it if
you can exploit the mongodb yeah we
haven't been able to explore that I
haven't really uh investigated it yet
but as we can see with HPA that it was
possible to exploit it yeah
vulnerability should uh or could
possibly be so there has been three
mongodb related exploits in this sort of
field of bug classes and those were
published by uh thing
earlier where he found that in one case
you could in Express for instance
you could create an ad document that
would end up in a safer eval function
and there he could do basic evaluation
and that was in RC for instance he did
that in he found an SQL injection
in the mongodb connector which made it
so that you could have it in one given
input field you could overwrite any
other field so say I have name as an
input as long as I can control the Json
string as an attacker I could just add
the fields to to change where the data
would end up which is an SQL reaction so
there was plenty of attacks that were
going in that certain
Direction I think
um it's not necessarily something that
will work with our combined attack thing
what this is better for right now is to
create exceptions to course exceptions
because we can override functions so
that they cannot run so we can cause
type errors we can make printing not
work we can create console log errors so
that logging doesn't work anymore those
type of things that's the level of
attack phase that we are in right now
but if you start scanning for it you can
find combinations where you would
potentially be able to overwrite the
global if you can override to go Global
you can things up badly so that's
one example of
finding a different attack path here the
recursive Loops the length those type of
things evals is of course good and any
type of interpreter that goes to a shell
or a third-party thing is is a target
that we want to go for we are going to
look into mongodb that's the thing for
sure you know because mongodb is using
Json so yes
so any more follow-up questions
over there a lot of questions thank you
for all the questions yeah
so assuming oh wow this feels weird so
assuming that these hidden fields are
also excluded from when you try to
re-serialize the object
wouldn't one very brain dead
sanitization method be to deserialize
re-serializing and deserialize again
which should remove all prototypes
good question I I have no idea no I I
don't know either
um
I I haven't thought about it sorry
but yeah we might get there but let's
talk later seriously that might be
interesting
yep
reach a hand if you have a one last
question
foreign
so
I want to gladly thank Christopher kibi
and Anton Leneer
was a great speech and great questions
yep thank you all right thank you very
much thank you