first things first
i am
verified on twitter
whoa boy
those of you who follow me on twitter
might know that for the last 11 years
i've been fighting with twitter
organizers to convince them that i
should get the tag because i've had been
i've been fighting with various copycats
on twitter over and over again finally
yesterday i got it so
that's all i needed
now
many of you remember me
as someone who used to work for a
company called data fellows or maybe
more likely as someone who used to work
for a company called f-secure but now
i am working for a company called wit
secure
if secure split into two companies first
day of july
the consumer side is called f-secure the
business-to-business side is called wit
secure
those are separate companies we are
still headquartered in helsinki finland
we are still in the same building
but those buildings that buildings now
split into different floors
people who work for which secure can't
get in to have secure floors and the
other way around which is weird but
that's the way it is however
there are exceptions
i actually work for both companies
i spend 90 of my time on which secure
but then which secure sales 10 of my
time to f-secure so i can actually enter
both floors or both areas of the company
which is
nice so
one of the largest
data security companies in the nordics
split into two companies we have secured
400 people
which secure is 1 300 people consumer
side and business side
but i'm not here
to talk about that i'm not here to think
about that i'm here to think about the
unthinkable
so how do we start this
well
when the door opened
and the captain
walked in carrying his
rk 62 rifle
i realized
that we have been caught
as you know in finland we have a
military draft system
all the males get to go to army they do
a year of training then after that they
go back regularly for refreshers
and the thing which
is important about our military draft
system is that we try to put experts
in the position in their reserve
unit which would match with their
civilian skills which means
whenever i go back to the army well
first of all they don't make me cut my
hair anymore you only have to do it the
first time around
second of all
they don't give me a rifle anymore
they give me a keyboard because i'm much
more
how should i say it effective
with a keyboard than with a rifle that's
the logic if someone is an expert in
telecommunications that's what they do
in the reserves if someone is good with
cyber stuff that's what they do in the
reserve if someone is a civilian doctor
that's what they do in the reserves
so one of the refreshers i did
years ago involved
a rehearsal where we were going around
finland
changing locations
every day or every other day
with a small group of geeks
and we had a mission of launching
attacks
against the military network
and there was another team which spent
that week trying to find us so trying to
physically
find us they were going behind us
trying to use different forensics to
figure out
what we were doing and where we were
very hands-on
very interesting
very exciting also the kind of thing you
don't get to do in normal civilian
environments and yes
on day six of the
refresher we were caught when the door
opened and the captain walked in
we knew that okay
we survived for six days but we didn't
survive forever
so finland
has had a very big neighbor
for a very long time
very big and very unpredictable neighbor
both my grandfathers
fought the russians
in the second world war
and we've been thinking about
how to prepare ourselves
for the unthinkable
as long as we've been independent
and today that of course involves
how do you prepare sell yourself and
your society with technology
technology is changing the world
right now during our time
faster than ever before
i think this is pretty obvious i think
it's pretty obvious that there's a
massive revolution going around us
but it's surprisingly hard to see the
size of the revolution you're living in
when you're living inside of it and this
is what's happening to us we have an
idea
that technology
and connectivity are changing the world
but it's kind of hard to see just how
big this change is
and i've been thinking about this a lot
over the last two and a half years
because i spent the pandemic time
writing a book
this one right here came out in english
last month
and in the book
i tried to illustrate how the world
changed and how it changed for the
better
and for the worse
thanks to this connectivity revolution
the internet is the best thing which has
happened during our time and the worst
thing
which has happened during our time it's
bringing us all these great benefits at
the very same time it's exposing us to
completely new kinds
of risks completely new kinds of crime
crime used to be local today crime is
global
one factoid i have in the book
is that in 1994
in finland
there were 140
bank robberies
140 bank robberies in which
robbers went to a bank with guns to
steal cash
think about that
140 times a year
the last time we had a bank robbery in
finland was 11 years ago
of course they don't happen anymore
neither you don't have bank robberies
either because banks
don't really exist they're only online
the few banks we have in the real world
don't have much cash
bank robbers
have went online
just like all the other criminals
and the real world bank robbers
were living close to the bank they were
robbing
they were from the same city from the
same town they were from within the 100
kilometer radius from the bank this was
local crime
today
when our online banking systems or
credit card systems are getting hit by
online bank robbers
they are not from the same city or town
or country
at all
they can be from anywhere on the planet
because that's one thing
the internet did it took away geography
internet deleted
geography it deleted distance
and in many ways it also deleted borders
and this is not the first time
a massive technology revolution changes
the world
of course we've seen this before
and the best comparison in many ways is
the revolution we saw
pretty much exactly
150 years ago
the revolution of the electric grid
city of stockholm got its first
electricity crit in 1870.
in 1870 you started replacing the gas
lights around the streets
with electric lights
almost exactly 150 years ago most cities
in europe started installing electric
grids around that time
and during these years during these
decades
electricity
has become
completely mandatory for our societies
today no society
survives without electricity
today when we when we see electricity
cuts or blackouts they're very short
thankfully because if he would have
extended blackouts
days weeks months
years
our societies couldn't function
we can't move around we can't
communicate our factories won't run we
can't feed our people as simple as that
and we are
not there yet
with connectivity
if internet goes down
and stays down
it's not going to stop our society
yes it would be painful yes it would be
very expensive
but we would survive
sas would still be flying their planes
from arlanda
the trams would still be going to
central station
they couldn't be selling tickets online
because there would be no internet but
they could function factories would
continue making food without
connectivity they couldn't do it without
electricity but they can still do it
without connectivity
for now
for a few more years
but it's coming
in 10 years in 20 years connectivity
will be as mandatory for our society as
electricity
connectivity will be as mandatory as
eventually an internet cut is going to
shut down our society people will start
dying
without connectivity
in fact i could also forecast that
eventually we'll see a time
when
an internet cut
will cut power
right now it works the other way around
if we lose electricity
obviously routers won't run without
electricity so we lose internet as well
what i'm saying is eventually an
internet cut will cut electricity
am i crazy no i'm serious i think this
will happen because everything will
become interconnected yes it's going to
take a while
but this is the future
that we're headed towards
technology revolution is changing
everything
internet is the best thing and the worst
thing that's happening during our time
and quite often it's the exact same
things which are the best and the worst
things let me give you an example
when internet came around it changed all
of our lives but
it was especially a big change for
minorities
and here we can think about all possible
kinds of minorities definitely sexual
minorities but even even someone who
just happened to have a rare hobby would
be a minority before the internet if you
were different you were alone
if you were different
you were alone you knew no one else like
you
in your city or town or wherever you
were then the internet comes around and
suddenly you'll find that there's tons
of people just like you who think like
you who are like you they're just far
away
but now you can reach them and this is
great
but then when we look at
destructive
ideologies or destructive minorities
like extremists
or school shooters
or let's say people who dream about
suicide
they will also find exactly the same
kind of support
from exactly the same place from the
forums on the internet it is the best
thing and the worst thing we get both
and we can't just choose the good parts
we get both
and technology
isn't neutral
we quite often get these
claims that you know technology is just
a tool it can be used for good or bad
well yeah true but clearly there are
technologies which are being used much
more
for bad
than good and i don't think technologies
by themselves
are as innocent as we often like to
portray them
but the problem is when we innovate
something we cannot
un-innovate it
when something has been
invented it's with us forever
no matter how much some politicians hate
strong security
aka strong encryption
they can't make it go away because we
have invented it it exists
so the only way it can be restricted is
by making it illegal which
is exactly the wrong thing to do
because if you want to control people
who break the laws you cannot make
things illegal and make them stop
break the law they already are breaking
the laws
i don't think many of us were expecting
what happened on the 24th of february
this year i certainly wasn't
i was reading
the same articles coming from
stories based on uh information
published by
u.s intelligence and uk intelligence in
which they
over and over again said that they have
intelligence which would indicate that
russia would be invading ukraine
i just didn't believe it
a friend of mine dmitry alberovich
i've known him for years and he was
repeating the same thing
you know
russia is preparing to invade
i didn't believe him
why because it made no sense
clearly russia wasn't ready
to invade ukraine
clearly they can't invade ukraine
they're not ready to do it yet they
invaded anyway and yet
they weren't ready so it didn't make any
sense
it was hard to say that this would
happen because it made no sense but they
did it anyway
so now
today
we're faced with the fact that there's a
war in europe
and this is not a far away war this is a
war which is happening
dead center in europe and it's happening
actually
surprisingly close to where we are right
now there are
towns in sweden
which are further away from us right now
than chernobyl ukraine
chernobyl isn't that far away
there's northern towns in lapland in
sweden which are further away than
ukraine
has had a long and complicated history
with a very big neighbor as well just
like
we have they have an even longer border
we
finland and sweden we have 1
340 kilometer of border
with the russians i'd like to think of
it as a joint border
that finland and sweden has together
maybe we are sort of like a buffer
between you and russia
something like that
and if one of the reasons why
russia invaded ukraine was to try to
keep nato away from the borders
now as we're joining both nato
russia will more than double
their nato border
and make no mistake we will join
the main reason why our politicians
our prime minister sana marine and our
president saul ninista
were so
decisive on joining nato
wasn't really
that we needed the support of a military
union or we needed
some kind of assistance
no it really started from talks
late last year where president putin
very straightforwardly said that you
know finland can't join
finland is not free
to make such a decision as if it
wouldn't be our own choice to make
well thank you very much
mr putin it is our own choice to make
and we do make our own choices
so it will happen
so what's the importance
of cyber
in all of this
when you look at the
things that governments do with
offensive cyber tools
clearly the biggest thing they've been
doing for years is
not about
waging war it's about espionage
using offensive cyber tools to spy
or using offensive cyber tools to
collect information for espionage
purposes or for information gathering or
intelligence gathering purposes that's
the number one thing
that governments both in the east and in
the west
have been doing
sure we also have examples where
governments use offensive cyber tools
some of you might call them cyber
weapons
to do sabotage
stocksnet would be a great example of
that
and then there's one more border to
cross and that's
full-blown cyber war
which happens when two countries which
are at war
are launching attacks against each other
using offensive cyber tools
clearly then that is cyber war but i
don't believe we will ever see
a situation where two countries would be
waging only cyber war on each other it's
one of the theaters or one of the
domains for war just like in ukraine
they are fighting on land on sea in air
in space
and in cyber space
in all of them at the same time
it's just a domain
for waging
war but these tools
cyber tools
for war or cyber weapons
are different
from all other weapons
the power of most weapons is not in
using them
but in showing them
it's enough to have the weapons and to
make sure that your enemy knows that you
have the weapons this is the reason why
countries to military parades this is
the reason why you can go to wikipedia
and check any countries air force or
navy and you'll get a listing of how
many fighter jets they have how many
navy ships do they have how many
aircraft carriers
how many tanks this is all public
information
so we have great visibility into
traditional weapons
because the biggest power of traditional
weapons is in deterrence
if everybody knows you have the weapons
then you don't need to use the weapons
because they know you have the weapons
the prime example of this is
nuclear no clear weapons
this is the prime example because
nuclear weapons have been used in
mankind's history in war
two times
in 1945.
hiroshima and nagasaki that's it
there are tens of thousands of nuclear
warheads on this planet right now in the
11 countries which have nuclear weapons
today
and the power of those nuclear weapons
obviously is not in using them it's in
having them and everybody knows
who has nuclear weapons it's the
countries which do
nuclear weapons testing
that's why one of the reasons why
testing has been done to show that you
have the capability and by the way
here's a party trick question to you
the question is
when was the last year that russia did a
nuclear weapons test
and then your friends will guess various
years and they will all be wrong because
the answer is never
russia hasn't tested nuclear weapons at
all the last time they tested nuclear
weapons was in 1991
when it was the soviet union
so for more than 30 years
russia hasn't detonated a single nuclear
weapon not even underground
which really makes you wonder if their
nuclear weapons would even work
anymore after 31 years of
corruption and whatever is going on
inside russia
so if cyber weapons
have no deterrence power is there a way
to get deterrence power for them somehow
maybe in the next military parade we
could have a truck
filled with geeks and nerds with
keyboards and
probably not
how could we do it for real
well i guess you could have
a
some kind of a war game
where you would invite outsiders and
representatives from other countries and
then you would show
how you're launching cyber attacks
against test targets to for example
disable i don't know
air control systems or radar systems
similar to countries that you are
worried about
that would show that you have the
capability but then again
nobody would really believe
what you're doing unless you would show
for real what you're doing not just
showing screens going blank but actually
showing that yeah there's this
vulnerability in this system and here's
how we connect and here's how we exploit
it
and you can't do that
you can't do that because cyber weapons
are the only weapons in the world
which you cannot show to your enemies
because they will get a copy
of your weapons
of your tools just by seeing them
if you show your tanks to your enemy
they don't get a copy of the tanks
but if you show your exploit they do
and this is not just theoretical we have
examples of nation states launching
attacks
against each other using exploits which
are then repurposed by the victim
countries to attack back this has
already happened
it's sort of like if you have two tribes
fighting in the jungle and one of the
tribe doesn't have swords the only thing
they have to do is to wait for the other
tribe to throw swords at them and then
then they do have swords
and this doesn't apply to any other
weapon
and this is made worse by the fact that
cyber
tools
offensive cyber tools have a limited
shelf life
they have a
best before
date
they expire they rust
they rust just like
real world weapons too
imagine
an effective attack today targeting i
don't know latest linux kernel zero day
in linux kernel right now or in windows
or iphone or some military system
how long will it work
how long will it be effective
a year sure two probably five
in most cases 10 i don't think so 15 no
bugs are found and fixed
vulnerabilities are detected and
corrected
systems change
they are rewritten from scratch and the
things you're targeting will go away so
think about this you have these
offensive tools developed by governments
which are expensive to develop they get
no deterrence value out of them no one
knows they have them and they will die
soon so the whole investment
is thrown
into garbage no one even knows you had
them you had no deterrence value you had
no practical value
cyber weapons are great and awful
as weapons they're great they're
effective
they're affordable they're deniable
that's an excellent combination
but at the same time they provide no
deterrence and they have a much more
limited shelf life than tanks or navy
ships or fighter jets
so during the ukraine conflict
how much have we actually seen
what kind of things have we actually
seen
i guess the best example of
offensive cyber capability
happened in the very beginning of the
war many of you might remember that on
the first days of the war the news
stories were filled with
shootings or or films about ukrainian
women and children queuing on the border
of poland trying to cross the border and
they couldn't get through they were like
massive queues
reporters were
mystified why can't the people leave the
country well the
explanation is that russians had been
using their cyber attacks to wipe
the computers on the ukrainian border
control systems
the borders were open but everything was
done with pen and paper that's why they
had the cues and this is very practical
this is very real world this is what
cyber war looks like in 2022
but it's been fairly quiet for the last
couple of months
before the invasion we saw plenty of
activity during the invasion we saw
plenty of the activity and during the
first weeks maybe the first two months
plenty of activity but it's been
quitting more quiet
and i'm surprised
because russians do have capabilities
but we are not seeing them use them
right now in the middle of this open
public conflict when there are actually
when there's actually a war going on
and the best explanation i have is that
the traditional generals in russian
military who run the war effort right
now
believe that the role of cyber is in
softening the battlefield before the
attack but then
when the real war starts cyber
takes the back seat
when missiles
start flying and bombs start dropping
and tanks roll over the borders
then cyber takes a back seat
maybe a little bit old school
thinking but that's the explanation i
have
now this is not for the lack of
i mean there has been some attempts
during these months most importantly the
in destroyer 2 attack which we saw in
the end of april
in destroyer 1
was the attack
in 2017 and 18 where
russian military operations cut power at
pricarbato obligo and in
two other obligos
inside ukraine
they tried doing it again
a couple of months ago and they failed
and this is an example on how ukraine
has been successful in defending
themselves
in fact
ukraine is the best best country in
europe
to defend their networks against
nation-state-level attacks
from russia
the number one
they're better than we are or you are or
germany or france or uk
they're the best
why
because they've been doing it for eight
years
they've been doing it for eight years
day in day out
there's the old law that you become a
world class expert after doing 10 000
hours of something the ukrainian cyber
defenders have done their 10 000 hours
they are world class experts
and there's been plenty of things to
learn from
many of you remember this photo
from 2018 it's the not petty attack you
see not petty
screens in this supermarket cashier
systems
and i went back to my notes
to 2018
because i wanted to find out where this
photo was taken
well it was taken in a supermarket chain
called rost and this photo
is from rostharkev
in harcover
in southern ukraine
so i googled rust harkev
it was bombed
three months ago by the russians so the
very same supermarket was hit first by a
cyber attack then by a real world
attack
this is what cyber war
looks like
what about then the attackers who are
not
part of the government
there's been plenty of talks about
civilians
including organized crime gangs who
support their countries and about
activists and activists both from the
west
as well as from russia
what's their role
well many of the most visible
patriotic haggar troops
from russia
disappeared or sorry appeared out of
nowhere in the beginning of the war
kilnett hacknet and no name 57 are all
example of groups like these
they
are not part of the government
they're not trying to make money
but they are trying to target
targets they believe would help
russia in this war
they communicate
over telegram or in tor hidden service
chats
and they synchronize attacks against
targets they believe
would make
some difference for russia in this war
effort
and since they are not trying to make
money that makes them a different group
from
the organized crime groups operating
from russia
most famously group conti
now conti has
this banned
roughly three months ago we believe most
of the county members now are active
parts of other
organized crime groups in russia such as
lockpit
but they famously aligned themselves
with the russian government on the very
beginning of the war this is a
screenshot i took from the tor hidden
service website of conti
on the 25th of february when the war
started on the 24th and they aligned
themselves
with the russian government
so what does that mean in practice
well here's a bigger screenshot
three weeks later from the same site
it's the site they use as their league
site
where they
use leaks from their victim companies as
a way
to force them into paying ransom
one of the companies listed on the page
is called nordex what's this
what does nordics do
well nordex is a german company actually
originally dalish company but then
bought by a german company
which is one of the largest energy
creation and distribution companies in
europe
and this is a recurring
theme
we've also seen
russian attackers especially hacknet
hack into
and do data leaks from companies like
d-tec and d-tec is one of the largest
energy providers inside ukraine
why are these gangs
targeting energy distribution and energy
creation in europe
because one of the weapons in this war
is energy
one of the main ways russia can affect
us the rest of europe is through
russian oil
coal and gas and the better they can
disrupt operations with european energy
energy distributors or energy creators
the better it is for them so for these
criminal gangs it's
it's a win-win scenario they make money
but they're also helping their
motherland
by choosing which victims or which kind
of victims
they're targeting
so the world is changing
if you go back
and think about how the world changed
in the second world war
well the war ended
between the united states and japan
with the nuclear
holocaust
and it's quite easy to say
that nuclear physicists
people working with nuclear physics
lost their innocence in 1945
exactly in the same way we
computer scientists we've
lost our innocence exactly in the same
way as
our research area has now become
a tool for conflicts
and a tool for wars
and there's no going back
once again we cannot uninvent
things which have been invented
so is it all bad news
are we
only seeing
doom and gloom
in our area of expertise which is
computer security
well no
you see i'm an optimist
and that might be
surprising because i've spent 31 years
working with the worst parts of the
internet
with the scum of the internet with the
criminals the attackers
the worst
aspects of this technology revolution
yet i am an optimist about the future
i believe
that the security of our systems has
never been better
i believe that the security of the
computers you use day in day out has
never been better
and i know it doesn't look like it
the reason why it doesn't look like it
is that
only the bad news are news
imagine you yourself or i don't know the
i.t team in your organization
learning about a new vulnerability
affecting your systems and then
working through the night
patching everything making sure all
systems are
updated and fixed and updated and
patched
and they finish patching the last server
at 6am
and then at 7am an outside attacker
scans through your ip range
looking for vulnerable machines and they
find none
you're safe
nothing happened
these guys these guys these girls maybe
you
did a heroic thing
and no one will know
because the only thing that happened
because of the work they did was nothing
and i can guarantee to you that
tomorrow's
newspapers here in sweden will not have
a headline
which says that the second largest
company in sweden
was not hacked yesterday
that's not news
when a company gets hacked that is
news so we only see the failures
and it's easy to see
only the bad sides but the truth is our
security is better than ever
and one of the biggest changes
in there has been new operating systems
ios is 15 years old
in many ways
this
has exactly the same
or similar platform
than a games console
this is a playstation or an xbox
a playstation or an xbox is obviously a
computer xbox even runs windows
but you never hear about viruses or
worms or hacks on playstations do you
no because it is a computer which is
shut down closed down you can't program
it yourself even though you own the box
you can't program it exactly the same
thing applies here
and that's a very very restrictive model
but it's also secure
model
how can you say it's secure when we've
all seen the headlines about
pegasus from nso infecting iphones
belonging to ministers and parliament
members and meps
well
this my friends this
is not a security failure
no this is a security success story
this is a success story why because it
costs 100 000 euros
to hack an iphone with pegasus
how much does it cost to hack
your windows laptop
like you know
10 crooner
which means
your phone only gets targeted if you are
worth 100 000 euros for an attacker and
here
the only attackers using this tool are
governmental attackers so you don't have
to worry about criminals only
governments
most of us will never be targeted by a
foreign government if the price for
targeting our phone
is 100 000 euros they might target our
computers but they won't target our
phones this is a success story
so i've been a computer security guy all
my life
practically all my life ever since i was
21 years old
i was 21 when i reverse engineered my
first malware i still have it with me
because i always carry it here
i even have my tailor make my suits
exactly the right size so i can fit a
five and quarter inch floppy disk into
my pocket
true story
so i've thought
for
decades
that my job is to secure computers
i'm a computer security guy i secure
computers
but slowly
i've started to realize that today
everything runs on computers
as i explained in the beginning
connectivity
is becoming the new electricity our
societies
run on computers which means my job
your job our job
is no longer to secure computers it is
to secure the society
that's our job
thank you very much
thank you mikko um
you get to keep flopping
what is it is it warm yeah it's warm
it's form
ah it doesn't fit i've talked to my
tailor
i'll i'll send my tailor's contact
information
what do you um
what's your definition of cyber war
you said it's not cyber words sometimes
it's
uh sabotage if one country is attacking
with all his might another country it is
no kinetic war is that a cyber war or is
it just acts of sabotage
well
maybe the discussion on the exact words
is a bit academic but i actually do
believe
that words matter and i strongly do
believe that if something isn't war we
shouldn't be calling it a war
and right now
we see a massive
um
devaluation of the word
war because it's not just cases like
cyber sabotage which gets labeled as war
even things like
phishing attacks launched by a
government and against another
government to steal information it's
called cyber war when it clearly isn't
cyber war it's intelligence gathering or
spying
spying isn't war espionage isn't war
spying is spying espionage is espionage
and if two countries are not at war i
don't see how they could be doing cyber
war against each other and that means in
my book stuxnet wasn't cyber war it was
cyber sabotage however if usa and israel
would have been at war with iran then
exactly the same attack would have been
cyber war because then there would have
been a war
so it has to be kinetic to be able to be
cyber as well it has to be happening in
other domains in addition to cyber so
and it's not enough that it would be a
cold war
for it to also be a cyber war there has
to be something real in my book
it's interesting to think what will be
the next domain
i mentioned we have like land war air
war sea war space war cyber space war
it's not going to end here we have five
domains today
it's gonna it's kind of interesting to
speculate what the sixth
domain will be right now we have no idea
the only thing we know is that whatever
the sixth domain will be
it's going to sound like science fiction
today just like cyber war sounded like
science fiction 30 years ago so it could
be i don't know
nano warfare where
enemies distributing airborne air cell
size tiny robots which enter your
bloodstream and change your thoughts and
if that sounds like science fiction
exactly that's what cyber war sounded
like 30 years ago
fair enough
do we have questions from slido uh we do
have questions from the lawyers one you
already just answered which is like
which is going to be the next big domain
so we're going to skip that um but one
uh question you were mentioning
like yeah cyber weapons doesn't have
deterrence uh but do you think the nato
exercises like the locked shield
exercises are they
a way of trying to build the deterrence
through cyber warfare um
yeah maybe in one way they could be i
don't think locked shields and similar
rehearsals and competitions
have been built for that purpose but of
course they do showcase capabilities
but the vast majority of our
capabilities remain hidden i call this
the fog of the cyber war it's quite
clear to see which are the best
countries in offensive capability i
don't think anybody really argues
against usa being number one they've
spent more money longer than any anyone
else building offensive capabilities and
it's clear that israel is pretty good
russia has lots of capability china has
lots of capabilities but then when you
go
beyond that to smaller countries what's
the offensive cyber capability of
vietnam
or south korea
be it's me and you can't google for it
either so it's it's kind of hard to
really really see where the real things
are happening now the
the deterrence value
is one thing about
uh rehearsals like log shields which is
a nato uh rehearsal there's another
thing which is also being built in these
rehearsals and in
nato research centers like like the
ccdcoe the center of excellence in
tallinn which is the rules
of war or laws of war for cyber war
which we will be needing today we have
rules of war for real world war like
you're not supposed to bomb hospitals
you're not supposed to use chemical
weapons like these kind of rules and i
do believe that eventually we will have
rules of war for cyber war
things like
when you distribute
offensive cyber cyber tools malware
backdoors they must not continue working
and spreading forever there must be a
kill date
sort of similar like you would wish to
have a kill date in land mines so when
the war is over they would no longer be
killing civilians clearly you can easily
program things like these into these
offensive tools and i think
they will become the norm i also believe
that we will eventually see
some kind of identification requirement
that when you deploy
tools offensive cyber tools as a
government you must
sign them somehow
maybe not so that during the conflict
you would show who's behind them but
then after the conflict you could prove
that this was ours this was ours that
was yours this was ours things like that
which you could easily do with encrypted
blobs inside the binaries i think things
like these will become
a part of the future of conflicts
you mean like a
private public key scheme was like oh
that's signed by the us
something like that just like in the
real world where you're supposed to have
the flag
in in your uniform to show who you are
fighting for something like that but
deniability is one of the main features
of it that's why it's unlikely to be
deployed
so that you could tell during the
conflict who's doing what but then after
the conflict you could prove that this
was ours or maybe someone else could
prove that this was yours five years
after the fact so we could now know for
real that stocks that was usa and israel
if they would have implemented something
like that but since they haven't we all
know it's usa and israel but we can't
prove it
um okay uh i think do we have any more
questions from
the audience there's a question right
over here okay
hi
thank you for a really good speech
i wanted to hang on to the deterrent
part
why can't a nation-state-sponsored
attack be part of the deterrent because
that's the sort of way to show their
muscles or the muscles or the
intelligence that they carry in that
country
when we look at
cyber attacks nation-state cyber attacks
which have been caught
the vast majority of them are from
russia and china that's one of the
reasons why russia and china are seeing
so big players in cyber when they
actually are
quite a lot behind in technical
capabilities
behind for example usa and israel in
based on on my understanding
and the reason i believe is that
russia and china don't really care about
getting caught
western intelligence agencies western
governments western militaries think
it's embarrassing
to get caught they go to great lengths
to make sure
that whatever they're doing in this
space
doesn't get caught or if it's caught it
cannot be attributed back to them
however in the cases
where they have been caught or when
there's been leaks about these
capabilities from western intelligence
agencies i think they've been quite
happy to take the credit because that
has given them the deterrence that they
can't get any other way
but like i said
it's unlikely that governments would be
voluntarily getting deterrence by
showing their weapons because then they
are giving the tools to their enemies
because these weapons
can be copied and deployed unlike any
other real world weapons
but actually the intelligence behind the
ones that are using the tools
you are not giving away them
and if you are going to show the
intelligence it's like doing the parades
so they are holding back to old
old-school deterrent
ways kind of
couldn't it be the case
certainly countries can show the end
results of what they have accomplished
with these tools but that's a different
story that's not really getting
deterrence from the weapons it's getting
deterrence from things you can do
and that's
we cannot compare the way we build
deterrence with real world weapons so
the way we build deterrence with cyber
weapons
i don't think we'll see a day where
countries are voluntarily showing the
technical details
of their cyber weapons it wouldn't it
would make no sense
i think
thank you
a ctf competition would be
a
military parade of the cyber domain
because you're not showing the result
you're not showing a certain exploit but
you're showing the capability of
creating
such an exploit so what you're saying is
that finland got a bit of deterrence
when our finnish team won the locked
shields rehearsal
something like that
we'll take it thank you
you're very welcome yeah
yeah us
okay any more questions
do you have any more questions i was
thinking something but you caught me of
course like
who solves this first you guys are the
russians
do you think that is
um
yeah i'm curious do have you heard
anything about how much the you know
finland is looking to expand its cyber
capabilities now that you know nato is
on the doorstep or nato is
becoming part of reality
we just got a
major improvement in budgets
to be put into this area
so yeah we are looking to improve our
capabilities here definitely
but that's just
that's all we know for so far but
finally we are seeing the kind of
budgets we should have been seeing
years ago so
that's the way you're flexing the
muscles as well it is yes yeah very true
good
okay thank you very much thank you