all right hello everyone we're uh here
at SEC T it's uh Friday and uh the
second day and the second day everyone
is very uh tired tired yeah but we
enjoyed an awesome talk by you you see
and uh as always a lot of energy yeah
thank you and it was like drinking from
a fire hose so I'm I'm gonna have to
look at on your GitHub page because
there was so much I wanted it was like I
everything is public exactly enjoy the
ride that's a really good one yeah yeah
it's like that's how I started
deliberately by saying you know there's
going to be a lot of stuff so just relax
understand what you see enjoy the ride
but because all the code and the slides
is already on GitHub so yeah no don't
don't try to write anything or just uh
listen and enjoy it yeah yeah but but I
mean the the take I'd say from this
um is really as a as a blue team or is
like what
how should we go about you know
protecting against this well it's you
know I have a big heart for Bluetooth
blue teamers and I think like a retina
but my heart is with the blue team and
uh to be honest I think really to be a
good blue team it's much more difficult
than a pen tester or retina to be honest
uh it's it's a really tough job and it
gets tougher with the years and we need
good people there and in general
especially when you think about defenses
uh they are not binary right you just
the only thing you can measure is time
time to detect time to protect time to
respond Etc and to narrow it down all
the time and this requires good people
good procedures baselines hardening even
before products because as you can see
all the time with breaches and as you
could see also in this presentation it's
very easy to bypass a lot of security
products as an industry and
it's very challenging for the blue
teamers in terms of Powershell what you
saw here like you saw there are defenses
but there are easily bypassed I would
say you don't have to try to block
Powershell it's not the right attitude
you have to be to able to manage it so
try to just find anomalies in the actual
code running on the machines because the
block it will not work as you saw yeah
you can run it in so many different ways
millions of variants yeah so
you showed me lots of crazy stuff with a
little bit
seeming gopher mode but this was more
remember this was more General like yes
or powershello not focused on a specific
attack area right so
um what your your title was about
converting people from back yeah yeah
and you sure converted me yeah
I wouldn't lose uh you know I wouldn't
stop using uh bash or shell scripts or
whatever the idea was maybe to tease a
bit just for people to listen because if
you say it's a cool session on partial
maybe people will not be interested but
yeah yeah
it will make you think yeah yeah and to
be honest I think and I got some
feedback when I came down you know it
kind of worked because I wanted people
to learn to appreciate Powershell
differently both as a retina or blue
timel and I think it it worked hopefully
to see the power playing around with
power Linux Linux yes I did quite a lot
and how is that though is it you have to
load a lot of modules how does it even
work no you just install it on it's on
GitHub you just clone it uh run it yeah
it works pretty straightforward
yeah I had no I know yeah I've never
started it I just saw it
Linux I would use it uh for uh a bunch
of things that require me to do like
extensive piping like pipe pipe to pipe
that I need to keep the object yeah
instead of parsing text which is cool
you can also always do it on Linux but
with Powershell you actually get objects
so you can convert except you can just
take the exact information you want very
easily in uh sure in less code yeah that
makes sense the power of objects so it's
like python so it has objects it's cool
but it's very intuitive like bash so
LSPs curl you don't have to write a lot
of code you know to access to be
proficient yeah yeah that's pretty cool
yeah
because I I think many people like me
feel that when you
when you when you first meet Powershell
that
it's strange and weird and and it's not
like the things you know before
uh so so there's a little bit uh for you
uh who we can assume with a power user
at Powershell now uh does it start to
come natural because because I think
it's very much an inversion inversion of
how you think about scripting when you
you know the
the beginning is uh is a bit hard for
some people also for me it wasn't
totally intuitive because the syntax in
the beginning takes time it takes time
to get used to how Microsoft built the
sit next because it's like a mix of uh
Pearl and Java I don't know like you
have the curly brackets and you have
dollar underscore like yeah Pearl for
each loops and it's like a mix colon
colon yeah it's like a bit of every
language but I think I uh at some early
point I I looked at it as an advantage
so although partial is the new kid in
the block of scripting it's fairly new
but it had the time to learn from other
languages so it took like the best
Concepts from every language yeah and
tried
success
but it tried to make like a super sort
of shell I would say it's good to know
it yeah I it doesn't have to replace
anything you know on the contrary it's
just another very strong scripting
language especially on Windows but not
only on Linux also I did really cool
stuff with it
cool so if you want to know more about
you where can you where can they find
more about me yeah
all my awesome profile on the Internet
is about music so that's true that's
actually really cool when you look uh
for my name on data you just find videos
of me playing uh in rock festivals and
playing weird guitars that I built uh
buzukita it's an instrument I invented
it's like a Greek mandolin with the
electric guitar and a acoustic guitar in
one body in high quality so that's all
you see in Google but if you look quite
closely then you find the GitHub and you
find okay it does something with
security also but but the Rockstar team
comes first yeah I think that's very
cool yeah it's a good balance you know
it's at the end like both really
creative I would say yeah yeah yeah many
people in infosec I find I see all the
time are have this mix of some form of
Art and a lot of musicians uh with uh
you know coding and cyber security and
sure I think that this really uh goes
well together yeah
we're not going to keep you from lunch
thank you for taking the time to talk to
us thank you pleasure to have you yeah
hope to see you in Gothenburg yep we
hope we hope to come back yeah it was
great thank you thank you