hi everyone we're live almost at SEC T
conference and we're still here at the
community night and uh right now we have
homework with us who gave a talk on sort
of eavesdropping on live streams or
maybe not live streams but streams from
from different streaming services uh
yeah and I saw the end of your talk and
my understanding is you presented magic
right that's that's the core idea here
you take something which is encrypted
yeah and you have some sort of reference
library
somehow you recognize when the same
stuff is transmitted
churches so basically what we do is that
so you can talk about live streams
because the streams are live
you eavesdrops them exactly yeah and
then you can recognize what what is
trimmed even though the streams
themselves are encrypted and this is
because of the protocols the protocol
that is used to download the stream
leaves some traces they leave some small
pieces here and there and thanks to
those pieces then you can retrieve the
video and there is
is this like a compression on Rachael
Laura or what what but what's what's the
what is it you actually are recognizing
you you recognize in this work that I
presented today it was to recognize the
title to recognize what what the video
is about yeah you can recognize a bit
more because you also know exactly where
in the video you are so basically you
can even reproduce What what is
currently being watched exactly at the
second
the other work that we are doing where
you can also classify so you can also
not recognize only the video but you can
also say what is it about
an events of our encrypted yeah so
that's that is so cool could you could
you I'm sorry to interrupt her but could
you sort of just elaborate on where
where there could be a a use for this
technology
so acceptance buying on your girlfriend
or you know everyone wants to do that
yeah yeah
um so that's what I try to highlight uh
at the end of the talk so you can either
be on the on the good guy side on the on
the bad guy side and the good guys side
I would say imagine that
um especially for example not only the
identification but classification you
are recording uh traces from Facebook
and you can maybe
um find out when people are watching
Terror videos yeah talks about illegal
content and this when you find out then
you want to cancel it that's a really
big deal on Facebook you want to stop
people watching illegal content that's
really something we want to do but you
can also think of the bad guys that
might use that to find out when you are
watching something that is against the
government yeah then I have to say then
you're in in between what we are trying
to show is that this is possible then
it's up to whoever is is making this
possible to to stop you know to update
the protocols cool yes you need to
because you're finding some sort of work
right there's
there's something like if a length or a
killer or we I
I'll let you explain in a second what
what the actual Oracle techniques or
what what it actually because you told
us that it's the it's related to a
titles and things like that yeah uh but
uh
I kind of lost my point here but but
uh yeah like what what would be the
obvious fixes against these attacks that
that's a really good question actually I
think there is not a really obvious
simple fix otherwise it would have
already be done somehow usually against
what what type of attacks that's what we
call
um in academics like passive Network
attacks that means that you are
passively listening exactly you are just
listening so somehow they are really
almost invisible to to contact to at
least to detect because you are not
interacting with the network you are
just listening so you cannot see they
are there
uh even though they can they can do some
heavy damages so how can you counter
them the basic techniques usually it's
you are trying to kind of Shuffle to try
to hide both side channels that you are
yeah giving away in choices the two main
side channels is the time of your
packets and the size of your packets the
only thing is that with the attack we've
shown
it is difficult to contact by just
changing these two main side channels
because the packet size is almost always
the same with streaming yeah it's almost
near the maximum size and when you look
at the time even if you randomize the
time of your packets they they're maybe
send like a little bit later
it still since the video is streamed
within like four seconds yeah this makes
me it's a hard real-time protocol
exactly exactly so except if we are
going somewhere where a protocol will
stream the video in kind of constant
bitrate where everyone's second there
will be the same number of bytes
then it will solve the problem but then
the compression will not be as good so
it's always a compromise yeah I think it
hasn't been like
predecessors to voice over iepy almost
kind of can reconstruct simple sounds
based on
detecting silences or something like
like that
um so uh
again I'm sorry sorry Peter for
interrupting but I'm really curious what
what what got you into researching this
that's that's a really good question I
think I think the very first
uh article I read was not a published
article it was like a media it was about
these guys that actually did something
very similar on Netflix
and I just read that and I thought wow
that's impressive yeah can we do it on
other services and I look around and it
was not really it doesn't be look for
that much and then I thought okay I'll
give that to some students and see if
that works if if that was five years ago
this attack that it has been shown yeah
and it's still working now so I think
it's maybe time to update this Dash
protocol
yeah so you are
your attack was talking about Dash
protocol yeah
um so an idiot's going to dash what's
what's the difference between
Dash and whatever else I'm not an expert
in streaming really but I mean in in
dash since you divide the video in small
chunks yep each chunk has a fixed size
as a size that corresponds to whichever
encoding you are using to encode that
chunk of the video I mean this this
protocol I mean uh they didn't think
about it maybe there was five years ago
that was before gdpr Etc maybe they
didn't think already that we cannot make
a protocol that gives so much precise
information about the video because they
were they were probably looking at
optimizing performance and things like
that
so it's very good in terms of how much
how it adapts to the bandwidth it's
really reactive all the smartness is at
the client so that means that it's
really versatile as a product as a
protocol it's just that it really gives
really precise information about the
video
all right
but would this be slightly similar to
like the an MPEG stream or something
yeah the dash protocol lower so the
difference is that when you have an MPX
stream let's like it's not stream it's
just you are watching a MPEG video on
your computer usually it will be
compressed right with a certain encoding
a certain codec
the the usual codec that we are using
now they are very good at compressing
videos what they use what what is called
viable bitrate so that means that they
will not use the same number of diets
for one second if you have one second of
black screen or one second of heavy
action you can think that one second of
black screen I can use really alone
number of bytes yes of course and heavy
action I will use a high higher than the
average
so the thing is that if you want to
compress wealthy videos you need to use
these viable bitrates so sometimes
increase sometimes decrease and that is
what Dash is leaking basically it's
looking even worse of the video itself
the video itself if you look every
second you will see this variable bit
rate but if you look every second four
seconds is even worse because the
difference are a bit bigger oh yeah all
right
yeah
um so counter measures are basically
redesigned the protocol yes now there
are protocols I think I think they will
take over soon in a couple of years so
we might not hear of this attack but I
know they also attack on both other
protocols because of this viable bit
rate so even if you have other network
protocol you still have this and
I don't know it's a compromise will you
compromise how much data you will have
to download to have this extra privacy
that's that's you know that's that's the
I'm sorry we're just backing it up yeah
right but uh I mean that that's the
compromise you need to take into account
you have to weigh a
privacy issue
on the same scale as your your bandwidth
issue basically I think that's that's
maybe the topic for the next
five or to ten years is like how much
performance are we willing to like
sacrifice to sacrifice to get better
privacy because because a lot of privacy
yeah right right
we don't imagine there at least when
we're Sweden we don't imagine an attack
even interested in this but but let's
say
but of course it's much more interesting
if we assume that you are in some other
place where it might but but let's say
like the hardest protocol to attack
where you couldn't inspect this without
let's say without uh
when it's encrypted then
you would want constant bit rate
and you would want constant size for
metadata so it doesn't
those leaks either I mean if it's like I
guess I'm sorry too but it's like
thwarting any any side Channel you need
to you know make everything look the
same kind of that's completely true
that's probably true but you you got a
point basically there are two ways of
making the attack either harder to
reproduce or try it like this constant
language
so harder to reproduce you said yeah
that's true that this attack is also
made easier because the dash protocol
you have this manifest file that gives a
lot of information where to retrieve the
information and then you can build this
database if you didn't have such file
where all the information is contained
it's just slower it just you will take
more time to find all the information
you need that's true for the constant
bit rate that will be something like
okay
that way I will not leak information
that would be good but the only problem
is for sure is that you will make
so either one option is that you
compress the video with a constant bit
rate so that will be you will use more
space you will use more data are you
willing to use more data to download
your videos
thinking that most people don't care
maybe about if someone else is watching
either there might be techniques that
that are currently investigated where
you can have a variable bit rate but the
constant bit rate will be on the on the
protocol so imagine that Network
protocol gives you not four seconds of
video but for like 4 000 bytes yes
whichever that means of video and then
it's the client and that will make
protocol much more complex because the
client will have not only to handle the
download but also to download to handle
like the playback yes you'd have to have
a much larger buffer probably exactly
exactly you have to sacrifice something
yeah
I think you mentioned students
right yeah so uh
you're working at the as a what what's
your what's your date job yeah yeah sure
so I'm assistant professor so that means
I'm giving lectures that's part of my
job as a teacher the other part is as a
researcher so this work I presented
today I have to thank the sixth unions
that did a great bashful disease so I
supervise them I gave them topic and
then they develop this tool so all of
this that I present today is thanks to
them of course cool so they are working
at Charles that's in Gothenburg yeah
yeah the best but that's why we asked
Universe of course of course my old alma
mater of course yeah
great well uh who Mike it was awesome
that you could take this uh this time to
to talk to us and that was really great
actually yeah I hope you enjoy the rest
of the conference yeah I hope so too
yeah
great talking to you yeah thank you very
much thank you thank you