all right welcome to uh the first
interview uh of uh the the first day of
uh secti uh we did some interviews
yesterday uh at the community at the
community night but but this is the
first real one and we have trouble here
and we just came off the stage uh
opening up SEC T
2022. in a true hacker manner yes
tinkering yeah and hopefully uh you know
hopefully a fun talk to you folks uh uh
thinking about uh security and reverse
engineering yeah not there's no uh uh no
world change in zero days got dropped
this was just a a fun uh thing something
to do with your home appliances and
classic Voyage board
yes yes exactly
um uh apparently uh there might have
been people from uh from the uh yeah the
vendors in the audience so that's pretty
fun I'm hoping to meet up with them and
Shout out later yeah cool
so you were you were sort of reaching
out a ham and saying you know I'd like
to see this you know become part of the
their their official offering and I I
think that's uh that's really cool I
think you know a lot of a lot of
companies would probably benefit from
making this available
and it's also something where uh the the
the people who are building uh Smart
Homes and doing home automation are
frankly nerds yes yeah and they're going
to be the early adopters who are who
will want to who would be interested in
hey there is a local uh rest API that I
can use to talk to my Appliance that's
actually a selling point for a small
percentage of the population yes but yes
I think yeah no but like a I don't know
like in Sweden nowadays the electric
bill is really really expensive so home
automation and monitoring of appliances
such as this is actually a thing now
like it's on the right like home
assistant like the open source home
assistant project has so many new
adopters you can see how many that
clones the Red Bulls and ESP home or
test mode that is like this open source
firmware those are a huge stream there
so I totally agree that that should be a
thing where you're able to sort of
integrate with a rest API or be able to
put an open source firmware on there in
order to serve your purpose right right
and the
um uh the the energy prices are also
really a driver for things like the uh
the power aware scheduling sure to say
let's not start the dishwasher Intel
power is cheap or available let's not
run the dishwasher while we're also
running the dryer these are things that
are fairly easy to do uh in in a home
automation system but are very
challenging to do in the vendor provided
apps especially if you have a dishwasher
from one vendor and a laundry from
another and the heater or the the what
the
water heater yeah or whatever you want
to so that's pretty cool and I think the
the arrow that is just getting started
like to be self-sufficient and be your
own producer and like like benefiting of
these spot prices when it's cheap you do
the laundry it's pretty cool so it's
actually you're you're you're in perfect
timing I guess for this I I think
there's a lot of interest yeah and you
know the uh the other thing that I think
is is really uh underrepresented in a
lot of the um home automation is the
accessibility aspect yeah the fact that
uh not everyone can can see a um a touch
screen and interact with it but all of
these devices are now coming with um you
know with capsense buttons everywhere
that you have to that sometimes change
their function yeah so being able to
build uh customized devices that then
interact with a wide variety of systems
I think that's very useful yeah I
thought that was a really nice nice take
on on the reasoning why you wouldn't
want to do something like this
because the the accessibility
it will I mean limit some people from
buying an appliance because they might
have a you know problem with their
eyesight or or something like that and
being able to to build a sort of a
control panel for them uh that's that's
pretty that's a cool aspect as well no
but I I'm guilty of that like when I
pick out a new Appliance in my home I
try to see if there is a rest API it
doesn't have to be on the actual Cloud
devices but can I Shane it so I can make
have like for example home assistant do
the queries yes and sort of run the app
but in a different context so that is
one way of going but this is this is I
think is should be an opt-in or out
thing do you want to do you want to
integrate to your own
um sort of thing great that will be an
awesome feature to have because
like
in aspects of security and breaking the
device that should not be the case
because you should be binary on which
functions you're able to sort of run you
can't put the centrifuge more than the X
amount of blah blah blah yes yes
apparently like you know what I'm going
like yeah it could be like you can build
your own integration using the
functionality as it's intended of course
you can break stuff then I think that
would be a cool way of doing it because
no one does that right and something you
mentioned earlier about you want to be
able to install your own firmware on
devices so things like tesmoto make that
possible with some sorts of things and
you know with uh with devices that have
large Motors or you know uh um uh
kilowatt sort of capabilities sometimes
we we might say well maybe we don't want
to install our own firmware there quite
yet yeah
um like yeah because things can actually
happen like reverse polarity and like
the models start to spin in the wrong
direction or yeah yeah it's shifting and
that could be exactly so they're like so
I I really like uh the ability to put my
own firmware on devices
um you know so many of my projects are
about that yeah right yeah the the
micropython for Ikea light bulbs
completely replaces the Ikea firmware
yeah 100 of it
um but the worst uh you can do is make
the light turn on and off that it's
there's really no yeah it's not getting
um uh three kilowatts of power coming
through there
um a heater on the other hand could
potentially yes exactly that
um and then in other cases like on the
uh the Magic Lantern firmware for the
Canon cameras there I didn't want to
replace the Canon firmware because it
did 95 of what I needed I just wanted to
make some small tweaks to make them
slightly more suited for what I needed
is that how it worked so it's sort of a
side card thing yes okay so you run it
on a memory card and then you have the
native ah yes okay so it was a
replacement but it isn't it it doesn't
replace sound okay so it um uh so it
actually uh the can the camera will boot
uh off the memory card yeah um and then
the Magic Lantern firmware uh hooks uh
uh some functions in the real firmware
and then jumps into into the real
firmware and then when when the firmware
reaches that stage during its
initialization this extra user code gets
called that then can create threads it
can create GUI elements it can interact
with the buttons and the hardware but
all of the uh the the OEM firmware is
still there in ROM unchanged that's
pretty cool that's cool yeah because
yeah they've done really good work on a
lot of it and now I know Peter I ran it
a couple of years ago that he's not in
screen but yeah the the more uh beard
videographer yeah yeah he has all the
stuff
yeah here he is now now there he is
yeah
um so you know I think there's there's a
um there's a whole spectrum of you know
completely open source firmware on the
device to uh running
um you know alongside the closed
firmware to totally close
now frankly I would love if uh if if
things like the menuing system on the
dishwasher and whatnot were um uh
perhaps fixable
um you know there's not so much in the
dishwasher but the uh the oven has some
frustrations where I would really like
to be able to add my own
menu elements yeah and right now I don't
have code execution on the device my
talk is purely about the communication
protocol but you know maybe uh do you
have foreign
so Siemens has uh they have a hack so
you're like a thing in Sweden is now
everyone is into pizza and you need
you've got to do a nice Pizza you need
to have a stone or a cast iron plate in
your oven yes but you want as high
temperature as possible and these uh new
fairly new ovens have uh what is it
called like the English word I don't
know but it's sort of Peter Liz where
you sort of it's super hot as a cleaning
functions
had it's a higher setting that you're
able to put on when you're going to make
your pizza right right but then some
smart person out there figured out how
you can enable the since the function of
burning everything off in the in the
oven is there how you can hack it so you
can get it a lot warmer which is perfect
for the pizza mode so that is actually a
hack out there there is a combination
that you have to do oh so you've got to
do up up down left right jump start
exactly like exactly that but so it's a
sheet code on your Siemens oven and it
actually works it's pretty cool but it
that's that's likely the same idea you
like this like body warranty but it is a
cool
to function someone is I need to have
this and they spend time figuring it out
but I think I think it's it's like you
know there's this this movement towards
you want to own your devices you want to
be in control you don't want your device
to be controlled by the cloud for
instance yeah and uh no but I think like
when privacy concepts are getting more
out there people know how data
harvesting or user data is actually
collected and sold yeah I think uh this
will be a tournament where but I guess
like we as sort of nerds or Geeks in
this field we already see that in home
automation uh when home automation is
not proprietary anymore we have the open
source stuff and we see like there is a
lot of adopters there so I think this
will sort of I think this is a natural
path I think
right right and the the other aspect of
um of this sort of openness is it's
easier to repair yeah and it's easier to
keep things going and yeah yeah as we
look at um sort of this desire to keep
uh appliances running longer to be able
to reduce the amount of E-Waste that
we're putting into the system
um that's actually a valid uh valid
point as well I didn't even think about
it E-Waste is actually probably a really
sound thing for the environment it's
just a screen that died so yeah good
yeah I've been checking both yeah so
being able to um uh to adapt them to
different needs or to uh you know
prolong their use
um you know and not big appliances it's
maybe less of an issue most people keep
their their dishwashers in their ovens
for many years
um uh the the one that we bought again
because it has the auto Open Door uh
replacement that had been in our house
for 15 years so that's that's a pretty
good longevity that's a good longevity
compared to it compared to a phone
um but a lot of our dashboards are built
out of around the house are built out of
old Kindles or old phones that uh
because we can install our own firmware
that then we can interface with our own
home automation suddenly they don't go
into the e-way stream that they they
find new life and this is uh I think a
really good reason for for being able to
build 100 I I did like the whole Rabbit
Hole thing with dashboards in my home
now so I have like this tablets and in
our fully where everything is more or
less integrated more like a display
thing but then you can sort of see if
the doors are open if the dishwasher is
running if the car is charging yeah yeah
and it it's so much more convenient than
pulling the phone out to be like and
strolling through six different apps yes
right yes yeah I think it's pretty cool
and yeah I said it yesterday as well you
get so I get so excited being at a
conference like this because there is a
lot of like-minded people it gives you
so much energy if you don't feel that as
lonely as you do no but yeah
talking with my wife about this she's
like I don't want to hear this but this
is like a nice input guys yeah it's
really fun yeah my partner uh is is
fully sold on the uh all of the the
automations
um that they they help write the the
Python scripts and to be to be fair like
she was so against it
not it will never work it will break all
the time I just want it to work but now
she's like she actually likes it and
it's but it's not that nothing is
dependent on it but it does
here to have yeah so it's pretty cool
like yeah the yeah
she learns to like it cool well drama
thank you so much for taking the time oh
question Peter yeah yeah like this line
here you were running animal
enumeration
[Music]
and what it says that the dishwasher
supported TLS null with neural with null
yes there was that question came up uh
during the Q a as well and I didn't
notice that until I put the slide
together and I never uh because that
that can't be good for
that it's rubbish so I'm going to go
back uh um actually I I could ssh in to
I could uh yeah do the uh set up the
wire guard tunnel get into our home
network and then yeah
because it's interesting like does it
even work yeah or if but it should work
but the Integrity of it should be
terrible yeah right right non-existent
but let's also consider what is the
threat model here yeah you know
um a man in the middle something
this is the same thing being offered
with that uh yeah okay so that is not
tested
um although I also want to point out
that uh different models of the
appliances
um uh have HTTP interfaces instead of
https yeah
um but on the ones that are doing HTTP
they uh they are doing their own AES CBC
and hmac wrappers around all of the uh
the website
it's really good yeah yeah you say a day
yes yeah so it's not only CBC but yeah
decent German engineer it is you know we
can hope
we've seen a lot of times
it takes too much bite so let's just Pat
it with zeros because that's easier no
the the pattern algorithm looks good
yeah you know I'm uh they're doing
proper um
oh shoot I it's been a few months since
they they are doing yeah and uh overall
I I haven't actually seen any of the
code on the devices I haven't gotten
code execution on the appliances but all
of the stuff sort of around it makes me
feel that somebody who knew cryptography
at least looked at it and gave them some
advice we didn't ask this and I
the night but is it uh what kind of uh
of operating system is it have you
figured that one or is it a real-time
Roselle doesn't work oh uh is it oh I
should have I should have put a slide
about that um uh I don't know anything
about that but I do know uh
I think I think it's the their web
server is called nebula and I've been
meaning to do some searches to try to
see if that's like a an off-the-shelf
thing that they've bought or you know if
it's something maybe that they built
in-house I I don't know but that is the
um that one string is the only sort of
clue that I've seen as to what's inside
because Bush they do a lot of computers
like everyone that has sort of connected
into the car World know that they have
this amazing no not amazing amazingly
weird monolith structure with their
ecu's for example and that will be uh
would be like even if you get code
execution it will be terrible because it
will more or less be like a real-time OS
well my Canon camera stuff I I'm pretty
experienced yeah
like I would be like the the path of
reversing that and getting something
nice out of it is really hard if you
haven't looked at that yes yes they can
be
and especially because uh they're they
you can't look at the source code or
examples
um I I love pulling apart devices that
are running in Linux because uh I can
load that file system into uh into my
desktop machine I can poke at it and
typically Things are Written in a shell
scripts so it's something like oh my
channel is easy yeah
um yeah compared to yeah some uh rtos
that has to fit in 32 kilobytes of of uh
a flash that's a much more challenging
reverse engineering Target yeah and like
monolith structures where everything
just have their own sort of confined
space Enclave like here we do this and
then you can do telnet to this and here
we do that and blah blah it's really
hard to yeah yeah it is sort of
fascinating when you do get into the um
uh the static analysis with things like
ghidra
um you can almost start to identify
different groups inside the company that
wrote the different modules that there's
like style choices that that make it all
the way into the binary yeah that's
pretty cool um and so it's occasionally
uh I've seen things where I can
definitely say
this company bought a USB library from
someone they bought their fat file
system library from somebody else and
then they had two different teams you
know doing the GUI versus the threading
that's pretty cool so it's kind of cool
yeah
yeah but I guess that makes sense when
you looked at a lot of it like you see
like if you do like a graphical overview
or something and then you can sort of
see if how everything flows that would
be a lot different if you build file
systems a lot I guess they have a lot
more edge cases like if they're not sure
things and that would be sort of blocks
in your yes machine so that would be
visible that's pretty good that's pretty
cool yeah yeah and a lot of it shows up
like a lot of times they'll have like
different login libraries that they've
Linked In so you know the file systems
log in one way and the task management
logs in another way and so you can you
you get those sort of Clues that's
pretty cool yeah
okay yeah so let's let's wrap yeah um
thank you again for uh taking time to
talk to us and um enjoy the rest of the
conference yes it's wonderful to be uh
back in our Stockholm it's um after uh a
few years in the Netherlands um uh this
feels very three-dimensional yeah I
think I've climbed more Hills uh in in
the past day than I have in the past
three years yeah yeah in the Netherlands
you have to look for Hills really
swim up yep all right thank you very
much thank you