okay so we'll start our talk we are very
happy to be here again in Sweden
Stockholm sector the land of Vikings and
Ikea and today we will present how we
found the many vulnerabilities in
third-party drivers in Linux in a
colorful way
I'm Iran shimoni a security researcher
at cyberwork primarily focusing on the
Discovery and exploitation of local
privileges Collision bugs across via
operating systems and I really enjoy
Also drinking and mixing cocktails and
sometimes doing meditation can happen on
the same time hello everyone my name is
and I'm a vulnerability researcher at
several Labs focusing mainly on
operating system internals and except
playing with Colonel as I'm enjoying a
CrossFit
so let's see what we have on our menu
today we will start with the difference
between a research in open source based
closed Source after that we will have
some Linux kernel internals 101 enough
for us to understand the bugs but not
too much to make you fall asleep
after that we will go to a very
important piece in every privileged
escalation research to which privileged
part can I talk from on the unprivileged
later we will see how messing up with
the colors on your keyboards can affect
to bugs and lastly we will examine a new
mitigation in the Linux kernel that
greatly reduces the severity of buffer
overflow attacks from the potential of
privileged escalation to a mere denial
of service
so let's start closed Source base open
source
on the right we have the beautiful
penguin indicating the lovely operating
system of Linux and on the left we have
the nonso lovely Broken Window
indicating the operating system of
windows
so those are the two operating system we
will talk about we can also honorably
mention Mac which is kind of in between
between open source and a closed Source
because you can argue this new kernel is
open source but the rest is closed
source
so what is so special about closed
Source well
obviously we lack the code of it so in
order to understand what happens under
the hood we either need to execute it
which really doesn't add anything when
we talk about drivers or reverse
engineer the hell of it now in order to
reverse engineer and understand what
happens we need to have strong knowledge
of low level operating system and they
have the ability to have like to exploit
things which is a very tiresome
the action and it takes time the good
and the plus about it is that usually
those tend to be harder to exploit so
vendors pay nicer bug bounties as we
wrote compared to open source projects
the approach we are going forward in
this type of research is first we try to
gather every possible Intel over our
Target if for instance we try to find a
bug in the windows kernel grapher win42
cases that consists of several thousand
functions it will be impractical to
start with just reversing the binary so
every blog piece or talk about it is
greatly beneficial for the task later we
will try to find any possible code licks
now every version of the windows kernel
had code licks in its history so and
doing a patch diff between a decompiled
or disassembled output to the source
code even though if it could be a bit
dated is very helpful than just having
nothing
after that it's very important to Define
our Target very closely because it's
very easy to get spared away while doing
research like if you reverse engineer
you're familiar that we use start with
one function and one function leads to
100 functions and it's very important
for us to have a straight line at our
Target
so the way we do it is mostly via
reversing and also via fuzzing but we
will touch about fuzzing soon
and open source on the other hand of
course we have the source code we can
understand anything that actually
happens besides that we can use the
tools called Static analysis in order to
find low hanging fruit bugs and more and
lastly we can compile and add debugging
Snippets instrumentation into the code
that will help us in the exploitation
phase
now the first step of course you know
open source open source research is to
find the damn code via GitHub git or if
you use the dark technology called SVN
you can go there of course
now the second step is to run several
static analysis tools now those tools
are very beneficial because they can
help us remember they can help us find
memory corruption type of bugs divide by
zero integer overflow and underflow in a
pretty short time
additionally there are some Advanced
tools like code ql that allow you to
write Advanced queries to that treat
your database that treat your code as a
database and then you can really track
the data flow from one function to
another which is another great tool
after that we compile and build the open
source usually add in some debug
statement that give us Vision about the
state of the software in important parts
and lastly if we manage to actually find
a vulnerability in the code base there
are good chances these vulnerabilities
again can read away the way to other
products as well as you're probably
familiar developers are humans and
humans are a bit lazy and we copy code
from one project to another so once we
find the vulnerability we can probably
find it in different places and we will
see it
and now there is the question of fuzzing
if you are not familiar fuzzing usually
consists of generating input towards the
torrent function with some kind of
feedback mechanism that tracks the code
coverage code coverage basically is the
way the amount of paths you went into
the target software sounds fantastic
well one of the problem that it takes
time everyone who used fuzzer Let It Be
AFL leave fuzzer or C scholar is
familiar with the thing that it takes
time to cosmetize the fuzzer to your own
solution
one approach that is kind of in the
middle and the one that we used in this
research is the usage of a Dom fuzzer a
downforcer does not have any fancy
feedback mechanism it just tries many
input that we have some prior knowledge
about this software beforehand and it's
very useful in the case we know the
specifics of the target for instance we
know we need to go to a particular
function and we don't need really to
spread out the entire in the entire code
base
and of course if you have more time
several weeks or months you can use a
full-blown fuzzer and in some cases the
most advanced the more advanced project
you need to use a better fuzzer
so what are the main takeaways of Open
Source research and why it's a bit
easier we have endless examples that we
can learn from people in the community
are usually very supportive so we can
ask them about them people tend to focus
Less on open source of more low-hanging
fruits and those low-hanging fruits but
can be impactful as a very difficult bug
it really doesn't matter
you have the option to add a code into
the code base and compile it of course
making debug in life a lot easier
fuzzing is also easier because most of
the fuzzing revolves around
instrumentation and it's pretty out of
the box if you can debug the program
with adding code and lastly reverse
engineering is also easier because if
you have the source code and you have
the decompiled output and if the
compiler puts some Shenanigans inside of
it you can pretty much easily understand
what has been done
so maybe if you were here last year you
remember that we gave a talk about how
to find bugs in Windows drivers and
third parties using KFL but today we are
not going to talk to talk about Windows
we are going to talk about a specific
penguin
yeah so as you maybe have figured out
the penguin in the room is the Linux
kernel or my specifically Linux kernel
modules but to understand what Linux
kernel modules are all experts
understand the general architecture of
the Linux operating system
so most of the operating system are
divided into two mainly Parts the user
space and the kernel space the main
difference between them is that the
kernel space is the actually privileged
part of the operation system that can
interact with the hardware an example of
that could be when the user requests to
read a file from the disk the request
actually goes through the kernel which
then proceed to reach the data from the
disk and returns back to the user space
when installing an operating system like
Ubuntu you will get the kernel obviously
installed with it so if you're
installing Ubuntu for example you will
get the Linux kernel installed with it
but it doesn't mean that you cannot and
cannot update or cannot add
functionality to the kernel in runtime
adding functionality and currently
runtime it's done via kernel modules for
example you can add new hardware devices
supports a new kernel devices and new
keyboard devices USB and everything that
uses the hardware most likely will
require a driver to know how to interact
with it
so we've conducted our research focusing
on the Linux kernel because essentially
each bug in the kernel is critical due
to the fact that the kernel is always
privileged and one of the best places to
hunt for bugs in kernel are third-party
kernel modules because most of the time
they're less examined and are accessible
by restricted user
exploiting kernel models bug can lead to
the same impact as exploiting vulnerable
vulnerabilities in the kernel itself so
it can be exploited to add another
service or to a full local future
escalation for example
the way we've done it is by looking for
big third-party vendors and examining
their code which one of them was
openrazer so if you may know Razer is a
big peripheral Hardware vendor focusing
mainly on gaming gear and if you want to
interact with them in a Linux
environment you will most likely use the
open open razor software which is open
sourced
so it lets you to customize your
Hardware so for example lets you to
create a custom macros for your keyboard
custom RGB it even lets you to customize
RGB colors for your mag holder for
example which is amazing
and again it lets you to set different
DPI and every configuration that you may
think about
every type of Hardware device that you
can see here translate to an additional
driver that you have to load into the
kernel to interact with it which expands
greatly our attack surface
an example of what you can do with the
open the open razor will be
for example a
the great Swedish flag
one of the Prime things that we need to
understand while conducting a
vulnerability research is how we can
communicate between the not privileged
and the privileged part and in our case
how we can transfer data between the
user space and the kernel space
in Linux there are multi-paced ways to
do it which will go briefly over the
main ones
so first of all a kernel driver kernel
modules can implement the normal read
and write operation which then can be
accessed on an exposed file via the read
or write sysc codes
otherwise the kernel module can oops
okay otherwise the kernel module can
implement the ioctal API interface which
usually each functionality is
distinguished by the command parameter
this way is very nice to use when using
a non-generic functionality so basically
everything besides reading and just
writing normal data to the device
another way to do it is by using shared
memory between the users and the kernel
Space by doing this it will be the
fastest way of communication between the
user the kernel
Linux also allows you to use exposed
file on a virtual file system like csfs
for example this way is very nice to use
because most of the time each
functionality will be exposed on a
different file via this file system and
it's really nice to use it when you want
to interact with your kernel modules via
shell scripts because again interacting
and just writing and reading to files is
very easy
and lastly there's another way I wanted
to mention which is using the netlink
socket this is a really nice way way if
you don't want to just use files it's
just creating a net link type socket in
the kernel and then it can be using like
normal socket communication via the user
space
so how can we even communicate with our
devices
so if you we will use the Linux so first
of all we need to make sure that the
kernel modules are loaded into the
kernel this can be done by running LS
mode LS mode show us all the kernel
modules that are loaded into the kernel
when grabbing Razer will show us the
drivers
because open razor chose the VFS type of
filex or functionality exposed we need
to know what's the path of the exposed
file so to know that we need to make
sure what that we know what's the vendor
ID and what's the product ID of the
device this can be done by running lsusb
just have a note that Razer will always
raise us vendor ID will be always
hexa1532 and by running lsusb it will
show us all the connected devices via
OSB and we can now watch the product ID
and lastly we can read or write into the
exposed file for example if we're
echoing one which is just writing one
into the file called Matrix effect wave
it will trigger the implemented
functionality in the kernel module which
supposed to lastly
use the wave effect on the device so it
will do this and we can see it also here
all right so now that we know how we can
interact with the internal modules let's
go to the fun part of hunting bugs thank
you
so what are we after we after memory
corruption type of bugs and more
specifically null pointer dereference
arbitrary Point Energy reference any
kind of pointer dereferences but for
underflow and the classical familial
buffer overflow
now the potential places that we aim to
find them is that of copying data from
one way to another like in mem copy SDR
copy and so on and while doing the
reference operation without doing proper
checks about the point return values
beforehand
and let's introduce two very
actually famous terms source and things
so on the left we have Nikola Tesla the
inventor of the light bulb we found we
fought him the wooden B probably RGB
colors and we wouldn't be here thank you
so Props for him thank you
and on the right we have a sink
with blue color and so on
so the both the two approach that we use
in order to find vulnerabilities is
either go from the source to the target
from or from the target to The Source in
other words we first map where we can
enter where our payload from the user
enters to the kernel and then where the
target is for instance a vulnerable mem
copy operation
after that we do the other way around
from the mem copy operation we trace the
path into the source
in other words first we ask ourselves to
which function do we have access to from
unprivileged user next we try to
determine which arguments we have
control over and what affects them then
we will look for data copying operations
like the mem copy Str copy and pointer D
references any one of those operations
is a good place to look for a bug and
then what we do backward tracing we're
going back from the sync to the source
so we again look for all the vulnerable
operation we see how the arguments in
between are changed and then we
determine if the function is even
accessible while doing those two things
we are like grasping a stick in two
hands and going going into the middle
allowing us to have better understanding
if there is a vulnerability here that we
can exploit from under from a
non-privileged user so let's have an
example this is like a real example in
one of Fraser kernel models the function
is called razor comma extended metrics
set custom frame 2 and it's responsible
to change the lives of your keyboard
you can see that it receives an argument
called the war index the row of your
keyboard start column and stop column
also it receive RGB data which is the
color of the you know the thing you want
to change on your keyboard can you maybe
spot a vulnerability here
so a good place to look is the mem copy
instruction and we also need to know
that I didn't tell you that that the
report argument buffer is in the length
of 80 bytes
now there is the third parameter of the
mem copy instruction the raw length and
the row length is being calculated in
stop column plus one minus start column
times three
and you're probably familiar that the
max size of unsigned car is 255 bytes 2
to the power of 8 minus 1.
and while multiple it by 3 we get the
value of
765. now the way the mem copy
instruction works is that you copy the
first 80 bytes into the buffer and then
we have a lovely
685 bytes of overflow on the stack the
very classic stock overflow bug now that
itself is not enough like to escalate
into root or to run code in the kernel
but alongside another primitive of an
info leak for instance is enough to pass
every mitigation so we thought but short
about that now another vulnerable code
as we said earlier one code can carried
away to another project
this is the Razer report Razer chroma
miscuan row set custom frame function
and it has
suffers from the same bug and this
lovely function is responsible for this
very important device
so by having this mug holder it makes
you vulnerable
to the not of service attack and
privilege escalation ones in the kernel
so this metal fin can be hot it can be
called and it's most definitely
vulnerable to code
and lastly another place we found design
vulnerability in Razer chroma standard
metric set custom frame is for your
mouse to change the colors of your mouse
so the message here is
don't connect
things to your computer with cool colors
I don't know
now let's see a demo show in case that
so the first thing we do as we seen
earlier is running LSU USB
yeah papa LS USB
and we can see here that we have the
vendor ID and the product ID of Razer
let's run LS mode to see if it's indeed
loaded in memory
we can see the we have the Eraser
accessory here now let's present our
payload
it's a very simple preload we can see
here that we must have the vendor ID the
product ID the target function that we
send the payload into is Matrix custom
frame which is responsible to like this
nice thing we can see our buffer is
longer than 80 bytes and hopefully
if everything works we will crush the
kernel so let's try the moment of truth
no let's see what happened I know I know
I know
yeah one sec please
every time we reboot the machine we need
to change the number of the device and
now hopefully anything will work yeah
okay and we crush the kernel and we are
very happy about that
[Applause]
all right so uh during the exploit
development with the Carter a newly
added feature into the Linux kernel
which was a part of fortify Source
mitigation
fortify cells basically aims to detect
buffer overflow in compilation time and
to mitigate them in runtime an example
of frontal investigation could be when
using a mem copy operation with a
dynamic size
the 45 Source originally came from
jlipsy but got introduced into the Linux
kernel into multiple steps in yes which
will call them mods which introduce two
mods which we'll call them Mod 0 and mod
1.
mode 0 aims to detect buffer overflow
over an entire struct and mode 1 M to
detect buffer overflows even in specific
members on a struct let's have an
example
let's assume that we have this object
struct which has three members arguan
which is in size of two bytes an array
in the size of six bytes and another
member called the arc2 in a size of four
bytes followed by a memco app operation
on the Arrow buffer
if we compile our kernel model with
fortify Source enabled in mod 0 we can
indeed still overflow our buffer thus
overriding the data stored in arc2 but
if we run in 45 source with Mod 1 we
cannot overflow The Arc too thus much
safer
so let's see the example in our code
um I'm showing the disassemble code
because again this mitigation is
inserted in compilation time this is our
vulnerable main copy operation without
45 Source enabled as you can see there's
no any validation on row length thus we
can easily as you saw Crush but if we
compile the kernel module with 45 Source
enabled we can see that a check was
added that checking if indeed our row
length is bigger than the allowed copy
size into the buffer which here will be
0x for D and if indeed the size will be
bigger than the value we will call 45
Panic which will crash more safely the
driver
just have a note okay let's see the 45
Source history
so fortify source mitigations and first
introduced in the Linux kernel in kernel
version 4 is 4.13 we're mode zero again
for just checking an entire extract got
introduced for both Ester copy and mem
copy family of function
later on on kernel version 5.11 mod 1
got introduced for Str copy family
function but still Mod 0 was turned on
for mem copy of volume function very
recently in kernel version 5.18 mod 1
was turned on for both of them but still
the mem copy only had the compile time
mitigation so the runtime mitigation was
similarly enabled and very like last
week the random mitigation for mod 1 for
mem copy got introduced
again this mitigation only exists
currently in the Linux but again for
older version that you see here
exploiting buffer overflows in the
kernel is can still be exploited into
everything Beyond denial of service
all right after finding the
vulnerabilities we reported them to the
open source project with a fixing period
which was merged and released on the
same day multiple cves were assigned to
different abilities and we have couple
more under disclosure and a blog post
about this topic that goes more deeply
into the vulnerabilities and the 45
cells mitigation just published today so
I go check it out in saber rock labs
site
you may ask yourself what's next so last
year we've covered windows DC recovering
Linux and maybe next year we'll cover a
more upper-leash operating system or
more pinkish we don't know yet
thank you
feel free to ask any questions
please
sorry
how does it interact with our
vulnerability well the kernel model is
loaded
you have the open functions that you can
send actually the payload into that
change the color of the mouthful for
instance or the keyboard and that's it
it's like calling a function
any more questions from the audience
okay then thank you very much for the
presentation thank you
[Applause]