good so contrary to what you might
expect from the title this will not be a
funny talk you might say Chris why would
I expect that the title is also not
funny I would not argue with you so
we're all here on the seaside a
different seaside and since it's not
funny we'll start with the conclusions
so the main punch line is that seaside
512 gives you relatively little quantum
security beyond what is coming from the
cost quantumly evaluating it on a
uniform superposition so in particular
for example key recovery costs about 2
to the 16 such evaluations if you have
about a terabit of quantumly accessible
classical memories that's ordinary
memory that's in your laptop but you can
query in the superposition and I'll say
a little bit more about that later and
so when you run the numbers on this
assuming that the evaluation costs not
much more than for the best case the
best case distribution which is a
plausible assumption we think breaking
seaside 512 cost a fair bit less than 2
to the 64 t-gates and it therefore falls
well short of the claimed missed
category one quantum security level ok
so let's unpack this a little bit like
if the clicker going good okay so
seaside was proposed at Asia crypt last
year it's a nice ogyny based so-called
post quantum commutative group action it
follows in the framework of KO venice
from 97 the central object is this group
action involving an abelian group G and
a set Z and the action takes an element
from each of those and returns an
element of Z note that this has nothing
to do with other s ogyny based
cryptography like s ID h which use non
abelian groups and don't involve group
actions so all we have to the only thing
we have to say it today is this killer
app for this group action is a
diffie-hellman style key exchange they
have a public parameter Z and then each
party chooses a secret group element
applies the group action with that
element and Z and that becomes their
public key and then they can each
compute a common shared key in a very
much diffie-hellman style
what makes seaside particularly
attractive is it's a efficiency profile
so you have small keys pretty fast key
for parameters that were claimed to have
missed category 1 security which is that
it should be as hard as AES key search
to break oh and these must be old slides
that's 2 to the 170 divided by max depth
ticket logical quantum gates
there's also signature proposals which
have attractive communication so the
main way that people have considered
attacking cset quantumly is to do
seaside recovery that has given the
public key fund the secret key or
equivalent and it was shown in 2010 that
this actually reduces to a hidden shift
problem on the group and in fact that
problem had been considered all the way
back in 2003 by Cooper burg there's
three main ingredients to the algorithms
first there's an Oracle that outputs
these random labelled quantum states by
evaluating the action on those uniform
superposition then there's some kind of
sieve algorithm which combines these
labelled States in a way to generate
more favorable States and then once the
states become very favorable you apply
some kind of measurement to recover
information about the hidden shift and
there's three classes of sieve
algorithms the first is Cooper Berg's
original which gives you two to the
order n Oracle calls and qubits reg have
improved the amount of space to down to
polynomial but increase the number of
Oracle calls that were required and then
interestingly Cooper burg give a
follow-up algorithm which gets you back
to 2 to the order root n Oracle calls
and classical bits of RAM which is
quantumly accessible means you can query
it in superposition even the RAM is
holding in classical bits Cooper burg
call this the collimation sieve or sisa
for short and it's assumes the prior two
algorithms and offers more algorithmic
trade-offs which we will exploit so
that's all asymptotic stuff but what
about concrete security so the prior
estimates for seaside 512 come from
costing the Oracle which was done in
Europe year and they gave a cost for
evaluating on a somewhat non-uniform
superposition but there's been recent
work we expect a similar cost for
uniform superposition we're not
concerned with the cost of the Oracle
too much we won't address that in this
work but we're looking at the SIF cost
so the original Seaside paper used revs
low space algorithm to
estimate about two to the sixty-two
Oracle calls and that's where that's
what allowed them to set the parameters
as they did thinking for aiming for NIST
level one this work from the last year
went back to Cooper Berg's original
algorithm and dramatically reduced the
number of Oracle close to about two to
the 32 but then quite a few cubits are
required for that so what about the
third algorithm Cooper Berg's
one that improves the previous two well
it turns out there was no prior work
looking at that so that's where we come
in and we look at this so we're going to
improve practically Cooper Berg's
quantum algorithm see sieve algorithm
and analyze it in the context see side
parameters this is a summary of the
various improvements I just want to
emphasize the final item which is that
we give code and actually runs
simulations of this this quantum
algorithm it's actually pseudo-classical
you can simulate almost all of it and
then just fake one little part of it and
actually run the run the thing on a
regular computer and we run it on
reporters all the way up to the real
seaside group order and here are the
final results the number of Oracle calls
can be brought down to something like
two to the 14 with with completely
reasonable amounts of classical memory
moreover the memory and be accessed
quantumly with existing methods using
quantum computation that's much lower
than the rest of the attack so this is
the is kind of the takeaway point I will
jump back through the final conclusions
the paper is available on ePrint and you
can download the code and run it very
easily at this location
[Applause]