my name is Jung Mazzone and today I am
gonna shoot an ultimate about parameter
choices of round 5 round white scheme is
a fabric Ian Christian and King
capsulation mechanism scheme based on
running with rounding which is defined
by following this is one of land to
candidate of NIST pqc standardization
and it it has unique feature that usage
of sparse and ternary secret vectors as
first means that the secret vector has
low Hamming weight and ternary means the
components consist of plus minus 1 and 0
like other lattice faced cryptography
each choice choose parameters by Alltech
algorithms and they considered three
attack algorithms the first one is the
primer attack and the hybrid tech and
the rusty Studdard attack but recently I
read their specification document and
notice that the Douro tag is not
correctly considered in their forums a
choice and as I saw the latest version
of document in their website I modified
the public LW estimator of a rich header
and we produced their furniture choice
and also operates
duratec and I also remote would like to
remark that I sent an email to around 5
team to improve this and they leap right
to me they are already aware of this and
they are trying to update the parameter
according to this and they gave some bit
at the bit security estimation in
star-shaped one so you can see that the
that should have one to eight bits
security cannot enjoy the crime stick
whatever this is table 1 and or 192 and
to five six
[Applause]