hi I'm Nicolas I'm sure to talk about
ground complexity of Byzantine
agreements this is the joint work with
Jean Cohen if the Hytner Matano london
alex subordinates he so what's a
Byzantine agreement it's the distributed
the tasks such that every party holds an
input bits and the parties are required
to agree on the same output bits and
there's an additional security
requirement that states that at least
one party should output its own output
bits so in this work we considered the
we wanted to bound the probability of
halting after one or two rounds and the
reason we aimed at for one or two rounds
is that three rounds is essentially
optimal so what do we show we show that
for be a protocols if there's security
threshold is something like n over three
meaning that at at most n over three
parties are corrupt then the halting
probability after one round is
vanishingly small and the halting
probability after realm two is far away
from one in addition we show that for
most ba protocols and under some
computer toriel assumption that
conjecture actually that I will that I'm
not going to discuss the halting
probability is also vanishingly small
after the second round so to show this
result we follow the classic blueprint
for deterministic termination meaning
that we considered a bunch of a sequence
of executions such that the input
configuration at the ends of this
execution gives you different output
bits and we show that there is an attack
for adjacent executions such that these
executions are indistinguishable for the
honest parties however for randomized
protocols this argument fails because
the randomness can be used to
distinguish
between these between adjacent
executions so to remedy this what we
propose as a solution is to abort some
parties in order to decouple the
randomness from the outputs this attack
gives rise to a nice of parametric type
inequality we managed to prove this
inequality for some limited cases which
reduce to the famous KKL the theorem and
frequence janta theorem but the general
case we left as an open problem so the
paper is available online thank you
[Applause]