hi everyone so I'm excited to be here
tonight to bring you the thrilling
sequel to my co-authors previous work
the crypto chickens cross the road
this is joint work with my advisor
Jonathan Katz and our lovely
collaborator Julian laughs okay so
synchronous consensus with asynchronous
fallback the crypto chickens go to the
beach alright so the chicken
cryptographers Club is deciding whether
to take a trip to the beach and now when
you or I go to the beach maybe the worst
thing that can happen is that you forget
your sunscreen or a seagull steals your
french fries but the chickens have to be
extra careful because they are always at
risk of being attacked by wily foxes so
either all of the chickens should go so
that they have strength in numbers and
they can fend off attacks from the foxes
where they should all stay home where
they'll be safe in their coops so the
chickens set out organizing their trip
by sending emails to the end members of
the club mailing lists
unfortunately they know from experience
that the mailing list may have been
infiltrated by up to F foxes or faults
being cryptographers they decide to use
a synchronous Byzantine Agreement
protocol to decide whether to go to the
beach
because of course these protocols have
the property that they ensure
consistency that either all chickens
decide to go or all chickens decide to
stay home as long as there are not too
many foxes that have snuck their way
onto the mailing list so they select a
protocol that tolerates the optimal
number of Fox spies F less than n over 2
assuming of course that the chickens
have a properly configured PKI
as if the chickens task was not
difficult enough they soon faced another
roadblock one of the email server admins
is also a fox so sometimes the chickens
find that their emails have been delayed
or reordered while at other times
everything seems to work normally so
they have no way of knowing on the day
that they are trying to plan this trip
to the beach whether or not the emails
will go through as they expect so they
know that they could use an asynchronous
Byzantine Agreement protocol of course
which would whether any unpredictable
network delays however these protocols
can only tolerate up to n over 3 foxes
as opposed to the optimal and
to tolerated by asynchronous protocol
okay can the chickens devised a protocol
that defends against FS greater than or
equal to n over three foxes when the
network is synchronous but still
withstands some F a greater than zero
foxes when the network is asynchronous
and because these slides do not have my
clever animations the answer is already
in front of you yes our result shows
that it is possible if and only if two
FS plus FA is less than n so the
chickens had a lovely day at the beach
and they all lived happily ever after
using our protocol and I see that this
has not been updated to reflect the fact
that just yesterday I woke up to an
email that this will be appearing at TCC
so please come and learn more about our
clever chickens
[Applause]