yeah definitely
that what this is and me too until I
discovered it so we click yes then we
click physics many centuries older
history in some ways they had theories
and prints sepia in the 17th century and
they have been looking for the grand
unified theory for centuries and in
Switzerland there is something that
makes roar de neri discoveries on this
but it's not the case that the
physicists have succeeded so far because
there is probably perhaps in the eyes of
some still a long way to go until they
have a grand unified theory and of
course for some people here this is
actually good news because until physics
knows everything we can still rely on
RSA and everything else because he
hadn't figured out how to build a
quantum computer yet nevertheless I
didn't want to talk about the grand
unified theory in physics I want to talk
about the grand unified theory of
cryptology and so you've certainly seen
a lot of work on this in our field in
the past there is lots of general
constructions Universal models and
whatnot generic systems and proofs and
models and the simple result is that's
why I'm standing here because I
discovered what this is that's you every
one of you here makes up cryptography
because without people without you and
us there wouldn't be any crypto and this
is us somewhere in Australia at an Asia
crypt conference we even managed to move
Asia to Australia and so the only thing
I wanted to mention here was that is
your needs your support and there is an
is your election coming up in this year
so go to the website and look at the
procedure and that at this time we're in
the nomination phase thank you
you