hello everyone welcome to bci las vegas
back in person
um i just say a few words uh first of
all i want to say uh thanks to our
sponsors uh diamond sponsor
lastpass and palo alto networks as well
as our gold sponsors i just named three
here amazon envision and blue cat
a little bit of housekeeping
please silence your cell phones
the talk is being recorded it'll be
available on youtube we also streaming
live so uh you know make it make it nice
here
if we have questions at the end
make sure that you come closer to the
podium we don't have microphone in the
room so the presenter can hear you
repeat the question for the stream and
answer it
um
picture policy
you should know by now besides a strict
policy for taking pictures make sure
that you have explicit content from
everybody in the frame should you take
pictures
keep your mask at all the time
before i introduce brad here vladimir
turkey how many people can speak french
okay so we'll do it in english but it's
just because it's you so vladimir is
going to talk about a certain form of
pollution from what i understand so hey
you have the flow
mercy dimitri
uh but thanks for coming to my talk
i hope you will enjoy it there will be a
lot of javascript inside but don't worry
we will cover
everything
feel free to sign very widely if i'm not
speaking properly in the microphone
vladimir
you everybody calls me vlad i'm a staff
engineer at datadog
i'm also a node.js core collaborator
i've been working on
application security for the last six
years in a startup that got acquired by
datadog last year so we are building
application security products feel free
to reach out
also feel free to follow me on twitter
at pauldefette
today i will take a chronological
approach on that talk so there will be a
lot of context stuff technical stuff a
bit of uh
self-soul-searching uh it will be kind
of a mix of a lot of things
don't worry the technical part is still
the biggest part
and a few disclaimers
there's a lot of storytelling that's a
very personal presentation it will cover
a lot of things i've done as an open
source contributor not as a data dog no
screen employee
and there will be a lot of back and
forth about what i had in mind back then
and you will understand why i say that
now also last disclaimer i've built some
commercial content online trainings
about javascript
security including prototype pollution
and i found it was fair to to predict
the disclaimers
okay so it all started uh
with the backbone t program
so
how many of you are familiar with npm as
a package ecosystem okay
a fair amount of people so just quick
reminders it's the most popular package
ecosystem in the world
and you can take this graph at any time
in the past few years it will look the
same npm as a javascript package hosting
repository
is the most growing and the most popular
package repository in the world and
that's been so for almost a decade now
there are millions of packages on npm
and npm serves
a huge variety of content of course
they're javascript backhand packages
node modules but they're also javascript
front-end modules like people get react
bootstrap from npm so front-end
libraries are also downloaded from npm
you have webassembly code that is
distributed over npm because it's used
on the web so wait no why not and you
have native executable uh those are the
native add-ons used with node.js so if
you want to for instance use sqlite
you're likely to use the sqlite3 native
addon on node.js and that might be
pre-compiled or not
for instance data.org as a couple
pre-compiled
native executable on npm to patch
node.js directly or even code in cc plus
plus rest
that can be compiled at install time for
node.js so why why do i say that well
in 2016
the question of vulnerable slash
medicine's package was a bit undefined
npm did not really npm as a commercial
entity did not
want to do any strong efforts in that
direction they had a lot of other things
to do and that was fair from their point
of view um sneak existed but was still
fair new and that's that's a commercial
tool and the node security project which
was basically an alternative to sneak
was deprecating because they got
acquired by npm to do something totally
different
than
vulnerable package management
so the node security project
came to the node foundation and say hey
we've got this database of vulnerable
and malicious packages
do you want it do you want to be in
charge of npm security as the node.js
foundation and we said yes
we were probably young and crazy
so we created a node.js ecosystem
bugbunty program and hacker1 was
extremely nice they offered us a free
plan for the ecosystem and we also have
a free plan for node core so if you find
minorities in node.js feel free to
report them on hacker1 i will be happy
to review them
uh and we started the backbone t without
rewards and depending on the case
sometimes the owners of the vulnerable
packages would give rewards so for
instance a versailles company had
vulnerabilities in a package themselves
and they rewarded the hackers with 500
dollars from time to time which was very
generous and that was a lot of work
handling this burgmanty program
especially when i was by my own for the
first six months
because we had hundreds and of reports
and usually reports there are trends
when people find a vulnerability
in the in search ecosystem people will
do everything they can to find the same
vulnerabilities in similar packages and
that's actually important for for the
rest of the talk
and then in 2018 january we get
a super report because it impacts 12
packages on the apm ecosystem comes from
a security researcher from canada named
olivier
and there are 12 impacted modules but
the weird part is it talks about
prototype pollution
and we had no idea what prototype
pollution was back then that was the
first time we heard about it all
together and we did not find any
literature
so the summary was utilities function in
the listed modules can be tricked into
modifying the prototype of object when
the attackers
control part of the structure passed to
this function this can let blah blah
blah
how can you override methods
in the javascript standard library
and that's where we start to go
technical and we forget about history
for
for a bit
so in javascript you've got basic tips
types you've got booleans objects
numbers big ends strings symbols and
undefined and pretty much everything
else
is objects so dicts are objects strange
objects are objects regular expressions
are objects null is a specific object
and objects are objects and map and sets
all this higher level data structures
they are objects too
and objects have method so for instance
if i call undedict foo 1 has on property
foo it will return true
and hazard property is actually a
property available
it's a method available on that object
uh if i check has on property and has
own property it's false and hazon
property tells you if this object
owns this property or if it's come from
somewhere else so now we know that we
can call a method named has on property
but it does not exist
on the object itself
so how is it available
where does it come from
well
let's use a debugger because the
debugger is probably the most marvelous
piece of software in the history of
software
yeah i'm terrible when i'm asked to
mentor juniors i for them to learn the
debugger rather than putting prints
everywhere
um
i never force anyone to do any anybody
ah anybody i'm doing anything don't
worry so if we debug it we realize that
there's actually a property named
prototype and that has on property is
actually attached to this prototype
so
how does that work
in javascript objects can't can have a
prototype
and when a method or property
basically methods are properties in
javascript
is not found on an object
we look up on its prototype
so if you want to access a property on
an object and if not available on the
object directly we take the object's
prototype and we check on that and the
prototype is actually an object itself
but
this
prototype might have a prototype so if
the prototype does not have the property
you're looking for well by recursion you
look on it on the prototype of the
prototype or on the prototype of the
prototype of the prototype until there's
no prototype available and that's why we
talk a lot about prototype chain in
javascript so let's talk about prototype
chain
uh
on the left hand side we define
functions uh constructors and on the
right hand side we use them so
let's
create an object that's called myproto
that should be a prototype for certain
objects and it has a function a property
named foo that is a function
then we define a class with the old
style in javascript where you define
just the constructor and you attach a
prototype property on that constructor
and here we put our own prototype with
bar
and hello world
as properties and then we defined a new
style class
that extends the old style class and as
bars
as
a property
so if we create an item an object from
this class here
well it has the property hello available
because it's available on the prototype
of old class old styles class that is
actually implemented in our new class so
that's just basic inheritance in any
object-oriented language but with
prototypes
and if we call baz it's available
because it's on the prototype here and
if we call bar it's available because
it's on the prototype here
same thing if we call
two it will share the same prototypes
and if we create item three and we call
the method set prototype off because why
it's why not we can this method exists
and we use my proto well now
the prototype for item three will be my
proto and we have selected an arbitrary
prototype
and what's interesting is that
prototypes are objects
and they are not defined multiple times
in the heap there's only one instance of
the prototype as an object in the hip
so for instance item 2 and item 1
you know they are created with new
on the new style class
so
their prototype is the same object we
can check equality object equality on
their prototype value
but this prototype
has
another prototype that is the one from
the old style class because
inheritance because the new class is
actually extending the old style class
and all of these prototypes they
actually have another higher level
prototype that is the object.prototype
the default prototype for objects in a
javascript heap
and on the other side item three it's
prototype it's my proto and the
prototype of its prototype is
object.prototype okay
so the gotchas are
objective prototype
properties come from the prototype or
the object when they are not found on
the object we look upon them on the
prototype and prototypes are the same
for two different objects multiple
objects can have the same prototype that
are exactly the same object in hip
and we can access the prototype from the
object directly that's where javascript
is a bit special so here i've got a
class
and i create two instances of this class
one with b sides and the other vegas
and if we call my item temba that has on
property show prop it will tell us false
also it's worth noticing that hazon
property is actually available on the
object prototype it's coming from the
higher highest prototype in the
prototype chain
okay so we can call object dot get
prototype off and that will return the
prototype so in our case show prop
is accessible on the prototype of my
item i don't think anyone has said that
much
prototyping talk in in few years
then you can also access the prototype
by calling underscore underscore proto
underscore underscore that's a kind of
outdated way to do it it's deprecated
officially but we can't really remove it
from the web platform whether that's the
front end or the back end because it
will break everything so there are
options to disable it i will see that
later but you can access the prototype
through the underscore underscore proto
underscore underscore property
or each object in javascript has a
reference to its constructor
and remember
the prototype is just a property on the
constructor so if you access the
constructor of an object
then the prototype value on the
constructor
you have access to the prototype too
and just to re-explain that prototypes
are single instance of objects if i take
my item and my item too and i compare
their prototypes they are exactly the
same objects
okay i think i'm good with explaining
your prototypes work in javascript
hopefully it was not too confusing
so what's a pollution now that we know
what a prototype is let's pollute them
a prototype pollution happens when an
arbitrary payload handled by the
javascript codebase can overwrite
properties or methods on the prototype
chain
and that's pretty much it and that
happens usually when a merge function is
called we'll see why
now
so here i'm using the
library in an outdated version
it was part of the original
report by olivier
on prototype pollution
so i create a malicious payload
with a property name underscore
underscore proto underscore underscore
remember that's one of the way of
accessing prototypes from an object
and then i place a property named oops
on it with it works
i create an object named a
and i don't
mutate this object at all anymore
because on the next line i say before
and i check if a has a property named
oops either an a is on the prototype
chain and it will say undefined because
there is no oops in the prototype chain
or on a
then i call hook.merge on a totally
brand new object nothing to do with a
and json.pass my malicious payload i
will explain why we use json and pass
right after that
and then i recheck if a has a oops
property
and actually tells us it works
because the call to the merge function
actually mutated
something in the prototype chain
because when the merge function was
called it checked if it could merge the
proto
property of this object and it did so it
accessed the proto
property the prototype of our brand new
object and added a property name oops on
this prototype but this prototype is
object.prototype the global prototype
for all objects so basically all our
objects in this javascript group hit
no
real return it works when you call oops
except if they have their own property
name oops
why do we use
json.pass here because if you define the
object directly
well
it will already have a proto property
and it will be kinda ignored by the
engine
but there's a gotcha in the historical
implementation of json.pass that makes
this proto valid only if it comes
outside of json.pass
i won't go in the depth of the
implementation of that but
the gotcha is that for this exploit to
work it must go through json.pass
but
so why
then as i told you let's check the merge
method and the merge method is actually
recursive it calls merge again on itself
because you want to merge objects
recursively because you want to merge
nested and sub-objects of your object
and that's where the prototype pollution
happens because once again you will
check if the object that is the target
right now
the first one here has
underscore underscore proto underscore
underscore as a property this will
return true
so you will merge property
on the prototype because recursiveness
i hope that's not too confused
okay other example in that case we don't
need the json.pass version because
remember all objects in javascript has
access to their constructor
so their own prototype through the
constructor so there's another exploit
there used to be another exploit in
lodash
where you would do basically the same so
here we've got constructor prototype is
that mean true
we create a b object
before we check b dot is mean it returns
undefined
we merge
the payload on a totally different
object and when we call b that is that
mean it will return true because we
polluted the prototype chain again
and why does it matter
well lowdash is actually one of the most
popular javascript package on earth it's
been downloaded more than 200 million
times
in
april that's the downloads per month and
it's been downloading 8 billion times
since the package was created
it's pretty much in most javascript code
bases and it has been having multiple
prototype pollutions meaning that the
world javascript ecosystem was at risk
with them
okay
let's take a break from the javascript
and saying prototype prototype and
prototype of prototype
and recursion and recursion and
recursion and go back to the report to
go a bit slower so we started to discuss
on hacker one and the report is still
private for a lot of reason even four
years later
but he's the gist of the discussion
first thing we did we acknowledge having
the report
and we just gathered as the bugbunty
manager team and be like
okay
what do we do with that now is that
really a security issue or is that a
quality issue is that a widespread
defect in the javascript ecosystem or is
it something that actually can be used
to
impact applications on their security
posture
and
discussions went on and on and at the
same time i started to reach out to
nathan la forest nathan la forest here
with the main maintainer of hook the
first library i showed
today
and i told him hey nothing i i don't
understand how it works under the hood
what i explained in the previous slide i
did not understand back then
just reading a report and it was hard to
understand
so
we we sat together over the internet and
started to put debug points and try to
understand how
how how that worked and that's how we
understood prototype pollution and it
blew our mind
and
we know
that there is a systemic bug in a lot of
javascript code base based on that uh we
know that everything that's merged or
deep clone
with recursion might be vulnerable to
that as long as it takes arbitrary
payloads in input
is it a security issue that that's a one
billion dollar question maybe i'm a bit
exaggerating but not that much
so we challenged a bit and the reporter
actually
provided an exploit in an existing code
base
node.js code base some kind of cms
blog management i won't name it because
it's the reason why the report is not
public yet because it's been fixed in it
but never published properly um
and
they actually highlighted
a crash in the application so node.js
applications are writing in javascript
and javascript is by definition single
threaded like worker threads are an
exception to that but no js applications
they are thing they are usually single
threaded and all http requests are
handled by the same thread at the same
time with a lot of asynchronicity so
if you crash one thread in a node.js
application well you crash the whole
process because there's only one thread
that's why error management is really
critical and if you manage to find a
crasher you're not crashing one request
you're crashing the web server itself
so they found
a crash by replacing a method by a
string which is fair and the codebase
was calling this method and that was
crashing because it was a string at this
point
um
so we found the denial of service
because that's
that's the definition of a denial of
service you crash to applicati
application server
and we also found cwe 471 a modification
of assumed immutable data
that was a good candidate back then with
our knowledge so based on that we had
okay we have an exploit at least one
real life exploits that has an
acceptable outcome
has been acceptable a malicious outcome
uh and we found some kind of reference
in referential we found this cwe saying
hey this has been acknowledged as a
group of vulnerabilities by the industry
so at this point we are mostly thinking
yeah that's probably your proper
vulnerability let's accept it as a
vulnerability report
so a bit of housekeeping
we asked olivier to publish 12 reports
instead of one single one because we had
to communicate with library maintainers
for them to fix and we didn't want them
to know the list of other vulnerable
packages
uh we reached out to the maintainers
shared the reports and we started
publishing fix and publishing reports
and we had like a few cwc
cve going out in 2018
and what happens after 2018. well that's
a good question yeah since 2018 there
have been 193
cv published for prototype pollution
2022 is not over
um
and not all projects attribute cves for
instance if i'm not mistaken sneak does
not apply uh published cvs on a lot of
packages when they're not popular enough
and the hacker one project for node
ecosystem for npm ecosystem has been
closed
meaning there might be hundreds of other
occurrences of prototype pollutions in
the wild
i kinda remember stats why it was one of
the most
the fastest
publishing cv machines in terms of
attack classes
there have been one sce in chibana
we'll go on that later and in december
it was a repo there was a report about
one cve
on pass server we'll get to that a bit
later too
and more recently last month
the royal institute of technology in
sweden published
published a really cool paper
on the topic
the reference will be at the end of the
of the talk it's a good write
so i told you let's talk about an se
because we found dos but what about sce
over prototype pollution
okay so
as i told you node.js is single threaded
so
if you want to do
tasks that are cpu intensive you will be
blo you will be monopolizing the single
thread and node.js has been designed for
ios for asynchronicity so if you block
the main thread you block the wall up
and you kinda does it temporarily
so kibana use a hack
when it has to do some computing it
start a child process which is very fair
until we had worker threads in node.js
two years ago that was the only way to
go and node.js shares the environment
of the parent process to the children
one
and this is defined as a javascript
object i think you kind of see where
this is going right
and node.js has an option
that's called that's an environment
variable called node options and
basically that enables you to pass
command lines argument to node.js but
through an environment variable so
instead of doing node.js dash something
then your executable you can do node
option
your flags then load your executable
which is something handy
well
what happened in kibana
is that someone found a prototype
pollution
to actually write the node option
property on the prototype chain
so when the child process was starting
it was inheriting the environment from
the parents
including the node option newly defined
and their environment viable on the
prototype chain and they would be able
to call dash e for eval
and run arbitrary javascript code
from the command line through a
prototype pollution
and since you're running arbitrary
node.js code you can call another child
process with a shell in it you can call
the file system
you've got an sce directly on the server
so that was pretty bad
that's been fixed and i know that the
kibana team has been doing a tremendous
job on that
the past vulnerability is more recent
the report is from december
but it has been published only this year
if i'm not mistaken past was a
standalone startup
that got acquired by one of the major
companies of the valley i'll let you
google where that is
but it's not google and they deprecated
the project and the current version of
pass is the open source community
version of that
and that's basically a rest api in front
of mongodb it's used to build backends
for mobile applications and
basically
it's it's an api it's a web api
over mongodb so you can write objects
you can read objects all of that
and it's vulnerable to prototype
pollution because it's called the merge
function at some point that's that he
exploits but also it uses a library
named b
bison.js which is the default library
used by the mongodb driver in node.js
so the attacker can upload a document
on mongodb
through pass that's basically the point
of this piece of software you can upload
upload and retrieve documents in mongodb
so good
and those documents are formatted in
bison and bison actually allows you to
register functions that will be executed
when you deserialize code from mongodb
but this is by default disabled
you need to
enable the eval functions property on
the bison library to
make the code executable
but there's a prototype pollution so you
can pollute
eval function for all objects in the hip
and when bison is checking oh is eval
function to set to true yes it will be
because of the pollution
and because
eval function is not default defined on
the object in bason library because if
the basin library had a real default
version not a per default default
property
meaning that if
the option object was updated with is
this property existing on the object yes
no if no its value is false
then it will not be vulnerable but what
they do is just does this property exist
on the object or its prototype chain
because it's easy to do and because of
the prototype pollution you could do
that so basically the outcome
run arbitrary javascript code on the
node.js server once again you can call
any node.js module fork
start spawn a shell do whatever you want
that's that's your sce
and that's a terrible slide ordering for
me i'm so sorry let's go back to the
cubana one for one sec
oh we think that node does not allow the
dash e in node options anymore
so you can't evolve keyboard as fixed
you can check the
report
sorry about that
how to prevent
well remember that our merge function in
herck
here is the fix
basically
we just needed to prevent the property
proto to be taken in account and that
was good enough because at the only
vulnerable path to herc herc was not
vulnerable to the prototype dot
constructor.prototype path
so
there are other ways
when you call an object in javascript
when you call a property it's a good
practice to actually check if the
property exists on the object directly
that's why we have has on property
and you can make sure that the property
is actually not inherited
and there's an alternative
you can actually create objects that
won't have a prototype at all so null
despite being an object does not have a
prototype
and you've got a method called
object.create that takes a prototype as
an argument and create a new object
with the argument as a prototype
so let's take our example again and here
i create a with object that creates
null
so we run the attack
and a is actually
not vulnerable to this attack because it
just doesn't have a prototype so there's
nothing to pollute
but there's there's a drawback is that i
can't call has on property or the usual
methods of the objects in javascript
because they're generated from the
object prototype
i think one of the
main way to prevent prototype pollution
and that's actually pretty
straightforward
is data validation and sanitization
just to make sure that the objects that
are coming from the user that are by
definition interested
don't contain properties you're not
expecting
so there's a very very very cool library
named joy for that and you define the
shape of the object even the size of the
integers on it regex to validate
properties whatever you want it's a very
good library to do proper type and
validation on objects in javascript and
by default it will prevent objects from
having and and unplanned properties so
shape your object and if properties are
not expected
they will be marked as invalid which is
pretty cool
sidenote
object decentralization is timeless in
javascript it's mostly json.pass and
that opens the door to a lot of other
issues over object injections one of the
most
impacting one is nosql injections
you you can check my previous stroke
just google my name and mongodb and
you'll see a few talks on the topic if
you're interested
so
that that's the conclusion now
what do i think now what do i think four
years later almost 200
published vulnerabilities later
did we open the pandora box or did we do
the right thing
well
during the process of accepting the
first prototype pollution report there
was a lot of uncertainty
i think we were good because we involved
other people we trusted
including community leaders as
maintainers so we did not stay as a
close mind team especially important
because in that triage team under
burgbunti
i think i was the only one working full
time no lyranto there was only two of us
working full-time on application
security and the other one were just
node.js developers with
no professional background in security
especially
so we did i think we did the right thing
by gathering uh group intelligence on
that
uh
i think we were fair in expecting an
example of exploit saying hey okay that
brand new that makes sense
can you demonstrate that it can have a
real life impact on an application that
would help us a lot
and try to link
to as little as much literature we can
even if it was just finding the right
cwe
um
i think we missed a few opportunities
under process 2
because we had a brand new
vulnerability class
we knew it was largely impacting
javascript as an ecosystem and we did
not do what we should have done which is
sit together with the node.js core team
and say hey
we need to compute the threat model and
evaluate if there are something in node
that could be
abused over prototype pollution and
maybe we would have found the kibana
case one year before it was published
by saying hey look you can redefine
environment variables
maybe
and i think i was really bad on
communication
i let olivier gave the talks on that
which is fair he was the one who found
the vulnerabilities uh fun thing uh the
next year at uh
west california i was giving a talk
about
node.js security model and it was in the
next room giving a talk about prototype
pollution
um and
olivier moved to something else after
because he's a security researcher and
we probably should have uh run that bike
as community leader and security leaders
in the javascript ecosystem evangelize
that's actually my first talk ever on
prototype pollution and i think that's a
missed opportunity on my side
for the fun story a couple years ago
someone tried to tell me there's a
prototype pollution in my code and i
demonstrate that it was unexploitable
but
sometimes you know
um conclusion uh what now monitor
incoming objects don't let proto or
constructors come inside your hip from
outside objects
there's an option in node.js to disable
proto altogether use at your own risk it
might
break some of your libraries
but
a good a good thing with same grip will
help you know if you're if your code
base or their dependencies actually use
underscore underscore proto underscore
underscore i'm saying i'm mentioning
some rep not only because you're in the
room
and enforce sanitization and prototype
less objects
a few links
the two last ones are actually my
classes if you want to deep dive into
that
the one that's here pollute me it's
actually a github repo
where i have written a vulnerable code
base you can download it start the
docker
repo and try to exploit it i did that in
10 minutes yesterday so maybe it's not
very good feel free to provide feedback
uh reach out on twitter if you want the
slides because i always forget to upload
them between jet lag and busy conference
time and the two first links are our
report the first one uh i think it's the
yeah it's the kth paper and the second
one is actually uh the sc in kibana
i think
i have time for some questions now
yes
so the question
is did we do any research to see if
other languages were very variable to a
similar class of attacks
i'm not aware of that and i was actually
reading the page about prototype
oriented programming this morning it was
like oh there's at least a few of the
prototype oriented languages that's
probably worth
checking
i think depending on the way inheritance
is implemented in other languages it
might make sense on the top of my head i
would consider that language the trend
on the jvm won't be vulnerable for that
but that probably needs to be checked
you can't yeah the application
[Music]
so the question is is there a go-to
payload uh a cheat sheet to find them
and because of those
uh
i i don't know if there is a list yet i
actually think
this one that replace has on property by
null
and same thing on that one uh that
should do the trick and just check the
object prototype on ndn
write a script and you can use one
single payload to override all of these
values so you will soon see
i think you've got a 70 chance of
crashing the application if you manage
to override them so yeah
i i can try to upload something on
github later
why was the back bounty shutdown for
node ecosystem not not core
mostly because
npm was acquired by github
and that was the best move for the
javascript ecosystem and no guitar
also npm started to do
bug bounty i mean vulnerability report
as a feature in npm within pm edit then
got acquired by github that has security
features so it did not make sense to
have like an extra
an extra
initiative on that especially since we
were doing that on our free time and
people like github are paid to do that
so they will do it 10 times better than
we do
uh do we have uh regression testing on
this vulnerable project um i
i don't know but that's the magic
about
um
about fashion in the bugbunty world is
that
so when we started the ecosystem but
bunty
the first report we get was a directory
traversal
in uh application used to serve static
content
and if you check the outcome of this bug
boonty i think the probably the first 50
reports were that then when proper
pollution was published we had probably
50 reports for prototype pollution so i
would say that people who are getting
trained to get karma and hacker1 are the
regression testing for that
if i may
um
if i rephrase
does googling search the code base now
um
i i i don't think we will online we've
been using that at all
i was actually discussing with two
people in this room earlier today
about the fact that this kind of attacks
are really hard to find a stat with
static analysis
if you read the kth paper
one of the point is that
they had a lot of false positives if i
remember properly don't misquote me on
that
they had a lot of false positive and
study static analysis
so i don't have a i don't think scanning
works yet for this class of attacks
okay if there are no more questions feel
free to follow me on twitter
ping me provide feedback i'm looking for
them too and ask for the slides and
thanks so much for being an amazing
crowd
[Applause]