all right hello good afternoon welcome
to b-sides Las Vegas you are in breaking
ground
uh this talk is the north northern
Virginia Shuffle lateral movement and
other Creative Steps attackers take in
AWS Cloud environments and how to detect
them let's get started please welcome
Philippe proteus
[Applause]
thank you everybody thank you for coming
for my talk so my name is Philippe as
you you heard from Pierce and my
nickname is proteus so just my mom
called Philip so
you can Comfort us wherever you find me
whenever so a little bit about me I have
at least 10 years of experience in
Security in general I'm a proud father
of a girl
and also blue team structure back in
Brazil
and I'm security researcher at Mt
security did you think she's security is
a startup company based uh focused in
Cloud security and third-party risk
management and as a asthma's role as
security researcher
part of my job is Googling around
reading documentations and writing box
to test for their abilities and this
kind of stuff
and sometimes we help our clients with
with questions so I I was there one day
Googling around reading docs and one of
our clients came to us and asking about
his Network diagram on AWS and he was
doing all kinds of nasty stuff he was
doing things like
people's appearing between Dev and
product environment draws accounts
between that and project environments
and I said no
you're doing something really nasty here
you shouldn't doing this because there's
the problem of lateral movements and he
says what and yeah and then I explain
him and then something popped in my mind
I just realized that uh Cloud security
is more complex than on-premise security
and I know that's a bold statement but I
do have uh analogy or a metaphor to
explain that
so
by the title of this talk
when I submitted this talk to besides I
was thinking well what things work
laterally and doesn't work watery so I
can think get a thing for my talk and
the only thing that I could think was
scraps but I don't like crabs I guess
nobody like crabs so I was talking to my
boss Sierra and he told me about this
kind of dances it's called Texas Shuffle
and for those who doesn't know which
Texas Shuffle kind of dancing style is
is something like this
seems nice right
but I'm a Brazilian and I'm from Rio
Janeiro actually so I have to bring
something for you for you guys to do a
contrast between the Texas Shuffle and
the dancing that I brought here today is
something that we call pasino it's like
a Brazilian thing so kind of like this
yeah two different dancing styles with
their respective differences
but and you'll get a little bit more on
this later
but just keep those dancing in mind
so when we talk about lateral movements
and possibilities of lateral movements
how many of you guys already did a pen
test on on-prem's Networks
how long did you guys take to get a
domain to me more than a day or more
than two days
usually you just pivot pretty fast
between all the networks find the domain
to me uh get the credentials and becomes
a domain administrator right so this can
also be done on AWS
but
on AWS you can have separate accounts so
you can have account a and account to be
and for do this kind of things in AWS
must have to be a VPC bearing between
those accounts and those vpcs right
so when an attacker usually attacker
doesn't land when he went when they when
when their objective is so he has to
move laterally right so if he hackets
are instance on the vpca
he can find out on other networks and
move laterally into the vpcb and so on
this thing in AWS we call data plane and
data plane is where your data lives
actually
but on cloud we also have another plane
that's called the control plane and the
control plane is like it's all the apis
that you call
to
make requests to your cloud provider for
example in AWS you called it the control
plane to create a new VPC to create easy
to ministers RS3 buckets or something
things like that
and
the the thing with the data plane to get
in you just have to get something
exposed like an IP address or things
like that but just to get in on the
control plane you're gonna need a
credential or a login password or AWS
access three keys and so on in the
control plane you have entities like
users rows groups and things like that
so how do you move it laterally on the
control plane so here you have a row and
in account a
and this road can assume another road
the road to in the same account
but the thing is
the the attacker who has who got the
role well he could also Zack and create
an instance on the vpca and then he can
jump from the control plane into the
data plane
and if the attacker gotta is a first
hackage aec2 instance and he find out
that his institutions has a role
attached to it he can assume that role
and jump to the control plane
and from there he can also find out on
other networks and other accounts in AWS
and jump from account a to account B
and he could also from the same ec2
instance if he find out another account
he can jump from the institutions in
account a to another role in a in
account B so you can think
pretty much see that this these things
getting even more complex than on-premes
Network right
and even though uh the same attacker who
has a role in account
in account TB he can also exec and his
due to create an instance on VPC on
account to be so
really really mess right so just to
bring that comparison between those
dances and I promise to my sister-in-law
do not make comparisons between dances
because that's not something that you
should do but we can compare features
between those dances so who thought that
the Brazilian Frank would be more hard
to learn
uh oh well who thought that the
Brazilian Funk would be harder to learn
than Texas Shuffle anyway
yeah
but the thing is the Brazilian fact it's
only fast he was dancing by himself fast
moves yeah but there's him by himself
the Texas Shuffle uh he has to interact
that has interaction between the
partners so they also can dance by
themselves if you watch the
the video clip again they also then
separated between them but they also
have to coordinate their weights and
balance between them so there's much
more aspects and complexity in Texas
Shuffle than Brazilian passing you
so
the texture Shuffle should be our Cloud
environment
the comparison between data planning
control plane and the balancing between
those
so
uh
I created not created actually I just
copied from the Cupid Shuffle some steps
to introduce you to the lateral
movements so everybody knows that musk
is that to the left to the left to the
right to the right now click now kick
now walking by yourself but that's a
really Anthem
um at least Cruisers and things like
that in marriages
so when we talk about lateral movements
on the data plane
uh
you between two two easy two instances
on different vpcs connected by a VPC
peering
some things doesn't work as expected for
example iarp protocol RP protocol
doesn't work as expected because in AWS
you don't have the broadcast broadcast
so if you enter in consult and do
arp-a you won't see any machine just
your machine in the router
so there is no easy ways for an attacker
to find out which other networks are
connected to the to this account so the
solution for this is to do a network
scam so he can scan the whole range the
whole slash eight range it's nice but
effective it's gonna if you the
if the blue team of that company has
some flow logs and things like that
you're gonna catch him
but it's effective for the attacker so
he couldn't find a new instance on those
and other vpcs and on other sub networks
and then hack it their way into this new
instance
another kind of lateral movement is when
the attacker came from the ec2 he hacked
the ec2 instance for example
and or a Lambda or ECS or a batch job
there's any kind of data plane uh
things that can assume a role and he can
just get those information enter on this
machine if there is a role attached to
it he can store these credentials and
jump into the control plane
by doing this something pretty much like
this so the attacker lens so this is
situ instance so he does a STS get
caller identity to find out which hole
he has and now you can see that he has
the thing she easy to roll
so you're going to dump credentials to
jump to the control plane by doing this
he is working he's using the metadata
metadata is a service from AWS who gives
a lot of information about the the role
that that situ instance has and
credentials and informations about that
instance so here the attack would be
able to get the credentials and then he
can use uh some tools to post
exploration that one of the tools is the
paku it's a open source AWS exploitation
framework developed by the Reno security
guys so if you guys don't know this tool
just download and play around pretty
good too has some some
defects I don't know how to say that but
it's pretty good too in general
so
there is another kind of lateral
movement that are called here step down
and that means when when an attacker is
able to get any kind of credentials or
access keys or uh login password without
MFA from a user or perhaps with MFA with
phishing uh the attacker get
discrimination connects the control
plane and if he find out there is a VPC
there and he wants to see what else
hasn't that he doesn't have enough
permissions to walking around that
networks well he creates a new ec2
instance then he sends a command for
that institution instance for example
using the SSM or loading the data inside
the user data for that Institute
instance and then he can jump to that
easy to instance and execute code here
in this example the attacker he sends an
sscm sent comments to an instance and
creating a reverse shell for here
attacker IP address on part 31 3037
so and when we talk about lateral
movements on the control plane things
are a little bit more trickier than on
the data plane right so
uh here we have three accounts let's
assume that we have three accounts
accounts a account B and account C if
the attacker gets a credential and
accounts a
and the accounts B has this following
policy here that says that the principle
is a AWS any entity coming from the
account a so a user is an entity from
account hey can assume role so an
attacker would be able to jump from the
account a to the account B without no
problem and assume this row
but when you think uh an attacker got
access to account B and he wants to jump
to account C you think you you you're
tempting to think that
this policy must be enough for him to
jump between accounts from account to be
to account C but that's not true because
when it happens when uh the the attacker
assumed the role from accounting a to
account to B and then try to assume a
role in account C he is not actually
coming from the account B it's coming
from accounting a and this policy won't
work
the true pulse that has to work it's
something like this it has to be uh
assumed role for an account to be with a
role and when you assume a rolling
account you should you should usually
you put a value like a testing or your
name your username something like that
and it also has to happen here in the
policy on our company
I would be pretty honest with you guys
I've never seen this in any of our
clients nothing like that so I suppose
not work like this
and the thing is that that thing that we
call uh assuming role a summary rule on
being a Sumo role on C it's called
roller chaining and this has a hard
limit of one hour from AWS so even
though if you could be able to assume
around be in a summer role on C uh the
maximum time that you can assume that
role is for one hour
that's not much a big problem because
all the apis from the AWS are real real
well documented and attacker might
script their way and creating
persistence in back doors all over so
this role chaining is not a big problem
but an attacker can be creative right
and usually they are so there's another
kind of movement that are called now
geek because when this policy comes from
the accounts B the account B is the root
an entity on an account to be right so
if your attacker has the action or the
ability to create an Institute instance
he would be able
whatever
all right so when they are counting when
an attacker in a county would be able to
to exact uh create an ec2 instance on
the same account
the ac2 instance is a entity on this
account so he would be able to assume a
role give a permission to enter which is
a situations to assume a role on account
B and he jumps to account to be as an
entity assumed by account a but he also
could be able to create a new instance
on accounts B
and then jump to account B and then
assume a rolling account receipt and
would be something like this
so he he went to the control plane down
to the data plane back to the control
plane down to the data plane and then
back to the control plane again until he
reached the account seat
so that's the curse because AWS doesn't
reach a situ instance uh
a situations using roles as a rolly
chaining thing so there's no limits
there's a limit to up to 12 hours
but it's a way to bypass that
so what are the attacker requirements to
make this thing work so it has to have
enough privilege on AWS so he must have
STS assumed role and preferably resource
star that means that he can assume a
role in any resource
and he also has to know a related
accounts on the same organizations so
this can be found in cloudtrail I am
policing through all things sometimes
you go to the GitHub account from that
organizations and find out they have
like three or four other accounts
uh which which account numbers shared
there because account numbers are not
really a secret right so you you can
share it's not supposed to but you can
and they also has to know a army of a
role to assuming the new account so when
you do an SDS assume role you have to
know the art that you the irony of the
role that you assume in the the new
account
this can be brute force it because
usually it's created by humans so you
can reinforce like a role like an
account number roll admin administrator
and things like that
but there's a special case because when
it's coming from the master accounts
there's a special case for that
so let's talk a little bit about
privilege escalation
privilege escalations a set of actions
that allows a principle to increase
their privileges for instance
uh you can imagine a user with a really
low privilege but with enough enough
actions to improve his
his actions his capabilities theirs was
a great research by the late Spencer
geitzen from Reno security labs and he
found out at least 20 uh 28 no
privileged Collision techniques
and there's a there was a really new One
released by spooker Labs today in his
talk if you guys saw it on app stream
about that upstream and there is even
more possibilities because with
combinations with eim pass role there's
a this is an action on AWS and there's a
really good research by Innova and Dam
and when he find out new kind of
privileged escalations combining eim
pass role and other actions from AWS
but the thing is not all privileged
collisions are created equal
let's take some examples a lot of the
techniques have the same effective
Effectiveness and allow you to become an
administrator ASAP so here we have two
techniques the first one is the IIM
create pulse version
that allows you to become assistant
administrator as just creating a new
policy version and becoming
administrator right
but that is the another technique called
set default policy version that depends
on you have another policy version that
allows you to become administrator
earlier so if you have the pulse version
if you want here that allows you to set
the photos version but the pulse version
v0
doesn't allows you to become a assistant
administrator this this technique of
privileged escalation might give you
some more permissions the permissions of
the version zero but not become a
assistant administrator right
so there is a tool there's called fault
Spain anyone have ever used it
yeah it's a good tool it was created by
Kinder McQuaid he was working in a sales
force at that time
and release these two on April 30 2020
and the current version is zero five oh
but the good thing about this too is
that it downloads your IAM policies
online policies custom policies and AWS
policies and analyze those policies
looking for privileged Collision
techniques data filtration possibilities
of tactic situations resource exposure
credential exposure and infrastructure
modification so you generated this kind
of reports 3D
3D HTML Report with those texts and
it is bar graph bars and things like
that so turns out it's pretty easy to
analyze privilege correlations with this
tool
so another attacker requirement is to
know the I the account ID of a related
account on the same organization right
so this can be found on cloudtrail and
here we have an example of a cloud
straight of uh em role getting
AWS API call
uh it's closing an account ID
and you can also be found in AIM
policies because if you have cross
account policies
and those trust account has to have the
number of the accounts uh to the
destination right so you can find out
new numbers there and also through of
things uh as the example of the GitHub
that I gave you guys before
so and the the third thing and the third
trick actually if the targets use AWS
organizations or awsc Contour Tower
uh the role that organization that AWS
organization creates and control tower
creates on the the child accounts on AWS
it's a well-known name it's called
organizational cards access roles and
for the control tower is at AWS control
tower execution and they have admin
privileges in their child accounts by
default
so
if an attacker gets access to the master
account you will know by just doing our
organization list the number of the the
number of the accounts he has and he can
also jump from his account from their
Master accounts to any other accounts
because he already know the rules for
that like organization access or AWS
control tower
even though the AWS control tower is
efficient role has two principles one is
defined the services so control tower
can also assume a role on on your
account but the the thing is there is a
principle here from the master account
as any entity on the master account can
also assume this role so you if an
attacker got access to a master account
it's done game over
so let's run some some true scenarios on
AWS
some usually patterns that people do on
AWS so the first button is called Hub
and spoke
when you have a multiple accounts which
accounts for a production account for a
development staging and so on and a
shared account who shares like database
and things like that so
as a AWS administrator you can do some
kind of mistakes for example for example
creating IAC to instance on the shared
VPC
uh with the two Enis one were routing to
account a and another one routing to
accountancy what that means that means
that if an attacker could hack any
accounting act in any situ instance in
account a find out there is an instance
on on the shared vpcs have the shared
vpcs here you will see that you have two
NIS and then another one will allow you
to allow him to jump to account C
and the other things that you can do on
this kind of scenario is do DPC peering
so if you do VPC printing between
account a to account B to account C you
are basically making your network flat
and there is another pattern there
called cicd account
it's like basically like this you have a
master account and you have your cicg
account and this ICD do deploy for that
for stage infrastruct accounts
and the master can access the dev and
the stage a user in a master can access
the depth and stage but he can use
usually access their products account
what our administrator can do to break
this pattern is create a cross account
between the dev and the cicd the
backwards you see and when he do that
the user might be able to get a
credential and have
then jump to cicd and then jump to prod
just by assuming role between control
planes
so in order to help our customers and
find out really easy ways to find out
privilege lateral movements between
accounts and those kind of things we
tested a lot of tools but none of these
what we expected them to do so it's time
to build your own right we tested
bmapper from NCC groups we tested
AWS SPX from App secure labs and
cloud mapper from Google Apps and a lot
of tools but none of them did what we
expected them to do easily actually
so we had some some requirements right
so we should use open source in free
tools
uh we should download automatically
through the AWS apis all the necessary
input to plot the graph
from also from the control plane in data
plane and also has to have a query
language to allow racy alerts
automatically
so we decided to use Grambling as a
graph database carry language and for
doing this we are using a bash Tinker
pop
uh behind we are also using Cloud
splaining to allow us to log in multiple
accounts and download the all the
information and also some uh splitted
scripts to download information about
the
the code of the data plane things that
we needed to to our project and we
decided to use the 3js that's a amazing
graph Library pretty easy to to make
things on that so
our model how we model that well all the
squares that you guys saw in the
presentation uh are things from the data
plane like ec2 instance lambdas ECS or
anything like that
and everything there was Circle uh it's
from one account and the colors
different different makes the difference
between accounts
and also we have an arrow with a
directional directional relationship
and so it's double time the thing is
this tool has no name yet so
vote on Twitter I just make a boat this
morning and you guys have this only
these four options of names sorry but
yeah that's what the Twitter let allowed
me to to put on percentage on on as
options and please vote
and we will publish that too as soon as
possible so it's demo time
all right
here
this is the interface of our no name yet
to as you can see right here on the left
and use we base the this interface in a
project from the GitHub the project
called graph XP
from a handle guide that I don't know
him but it was kind of we just uh
modificate a little bit the code to make
this work the the he has a
JavaScript grammling carry interface
with the the Apache Tinker pop
so just to grab I already loaded the all
the information from the AWS
and just click search you'll be able to
to graph this information so you can see
uh routes are
control plane stuff uh squares are data
playing stuff
you can zoom in throughout pan for left
to the right
but the data that I show you guys here
it's like a mock-up data from one of
based on one of our clients who has hack
it so the attacker would be was able to
create to grab his credentials create an
institution and just do that I'm hiding
but the thing is if the attacker would
be able to it was a bot so it was not
smart enough to find out lateral
movements but if it was a person if it
was a real attacker and he find he could
be able to find out lateral movements
our clients would be screwed and I show
you guys why
you can you can move the the
pieces around and this is the user
hold on the credential liquid and the
attacker was able to create an ec2
instance
and this is institutions was in the
master account so he would be able to
jump to all those other four accounts
that he has
there are the green the blue the orange
and the light orange accounts
and this client has also has a VPC
viewing between other accounts the
orange account so this instance he would
be able to
perhaps hack this instance and then jump
to another instance and then also become
assistant administrator because this
instance here wasn't a private network
but he has the administration role
attach it to it
and the easiest way to analyze things
like that is to look for clusters like
this one and this one the second the
second clusters is from his cicd so
there is account who will deploy here an
account for deploy here and there is a
easy two instance with Jenkins here to
deploy it for those accounts
and things like that are usually limited
with a road because laminate has has a
role attached to it
and they're like sparse they are not
connected to the whole graph
and you can also use a filter like
privilege escalation here and you'll see
that if you
Fade Out
or raise the transparency the other
nodes and there is a possibility of
privilege escalation here from between
those two rows
and if you click on the edge you'd be
able to see that there is a label Edge
for privileged collection if they create
positive version so you can also carry
information between those nodes
so we have some future work to do or our
to-do list as we used to call so one
thing that we want to put on this tool
is to be able to evaluate restrictions
of all privileged escalation techniques
because
uh for example the example that I did
that I said before there are some kinds
of uh the previous escalations that
needs a situ instance that leads lambdas
if there is no role with a in that that
account with the permissions enough to
that Lambda will not be a privileged
escalation at all you won't be able to
get more actions we all started like to
edit support for other resources like S3
and RTS
support for his soft-based policies and
a better visualization and featuring
parties too
and we can draw some conclusions from
here well first of all is try to apply
the least privileged IAM role
permissions and I know that's easier
said than done
but you can abuse fscps and IM
boundaries to limit uh most of most of
what an attacker can do in your network
another user resources start because
when you do resources start you can do
those actions that it has permissions in
any source so a good thing would be
restrict the kind of resources that uh
this attacker can make moves so other
thing is don't run local overloads in
your master account so your master
account in AWS from organizations should
be empty uh as much as possible don't
cross account don't cross any account to
the master so that case on the CI CD
when the there is a connection between
the cicg and the dev and the dev back to
cicd if you do this kind of thing things
you're alone allowing privilege
escalation privilegation I'm sorry
you're allowing lateral movements and
always review all your trusted across
account policies and for sure segment
your networking accounts as much as
possible
so thank you guys that's all I have for
you today uh
[Music]
any questions the code will be released
uh on YouTube security
and hopefully soon
any questions
I've got the microphone here if anybody
wants to have a question just raise your
hand and I'll try to hand it off
I'll ask a quick question a lot of the
stuff you talked about today does that
does it also apply to other Cloud
providers like Azure or Google compute
platform uh the lateral movement yeah
it's possible you know all other Cloud
providers but the things like uh AWS
organizations are basically on AWS
thank you
thank you very much