uh what's up please welcome jonathan
lightshoe and patrick white
hello everybody
uh good afternoon and welcome to uh
scaling the security research to
eliminate open source uh vulnerabilities
once and for all
um my name is jonathan leitchu i am a
software engineer software security
researcher
i'm the first ever dan kaminski fellow
at human security i'm a ghetto star and
get up security ambassador um and you
can find me on twitter at jlightshoe and
on github at j light you as well
and patrick
uh yeah i'm patrick way i
work from darren i'm the open rewrite
team i've been writing software for 20
years or more and excited to be here
talking to you today
so short disclaimer um
uh we're going to be discussing so first
off i'm sponsored by github second off
we're discussing a sas solution
that is sold however all the tools and
infrastructure and everything discussed
in this talk is available for free and
free for open source uh are not free for
corporate but free for open source and
you can use this stuff in your own
security research focused on open source
software
and with that other way i want to talk
about so this uh the work and my
employment is sponsored by the dan
kaminski fellowship
the dan kaminski fellowship was created
after dan passed away last year i sadly
never got the opportunity to meet dan um
dan for those of you who don't know was
the hero that was uh he was known as the
hero of the internet for his incredible
2008 dns vulnerability that he helped
silently patch
and the dan committee fellowship was
created to celebrate dan's memory and
legacy by funding open source work that
makes the world a better and more secure
place
if you have a project that you want to
work on
that you think will help improve the
security of the internet human is
accepting applications for the 2022 dan
kaminski fellow currently
so this story started with a
vulnerability a simple vulnerability
and this vulnerability existed in my
company's code
it was the use of http to resolve
dependencies in in my company's gradle
build um and the reason this is
important is because if you're using hdp
to resolve your dependencies in a maven
in your gradle or maven build um
it uh you can have that connection get
intercepted and people can maliciously
inject additional code and be running
additional code in your ci cd
development pipeline or on your
developer machines
and this vulnerability didn't just exist
in gradle builds uh i it can also exist
in maven builds this is an example that
where your dependencies are getting
resolved uh for compiler and test
dependencies and this is artifact upload
so this is the final release artifact
for a gradle
for a maven build and with this
credentials are also attached to it so
you're also exposing credentials
publicly
and this vulnerability was everywhere
it impacted organizations like spring
apache foundation red hat kotlin
jetbrains jenkins gradle groovy
elasticsearch eclipse um oracle the nsa
linkedin and stripe um and so i i found
this vulnerability impacting all of the
open source projects of all these
different organizations across their
getup accounts
and at this point i realize i was like
this is bigger than i thought um so i
reached out to maven sauna type maven
sonar type is is um the pip to the
python ecosystem the uh npm to the
javascript ecosystem maven sonotype is
that to the java to the java ecosystem
and they said that they looked at their
traffic logs and saw that 25 of their
traffic was still using hdp in june of
and so i said all right how do we fix
this
so i pushed forward an initiative that
on january 15th 2020 all the major
artifact servers in the java ecosystem
would decommission support for hdp in
favor of hdp https only
and uh
and we published a blog post i published
a blog post and then i reached out to me
and sauna type again um in january of
2020 and they said that 20 of their
central traffic was still using hgb
instead of https even after you know uh
like three quarters of a year of trying
to disclose this to people
and so
you can imagine what happened
on january 15 2020
broken software broken software
everywhere
um uh but we stopped the bleeding um
but this didn't fix the whole problem
what about the other repositories
these are only the most commonly used
repositories in the java system um maven
central j center spring and and the
gradle plug-in portal other companies
post their own java artifacts on their
own servers and so you'll see other
companies uh urls are build your urls
and other builds across the system so
how do how do we fix the rest
and i said well i mean
opening issues is one way to do this but
like let's just go fix the problem right
um and so i said let i'm gonna try bulk
pull request generation
and so how did i do this the uh first
off the first thing you need to do is
you need to find the projects that are
vulnerable right you need to identify
the open source projects that have this
vulnerability and so how i did this was
i wrote a code query for it
and uh this code code query looks for
maven palm files that have the use of
http in this sensitive location in the
great in that file in that xml file and
will flag it
and by scanning uh codeql scans hundreds
of thousands of open source projects on
every single commit
and you can run and they build databases
for those for those projects that you as
an open source security researcher can
run queries against and find
vulnerabilities in open source at scale
and so they also will pay you for
queries that you write and contribute
back to github
for the github for as part of the github
security lab binding program and so for
this simple query github bountied me at
2 300 for this
um and using the list of projects that
were vulnerable from this query that i
wrote
i started generating pull requests and
so the first bot the first thing that i
ever the first
pull request generation generator that i
ever wrote was python based
it used a wrapper over
github's hub cli added one nasty regular
expression and there was a lot of logic
about bouncing off of github's rate
limiting um
and this was version one um it probably
looks pretty washed out now but like um
uh this was the first pull request
generator uh it's the it's a there's an
underlying engine but like this was the
logic for
generating pull requests to fix the
security vulnerability and this is the
secure this is the regular expression
and the reason that we had to use a
regular expression uh i'd use a regular
expression instead of using an xml
parser is because if you parse xml into
an xml parser and then you modify that
xml the xml that comes back out when you
print it back out will be in the format
of the xml parser's output not the
output not in the format that came in
and so if you're trying to modify tons
and tons of different xml files that
have tons of different formatting you're
gonna end up with massive diffs and
they're all gonna end up looking like
the same thing and you're not gonna end
up
looking like the code the maintainer
gave you are started with and they're
not going to be happy they're going to
be like great thank you for fixing this
but it doesn't look like the code i
wrote
and the other problem is this is using a
regular expression and
when you have a problem that uses
regular expressions you're gonna end up
with two problems um because uh yeah
anybody who's working with your regular
expressions understands this um but it
worked um
this is
my github contribution feed for pull
requests um when i generated this and
this is an example of the diff that was
generated right you can see that the all
the places where http is being used in
this sensitive location was fixed
and uh i generated
1596 pull requests with this uh
this python bot that i wrote and as of
2020 to 2022 today um we've had about a
40 merge rate of those 1596 pull
requests
and for this uh github awarded me a four
thousand dollar bounty under the github
security lab bug money program for uh
not just that writing the query that
found the vulnerability so this is in
addition to the 2 300 for writing the
query this is for actually using that
query to try to fix the vulnerability at
scale
and i got hooked on this idea of bulk
pull request generation as an idea that
we could use to fix vulnerabilities at
scale across the open source ecosystem
this is my github contribution graph for
you can see the two peaks i actually did
two different campaigns uh in 2020 um
and you know this this tells a
complicated story uh
so
i have a problem
um
my problem
uh i've adhd um that's not my problem um
but my problem is that uh i love chasing
squirrels and vulnerability disclosures
are perfect places like you go read a
vulnerability disclosure and you're like
i wonder where else that is in open
source like how many other places can i
find that vulnerability
and the problem for me is that if i use
codeql or if i use code github code
search
i will find too many security
vulnerabilities
and
for example this is um codeql results
for zip slip right i can page through
pages and pages and pages of results for
zip lip vulnerabilities across open
source
so i'm finding too many vulnerabilities
and so
i need a way to fix this problem i can't
just report to all these different
projects i need a way to find to scale
my knowledge of security vulnerabilities
to fixing these vulnerabilities in in a
more productive way and so i need
automation
and so at this point i'm going to pass
it off to patrick to discuss um open
rewrite
thanks jonathan
yeah so that is a challenge i mean
jonathan really expressed a couple of
challenges that he faced right like hey
i want to use this regular expression
and of course that's a problem or i'm
going to use an xml parser and it's
going to come back goblin goop and
not be a viable pull request so and then
there's scale how do we detect all these
things
[Music]
all right
all right so he needs automated
transformations at scale
and this is where this is where open
rewrite comes in um
you know somehow as software engineers
we're professional automators we we
automate
anything that we can possibly automate
it's just in our blood it's what we do
but for some reason in 2022
most of us are still slogging through
the tedious task of updating that
dependency finding the breaking change
uh you know a framework upgrade whatever
it may be it's a tedious task and we
like burn our fingers on the keyboard to
do it well finally
finally we have an opportunity to do
something different finally it is 2022
and now as software engineers we can
start automating our own tedious tasks
and
this is one of those projects when i
learned about it for the first time i
realized like this is something new this
is this is game changing right we've
been writing daos and business logic for
who knows how many years but now
now you get to write
code for your own code the the model
that you're working with is your code
it's it's
it's amazing and it's incredible
so what what makes it amazing what makes
it possible and and what really is it so
there's a need to transform code and it
was discovered that hey the compiler
represents source code as an abstract
syntax tree it's like compiler's
representation of source code it's bare
minimum but if you look at that tree you
can kind of
start to formulate ideas on like hey i
could i could transform that tree
i could write it back to a source file
and i could i could make a diff i could
make some change well
that's a nice concept but
again the compiler's ast is bare minimum
there's no formatting the compiler
doesn't compare but care about comments
or spaces or tabs
if you modify that and write it back to
a file you're going to get
not a pull request
so one of the first challenges for open
rewrite was to make this a fully format
preserving abstract syntax tree so now
we have an abstract syntax tree that
preserves that precious white space and
the comments and all that contextual
information that's so valuable to
developers and you can write that tree
back to a file that's identical to its
origin
so that's a huge unlock
if you're able to do that we're also
able to auto detect the style so we need
to write source we need to transform
code and write it back according to the
style of that particular project so open
re-reg will detect like hey this is
using spaces this is using tabs this
maybe has two spaces in a tab uh you
know the the nuance is like braces on a
new line so all that is done for you by
the framework
but there's another challenge so we we
got past the the fully uh you know the
format preserving
but
again a compiler's ast is single level
that the type information is not it's
not fully typed so you you look at that
log.info and is it log4j is it slf or j
is it something custom you need you need
the full depth of type information on
that tree
another problem that was solved by the
open rewrite team
and with that what you end up with is we
have a fully type attributed format
preserving abstract syntax tree it's
syntactically and semantically aware
and if you compare that to the compilers
tree you can see like that's dense
there's a lot of information there's a
lot right there that you can use to make
accurate
transformations at scale that
match the format of their source
well
even a simple simple tree
is a complex ast right just a simple bit
of code is a complex axt if jonathan is
going to do this at scale we have to
provide him with the tools to be able to
get beyond the tedium
one of the biggest challenges like so
is is take take this little conditional
statement here jonathan is going to
share with you a recipe a zip slip
recipe in a little bit and he needs to
insert this conditional statement into a
block of code
to do that and to
to handle the formatting and everything
else for all the different projects
would be nearly impossible so what we
have is we have a templating engine the
templating engine allows jonathan to
build a tree
out of a out of code so he can write
code in in java and build an abstract
syntax tree from it and he can do it in
two statements
so here here's an example of building up
a java template you can see that there's
the conditional statement it's got some
handy features like uh
parameter substitution and etc you'll
notice that there's not a lot of
formatting
and this is where he's going to apply it
to the tree it's got a coordinate system
so you can say hey take this bit of code
substitute these parameters and place it
in this spot
in the end
he can go through thousands of
repositories find a vulnerability and
insert that conditional statement
exactly where it belongs with the exact
correct formatting
and so with that i'll hand it back to
jonathan so he can share with you some
of the more work that he's done on it
thank you patrick
so
with open rewrite
with the with what ownvocal rewrite
provides what other vulnerabilities can
we fix
um and what what's possible now so i'm
going to talk to you about three
different security security
vulnerabilities and uh talk through open
rewrites of application to fixing those
vulnerabilities so the first
vulnerability we're going to tackle is
temporary directory hijacking
so temporary directory hijacking the
basis of temp directory hijacking is
that on unix like systems the system
temp directory is shared between all
users this is not applicable to windows
and mac os but on most other units like
linux operating systems
the temporary directory is shared shared
between all users
and this is the vulnerability
this is the way that you will find a lot
of java code creates a temporary
directory in java where they will create
a temporary file call delete and call
minter
and the reason that this pattern exists
is because prior to java 1.7 there did
not exist an api in the java standard
library to create a temporary directory
and so what people did was this pattern
of creating a file deleting it and
creating a temp directory and this
creates a randomly named pseudorandom or
using a pr uh
secure random number generator generates
a random name for the file
um this also if you were to look up on
stack overflow how do you create a
temporary directory in java this would
have been the solution and unfor
unfortunately you'd end up with this
vulnerability
and so this vulnerability exists
here it's a race condition between the
delete and the make dir and the reason
this vulnerability exists is because
um
an attacker can see the creation of the
file and see that that file gets deleted
and then race the java process to create
the temporary directory before the java
process does
and the reason this is a vulnerability
is because make dir if it fails returns
false
not it does not throw an exception
and so the way to fix this vulnerability
is to throw that logic into an if block
that's one valid solution but it's
imperfect and the reason that it's
imperfect is because when you use maker
you're using the default uh you name set
uh the default u name and that will make
the directory with all open permissions
to let it be it will not be editable by
other another user but it will be
visible to all other users so if you're
writing sensitive information into that
directory that directory's contents can
be viewed by all of the local users on
the system
and so this is the fix it's to use the
new java files api which has a create
temp directory call um which is secure
and this vulnerability that i i found a
bunch of different places has i've
received a bunch of cvs for this um and
so i said okay there's more of this than
just these cvs let's try doing both pull
request generation
and so that's what we did
um and so far um
it's actually number is not up to date i
i i did more last night but um i don't
know exactly what it is all it's in a
later slide but at least 64 pull
requests
and this is what the pull request looks
like you can see that there's the
deletion of the delete and the maker and
the replacement with this new api call
but we can do more complicated
transformations than that
let's say that those makers and deletes
were used inside of an if block you can
also remove those because they're no
longer needed and just replace it with
that single
line vulnerability number two that i
want to talk to you about is uh partial
path traversal
so the basis of partial past reversal
let's assume that you have two local
users on a fought on a system user sam
and you want to isolate your logic to
only operate within the directory user
sam
and you have another user on that system
user slash samantha
partial path traversal allows an
attacker to access a sibling directory
with the same prefix
and so taking this example again
um where user sam and we have user
samantha um if you're sandboxing your
logic to user sam it's vulner you can
access user samantha because it's a it's
just it's a prefix of user sam or sorry
user sam is a prefix of user samantha
and this is the vulnerability
the vulnerability uh and the reason this
vulnerability exists
is because
when you call a file
when you call the method get canonical
path on a java file
you'll notice that
the trailing slash gets dropped from the
string
and so
what you're comparing is not when you're
using this in a string comparison you're
comparing paths without the trailing
slash
and so going back to this vulnerability
the example is let's take user sam and
put those into the two locations in code
where they're going to end up
and then we have a user supplied input
that comes in which is dot dot slash
samantha slash baz when that gets
appended together you're going to end up
with user slash samantha slash baz and
this bypasses this
guard
and so what's the fix for this
vulnerability well going back to the
original example
what we're looking for
is um this is this is one valid fix
where you re-add the slash back in
however you're still doing string
comparisons and that's less than ideal
um a better solution
is to um replace
uh the uh get canonical path with get
canonical file turn that into a path
object and do starts with comparisons on
the path object
because java's path object will do this
comparison and do this starts with check
correctly
so how do we find this vulnerability to
actually fix it
well first what we need to look for is
we need to look for starts with calls on
that you need to look for starts with
you need to look for the string method
starts with call and then you need to
look before and after and see the get
canonical paths on either side that
starts with call but you also if you're
going to fix this vulnerability
correctly you also want to make sure
that you're also filtering out cases
where that
slash that
separator character is being appended
correctly
it can't be that easy though can it
well
developers also write code in a lot of
different ways what happens if the
developer doesn't just write this but
they extract one half of this to a
variable
or they extract
or they extract the second argument to a
variable or let's say that the correct
logic is extracted to a variable
how do you identify this vulnerability
still existing even in the context of
of that logic being pulled out into a
separate variable we need this concept
called data flow analysis
so data flow analysis lets us
track
the uh logic from the sources of
variables and how they end up where
they're uh how they end up flowing to
variables and this lets us for example
see
that these variables are getting
assigned to these different locations
and it can be more complicated than this
it can also go through intermediate
variables
so data flow allows us to uncover hard
defined vulnerabilities and prevents
false positives
and
um the data flow analysis api is very is
modeled after coqls so if you're
familiar with codeql or you learned open
rewrite you can translate that knowledge
back and forth between these two
languages and these two frameworks to
find these vulnerabilities and also fix
them
and putting it all together you can see
in this example
where the path
was removed or this path that was
vulnerable gets replaced in this place
and so this is an example of the actual
diff that was generated for partial path
reversal
um i have a brief aside story because
it's just was just too funny not to tell
um there's a case study of this
vulnerability cve uh
five 2022-31159 uh the vulnerability
existed in the uh aws java sdk
um and it was partial past reversal they
were created this guard which was
checking to see if
while downloading the contents of an aws
s3 bucket if the s3 bucket key
um
uh
was was traversing outside of the
destination directory while you were
downloading the entire contents of the
s3 bucket
and you can see that this this partial
path reversal vulnerability was being
used as a guard against path traversal
in this leaves root logic
and uh so this got a vulnerability cv
assigned to it everything went well fine
on that
but there was a little bit of drama in
another way
i had an email with the aws security
team uh where they sent me this email
and they said we'd like to award you a
bug bounty uh however you need to sign
an nda for this for the for us to award
you this amount and i said i don't
normally agree to ndas can i read it
first potentially before agreeing
and aws came back to me and said we're
unable to share the bug bounty program
nda because it and other legal other
contract documents are considered
sensitive by the legal team
it was it was like
amazon used uh legalese and it hurt
itself in its confusion like
so uh story that just could not be not
told as a part of this um all right so
the third vulnerability is zip slip
um so people who have been hackers for a
very very long time are probably know
what this is but to summarize zip slip
is a path traversal vulnerability that
exists while unpacking zip file entries
because zips are just you know a name of
where you want the desk the pad the file
to end up to the contents of the zip
file
um
and so this this vulnerability can exist
in java um because it's very easy to
unpack zip files um
and so this is the logic to un that
you'll see in a lot of places to unpack
zip files the snick team did a bunch of
research back in 2018 to eliminate a lot
of this vulnerability from the open
source ecosystem they reported it to a
bunch of different open source projects
not just in java but other languages as
well
um and uh their fix was you know for the
most part correct but there were certain
cases that actually were still
vulnerable to partial path reversal from
zip slip um but you know that that's
neither here nor there um the uh so this
is the subset of the logic that that
leaves you vulnerable
um it's that the entry name
um flows to
this file output stream when you're and
you're copying the contents of this file
output stream so you're using
potentially malicious zip files to
download the con or to you're you're
unpacking potentially malicious zip
files into uh an
outside of the destination directory
potentially if there's a pat if the
attacker has supplied a pass reversal
payload in the entry name
so zip slip is complicated
the zip link is complicated because in
order to fix it
you need to add this guard
that protects against this vulnerability
existing
um you're you're checking to make sure
that the uh
that the the file is within the
destination directory
but the further problem with this is
that even though that's a valid fix
there are other valid fixes as well
this so this is one valid fix for it but
this is another one where you just put
the logic inside of an if check
and so in order to determine if you are
not going to be able to reach this logic
you need a new concept and it's called
control flow analysis
and so control flow analysis lets us
determine that
is there a guard in place that protects
against this vulnerability or not right
so the version on the left does need to
get fixed but the version on the right
does not because there's a valid
protection against this vulnerability
and control flow analysis uh did not
exist in open rewrite prior to the work
that we were doing um but it it lets
when we added it it enabled us
to take um this you know take up take a
chunk of java and produce a graph
which is
at every jump what uh what is you know
what what chunks of logic are reachable
and so that lets us for example for zip
slip we can build a control flow graph
or zip slip and traverse that graph and
determine that if you reach the starts
with call and that is false then there
will be an exception thrown and that
that untrusted logic will not be reached
so you'll it's a valid guard against
this against reaching um that potential
vulnerability vulnerable logic
and so when we put this all together
this is the example of the diffs that
you can generate
um and you know here's another example
where you can see we've not only you
know
fixed the code but we've also
cleaned up the surrounding code as well
and so uh pull request generation right
let's go do some pull request generation
if you've got security vulnerabilities
you can get a pull request
um so the problems with pull request
generation one of the things that you'll
run into really quickly is how fast can
you generate pull requests
when you're generating pull requests
um i think i said real fast
there are three different types of steps
that you need to make
there's file io
there are git operations
and there's the github api calls
and file i o is basically free because
it's happening on your local machine you
have git operations on github those are
free they're not rate limited but then
you have github api calls that are rate
limited
so the first step is you check out the
source code and download it
which is a git operation and then you
file i o which is branching applying the
diff and committing the change then you
fork the repository on github which
does actually um
um that so you fork the repository on
github um which is an api call
um and then uh you rename the repository
and github and you push the changes um
again a git operation and then you
create a pull request on github so of
these things there's three api calls
and the three api calls
um
there's a story behind this
the you have three api calls um that uh
are neat that are rate limited by github
right and so github recommends that for
every um request or for every uh every
between every request you wait at least
one second
um additionally there are other rate
limits that are in place that they want
to prevent you spam users or malicious
users from generating more pull requests
uh they don't want people spamming
maintainers right they their users are
maintainers they so they're trying to
protect their users so if their their
protection of users unfortunately
limits our ability to do this work of
security researchers um so if there's
anybody github in the audience if you
could stop rate limiting your api or at
least not doing as much that'd be
greatly appreciated
so we've made it this far
um we've vulnerabilities have been
detected style's been detected um code
has been fixed and the rate limit's been
bypassed um
how do we do this for all the open
source repositories that we want to fix
and i'm going to pass it back to uh
patrick to discuss modern
down button
well first
let me make sure i've got it right side
up
we'd like to the open rewrite team we
would really like to thank jonathan and
shawn for their work
on behalf of open rewrite i'd really
like to commend jonathan ansham for
their work to add control flow and data
flow to the project
not an easy task these guys worked hard
they put their heads down and they
pulled it off so some context shawn is
my intern who has been working he's in
the back but he's he was essential to
making control flow something that was
possible nice nice job yeah you guys you
guys rocked it
all right so
modern is a company that's supporting
open rewrite
and we we provide a uh a free service
for open source projects
um it allows you to run you know our 800
plus recipes over 7000 plus repositories
um
you could do your transformations at
scale you can you can find usages of
types of method implications all across
either all of all the seven repositories
that we have ingested or whatever you
have in your organization
and it'll also generate an update pull
request for you this is really what's
allowing jonathan to scale
so as i mentioned before
the open rewrite the suite of projects
we've got testing frameworks logging
frameworks rewrite spring
rewrite kubernetes
you name it we've got a whole suite of
projects we have more than 800 recipes
including complete framework migration
so uh you know j in it four to five is a
really tedious uh transformation to make
we have a recipe for that you want to
get from spring boot one to two you need
to do
uh cheating at four to five
we can bundle that all together so the
developer is not having to sit there and
bang their
head on the keyboard and just work their
fingers to the bone with all these
tedious changes
so back to pull request generation
jonathan he's finding vulnerabilities
everywhere he's got a handy-dandy recipe
to fix them and now he needs to get
those out
madarin also provides the ability to
to run that recipe costs all 7 000
repositories that are indexed and
generate pull requests for them you can
see they have a message that's uh
contextual and
and
yeah lots of results
so
i could talk about this or we can kind
of give you a quick little demo of video
here you can see it's it's run the
recipe
it's generated some results it's
jonathan putting together a message he's
put it signing his his pull request and
off it goes it's it's running through
building pull requests at scale so now
as jonathan finds those squirrels
everywhere
he's got he's got the tool to fix him
so
now
so there's more than seven thousand
repositories in the world um how do we
find the other vulnerable projects right
and this circles back around to what we
were talking about at the beginning of
the talk codeql
so codeql uh as i said before it uh
index uh indexes over a hundred thousand
open source projects and at least thirty
five thousand open source java projects
um it's they support python cubase plus
um see python go
uh
and some i think there's some other
languages in there too but um
it lets you write queries to find these
vulnerabilities at scale and so those
queries because there's more than 7000
open source projects out there you can
use codeql to identify the vulnerable
projects and then you need to make open
rewrite aware of them or the modern sas
aware of them and the way to do that is
you just generate a poll or you open a
pull request against this repository and
add to the csv file and then open
rewrite will try to go out and build
that project
to
to index and let you generate pull
requests
so finally let's go generate some pull
this is
basically all of the the giant pull
requests that are projects that i've
i've either been a part of are aware of
the only one that i actually was not
directly involved with is the our
hostname array uh one where github used
my python bot to generate those pull
requests to fix uh a
uh
array overflow vulnerability um but the
other ones and these are all pull
requests that i've generated and for new
pull requests as of 2020 i've generated
over 9 5 000 sorry wow 590 pull requests
um and to my name across my history as
an open source security researcher i've
generated over 5200 pull requests
and uh one of the projects funnily
enough the three different the three pro
uh
the three vulnerabilities discussed in
this talk um there was one unfortunate
open source project that received all
three pull requests um
uh so yeah and this is my github
contribution graph for 2022. uh it's not
done yet but you know you can see the
the impact of bulk holder across
generation on that
and so now i want to talk to you about
some of the best practices for uh bulk
polarized generation
first off messaging
um
you're dealing with maintainers you're
dealing with real people
um
there's a saying all software problems
are people problems in disguise this is
100 one of those cases right you're
dealing with actual people maintainers
of the software um and
you need to be sensitive about that
you're not just disclosing a security
vulnerability you're not just disclosing
a bug in this you're disclosing a
security vulnerability and so there's a
certain amount of ego that gets wrapped
up in this we're challenging not just
you've had a bug which maintainers have
been pretty normalized to but you've
developed you've had a security
vulnerability that could put your users
at risk you're you're hitting them in
somewhere that's different and they're
not used to and you need to be careful
about that
um
so lesson that's that's the you know
lesson zero so lesson one about this um
sign off on your commits
um and this is what github sign up this
is basically uh you add this to your
commit messages
um and why well the reason why is uh
there was a bunch of lawsuits a lotta
yada yada tldr lawyers
um
if you don't your pull requests will be
rejected by evil dragon bureaucrats uh
so
gpgs are sorry uh
sign off on your commits
lesson number two be a good commit is in
gpg sign your commits
um if you so this is what signing your
commits looks like it shows up as
verified um and you won't end up like
somebody impersonating linus tar torvald
on github because you know uh so if you
gpg sign your commits um it'll prevent
this lesson three um there's a commit
there's a standard called ccom which is
a commit format um and if you lay it out
thank you thank you
so the story i'll tell it when this is
over but yes
there's a story i'll tell this one this
is over so sec thank you so much i
appreciate i asked
we have a tradition where speakers are
allowed to make an outrageous request
when they submit their talk yes we
accept their talk and we like the
request
we'll fulfill it
however we often fulfill it in sort of a
slightly evil genie sort of way so
thank you you are quack quack thank you
i appreciate it yes
there's a longer story so this is not
the first duck that i've ever seen i
spoke i spoke about the zoom
vulnerability which i found in shmukon
and for some strange women somebody
brought a duck up on stage for me
because i also use the duck in that talk
so i try to put the duck in every talk
and so i just said hey if you want to
bring one that'd be great and lo and
behold they have
all right
taking a step back
um ccom so it's a commit message
standard for for putting all the
information in about a vulnerability
into the commit message so that it's
parsable um
uh yes
lesson number four um there are risks to
using your personal github account
um anybody here who's familiar with
github uh github's angry unicorn
this is github's angular unicorn that
occurs when you hit a 500 error
this is my github profile for most 2022.
sorry 2020. um
uh
and the only way that i was able to fix
it was by reaching out to github support
and i'm also github star talking to them
directly and and asking uh to help so
you can break your github account if you
do this uh fair warning um
coordinate with github uh there is
there's a benefit to doing this because
if you if you use your personal account
and p and maintainers have issues and
comments you'll get notifications and
you can engage with them which is
important from the communication side so
there are risks but there are also an ad
an advantage to doing it this way
um
[Music]
uh yes this is my github profile for
most of you coordinate with github
um i reached out to github before
attempting this um they want to know
that you're doing this so that you're
not spamming they want to make sure
you're not spamming people so it's a
good thing to do
and then lesson number five is consider
the implications
um shortly after engaging in my most
recent round of bulk plural quest
generation i received this issue on my
security research uh i have a j light
shoe slash security research uh get a
repository is this responsible
responsible disclosure now i use the
term coordinated disclosure when i do
vulnerability exposures which is the new
more nuanced term um
but
either way you're going to call it
coordinated disclosure responsible
disclosure the answer is no this is full
disclosure of a vulnerability you're
odaying them potentially and that there
are implications there that you need to
consider
um
i argue that given the scale of the
amount of vulnerabilities in open source
it it actually
is a better net good to fix
vulnerabilities like this than it is to
not report them at all because that's
the alternative that i'm facing there's
only so much time in a day that i have
as a researcher and so
you're gonna end up full disclosing this
vulnerability
but the net benefit to the security the
internet is more is positive
and so
i want to leave you this this conclusion
as security researchers
i feel we have an obligation to society
we know that these vulnerabilities are
out there
and we know how to fix them we've
written pen test reports we've seen them
in source code reviews we've had them
come in from you know a variety of
different places right we understand how
these vulnerabilities exist
there's this problem in the industry
for every 500 developers you only have
one security researcher this is from
github in 2020.
so we are vastly outnumbered right
and
spoiler a lot of developers don't watch
besides talks don't watch black hat
talks don't watch defcon talks right
it's the unfortunate nature of the world
right so how are we going to be able to
best scale our knowledge
of
math science technology security and the
vulnerabilities that are out there to do
the most good in the world
and i argue that security uh pull
request generation
in this manner is the best way
to have the most positive impact in the
in in the security world or in this for
the security of open source
and with that i want to leave you with
one final quote from dan
um
this is on dan's twitter account um
it's still there to this day
we can fix it
we have the technology
okay we need to create the technology
all right the policy guys are mucking
with the technology relax
we're on it
i want to leave you
uh with some uh sound bites uh learn
code ql uh it's a really powerful
language um it's not
easy but you'll get it like it takes a
learning curve but it's worth learning
um you can do a lot with it you can find
really cool vulnerabilities it's really
cool writing a query and just having
them fall out of open source it really
it's really that easy they just start
falling out of of the open source code
um
contribute to open rewrite and you can
deploy your security fixes at scale
and then join the github security lab
and open rewrite slack channels where
you can discuss with me and other
security researchers who are trying to
tackle this problem of open source
security um to fix these vulnerabilities
i'm also going to toss on there if
you're interested in open security open
source security in general um consider
joining the open source security
foundation which is a subs it's a
project on the under the linux
foundation where a lot of the security
the discussions around the security of
open source are being discussed in
working group meetings every single week
so
um and then finally i want to say thank
you to human my employer um modern uh
for being spectacular and enabling this
work to even be possible uh lydia uh who
uh helped we ran she was the black hat
speaker coach that we ran this by like
way too many times to get this into the
state it was in and then sean my intern
who uh was instrumental in allowing
control flow analysis to exist um
so
also the graphics for control flow or
where some of his work so um thank you
that's that's us
[Applause]
my
yeah so your question was um what other
languages does open rewrites support
besides java
we have a xml we let's see
xml javascript
we're working on javascript yes working
on cobalt yes um
hcl
um kotlin's in the works properties no
not just not javascript currently
javascript's in the works um java
uh
gradle build files that's right um
groovy groovy
uh
yeah so it's
dominant predominantly java currently
but there's there's a lot of other work
going on it needs to support a bunch of
other languages too so
um yeah anybody else
going once
we'll take any questions i promise
going twice
yeah so
yes i try to put the wack duck in every
single one of my talks and uh yes so
this is a callback to that but also to
my previous zoom talk uh about
the oday that i dropped in zoom back in
2019. so go back and if you're curious
about that vulnerability go back it's
shmukon i talked about the zoom
vulnerability that i found so
um
any yeah any last questions yes go for
it yeah
so the question is it's
the goal of the best practices
about about trying to mitigate being
evil
and it's not just about mitigating being
evil it's like you're dealing with real
people but you're also
you don't want to come across as a bad
actor right because get up will bank
if you're a bad actor right like i mean
they will take into account like you're
trying to do the right thing but like
you don't want to get banned from github
um so
yeah i
it's about trying to
uh do the right thing in the context of
also fully disclosing a security
vulnerability in public if there was a
way to do this quote you know in a way
that was private if github supported
private issues like creating a private
issue or a private uh pull request
i would 100 percent go down that route
it just does it's not it's not supported
by get a current
john hook like you have a
question no okay just checking
yes go for it um
[Music]
um
are there so are there organization
bought organizational bodies around this
sort of effort
no there is no so
as far as i'm aware
work like this around fixing
vulnerabilities at scale in this way
i am not aware of any other large-scale
efforts besides the ones that i've
engaged in to do this now they've not
i've seen for example like i've seen the
jenkins project go and generate a bunch
of pull requests specifically for the
jenkins project so like that's the
security team from jenkins doing that
specifically but i have not seen there's
no major project
that is actively engaged in this um this
has been something that i've been it's
been a project that i've been passionate
about and that's why i applied to the
dan kaminsky fellowship saying
i do this thing i have done this thing i
want to do more of it and they accepted
my application to enable me to try to
see what i could do in a year to to
scale this thing that i've been doing as
a side project into a full-time job so
this was my full-time job for the past
since january was working on this
project um
and uh
so yeah so that that's that's what
enabled this um i would love to chat if
you want to do more of this because i
want to do more of this in like i think
that more of this is awesome um yeah
anybody else open to any questions
or you can also come chat with us
afterwards i think that's
anybody okay thank you all for coming i
really appreciate it thank you thank you
and if you want to chat with us or you
can reach out to me on twitter uh i'm
also available there so thank you