good morning everyone this is breaking
ground so you want to build a c2 uh
before we kick off a few quick
announcements as always like to thank
our sponsors especially our diamond
sponsors lastpass and palo alto networks
gold sponsors intel google blue cat uh
it's their support that makes this event
possible uh because we are being
streamed live please turn off your cell
phones we do not have audience bikes in
this room so raise your hand high after
the talk and we will call on you
uh and lastly uh just a reminder photo
policy does not allow taking photos of
other attendees and math should be kept
on at all times with that please welcome
i digital
fan good morning everybody or afternoon
as it feels like to me honestly uh
welcome so so you want to build a c2
um so i'm going to talk about some crazy
stuff that went through uh me building a
c2 that is fully in use today kind of
actually in the current ctf that's
literally running right next door to us
okay cool so give a little bit of
background to myself um obviously i'm a
security guy i love to program i love
linux a lot
i love windows really because i've been
forced a lot of my life to work on it
i'm creator of too many projects account
and at my day job i kind of do more
social security architecture stuff some
offensive purple teaming things and i do
a lot of work for prosv joe's so mainly
i do a lot of work with the red team as
you can see
but also i do a lot of work with the
gold team maintaining
infrastructure and architecture and kind
of doing system administration stuff
there
so stupid beginnings as i say every
project starts with a stupid idea
so we're going to take take us back to
2011 the dark ages of java a long time
ago when i started college i was
learning java as one of the programming
languages you know in my stack that i
know today and you know they say kind of
laziness breeds innovation i kind of
feel like it more breeds stupidity at
least myself
me being me i was really lazy and i
wanted to encrypt data at rest and i
looked at the implementation of aes in
java and i said no screw that i don't
want to do that that's too much so you
know what i did i did the best thing
possible i rolled my own crypto
don't do that um it led to it's uh led
to the invention of cbk which is a sort
of lazy man's encryption um it stands
for cipher block key it's like some like
uh round cipher thing it's probably
super duper insecure
but i still listed on github
so kind of going forward now um now it's
like 2017. i started learning going uh
because my work kind of wanted me to
develop some projects that were kind of
uh architecture and os independent so
the the language at the time really to
learn was go and i was like awesome so
me being myself a person who kind of
learns by doing i really needed a
project to learn i needed something to
do outside of my job like kind of the
things i needed to do because i wanted
to like dive into the actual stuff that
go kind of provides so what i did is i
revisited some old projects to rewrite
um i ended up actually looking to cbk to
rewrite i was like you know can i make
this crap code run faster completely
forgetting it's super insecure
so uh we'll get to where that
comes in but um so
at the time currently i was doing a lot
of red team development as well as most
of my life in cyber security i was doing
basically offensive stuff um now the
thing was is
while doing all this i never really
found a tool that like worked correctly
that really fit the needs that i wanted
there was things that were missing like
there were workarounds you had to do and
they were like super clunky um things
could be dependency heavy or you know
the setup was like super annoying so you
know that actually led me to a lot of
the tools that i've you know built today
there are some super c2-ish things that
i've made like ws bind there's some like
exploits and things i developed some of
the things i've already previously
talked on like in your mems which is a
talk on antivirus evasion i've also made
some utilities and i also made some
stuff like kind of for trolling and
shits and giggles realistically
so
that all leads to xmt xmt stands for the
extensible malware toolkit
so you might be asking what is xmt xmt
is an offensive security framework it
does a lot of malicious things really
well and i say malicious things i mean
like anything the miter attack framework
may cover like you know dll injection
assembly injection um you know processed
doppelganging etc um and it provides c2
functionality and the only thing that's
missing from that c2 functionality
honestly is a user interface and what i
mean by that is there's no button i can
click to say do this i'd have to script
all that out but everything else is
still there
the one cool thing that i made this with
and i like an idea with is that it can
be extended for any purpose so i leave a
lot of room for users to input functions
to change how it works to add things to
extend functionality there's pretty much
like anything you can extend it to like
anything that really you can put your
mind to encode
uh the one good thing about it it's
since it's go it's multi-platform
multi-operating system so i've actually
took some time to make sure that it
supports and it works on every operating
system and every os that golang
currently supports in mainline
but however sorry
but however it's currently windows
favored so meaning like a lot of the
kind of the toys and the cool things in
windows uh that it does support really
only work on windows at the moment i'm
adding some linux support as i go but
some of those are kind of hard to do one
to one
and uh currently on the picture on the
right well it's on
kind of my right um that's the status of
the repo as it is right now and
currently we're at 32 000 lines uh as we
speak
so what did i want in xmd when i was
developing it i kind of wanted to be
easy to use i want it to be modular
flexible i want to be simple at the same
time so i wanted something to be you
know configurable to an extent where it
works out the box but also i could you
know kind of change up how it works i
wanted things to be
not dependency heavy so i didn't want to
rely on a lot of things
and i also wanted to have a small build
footprint you know i shouldn't have to
spend time building my implants i should
spend more time like popping boxes and
throwing shells
so kind of giving a quick list of the
things that make up xmc i know it's a
lot uh we have the overlying c2 package
which contains like most of the c2
functions
uh config transform wrapper we will
actually talk about in the next slides
uh there is also the task package which
doesn't really make a super big
appearance but it basically handles
everything when it comes to tasking or
uh you know if you want to create custom
tasks for xmt to do
then you have the cmd library which
contains everything executable so like
literally anything dsls assembly um you
know etc
uh the filter library the subpackage
filter under it contains the cool filter
um struct that we can use to literally
select processes that we want to target
so we can set parent processes or
processes that own are like assembly or
a dll et cetera and we have like cool
things like setting the parent uh
setting if it's like executable it's in
a session or it's a service um like
excluded processes etc then we have our
communication library which contains
most of our communication privilege uh
primitives the limits library puts guard
rails around some of the things we can
do
which is kind of cool then we have the
pipe package which is actually a
it's before the golang implemented
name pipes and it's sublet it's standard
library but this actually supports linux
and windows and it supports setting
security permissions on your pipes as
well so you can do a lot more cool
things with it
wc2 is my own version of a web c2 are
basically connections over http and
we'll actually get into that as well
data is just a package allows the right
uh data primitives like any golang
primitive it contains some like cool
really util helper functions including
some like memory buffers and such crypto
same it's just some more cryptographic
operation things
device is actually one of the coolest
packages and one of the largest it
contains basically everything from
interfacing directly with the device
we're on
so we have the evade package which does
like defense evasion some other things
like overriding hooks that might be
placed in us by antivirus
we have a local package that deals with
identifying and detecting things on a
local host
we have the regedit package which is a
high level interface for the windows
registry
then we have one api the window api
registry and window api service when api
is actually my own rewrite of the
windows or the standard library windows
package for golang and we'll talk about
that one
the registry package under is the same
thing it's my rewrite of the golang
register package and service is also
again a rewrite
man is the home of guardian and sentinel
guardian is our sentinel is a loader for
xmt and allows you to basically load it
into like any process debate based on
your rule settings like load it from
like a http endpoint from a dll from a
file and disk whatever
guardian allows you to keep a singleton
instance running current currently on
the device and it will keep that
instance regardless of you know what
persistent mechanism you use so you're
not like actually running a thousand
implants on a host
lastly of util it's just like a basic
utilities directory uh contains some
things we'll get into x error because
it's a custom implementation of
the errors package you go it does some
really cool stuff that we'll get into
bug tracks is a debugging library that
allows uh you to to kind of log you know
if the process crashes or anything super
helpful
text also contains a red regex free
uh text matching algorithm and uh
basically uh parser so you can do like
some really cool textual expressions
without all the bloat that the regex
package in golang provides
lastly we have crypt and i will talk
about crypt in a little bit it's a sort
of textual cryptographic helper that
we'll get into that allows you to do
defensive asian
so i know that was a really long thing
but i want to highlight now some of the
things that actually and some of the
interesting things that are actually
take part into xmt itself
so one of the first things if you're
developing a c2 is identification it's
like one of the most important things
basically it's the process of getting to
know our host device so it might be like
the os version the architecture um the
you know interfaces uh which and ip
addresses it may have
then also is basically generating unique
identifiers that are unique to that host
specifically as well as any environment
info so like the username the domain it
may be running under if it's windows and
like your basic process and parent
process id values for example
and what this actually led me to is we
ended up having to uh
create our own ud uid library we
originally used the machine id library
but it seems it's abandoned now since
like 2019 and unmaintained so we created
our own which actually used some a
little bit cooler features
and used
a better identification system in
windows such as using the system sid
instead of like the cryptographic hash
of windows which doesn't change as much
compared and is actually a little bit
more unique
and that actually led us to generating a
32-bit or 32-bit identifier which
generates a 32-byte machine specific id
called the signature and a three-bit
instance specific call just a device
session id and basically these like uh
these 32 bytes generate this session id
that's unique across every single host
that you connect to
so networking speaking computer
now developing this
i wanted to be super protocol agnostic
and you know honestly the lazy man in me
really didn't want to write code for
like different types of connections uh
you know i wouldn't be able to handle
pretty much anything without having to
worry about what the underlying
connection is i didn't want to have to
you know write workarounds for something
stupid
and i also wanted to make complex
connections well easy i didn't want to
like i wanted i wanted to have complex
connections but i didn't want myself or
like anybody else on the other end to
have to deal with
all the bull crap of like managing that
connection like i don't want to have to
anybody deal with that
and what i ended up doing is these
things now basically operate on the
net.com interface which is just you know
basic to go
so networking so some of the things that
do go into networking we actually
actually took the uh idea and split it
out into a thing called connectors and
basic connectors are the simple
interface that provides the ability to
listen and or connect
and it's defined actually in code by two
interfaces which is one the connector it
accepts a context and a string you want
to connect to and then it returns like a
netcon and or an error and the acceptor
interface which gives you a you provide
a contacts and a bind address that
returns a net listener and or an error
some can actually support both
some are you know one some are the other
but most of them do have support for
both built in
so and we have for built-in current
support we have tcp udp ip icmp http
https tls mtls and you know like i said
before a lot of things you can create
custom ones for this so the
the
ability for you to create custom ones
you just have to basically implement
these interfaces then there you go
okay so one special highlight i did want
to talk about is the udp connector so
all connectors at least by default as
you would think they're stream sockets
so meaning you know we're not like
basically we're not looking at packets
we're looking at a raw data stream
now if you know anything about udp udp
is completely packet based
same with ip and icmp for example and we
really needed a way to support streaming
over udp i really don't want to deal
with edp on its own separate thing
so i ended up working on developing my
own custom udp listener
and what this listener does is it
contains its like own connection ring
buffer and what that does is it
maintains a active connections map and
this will take new connections and pipe
them back to uh like the accept calls or
if it already has connection that we are
currently mapping it'll take the data
and push it into the current socket
buffer that we have
and it this makes internal like a heavy
use of channels uh to work uh work on
multiple go routines at the same time
but it actually works up really great
and it's like super rock solid like you
could talk over this as if you were
talking over tcp and you wouldn't know
the difference
um you know i've used this to like send
like hundreds of megabytes of data and
it just goes
um you know which is really awesome
and i ended up taking the success of
this one and using struct inheritance
for the ip icmp connector so now you can
talk over ping or like any kind of you
know ip based protocol as well the same
way and with easy support
so next one the wc2 connector the wc2
connector has the same problem as udp um
you know it's http i didn't want to
restrict just to post you know i didn't
want to kind of send like a thousand
post requests like every second that
would be really suspicious
so you know um i'm no stranger to web
sockets and in fact i wrote the
scoreboard over there which makes heavy
use of websockets so i ain't no stranger
to them but i was like man how can we
implement these
so i dove down into the code golang
source code and it turns out golang will
return some http bodies as read write if
you play nice
but you need really specific conditions
uh one you need a 101 hd uh 101
switching connections uh response from
server
can't be http2 and the server must
hijack that connection and you know this
is kind of obvious when you think about
like web sockets like underneath the
hood this is kind of how they operate
but you need to all do this all in like
a custom way so that way you can
basically jack that connection right out
of there and what happened is we ended
up having to use reflect in order to
grab this because we needed like the
direct neck con
but we can actually index inside the
supplied struct and we can just pull the
connection out of there and now just use
that as if we're talking overall tcp
so
some of the other things that i had to
implement to like kind of improve in
this area
is during my offensive security kind of
lifetime uh and some pen tests is that a
lot of firewalls would block uh http
connections based on like their cookie
state and basically like if it's not it
doesn't recognize it as like a real like
web session because it would basically
apply a cookie to that session over the
proxy and if that session came back
without that cookie you'd be like no i
ain't accepting you so i had to make
sure that we actually like worked on
keeping session state inside as well
and the other thing is we had to add
actually proxy support for it uh golang
doesn't have any windows proxy support
at all um it has like next proxy support
super easy it's all environment variable
based um so what we ended up doing is
and ended up implementing our own uh
proxy function and we call it
device.proxy and it's literally a
one-for-one drop-in of the http proxy
from environment function
which is great so now we can use this
for linux and or windows and it'll just
work out the box um and this uses the
one api i call uh when http get default
proxy configuration which is basically
it returns the either system based or
gpo based proxy config on the host and
we can parse out that data and then get
like any of the proxy like what the http
proxy your http exceptions etc and we
just pull it out and now use it
now the funnest thing i like to talk
about the hardest one uh routing routing
is really super complex and i hate that
it is complex but the reason i made it
complex honestly is because we need to
support like a lot of feature sets
some of the features we didn't need
support would be like multi packets so
if i'm sending data to a host and or
like a command to a host and that's like
one packet for example i don't want to
have to wait for it to connect back to
me again to wait and go send the other
one like i can just send both of them at
the same time like if it hasn't talked
to you back why am i going to wait
another time to send it another packet
so i can send multiple all at the same
time downstream device so we're not
wasting any time
then we want to also handle fragments um
so if the packet's like too big you know
we want to cut it up into bite slices
for example because i mean i don't know
about you but sending a pack a 100 meg
dns packet doesn't look okay
um then also there's a mode we created
called channeling mode channeling mode
basically allows you to break the normal
like kind of weight back for a packet
response from the client or the implant
and now you can act as if you're
directly at the terminal of the machine
so it's like instantaneous feedback or
instantaneous file uploads downloads etc
so we also need to kind of have a work
around that make sure that works
correctly
and last thing proxy connections or
pivoting if you know if you're familiar
with that nomenclature where we wanted
to be able to piggyback off of other
implants connections
and this kind of led us down this huge
you know rabbit hole of basically
working on the thing of routing the
identity and flags
so to kind of uh give a button to that
uh basically we use a struct called
packet which is the
huge basis of enterprise communication
and it contains a thing called flags and
device id
basically flags are a boolean uh state
of a packet as it flows through like the
network to the actual final c2 server
and it totes it notates the fragment
size uh the fragment state as well so
meaning like the group id because we can
wait on multiple fragments if we want to
and then the fragment position inside
that group and then the the total amount
of frags we actually want to receive
also these flags will actually determine
how we want to act on a packet as we can
like optimize the our receiving of
packets like if every packet coming to
us just goes to us we can just
multi-batch process those immediately
versus like if it's a flag multi-packet
meaning that we have to now unpack it
scrutinize and look to see if we can
forward it to like a downstream client
or upstream um so you know we can kind
of use these to like speed up some of
our processes as well
so getting into channels that i talked
about earlier so like i said channels
are a direct connection to the c2 server
like i said the easy way to describe it
it's like you're at the terminal of that
machine it's instantaneous communication
it will work through proxies and pivots
directly as well now the caveat of this
is that every single hop between the uh
implant and the c2 server it enables
channeling mode through and through
because i mean obviously if i'm waiting
on a upstream packet from another device
i you know it's not instantaneous
anymore right so it's going to enable
upstream through every single device so
if whatever end uh sent the flag flag
channel it'll then bam uh instant set
that up and then once whatever sides
like all right i'm done it just sends
black channel end and the whole thing
comes down however if one of the hops
between like a and b
is uh channeling on its own meaning like
that device specifically has decided
it's gonna channel that one stays up
unless that device is like all right i'm
done as well so we're not tearing down
other people's connections
so proxying uh implants can piggyback on
another uh implant meaning like i can
talk to another one behind if i'm like
segmented behind a firewall or something
um the implants don't need to know at
all so like they don't even know they're
talking to proxy they think they're
talking to the c2 which is great we
don't handle it like any any different
and we can use a thing called packet
tags to mark ownership and the reason we
do this is so we can know where to route
packets through we want to have packet
routing super easy so we use a thing
called packet tags which are hashes of
the device id which the server will tap
onto its uh packets that way there's no
extra packets being like added so we're
using less network traffic
and now we can constantly update the
server say hey yeah i still got this guy
i still got this guy i still got this
guy so the server still knows now what
this allows us to do is if we have
multiple instances inside of a network
and there's an instance way down there
deep in the net it can talk to multiple
different hosts and keep switching back
and forth you know and the server on the
other end still knows where it's at and
knows how to route its packets so
nothing gets dropped nothing gets missed
we can you know send them all correctly
so getting into some of the things that
actually make networking really fun at
least for me as a red teamer there's a
concept called wrappers and transforms
and they allow you to augment c2
connection and basically what this means
it allows you to like obfuscate
masquerade or encrypt your connection
we have wrappers which literally wrap
the connection they are stream based
things they have unlimited uses they
have an order so you can go like you
know encryption compression obfuscation
or you can go encryption compression
compression if you want to um then we
have transforms transforms actually
transform the connection they are block
based they access the entire binary
payload before it actually gets written
to the wire so what this means is you
can completely rewrite your your um your
data so you can reverse it if you want
you can change it into a dns packet you
can change it to an image doesn't matter
you do whatever you want with it and but
because of how they work they're only
they can only be used once
so some of the things we do build i have
built-in support for for wrappers for
example are encryption we have xor aes
cbk because i'm funny
we have compression uh gzip and lzo
currently uh we have uh hex and base64
for encoding then transforms right now
we just have base64 and we have dns so
for the dns one i really like that one
because it literally masquerades as a
perfect rfc uh like fitting packet so
like wire shark and everything else is
none the wiser that's a dns like
communication between the two so these
will like masquerade right through like
a level seven firewall or a lighter
seven firewall
so now you may be wondering all this
stuff's going on between like hosts well
like am i wondering about like privacy
or encryption or anything um well yeah i
answered that with key swapping so key
swapping is a thing that's enabled by
default you can disable it by a build
tag and it's basically a lazy mutual
authentication between host and host are
the server and the implant and basically
what happens is when the implant talks
to the server for the first time it will
tag its packet with a specific flag it's
opt-in but if it's built with it it
always opts in and then it sends some
randomized key material at the end of it
and what it'll do is it sends it to the
server the server will then do some math
based on the identifier of the packet um
and some time-based stuff and the um
the mutual like data that the packet has
been sent with then the client on the
other side will do the exact same
mathematic formula and basically now
they have both generated key material or
a key that
neither side is sent across a network so
now they both have a separate key that
they can use to encrypt their packet
data without you know anybody else in
between knowing it
now because of the fact that we use like
uh the ids and the flags for routing we
can only encrypt the actual contents of
the packet so you know uh
the actual data contents of it are
encrypted using xor for speed but like
everything else like the flags and stuff
aren't really encrypted because we can't
really do that
um but the cool thing about it is is
that if i'm sending packets through a
proxy the proxy can't read my packet
data like it has no idea what i'm
sending it just looks like a bunch of
gibberish but the server on the other
end will read it and be like oh cool i
know what this is
and it's rotated regularly so every so
often there's a chance that the client
will say hey server let's do this again
and the client will send some more key
material back to the server and they'll
do the whole song and dance as the
beginning
so now the kind of thing that wraps all
this stuff together profiles
these things bring implant settings
together with a little bit of twists
they are a binary table that are kind of
like a uh type length value uh format
but they can also be in json if you want
to be like stealthier and smaller uh
smaller in your binary size you can
actually disable json parsing
but it contains settings for containers
wrappers and transforms
excuse me and i contain multiple c2
servers
so if you have multiple hosts that you
wanted to connect to it'll just select
one and send it to
but they can also tame things called
selectors and groups which i'm going to
talk about next slide
selectors in groups they are one of the
coolest things in my opinion they can
basically break up a profile into
multiple like separate like sub profiles
and what this allows the implant to do
is it changes its encryption or like it
changes how it acts on the wire so like
it's encryption who it's talking to how
it acts it can completely change that up
and that's without any interactions from
the person like operating it like this
will do it automatically so you know
it'll switch it up like either you know
based on like a time or based on
randomization and um if the server's
configured on the other end to accept
this still then it just keeps going like
nothing's nothing happened and basically
we use selectors to kind of determine
how we switch these then we have like
last valid which says hey if you know
the first one hits an error switch to
the next one or random just as mad chaos
just switch to one like every single
time
or we have round robin which is every
connection operation switch to the next
one on a weighted based order
semi-round robin same thing but if
there's a 25 chances hit then switch 75
chance don't
semirandom is again if you hit a 25
chance then it will switch to the next
profile
but this is completely optional um and
the great thing about it though is is we
have a python script in the
repo under tools config.pi that will
actually like do all this for you it can
either be used in api directly in python
or it can be used as like a command line
thing but allows you to build these like
complex profiles pretty easily
now defense itself so one of the things
i spent a lot of time on uh for defense
is limiting identification so we
basically want to reduce the possibility
that when a blue team looks at this
binary and says oh obviously that's a go
binary or obviously that's you know
whatever it's it's c2 it's malware etc
one of the things i do this by is
reducing recognizable strings that do
exist in the binary and this actually
reduces our size which to be a plus
we also do some things like some checks
and some kind of work around to look not
as malicious as we normally would
one of the ways we do this is we enable
a thing called implant mode which is
enabled by a build tag it basically
trims a bunch of unnecessary stuff off
the binary and even though it's golang
and gulen's
compiler is supposed to be really good
at like trimming the fat and things that
aren't used it can sometimes leave
things in there that it may use that are
really never actually needed so we
actually basically force it to remove
these things completely from the binary
it also converts errors to numbers so
that x errors package i was talking
about on the wire and in memory those
are converted to a numeric version of
the string so
basically like in memory and everything
there are numbers but like as the
operator reporting back on the error you
would only see the string so like it
converts it back for you so the grass
the great thing about it is that if
somebody's doing memory forensics on it
and for some reason you hit an error and
it's like access denied or i don't know
you cannot spawn this process for x
reason it doesn't literally say that
it's just like uh 256 or something you
know so and it's great it saves us bytes
over the wire and it's kind of less work
for us to kind of do comparison
and it also actually guts three
megabytes of size for the binary which
is pretty crazy um oh and it also cuts
logging i don't expect an implant to log
anything to stud out you know so it
shouldn't even be printing anything to
set out why would you have it do that
but um but yeah it cuts it really small
and it removes a lot of stuff
now crypt mode crypt mode is a really
cool mode
it like implant mode uh is a build tag
and it's based on the util crypt library
now this actually is a way to compile in
all of our strings as encoded and this
removes 90
of our strings from the binary and i
mean are not like the runtime strings
but like whatever we use like built-in
file paths for like linux for example um
and it's based on like an ldflags
argument that like packs a string table
and there's you don't have to do this by
hand i think you'd be crazy to do that
um we have automated scripts that will
do this for you and they're included in
the tools directory and what it does is
it actually looks at your build tags and
your build environment and will say hey
are you building this for windows okay
nix all the linux strings we all need
them or oh you're building for linux we
don't need the linux or we don't need
the windows strings so it only uses
exactly what you're needing
but basically technically speaking what
it does is it builds a base64 encoded
string block and with that block is when
the program is first and knitted um it
unpacks that uh block which is also
encrypted with xor and on first runtime
it basically slots all those strings
into a index on a string table and all
the packages that have consumers for
that will then basically load that
string via index so then all those
strings will come back and so where
they're where they are like in their
format
so now defense i'll build my own loader
so i actually um thought the assist
windows package in golang was really
heavy and what i mean by that is it
pulls out a lot of dependencies it's
super string heavy it adds a lot to your
binary size and honestly one of my
things it's a pain to deal with
so i said screw it i'll build my own um
what i ended up doing is it's almost the
same-ish but i added a lot of
optimizations to it especially some like
memory optimizations
and i also added some mutex locking and
improvements as well so we're spending
less run time like spinning on certain
things that we really don't need to
but one of the other reasons i really
did it is because i wanted to load dll
functions based on an fnv hash of their
name instead of the actual function name
so if you're not familiar when you load
a function in windows you first load the
dll by the name like kernel 32 dll then
you load the function name so like get
windows version for example then you
load that so that's a string value so i
didn't want to do that i wanted to load
it by like i don't know one two three
four five six and i wanted to load that
so what end up doing is i built my own
dll loader that actually um
basically loaded these like this and how
it works is when you receive a handle to
a dll it's actually the address that it
sits in memory in windows so what you
can do is you can go to that mapped
memory and start just reading it out raw
so what we did is we started parsing and
loading the virtual exports table which
contains like all of the like an index
array of all the functions and we hash
the string names of them then we compare
the string name or the string hash to
what we had and then if so that matches
then we look up the ordinal position
match that to the function address and
bam there's your function um
we only do this once per dll it's loaded
so we just load all the functions that
we need then bam we're done now the only
pain in the ass that had to deal with
this is exported functions so exported
functions if you're not familiar is when
a dll points to another dll another
process hey that function it's over
there now windows does this for you
automatically so you would never know it
it exists but in this case it doesn't do
it so
it's basically a string
instead of a function f pointer so we
actually had to parse the string code
do load library then get proc by name in
order to actually grab that but now we
had it automatically and that's it works
perfectly and as you can see on the code
on the right hand side that's actually
literally the code that we use for this
it's weirdly it looks weird i know
because we're doing a lot of memory
operations but like for example at the
for loop the three lines after we're
getting the the fnv hash of the string
we're just like casting the string value
to a 256 byte uh
like array so we can just grab it from
there then we just grab the uh the
address of the function after that then
we check if we need it then we just
check if it's an exported function and
if it is we go do that resolve that if
it's not we just store it and that's it
it's actually pretty simple once you
kind of get around to it
so and as you can see from the left and
the right hand side so on the left hand
side is what we had before when we had
all of our functions loaded by string
value and on the right side we have our
function now loaded as their fmv hash
value so now none of these string values
will now be in our binary at all
which is actually really cool so now we
can like load like dangerous function
one and you know even strings for
dangerous function one it doesn't show
up
so i kind of remember a lot of like
highlights of things that um are like so
there's a lot of things in xmt that i
kind of wanted to go over but like i
don't have a super a lot of time so i
wanted to make sure i at least cover the
highlights of it
but you know what i did want to share as
well are some of the things that kind of
maybe really mash my head into the desk
when i was building this there's a lot
of those moments honestly
but um yeah i kind of wanted to cover
some of the funnier ones
so killing the unkillable this was a
really fun one
so the golang run time was never meant
to be killed it was never meant to be
like ended at all so like if you go
search for like closing the go runtime
on like google you get a bunch of stack
overflow results people like well how
can i close the runtime and they're like
good luck buddy like there is no way to
do it um the devs have even acknowledged
the fact there's like no way to do it
like i've looked in the code myself you
can't shut down the runtime so imagine
you had your own library legitimate
thing like it's like
legit library.dll you load it into a
process then you're like all right i'm
done you exit close all the proper
functions do all like the niceties that
windows want you to do when you're
unloading a dll cool
go back and look at that process in um
like task explorer process explorer
you'll notice the runtime's still just
chilling there it it didn't quit
and you know it might be oh this is fine
but like
when you're injecting into lsas
this ain't good
so you you wanna you know you know you
wanna get rid of this in some way shape
or form so i actually found a way to do
this and it's in my opinion really
clever we found a way to kind of clean
up all the go go routine functions and
go routine threats are going on
so
go actually doesn't keep track of its
threads that it creates it doesn't like
you go look at the code it doesn't care
it creates a thread closes the handle
all right whatever um so i was like crap
well how do i do this i can edit the
runtime which i can do that i've done it
i tweeted about it actually it's just
like i wanna add this but i know
nobody's gonna accept that commit um so
i was like okay well
i gotta find another way so i put on my
blue teamer hat and i said all right
well how am i gonna find a golang thread
inside a process so what i end up doing
is
you can actually all the golang threads
have the same base start address all of
them they literally do so if you look in
the at least for windows i can say this
if you look in the code then you look
you search for like create thread a
you go down it's the same it's the same
function so it's the same function
address every single time and you can
verify this by going into the process
explorer and looking at the threads same
base thread address i said okay cool
same base thread address
and the other thing is they're all
started roughly around the same time
cool so we can identify those so we say
all right now we enumerate through our
threads we say okay is it in the same
module as us yes cool same base address
cool um you know it started around the
same time cool all right kill it there
you go and then we just kill our own
process
go run time's gone so i
uh run this now and if you run this and
you look at the threat runtime is
cleaned so and this actually led to the
development of device.goexit which
eventually does call when api uh kill
runtime i'm trying to work on this for
linux it's a little bit harder in my
opinion because i have less linux
development experience um but on windows
you can just call kill runtime or go
exit and now it'll just completely clean
the go runtime and in fact i did a
commit literally a couple days ago to
fix a bug it was so good at killing the
go runtime that if you had two runtimes
loaded in a process completely for
different reasons like you gotta go
laying service running in a thing and
then you had a
injected dll and then ejected assembly
if you ran this it killed everything
which not good so i actually edited
edited some fixes that you know actually
make it only kill itself
so i thought that was kind of an
interesting way so now we can actually
kill the go runtime
uh second one crashing with style so i
actually had a problem that i actually
uh
blue screened a lot of boxes during a
ctf one time and i really didn't know
why and i ended up blue screening a lot
of my testing boxes too and i couldn't
figure out what the hell was going on
so and basically i kind of narrowed the
actual cost down to cfg which is control
flow guard in windows and this runs for
pretty much every operating system based
binary so like scope host or i don't
know uh colonel um lsas uh et cetera and
um basically strict handle checks are a
thing what that does is if you operate
on a valid handle doesn't matter what
you do it kills your process immediately
and so if you call closed handle on
invalid
uh if you call a closed handle on a
valid handle it still kills your process
which is like dude i'm just trying to
close the handle um which actually ended
up being the reason why my process was
crashing by the way um so and what was
causing it was there's a race condition
in the cmd process struct that the
process opened closed way too quickly in
the span of cpu time so my go run my go
routine that started to watch it
didn't start in time enough for that
process to close
then wait for single objects
for some reason uh not documented by the
way in the api documentation for windows
it will wait infinitely
for the um for the process to end er for
the process now because it's dead so
wait for a single object just waits
infinitely
so trying to close that would then you
would call close handle on it and that
would cause the crash so now you would
see a blue screen on your device and
windows wouldn't log this
i i couldn't get it to log it i
seriously there's nothing i could enable
like even syslog doesn't log this so
like i was like okay well maybe
there's i'm doing something weird with
memory because i've so done that before
but no and i kind of narrowed it down to
this so i ended up having to call uh
wait for multiple objects which works
properly
and we create our own event as well so
we now have our own event to signal so
that way we can actually end it properly
and detect that invalid handle if it
happens
last story time i have process dump woes
so the one api function uh midi dump
right dump is really weird it's really
weird um
in memory handle pipes behave oddly so i
actually um
i was using this to write a thing
because now you can dump process it
allows you have a native function dot
jump process memory and i was like all
right let's just dump process memory
dump across the memory and see if it
works um when you use it in uh it allows
you to specify a file handle so when you
specify like an in-memory file handle
like a memory pipe for example
it
dumps it works it drops 40 bytes off the
response
just
for no reason it just i
can't figure it out if anybody knows let
me know seriously but like that memory
pipe completes 40 bytes are gone and it
just val it's per those
bytes are important to the backup and it
basically invalidates it completely uh
which is great so
direct dump worked fine so i was like
huh so i ended up having to um work
using callback functions which uh
i actually found out about the uh i
actually found out about sliver and i
was like oh cool let me take a look at
what they're doing because they
implemented that as well and they had a
great example of like using that and i
was like all right so like i have to do
it this way apparently which is fun um
but yeah so
i had to basically do the long way just
to kind of get this to work
so demos
so i have some cool demos here wrong
button so i'm gonna do the second demo
first because my internet connection is
really bad in this room
so i apologize for that
so
okay so this is actually one of the real
implementations of xmt like as a proper
c2
it's called thunderstorm so thunderstorm
has things called bolts which are
implants and that this this uh c2 is
actually what we're using over there
so
i am go so currently there's nothing
here so i'm gonna go back into my
windows vm
and as you can see here there's a little
exe doesn't look harmless or it looks
harmless test exe so i'm gonna run it
i don't know why it didn't pop up it's
supposed to pop up but as you can see
now it shows we got a bolt here so we're
like cool
so we can actually go into it so
type it in and we now got interactive
shell
is that legible in the back i hope
um
so we can actually type in like net user
and it'll just take a sec
and then now the bolt has the bolt has
told us that we accept the job and most
of this is built into xmt it's just
literally the pretty front end is like
the only thing that's added onto this so
now we just got our output from our
command
and for example i can run channeling
mode that i talked about earlier
challenge mode says okay
so
and there you go so now we have like
we sort of have like direct interaction
with it we don't have to wait as you
notice there's no wait period at all for
it um
we just keep entering commands and there
you go so what we're going to do is
we're going to
do some other fun things
so now one cool thing is as we can tell
we go into here and type t
and we see test exe sitting here looking
all nice in our in our process list so
let's change that
so let's do a migrate so we do migrate
target explorer
exe method asm
and then we're going to point to a dll
let's test
make sure i have it
test v on yellow
so we're gonna hit enter
can't spell there you go okay so
now we did a migration
so
if we look
now across the idea is 3988 i don't
believe there was our one before
so we go back
it's gone
so we go to
398 so now we're running in our explorer
process so now we completely switch
contacts between process one and process
two and we're still running we haven't
switched uh we haven't lost any context
or anything we're still in channeling
mode running perfectly fine so our
network connection switched over to
explore exe and basically everything
else that we had the knowledge base if
you will uh switched over and that this
is still native to xmt it's not like any
pretty add-on that i've extended or
anything this is all default context
so let's do something uh see i can also
uh
do some other things like
okay windows so i can see what windows
on their machine there's a lot of
capabilities we built in like some
really stupid pretty stuff for windows
as you can see but those are some of the
examples
and let me see if i can get my wi-fi
working i will show you the live thing
because currently we have the live ctf
running
the reception in this room is really bad
all right
we'll worry about that later so
i can't show that demo because it's
really bad connected
it's really bad connectivity and i think
it's not playing nice but um these are
some resources that i have so we have to
get our repository it's just ditch.sh
xmt that's the direct thing all the code
for this by the way is public i don't i
don't close anything i don't believe in
closed source code so you know um if you
want to fork it or use it i don't care
um also thunderstorm the thing i was
using also all open source um as well so
if you ever want to use it you know just
for shits and giggles or you want to
poke at it and see how it works go for
it um it's at
sh slash ts and lastly there are some
other things that i looked at that
really helped me um
kind of get like a better handle on some
things and there was a really great talk
that resonated with me which was in
during defcon safe mode there is a talk
uh by ben kurtz and it was offensive
going uh bonanza if you haven't seen it
it's a really good talk i really love
his talk
so yeah uh we have about like 15 minutes
i can close up thank you guys for
listening to me rant for a little bit um
and then i will go for questions
if there is any uh
yeah so uh he asked um if uh if there
was any way that i made like uh see uh
cd traffic like web app traffic yes so
the wct listener i may not mention this
is my fault wc2 is basically a web http
c2 so it looks exactly like standard web
traffic if that's what you mean it
carries like all the default headers um
i did want to do like a direct get post
one or one that looked like looking like
posting images uh that's a connector i'm
planning to add but right now wc2 is
like the go-to for that so it'll do that
like all the proxy support and all the
fun junk um
and it will um
i'm missing the word here but that's the
one that will do that current currently
so there's a lot of options to it that i
it's more than i can explain and i'm
kind of a talk i feel like um but if
that answers your question
oh you're asking
gotcha oh you're asking does the url
change yes right that's what you're kind
of asking yeah so the text library is a
text uh replacement and matcher like
algorithm thing you can supply special
text routes that will do that so you can
say like i want a string route that
looks like this or i want a route that
looks like this so it changes every
single call is that what you're asking
yes we have support for that so yeah you
just have to write like a regex looking
string and it'll take that and then
parse it out as with and then the end
point can actually match those so you
can actually kind of catch blue teamers
trying to
do that so you can match on like the url
the header uh headers host names user
agents etc so um but yeah does that
answer that yeah
cool um i'm gonna try
the functionality that you were
describing under the profile section
that's kind of similar to football
strikes um
beacon shell um
would that be detectable with uh tools
like uh retail analysis that john
um so you were asking uh if the c2 uh
the profiles thing would be since it
looks like it looks like the uh see the
cobalt strikes uh kind of profiles
method
i don't think so if it is that's really
cool um i don't think so because it
probably sits in a different memory
layout and
for at least so for thunderstorm we
actually encrypt all this stuff as well
so it's actually xor wrapped in
everything in memory and after it's used
so i don't think it would fit i don't
think it would check it but if it does
that's awesome um but just because
it would be like uh
and we
yeah we do have jitter and stuff so you
might be able to match it on that um
he asked if it would he might be able to
match like the jitter or something which
yeah that could definitely match that uh
i would say um but i don't think it'll
match that traffic exactly if it does
you know that's pretty awesome but i
don't because the layout and everything
i don't think it exactly matches one to
one does that answer your question
blue teamers so blue teamers one of the
things i try to tell blue teamers all
the time is know your land so like know
what's running so i deal with a lot of
windows things and people forget like
what is actually like native on windows
and granted i don't expect you know
every dll but i want you to spot
inconsistencies in it like there are
some so i can make binaries and windows
that look like exactly like windows
binaries but there's things you can kind
of
look at like
that's kind of sus right there
okay
i'll give you one um so
a lot of people don't sign with binary
manifests so like examine your binary
manifests i've seen a lot of people
compile without them like resourcing is
becoming more popular a lot of people
don't resource so if you look at a
binary and go to its details tab that's
the resources of the binary so you can
like specify custom like values for its
name title description etc
you can analyze that first and if
they're smarter they'll put those in
there but then manifesto i think people
don't catch like compatibility manifest
process hacker too if you've ever used
process hacker look at it i found about
it last year because the blue team were
talking about it it's really awesome and
it can examine uh manifest and like
it'll say if it's manifested for this
windows like
um i'm running windows 10. why is this
program manifesto for windows 8 saying
it's lsas i don't know about that so you
know like that i would say would be a
first start um but also examining like
um you know like i used to love carbon
black for this is um you can examine
your threading and stuff like process uh
hollowing is a big deal that a lot of
people don't catch so like examine like
look like even process explorer be able
to show you like oh that thread doesn't
look right like notepad shouldn't have
more than one thread no pad single
threaded by the way like it shouldn't
have like multiple threads running in it
that's that kind of like answer i could
probably go on a lot about this like
like i talk a lot over there so but um i
hope that helps a little a little bit um
any other questions
um
yeah in terms of the uh payload on a
system do you have any options as far as
putting like a powershell
so i want to do that i don't have a
script and up for it i can do it um so
the thing you've noticed with migrate
i'm sorry you asked what are some of the
things i can use for uh loading like in
the initial compromise loading and um
you're saying about powershell loaders i
want to build that i haven't built that
yet but we can load via assembly we have
a there's a built-in i've i've built in
the srdi library into xmt at least the
the dll to asm loader and so you could
convert dlls asm on the fly and so we do
that a lot so that that migrate that we
noticed i did that all in asm but the
dll was an actual dll um but we have
that capability we have it for other
things so like there's a there's a
loader we have for thunderstorm that
does that like natively but not with
power shell it's it's on the road map i
guess is my answer uh does that answer
is
if you catch me around somewhere you can
ask me i will talk your ear off that's
okay um is there any other questions
before i close out
go ahead
i'm um
sorry so he has keep swapping out using
diffie-hellman
no because i'm too lazy to do that but i
would love to do that what
oh um i'm too lazy to do that i'm just
doing like a basic key swap and i'm
basically using the material on both
sides to do uh
basically basically the values only one
way if that makes sense so like i'm not
i'm not sending any of the key data like
at all i'm saying the basic source
material to generate from that but it's
not any any diffi helmet unfortunately
now
uh any other questions
uh cool so thank you guys again for
listening i hope you guys have a great
rest of your weekend