hi there everyone okay uh we are from
RMS uh next slide
um my name is Russell Thomas and I've
been at RMS about uh three years give or
take I come to the organization with the
background in data science at a Regional
Bank uh PhD work in computational social
science and before that uh
high-tech Enterprise
r d marketing manufacturing
Bachelors of Science in electrical
engineering and management Chris my name
is Chris Voss uh I've been at RMS for
about seven years
um
bit sorry closer look at my head a bit
of RMS about seven years
um
been working on our cyber rest models
since since the outsets uh I have a
background in mathematical modeling
particularly in the context of natural
catastrophes so I have a a masters in
risk and environmental hazards and a
Bachelors in physical geography both
from universities in the UK as you can
probably tell from my accent
um
so as Russell mentioned we do cat
modeling and for many of you in the
audience when we say those words this
might be what comes to mind uh however
unfortunately today we won't be spending
the next 45 minutes checking out
different designs of you know denim
jackets for cats and that sort of stuff
instead what we'll be talking about is
catastrophe modeling which is a field
within mathematical modeling focusing on
quantifying the risk associated with
rare severe phenomena things like
hurricanes earthquakes floods pandemics
and of course cyber attacks what we have
on this lovely slide here that completes
Russell
it's just an example of
some uh realistic but uh synthetic
hurricane
um tracks from our North Atlantic
hurricane model so passovers Russell
so when we say rare catastrophic events
uh one of the features of this talk is
going to be some Seinfeld memes I think
we would all agree this particular
episode where Frank Costanza fell
backwards on a little few Sealy Jerry
statue and it ended up in the
proctologist's office as a very rare
very catastrophic event
so as we mentioned you know Russell and
I focus on Cyber risk modeling but uh
this is just this is just one of a whole
Suite of different catastrophe models
that RMS build our firm builds
everything from North Atlantic hurricane
models to European flood models Asian
earthquake models and you know terrorism
pandemic and of course cyber risk models
so our primary clients sit within the
insurance sphere uh this little slide
here just kind of gives an overview of
the insurance value chain starting from
Individual companies who if they want to
buy insurance will speak with insurance
brokers
they'll get a policy of an insurance
company but those insurance companies
typically don't want to
those those companies
um don't want to hold all the risk on
their balance balance sheet so typically
they interact with reinsurers to shift
some of that off and you can see the
flow of risk from left to right here now
RMS is a company provides risk
quantification tools and services
throughout this value chain uh in the
context of cyber risk we're primarily on
the sort of right hand side insurers
reinsurance Brokers and reinsurers
themselves
so what do we actually mean by risk well
very simply risk is often defined as
being the product of likelihood and
impact now in our context impact
actually means the direct Financial
losses experienced by companies that
unfortunately are on the the bad end or
a cyber instance now on the right hand
side here you can see some of the types
of impacts that are considered by our
modeling you can see everything from
Lost Revenue that occurs during an
incident so of course as we know when a
bad ransomware incident occurs often
that means a company can't operate at
100 so we'll be quantifying that sort of
thing
quantifying forensics cost incident
response costs some kinds of fines
notification costs and Ransom payments
and that sort of thing however we don't
quantify is things like post-incident
upgrades lost to Share value and this
sort of thing and that's primarily
because these are the sorts of losses
that are not covered by insurance
contracts in the Cyber Insurance sphere
so as a result we really focus on
incidents that
are above a particular severity
threshold we're really only interested
in stuff that causes realized Financial
pain to companies not so much about
other kind of incidents that perhaps
network security folks are concerned
about intrusions that they want to
follow up Etc but we're really
interested in if it results in a
financial loss we're interested if it
doesn't not so much let's please and
as part of this we model a diverse range
of different types of cyber incidents
everything from data breaches to
ransomware attacks wipers Cloud outages
and this sort of thing and each of those
different what we would call sub Perils
of cyber have different likelihoods and
different Associated Financial losses
and of course depending on what type of
company we're talking about you know a
small company versus a large company the
likelihoods might be different to any
industry we're talking about the
likelihoods also might be different
okay a quick show of hands anybody here
work in the insurance industry cyber
risk okay interesting uh anybody here do
risk modeling as a business
as opposed to
okay so what I want to contrast here in
this next series of slides is
how these different perspectives of risk
vary and overlap but are significantly
different that's really critical to
understand that how we approach modeling
and how it may be different especially
from the Enterprise
so if you're a risk manager in an
Enterprise
essentially all risks all bad things
that hap can happen your business are
important
so if you get hit with a really bad
event
causes big Financial losses or big
reputation damage you've got to go in
front of your board or something that
could be a catastrophe as you define it
but from a population standpoint if
you're the only organization get hit by
that the population or the people that
look at populations like governments
Regulators they may not see this as an
extraordinary event it's bad for one but
not necessarily for the population
but if you start seeing events hitting
many organizations essentially or
roughly in the same time especially the
same type of attack and attack severity
now we've got a population level uh
catastrophe
now it's critical to understand that
insurance companies View and manage
cyber risk in the context of a portfolio
that's how they decide what the premiums
are going to be and what the rules for
coverage are going to be how much
Capital to allocate and how to even
acquire reinsurance and report to
regulators
so portfolios have boundaries who's in
and who's out portfolios have rules of
coverage in terms of conditions and even
every customer is going to buy different
levels of coverage so while a single
insurer may look at the population and
sort of take that Advantage perspective
they're always looking at a subset and a
key part of the RMS product is to help
Insurance customers go from the
population or macro view down to their
particular portfolio view and say what
does this mean for the types of
customers we cover
so what RMS does in our model is in in
this version six that we've just
introduced we model a synthetic
population of all firms above a certain
size threshold
and further we uh separate this
synthetic population by the industrial
sector as well as the geographic uh
jurisdiction
and critical to our modeling is what's
the footprint of given attacks and we're
concerned about how many threat actors
there are and there are campaigns and
what are their footprints
and different campaigns can have
different Footprints and that can affect
who's uh who's affected and uh
how many so some may be horizontal some
may be vertical and in the worst case
scenarios
they may cover a very very large portion
of the population and
this is really a prime concern to our
customers and to our models
cool thanks Russell so to sort of
formalize this I think it's helpful to
sort of reiterate a couple of things so
the first of which is that we can think
about risk in two categories we can
think about what's called attritional
risk and essentially these are incidents
like Russell mentioned at the very
beginning which are sort of independent
which can still be substantial in scale
but are not associated with many many
companies being hit so an example of
that would be something like the 2017
Equifax data breach which was brutal for
Equifax but it's not like it hit
thousands and thousands of companies
simultaneously
then we have tail risk which in our
parlance is really focusing on low
probability High severity events that
hit many many companies simultaneously
so these are things like Wanna Cry and
not pettier might be examples of Terror
risk and of course we can all imagine
much more terrifying examples than any
of those you know that might potentially
occur
so we wanted to sort of touch on how
this influences insurance premium
because that might be something that you
know a touch point that you folks have
you know directly with the insurance
industry and so insurance premium really
is covering the the average loss that or
the mean loss that your company might
experience in a given year and this
includes both attritional and tail risk
so on the right hand side I've got a
very super simplified example of an
imaginary company and let's say an
insurance company comes up with a ten
thousand dollar technical premium Now a
technical premium essentially is defined
as being
the amount they're charging directly to
cover the losses that you might the
claims you might bring it doesn't
include profit or other sorts of uh
other sorts of costs so next one please
also so again these numbers are made up
but as hopefully it will help us follow
through so the attritional component you
can see here is about seven thousand
five hundred dollars and the way that
this might be computed again this is a
simplification is that you might take
the mean loss that the company might
experience conditional on an incident so
given that they've experienced an
incident on average what's the dollar
cost and then what you do is you combine
that with information about the
likelihood of that happening or the
probability of that happening in this
case five percent for easy numbers and
then you get what's a probability
weighted loss which in this case is
seven thousand five hundred dollars but
that only covers the attritional
component those sort of independent
events what you also need to consider is
the tail component which is often called
the catastrophe load and this is then
considering okay what about all those
events which might hit loads of
companies simultaneously in this case
here our example is saying that on
average if our company gets caught up in
one of those events that the loss is
going to be 250 000 on average but
there's only about a one percent chance
in a given year that that this company
gets caught up in this and when we do
the probability weighted loss we get 2
500 sum them and we get 10 000. um nice
place so one thing that
we thought is kind of useful to to
mention
is that you know Russell spoke about the
different scales of risk and what what's
catastrophic in in the eyes of an
Enterprise versus the eyes of an
insurance company or the eyes of a
population and it's worth mentioning
that you know for an individual company
you could imagine that perhaps you know
a brutal double extortion event might be
the worst case scenario right where all
of their commercially confidential
information gets stolen you know
personal information they have get
stolen and leaked and at the same time
their operations grind to a hole because
everything's encrypted horrendous
however due to the scaling properties of
double extortion
and those sorts of attacks might not be
the drivers of population level
catastrophe risk it might be something
like a wiper that is just rolled out
through a worm or something like that
instead and ultimately
depending on the angle at which you're
approaching risk management you might be
concerned about certain types of
incidents over others
so before we really get into the meat of
the presentation we thought it'd be
helpful to really spell out what
catastrophe models in particular are
cyberis model does and what it doesn't
do
what it does is assesses the likelihood
of different loss outcomes we're not
trying to make predictions of exactly
what will happen now to use a simple
maybe appropriate analogy in Las Vegas
if we imagine a you know a dice what our
model is saying is that the dice has six
sides and each side has one over six
probability of it of it being rolled
what we're not saying is that the next
roll is going to be a two
um if we did know that then we wouldn't
be here and we'd be in the casino
instead
um
laughs what else what else does it do
well what it really tries to aim it aim
to do is to capture the key drivers of
risk what we're not trying to do is
reflect all of the complexity of the
real world all of the you know huge
depth of technical complexity that
you're all super aware of and you know
all the complexity of decision making of
threat actors ultimately we're trying to
identify what is really driving risk
um and ultimately this comes back to the
fact that all mathematical models are
simplifications of the world they are
helpful decision making tools but
they're not supposed to you know reflect
all of the ugly details of the real
world and finally what our models do is
they complement expert judgment as a
decision-making tool they're not
supposed to replace humans because as I
mentioned before these models are
simplifications so we need expert
judgment on top of it you know some
people might think that the output is
too high too low
etc etc so
um now that we've sort of laid the
groundwork of that we'll move on to our
first lesson which is the benefits of
causal risk modeling
so a causal model is a model that
represents the causal or mechanistic
relationships in a system
on the flip side statistical models are
models that reflect the mathematical or
statistical relationship between
different variables next slide please so
here we have a toy example of a
statistical model that you might use in
the context of cyber risk so this
follows a very very popular framework
the frequency severity framework so on
the left hand side here we have a
probability distribution showing the
likelihood of a company experiencing an
incident here you can see there's like a
75 chance that it doesn't experience an
incident just over 20 chance that it
experiences one incident you know and a
small percentage that hits two three or
four incidents and then on the right
hand side you have the severity side
which basically says given that a
company has experienced an incident what
are the range of potential dollar loss
outcomes and they're Associated
likelihood so on the right hand side
that's a probability density function so
essentially where the the curve is
highest you're sort of most likely to
see an outcome but we can see that all
the way down to very large numbers there
are there's a chance that the loss plays
out this way
um
one thing that those one thing that
these kinds of models uh are good for is
when you have a lot of data but what
they're not very good for is trying to
quantify very very extreme outcomes that
you haven't observed if I want to ask
the question what's the likelihood that
next year 25 of companies get nailed
with a wiper this sort of model can't
help me because we haven't observed
anything like that in the past we need
to use different techniques so yeah so
just to underline that last point I want
to share a brief story conversation I
had uh 2008 or 9 with a famous security
consultant keynote speaker and he is
that 15 minutes did you just wait 15
minutes
thank you scared me so anyway he was
arguing against the possibility of ever
quantifying low probability High
magnitude loss his argument was if you
take infinitesimal probabilities against
incredibly large numbers your margin of
error you can end up with any results
so he was uh just trying to dissuade me
and other people from going down that
path
so coming back to our Seinfeld meme
how would you
any of you estimate the likelihood
probability
the risk associated with this particular
loss event
well I would challenge you to take a
standard statistical model of frequency
and severity and apply it to this it's
very hard to get off the ground and have
any credible information
so what we at RMS do in our version 6
model is we model a synthetic world that
has all of the key elements
firms software vulnerabilities
campaigns threat actors and we connect
them in a mechanistic or causal chain
so in this case if we wanted to include
this we'd have to have a threat actor of
the type Kramer and Kramer would have to
have the capability of building weird
things like little statues
and his attack pattern would be leaving
that statue on the ground where somebody
might fall on it and then the causal
mechanism is how is somebody like Frank
the potential victim with vulnerability
here likely to fall and if he falls
what's the likelihood that he's going to
fall in a particular way that he's going
to have to visit a proctologist
so to go a little bit deeper into this
synthetic world as Russell described we
here are really trying to call out as I
mentioned earlier on the key drivers of
risk in the Cyber kind of risk ecosystem
so here what you'll see is components
everything from Individual threat actors
that we spawn that have various
different characteristics size skill
motivation Etc things like
software different kinds of software
that exists with different market share
and what kinds of companies use those
pieces of software vulnerabilities of
course which are crucial to understand
and that the rate at which those
vulnerabilities spawn and their
characteristics and of course you know
what their exploitation kind of
characteristics look like but then also
things like the different ways in which
threat actors can gain initial access
into uh into corporates right things
like social engineering have extremely
different scaling characteristics to
worms for example and modeling the
specific ways in which those play out is
super important
so
those of you kind of who
work in a field a little bit closer to
us might be wondering how on Earth do
you operationalize all of that well so
this is a bit of a simplification but
ultimately the way that this works is
for fifty thousand uh synthetic years
what we do is we simulate
we initialize a world in which you have
software with different market share
characteristics different
vulnerabilities that have been spawned
with with various different
characteristics and then of course
putting into place different ways in
which threat actors can get into into
companies and different bad things they
can do once they're inside and then
those threat actors essentially are able
to evaluate their different options each
of each year and Russell will talk a
little bit later on about how we go
about that and then these thread actors
will choose what nefarious thing they
decide to do and we essentially rinse
and repeat this process exploring lots
of different states of the world because
none of us can you know write down on a
piece of paper now exactly what's going
to happen from a vulnerabilities
perspective you know over the coming
year so we need to explore a broad range
of potential outcomes and once you
repeat this process essentially what
happens is you get
synthetic attacks occurring some of
which are much larger in scale than
others
[Music]
yeah just uh those of you who might be
familiar with
epidemiological models of infectious
disease especially across a network or a
geography similar structure those models
take the bacteria point of view or the
virus point of view and the hosts the
susceptible hosts are sort of provide
the backdrop for the virus to move
around so in this case the threat actors
take the primary active role in decision
making and determine what campaigns
happen and firms at Enterprise by their
policies and practices more or less
determine the environment in which they
operate
cool so as you can imagine you know
building this sort of model as opposed
to a statistical model is a huge amount
of work both from a Time effort and data
requirements perspective so why on Earth
do we you know pass out to all of that
well
as we mentioned earlier on it's our firm
belief that you cannot
robustly quantify extreme cyber risk
through simple statistical models and
through this kind of model that we've
described extreme events are emergent
from this particular model and the
reason why that's the case is you will
get years inside of this 50 000 year
simulation where you might have an
extremely large skilled and aggressive
threat threat group
who are operating in a year in which
there are a slew of you know very very
high severity broad reaching
vulnerabilities and it's essentially the
superposition of many bad things
occurring at once that ultimately can
result in catastrophic activity
um there's also a bunch of other
different uh benefits
I think really importantly is that
assumptions in this sort of model can be
directly interrogated by domain experts
if a domain expert wants to ask how do
you consider patching and you know how
do you consider that some companies are
slower patching than others if you ask
that question to the statistical model
that we mentioned at the beginning that
question doesn't make any sense there's
no notion of patching inside of that
model whatsoever whilst in the context
of a causal model such as our own you
have particular components that are
directly addressing that sort of
phenomenon real life and you can make
sure that you are capturing the process
in a robust manner both from a
quantitative and a qualitative
perspective
um
uh okay let's just move on next yeah
um so yeah we're kind of taking a little
longer than we'd hope but uh
um so good news on empirical data so
there's a lot of good news I think on
the empirical data front I think it's
things like the Frameworks that miter
have produced things like the attack
kpec and defend Frameworks for us have
helped absolutely enormously in terms of
providing a common language to describe
different phenomena but also as a way to
be able to homogenize uh data from
different sources you know if you've got
Source a and Source B both tracking
thread actor activity and they're
describing you know persistent
techniques persistence technique lateral
movement techniques all these sorts of
things using the same language for us
that makes things a million times easier
so this is really great next
I think incident data is becoming much
more readily reported in the past things
like data breaches were you know pretty
commonly reported due to regulatory
reasons but I think more and more
companies are becoming less ashamed of
of announcing that they've experienced a
ransomware incident or other kinds of
incidents like that and for us more data
results in better models and just
quickly regulatory influence
Securities and Exchange Commission
privacy reporting requirements are all
and obviously the European requirements
are all positive here and from our
standpoint our customer standpoint we
look forward to more of this uh being
more comprehensive
cool on top of that you know there's a
whole series of uh
publicly available and extremely well
structured data on vulnerabilities so to
some extent also on exploits I think you
know there's still some uh perhaps some
work to be done there but again that's
incredibly useful from our perspective
I think something else we really want to
call out is the substantial body of
really high quality statistically robust
work that uh sort of is out in the
literature big big shout out to the
folks at scientia but also Folks at
Verizon and various other different
reports I think this sort of information
you know really is positive for the the
the discipline of cyber risk
quantification in general just
historical context some of you maybe
have been around in the industry long
enough to remember cost of a data breach
reports by an organization beginning
with the letter P so we have uh
significantly Advanced beyond that
and then finally you know there's some
really great work that's going on in the
broader Community
um you know where there are very
talented dedicated professionals putting
their you know data science statistics
and I guess cyber security knowledge
together to put together products such
as the epss which is the exploit
prediction scoring system this is super
interesting both from our perspective at
the macro level but I think also for you
know practitioners as providing you know
valuable insights to the probability of
individual exploits being of individual
of individual vulnerabilities being
exploited to help with things like
prioritization a big improvement over
their uh cbss severity system
so all of this Foundation of data
was really a prerequisite for us to even
consider this sort of model certain
areas we definitely feel you know are a
little bit more tractable with current
data than others I think we're very
comfortable with where we are with
things like software vulnerability
spawning
the cost of individual attacks as well
as the mechanisms around initial access
vectors
and the flip side there's some not so
good news
so in general
in this Arena we're always going to be
suffering with relatively short time
series compared to natural phenomenon
like earthquakes and floods and so on so
even if you can collect 20 or 30 years
of data really only the last 10 years
and sometimes five years is applicable
because then you have an environment
that's more or less consistent with
where you're operating today so we are
constantly having to go through data
analysis and data evaluation process
with any empirical data source as to how
far back in time we go and how we make
use of that and of course as we look
forward the dynamic nature of what we're
dealing with is crucial I'll just
mention an area of my own work in
modeling high-level Financial theft from
Banks which was a very active area for
certain nation states uh three to five
years ago but those nation states have
shifted to cryptocurrency thefts uh so
one of the things we have to evaluate in
a practical sense is if we're going to
be putting out a model that our
customers can be using for the next year
how how much do we anticipate things
that may be in the process of changing
uh will the uh prevalence of ransomware
continue for the next 12 to 18 to 24
months is that the same as it has
now
crucially there's still struggling for
information around incidents especially
breaking down the loss event into
categories that we can use what's
publicized is not always uh the most
important or the most useful and the
biggest gap of all is information about
threat actors and
um I'll just give a shout out had some
conversations over the last couple of
days and put out over Twitter
proposing a project collaborative
project around modeling threat actor
capability
Evolution and change so if anybody is
interested in getting involved with that
think of it as sort of like an attack
framework but focused on threat actors
not from a threat Intel point of view
that indicators of compromise and ttps
but their organizational capabilities
and their value chains so come up and
see me afterward
so this leaves us with the need to um
evaluate uh excuse me fill in the gaps
with data with expert knowledge so we
mentioned here threat actors and one
area I worked on was how do threat
actors make decisions around campaigns
given the options available I just got
the 10 minute notice so I'm going to
pick up the pace a little bit I hope
that's okay
so we're going to walk through a
simplified example from the end result
backwards so the end result we have in
our choice model is Choice probabilities
here six campaigns are available to this
threat actor and what we end up here
with Choice probability and a random
draw is made based on those
probabilities to the campaign Choice the
choice probabilities here are simply the
normalized outcome scores
so how do we get the outcome scores and
how do we come up with six campaigns
well in this particular case it's three
initial access excuse me three initial
access vectors
cross product with two particular attack
types execution techniques so we've got
ransomware the data exfiltration and
three different ways of getting into the
population and given their weighted
attractiveness that determines the
outcome score for each
now weighted attractiveness is sort of
where the magic happens here it we need
to discern the relative attractiveness
of the firms to these different types of
an attack so a firm that's highly
attractive to a ransomware person is not
necessarily as attractive to the same to
a different attack or even the same
attacker if they're trying to exfiltrate
a bunch of confidential health
information
a mission so we'll move on to the next
thing
so this next lesson is I guess a bit
more of a tutorial for for those of you
who are kind of interested in you know
applying
statistic simple statistical methods to
your risk quantification work so we're
going to talk about probability
distribution so probability distribution
is essentially a mathematical function
listing a range of possible outcomes for
a particular process and the
corresponding likelihoods on the right
hand side here we have a normal or a
gaussian distribution bell-shaped curve
for adult male height in the United
States
Now using observations we can actually
come up with some reasonable parameters
for what this mathematical function
might look like
and the benefits of fitting these
functions are quite numerous actually
the first of which is enables you to
estimate the likelihood of different
outcomes if you wanted to know what's
the chance that someone is more than six
foot three tall you can ask that to this
mathematical function you can ask also
what's the likelihood that they're
between five foot and five foot five
tall you can also ask that sort of thing
it also enables you to determine the
likelihood of unobserved outcomes and
enables you to generate synthetic data
through sampling in this case here
Russell just showed you know if I ask
this function give me five numbers it
will draw in a way that's proportionate
to the probability density now
so how would you actually go about doing
this in this imaginary example we're
saying you know if I go around my local
town and measure the height of 100
different men I might get a histogram
like you can see on the top right sorry
it's a little bit small
and if I was thinking okay what sort of
probability distribution do I want to
fit to this there's lots of different
considerations that I might want to make
but one of them should be what is my
prior knowledge about this particular
process you can see in the histogram
it's bimodal meaning it has two humps
however having lived as a human for a
number of years I know that actually in
general you know there's a sort of a
smooth spectrum of heights and there's
not a small there's not a valley of
height in uh in the male population so
we're going to choose a unimodal
distribution next
so in order to actually fit this there's
a lot of different tools that can really
make your life easy we use various
different languages in our team I quite
like Julia and what you can see here is
you can fit that red line on the right
hand side with just a single line of
code it's not too terrifying you know
there's of course a rabbit hole that you
can go down from the statistics
perspective but just to start getting
familiar with this sort of stuff there
are a lot of tools out there that can
really help now there's a question of
how good a job did I do and there are a
whole bunch of diagnostic plots that you
can do which are pretty straightforward
to follow but uh I'm running out of time
so I'll pass the button over to Russell
again
so a huge lesson that we learned through
our experience in modeling the iterative
process of looking at the data
generating the model looking at the
output is our definition of tail risk
what drives that curve whether it's in
the critical area or not so critical
area is threat actor capabilities
so I want to give you a window into into
this process and how we arrive there and
one critical factor in this tail risk is
what is the addressable population for
any attack
so the addressable population for the
not Petty attack was huge because it was
a wormable uh Windows vulnerability and
therefore it could spread very widely
so what factors determine that
addressable population
so obviously attack a strategy exploit
capability products they're going after
and their coverage in the population
uh
and I'm going to skip to the bottom
which are interdependencies between
vulnerabilities if they exploit multiple
vulnerabilities
a given attack May exploit two three
five maybe even more vulnerabilities
conditional on the victim that they run
into if those relationships are or
logical relationships that expands their
Market gives them options but if those
are and relationships those are points
of failure because if any vulnerability
any exploit in that sequence of ands
fails the whole sequence fails so we
believe that attackers when they're
defining their attack strategy either by
conscious planning or by experience
essentially assemble their attack
strategy to try to come up with an
addressable population which fits their
goals and their capabilities
so what one lens on this is the initial
access Vector of worms so here we've
modeled just the behavior of worms uh
and What proportion of the population
that they would be able to access
and you can see in and this is an
example of a sub analysis within our
broader simulation
you can see the vast majority of worms
are down in the 20 range
so what's interesting is this range
above 50 percent this is the worst case
of the worst case
and this slide here it's a bit of an eye
chart but this is a diagnostic output
from our simulation where we look at in
detail the characteristics of these
simulated attacks in the far part of the
tail
so we went in and estimated well how
prevalent are multiple uh
vulnerabilities cross OS vulnerabilities
uh are they wormable or not and we
created our own simulated world of these
and this helps us evaluate
are these assumptions realistic does
this correspond to what anybody is has
said from an expert opinion and we can
go back and refine that
so I'm not going to read all of these
points but this iterative process about
well how bad can things get what does it
take for an attacker to really attack a
very high portion of the population led
us to not only produce the quantitative
output but the reasoning behind why this
is relatively rare more rare than than
some Cassandra's might be claiming
cool so um
almost wrapped up um we thought you know
we've been speaking about Doom and Gloom
so we thought we'd share what some of
the output of our modeling is in terms
of how bad can bad be so we can ask the
question of our model
you know
what are the characteristics of the most
rare and broadly hitting events so here
we're talking about stuff that we think
it has a less than a one percent chance
of happening next year you could also
say that's less than a one in a hundred
chance of happening next year so our
model suggests that about
9.4 or greater firms are likely to
experience an incident from a common
cause this is sort of in the realm of
our worst case and we think this is most
likely to be driven by worms there's
also a chance of supply chain attacks on
very very large vendors and we think the
uh the payload is very likely to be
wipers
partly because of the the threat Act of
motivation you know on the on the
state-sponsored side but also because
ransomware attacks typically have
on the sort of business side for the
threat actors they need to process a
large number of of transactions whilst a
wiper it's possible for you to just drop
it and walk away
um
and over back onto Russell last point so
I've been in this business for quite a
while
I presented to uh angel investor group
incubator
with a bright idea of a research agenda
investment opportunity for quantifying
information security risk and making it
financially material to executives
and I got blank stares and polite
nods and then I invited myself back
again I said I want to give another
presentation because I want to get
something going and they said uh I think
our calendar is full here
um but I kept going and I know people in
this room and people in the audience
watching on YouTube have been on this
journey for a similar time periods
2022 is a different time uh we wanted to
have a whole bunch of corporate logos
and organization logos of all the people
participating in this world now some of
the people here in this room uh
I kind of feel like we're in a golden
age of risk quantification and
information security
there are so many more participants now
there are so many more good platforms
and initiatives academic conferences and
resources
so if anybody is interested in getting
involved with this for a start be happy
to talk with you uh if anybody's in it
been in it for a while and you want to
up your game or get more involved be
happy to talk last but not least this
event in the ground Truth uh track is
evidence of how far this community has
come in the past 15 or so years
so I uh told my UK colleague Chris that
the American audience was very active in
asking questions and engaging in
conversation so now is your opportunity
to do this as we get to our microphone
setup
hello Russ be close
hello Russ hi I I presume that that uh
slide at the beginning with your
modeling risk has a little closer as a
result of impact times probability was
just a straw man argument that you threw
out with the rest of your sides which
didn't back up that approach or am I
completely misreading what you guys have
done here because it doesn't thankfully
it doesn't seem like you've gone through
that dark Road into multiplying apples
to times oranges and you might want to
educate everybody on exactly uh the how
you are modeling risk there uh thank you
for that question uh so if everybody
understood it he he's saying we
introduced one of the early slides risk
is likelihood times impact or severity
and that seemed in contrast to the rest
of things we're doing
so
in the early 2000s
there was a lot of
um
I will say expert commentary
driving people to do quantitative risk
modeling using that simplistic formula
alone
and trying to get you to think about
every single asset and every single
vulnerability and applying that formula
to every single one
uh I was once at a conference where a
high-level person at a bank told a war
story of taking his team through such an
exercise
and after two weeks gave up in
exhaustion so they had carte blanche to
work on this until they got it done for
some Board review and they gave up
the trouble with that is it makes sense
at a conceptual level
so at a very broad definitional level
the definitions are consistent but how
you get there is crucial
and it's not the same
you know our whole presentation about
causal modeling and getting to the
probability of certain events happening
in their conditional severity
is we think we're arguing is a viable
supportable path to getting to that uh
risk definition
so closer closer so
um
there are lots of domains that are
modeling risk uh as you mentioned
earlier like finance and floods and et
cetera et cetera
um
are there similar uh approaches to
causal modeling in all of those domains
and is there a common methodology
between them
yeah I can try and talk to that a bit um
so I think there are certainly overlaps
um in that
the process of trying to
create a broad range or a broad catalog
of scenarios of bad things that could
happen and Associated likelihoods I
think is common across the board we
described you know our methodology here
for something like a hurricane model
what they do is they have a model that
spawns low pressure systems inside of
the North Atlantic and kind of track
tracks how they you know intensify for
earthquakes you know they have
um
models on you know for different fault
probabilities and these sorts of things
so there's I think at a very high level
you know this notion of having a catalog
of bad things that can happen and then
you combine that with the economy or an
insurance portfolio to see uh how it
comes out however of course you know in
the context of cyber what is very
different is where you've got the human
decision-making angle right we often
talk about how you know you could build
the most perfect synthetic world of
vulnerabilities and you know software
Etc but your assumptions about how
threat actors make decisions ultimately
is going to be what's driving you know
the likelihood of really bad things
happening so I think there are certainly
areas of commonality but having a
man-made risk I think adds an additional
level of uncertainty that is perhaps not
in place for those natural catastrophe
models anything else yeah uh terrorism
risk modeling which is something that
RMS does is the closest analog uh and
they use similar approaches not
identical but similar
hi there I work for a very small
precious startup and I would I'm in QA
I'm the closest thing they have to
security how do I get my very small very
new to the startup World very literally
young engineering team
thinking about these sort of War games
these possible things that could happen
how do we react to them without scaring
the pants off of them
that is a courageous huge incredibly
important question and Challenge and
anybody in this room who claims they
know the answer to that or there's a
foolproof path
I think you're kidding yourself so
everybody who Encounters this I mean
this is one of the most challenging
things in the whole security world and
Quant risk
so I'm I'm going to give a try to answer
but so it's such a big question it
deserves more time I invite you to join
the Society of information risk analysts
because I assume that you are interested
in a quantitative risk approach to this
question as opposed to hand waving or
framework bashing or please no jargon
hurling approaches okay Society of
information risk analysts is a community
of people pretty Grassroots and there's
lots of people and resources
who can you can connect to that will
help break that down and give you tools
to make progress on it awesome thank you
uh thank you for the presentation so
um you were mostly it looks like looking
at
um sort of a large population from the
perspective that insurers and things
like that uh I'm wondering if you've uh
had any experience with how well this
kind of causal modeling uh would or
wouldn't work for a company trying to
predict uh catastrophic events happening
specifically to them uh for instance to
decide whether or not to invest in some
sort of barrier to like or how much how
much they should be paying for insurance
things like that
very good question very forward-looking
because that's the next logical well I
won't say the next it is a logical
progression
for firms like ourselves and models like
this
uh
I will say the
transition between population
perspective and a firm specific or even
a value chain which is sort of an
in-between thing
is tricky from a technical an Evidence
how much granularity you notice in here
we abstract attacks into two two phases
initial access and everything else
firms care a lot about that everything
else that's the whole elevation of
privilege and horizontal movement and
partitioning your networks and so on
I would be very interested in talking to
anybody who's interested in that path uh
official announcement RMS has been
purchased by Moody's Analytics Moody's
Analytics is a famous publicly held
company modeling risk across a broad
portfolio and I know that they're
interested in this topic I will
definitely come and talk to you about
that afterwards thank you
hello thanks for the talk it was really
interesting
um you talked a lot about external
threat actors and I was just wondering
how do you quantify Insider attacks
um the likelihood and impact given that
the initial access is kind of taken care
of so the question is about Insider
attacks as threat actors
uh our current model does not include
Insider attacks uh maybe Chris can
comment it's my understanding that
Insider attacks are not normally covered
as part of normal cyber insurance
uh I mean that may that may well varied
from company to company but so what we
described just throughout this
presentation is our framework for trying
to quantify catastrophic cyber risk
right so it's our assessment that
although inside a threat is definitely a
big thing the likelihood of you know
armies of people simultaneously deciding
to you know take up the mantle against
their corporate oppressors uh is
extremely unlikely and that you know the
source of attacks that we're trying to
model here around big supply chain
attacks worms from malicious external
threat groups are likely to be the
drivers of things that's not to say that
we don't consider internal uh
uh Insider threat implicitly I mentioned
earlier on you know we have the this
kind of notion of a statistical model
where you have the likel of certain
things happening we actually model the
attritional risk uh through that sort of
method so we have quite a lot of data to
see that you know these sorts of attacks
do happen so inside of our model we sort
of are implicitly capturing this but
we're not you know Express you know
we're not calling it out uh so so
in principle we could add insiders as a
new attack category and I don't think
really anything in our framework would
fundamentally change we'd have to add
ttps that are appropriate to insiders
and so forth and but as Chris said it
probably wouldn't affect our overall
model output
now I will say
uh my own personal opinion to getting
back to this gentleman's question about
Enterprise level
I think potentially one of the most
catastrophic types of attacks for an
Enterprise would be executive level
Insider attack
Executives who have enough technical
Savvy to go back and change your
financial systems right so think of
Worldcom type scandals and so forth
uh if I were an Enterprise risk manager
I would have executive or privileged
access that causes major financial fraud
in your threat model
hi Steph I'm from STX I have a question
so we have create models in the past
like for hurricanes stock strong wind
and everything
with lots of experience this is all
natural science you can do controlled
experiments and so now with cyber we are
more in social science the environment
changes permanently now we know quoting
Nasim Talib the bigger the risk or the
bigger the event the less we have a clue
where or how do you draw the boundary
between stuff we can model and stuff we
fundamentally cannot model
uh so I'll give us both a chance to
answer this Chris can think about it
while I'm babbling on uh you've raised a
crucial point so I mentioned at the
start that my PhD work was in
computational social science
social science is a very broad loose not
tightly integrated set of theories and
methods compared to physics for example
or chemistry
but there is a lot of
things to draw on so I mentioned in the
model of threat actor decision making
that draws upon consumer Choice firm
investment
so-called maximization of subjective
expected utility and so forth so we can
apply these especially in narrow
contexts
Define a context of certain human
behavior for example peer influence to
what extent do threat actors think
through their own
Roi versus they just follow the crowd or
they've they follow on the habits of
what
somebody else does or they acquire a
tool set from the dark web and start
trying it until it doesn't work and they
do something else so there's a fairly
good body of knowledge and methods and
Theory to inform that now the trick is
as you said before and this is a matter
of expert professional Judgment at what
level do we apply this how granular do
we get is it better just to treat this
as a you know random dice throwing
because we don't know a lot of details
and there's so much uncertainty or can
we treat it as you know a rational
decision-making process where the agents
have a lot of information and they might
even make strategic choices in a game
theory sense I'm going to trick my
opponent and I'm going to fake this and
do that so uh
it's my answer Chris yeah
yeah I guess my I'll just give some
maybe a slightly broader comments which
I think that ultimately
however good your model is there needs
to be an acknowledgment I think of
the uncertainty in this field is likely
to always be greater than in the context
of a hurricane for example for many
reasons as we mentioned you know you've
got the whole human decision-making side
of things the threat landscape changing
far quicker than you know
than climate change is changing
hurricanes for example and then you've
also got I think the observability
challenge you know with a hurricane you
know you can use satellite imagery and
you know ground anemometers to measure
the wind speed to make sure that your
model is producing realistic output with
cyber it's extremely difficult for us to
at scale you know scan the internet to
see which companies actually had a
ransomware
strained successfully deployed on some
of their servers right so I think
it doesn't mean that this that
uncertainty does not mean in my view
that this Pursuit is not worth doing
because I think certainly from the
insurance perspective as soon as you
insure a company you need to start
thinking about this sort of thing and
either your sort of finger in the air or
you're trying to use techniques like
we're trying to use but um yeah I think
I would endorse what Russell was saying
but I think also yeah there needs to be
an acknowledgment of a greater
uncertainty in this sphere
thank you
uh hopefully just a quick one which was
one of your points was around the lack
of incident information one thing was
around the lack of incident information
you mentioned that internet information
is hard to come by I was just wondering
since you work so closely with insurers
um you know their clients of yours they
they've sort of received a lot of this
modeling wouldn't they have a lot of
incident information from where they're
paid out and have you been able to
leverage that
so the question is do we get information
from insurance from their claims
information and others that we make use
of so
it depends um I think for insurance
companies this is my personal take not
that of RMS uh is that you know
insurance companies you know they view
their claims data as being a form of
intellectual property especially if
you're a insurance company that ensures
many many companies that data on the
frequency and the types of events and
all these sorts of things is really
really valuable to you certain insurance
companies will view that actually they'd
rather not share that information with
vendors such as ourselves because they
don't want their competitors to benefit
from that intelligence whilst other
kinds of companies
um maybe take a longer view that they
want to actually having robust
quantitative methods is
necessary for a cyber insurance for a
healthy cyber insurance industry more
broadly so uh yeah we get we do have
some claims data from some of our
clients but we'd always like more but we
understand that actually it's a business
decision making a business decision as
well as uh other kinds of things
there is a informal process
where some of that information gets
exchanged implicitly it involves them
running the model and looking at their
own data you know wait a minute we don't
what you're saying this and we're we're
saying that
so whenever we get bones of contention
irritation we're too high compared to
what they think are too low that sort of
informs us indirectly about not the
details but the overall summary of where
they are in the risk curve
I think as well actually it's also worth
noting that some insurance companies do
release claims statistics reports which
are also pretty you know interesting
where they you know they're not
releasing the names of the companies
that were hit or anything but they're
saying that you know for companies with
less than five billion dollars of
Revenue you know two percent of them in
our portfolio took a claim or something
like that so I think yeah data is being
shared but not as openly as maybe some
of us would like yeah thank you
all right I think that's a wrap thanks
everybody
[Applause]