all right good morning
i'd like to welcome you all to b-sides
uh this specifically is the ground floor
track so
uh today i have the honor of introducing
uriel who'll be going ahead and talking
about mail or analysis the red team
edition
uh before we do that of course i have a
couple of those little announcements to
give real quick so
first we'd like to start with uh our
thanking our sponsors who are
responsible for making all this happen
without them we literally couldn't be
here doing what we do
we'd like to especially thank our
diamond sponsors lastpass and palo alto
networks and our gold sponsors uh amazon
flextrac and google
it's their support along with our other
sponsors donors and volunteers that make
this event possible
these talks are being streamed live and
they are being recorded and will be
posted on youtube so there is no need
for you to take photos or videos of the
presentation
we ask that you try to silence your cell
phones keep them in your pockets
as a reminder
our policy is photographs is that you if
you do take a photograph
you should have permission for anybody
who's in the shot we're very sensitive
to being photographed uh some uh
presenters and or uh members of the
community prefer to stay anonymous so
please remember that as you're taking
photos around the conference uh also i'd
like to remind you if we're going to do
questions and answers afterwards please
step up and use the microphone it's not
so much for
us in the room or for the presenter but
it's being recorded so that those who
watch it later can hear your question
clearly as it's being asked
so
all right uh with that i'd like to go
ahead and turn it over and say there it
is uh thank you so much for being here
thank you very much for introducing me
so first of all cheers give yourself a
round of applause please
oh oh
come on come on open up
so uh first of all cheers
cognac
um
so first of all my name is royal kosai
thank you for presenting me
uh first words of appreciation uh before
we going to start with our presentation
uh i want to thank uh first of all i
want to thank god and my mom of course
because if not for them i will not be
here i want to thank besides for making
this amazing
conference
and of course thank you amazing audience
thank you for being here so let's get
started
so
i like my talks and my presentation be
less about talks and more about doing
and more about practical stuff
like you know we'll do a couple of demos
so i'll first introduce what i will show
you in the demo so you'll have some
interest
the first demo will be about the dark
side run somewhere and how you can as a
red team learn from it
and basically how you can take the same
concepts and kind of implement them in
your own malware you develop
and another demo which i'll introduce
how to implement some of the bypass
antivirus bypass techniques in your own
malware in order to basically evade
antivirus and edr software
and my goal in this presentation this
talk is basically for you
to open up your mind
to be fluid
not to be rigid
and
basically
help security grow and become better
so
basically let's get started
so this talk is not only for retimers
it's for everyone but
the the aim is specifically more about
retimers
but again anyone can learn from it take
the concepts take the tools and uh you
know implement it
so i want you
to learn malware analysis
now what the heck a retimer want to know
about malware analysis like why
any retimer has its own tools
his own c2 his own
thing
and eventually you know most of the
people that are retimers
are uh you know more about
infrastructure penetration testing or uh
you know uh active directory and stuff
like this
but in the end of the day most of the
adversaries or the attackers
will go for your data
okay
they will write ransomware they will
write some info stealers they will
use mostly malware
so if you want to become
a stronger retimer and a better security
researcher
you need to learn malware analysis and
not only for the sake of malware
analysis
but
for the sake of offensive security
so a little bit about me my name is
uriel kosair i'm the book author of
antivirus bypass techniques
basically the book presents you 10
practical techniques
which you can implement in your own
tools and will help you to bypass
basically any antivirus and edr
and of course this book also provides
some security recommendations that you
can use in order to develop better
antivirus and do better detection
engineering and stuff like this
i'm also the founder of malware analysis
co which is basically a website that
gives you all the necessary information
you need for malware analysis like tools
cheat sheets stuff like this
you also have my courses there i
provided course like basic malware
analysis advanced reverse engineering
and other stuff like malware development
basically i like to do male research
and other security related topics i'm
also the red team tech leader of the
biggest company uh like the biggest beer
company in the world called abn bev
uh just a small disclaimer i'm not
talking in behalf of abby and bev
talking behalf before myself but just
for you to know
um also youtuber blogger lecturer uh
like uh one of my biggest passions
actually is to uh teach students and
give them the knowledge and and given
tools
to become better security professionals
and also
uh to enter this field so i doing this
for something like 10 years in israel
around the world also
and it's a great honor for me also to
stand here
so before the show begins
what the heck is malware analysis
i like to define things
very shortly without all the wikipedia
mumbo jumbo stuff you know
so metal analysis basically is the art
of analyzing and research of malicious
software behavior and patterns
and by researching malicious behaviors
and patterns you can learn a lot from
them
for the sake of blue teaming like
detecting malware extracting indicators
of compromise understanding the ttps and
all this stuff
but also
as a rhythmer you can
learn a lot from those malware from
their techniques from their bypass stuff
uh how they obfuscate their strings how
they use their malware how they're how
they actually literally move in your
network so it's
analyzing malware is like getting into
the head
of the author of this malware it's like
reading a book you know for me it's like
reading a book i think it's even better
than mozart yeah most of people don't
really like to
reverse engineer assembly and sing all
this mumbo jumbo stuff but
for me it's actually an art
so the levels of malware analysis
so the basic level is you can
basically take a malware sample if it's
an executable file powershell script
whatever you can throw it inside a
sandbox which is basically a virtualized
environment with all the necessary tools
um to analyze the malware and basically
you have things like any run or
hybrid analysis which are basically
you can take a file throw it into either
the sandbox and it will give you
uh like the overview of what the malware
actually and how is executed and all the
stuff of course if there is malware with
anti-sandbox and other evasion
techniques most likely it will not be
executed on the sandbox so it's kind of
limited but it can give you a good
overview of what the malware does and
also helping you to extract indicators
of compromise
the next level is called static analysis
is basically taking a file uh extracting
strings understand the
the building blocks of the file
before you actually execute it on your
sandbox environment on your virtualized
machine
okay you have dynamic analysis which is
basically to execute the malware on your
virtual machine to see how it behaves
use tools like procmon plus explorer api
monitor understand what kind of
windows api functions are executed and
all this kind of stuff and of course the
most amazing stuff that most people are
i think frightened of is reverse
engineering it's a god damn get get into
the assembly code or whatever it is
and understand how the malwares actually
work so it's kind of interesting for
example if your malware opens a socket
and interacts with us with you know with
an external server or c2
how would actually do it
okay what kind of windows api function
uses how can i use it for detection
engineering
how can i re-implement it in my own
malware my own ratings in my own attacks
you know for example whenever you want
to interact over http with some external
server you can use
various windows api functions you can
use this socket you can use uh
internet open url and you have all kind
of ba and bunch of other api functions
okay
so this is only a small fraction a small
example for you to understand
what you can do
with the power and knowledge of malware
analysis
so
we talked about malware analysis blah
blah blah what it is what's the level of
this kind of stuff so first of all
cheers another ship
ah amazing
so
what is red tv you know
you will you will ask someone
and they'll say you oh it's the
it's the knowledge of using or takes or
or you the use of tools like metasploit
and cobblestrike and do that and do this
and but like what is the essence what is
the goal of receiving like actually
so first of all right is not about
achieving a d a
domain admin and you know what let me
tell you another thing
most of the attackers and most of the
malware doesn't even care about getting
a domain admin you know why
because most of the networks today
are very very hard to manage
their permissions
and their security it's very hard to be
a blue team it's very hard to like
literally implement security controls in
the right way
so even a ransomware today can encrypt
your document files without having local
admin or even a domain admin so what the
hell it needs the domain army so most of
times malware or attackers will go for
domain admins
if it's really necessary for them like
to literally move between forests
uh through other networks or just for
the fun of it yeah
so writing is about simulating real
world threats now what the heck is a
real world trade
uh doesn't running kraken up exec with
metasploit with all the cobalt strike
mumbo jumbo stuff is actually ready
um
it's the tools it's not the essence of
it
so
the purpose of reading is to provide a
real-world picture of business related
threats
like for example if you're a pharmacy
business
maybe your adversary will not be conti
or reveal
it will be
maybe
another pharmacy company
i don't know uh maybe another competitor
maybe some
insider threat i don't know
and basically you need to define as a
retimer what is an actual threat to your
company that you're trying to red team
purpose is to act like the adversary or
the enemy
based on accurate rate intelligence
and
of threat actors targeting your business
so the use of threat intelligence will
help you
to become more aware of what kind of
threat actors and ttps
you actually need to simulate
in order to give the real picture of the
security posture of the company
simulate potential threats actors ttps
tactics techniques and procedures
okay it's like
understanding the tactics uh the
techniques they're using maybe that the
threat actors using mimikats to dump
elsa's maybe they created their own
version of mimikats with different api
functions which most most of edrs
doesn't really
uh even detect them i don't know
um
and based on
these data like the ttps you can
actually go
and do your stuff
for example if you have three attractors
like conti which they're basically a
ransomware group
i hate them of course
they attack a couple of my clients also
but you know
the world is hard
but if you understand that conte is
actually targeting your business and you
understand their ttps
you can
go and simulate the threats on the
company you're attacking of course in a
secure manner so always take opsec into
your mind when you're doing retin
and eventually the
real goal of red teams is not to go to
blue team and say
yeah
you're you're you've failed or
uh be childish i i i win you and and i
overcome you and all this kind of
you know
the real purpose of writing is to help
organizations become better that's it
and of course helping the blue team
become better
so if you're as a red team understand
the craft
the techniques the tools that the blue
team uses
and also if the blue team understand how
the red team is operate
they can basically help each other
so
retimer
must have an adversarial mindset this is
for sure you cannot be a red teamer if
you don't know how to think look like
your enemy like a criminal
okay like a bad guy
but mama always said like
told us to stay away from bad guys you
know
oh so sweet mommy
i like my mom
and
she has amazing tips for life and she's
even right
uh but not in the case of wretting
you actually need to think like your
enemy and it's kind of hard um
like psychologically not only
technically
so
uh to know your enemy you must become
your enemy i know it's kind of uh hard
to do it but
uh if your skills of mimicking others
and and to be like uh
uh
[Music]
to
mimic others basically and to understand
their psychology it will be much easier
for you to do this
now behold the real power of retiming
cobalt's right
no no
no don't take it seriously like
cobblestrike
hollow track is an amazing tool you know
it's amazing too it has a gui it has a
lot of features
bypass evasion modules it does amazing
job okay so
uh
take it in the right perspective but
mostly when you talk to retirees they
are about the tools like writing cobalt
strike my man
you're not ready without cobble strike
you need to have cobras right
i don't agree
i don't agree it's just one of the best
tools out there i think but
it's not what actually defines
a retimer
so why not doing things like this
now
in the left you have cobalt's right in
the right you have either pro
personally i like to smoke when i
doing reversing
kind of cool and you know opens your
mind
[Music]
what for me represents the right picture
like ida
is like
go
and understand your own tools go and
understand your own techniques go and
understand other adversaries techniques
and tools and malware
go
and research stuff like
someone asked me like uh five years ago
you know what it's mimi cats and they're
like
uh
i
think so many cats this dumb tool blah
blah and it's like what this and that
comment does and it's like
whatever dumps the elsa's memory okay
it's like yeah
and i asked him you know what
how do you actually understand how it
works you know when you're asking
someone
what is something
do you know about something
so what is the actual level of
understanding of this question
like
for example mimikatz
what is the level of understanding of
this tool
how do you actually know how it operates
how it acts what kind of functions it
uses in what languages it was written
and compiled
do you
or just go grab the tools execute them
and you're ready
which
to be honest most of the time
it's working it's like
not maybe mimics but other tools you
know but in order for you to become
a better returner or a stronger security
professional
go and try to understand how this tool
operate like go do some wireshark
like understand how the network packets
are going on
like understand how the tool you are
using for example mimikats to dump lsas
what's actually doing like opening a
handle
to the else's process enumerating
the pids of the processes
receiving it handled with open with the
open process windows api function
use use of the mini dump function to
actually dump
the lcs
and after you actually understand this
functionality you can think maybe
maybe there's other functions or windows
api functions that i can use
which most likely most cdrs and
antivirus will not detect it
so it will open up for you a greater
world
now don't get me wrong
both malware analysis and red teaming
are not about the tools one is using
but the ability to research and
understand technical and abstract
concepts
eventually
so i think you kind of understand why
malwanas need to concern returners okay
but one of the reasons is because the
bad guys do
they go
and learn from each other's malware from
each other tools from each other
techniques
and they actually go and re-implement
the same techniques the same tools or
the same concept basically in their own
malware for example if you heard about
the log b3 ransomware also did a video
about them
they literally got
the code from dark side ransomware
copied some snippets from it for the
decryption runtime decryption mechanisms
and for dynamic api resolve which will
talk about it and then literally copy
and paste it
the same technique the same concept in
their own malware it's like what the
hell i'm i'm like researching the lobby
transformer and it's like
uh
like minimum 50
uh the code of dark side
so if the bad guys go and learn from
other malware and other tools
why not the returners the good guys
so threat actors evolve by learning and
leveraging the craft and ttps by
researching malware samples in the wild
it is one of their secrets
but
not anymore i hope this talk will
actually open your mind and give you the
necessary tools
and necessary mindset to become a better
security professional
so let's talk about uh quickly about the
malware development lifecycle like the
mdlc i call it it's like sdlc for
software development lifecycle but for
malware which is kind of the same
so you have malware development
you develop your malware you know the
malware need to check in which kind of
environment it actually resides whether
it's linux windows what kind of version
what is the mac address the ip address
what's so called information gathering
or situational awareness so the malware
need to be aware of where is actually it
and then based on this information which
most likely be sent to an external c2
server
the malware will receive the
configuration or the next stage of
execution
so
part of our development like any other
software development
is to test and do qa like
go and develop your malware in a secure
manner of course for good purposes
uh and not for bad purposes don't be a
black hat be a white hat you know
it's kind of cool because for example if
you want to learn c and assembly
and doing this
via developing malware it's much cooler
than developing
uh
the checkmate or snake game this this my
my opinion okay
then you want to implement some malware
defense bypass techniques inside your
malware
like
most likely if your malware will drop in
one of the computers or networks that
you're targeting there will be some
endpoint protections that you want to
buy this like dlp edrs antivirus stuff
like this
then you want to actually do some
offline av and edr testing before
actually distributing the malware
and then it's one of the things that i
want to talk about today
is ioc collection and removal like
it's it's fine that you actually develop
your own malware you use c or python or
partial whatever language that you want
but
after you compile your malware
like with visual studio
or with c
or with you know gcc or whatever
compiler is out there
how the file is actually look like for
the edr for the antivirus for the
malware analyst for the researcher
does the strings that you actually used
or the variable names or the function
names or any other ip addresses that you
used in your own malware
they actually presented in your malware
like in a
clear text you need to obfuscate them
maybe one compiler
compiled it in a one way and another
compiler
compiled your malware in a different way
which will be much harder for malware
analysts and edrs to detect
so if you compile for example c written
malware in
visual studio
it will be basically a different output
if you
compile it
in for example gcc compiler okay
so
it's basically a research topic for you
if you want to kind of
test write a malware try to actually
compile it with different compilers and
see the difference do some diffs uh
strings up code differentiation uh see
how it actually the compiled versions
are differs from each other
okay
and then for example
if you have some malicious or suspicious
ioc presented in your compiled malware
you want to kind of like somehow remove
it obfuscate and prep it or whatever
and of course uh
as a white white attacker or whatever
you want to use the same uh like
techniques and iocs used there and like
work together with the threat
intelligence
and like try to understand uh how they
are actually relevant to other malware
in the wild for other trade groups
basically you do not have to develop
your malware from zero
and this is one of the things that
basically i want to say here
you can learn from real world malware
samples and incidents for example you
can go for
the colonial pipeline incident if you
remember
the same incident that actually broke
half of
the gas stations
in the united states it was actually the
dark side run somewhere like a small
a piece of executable
disturbed and and crashed half of the
gas stations in the united states
something like this not really exactly
on the numbers but something like this
so what one executable file one
ransomware can do to your state not only
for a company
think about it
and how much can be learned
from the this runs away
and i also want to dive with you into
this ransomware like i don't have all
the time in the world but we'll do
something simple there
so
let's talk about darkseid ransomware
runtime code decryption and dynamic api
result now
don't get creepy on me please it it's
going to be kind of a deep technical
stuff like assembly stuff um i'll try to
explain it in a
like in a simple fashion
and let's begin so let me just
start my virtual machine here
so what do we have here
we just do
okay can you see something here like
like this maybe
yeah
so
we have the dark side sample yeah yeah
the same the same
malware that disturbed half of the
united states
gas stations
so
if i open this file inside pe bearer for
example i want to see the sections and
imports like the actual
sections you have in the executable
files and the imported functions
now
i
just remember
uh analyzing malware is like reading a
book
and each one each book has its own
sections like you know it has a title
it has the data in the title and so on
so
you can see here we have two text
sections
now most of normal files will have one
text section
the text section actually contains
the
execution code like the machine code the
assembly code that is need to be
actually executed on your cpu on your
operating system and then you have
another
section called text one you know kind of
weird
now
in most files even most malware if you
go to the imports
you will see
much
larger dll entries
and for each dls you see
at least five to ten
imported functions
you can see where i'm going you have
only one dll kernel 32dl one of the most
basic and mostly used dlls in windows
and they have only one function called
exit process like what the hell like a
normal malware or normal file will uh
will include more dlls like socket and
you know create file great process you
know like basic stuff and here you have
only one function what the hell
so
if you open up the
if you open up the malware inside ida
pro and go again to import you'll see
exit process also only present here
and basically this is the starting point
from where the malware actually begins
now this is not the actual function
names okay so this is the function names
that i call okay so each call here in
assembly is basically calling to a
function so for example you define the
function in c like for example void blah
blah and it has two parameters
so this what we have so you have here
basically two parameters which are
basically encrypted blob
you know basically an encrypted mumbo
jumbo stuff here
and this called mumbo jumbo stuff will
do something
then do another something and eventually
go and decrypt
those encrypted blobs
now if i'll do space here i'll see that
the actual code here is under the text
one section that we saw
which is not very normal
and eventually if i go here to like
for this call where show begins
where it's actually where the run source
start to encrypt your computer
if you go here it's like gibberish
nothing
what the hell
so
if i double click you can see here we
have the text section
so
it's kind of occurs to me that
the decrypted blob will be
uh placed
in the actual text section so this mumbo
jumbo stuff will be eventually decrypted
and be an actual code to analyze so we
have uh basically we have to execute the
ransomware on my virtual machine uh so
be careful with it
let's begin so
basically
i'll go and put a breakpoint here
and start the local windows
debugger whoa
okay so now it got to the breakpoint
so now the actual code is here so we did
whatever stuff it does here
then we do
f8 to actually execute the function now
just for understand what kind of
decryption it uses here if you go double
click
on this function
it calls this this function which i call
decryption festival
which actually go and
call another function
and eventually duke soar
blah blah so it will basically
store the values and in that way decrypt
the content
okay so let's do f8
i hate this computer
okay and another f8
and now
we'll need to see something like
different here
so
before i actually go inside this code
let me just undefine it in ida and
reanalyze it again because for either
kind it's kind of like uh
hard to understand what is going on then
so if i
select here the code
like this
i go and do
uh like analyze selected area or c
analyze
and i'll hope it will give something
sensible
okay
here we have some things here
let's do here c worship begins
amazing
do another c
we kind of need to help either to
reanalyze the code basically
so now
i'll go in f7 which is basically go into
the function
um
let me just also define it as a function
like
with the p
now i defined it as a function and like
if now i can do space and i will see
everything in a fashionably mannered uh
you know execution flow okay so
basically i either after the decryption
has occurred i i undefined the data that
i just kind of like got hard time to
analyze re-analyze it again and using
the p
button in the keyboard basically i
define it as a function
for ida to understand it is what is the
actually building blocks
cheers
okay so
eventually
it will go and call here two functions
this first function the second one so
if i go to this
function
it will do some weird things which will
basically
eventually
will resolve the apis or the functions
of
the of the run somewhere so suddenly you
will have
some functions appear there so
let's try to do
f8 here
call the first function
as you can see
it it resolved like a lot of dlls
and
now we got to actually resolve the
functions also
so
then i do another
f8 and now you can see a lot of call
blah blah something called blah blah
something d word whatever it's actually
a sign that is calling to the
dynamically resolved iat the import
address table the actual functions of
the dls which are resolved in runtime
okay so if i go into this call
or maybe to another call like let me do
i hate this computer
and if i do now
for example
i'll do this call i'll do f7
it will go actually
and call show 32 command line argument
so this function didn't appear in the
executable file
how did it actually
now appear so the two functions that i
presented you here they're actually
doing what's so called dynamic api
result
now if you're as a retimer go and
re-implement the same technique or the
same concept in a different technique
you can evade most of the static engines
in most of the interiors and antivirus
and it's kind of easy to do it
yeah
so
for the sake of uh for our time
i'll go back to my slides
i actually have a run somewhere running
now on my virtual machine and i don't
give a hell about it okay
okay so as we saw no functions in the
import address table
we can see that the sections are packed
or encrypted
okay so you see there is a high entropy
most likely if there is a higher uh
value than seven it will be most likely
encrypted and coded or obfuscated
so
first before it goes into actually
resolving the apis it will do the
decryption so where
where i showed you the two decryption
routines with the source stuff this is
where actually the store is made
and the text section is actually
decrypted
and the dynamic api result
basically it takes um
both functions of load library which
literally loads a dll file in runtime
dynamically
and then uses the get proc address
the get proc address function is like
the
uh the broad like load library and get
processors like the brother and sister
of resolving apis or loading functions
the getpro address function will
actually import the specific functions
from the dlls
and voila you have the result functions
in runtime
there was some confusion uh as far as
double booking the room uh if you are
looking for the 12 o'clock reverse
engineering a dos pc fm
v game from 1994 by andrew it's now down
in the proving ground i'm sorry to have
interrupted thank you it's fine thank
you
so we talked about or i showed you
actually how it looks like
reversing a malware or it's not always
like this
uh if if the for example malware like
agent tesla or the yashama ransomware
which i also have a youtube video on it
you'll see that the malware is actually
compiled c sharp like dotnet c sharp
i hate oop languages i hate i hate them
but they're much easier to uh analyze
because you don't need to actually
analyze assembly because
dot c sharp is a high level language uh
it's called il assembly and if you put
this executable this compiled executable
into tools like d and spy it will
literally decompile the code
you literally will see
the source code of the malware
um
in c plus c or c plus plus compile
malware you will not see
the actual source code you will see the
assembly so either will do for you a
disassembly not the compile so it's a
different process
so now let's do some offensive stuff
uh
present you two bypass techniques
the first one is called rename
obfuscation and the second one is called
memory bombing which is my favorite um
again they're referred also in my book
antivirus bypass techniques i'll be more
than glad if you
will read this book
so let's take a simple reversal
like the most basic stuff that
retimers and pentas are like reverse
shadow
so you have a
c plus plus or c plus plus basically
code here
which defines the main function it
receives
two to three arguments
you define the ip that you want to call
back or to communicate with and the port
of the c2 malicious
whatever server
okay then it actually
calls the function with the host and
port
and you can kind of get what where i'm
getting it like
if you have a function named execute
shell in your code what is the
probability that antivirus and idios
will
detect it
you know
think about it
so the function of execute shell
basically takes two arguments uh you
know the ip the port
creates a socket blah blah blah blah
blah blah blah stuff and you know uh
defines the connection of ipv4 in this
case afinet and defines the receive of
data the buffer itself like whenever the
city server uh as an attacker you want
to execute a comment it needs to send a
comment and you need to receive the
output in the server side so this is the
thing
so
now we actually compile this
malware or reversal
and now we'll start to look for iocs
and again not only like you you
literally switch your
perspective
to a blue teamer
now we're acting like a blue teamer
this is the real power
like
you're already writing your malware your
whatever stuff you're doing then you put
the blue team head and you're okay if
i'm a blue team how do i detect it
what can what kind of iocs artifacts i
can find and rely on in order to create
my detections with the r or whatever
detection language it uses so if i do
your strings on the executable and i'll
use find str in case sensitive on cmd
like if any star is like the lame
version of grep in windows okay
i hate windows
okay
um
and you have this cmd dot
something like where is it dot exit
one of the reason you don't see the dot
exit it's because i used uh c plus plus
which is a shitty language i like c but
i hate c plus plus because it's oop and
and also to reverse engineer simplest
plus is much harder
and basically
um
you don't see cmd dot exit because there
is a null terminated string not an
alternative like a slash n
in each one of the strings for example
if you have i i p like
192.168.0.1 you you'll have in the
strings 192 168.
and then a new line
zero and one what uh
say plus plus don't ask me
okay so
if you're writing your malware z plus
plus it basically be
better for you
uh or easier for you to bypass rather
than c because c compile executables are
much easier to read you literally see
the strings the you know variable names
or whatever you know functions they're
defined and it's much easier to
understand
um okay so what now so now i'll
implement some rename obfuscation
so as you can see it's the same code
um
i changed the function from execute
shell like a shell what the hell to run
little generic name run run what
then you have host and port which again
it can be benign it doesn't have to be
malicious you know
um
you're in in the code before you saw
that actually
uh music create process with the cmd dot
exit and it's like cmd dot x in one line
so i did a simple trick you know
i
basically defined two char variables
cm
and d dot exit and then i concatenated
them together using strcat ins and in c
or c plus plus whatever as a pointer
variable of course and i pass this
pointer variable to create process
to the windows api create process
function
and
it basically changes things
in a compiled version
then you validate it again die you'll
see removal
yeah where's the cmd thought something
yeah
gun
got away
the second technique that i want to show
you is memory bombing i
i think that i basically the first that
name this technique is memory bombing
not something new but
presented in my book
and it's very
it's very basic like the first technique
used to bypass the static engine of
antivirus and edrs this one is just for
the dynamic engine
like
whenever you execute your malware or
your executable
the dynamic engine of the antivirus or
the edr will basically allocate a
protected virtualized memory like
virtual alert or something like this
it will put the code inside this
emulated uh environment or memory in
your computer and it will try to execute
it
now
as we all know
antivirus ddrs has one problem
uh basically two problems
the fear of false positives
yeah
and
the
limitation of resources in your computer
because think about it and diverse and
ears are residing the same memory in the
same operating system the same computer
so of course there have some limitations
now think about it if i
allocate
enough large memory like eight megabytes
20 mega whatever
so dantiverse like looks in your mouth
and said ah man it's too big for me
move on
and it let it let your malware execute
because
if there is any chance that it will
terminate a legitimate process or a
legitimate executable
big problem
and this is the same thing that i'm
actually exploiting here the fact that
any antivirus anywhere has some resource
limitation
and i'm allocating a big chunk of memory
for him to choke out
and later malware executed
and now for the detection test results
before the obfuscation and memory
bombing is made 35 detections
after the fescation and memory bond has
occurred
half
down
f down like more than 50
it's a lot
now think about it if i'll do things a
little bit differently and i'll
implement maybe even one or more
bypass techniques
i will create a fully undetectable
malware
zero detections
yeah
this is the reality we're living at this
is why you need to become a better
security expert this is why you need to
understand both sides red team blue team
whatever color you want to purple theme
yellow
all these colors it's not about the
colors it's about
the way you're working the way you're
taking the way you're approaching stuff
so for you know for the sake of ending
this uh
presentation
you know some important tips for success
always understand your tools and malware
go as deeper as possible understand the
iocs generated in your compile malware
the network packets the actual use
functions everything that you can
go as deep as possible you will be
surprised as what you will learn the
most
learning experience i had in my own
offensive blah blah career
is through doing the blue team stuff
into the response forensics now right
now it's like seeing the other side of
things
you know what i really appreciate blue
teamers because it's a hell of a hard
thing to do
and always the complaints are against
the blue team the writing is kind of sad
but
learn malware analysis to understand
think like a blue teamer and again
marouane is not only for bluetooth is
for red teamers
the bad guys do it they analyze malware
and they learn from each other i
actually showed you it with the dark
side ransomware and if you want you can
go to my youtube video about log b3
ransomware and you kind of see the same
code re-implemented there
research malware to gain deeper
knowledge and inspirations better
understanding of operating systems of
coding of everything
follow the mdlc model malware
development is like any other sdlc
process so write your malware
in a good fashion like
one of the malware research like they
call auto max keylogger
um i actually found a vulnerability
there which i exploited dll hijacking
like
if if you have automatic skill or in
your computer and and and i'm an another
attacker and i want to persist or maybe
even escalate privilege in your computer
i can exploit the same malware the art
of skill group to
be to resign in your computer so it's
kind of you know so if it's very
important for you for like opsec uh
operational security and everything
securely code securely code your malware
yeah i know it's kind of funny to say
that but yeah
be curious passionate and innovative i
don't need to say this
and take some breaks in between don't
work like uh
like a juggernaut take some breaks in
between
cooperation
cooperate don't be a jackass
yeah
if you want to do a real
adversary simulation adversary emulation
writing code whatever you want
you need to cooperate with teams like
trade intelligence you need to or do the
sort of intelligence for yourself and
understand what
is the actual value you provide your
company based on
the
actual threats posed on your company
and eventually take your report that
research simulation you did or the
retaining
work with the blue team
and gain a better security and money
time
again think like fluid water not like a
rigid rock
they can operate like a criminal
help security grow and become better
if you want to have some more resources
some more fun more learning experience
you can go into malware analysis school
you don't have to take my courses do
whatever you want you can learn for
yourselves
but you can use the resources the cheat
sheets everything is most of the things
are for free basically um my webs is
like an index you have everything there
or whatever you need uh if you have some
suggestions or uh things that
you think you i may add to
the website feel free to contact me
in my twitter whatever
yeah that's it thank you very much
[Applause]
thank you thank you your amazing
audience any questions
yeah
okay can you go just for the microphone
they asked yeah
questions questions
cheers
uh in terms of uh sandbox analysis uh
now that cuckoo's kind of been uh not
updated in a very long time i saw on
your site you have a bunch of sandboxes
listed but
it could be closer to the background
yeah okay testing amazing all right on
your website i saw you listed a bunch of
sandboxes um i used to use cuckoo when i
used to do this kind of stuff yeah i
haven't updated that forever the sandbox
is you listed i see a lot of them are
like paid solutions is there anything
you can still run locally similar to how
cooper used to be where you could step
into a process and interactively you
know like make a change like click on a
link or something or a button um and
then go back and get your analysis at
the end yeah that's not like uh running
the cloud
because if i'm dealing with very
sensitive data i don't necessarily trust
a company that says they'll keep it
private and keep everything local okay
thank you for the question so basically
yes about uh you know
plausible and workable sandbox out there
so basically if you go to my website
you'll see there's a bunch of uh you
know sandbox that you can use maybe
there's other settings that i'm not
aware of um
you can you basically have two options
you can implement your own
automated sandbox in uh
using cuckoo sandbox which is free open
source i actually use it in my army
service uh where i did the research and
security stuff
and it's kind of helped me you know to
gain the first visibility and
understanding of the malware it actually
um also uh communicates with your virus
total and brings you all the detections
all this kind of stuff um so if you want
to do something locally use a very
strong server with you know ssd storage
and whatever uh you know a zeon cpu
everything um
at least 32 gigs of ram because it takes
a lot of resources
basically you can implement cuckoo
sandbox it will do amazing job but take
into account there is a lot of
troubleshooting and a lot of problems
that you need to face like python
and linux and yada yada a lot
of yeah
if you want to
use a cloud-based sandbox you can use
any run which is amazing
uh for understood it's russian-based or
something i i don't know
from what i heard
take care
good luck don't put any personal
information in your malware or something
[Music]
uh you can use uh you know hybrid
analysis um and you know other other
solutions just go to bangladesh you have
their
sandbox
links you can use all of them
other questions
thank you
[Applause]
your amazing audience thank you very
much may god bless you all thank you