welcome everybody
uh this is panel discussion today is on
software bill of materials and we have
with us fortunate to have a great panel
that we're going to discuss and talk
about where we stand today with it and
where we plan to go with software bill
of materials or s bomb as we've got to
let her speak first
so uh
katie would you like to introduce
yourself yes sure hi
i'm katie bratman i work at new york
presbyterian hospital as part of the
vulnerability management team and also
as part of the daggerboard development
team we'll be talking a little bit about
daggerboard today it's an sbom analysis
tool
adam hi i'm adam kojak um i'm um a
developer at new york presbyterian
hospital as part of the information
security team
alan
i'm alan friedman i'm from the
government i'm here to help i'm from
sisa and i'm the guy who doesn't shut up
about us bomb
and lastly my name's christopher gates i
am a medical device developer and an
expert in embedded product cyber
security and i've worked with alan now
for seven years on various projects
something like that yeah
so the first question here is uh why do
we need an s bomb
so
if you go to the store and you buy a
twinkie it comes with a list of
ingredients uh to me it's just kind of
baffling
that the most important software in the
world doesn't have the same level of
transparency as we expect from a
non-biodegradable snack
uh
the important analogy of sort of that
list of ingredients that list of
ingredients by itself
won't magically save you
but one
would you buy from someone who couldn't
tell you
what they were encouraging you to eat or
in this case have your life depend on so
the value of doing it even if you can
never touch the data yourself you still
want someone to know that they have it
but the other thing is right you can't
do all of the things that we might do
with a list of ingredients uh right
protect your family from allergies
vulnerabilities uh follow
a uh
a certain religious based restriction
right the analogy there might be hey i
don't want things from certain types of
development environments or countries on
my network for certain reasons
so it really enables a lot of great data
to say or it's the data layer that
allows us to sort of think more broadly
about different kinds of risk
um i'll let you guys jump in about why
it's important for your orgs yeah so we
work in healthcare and where s bombs
really come in handy for us what we're
seeing is with medical devices so
oftentimes what happens is like we get a
medical device it's thrown on our
network we can scan it with a
vulnerability scanner but we don't get
the full picture of what it's made out
of that list of ingredients and so this
is where an s bomb can really help us we
can take an s-bomb before we buy the
device in our
purchasing process and then analyze it
and say do we really want to continue
with purchasing this
if there's a risk that was found how can
we mitigate it before implementing it
and so on
so i'll join with one more thing
there are organizations in the world
that only use like six types of software
right if you are just a traditional bog
standard enterprise then
s-bomb is gonna be nice for you but
there's going to be public security
advisories for your microsoft products
your cisco products right those have
mature product security teams and
data about vulnerabilities and risks in
those products is well documented and
easy to access
what we're talking about in the cavalry
track is a very different world right
it's the world of things that are
literally matters of life and death
those tend to be much smaller
organizations that produce them
and
yes some of them are starting to do
vulnerability disclosure and security
advisories but often the risk is not
going to be
this particular widget
uh in part because they haven't they
don't have security advisories and also
because
someone may not have developed a
targeted attack for a foothold
on that product the risk is sort of
automated scanning tools that are going
after some of the components and so
that's why particularly in safety
critical world medical infrastructure
ics
having that understanding is going to be
important and the last thing is right it
doesn't always feed into hey i need to
patch this some of you are familiar with
just how hard it is to patch something
that if i unplug this
people lose power people lose water
people die
but what we can do is start thinking
about it as more maturely of oh there's
a potential risk here so uh my long-term
plan is segment my network my long-term
plan is work with my threat intel to
sort of see if there's anything being
disclosed so again it sets up the longer
term risk especially in our cavalry
mission space
in a word it's all about transparency
and it allows you to assign risk to the
end user because somebody manufactured
something here you manufactured this box
or that
particular projector or that wireless
access point that's sitting over there
we look at that and as engineers we go
oh i know what that is and i can do a
physical attack on it tear it apart
reverse engineer it all right but as a
user
what they don't know they're bringing
this in and putting it into their
environment and potentially affecting
their environment their neighbors
environment everybody's environment i
mean we've seen a lot of denial of
service here distributed denial of
service attacks so it's actually more
than just the 16 critical
infrastructures the united states it's
everybody we don't want another marybot
type of episode again
transferring that knowledge to the end
user so they can say how much risk do i
feel comfortable with
right oh this has got a vulnerable
version of openssl in here i can live
with that i don't really care and some
people will other people will take it
offline and pull it out so it is about
disclosing all of that information not
keeping it a secret moving it to the
people who really are going to be
affected by it and that isn't the people
who manufactured it
so about four years ago
uh
i was working with alan on another ntia
project that had to do with updating
firmware and how you patch and do
upgrades of firmware and for devices in
the field and we rolled off that and
alan said hey i'm thinking about working
on another project here
that's called a software bill of
materials i said oh what's that
he says it's kind of like a list of
ingredients uh-huh
of what goes into your products i went
hey you know
what are we going to do a month of that
i mean that's going to be a short
project
that was four years later i hadn't a
clue what all the edge conditions were
that we looked at
and in that period of time allen put
together um
multiple working groups that cover
different aspects of software build
materials
but they all consisted of experts in the
field
and really humbling experts i mean i
quickly realized just how
ignorant i was of what this environment
required and how to handle this and to
this day i still find things that's like
oh yeah i didn't think about it that way
that somebody else already thinks about
great multidisciplinary group nobody
nobody heard cats like allen
all of these people are experts they're
we're all egocentric a-holes all right
and we all have our opinions and this
man would manage to keep us going all in
the intended direction and everybody
working together uh you know if we spot
that uh comet that's about to hit the
earth and we need a team to
mitigate that i want him leading it all
right so it's been really interesting
and very educational over this period of
time and now recently allen moved from
ntia to csa and where this new working
groups have started up so
ellen i've talked too much already
what what are your what's your feeling
on the work groups both at ntia and csa
first of all flattery gets you
everywhere thank you um
the and and this is actually what i love
about what we built for the s bomb
community right it's always very clear
very much not my idea in fact since i
joined government pretty much every idea
i've stolen from the cavalry and said
okay they start off with a great idea
let's actually try to use uh the flag
behind us to pull together communities
to make it happen so i want to uh doff
my hat to uh josh and bo and everyone
who's been part of the cavalry i think
it's it's this is what it's supposed to
do it's supposed to sort of take ideas
mature them and then hand them to folks
who can implement them
so
uh the first phase we have to do is
actually come up with a shared
definition
the idea of an s bomb as chris said
is is not that complicated but we need a
couple things one we need a shared
vision of what it looks like uh and no
one had actually sort of articulated
this is what an s-bomb is these are the
boundary conditions and how to make it
happen so the first years was focusing
on the what the why and the how
uh
and
there are the
good news is there was at least one data
format that could transfer and to convey
s-bomb in a standardized fashion the bad
news is there was more than one uh and
that's some fun that we still have is
sort of managing the data formats uh
we're gonna have a meet up in right
after this if anyone wants to talk more
about that
so we're now at a stage or last year we
would have staged where we have the
basics
there's no reason why an organization
cannot start producing s-bombs asking
for s-bombs thinking about how to use
them
our focus now is on operationalization
scale and automation right if we can't
do this if we can't integrate this data
into all the other things that we care
about in security then we're not going
to make the progress we need
uh right my vision three four years from
now is that we're actually not talking
about s-bomb as a unique thing it should
just be a standard part of our security
ecosystem the same way that right most
of us don't spend our days thinking
about cves there is a small community
that does but it's really we just
integrate it into how we think about our
security data
so
the plug for the work that's going
forward
uh if you'd like to get involved and
i'll remind you at the end uh we've got
a couple of uh focus points one is uh
cloud and sas
a lot of the focus on s-bomb thus far
has been on on-prem software which makes
sense right i have to defend it it's on
my network uh and certainly in our
safety critical domain around the
cavalry uh that's huge but i would and
you guys can tell me if i'm wrong i
think most medical devices now have a
cloud management component right
frequently yeah pretty quietly uh and
same is true in ics the same is true in
in a lot of other in automotive
so we need to be able to tell a story of
what does transparency mean
for a sas application that may have a
daily or hourly build
uh and could be very large so we want to
tell stories of use cases and then
ultimately implement it right so
does the s-bomb of a container is it
just the application logic is the
application logic in the os is it the
application the os and the orchestration
we want to sort that out we want to do
that with both producers and people who
use that data defenders
the second piece is going to be focusing
on tooling
how do we
make sure that if two different
suppliers or two different open source
projects produce an s-bom they're
reasonably similar uh and then we're
going to talk a lot about consumption
and the great tool that nyp has
developed in a little bit
we're also going to be focusing on
um
moving this data around so how do we
move all this metadata around especially
the complex supply chain so it's got to
go from you know an rtos vendor to a
medical device manufacturer to a
reseller to
the hospital
and then the last piece uh is going to
be continuing some work that started
ntia
uh which we call the awareness and
adoption group uh which was very ably
run by audient josh uh
and that is to sort of help think about
one how do we make it easier and cheaper
for organizations to uh engage in s-bomb
and also how do we coordinate all the
different things that are happening
around the world so right now there's
some work that's happening at the
international medical device regulatory
forum one of chris's favorite
organizations
uh there is there's great work happening
in all sorts of different corners of the
ecosystem we want to make sure that
there's a common hub to share
information
absolutely and when we started off i
mean really the only person i'd ever
heard talk about software billion tills
before allen was josh and josh started
this and he was sort of out there alone
and we all went okay i don't know what
that means and kind of ignored all that
but in these working groups he really
set the pace with crawl walk run uh and
how we implement that and we have been
crawling for the last four years
literally the we spent a number of weeks
deciding how to spell s bomb i'm not
kidding okay
is it a lowercase or a you know
uppercaseout all right there were things
like that and we started at that level
and now we have all these tools and
techniques of how to apply this more
importantly we've got an executive order
that came in that now makes it not just
little medical that's involved because
they were the first ones into it but the
16 industries of that are critical to
the infrastructure united states so now
we have vendors and organizations that
are looking at this saying oh yeah i
need to supply you with an s bomb
we're moving from crawling we're into
walking what is run look like and how do
we get there that's what we're doing
we're moving forward this is both an
open source
problem and a proprietary you've got
tools from both sides
and that's where we are right now we're
right now and walking and trying to head
toward that running
so um
i keep talking about medical because
that's what i do is make medical
equipment but there's a lot of other
industries that are right behind us in
some cases they might be ahead of us i
mean automotive comes to mind they're
very much into this and certainly it's
not just the united states it's across
the entire world countries like japan
and stuff are very interested in this
and what are you guys seeing are you
getting other interesting you know
comments from other industries or i'm
going to put it to all three of you
or even from other hospitals besides new
york press and what does this look like
is there interested in adopting this and
getting ahead of this ball
uh i do think something that's
interesting in the hospital field is
we've seen some hospitals start by like
when they negotiate new contracts with
different vendors saying okay well when
you provide us with a medical device we
need you to provide us an s-bomb as well
otherwise we won't
sign this
so that's one way that people are really
pushing s-bomb in healthcare
money works money always works don't
count on somebody's better nature if
it's in their financial interest you'll
have an s bomb the next day
and then i think something interesting
that's come from daggerboard is so we
publish daggerboard it's open source and
it's on github and we're seeing people
that are wanting to contribute they're
kind of interested and recently we were
asked okay so how can the results from
daggerboard integrate with an asset
management system and that's something
that we'll talk more on later but it's
kind of an interesting idea that's
really pushing us bomb further
so the tools that have come out of this
like daggerboard and we're seeing them
break up to it as we first got into this
in ntia early on we realized we had to
do authoring tools because it's a
chicken and egg problem
and we've got to start somewhere all
right nobody was asking for this but
then nobody could create one even if
they were asking for it nobody could
consume one nobody could distribute one
so we're starting to see these tools now
come out for the the two major formats
spdx and cyclone dx that are used for uh
software build materials and the tools
are there we're starting to see more
these pieces of the chain over its life
cycle fall into play and and tools like
daggerboard are definitely it and uh i
think that's good that we're seeing both
commercial ones i hope they hang in
there long enough to see success as well
as open source ones like daggerboard and
uh at this point we've been talking
about daggerboard and why all this but
uh adam and katie
history of daggerboard where did this
come from i when i think of open source
my first thought is not a hospital uh so
how did this how did this come about
as the fact that you guys created one of
the better tools out there yeah i think
that we feel really lucky to be on a
hospital information security team and
have the opportunity to make this tool
actually it was a lot of fun but
basically where we started was so arcizo
he's a member of the healthcare working
group proof of concept for s-bomb and
based on some of the meetings that they
had he came out with this idea that was
hey
uh we have the resources i think we want
to make this tool that makes it easy to
take an s-bomb and analyze it find all
the vulnerabilities associated with it
and report it so that the user really
doesn't have to do that much because
there wasn't anything out there that was
like super freely available at the time
so
that's where the whole idea came from
was let's make this easy to use and free
and here we are now we actually managed
to make this app open source it and it's
free
something that was kind of interesting
along the way was it's just like any
other sort of open source project where
we started really small we had
the ability to do one thing like a
script that analyzed s-bombs and now we
have this project that's just grown a
ton it can do a bunch of things um we'll
see in a minute in a little bit like
we're going to add more features have a
version too uh and because it's open
source we are always looking for people
that want to contribute and work with us
yeah and it started out as a beta
project originally by the vulnerability
team
and we linked up as the devops team just
to make it revamp the ui make it easier
for the analysts to use as a whole see
all your vulnerabilities in one place
all the packages in one place as well as
making open source which was really one
of the main goals for getting this app
uh
out there
some of you folks i may have undersold
what an s-bomb is you're thinking hey
i've used three pieces of libraries and
frameworks and operating systems in my
product in my device that i've created
why do i need tools like daggerboard
and the answer is transitive
dependencies
are you all aware of log4j and what
happened last december okay yeah i'm
getting a lot of head now it's good okay
log4j is a very commonly used java
library for implementing logging so
you're sitting there at your day job and
one of the requirements says oh my
application has to have logging first
thought that comes to your mind is log4j
it's used by everybody in fact some 80
000 projects have used log4j
so you reach out you include it
when you include log4j you go hey that
would be one of my elements in my
software bill of materials and indeed it
would
but there are 294
sub dependencies in log4j that you as a
developer have no clue you just brought
into your product
and with
intentional corruption of these public
libraries skyrocketing last year it was
650 percent the year before that was 400
and some percent i don't know what it's
going to be this year we just heard
today about pi pi there were 10
libraries commonly used libraries in pi
pi that have been intentionally
corrupted to harvest credentials
people are poisoning these repositories
so if you have 294 of those
sub-dependencies you can't do that
manually
that's why you need tools like
daggerboard and other tools to go there
and look at this and tell you what it is
on a daily basis to come up and say oh
this one's buried 17 levels deep and we
found it here and it's we now have a
known vulnerability that's in this
product
so it is the only way it's where
everything in cyber security is headed
you've got to automate it all of this is
becoming way too complex way too big for
any person or group of people to do with
a manual process so tools like
daggerboard accent and with that let me
stand out of the way and why don't you
do a demo of daggerboard
i'll sit up here with ellen wow thank
you thanks for keeping me company but
yeah by the way uh we're originally
under direct i was like where's your
jacket i don't understand we had a whole
plan
didn't happen
all right so let's go over
you know
what's important when we built this
application so s bombs we need them all
in one place but we need to start at the
design level so and i don't want to bore
you guys with the technical stuff but
i'm going to go over pretty much how
simple it was just to start the project
and what features it had so first and
foremost like we use the django
framework just to start the application
to build the as a web application django
is very friendly with it's very data
driven very friendly with using data and
you know using sbom data it worked in
our favor
so and mainly
the main tool is to scan and parse the
s-bombs and being able to scan based on
spdx or cyclone dx
another thing was to be able to
integrate it within any application and
that's where we had ldap and local
authentication so you could implement in
your your own and we have fancy charts
and graphs all over the place so any
analyst could look at all the all the
graphs that are needed there and most
importantly the open source that we made
it for open source purposes
so our app doesn't generate s-bombs and
we want to be clear with that um
s-bombs should be provided by the
manufacturer uh but if an s-bomb needs
to be created from a manufacturer so if
you're from a manufacturer um it's very
easy to build and that we for for us
whenever we need to build one we use
sift which is a great tool and it's
really easy it's just a one-liner um
just you could connect it to your docker
image or your requirements and produce
all the s-bomb in any format in cyclone
dx or spdx
any format that's required
so for daggerboard what are the
important tags in this case for this
this is an example of an spdx document
and
the document name we use the document
name the
creator the organization the package
name and the package version those are
the four main tags that we use for all
the analysis that we perform uh within
the application yeah so
in a minute we'll show like an actual
demo of daggerboard all the data you see
in daggerboard it's just coming from
these tags mostly in an s-bomb file
yeah and this is just a quick example of
how easy it is to upload an s-bom within
our tool
pretty much you go to the upload
choose the spd-x or cyclone dx document
submit it
and you are prompted and the analysis
begins it's all automated that way you
don't have to go through an xml document
and pick it out yourself so we we do all
that for you yeah and again so this is
like not really a live demo um we don't
have internet right now but that's why
we're showing a pre-recorded s-bomb
upload yeah we're really worried about
the demo gods um we don't know if our
internet will work or not so we
pre-recorded that and have a local
instance for you guys
so what's down the line what's on the
road map um do you want to go over so
before we get into the full-on demo um
these are just our next steps for
daggerboard so the the next thing that
we want to integrate is vect support
this will give us the ability to reduce
false positives we have in our data
maybe for a given product it'll we can
more reliably say these different s
bombs contribute um
so we should mention what vex is
first off vex was a term that came out
of the working groups was a term that
came out of the working groups
that absolutely everybody in the working
group hated and still hate we hate this
term it's a horrible term but what it
stands for is vulnerability
exploitability exchange
and the way to think about it is it's
extra information that is encoded in an
s-bomb
and it's from the developer of the
product to say a couple of things i'm
investigating this
vulnerability
i've decided this product is not
affected by this vulnerability or it is
affected by this vulnerability and
there's some couple sub states under
there that lead with things like how
it's configured so if you can figure it
one way oh you plugged in ethernet into
the rj45 jack yes you're vulnerable uh
there's things like that that it's done
in there
very useful because there's estimates
from 70 to 90 percent of unknown
vulnerabilities can't be exploited as
instanced in a product
so vexes allow you to give you more
clarity into it but it also gets back to
a level of trust
so for me if i there's a company i think
is good uh phillips phillips medical
okay and i know they do good stuff i'm
gonna trust their vex
but if it's acme medical i almost said
it really almost set a real company
there so
and i don't have that trust in them
i'm not going to care what the vex says
i'm going to unplug that device until i
know what it really is so this starts to
bring trust into the whole process and
that's nothing we can encode in xml or
json that's only something that can be
had over years of experience with the
developers who are doing this so vexes
are extremely useful
it is a very much in a crawl form
as we get into walk and run in the years
ahead it'll be extremely productive and
makes s-bombs even more valuable
sorry for jumping in kit no no that was
really good
so the next feature that we want to add
to daggerboard is an api
right now
you can upload an sbom and get results
vulnerability results but
what we need is the ability to have
another system pull this data and say
hey what's available and this can get us
to our goal of integrating with asset
management systems um maybe ci cd
pipelines those are just a few examples
we had in mind
so
our third uh
pro or item on our roadmap map is to add
the ability to search for cves
like chris had said earlier we all know
about the log for j vulnerability from
last winter
right now within daggerboard you can
find an s-bomb like based on the
product's name and like based on what
the s-bomb is but we can't globally
search through all of our s-bombs that
have been uploaded
by for cves for packages so that's
something that we think would be really
helpful for the vulnerability analysis
perspective
and then finally
the biggest thing
a part of daggerboard was to get it open
source get it put on github it currently
is on github we have our link up here we
encourage you to take a look at it give
it a try and if you want to contribute
or discuss anything we're always open
and so this brings us to our demo
all right so let's kick off the
well let's get the beautiful login page
that we we built here um so we need the
icon of the so you're probably wondering
what is the dagger board
and it's basically used to keep the ship
afloat so and to keep your company
afloat
you know you need to scan and analyze
s-bombs you don't want any holes in your
ship
so that's what the representation of a
dagger board is
um so this is our login page let's log
in
and from we need to know from the
perspective of an analyst what they want
to look at so the two major uh things
here are what are the most recent
s-bombs that were uploaded in this case
you know and all the data here is not
real this is all demo data from very
old so there's no scrutiny on apache or
anything else that you see here just as
a disclaimer for you guys um
so yeah we have the last two um s1's
that were uploaded and the overall
uh grade for that s bomb we calculate
the grade um based on the vulnerability
risk that's within um
that we we pull from nvd national
vulnerability database
and along with their severities high low
medium high
in the middle section we have our
highlights you can see how many total
vulnerabilities were found within the
application
how many weekly the average vendor grade
amongst all the all the s bombs that
were uploaded and at the bottom we have
a little um
we have a of all the we have a table of
all the s bombs that were uploaded
so moving on and we actually displayed
this page during the the recorded demo
this is where you would upload an s-bomb
this takes us to our s-bom analysis page
so what we can do is we can search for
the s-bombs we've uploaded to go ahead
and take a look and again like adam said
we intentionally grabbed really old
docker containers to show pretty charts
and show a lot of vulnerabilities
elasticsearch probably is not
an s at this point this is very old um
but so once we've uploaded an s-bomb
let's look at our results we can see
here's the product uh we have a grade
here we have the total vulnerabilities
that were found an average cvss score
and then we've got a beautiful spider
chart based on the cvss vector and then
a total of the vulnerability severities
so scrolling to the bottom of the page
we can see the packages that were found
from the sbom file
and so we can see we were able to find a
cpe here and that's how we pull
vulnerability data at this point
now
this is the part that i really like
because i'm on the vulnerability
management team i can go through here
and
find more information about what
vulnerabilities are present
i could maybe search for something
that's high i can maybe search for
for a package and then most importantly
one way that you may go through
prioritizing your results is we want to
know if an exploit's available so we can
do that and we get an actual reference
to exploit db
we can sort by severity
and
then
finally if we want to we can export a
report of all the vulnerabilities that
were found
and view it beautiful csv
and then moving on so we have a vendor
analysis page and this is just a way to
group the s-bombs together based on the
creator tag so we have apache software
foundation here
same sort of sorting if we wanted to
view something else but
we can see here we have five total
s-bombs from apache
they've got low grades
total 80 vulnerabilities we can see a
table here that shows when we uploaded
these different s-bombs and then just
the general distribution of
vulnerabilities
we get a snapshot of whatever was most
recently uploaded so groovy was our last
s-bomb and then uh just an overview
these are the different s-bombs that we
had from apache
so now we'll move to the admin page
yeah so if you want to deploy this in
within your own environment or for your
own
organization uh you need to make it
easier for your admins to configure do
certain configurations so we gave it the
ability to for our back controls for
your users you don't want some people
you only want some readers to read the
data versus people who could upload the
data
we also have the ldap configuration so
you could sign in
easier for your org
you can manage your users we have a
database
we could basically create you can modify
the database if you have to and as well
as the grading you can modify the
grading policy so it's not just fixed so
based the criteria for
calculating grades is very subjective
um you might want to consider like if
there is
10 if there's
10 high vulnerabilities what does that
mean to your organization and you could
definitely configure that within the
environment
um
and and that's about it um that's the
admin portal and this is just one
example of what we've been moving
forward with on the s bomb initiative
and we've it's come a long way as like a
healthcare uh hospital and we're very
like proud of ourselves and you know
we're not really a tech giant we're a
hospital so we've come a long way with
buildings up and we're very happy with
it yeah and i guess it just shows as
part of the calvary track um that
organizations like hospitals if you have
the resources or you're willing to do
this you totally can do it yeah so yeah
please visit our github and please
contribute anyone and everyone's welcome
to contribute to healthcare as a whole
thank you
i i want to flag one really cool thing
about this build there are many really
cool things about this project but one
of them is
there are a lot of security tools that
just do one security mission but don't
think about how it fits into an
organization and i think the thing that
struck me from this demo is oh yeah you
we need admin tools we need to actually
understand who's going to do what this
organization figure how it fits into the
broader mission and so i think that's a
really cool feature
uh that as we start thinking about more
open source tools that we can build
instead of saying don't don't just do
the the small thing figure out how you
can integrate into the bigger picture
so i think that's an uh thank you
an interesting point too is that so when
we started on this the daggerboard idea
came from the healthcare aspirin proof
of concept uh and initially in our first
phase of daggerboard we decided okay
this is only gonna be for medical
devices let's keep it specific to
healthcare but then as we got to our
second version of the app we realized
okay no this applies to every industry
that works with s-bombs
other people are working on it too we
want daggerboards to be used by anyone
not just hospitals
yeah and just the admin configurations
alone i mean that was just that took a
while to build and you know to
understand how to map it and there's a
lot of configurations that we did but to
come at the end of this like it's
basically this is just a starting point
for this application um we're really
looking to build this uh further and we
definitely have a road map ahead for a
little bit
one of the things i took away from that
presentation that's really important is
it gives you the quality idea of your
vendors
the people you're buying from so maybe
you've got uh you know that pdf viewer
you put in your program from a large pdf
vendor who will remain unnamed but you
all know that name starts with an a uh
and you go you know these folks never
give us patches they have nothing but
vulnerabilities and all this the next
time i'm going to create the next
product maybe i'm going to go over and
try some other competitors product and
put that in there and so you're looking
at this and you're doing continual
improvement upon your product
based upon not just availability and
cost and form fit and function but also
cyber security how good of a program did
they have are they working with me are
they a partner or are they part of the
problem so i think a tool like that is
really useful to know
remember we're all in this we're there
isn't anybody who's outside of this
we're somewhere in the supply chain that
either we're sourcing it originally or
we're building on top of it but i do
have one question for katie and adam do
you have an s bomb for daggerboard
yes we absolutely do of course yeah
[Music]
it's published on that repo forever it's
on github yeah and that's where it
should be
and that brings up an interesting topic
which is some of the people you're now
seeing complain about the fact that oh
well if we give you our s-bomb we have
to
hide it behind a firewall credentials
and the fact that you can't just get
access to it the proper place for s-bomb
is publicly available in this case in
the repo all right if you sit there and
think that your intellectual property is
going to be exposed by the third party
software components that you use then
it's not your intellectual property it
belongs to the people who created the
software components okay
so so
go ahead i want to show you the first i
i agree that is the the awful place to
do it um many of you know sunil yu an
early leader in thinking about s-bomb
and transparency uh he moved over to a
company called uh jupiter one one of the
first things he did was saying we want a
public s bomb and so jupiter one.com s
bomb is their live s bond right it's a
cloud-based product which means
there are very frequent builds uh but so
you get the live build
but i also want to zoom out a little bit
and talk about some of the cavalry
mission
which is
it is our job to hold people's hands
and walk them down the path for better
security we can't just say
right do security now and we'll beat you
right nerd harder
we haven't seen who says that doesn't
work we haven't tried that approach
but i think one of the there are
companies that just have very natural
aversions
to sharing
anything right there there's no okay
part of it is there's massive amounts of
tech debt so they don't want to show
that they have been shipping old stuff
uh and part of it is just culture right
so my lawyer says i shouldn't do this
and i don't know or care enough i
haven't talked to my customers enough
customers enough to push back
so
one of the things that we've done is
sort of try to push back on why it has
to be secret uh there's a great myth
busting document on the nti website that
sort of pushes back against that but the
other thing we can do is to say
you don't want to make it public it's
okay
why don't you try to figure out
what access control at scale looks like
for your thousands of customers
and and yeah just you just need to make
sure that all your customers have access
to it uh in a timely fashion and it can
integrate into all of your customers
security tools and by the time you sort
of they start to think about how complex
it's going to be to engineer
a way to share it safely
they'll realize this is just a lot
easier to share directly
so there are ways that we can use some
jiu-jitsu to get people
uh to be more comfortable sharing
at the end of the day you're moving
around xml and json files this isn't
exactly rocket science
uh there's lots of ways to do this there
i mean obviously you could email them it
doesn't scale okay nobody wants to see
that you could put it on your website
probably doesn't scale either it's a
good first step you could actually set
up your own servers and have those
servers they're nothing but repos for
s-bombs that's now getting into the
place where you want to be there's
commercial activities like uh archivist
is one of them which one of my open
seats whatever c3 whatever some of them
that do distribution
um there's even a a wasp project to
establish a open api
so all of these repos will have the same
api restful api so you can just reach
out and automatically with programs like
daggerboard once you indicate i have i
want to fetch this one it constantly
fetches and updates it and brings it in
and uh so it's it is definitely moving
into that walk run area where this can
start to be really really useful so
we talked about where we've been we
talked about where we are what's next
where are we going with s-bombs what do
you guys want to see what do you think
we're going to do alan what is sisa
going to do with s-bombs now that we're
here uh
well what so as i mentioned the current
status is where we're all able to sort
of start moving this direction
the longer term vision is really
integration and automation and that sort
of means hey we've got to have
interoperability those are fun
challenges uh they're engineering
challenges they're also business
challenges uh policy challenges uh and
and also massive opportunities so you
know i i love that dagger board and
hopefully you'll talk a little more
about how you're gonna integrate this as
an asset management because that's where
we need to be going
um i've talked about briefly these four
work streams that cease is going to be
mentioning uh the i'm going to start
repeating an email address if you'd like
to be involved and you're not on my
mailing lists
sbam
sissa.dhs.gov what was that allen s-bomb
at cisa.dhs.gov
uh just send me a note we'll we'll sign
you up for these work streams uh and
then of course the other fun thing is
let's start building things
and that's kind of uh where we're
winding down here at this point but i do
want to point out that what we need is
more open sourcing we need more
community involvement
uh we this is a call to arms all of you
need to get involved producing creating
tools
making s-bombs making them available
this is a big project it's certainly not
what i thought the first day alan
started this okay it is a giant tidal
wave that we all need to get behind and
help what do we do for the cyber poor
who are out there how do we get them in
a good place okay they need help
there is a hospital that's in ohio
well as a medical device manufacturer we
always refer to hdos health delivery
organizations like it's this monolithic
thing they're all the same
like they're all mayo clinic or new york
presbyterian or or an organization
that's large and doing things correctly
they're not they're a spectrum so they
go from that far extreme to this
hospital in ohio where the same guy who
mows their lawn sets up their network
i'm not kidding this is the case and
everything in between how do we help
those people all of them they all matter
especially those little guys they don't
have the resources the knowledge the
funding to do this
it's all incumbent upon us to put these
tools out there get the information in
front of them lower the bar so they can
adopt this stuff
think about this it's your
responsibility
these gentlemen started the ball rolling
the rest of us are just rolling along
with them and i'm including all of you
in that as well too
last words alan uber last i'm going to
start with you first
s bomb sissa.dhs.gov
uh i don't have anything to promote
besides check out our github but um just
to touch on what chris said yeah i
actually used to work for a hospital in
kansas and we would buy a lot of those
small hospitals from rural kansas that
were tiny and
the first things that would happen after
you bought these hospitals was they got
hit with ransomware man what do we do
now because no one can do anything and
so
um they didn't really have much i.t
there and this is where s-bomb really
helps us let's let's get s-bomb out
there let's find out what's in these
environments let's help these smaller
hospitals figure this
out adam yeah
uh i i guess just contribute um
contribute uh right now you know we have
our day jobs and now that we've deployed
something on on github as open source we
have outsiders telling us to hey can you
fix this can you fix that but we have
our day jobs we also need to you know
work for the you know at new york
presbyterian um so please help us out
this is matters this is important we
don't have any other way to do this when
you look at those black boxes you don't
know what's in them nobody does
even the experts like myself i'd have to
tear it apart and spend weeks on that
one version to find out what's really in
there a lot of work a lot of effort we
need to lower the bar on this we have a
huge installed base of really crappy
products out there
in the medical device industry we
specialize in that we've got hospitals
that have 30 year old components in it
all right
30 year old components how secure do you
think those really are
they're not
we're looking at all of you think about
this this matters this could save lives
this will save lives as we go forward so
whatever industry you're in make certain
you're looking at this ask your vendors
for s-bombs whatever you're writing even
if it's a diary app that you're going to
release you know out to the app store
ask your vendors that you're using
where's your s-bomb ask this keep that
ball rolling keep it going i want to
thank all of you for the gift of your
time here today to listen to us
and we hope to see you in our meetings
so obviously this is super valuable
especially for the target rich cyber
poor we discussed yesterday they may not
be able to buy new things or hire new
people but they can at least know what
they're getting in these
obsolete or older technologies and know
am i affected where am i affected when
the next log which they happen the bad
news on some of these hospitals is now
seven eight months later
some of them still don't have a
commitment
on what's in the software when are they
getting a patch so we're on a journey
we're crawl walk running but this wasn't
merely about s-bomb and the great work
here i just want to
look at these two developers
and the attitudes we keep hearing from
thought leaders in cyber security that s
bomb's too hard no one can do it no one
can make use of it they say screw it
let's just build something
and part of this was a meta hint that i
wonder if part of the next phase of the
cavalry is we start teaming up with
software developers open source
contributors and that this is just one
of maybe dozens of projects that could
help waste water treatment could help
oil and gas could help the target rich
cyber poor and the food supply
and i kind of like their attitudes i
kind of like the contribution and i kind
of like the idea that instead of just
just pointing out problems we might be
able to create the tool chains that the
private center is not yet willing to do
this is a hint and a nudge
not just to take s-bombs and maybe put
the known exploited vulnerabilities list
in it so they can target more
specifically
but also what tools could you ask for
build or contribute to and advocate for
so this is a hint maybe for the future
of the cavalry
we're going to be outside if you want to
talk with us after this presentation if
you've got any other questions
right now if you don't want a voice in
public right now it's a q a period
questions
we don't have any portable mics
i haven't i haven't been on the
discussion list so
have you been thinking about and i'm
already well familiar with s problems
josh may not recognize me but he'll know
me in a minute
um
have you thought about when you're
talking about cloud transparency other
aspects that aren't just software
components
like
does the software do sso integration you
know does it support saml does it
support oauth whatever
do you do things like validating email
addresses before subscribing people all
that kind of behavioral stuff that's
another level
of operational information
separate from what are the software
components you use
and i think it kind of like you said
about tying it into
configuration management asset
management tying it into information
security policies at the organization
that's building the software
as a cso type role i get asked by people
about the practices in our organization
and everybody sends me a one-off
questionnaire with 150 questions there's
no standard for
and i'd love to have a standard form
that's s-bomb-like to give them
to say
here's the change management control
practices we follow here's the software
development lifecycle practices we
follow et cetera et cetera
so when you're buying this product from
us this is what you're getting
you want to chime in on the
questionnaire
they touched on one of my subjects okay
this year the health sector coordinating
council released the model contract
language mc squared 45 terms for
hospitals to use in contracting with
medical device suppliers
and it talks all about the different
cyber security expectations the most
dysfunctional relationship ever is
hospitals to medical device
manufacturers always has been i've been
doing this 50 years it's been horrible
i'm trying to make it better i know a
lot of other people are too
it's kind of our goal we're starting
with cyber security
but this goes into a lot of different
places so how do you do this so when you
get those questionnaires
mds squared of course obviously you're
going to be filling that out obviously
but the custom ones we're trying to
minimize
if we can get them to align to things
like this mc squared that will be a much
quicker way to answer much less burden
on the manufacturer in a much better
position we'll all be in
so on the idea of enhancing small i
haven't seen a lot of discussion around
specific security features although
measurement of security features is one
of my key passions which is how do i
sort of quickly and cheaply determine
security features
where we are seeing a lot of attention
especially from the cloud native world
is saying in addition to my dependencies
let me document my broader security
process so let me have um right secure
robust attestations of what compiler i
used what my build chain was where i
actually got the source from uh and
having each of those artifacts signed
along the way
the challenge is how do i meet how do we
put enough semantic value into that data
so that we can enforce it at policy
level otherwise it just turns into right
a paperwork exercise what we want to do
and there are organizations including
solarwinds today which is sort of saying
here's the policy and we're not going to
let code go to uh go live until it's
checked all these boxes
and one thing that the two major formats
that we've influenced in ntia
are cyclone dx and spdx
they are both in motion
and generally if one does something good
the other one does something good and
copies it i'd
argue that you go out i'm not going to
tell you which one's better i have my
opinions let you find your own
but cyclone dx does have some of the
stuff you're talking about in separate
artifacts
hopefully spdx will answer that and
everybody will keep motion and we'll and
we'll have ways to uh rosetta stone all
that information together because that's
where we need to be i think we've just
got two minutes
i'll be quick i have a really basic kind
of s-bomb question i guess within policy
is there anything in the executive order
or anywhere else that kind of uh
mandates
uh the existence of s-bombs for
federally funded software or products or
that sort of thing that exists right now
where that's gonna be coming down the
line legacy thank you yeah or well we're
going forward either way so the
executive order 14028 from 2021 uh
mandates that everything the us
government buys will ultimately have to
have an s bomb that's going the
mechanism is first it's going to be a
memo from omb that's going to come out
soon uh and ultimately is going to be
part of the federal acquisition rules uh
there's also some language in the draft
ndaa
uh the national defense authorization
act uh that is going to apply to a
couple different parts including a dod
land happy to chat more about this and
one last thing in medical device right
now in senate is it's already out of the
house is the patch act
i see somebody who knows this okay good
uh what they added a writer on there
that says not only is all the cyber
security work needs to be done for
release of the product and that includes
s-bomb but also all the existing legacy
product out in the field
one more question
can we do one more question one more
question since we're taking up lunch
great thanks
um is it a reasonable step for medical
device manufacturers to just put that in
the mds2s like the s-bom details kind of
as a as a baby step to having more of a
live stream there are questions in the
mds2 about if you have an sbom and all
that it's not a great place to do it uh
it's not in a format that's easily
machine readable so let's say i've got
javascript is the basis of my device in
some way phone i may have two three four
ten thousand
references
doesn't really work in that you wanna
stick to one of the markup languages
json or xml that can be easily sourced
consumed we're out of the days of
emailing and texting each other to each
other if i have to open up excel to pull
something out of it ain't gonna happen
right not gonna be scalable so
flag that you've got one
even point to the url where it can be
fetched but
now
um
you want to come up we're going to be on
the balcony the balcony overlooking the
pool overlooking the uh fire pits uh to
have a little meet up and i've got
stickers
who doesn't love stickers