so on the same day October 1st
um of
2021 we uh the Wall Street Journal
published uh the the loss of that baby
in Alabama
um but we knew that we dismissed as
anecdotes or random or just one uh we
also on that same day published um the
first statistical proof of loss of life
that um cyber attacks can degrade a
hospital and a region sufficient to
drive access deaths both for time
sensitive conditions like heart brain
and stroke
uh and Pulmonary but also through some
excess death analysis our data science
team did and then number uh three on the
panel is uh Lisa young systemic and risk
management and cyber physical citizens
person from the team
so that's going to be session two is
some of the things we saw where bits and
bytes were meeting like uh you know
flesh and blood on a daily basis
um I think several of us have PTSD from
that but um these are some of the
superheroes from different backgrounds
than hacking that brought their skills
to Bear along with Beau and others
um and Spanky and many others that had a
very different pandemic experience than
many of you
uh next up will be um rivers on fire and
David Batts is going to walk through
since many of you didn't even see all
these but we had existence proofs of the
attacks on water on food supply on oil
and gas pipelines on municipalities and
we have a a tour de force through some
of those existence proofs and possibly
how parts of government are are and are
not reacting appropriately so that'll
simmer you in maybe things you knew half
of but you'll know more of
uh followed by um one common thread
through most of these victims is they
are Target Rich cyber poor we just took
a riff on winning ether's poverty line
but in a much more applied and
operational way and one of the
uncomfortable truths here is even though
the government sponsors ice ax and uh or
information sharing analysis centers for
all 16 critical infrastructure sectors
and even though they sponsor sector
coordinating councils of leadership from
the public private partnership and even
though there's lots of free information
sharing and free indicators of
compromise and free resources from sisa
and the different agencies responsible
for those 16 like Health Care is HHS or
the healthcare industry
most of the participants in there are
the Cyber rich they're the haves not the
have-nots most of the attacks and the
victims or the have-nots they're below
that poverty line so if the private
sector sees no money in helping the
Cyber poorer and the public sector says
let's partner with the private sector we
have a very circular problem so I have a
deep passion and burden on my heart
for fit for purpose
help to the Target Rich cyberport owners
and operators of critical infrastructure
we cannot say just do best practices
just do zero trust just do this just do
that they don't have a single cyber
security person on staff we have to meet
them where they are identify and buy
down risk and we do that every single
day uh and this is Task Force with what
we had available I'm hoping maybe part
of our next phase of our mission is
crowdsourcing and creating tools that
actually help people because the private
sector won't
my framing for that is if you think of a
pyramid with a Fortune 100 and 500 up
top and then there's everybody else down
below
ransomware gave the adversaries the
attacker as a way to monetize the
cyberpore
Defenders have not figured out how to
monetize the cyberpore
so it's a Feeding Frenzy
attackers can monetize the poor
Defenders have not figured it out so
they are
prone they were always prey they were
always prone and now Predators have
taken notice so we have a Feeding Frenzy
for the foreseeable future and when you
press my former agency and their
teammates in government they say well we
partner with the private sector
um and that's a sincere answer but it's
not a helpful one so there are some
existence proofs that some of my
assistant teammates are going to talk
about where we did things for the
cyberpore like get your stuff off search
or was I like to call it get your
off showdan
um free skinning Services uh we coined
this thing system.gov bad practices
you're going to hear about so not just
best practices or what are the most
dangerous things that we encounter and
how can those become the negligent
standard or eradicated strategically and
while they are common practices that are
also dangerous
so that's going to be maybe a nudge and
inspiration for tomorrow uh Jen Ellis
has assembled uh some Guppies as well a
lot of progress has been made over the
last two years so we're gonna have a
policy update with our friend Leonard
Bailey from doj on strides to further
decriminalize good faith security
research which is one of our day one
goals so that's amazing
and uh we have a hacker as a senate
staffer uh and a pretty important Senate
uh position who's going to talk about
some of the other things that have
happened and things that are coming
because a huge chunk of what we do is
not fixing a single flaw on a single
device from a single manufacturer but
maybe changing the rules to make more
defensible maintainable reliable digital
infrastructure
and then we'll have the feedback loop
from you so that was a lot of stuff for
day one uh you're gonna hear much more
detail from our assembled team
um but this is to simmer you in the
discomfort that shits on fire
most of them are the target rich in
cyberpore they're not ample Solutions or
engagement models and in some of those
sectors like food there's not even a
nice Act
so uh just like I said the Cavalry isn't
coming nine years ago I meant it for
different certain specific details but
for now there's a lot to do and there's
no one stepping up to do it so we can
either get them to the starting line
with us or we can fill a void
temporarily but um there is much that
has been accomplished that we should be
very very proud of
and there is much much more to do
which will pivot us into tomorrow and in
case I don't have an opening session
I'll do a much faster version tomorrow
uh press coverage has been one form for
cyber security for a very long time so
we've asked Lily hey Newman from wired
to help us assemble some press to say
how should press change if shit's on
fire now we always say well until bad
things happen you know this is
theoretical well they're happening and I
want to ensure that we don't always have
a private or commercial voice giving you
know corporate talking points when
there's people dying or that whenever I
say hey there were losses of life in
this particular ransomware in a hospital
we don't have someone say yeah but what
about the patient record count and the
fines like we want to make sure that
we're focused on the right things and
this will be a conversation tomorrow
about how can we best make ourselves
available to the press and how do we
ensure that coverage
of consequence
um
makes deliberate conscious Choice
changes and there are some obstacles
that are unobvious that Lily and I were
discussing a couple days ago it's going
to be tough right press works a certain
way we work a certain way we're gonna
have to work a different way if we want
to make differentiate corporate security
from cyber physical safety uh and Public
Safety
uh followed by s-bomb s bomb is a double
talk uh spam software bill of materials
um this is one of those uh
day one Cavalry ideas it's across the
chasm and is in an executive order it's
happening uh it's inevitable uh it is
not easy there's some opposition but
s-bomb is a dual dual talk tomorrow it's
really both showing how things like
software build materials software
transparency software trustworthiness
could be part of the answer for starter
it's cyberpor maybe they can't invest in
security but they can get more
of a head start and a leg up on some of
these things but also um one of the
coolest things in the espa movement was
an open source project called
daggerboard that was a hospital said hey
no one's building anything for us we're
going to build it ourselves and they
open sourced it so it's not a solution
for all things s-bomb but how do people
consume and operate and Avail themselves
of things like s-bombs from plural
places and plural levels quality next
time there's a log for Jay and there are
still hospitals calling me even last
week saying it's been eight months Josh
I still don't have an impact analysis
from my vendors eight months later we
still don't know where log4j is for some
of the medical devices no no promise of
patching so that's part of why we want
to talk about s-bomb and I think it's in
decent
universe and a grain of sand that may
Inspire why we need more developers in
the Cavalry ranks why we need to build
more tools that can meet a wastewater
treatment facility where they are solve
their problems for their most egregious
exposures
while we're waiting for the Cavalry to
come from either coin operated private
sector and or
um
the government figuring out who swim
Lanes or which swim lanes and how to
help so that's going to be um both
informational for s-bomb but also
hopefully inspirational for the kind of
things we might want to do in the next
phase of the cavalry
um trying to do this for memory uh we
have an ICS talk
um on how to talk to uh
stakeholders about ICS and OT security
issues and I might have this in the
slightly wrong order and then we also
have a basically what I've been calling
acting black act Global act local act
Global uh talk which is there's been
some state level experiments and Ray
from Michigan is going to talk about one
of the state level experiments in the
state of Michigan for hackers working at
the local state level there's been a lot
of efforts from Beau from others the
national government Association in the
past but this is more tailored fit for
purpose at each state or municipality
level and then we have some people from
the Cyber peace Institute that are
talking about how that is a part of an
overall Patchwork of parallel
experimentation internationally and
there have been some national and Global
movements like the Cyber threat
intelligence leagues CTI League that
helped operationally with these Hospital
attacks early in the pandemic and
continues to so there are new parallel
efforts Cavalry in shape uh or in spirit
and this is potentially one of the areas
where we're going to have to go hire
internationally bowled a really
incredible uh initiative with the world
economic forum
that is one of those global examples of
maybe minimum pledges for how iot should
not have hard-coded passwords for
example uh or be patchable
things that you might have heard from
this group for a while
so um this could be part of our future
is scaling up and down and laterally and
seeing what you can do to help your
local municipalities for your food your
hospitals your state governments
and then uh I think I'm doing I didn't
miss any but we're also going to do a
very large chunk of workshopping to hear
from you as to what you think we can and
should do and commit to do and how we
can get some scale and uh Jen and others
reminded me that um while Beau and I and
some of the other long-standing
Advocates and public speakers and
ambassadors do the best we can we really
need logistical and organizational back
office support we need project
management we need to get better at
being historians capturing the truth
maybe having records of what happened
when in what order by whom
um so there's a lot more roles to be
filled that would give us more scale
more staying power and more parallel
action and clouds I don't see clouds in
the room it closes been the volunteer
coordinator in Wrangler for much longer
than any single person should have to so
we're really looking for more uh Welcome
Wagon and onboarding that can whenever
someone says hey I would like to help
how do I get started so there's a lot of
volunteer roles to be filled and maybe
we can identify some of those in our
two-day two-hour session tomorrow
I just gave you an avalanche of
logistics as opposed to inspiration how
much time do I have left
where's my Proctor huh
how many
okay
all right any questions on that
Avalanche
the overall theme and feeling we want
you to have is nine years ago we said
stuff was flammable and we wanted to be
left a boom to prevent harm and maintain
trust we've done some incredible things
and I hope for a few minutes now to
share some of the highlights in the last
nine years
um while I pull up some slides
but uh
now that things are on fire I do think
the mission needs to change
um I just don't know how you know we
could say mission accomplished I don't
really think that's apt uh we could
definitely get some new leadership and
new blood into the mix but I think it's
going to have to be
um
a reorganization of the focal points and
how we measure success all right
um
would you like to share a couple of your
favorite accomplishments over the last
nine years or compare and contrast
yeah sure so as as I was thinking about
um what we could talk about today
uh it occurred to me that like nine
years ago
uh as Josh said there was a lot of
kindling there's a lot of things that
could catch fire some of them we saw
catch fire and we paid the most
attention to those tended to to look at
those the most because they're in the
press or the hype cycle uh but that's
not all that's happened in these so for
every highly visible failure there is at
least one measurable uh piece of
progress in that area so if you think
back
um you know nine years ago I think that
was a year or two after uh we saw people
drive cars off the road uh through
hacking them
um the Auto industry said oh well that
only happened because you were sitting
in the seat next to the driver
uh that can't happen remotely and then
the next year they made it happen
remotely they said well yeah but that's
theoretical and it can't happen
um
this is where
uh when we came in we started talking to
some of those car makers started talking
to Nitsa the national highway traffic
safety administration
um some of those different organizations
pulling people together we published
something we called the the five-star
Automotive cyber safety framework
playing off the five-star crash rating
system uh and started talking about that
trying to get some adoption and
awareness and managed to actually I
think incept quite a few car makers
um who you know some of them hired
sizzos because they saw an increase in
talks at black hat but uh when they got
there what they got there they didn't
have a tool kit right you tend to apply
what you have and most of the toolkits
we have are for how do you operate an
environment you know how do you build
your corporate network not how do you
build a product and so what we put out
was actually really helpful for those
individuals to think through as well as
contribute to it and then go apply it in
their own organizations and so we've
actually seen within the car domain a
couple of things come out
for automotive cyber safety Nitsa
published one the automotive ISAC
published one and we've got a couple of
friends in the automotive ISAC the
person who ran the aviation ISAC for a
while went over to the auto ISAC and
she's very very friendly to hackers
um so we had some successes there and
the industry had some successes there uh
also if you go back and you look uh you
had people at black hat Defcon b-sides
talking about medical device security
issues and there was a lot of uh kind of
fear around medical device security
because there are people walking around
probably some even in the room today
um who have a higher quality of life or
who wouldn't be alive without a medical
device connected to them at all times
and at the time you know the industry
and the hackers were at odds with each
other
fortunately the FDA stepped in and said
look we don't know what's going on we're
not cyber security experts but there's
something here we need to figure it out
and we need to figure it out together
and help bring together the hackers the
manufacturers the doctors the patients
everybody else that we published
something else called Hippocratic Oath
for connected medical devices again
playing off of something that that most
people already associate with that
domain
um and I it's on the screen here I won't
read through it but the idea was that uh
just as doctors take a symbolic oath to
act in the best interest of their
patients when they're delivering care
the same should be true with devices
that deliver care now that they are the
primary way that doctors interact with
patients either directly or through
proxy
um and this had a lot of success uh the
FDA you know I won't go through all of
the successes in this because as Josh
said we've had a ton of success in
healthcare and medical but the FDA put
out something that they call pre-market
and post-market I won't get into all the
the wonky policy details of that of
those two docs but essentially if
something is going to go on to the
market and be sold in the U.S it has to
follow certain guidelines the FDA
reviews that once it's on the market if
there are issues that come up that could
impact Effectiveness or patient safety
the FDA wants some ability to have the
manufacturer address those and if you
put those two documents side by side and
align them with this Hippocratic Oath
for connected medical devices it's like
one for one almost everything that we
wrote about is now the law of the land
it's it's instantiated in this guidance
um
for medical device makers that this is
how the FDA is going to evaluate you so
it's not suggested it is effective if
you want to get on the market and stay
on the market you have to follow these
rules of the road
um tons of thank you
um
tons of medical device makers are out
there we have the biohacking village
device lab which uh if you haven't been
I highly recommend it a bunch of medical
device makers come in and bring devices
put it in front of hackers and say we
know you can hack this we just want to
know how so we can fix it that is 180
degrees from where we were nine years
ago there's been an amazing amount of
progress there if you look at the
household iot
so uh you know household iot is a bit of
an outlier there's not as much human
life Public Safety attached to that but
it is a huge issue and I remember
um
flying to Austin Texas uh one October
for an ntia event where Allen had
gathered a bunch of people to talk about
software updateability upgradeability in
iot
and there were a lot of people from
industry there some of whom were all
about it and others said ah it doesn't
matter it's not a big deal like if uh if
something doesn't work you know we'll
just disconnect it from the network
that'll be a fine that's a fine solution
um and I think I said something like uh
you know it's not the individual attacks
um against a single device that matter
it's leveraging all of those exposed
prone devices on the internet to cause
harm and what was it Alan like a week
later that the Mirai botnet hit
and you know people in the room are like
oh you're wrong it's not going to happen
no one would ever do that literally a
week later this happened and that caused
a whole lot of things to happen in
government I I sometimes say that
government lost its Collective
um because this was such a pronounced
impact
uh that they thought only a nation state
could have this kind of impact cause
this kind of harm on the internet well
it turns out it was some uh College
dropouts who were trying to knock a
competitor's Minecraft server off the
internet so this is like hobbyists
extremely low level of capability folks
who were able to have a huge outsize
impact and so there were many many
initiatives that started in the US
government as well as others
um that led to I think a lot of progress
uh in that area up to and including you
know some of it uh kind of snowballed
and people were saying well if this is
the impact that could happen to home iot
devices what about bigger systems
pipelines industrial control systems and
so you've seen in the past couple of
years a series of executive orders
Congressional actions and other things
looking at what we can do and it turns
out
um most of the government's action in
this area has been how do you operate
the equipment more safely
well I think a lot of us were saying and
have been saying the the hackers in the
in the world hear the Defcon black hat
and all the other b-sides around the
world is once you get a vulnerable
exposed uh thing on your network it's
already too late to do a lot of the
critical safety critical steps that can
only be done when you're designing
building it and implementing it so let's
move way left not just left of Boom but
left of by
and get to a place where we can
influence those standards so you've seen
a lot of things in executive orders uh
and in some other government requests
and right now they're trying to figure
out how they can get left to buy because
in some cases their authorities don't
let them
um so they're working on uh you know new
types of ways that they can actually
equip organizations rather than
hamstring them or allow them to be
hamstring hamstrung so that when they
buy something they can know what the
security posture of that thing is they
can put measures in place and they can
choose alternates
um if what they see in the market uh in
some segments of the market doesn't have
the security capabilities they need so
for all of the the Badness we still are
in there's been a lot of progress in our
day one thesis was can't be just us
doing it and it can't be any part of any
sector any industry any government doing
this it's got to be all of us working
together and so where we see some of
those successes I think it's our
responsibility to highlight them to
promote them to Dogpile on them to jump
in and and help lift those up to make
those road maps for success for other
Industries to build on them to extend
them and just to make sure that they
they get the effect that they need to
have
yeah there's so much to be proud of and
so many of the people in this room and
not in the room people streaming online
people at home that have done some
things so maybe to punctuate that
um a couple of the things as I reflected
on the flight here
um
there wasn't a lot of ice act when we
started you know we helped get that off
the ground the five star has become a
blueprint for how do you avoid failure
take help avoiding failure without suing
the help or capture study and learn from
failure respond to failure contain and
isolate failure
uh we affected the shape of the FDA
policy for the US and the planet we
caused the first safety communication
and recall with zero dead people first
and that was like the moment when we
really knew that we were on to something
we uh
extended our reach into other areas when
that Mirai botnet happened we wrote a
law hackers wrote a law
now obviously there were Partners in the
senate in the house and it took two
entire Congressional sessions but in
late 2020 that thing passed into law
it's a minimum hygiene standards for iot
purchasing uh he mentioned the executive
orders we knew that this isn't just
about responding to failure but this is
making more rugged defensible survivable
uh anti-fragile things and then we've
really tried to ensure that the Next
Generation regulatory is focused on
threat modeling and Patch ability and
maintainability and embrace of hackers
acting in good faith with coordinating
vulnerability disclosure programs which
is now required for all federal agencies
all federal agencies have to have a
coordinated vulnerable disclosure you're
gonna hear from Leonard they'd be
actually giving guidance to not
prosecute hackers acting in good faith
so we are increasingly making it easier
for us to keep people safe and then when
the planet was going through a once in a
hundred years
um
very dangerous very lethal event they
turn to several calorie people to both
design and Implement what the federal
and Global Response should look like
um so we got to put on
get conscripted to a certain extent and
put on go time
um and we could only do this because of
the collaboration and creativity of
every single one of you and we hacked
the government in in lawful ways and
hacked the planet I mean I don't think
they fully realize the impact the
long-term impact is some of the things
that we published like bad practices
this is going to this is already
changing insurance
we have just declared what bad looks
like what negligent looks like what
dangerous looks like and the student you
walk past as a sinner you endorse and
just in case uh you don't come for Don's
part the at least the two we got through
initially was the use of unsupported end
of life software in service of critical
infrastructure and National critical
functions is dangerous
and material elevates risks to Public
Safety economic and National Security
this dangerous practice is especially
egregious in Internet reachable
Technologies
we've now put a stake in the ground
could enable
Insurance exceptions wrongful death
lawsuits
FTC consent decrees
you name it regulatory action and then
number two is the use of hard-coded
default and guessable maintenance
password is is also dangerous so this is
a growing list of things and some of
those hacks will have long-standing
future implications but these were
powerless hackers at b-sides
being bold and trying to make sure that
we hold ourselves a better standard so
before I shift to the last 10 minutes of
Ramon's concert
um I'm going to say one of the lines we
got into the executive order
um
because I think this is me trying to
channel my inner Dan gear uh but now
that things are on fire
it's just a riff on what our day one
problem statement was I said that in the
end the trust we place in our digital
infrastructure should be proportional to
how trustworthy and transparent that
infrastructure is
into the consequences we will incur if
that trust is misplaced and I've always
looked at this group as we trust things
without them deserving the trust and we
want to you know narrow the gap between
overdependence on undependable things
and ensuring that our neighbors and our
loved ones can
enjoy the benefits of those connected
Technologies the promise without the
Peril and I've always said the failure
mode wasn't the specific losses of life
it's any crisis of confidence in the
public to trust these Superior
Technologies so we are in my opinion the
lighthouse Keepers to be that heat be
light be heat be good
to try to ensure that we're warning both
the promise and the Peril of these
choices in that order dependence and
we're in a very dangerous moment in
history
where we're
out of balance there and your actions to
date have put us on a better footing but
there's so much more to do for the next
couple years and I hope to answer the
question what should the Cavalry look
like with you today and tomorrow and
throughout the rest of the week and
through Defcon but Bose really taken
some of this Spirit into the Defcon
policy track Village whatever we want to
call it and just walk around the
Villages Maritime Village Aerospace
Village ICS Village a biohacking village
we have a large Auto hacking Village we
have a large and growing tribe of tribes
that are all learning from each other
and making each other better through
parallel experimentation so I can't wait
to see what you bring to this
all right harsh uh transition to the
last maybe 10 minutes I'm not going to
show you everything but I was spitting
fire in uh New York City two weeks
through two three weeks ago
I'm just going to show a few things
there from there
all right so Andrew matuition
um
had said
No One's Gonna listen to you it's not
gonna be like a cyber 911 or cyberpole
Harbor it's going to be like the
Cuyahoga River in Ohio right it caught
on fire and stayed on fire how do you
put out a river on fire you all heard
this from me if you've been in these
rooms before
um we have had fires folks we had
Oldsmar water facility the water we
drank has been on fire
fire the food we put on our table with
JBS and other meat and food supply chain
attacks fire
the oil and gas that fuels our cars and
our homes fire
the municipalities the schools the
people who function our local
governments and our federal governments
at the National Security level have seen
compromises and even
fire
timely access to Patient Care which
Kendra's session is going to go through
in extreme detail but we have had losses
of life
so with the precursors were when I
started that we served on a
congressional task force for healthcare
industry cyber security as part of this
is a 2015 law and in Spring of 2016 a
single Java flaw in a single uh it was a
deserialization plot a single JBoss
library in a single Medical Technology
took out Hollywood Presbyterian hospital
for a week
uh you had to divert ambulances in LA
traffic even a block in La is maybe not
a survivable reroute they actually
cancel surgeries move patients
throughout the week it was harrowing
later on when we were about to publish
or just had published the Mirai botnet
that we referred to we published our
Healthcare task force report saying uh
overtly Health Care cyber security is in
critical condition I'm reminding you of
this slide because Kendra may have a
slide that says provide medical care is
in critical condition the national level
but the idea here was these were the
Cyber poor they didn't have security
people on staff they were defending
Windows XP or older they were over
connected to each other flat unsegmented
networks and reachable by the outside
world this wasn't about privacy I love
my privacy I want to be alive to enjoy
it
and uh and yet everything was about
HIPAA uh and then lastly Billy Rios
pointed out a typical medical device
could have a thousand or more cves in it
and while most of those are not
exploitable it just takes one
and we said this is not good and we
talked about well there's no money and
we said we can't afford to protect it
you can't afford to connect it or my
Stan Lee friendlier version of great
connectivity comes great responsibility
and then our UK Partners had 40 of their
UK of their National Health Service
disrupted for Mother's Day weekend
within days of us trying to publish this
so the U.S got quite lucky but not
patchy actually did more damage to U.S
infrastructure including nuanced
software and a bunch of medical devices
and some hospitals shut down for time
and some kids in this book couldn't get
they were cleared for surgery so kids
had potentially delayed surgery because
of the entanglement and brittleness of
I.T systems little kids couldn't you
know get surgery without some heroism
from maybe somebody in this room
um and what we know is that delays cause
uh patient outcome harm so you've seen
this from me before but I'm reminding us
as a primer for Kendra's session here we
know from a seminal piece of New England
Journal medicine a study that has
nothing to do with cyber security that
if you have a heart attack during a U.S
marathon in a U.S Marathon City during a
marathon you're more likely to die
uh and the reason is the 4.4 minute
longer ambulance ride to get around the
runners
had a statistically significant
mortality rate after 30 days
so we know time equals mortality
for some of these immeasurable
quantifiable ways and I said okay so
this is from Christian demaff one of our
fantastic teammates and Jeff Tully board
certified Physicians that grew up going
to
uh Defcon quality and replicant and they
helped us understand that certain time
sensitive conditions um any delay
irrespective of cause can affect
mortality so if we know delay affects
mortality for brain for heart for
pulmonary on a certain graduated
timelines
if cyber security can introduce
significant delay cyber security can
introduce loss of life
so we started killing people at the
cybermed summit which is now its own
non-profit cybermed is doing a lot more
and formalized including the first DC
event recently uh where I think Senator
Warner gave our opening remarks
and we showed that you could introduce
real hacking in contrast with real
um physiology to see if doctors can
notice what happened save the lives and
through demonstrable real world hacks
like
insulin pumps like Jerry Radcliffe like
the bedside infusion pump from Billy
Rios like the hacking of pacemaker
defibrillators maybe with a three-digit
universal access code that maybe caused
a recall
um that these Physicians is well trained
as they are implicitly trusted this
technology and were gobsmacked we then
started doing more tabletop crisis
simulations to test their assumptions
um and saw different failures we hacked
the Integrity of blood banks in the or
so that you put the wrong blood type in
the surgical field and it coagulates and
bad things happen and we found you could
even hack people without touching them
uh if you can't tell if a stroke is a
rupture versus a clot the clot Buster is
a miracle drug that will save your brain
and save life time is brain but if you
can't diagnose it quick enough if you
give that to a rupture you'll kill the
person they'll bleed out so it's merely
disrupting Imaging and not having next
proximal Alternative Care in driving
distance or helicopter distance meant
people died that didn't need to
and then you don't even have to hack the
device at all there was an incredibly
expensive radiation delivery precision
machine that heavily relies on cloud
computing the cloud was down for a very
long period of time during the pandemic
and so those incredibly expensive
otherwise functioning uh radiation
delivery devices couldn't do their job
they were bricks big heavy paperweights
because we always assume the cloud will
always be there except for when it isn't
so during the breaking points here
um when the con this is where I get
heavy okay
um and I may say more during the week
but this has really messed me up from my
public service and I'm getting over it
I'm trying but when the country hit 500
000 dead Americans from covid we also
hit 150 000 additional Americans who
lost their lives from uh non-coveted
excess deaths the CDC tracks checks xss
all the time it's a rolling average of
who died in which state in which month
from which condition so if you normally
see a hundred from this place in this
state and you see 110 you have 10 excess
deaths I asked my team hey I bet you
these are time sensitive conditions
what's killing these people let's study
it and remembering the four 4.4 minutes
can lead to loss of life for a heart and
four hours one to three to four hours is
loss of life for strokes
what could four weeks do four weeks
a regional outage to the state of
Vermont
so I said we need to study this we need
to understand what happened and my team
is going to take us through that in the
next session but
um while we were racing the publish and
it took much longer to publish than I'm
comfortable with and a lot of extra
people died in the meantime The Wall
Street Journal put on the front page is
that that baby
um is possibly the first victim of cyber
disruption uh degrading and delaying
care enough we are surrounded by
technology this is the bonding moment
Beau and I had nine years ago in the
speaker Lounge about
was it confer on the the NICU infant
fetal heart monitors if you degrade
these technology assists you degrade the
care we have more patients admitted
because we have been able to scale with
technology take that technology away and
you're more much more dangerous moments
so the patient has to be at the center
of this
and lives have to be at the center of
this we should care less about record
count and more about human life timely
access to care
so we published some stuff it took a
long time a lot of people in government
did not want us to publish this but we
are tenacious and stubborn and creative
and we did a turducken within a
turducken but we got uh we got it
published and essentially what we found
was uh back in February uh March of 2020
2021 at the one year mark
um we said are there any leading
indicators any leading indicators that
correlate to this um excess death
surging we had and what we found was
another public data source called ICU
bed count or intensive care unit
um bed count 75 is usually optimal
during the pandemic it was fatal and we
measurably so and for example what we
saw is if you hit 75 percent
ICU strain Nationwide you'd see 18 000
dead Americans two weeks later an
additional months four and six weeks
later if you got to one hundred percent
you'd see eighty thousand dead Americans
and unlike
covered deaths these were primarily 25
to 44 year olds these are younger people
that needed timely access to care I
myself almost didn't get timely enough
care for surgery
because of the strains on these
hospitals so we wanted to warn people
that if you could manage your ICU strain
you could avoid elective loss of life we
published this um something that Kendra
is going to walk through
called provide medical care is in
critical condition and uh and through
this analysis we could see that systems
hit by ransomware for protracted amounts
of time could be strained sufficient to
lead to loss of life
and I recently testified to the Senate
on the record that these attacks have
led to measurable loss of life so it's
in the ecosystem now and when I'm asking
each of you for the next couple days is
not just to up and renew your
participation but how do we change the
conversation so that whenever someone
says there's an attack we don't just go
back to well how many records were there
or what was the cost of the ransom or is
there a HIPAA fine none of those things
matter what matters is timely access to
patient care for you for your loved ones
because the a growing toll
from these attacks is that we have seen
10 20 and 30 losses of critical
infrastructure Workforce the people who
make sure we have drinkable water who
make sure we have food supplies and
groceries stocked we make sure we have
timely access to Patient Care we make
sure the oil and gas and electricity
works and we are with Maslow and
we can't
so as the world is increasingly
depending on digital infrastructure they
are increasingly depending on us so what
role will you play and how should we
change over the next two days because
we've done some incredible things over
the last nine years we've been left of
Boom
more times than I ever expected
but there's a lot of booms right now
shit's on fire what are we gonna do
about it thank you for being here and
I'm out of time