really appreciate you joining us this
afternoon
what we're going to do here is I would
argue going to be an extension of what
was discussed this morning only we're
gonna we're gonna widen the aperture a
little bit we're not going to talk about
health
we spent a lot of a good time talking
about health so we're going to talk
about mostly not Health although health
does does sneak in because we're talking
about critical infrastructure and
fundamentally our critical
infrastructures there's many
interdependencies in interaction amongst
and between critical infrastructure
which I believe you will see so stuff is
on fire let us see who is with us today
okay let's see uh let's see so we've got
Meg West who's a little bit off the
screen and unfortunately Meg was not
literally able to join us today but Meg
sends a very special video message and
she introduces herself
um she's uh works as a incident response
consultant for IBM's X-Force and she'll
she'll talk a little bit about some of
the things that she's done so look
forward to that but I'm pleased to
introduce uh Lisa young she currently
serves as a metrics engineer at Netflix
her Mantra is
cyber risk management is a team sport
team sport you heard it here
uh Lisa has got a fabulous background
including being an instructor please
don't read that they can read it
I'm going to read every word
no uh she's familiar she's been in a lot
of different Industries including
telecommunications Financial Services
Airlines manufacturing Automotive
and Marine
just the water Marines okay
um and uh she
she was a cyber security engineer uh for
cert at Carnegie Mellon which has done a
bunch of stuff in the space she was
doing that for 11 years okay uh right
next to her is Mr Dean Ford wave Dean uh
Dean is a managing principal engineer at
luminary automation cyber security and
Engineering LLC uh Dean's entire 20 over
25 years has been involved with
automation systems engineering and
Consulting
he sort of stumbled into this via a
co-op opportunity at Anheuser-Busch in
1994. fell in love with Automation and
the ability to see how things connect to
each other
um he's passionate about educating the
public it's us and policy makers about
some of these issues regarding
um the role of Automation in critical
infrastructure he's also the chair of
the American Water Works water utility
technology and automation committee and
I'm not going to use the acronym for
that thank you
Mr Bryson bort he is the uh before I got
his bio I wrote a short sentence I wrote
Bryson board is the CEO of Scythe an
army veteran and an all-around good guy
then then I got the longer version so
yeah did I yeah then I met him good
guy's been retracted yeah updated bio
uh I did mention uh Scythe he
also started uh Grim a cyber security
consultancy the co-founder of the ICS
Village which you should definitely
check out at Defcon in just a couple of
days do check that out uh senior fellow
with the Atlantic Council on Cyber
uh statecraft initiative National
Security Institute and an advisor to the
Army cyber Institute
and as an army officer an officer I tell
you
he was a battle captain in Brigade
engineering officer in support of
operation Iraqi Freedom before leaving
the Army as Captain okay
and we have also with us we're just
tremendously honored Elizabeth or Liz
leverages almost two DEC two decades of
legal public policy and business
experience to build and scale cyber
security Focus companies she's currently
the Vice President of Operations at
Scythe prior experience includes serving
as a senior assistant City attorney city
of Atlanta
um and dealing with Aviation
and she was also involved in incident
response which we might hear about later
hmm incident response
um and I as your humble moderator my
name is David Bots I'm the managing
director of cyber infrastructure
security at Edison Electric Institute
um I have worked uh literally worked for
an electric utility for about 20 years
about a decade of Energy Regulatory
Compliance physical cyber security
working with lots of different federal
agencies including Department of energy
Department Homeland Security and others
um
yeah and I'll just mention one more
thing I'd like to thank Mr Scott Alger
from the I.T ISAC for his assistance in
providing some background information on
the food and egg sector risk so
here's how today is going to go we're
gonna we're gonna we're gonna start it
at a certain level we're going to start
talking about examples of incident
response we're going to then move into a
discussion of risk and how to think
about risk because risk is hard and
generally as humans we don't ten we
don't naturally do a super good job of
thinking about our quantifying risk
we're then going to go through a number
of different critical infrastructure
sectors and talk about how stuff
is on fire
okay so now here's Meg and I I put in a
little tip here
play the video now
Meg's on a plane on her way here
okay
[Music]
we're not seeing it yet
she's over there I mean I can see it
great yeah
oh let me do this
[Laughter]
oh no all right so that would get
anybody no computers wait where's Tom
yeah computers are hard you know
did you turn it back off and on again
there we go
all right
um Meg who are you and what are you
going to tell us
[Music]
hey there welcome to the b-sides Las
Vegas I am the Calgary and stuff is on
fire talk my name is Meg West and I
currently work as a cyber security
incident response consultant on IBM's
X-Force team prior to that I worked as a
global cyber security incident response
manager at another Fortune 100 company
need this to say I have quite a bit of
experience working in cyber security
incident response and I'm here today to
tell you about two real world incidents
that I have personally observed of
course given the nature of the
conversation that I'll be talking about
I can't tell you exactly who the clients
were but what I can't tell you is that
I've seen these incidents happen several
times before so be careful because they
could be coming to a network near you
the first incident I want to talk about
occurred in the cloud what actually
happened in this case was the client had
an admin account where MFA expired on it
due to a licensing issue and that
account actually happened to have an
extremely basic password that password
was also leaked onto GitHub if you're
not familiar with GitHub leaks they're
happening all the time so be careful to
keep your API keys and other sensitive
passwords safe and left out of your
GitHub code
the attacker was able to Garner access
into the admin account and once they got
into the cloud they started up spinning
up extremely powerful virtual machines
so if you don't already see where this
is going I'll give you a hint it has to
do with crypto if you're not familiar
with what's been happening in the cloud
lately especially in the context of
cyber security incidents a lot of
attackers nowadays are garnering access
to clouds and they're spinning up some
really beefy virtual machines to host
crypto mining operations the client at
the time probably had a spend of about a
thousand dollars per month and after the
attackers spun up these virtual machines
their climb their spend climbed up to
about fifty thousand dollars per month
so you do the math that's quite an
insane difference of forty nine thousand
dollars per month especially when you're
not expecting it
to remediate this it was obviously quite
simple changing out the past or taking
down the virtual machines opening a
ticket with the appropriate cloud
provider and basically Becky Mercy
saying hey I messed up can you help me
out here there's some fraud occurring
but this really could have been avoided
how could we have avoided it the things
I mentioned earlier being cautious what
comments you're making into your GitHub
repositories making sure that your MFA
is appropriately enabled keeping track
of your licensing for accounts these are
all really basic things but
unfortunately they're very easily
overlooked in the second incident I want
to talk about this also occurred in the
cloud however it wasn't about licensing
and it wasn't about MFA nor was it about
passwords it was actually about an NFP
group being incorrectly configured if
you're not familiar with the term NSG
that stands for Network Security Group
it's akin to an access control list on a
firewall but it's more applicable in the
cloud and unfortunately for this client
they left their NFC wide open
essentially allowing anyone to access
into their cloud and a researcher let's
call it that was able to get access to
the client's cloud and Garner a lot of
sensitive data that researcher if we
call it that reached out to the client
said hey I access you know several
hundred gigabytes of your sensitive data
within the cloud and if you don't make
XYZ remediation and containment steps by
this time frame I'm going to go to the
news and tell everyone about this
vulnerability that you have how you're
leaking all of this personal information
so again this could have been really
easily avoided it was actually found
that the client had done Showdown scans
earlier and known that the nfg group was
not properly configured however it can
be assumed due to
improper Staffing lack of resources and
honestly just human error overlooking
and correctly configured NSP that this
incident was allowed to happen if we
take a look at the oauth's top 10
reasons of incidents happening year over
year we're seeing that misconfigurations
are one of the largest reasons leading
to cyber security incidents why do
misconfigurations happen nine times out
of ten is because of human error so
those are two really interesting
incidents that I've seen happen quite
often in the cyber security field and
they're also incidents that have we just
taken some simple measures double
checked our work not had employees that
were burnt out overworked had someone
else to back them up and look over the
work they were doing these incidents
could have been easily avoided I hope
you enjoyed this information I'm finding
more and more incidents that are
happening just because of simple human
errors but the fact of the matter is the
real life and real world impact is huge
both of these incidents happen to
Fortune top 500 clients so to be honest
they could easily happen to you I hope
you have a great rest of your conference
and I'll see you next time bye
Meg
thank you thank
you
okay you ready for me hang on
all right so uh I'm Lisa young I'm
excited to be here
and uh
correct I'm ready
okay cool all right so so I have this
talk that I give it's called all roads
lead to risk so I just crib these notes
from there so I didn't have to make a
whole new presentation so every time you
hear the word risk I want you to think
uncertainty we use the term risk
interchangeably with threat
vulnerability control asset you name it
so I'm here to challenge you all on your
language but the most important thing is
when people are concerned about
something that doesn't make it a risk so
I always say you should move on the
Continuum from areas of concern to
actually doing some analysis or
something and figuring out if it what's
exactly uncertain about what what the
situation or the condition or the threat
or whatever is the area of concern so
there's no part of an Enterprise
regardless of mission regardless of type
of organization that's not exposed to
some kind of risk and the type or
category of the risk might be different
but the workflow to identify assess or
analyze or take some action to respond
to risk is largely the same and you know
so for those of you who don't know if
you weren't in the last presentation I
serve on the board of directors for ISC
squared so if there's any disgruntled
people in the OR organization you can
talk to me because we're making some
serious changes to the organization and
I hope you see that
um but in in that role we identified the
top 10 skills that'll be needed in cyber
over the next 10 years and obviously
Cloud security data analysis malware
analysis all those things are on there
coding programming all of those but risk
assessment risk management and the
ability to talk across and work across
silos right to actually translate the
things that we do in in technical terms
to business impact terms and I said this
last time and I'll say it again but uh
uh you know one of the reasons why the
covid task force which was up here
before if you missed it won an award is
not for all the good work we did which
we did a lot of good work but it's
because we made people who were in silos
talk to one another right and I think
that that's going to become really more
important as we go go through this uh
this everything that's going on in our
world next slide please
so uh when I I actually you know use the
word digital I don't really use the word
cyber much because I don't think it has
a lot of meaning
um so I actually have a master's in
public policy and one of the
um one of the exercises we had to do I
went to the University of Maryland one
of the exercises we had to do was Define
cyberspace cyber security and all those
terms as related to public policy so I'm
not really fond of the word cyber but it
does get all the money so the but the
problem is is that if you all know the
OSI model it's all ones and zeros anyway
I'm a telecom engineer so you know the
whole point is that digital is pervasive
and this whole notion of cyber physical
what it's being called now cyber
physical systems safety systems cyber
physical so I like to think of the word
digital and building digital trust right
and so this just is a graphic I crib
from the Masters program the University
of California at Irvine and they do a
cyber physical systems but it's also
referred to which you'll hear throughout
this conversation I do a lot of work in
critical infrastructure I just recently
did an assessment for a water company in
another country that was deploying a
thousand iot sensors to to understand
what was in their infrastructure right
so you can imagine where this all goes
so the point here is that you know these
things are tightly coupled to all of the
systems upon which we rely and you know
use in our daily lives the other thing
is I happen to be privileged enough to
own a spa in my backyard and I fill it
up every few months I mean you know you
drain it you fill it up it's not like a
pool
and I've noticed because you know the
chlorine shortage right there's no more
chlorine in my water
um uh so when I fill up the pool I have
to add additional chemicals now when I
read their monthly water report it tells
me that they've gone to bromine but we
don't exactly know if it does the same
thing as chlorine so I'm just telling
you this because there's things that
slip through the cracks that we don't
always pay attention to
um okay so next slide please
so is there anything different about
cyber risk right
um you know cyber generally speaking in
the context here is it's of or relating
to computers digital infrastructure but
what um the difficulty is is that you
know our risk which I use just the
common dictionary definition of risk and
when you put those two things together
what it says is it typically involves
unauthorized access right so it's not
just the digital things the
misconfiguration the things that we're
concerned about but there's also this
element of unauthorized hackers right
unauthorized use of computer and
computer technology but what I want to
say here is that our risk increases
cyber risk whether you call it cyber
risk Digital Risk whatever you call it
it increases as our dependence on these
cyber physical systems actually
accelerates uh next slide please so this
is um I do a lot of content development
work for isaka so if you've seen the
risk I.T framework the risk it
practitioner's guide if you've seen the
risk I.T starter kit or the scenarios I
think we just released a few weeks ago
so I'm a futurist and so I like to build
scenarios for things that might happen
in the future and I use and they're
they're published now so they're freely
available
um uh eye socket just released a bunch
of them but basically the constructs of
how do you think about what could or
couldn't happen because one scenario
could have multiple outcomes in the
future right and how do we start
thinking about that as a way to get
senior leaders and decision makers more
information or more option more
optionality about what decisions they
should be making and so this is just a
high level risk management workflow
people spend a lot of time on assessing
controls assessing variety of things but
what they seem to miss in my judgment is
they miss the identification what are
the things that are pertinent to us
depending on the type of organization we
are right because each of us has a
different Mission but the scenarios can
be used in every step of this workflow
um to you know every step of the risk
management process or workflow you can
get a better understanding of what
actions to take or what actions not to
take based on you know your workflow
next slide please
so I know this is a little complex side
normally it's a build but we don't do
builds here so the point here is that
this is the organizational context to
think about risk management so I'm going
to start from the organizational Mission
every single organization whether it's
for-profit non-profit business
government whatever it is has a reason
for being okay I did a lot of work over
many years ago helping the military you
know set up cyber sort of thinking about
cyber
um as a as a discipline in a domain and
when we think about the organizational
Mission we use business activities
whether you call them projects
initiatives workflow business activities
business processes productive activities
we use those in order to execute our
mission but those uh business processes
that we use are reliant upon assets
right and you can think of assets as
people Information Technology facilities
Supply chains supplies raw materials you
name it you need to Define what those
are for you you and what the critical
ones are to your business processes that
allow you to deliver your mission and
any of those assets people Information
Technology facilities Supply supply
chain we wrap our processes around them
we call them risk management processes
we may not call them that explicitly but
all the things in this box over here are
examples of things that we do to keep
those assets operating in their intended
condition so that we can continue to
carry out our initiatives whether those
initiatives are automated or manual
doesn't really matter
the point is the more we rely on the
Technologies which relies on the assets
we need to wrap them in a way that
allows them to continue to operate
regardless of what happened whether they
operate in a degraded state or anything
so that we can keep going now the
problem with many of these things in the
Box over here on the right hand side is
that they're all done individually
they're discrete efforts they don't
collaborate right and so one of the
things that we can do and should do is
to collaborate more across silos and
figure out how to collect data once use
it many times right for multiple
purposes so next slide please so this is
just another way to say that you know
risk identification and assessment uh
they have to help the organization
identify what is most important you know
what conditions and call them by their
proper language and then you know I
think you mentioned quantification I'm
not going to talk about it but you know
I'm I'm not a probableist although I use
probable Theory to figure out in my
scenarios what could or could not
materialize but also I'm a big impact
person and um and you know it's
important to understand and talk to
Business Leaders in terms that they
understand about what the impact could
be from a degraded state or an asset
being taken out of service
uh next time
oh this is it oh well there you go okay
so uh then never mind I'm all done
that's all I wanted to say and we'll go
on to the next person now so I'm here if
you need to talk about any of this
anymore after
you're up next babe all right thank you
thank you
oh I look pretty good there yeah you
look great
um you got to get close to the motor
yeah so one thing
um
I just learned that I still had a toner
account
so don't send anything to that this is
my this is my connection to the world
now
I I have given up on social media
um so
well risk is the first word risk
identification no that one was mine okay
I'm sorry there you go
so stuff is on fire
um so uh real quick uh what they uh what
David asked us to do and and I tried to
follow that and be a rule follower for
once
um so everybody's probably familiar with
a couple of the the most recent events
that have really thrust the the water
sector
um and when I speak to water I mean
Water and Wastewater to us it's the same
thing to you it might be very different
things but
the plants are the you know if you're
living Downstream of somebody else's
City you're drinking their Wastewater
sorry
um so
um so just so you know that so old smart
everybody was very familiar with because
it happened about the same time and the
colonial stuff and all those things
and and I'm not going to go into the
details you know some old machine was
sitting there and it was got left on and
somebody else accessed it and you know
blah blah blah blah and they they got a
hold of the the controls
um the one thing about OT is that I'm
sure most folks are aware you know just
getting into access doesn't really get
you anywhere you got to know what to do
with that
um so this particular person also knew
what to do with that once they got
access and they went over and started
controlling some some chemical infeeds
that were very bad
um
there's a whole host of problems with
that that
um
that aren't cyber security related
um and so I I struggle with this concept
of you know everything's a cyber
security problem to to an asset owner
like water it's just one of thousands of
risks that we manage every day
and unfortunately the public doesn't
even understand what it costs to
generate the water that they get and we
are in a constant struggle you know you
try and raise your rate by five cents
and all of a sudden you know the world's
on fire
but most most water utilities are not um
even covering their costs to produce the
product that they're selling and another
thing that most folks don't understand
is most water utilities are the only
Revenue generating
um true Revenue generating uh entity
within a city everything else is tax
based
water utilities Wastewater utilities are
Revenue based they send you a bill you
pay the bill so they're also the ones
that's that can get rated when the
city's not doing very well
um so anyway there's a lot of things
working against the water utility
in this case it was a simple issue you
know they left the machine on from some
startup a decade ago
um so you know was this really a cyber
security issue was it a people issue
why did that machine get left there
where is the process is in place to go
around and ensure those things are taken
care of
um so we you know my my view of the
world is a little bit different in that
that that there were a lot of other
things that failed and that's usually
what happens when these things fail
right it's not just one event it's a
Cascade of errors that occur in order to
cause a problem fortunately this
particular problem the operator happened
to be paying attention and caught it in
time
um the other one the Baltimore city
um ransomware
you know it it didn't affect any water
delivery at all
um it was a billion issue billing
systems issue which we're also going
through some major upgrades
um
you know same kind of right that some
person clicked on something they weren't
supposed to launched a whole attack so a
lot of issues out there that that are
being faced you know utilities are in a
unique spot where they have to be very
transparent with their users with their
clients
they're also a unique spot that that
specifically in the water sector
information is shared there's no
competition
so people share information all the time
best practices the Water Works
Association the water environment
associations the Wastewater side ins and
outs
um you know there's a lot of information
sharing and and um
past what's on fire if you could go to
the next slide there's some stuff that's
smoldering out there
um
public awareness is is
is a good thing and a bad thing so
you know now we've had these incidents
so now everybody wants the utility to
take money that they don't have and go
spend it to fix cyber issues so if the
board's agendas don't have cyber on them
then you know
uh turmoil occurs and things happen and
people are upset well you know we also
have to keep the plant running and we
probably need to replace a generator
that won't start to keep the plant
running during a power outage which is a
far more likely event from a risk
standpoint
than than a cyber incident so again it's
a it's a management issue for us
um and so public awareness also now has
elevated a lot of the work that's going
on here and why I'm excited to be a part
of this is that it's helping us get some
things pushed through which will then
Force some you know when you're when
you're in a situation it's it's one of
the few things that that we don't like
one's a consent decree we don't like it
but when it sure does open up the
checkbooks and allows us to get some
stuff done
so my utility friends are gonna like
that but it's true it's very true
um along with that then comes from
government regulations so
um you know we we focus a lot on the
quality of the drinking water
um uh that's our primary primary
objective is quality of your drinking
water everybody feels clean today right
you're welcome
so
um and again it's it's a lot like
electricity you know you flip the switch
on the lights come on
you know there are there are an
increasingly number of fewer people that
understand how that electricity gets to
the house how that water gets out and
and you know understanding how all this
stuff works together so hopefully these
camp we can get some campaigns going
that's a big work of the awwa
um there's some water as life campaigns
water one uh one water
um
no water no beer
it has been
um but essentially the you know the next
thing that's coming is is that the Fert
nerk ferc that is in the electric
utility is coming to water
you know water
applauds that bring it but you can't
apply it without also applying the
funding
we have a much bigger problem Beyond
cyber is that
um you know the the Flint Michigan's out
there you know there's a lot more of
that than there are of of this cyber
issue we've got a trillion dollar crisis
and it's all buried
nobody sees it so that was that report
was 2016 so that's probably 2 trillion
by now
um most utilities you know pipe is only
designed to be in the ground for 20
years 30 years 50 years most utilities
aren't replacing pipe fast enough to
ever catch up so we're still pulling
pipe that's wooden out of Baltimore
from the original piping it was in so
just think about that as we start
addressing this and then you've got the
problems in California that
do I really care about cyber when I
don't even have water
and then when you start to think about
it and say okay well I sell water
now I'm regulating and telling people
they have to use less water
well but I have to spend more money to
take care of that water and do cyber
security but my Revenue just reduced
because I'm requiring you to use less
water
costs the same whether you use a little
bit or a lot that costs me delivering it
to you is the same so there's a lot of
those challenges that we're up against
uh Workforce Development for us is um
you know the the gray the gray hairs The
Brain Drain
um what are the words there's a ton of
words out there for it the problem with
the utilities is it's as public sector
jobs they're not able to keep Pace with
the rapid changes in the market right so
they'll they're a great training ground
and people learn their their trade and
they're gone offer double salary right
now the good news is that with the
Millennials and and the Next Generation
there's a lot of social awareness and
social conscience there we've got the
game on that right we're making water
good for society
yeah
um funding for risk mitigation we talked
a little bit about that
um the other big one for us right now is
is the fallacy of cyber insurance I I
really wish
um that that would be regulated out
um and nobody would waste money on it
um you know all it takes is you to file
a claim their job is not to pay it
you're expecting that they that they cut
you covered
um so it falls back a lot where you know
the the boards and things are looking at
this differently the bottom line is if
if Europe had a known issue you know
you're not covered that as you will find
with most insurance
um go talk to your insurance broker
sometime and have a lovely conversation
about that
and we've got a huge issue with
technology obsolescence we were talking
a little bit earlier
um what's it you know that back in the
day that when the river caught fire that
initiated the Clean Water Act the Clean
Water Act then caused us to go around
and build a lot of concrete a lot of
that concrete
went along with that came a computer
control system that computer control
system is at the early age of Automation
and nobody really understood what they
did so they got a ton of automation had
no idea what to do with it and so very
few places actually did anything with it
it was never in the water industry
Automation and technology is not really
a an investment it's a it's a tool and
it's a necessity
Private Industry would never automate
something that didn't have any return on
investment the water industry has to
automate things whether they have a
return on investment or not
because of the quality and the safety
issues so
we have to we have to change that
thinking in the in the industry and
change that culture I've had a
conversation the other day with with
um you know everything's going to the
cloud Who
the
if if the people that are using the
cloud data can't understand how to use a
trend on my computer when it's local I
haven't helped them any by moving it to
the cloud
I haven't gained and I've added in fact
I've added risk because now they might
lose that the only source of data that
they had so there's there's just a lot
of that cultural change that that I see
being a 20-year Private Industry guy
making beer and drugs and cars and all
kinds of other stuff and moving into the
water sector
a lot of challenges that that we've
solved in gas and oil and electric
haven't they're they're looked at as
brand new problems in the water sector
and so there's a lot of a lot of
opportunity for sharing of information
um so I'm gonna settle it up at that and
uh thanks for having us out
foreign
thanks very much Dean I appreciate that
and when we talk about food
uh and food and egg
um I think you'll hear some common
themes where people say this is a new
problem we've never had this problem
before we've no one has thought about
this and that's what we're going to talk
about we're going to talk about food and
agricultural sector problems which are
well frankly their Legion uh there's a
lot of issues here so let me jump in
according to
the U.S government and sis specifically
2.1 million Farms over 900 000
restaurants over 200 000 registered
manufacturing processing and storage
facilities in these United States
food is a big deal in the United States
okay show of hands who had some food
today okay
yeah
so probably everybody or after you
showered
yes both and we should also ask who who
had water today but
um food is a big deal economically
20 approximately 20 of this nation's
economy is structured around food
growing it
uh harvesting it manufacturing
processing advertising delivery and the
last mile at the store so 20 of the of
the entire economies is a relatively big
deal
so what's going on are there any
problems yes there are problems stuff in
fact is on fire okay so let us talk let
us first start with concentration risk
now I would say on this picture we have
two examples of concentration our first
example of concentration is a nice
person who's who's thinking thinking
very concentrated thoughts that's the
good concentration there's a bad
concentration as well in the bad
concentration is
uh the glass in this case a magnifying
glass the Sun hits it starts a fire
that is where we are at with vendors and
vendors in the food space
so just a couple of really interesting
statistics
um overall only 15 cents one five cents
of every dollar that we spend in the
supermarket goes to Farmers what
15 cents so that means 85 cents goes
somewhere else uh processing uh
processing storage transportation and
marketing
but consolidation runs really deep four
firms or fewer controlled at least 50
percent of the market for if we take all
of the different elements of food
Dairy meat what have you
um
uh 50 percent of uh four few four firms
or fewer controlled over 50 percent of
each each of those sub pieces of food
for almost a third of shopping items the
top firms controlled 75 of market share
so there is very significant Market
concentration well okay what's the worst
thing that could happen
oh there's actually a lot of worse
things that could happen so in meat
specifically right now in today's world
there are four major companies that
control depending on on the specific
type of meat you want to talk about 55
to 85 percent of the market is
controlled by these four firms
um
the White House has accused these
companies of contributing to inflation
by Rising raising prices while
generating record profits what's really
interesting is that the U.S subsidiary
of Brazil's JBS South America which is
the world's largest meat supplier they
Pro they they alone that one company is
responsible for 20 of the meat
production in these United States of
America 20 one company no problem oh
there is a problem the problem is that
in late May of
2021 ransomware visited their firm
so all processing of all meat in both
United States and Australia stopped it
just it just full-on stopped and a lot
of a lot of Downstream uh impacts from
that especially if you're a farmer who
can't deliver uh your livestock to the
slaughterhouse there are no pictures of
slaughterhouses here only relatively
happy animals who are about to go
upstate to New York
um
JVS however ended up paying 11 million
dollars in ransomware to the Cyber
criminals a week after discovering the
incursion
so
other examples of concentration here's
one infant formula according to data
compiled by the Allied market research
these four companies control 90 percent
that's nine zero percent
of the U.S infant formula industry you
see the names
but there's one name in particular that
really gets my attention
um and that is the good people from
Abbott nutrition
so
uh there are some challenges here
between December 1st 2021 and March 3rd
of this year 2022 the Food and Drug
administ Administration received nine
reports of infant deaths related to
infant formula manufactured by Abbott
nutrition in Sturgis Michigan
so in February of this year February 22
2022 Abbott voluntarily recalls powder
formulas that were manufactured at that
one plant
so that one plant just it it stopped
um
uh I'll have you just so you're aware uh
Abbott alone
is responsible for about 40 percent of
the infant formula in these United
States of America
half of their production how much half
of their production in the United States
comes from one plant
one plant so
20 so said another way 20 percent of all
infant formula in these United States
comes from this location and there's
some infant formula that 100 of it comes
from this location because at this
location it makes other formulations
that are available nowhere else
um
so let's let's walk through what happens
so in February uh the recall happened
and Abbott stop production they said
okay we're gonna do a better job we're
gonna get after this bacteria that is
causing problems no admission to guilt
um so they did that four months they
were offline producing nothing
um you see there the picture of military
assets being used to transport formula
from Europe into the United States
because parents were desperate desperate
because infants could not
there was no there's no formula so this
was this is a pretty terrible situation
so early June Abbott resumes production
cool
um then what happens uh then the weather
happens the weather happens and in June
June 15th of this year a storm happens
in beautiful Sturgis Michigan and Abbott
gets water coming up through the floor
and they got they got all kinds of
problems in their Factory they stop
production again
and it takes them about three weeks to
restore clean stuff out get it all going
again but think about that think about
four entities that have this control
over infant formula which if you have an
infant that cannot tolerate any other
kind of food that is critical
infrastructure to you no kidding I mean
this is
the definition of a life health safety
issue for short
um what else is going on in agriculture
oh we should talk about agriculture we
talked a little bit about food let us
get to agriculture so
um uh as the the good people at the FBI
did Issue a warning and they sent out uh
they sent out April April 20th this year
FBI warns of ransomware attacks
targeting U.S AG sector
um in the interest of time I'm not going
to go through these but uh this came out
this is a super public there's four
specific instances of attacks against
food producers grain storage elevators
Etc this is like a no kidding warning no
kidding warning what that happened on
April 20. nothing bad would ever happen
after April 20th of this year
oh but their bad things do happen oh how
did this happen so
um the nice people at fent
um got ransomware on May 5th egg Co we
can concentration concentration so AGCO
that that's the name I'm not lying AGCO
agriculture company uh they owned this
big tractor company they own a lot of
tractor companies they got ransomware
um they've gone pretty quiet but it
doesn't take it's not hard to understand
the Practical implication of ransomware
against a manufacturing facility that
produces tractors can cause those
tractors to not be available to the
marketplace when the marketplace wants
to do things like buy tractors fix
tractors use tractors so this is an
attack against agriculture critical
infrastructure and
it's an issue but there are other issues
related to tractors now
we all laughed uh and we were super
happy when we saw pictures uh picture on
the left of tractors Towing uh disabled
Russian tanks in Ukraine we said yay
that's great
um but then we got sad for a second when
we learned that Russians were stealing
looting pillaging Ukraine in an
unprovoked war and were stealing
tractors so he said boo but then we
heard that John Deere remotely disabled
the tractors and then we said yay what
we said yay for a minute
just a minute
and then we thought about it and then we
said ooh yikes
no
I want to give a shout out
he might be here in this room I don't
know we did talk before this
presentation
and that is if there's one person that I
would I would strongly recommend that
um you follow you follow on the twitters
and in in all the places is Mr sick
codes
um so big day big egg is Big Data and um
I grabbed a lot of this information from
him he's doing amazing work and I'm
going to talk about uh his Defcon 30
presentation a little bit but
um in this picture you might see a
tractor but do you know what that
tractor is that is a data collection
device it is collecting all of the data
all of the time uh moisture uh uh it it
collects everything about the production
used in agriculture and
um so you say okay well what's so bad
about that
yeah for all of the data from every John
Deere tractor is being collected and
stored in one place what could possibly
go wrong oh right everything everything
could go wrong because this data speaks
to very precise operational impacts that
are going on for a given farmer we
talked earlier about I think it was 2.1
million farms in these United States of
America
if there's one company that say given
their Market I I don't know how big the
John Deere Market is compared to others
um my belief is that it's at least north
of 40 percent probably higher than that
but the good people at John Deere they
have the data they have all of the data
they got all the data
now what happens if all that data is a
sync is in a single portal
would that represent a very nice Target
for an adversary
yes yes it would what could you do with
that data you could you could do a bunch
of things you could do things
commercially like you could say
tractor a does not belong to Bob it
belongs to Robin and Robin's tractor
belongs to Pat that'd be kind of a pain
in the neck but you can issue a
multi-year denial of service attack
against one farmer or more than one
farmer maybe a bunch of farmers maybe
through a single portal you reprogram
the tractor there is remote access
involved related to this portal you
reprogram that tractor to dump so much
fertilizer in a certain area of the
field that that field cannot grow crops
again for decades
that would be a bad day
but here's the thing this this is the
world that we live in and again you want
to follow Mr sick codes because and and
uh he's
he's trying to be as responsible as he
can he's telling the good people at John
Deere some of the issues that they have
for some reason they were not super
interested in listening but he's he's
working with um uh there's a lot of
concentrated risk as it relates to
um big egg and big data I don't want to
I don't put all the blame on John Deere
because basically every other uh tractor
manufacturer is in the same game of
collecting the data this relates to
um uh carbon offsets uh production you
think about in today's world uh corn is
used for everything including food it's
also used to create natural fuel biofuel
a lot of issues related to Big
agriculture
um big eggs big risk this metallicy
device is an example of a piece of
communications Hardware that is in every
or essentially every tractor which
fundamentally is a data collection
device that sending all that information
back home and so here's the big reveal
Saturday evening or Saturday
sick codes is on the main stage talking
about hacking the farm breaking badly
into agricultural devices if you're at
Defcon you definitely want to check that
out
okay oh uh there is an announcement here
thank you
so one of the one of the fabulous
benefits of speaking at Defcon is you
can make outrageous Pizza
[Music]
don't lose your cookies
okay
besides LV besides LV because besides LV
is way cooler than Defcon because Defcon
doesn't know how to do this
uh is you can make outrageous requests
and if you don't mispronounce the name
of the conference that you're in they
might accommodate you so
I would like to welcome Mr bort to the
floor to share with us
your mic is right up there
all right well thank you for giving me a
low bar to meet in comparison David
[Laughter]
just jump over
who knows what industrial control
systems are
right
what is an industrial control system
it has now been zero days since stuxnet
has been mentioned thank you so that is
that is the common perspective we need
to understand that all too often in our
industry we talk to the echo chamber of
ourselves right not everybody is as
smart and as good looking and as nice as
Jen Ellis foreign
right so
who's got another answer for winning
industrial control system is because
that's not wrong that's actually
literally what 95 of the world would
probably say
oh you got another one
like the Tesla manufacturing floor
Tesla manufacturing floor so
manufacturing is a place where there are
a lot of industrial control systems
anything that controls life systems
elevators
cameras I like how you used the the name
in it well it does controls right and
that's part of it so the simplest way to
think of an industrial control system is
any computer that's at least 20 years
old
[Laughter]
now unlike your random computers that
you carry around with you or your pretty
laptops
these don't just focus on data
these affect the physical world that's
what we're controlling it's not just
data it's physical impact
and when we lose energy
we go to the Stone Age immediately
that's not me worrying about cyber
insurance
that's not me worrying about data
that is we are Stone Age like that
all right so it's not often that I get
to actually say I was a primary source
so two and a half years ago at RSA
that's another conference than b-sides
hahaha
then director Chris Krebs and I were up
on stage he was the cyber security
infrastructure Security Agency they care
about security so much it's in the name
twice
and we called the coming rash of
ransomware ransomware had been around
for a while but the difference was we
painted it as a coming National crisis
and as of 2021 just like when we think
of industrial Control Systems from 2012
we think of stuxnet ransomware in 2021
became a kitchen word
what I mean by that is it escapes the
expert parlance of this is exactly what
ransomware means it became something
that was talked around the kitchen table
because it actually affected your daily
citizens life
your average citizen does not think
about cyber security
in fact I would argue in your personal
lives you rarely do as well you don't
wake up and think about what am I
cybering today except at my job
right you think about shower
thank you for the water
you think about breakfast you think
about your boss as an
you think about your car right you think
about all of these things this is not a
top priority and so when we get
and it's always for a bad reason but
when we get that opportunity as a
community because something is bad
enough that it gets the attention that
is our opportunity for change right I am
the Cavalry has been pushing these ideas
for years and I mean unfortunately it
takes those kinds of big moments to make
change going back to where we're talking
about risk we as humans are terrible at
understanding risk and what it actually
means for ourselves which is why we all
think well yeah that's bad but I got all
these other things to worry about and
until it happens I don't care
so ransomware has now
innovated right ransomware used to just
be I just locked your computer right
Saudi aramco all of their computers
overnight paperweights now what's
interesting about that is it did not
directly affect any of the industrial
control systems
not a single one was affected
but every single computer in the
Enterprise Information Technology
environment paperweight
do you think that you can run your
operational Technologies without your
I.T
nope
so now they've expanded it not only am I
going to lock your stuff but I'm going
to exfiltrate it and then I'm going to
use that as double extortion so pay me
the Bounty for well Bounty sorry
if you've been following any of the
cryptocurrency stuff that's been the
latest thing is hey we're going to call
you white hat afterward if you return
the money
true story that's a that's a bounty that
was why I was in my head no so hey The
Ransom to get the decrypter to turn your
data back on so you can operate
and we won't release your stuff
then they thought wait we can do even
better than that because what do we get
with your data well I get all of your
customers and all of your vendors and
all of your supply chain
huh wonder if any of their data is in
that
I wonder if you not want them to know
and so that's the triple extortion now
where I'm going to also Ransom that
against all of the relationships that
you have
um so the question of this has always
been almost all ransomware comes out of
roughly Eastern Europe and Russia
the great majority of it and the
question has always been what is the
alignment of clearly Russian
intelligence military to that and for
the most part there is no absolute
Smoking Gun where somebody got caught
with it being like in a direct handoff
but there certainly was at a minimum a
kind of wink wink will let you work here
and that changed when we had the
Ukrainian War
so one of the big ransomware groups
there Conti within one day of the attack
came out publicly and said anybody that
does anything against Russian computers
we're going to attack you back
furthermore as we discuss this in a
later slide we're going to talk about
how very curiously a lot of the
ransomware targets tied directly to
Russian national strategy
huh
turns out we're not really talking about
this computer nerd are we
because this stuff doesn't just exist on
the realm of what we have to do for
computer security it's the question of
motives
and why
um and then we have also example of
activists using ransomware in the biela
Russian cyber partisans
slide all right so why it's so important
we don't call everything an attack
have anybody ever seen those statistics
where like we stopped 600 million
attacks a second
at the airport
not a bulletin board when we landed in
Vegas if you didn't see it you know
which one which is the one we hate um
dark Trace
sorry I have opinions
um and what they're doing is turns out
that all of this interconnected stuff
is constantly being swept by all sorts
of different people who had written
scripts to crawl it to touch and do that
well when I touch a port and I touch
that port and I'm enumerating the
surface and touching that stuff they're
calling those attacks
well now go back to our industry our
community problem of we've come across
as The Boy Who Cried Wolf
and so it's hard for society to tell the
difference well you said 600 million
attacks
and I don't see any real problem with
that
so we have to be very careful with our
language
we have to think what's the difference
between reconnaissance what's the
difference between initial access and
then what's the difference where I'm
actually causing impact
right Dean mentioned this earlier the
difference between axis impact those are
the two key attributes when we look at
industrial control systems
the other part tying it to it right
everybody's familiar with the CIA Triad
confidentiality integrity and
availability
availability is the biggest key in
industrial control systems
I'm not doing it three times
so we need to be careful about our
language because it changes where people
are going to be listening to us
especially at b-sides
where's your Bounty buddy
all right so who's heard of the Purdue
model
I have okay the Purdue model is the de
facto Enterprise architecture model that
we use in industrial control systems
and it's fooling you
it was originally created to be able to
establish the timing of these Control
Systems so that I could get them to work
and the problem is we looked at that
from an I.T background and from a design
and a security background and well like
one two three four five I mean that's
defense in depth right
foreign
it intuitively gives you that feeling
doesn't it
but here's the reality
Pixar is uh what gonna be recruiting me
so we have it we all understand I.T
beachhead
so like in the Florida water hack
what they did is they accessed a human
machine interface
these are higher level machines that are
there in these environments so that I
don't have to literally run around to
every sensor or control system I have a
single map of them I can see what the
state of those are and I can make
modifications manually if I need to in
the case of the Florida water hack the
um the HMI they changed it so that the
PLC stayed open the programmable logic
controller stayed open and that
increased the amount of lie that was
going to be processed through the water
at that point
that PLC is at the bottom part that's
the traditional operational technology
these are relatively dumb devices
they just do what they're told because
all of the intelligence is being done up
the beachhead that was a besides click
please thank you
oh forgot there's a theoretical air gap
right
has anybody ever actually seen an air
gap yes
you've seen a real air gap
and maintained it and nothing ever
crossed it ever ever ever ever ever not
once
exactly
so an air gap is not an air gap is not
an air gap
um and there are lots I mean there are
better ones or Worse ones but the
reality is you always have to have a
reason for something to touch something
at some point
and the challenge here is that the
primary reason that we have in
industrial Control Systems these
connections well just think about what's
the most logical thing right it ties to
a lot of what he was saying about in
water
well it's the same thing in electricity
what do I need to get from my what's
happening in the operational environment
that ties to business administration
money Billy Money
billing
it's always going to be a need for
so
okay so this is the reality this is the
threats perspective of all of that
most of the access comes in through
Information Technology because that's
his job there is never an air gap so I
move over into a beachhead and a
beachhead is a higher level system like
an HMI was an example I gave another one
might be a distributed control system
and here's the thing so
when we talk about pure operational
Technologies they're all these wacky
really custom protocols and
architectures and codes like you you
take years of training to learn how to
code at that level
but here's the thing
that HMI and the DCS speaks all of that
it's already built for it that's its
entire purpose is to talk to them and
tell them what to do
and what operating system do you think
those things run on
the X works
pick your version of Windows only two
generations old
all right so that's what I looked like
with my coveted beard
you haven't seen cyber Gandalf
I think that was an RSA uh interview so
what we've seen in the last 10 years
and this is public right I'm not sharing
anything classified you can look this up
and they've been publishing more of this
since 2012 we have seen iterative
intelligence campaigns we've attributed
them to China to Russia to Iran
North Korea shows up a little bit but
their primary modus operandi is
ransomware so that dear leader can pay
for expensive whiskey
the other three have much more
interesting per you know purposes
against us so why that's important is we
talk about the Cyber Redline has anyone
heard that before
right what's the point where an attack
is something we're going to respond in a
certain way
because if you notice 10 years of
hundreds of campaigns
with this having an increasing Up Tempo
and yet there's been no real loss of
life as there
why do you think that is
what's that
because that's a red light do you think
the United States government's response
is going to be we're going to cyber you
back
no the number one military in the world
is not going to cyber you back if you
cross the red line
our adversaries know this and so what
the intent has been is I want to map I
want to do reconnaissance I want to
break in I want to understand I want to
iterate and go through
um a theory if I'm gonna can jump into
the water example is that Florida water
hack
that change of that lie would have
changed it to a dangerous level
so
does my hypothesis hold water
at that point and here's why I think it
does because there's a second manual
safety in that process
they don't immediately release that
treated water directly into the water
supply they manually test it in tanks
that they hold
this threat that actor who whomever it
was knew that and what they were doing
was measuring response
so last one Colonial pipeline Colonial
pipeline Silver Lining is that that's
that's the part that's the good that I
have on there the one good part is
ransomware became a kitchen work yeah
speeding up got it
so what's the bad the bad is a private
company unilaterally made a decision
that shut down
oil and gas to the entire southeast of
the United States
they did that without this affecting
operational technology directly it was
I.T only that was affected and I believe
this is my call and I'm being recorded
so too bad Colonial you
um
no they panicked
they responded out of fear they didn't
know I mean they they shut it down with
an hour of it being called like they saw
it and then they immediately shut
everything down I second that what's
that by second yeah and what is it that
causes this fear the fear is when we
don't know and we haven't trained it
before
they didn't train
they did not practice the response
tabletop tabletop tabletop if they had
done just a couple of tabletops I
promise you I promise I mean
maybe some degree of confidence that
that probably would have been handled
differently
thank you
all right lawyer Liz we need you to lay
some True Stone on Municipal service
sector problems are there any
now not even a little bit and so typical
lawyer disclaimer
um while I am a lawyer unless you work
for Scythe so Bryson excluded and I
think we have one other colleague in
here I am not your lawyer and even
beyond that I am not your personal
lawyer so if y'all get arrested in Las
Vegas I am not licensed to practice here
I will not bail you out of jail but I
will laugh hysterically and make sure
your mug shots get posted everywhere of
course make sure I have full concerns et
cetera et cetera et cetera but in a
prior life before jumping over into the
startup world I was in private practice
even before I joined the city of Atlanta
so as anyone's familiar with state of
Georgia because we don't do anything
wrong or newsworthy et cetera et cetera
et cetera but there are 159 counties in
the great state of Georgia
so if you're thinking of the sticky
spider web that gets built when you have
a 159 counties in a state that if you
know Atlanta maybe you know Augusta
maybe you know Savannah
those are our big economic areas in
addition to Gainesville Georgia in
Dalton Georgia which are two capitals of
Commerce for chicken
poultry manufacturing and carpets
so now you're thinking wow the great
state of Georgia and all these counties
are just FL their coffers are
overflowing with cash no so I got to
serve as part of a team that were the
county and School Board attorneys for
about 30 of those different state or for
30 of those different counties and
school boards so if you want to talk
about getting in the weeds and talking
about old school systems when you have
some of the most economically depressed
areas in school districts where schools
are serving as you know everything in
addition to counties counties are
providing lots of different answers for
all kinds of things so when you're
talking about a ransomware attack on a
County government that if they can't get
their systems up the Social Security
checks other Community Support Services
are immediately shut down so next slide
so we're going to talk a little bit
about and I kind of jammed a lot of
things in here because some of us being
lawyers and Rural followers held to the
two slide requests
[Laughter]
thank you thank you very much
some of us also read the emails and
other Communications about the panel
thank you
so now that we're going to talk about
Municipal governments as well because I
wisely decided you know what I was
having fun with technology so I'm going
to get out of Private Practice and I'm
going to go into public practice so I
joined the great city of Atlanta as a
senior assistant City Attorney in charge
of the world's busiest airport
technology project so I in 2017.
had joined the city of Atlanta in 2018.
well before it became a national topic
for everybody else around dinner tables
in Atlanta we suddenly got to learn oh
ransomware samsam and being one of the
only attorneys uh in the Department of
Law who had any background whatsoever in
cyber security information security
researchers hackers you can imagine kind
of the oh moment when I'm on the
department of aviation's network
computers and my colleagues on the
actual city of Atlanta Network computers
suddenly we're going hey I can't access
my files I got this thing up
well by the grace of God we had also had
implemented Network segmentation so our
Watershed Department was on its own
network there was not crossover that we
could tell we joke about tabletop
exercises let me explain to you what
happens when you realize there is still
one uh computer that is probably still
connected from the middle of the
Airfield FAA requires that you have fire
stations so that you can have fire
trucks that can get to every any
aircraft emergency with x number of
seconds
so we had one fire station that still
perhaps maybe was connected to the
city's Network that we are realizing in
these so if you want to see someone run
quickly
tell them that you may have one computer
that may be about to boot up that is
still connected to the city's Network
that also is a crossover point to the
world's busiest airport uh Network and
if someone can get over to that and
kindly unplug it from the wall and
essentially smash it and do it right now
that is what we're doing so what I
wanted to highlight real quick in
talking about municipal government so I
could have painted this picture you've
got these governments that are not full
of experts everything literally is on
fire when it comes to for example city
of Atlanta and we had a bridge that
actually caught on fire and collapsed so
when you have all of this and you're
thinking okay well what happened
recently and Somerset County New Jersey
well they got hit recently and their
county databases and everything got
taken back to they got to party like it
was 1977.
so if you can imagine all the services
um I'm not saying anyone Josh Corman
recently uh became married
um and you go file some paperwork well
what happens if you can't access that
paperwork because Somerset County New
Jersey is partying like it's 1977 and
they're going back to hand records
so okay but not only that when you go a
little bit deeper what happens when all
right so our systems are down we're
being we're on a reservoir attack we've
table topped the out of this and oh
wait how do we communicate with each
other or how do our citizens communicate
with us oh I know what we're going to do
we're going to set up Gmail accounts for
the County Commissioners for the health
department Emergency Operations County
Clerk and Sheriff's departments we're
operating off of Gmail accounts
so
fun when you think about it so it's
taking it from this like high level oh
no we're talking about it
OT systems we're talking about risk
mitigation now we're talking about Gmail
because that's what the Playbook has so
all right what's happening in the middle
of the war room is all of this is going
down well one of the great ways to
highlight this is the great state of
North Carolina in March the governor
um had an executive order says all right
we've got the Statewide task force
because as you're in the middle of the
storm and you're thinking okay who do we
call by the way half your playbooks are
on the network you just shut down there
are some weird people like me who are
probably in your department of laws I
think where I print everything
so I'm racing to my office which was fun
and heels uh to say oh wait I think I
have hard copies of the following things
so as you're pulling all this well the
governor North Carolina says sorry we're
gonna have this executive order
everyone's going to work together we've
got this task force yeah the task force
had been in place since 2017. do you
know what no one knew it even was there
for most of the time so great we've got
all these resources who are you calling
you don't know who to call because it's
not obvious next slides please as we'll
skip over that because we're going to
jump right into the education sector
because while education attacks are
actually on the decrease decline what is
happening is the cost so we're going to
flash back real quick to save Atlanta
because we talked about insurance
earlier
um yeah great Atlanta had just gone
under our policy had just gone into
effect we had checked all the boxes I
believe we had made need one payment
towards our policy and 20 million
dollars coverage but when you talk about
schools and we're going to think of
Alice Cooper school's out for summer
well in New Jersey one of the largest
school districts in New Jersey had a
ransomware attack recently which meant
for all of the high school students they
had to cancel their exams
so if you were waiting on that exam to
lift up your grade that was going to
help you graduate so sad too bad because
when you talk about these school
districts and everything being on fire
think of what's Happening we're there
still not back these students did not
know what to do with overhead projectors
because the school district had to
utilize overhead projectors they said
well this is a great exercise in stem
because what happens when you don't have
access to it and you have to they were
able to find them so not only that but
they had no access to the online
resources where you have now put all
these great books in all of the
educational teaching materials online in
the cloud you're accessing them from
your tablet no
these students no longer had access to
that because the county had to then pull
it off but when you look at okay well
who do you call when it's the school
board the school district that's gone
down well first of all you call the
school board you call the superintendent
you call the school board you call the
school boards attorneys you also call
the State uh Bureau of Investigations
you call sza you call the FBI the doj
you also call and as I highlight on
several of these slides about six
different other agencies and if you want
to have fun you sit with your popcorn in
the back and watch all of them fight not
over who is taking the lead not only
that if anyone here has worked for a
company that represented the city of
Atlanta and our ransomware attack I
applaud you a lot of y'all led me to
drink
because we had about five different IR
teams sitting in the emergency response
room all deciding that they were going
to leave because they had a contract I
said great
sweat you all have the same contract
because that my predecessors didn't know
but we didn't plan for this we didn't
know what was going to happen we didn't
know who was going to be to leave so
everything is on fire it's even more so
on fire when you have all these County
governments municipalities School Board
attorneys and no one who knows what
they're doing nor do they have the
resource to pay for it because they
probably oh by the way accounting and
city state municipalities I think a lot
of them are self-insured
because they get to opt out of insurance
requirements so we have no pot of money
uh we have no idea how to solve the
solutions and so I now work in the
private sector once again for a startup
[Music]
so here we go thank you
thank you uh we have time for uh one
question
so if you've got one question
if you can either walk over here or wave
to Katie
and she will bring you a mic
quickly
earlier this year I started to hear
about an incident response framework
called ics for ICS
um do you have a take on that whether
it's good or bad or well
is beneficial or well yeah so yeah ics
for ICS was championed by the Vice
President of product security uh where
she at now Schneider Electric she's at
Schneider Megan Samford
um and what her idea was so she had a
background working Emergency Management
at this in the state of Virginia and the
idea that she came up with is that if
you look at how disast recovery and
Emergency Management is done with like
FEMA that it's standardized across
vocabulary and process everywhere so
when we're doing industrial control
system response what if we could
standardize that same way and so that
culminated in um with a lot of joint
agency work
um that debuted actually at S4 in Miami
in June
um so in short it's a fantastic thing
it's a great idea and there's a lot of
steam coming behind it including
training and certification
Mr Corman do you have a question I'm
just hoping that anybody that has ideas
for how to collaborate with our water
friend
um or anybody up there
empathy starts with a drink it starts
with a drink
um no beer without water
it's gonna start with empathy because
the opposite of a profound truth is not
a lie but another profound truth so
these are both dangerous outdated
systems they don't have time and money
for and we can't allow them to be that
vulnerable so if there's any coaching or
advice you can give us besides giving
you a drink uh as to how to best be
truly helpful versus you know
taxi drivers
um
I think true to the mission
um you know we all live in a community
that is being serviced by somebody
um start participating in the board
meetings and asking questions and
helping them understand what their risks
are
uh
that's that's probably one of the best
ways I could could offer up to to get
involved
and most of those who are
televised now anyway so
you know it's like any other industry
though it's you know the the email
server has a thousand percent more
availability and uptime than the than
the systems running the plant
um so they they get computer racks and
server rooms instead of the janitors
closet so
okay
um please join me in thanking our
fabulous panelists