we can use this time however we like the
original intent was
um
we had a long day of telling you how
stuff is on fire
how much has changed over the last two
years imposed an open-ended question of
how should the mission evolve
now that stuff is on fire
so we started by giving a high level
overview of what things looked like nine
years ago through now when we started
this crazy Journey
then we did a deep dive on the impact of
Health Care and vaccine Supply chains
and how this became quite urgent and
really
put a bright Spotlight on that most of
these victims in critical infrastructure
are cyber poor
and we can't just give platitudes to
and then we went through a tour de force
of how many things in critical
infrastructure are on fire the water we
drink the food we put on our table oil
and gas pipelines schools municipalities
And Timely access to Patient Care so we
are messing with Maslow's hierarchy of
needs
and uh then gave a policy update on some
of the things changing pretty much a
heavy focus on the decriminalization
research which is at Great risk we were
in The Heading the wrong direction last
when we first met here nine years ago
but now that things are on fire and the
public and public policy makers can see
that
um our original Mission was to let
people know things were flammable and
that bad things could happen were they
to catch fire
and the question I had on one extreme is
maybe it's mission accomplished and we
should all pack up and go home and have
a mission accomplished Banner probably
not
or
um we could maybe keep doing a job that
the private sector doesn't want in the
public sector is often ill-equipped to
do
I don't think that's a great
responsibility either
um so we don't have an answer to our own
question but part of it is how should
our mission evolve and change so today
was mostly stoking
things that maybe you heard about from a
distance maybe you
um
new one or two of the stories but not
all of them but now that you've been
confronted all day this is our feedback
session before tomorrow uh where you can
ask things you didn't want to ask maybe
in the larger group
um and or start brainstorming because
tomorrow we're going to try to shift
into not the answer to the question but
pieces of the answer to the question
uh and as a preview a reminder of what
tomorrow's agenda is we're going to have
Lily hey Newman from wired uh and two
other journalists talking about how
media coverage is changing out of
necessity and how we make sure
um someone's focus on the public good
and Public Safety instead of just
selling products or fear-mongering
uh followed by a deep dive into s-bomb
which is one of the biggest victories I
think we've had come out of here for
software trust and transparency in the
executive order that was just mentioned
but it's not merely about s-bomb it's
that part of the s-bomb community
decided that if something's missing from
the private sector Market that we build
free open source projects and tools to
help people be safer so maybe for these
Target rich side Rapport we're looking
at pulling in more developers or more
product designers or people that can
nominate use cases that could help these
Target Rich cyberpore that are
underserved and under increasing attack
um so tomorrow's kind of a dual thing
for s-bomb it's going to be showing you
what they did to make this uh manifest
sooner
but also hopefully Inspire maybe there's
a solution for wastewater treatment
maybe there's a different set of
solutions for uh under invested health
care or for the food supply maybe
somebody can say I'm I'm not happy that
there's no food supply ISAC we should
start one
um or we should start some communities
of Interest or special interest groups
so tomorrow's stimulating some ideation
of things that Cavalry hasn't tried and
then we're going to Pivot into
how to make uh OT and ICS things
relevant to Business Leaders as opposed
to technical people and one of the ones
I'm really looking forward to is we have
Ray Davidson from Michigan who has a
pilot in the state of Michigan for
hackers collaborating with their state
and we have the Cyber peace Institute
looking at how they've studied many
experiments like the Michigan experiment
across the US and across the planet to
see which things are working and there's
other initiatives like the Cyber threat
intelligence league so that's I lovingly
call that the act locally act globally
session because I think we're going to
have to scale up and down and sideways
um and Federate this model so it's a
little less dependent on
um
10 Central voices and and more on the
2000 plus that are growing in our
assistance and I think it's going to be
pulling in new types of teammates
and then we want to have a brainstorming
session for like a good two hours to see
what we might want to try because we may
have some big decisions to make
including hiring a professional staff
which we've never taken a penny so that
would be a scary move for us
or um merging with some other existing
initiatives or
um
there's a lot of options at the table
but I want maybe the best option will
come from you so right now is not so
much to design them all
but to hear uh Audi and some of the
others know that I have a thing that
every time I give a talk I don't want to
just hear hey that was a good talk I
want to ask three basic questions what
was the strongest thing the weakest
thing and the key takeaway
um so similarly whether it's that's too
structured or whatnot like what
surprised you today and I'm gonna stop
flapping my gums here but I want to hear
from you
what was the most surprising part or I
think I understood why you talked about
water but I don't you never connected
the pieces so maybe we missed the mark
on our intended message
but I really want to make sure that uh
people understand that we
we're starting to see a lot more harm
manifest on the things we've been
warning about
there's very few people willing and able
to do anything about that and For Better
or For Worse this community besides and
on slack and on the two intertubes has
been the voice of reason catalyzing
safer outcomes sooner working with great
teammates like Leonard and uh others in
the executive branch and internationally
and whatnot so I don't think the work is
done but I am
I carry a humility of not knowing what
to do next and would like to hear from
each of you what resonated the most the
least and as we head into tomorrow it
may help us emphasize or punctuate and
refine the message
so
hey Jen we have a first question yeah
there's a mic being passed around
strongest thing weakest thing you take
away missing piece
uh
um I am not an unbiased third party but
I will tell you
what was stunning to me and here I'm
staring very hard
and a representative of the Department
of Justice
uh
Market concentration
I would suggest
leads to the rich get richer and the
poor get nothing
as a general matter
when two big forces joined together they
write fancy words to the Department of
Justice that says
don't worry
we are definitely going to
we will help pricing for consumers
there'll be no harm to Consumers those
are the fancy words that are written
as a matter of practice though I would
suggest that in general what we see
is we see
the top one percenters
make a bucket of money
the little people
generally get a kick in the teeth but
fundamentally
the risk is concentrated into
fewer and fewer larger and larger
players
that lead to
uh
uh a risk reward that ends up harming
consumers
um
rather than turning this into an
accidental q a for a gutty
um
can we do like a speed round of like
feedback and once I hear some themes
I'll I'll baby pose some questions to
all of us yeah
speed round
um first just submit general education
like something we could probably talk
about later is you know are you
organized are you an actual
non-profit or whatever your business
organization is second
um the thing that I see is is somewhat
similar to what you're saying David but
I think the opportunity exists in the
underuserved communities for an
organization like this to do the
greatest good
um in fact you know cities and and
things like Jackson Mississippi that's
that's going through a terrible Water
Crisis
because they've been completely defunded
um
through an overall fault of their own
but need all that support so that's
that's what kind of my personal mission
is you know the the big cities don't
need the help it's a little it's a
little guys that need to help
okay I'm hearing some uh recognition of
one of our themes of the cyberpore the
have-nots thank you
um so I attend these conference
as someone who's married to a technical
person
I went to the first Defcon for my first
Defcon was four
um I've been
I'm a I'm more aligned with in the last
seven years with what's going on
politically in my local community
and the one question that I always ask
in any conference in any
taught is who isn't in this room
and we still see a bunch of older white
men maybe some younger white men and a
few women
I saw like I counted today like four
black people
um I'm Native American I don't present
brown but I'm always looking
for the people that aren't here from
these underrepresented communities
because I can tell you they don't even
know what the hell is going on
uh they don't even feel like they have
any access if they own a computer
they're like afraid to use it because
they don't want to break it
so um as a speech and debate coach I
mean a former DOD employee but now a
speech and debate coach
um I am looking at ways to reach out to
our community Through the youth I have
so many parents that come to me when
they're kid they see finally their child
give a speech or they go to a tournament
and they're just like overwhelmed and
they're like I wish I could do that and
I could literally tell them give me two
hours and I don't care if English is
your first language so I see this access
thing going on with there are a lot of
problems out there there are a lot of
Creative Solutions that nobody ever
thought about because they haven't hung
out with someone in the from Jackson
Mississippi that is trying to work on
their Water Crisis they haven't worked
out on they haven't actually like been
on the reservations where people are
likely to have electricity I can tell
you that Native American access to
Internet is very low and I'm just
assuming that a lot of poor rural
communities it is so I've been working
with my state and the FEDS trying to
make
um get the idea out there that internet
should be a public utility for one thing
and therefore something that is funded
by the government and accessible to all
Americans the way that we started the um
electric co-ops I believe in the 30s to
get electricity to the rural communities
so that's where I'm going with this is
people need to know that this is even a
thing
and and it's the Outreach and I'm really
excited about hearing about the group in
Michigan I am because that's that's the
kind of thing that I'm trying to push
and then when they were talking today I
thought about 10 different ways you
could get in touch with your Congress
people and be effective so just saying
that I think that um that you've all
been focused on what's good and bad with
the internet and I think that it needs
to be accessible to a lot more people
and I agree that these very very large
companies a reminiscent reminiscent of
Ma Bell of the 70s when they broke up
the phone companies right
um we're just back where we've always we
always go we always like get the very
very rich holding on to all of the stuff
and
I would like to see the communities
taking some of the power back okay
is this oh go ahead so hey so I've I've
got some uh perspective as well
um
for a long time I've said that every
company is a tech company it's just most
of them don't know it
um from the conversation like today I
think that every
um every division of the government is a
tech division they just don't know it so
the I firmly believe that iot is an
environmental issue that we actually the
EPA should be regulating iot because the
two people that are involved the
purchaser and the manufacturer have no
incentive to protect the internet
like the it's cheaper to buy to buy a
cheap video camera or or VCR than it is
to buy one that's secure and the people
making it are buying a budget like
usually third party putting in things
with root access and back doors not even
caring because they're just selling it
for the most profit so like so this is
literally like the Mariah Bots like
Mariah botnet is an example of what
comes when you pollute the internet
but this is just one example right like
we've any other like the Federal Trade
Commission like any of those those all
need to be tech savvy Because the
Internet is creating the new framework
for how we Define the world
and if we allow these things to be built
wrong then we have all these riddles
with holes like you wouldn't let someone
build a bridge where people kept driving
off the sides
all right that's that's my rant but uh I
work in a Fortune 500 company I care
about these things yeah while you hand
the mic one of the slides I skipped this
morning because I took too long uh
I said there's no Zeitgeist like you
might have heard Christoph say the
rugged software Manifesto from like I
think it's 12 years ago now I don't know
I can't remember when we did it but
um I said what's the Zeitgeist or what's
the Hippocratic Oath for software
developers and I put up uh zuckerberger
saying move fast to break things
I'm like including democracy sometimes
and then I also showed uh Reed Hoffman
which is a lesser known for hackers but
very popular for startups which is
um if you're not embarrassed
by your your product the day you
launched you waited too long
and I showed the the Tacoma Narrows
Bridge and I said imagine if the people
who built our skyscrapers and our
bridges said if you're not embarrassed
by the riveting the day you open the
bridge and we are we are creating
digital infrastructure software
developers are and hand in glove with
security and risk management
professionals or threat modelers we do a
lot more to protect Enterprises and data
than we do to protect infrastructure in
humans and part of the Zeitgeist the
Cavalry was to shift things to what is
more important
um I'm gonna try to shorten this to
protect the innocent and give the mic to
the next person but um I gave a keynote
in New York City about the the kova task
force about two three weeks ago three
weeks ago now I think
and um the guy that came before me
was talking about we need less focus on
ransomware and this other stuff what we
really need to focus on is data
and intellectual property and and it was
a vendor it was a vendor
saying things that they can help with
which is not in itself wrong
but one of the analogies I used
probably better than I'm going to say it
right now is if you're walking down the
streets after a show tonight and you get
mugged and they say your wallet your
life I hope that you would prioritize
properly
but we don't and I said with HIPAA you
have more incentive to have a corpse of
their privacy intact there's no
incentive to protect patient care
there's only regulation to protect the
data
and then we give away for free anyhow
when we relax things for the pandemic so
I would like to see at least this
community especially because we are
bridge Builders and we're
multi-disciplinary in nature
to help people understand the
consequences and the proportional
dependence we should have
um so something you just said really
resonated with me which is If all we're
doing is responding to bad
indefensible unreliable infrastructure
then we're never gonna
change anything so that's why we really
push hard on software Bill and materials
offer transparency threat modeling
patchability according to disclosure
we're trying to build an ecosystem that
can anticipate and avoid failure respond
quickly to failure remove any sort of
chilling effect or disincentives there
it doesn't mean we've got it all figured
out but I think focusing on a few
Primitives a more dependable trustworthy
transparent maintainable
digital infrastructure is a good
instinct
we just need better reach and and faster
um
all right uh I don't want to put
everyone in the spot there's a couple I
haven't spoken is anyone else have Ray
you came in the room or
um you're gonna speak tomorrow about
ah okay
the Zeitgeist for tomorrow yeah
all right any other feedback yeah um so
my name is Maurice I work for the US
government usaid uh the foreign
assistance agency and so I missed the
very beginning of your rant but it's
very relevant and uh apropos to the work
that we are doing as we are pushing
digital Technologies around the world
right uh what is the Do no harm or
relevance there in terms of ensuring
that what we're putting people's hands
is secure or as secure as possible and
it's something that we uh as an agency
as an organization are getting smart
about
um my comments on uh or thoughts on kind
of I'm the Cavalry and how it's evolving
I'm really interested to understand the
appetite of membership on
thinking uh critical infrastructure plus
um so looking at
um either spaces that are not
traditional critical infrastructure so
like Independent Media which is under
assault around the world how do we work
with media organizations to ensure their
security or at least Independence
um or thinking about uh Beyond just The
Operators uh of CI is thinking about the
users and the individuals kind of
Downstream uh that may also be or are
very security poor and not in the US but
then around the world as well over
anybody else
so since since I was invited
um the a thing that I have heard that I
really like is the think globally act
locally kind of kind of aspect and I
think one of the common themes that that
I heard I have heard and I want to
encourage is thinking of uh this is part
of the Zeitgeist probably is thinking of
the end user or the the individual human
being that is affected and how they're
affected and trying to make the link
between the technology that we're that
we're implementing and how it's going to
affect people in their daily lives when
they don't think about it
because that's what we have to think
about is I I loved the Apple Macintosh
operating system when it came out back
in 85 well that was when I got my first
computer because it was the operating
system that just worked and it really
did so we have to we have to make it
people don't want to think about this
stuff so if we think about it then then
that's our job
thank you
anybody else
hey I'm John boss I don't I probably
haven't met most of the people in here
although I've I'm sure I've probably
seen your faces if you've seen mine even
though you can't tell who I am right now
uh I go by boss man online
I've been going to Defcon
Etc since
I don't know sometime back in the Lexus
Park maybe nine Defcon nine mostly CTF
School of Road stuff like that um
I still feel like I'm being up to speed
with what you're doing and what you're
saying I like it every time I hear you
talk or see you do something I think
it's cool and I want to get more
involved I just feel I don't really feel
like I have a lot to add other than to
say and like
the movement and I like what you're
doing and I'm and I'm trying to be
involved I feel like I'm not the right
com sales I don't know but uh I feel
like I should at least tell you who I am
since I'm sitting in here and why so if
anybody like to talk to me about
anything or if you have any questions
I'd love to answer it but for now I'm
really just a spectator
thank you and one of the things I think
while we've done a lot right we we have
not
been creative on creating shovel ready
jobs for everybody we we certainly want
um a meritocracy and a stone soup and
we've been delighted and surprised by
people that bring something we never
even thought of so we like to be open to
those possibilities
uh but there's a whole bunch of folks
that do want to help and we haven't made
it as easy as we could and I think that
may include if we did invest in some
back office or some professional staff I
believe that would improve
um Kendra for example if you were here
all day um from the ciscover task force
I didn't know her at all when she joined
the task force and uh she doesn't have a
hacking background and she brought such
organizational op Tempo and rigor and
tenacity for getting around
bureaucracies and almost a delight for
hacking bureaucracies that it's like my
kryptonite but like the more people we
find like that they're good at the
things we're bad at and we find that we
are able to do new things
um so that middle ground of people that
are Avid supporters but don't yet know
how to contribute
um I'm sure we could uh invest in that
and probably need to at this point to
get better scale
um anybody else I'm gonna try to
synthesize a few of these themes
um just a couple other follow-ups
um
as a licensed professional engineer
uh
um
certifications don't mean anything
they're they're something you buy and
you study for and you right there's no
there's no legal backing to them there's
no liability back into them
there's probably no propensity or even a
pathway to get to a licensed model
but I think there's a lot of good things
that come that can come from that
organizations that you know the National
Society of Professional Engineers that
you know we evolved from it a long time
ago and there was a better place for
that but your your discussion around the
Tacoma's Bridge things like that
you know
as Professional Engineers we don't play
in the money space we play in the
qualification space right so you're not
gonna you're not gonna lowball a number
to build a building is going to be
qualifications based so
there might be something there I I it's
it's more it's turned into such a legal
mess now
um I don't know but just throwing ideas
out there
um you know my my duty is to the public
before it is to my even to my employer
that's an oath that I signed right when
I become a licensed professional
engineer so
um isn't there a ring that some
Engineers wear yeah yeah
order the engineer yep
um the other part was as just as a
practitioner I'm I'm very concerned
about the number of
Point solutions that are out there
and the the harm that that's going to
cause
a lot of my clients are buying stuff
and
they've already bought stuff that'll do
what that does but that sales guy did a
better job of selling that feature than
the other guy did so
I'm if there's something we can do
around that that that would be huge
because there's there's a lot of
software out there that can do a lot of
stuff if we know how to use it
and uh and deploy it properly
um on that last point I'm just going to
play jazz a little bit
um I wanted to synthesize many themes
but I I will forget this one if I don't
say it right now
um
this is a partial thought
I don't want to be crucified even on the
streaming for saying this but I have
increasingly
even when I started this thing even when
before it with the rugged idea
I felt that there was really two cybers
there was the commercial low consequence
private interest local harm
and then the public good and I I always
felt that what's right for the private
good is not what's right for the public
good and even if you just truncate the
public good for a minute
um a lot of my prior rate uh ranting and
advocacy was
you know I said like Tron I fight for
the user uh and I felt like most vendors
were trying to trick cisos and separate
them from their money or that we got our
education on the bad stuff from the
people selling you the anti-bad stuff so
we already had perverse incentives at
failed markets and whoever said
incentives today give yourself a Pat in
the back because this is an incentives
problem we have Technical Solutions for
a lot of these things we know how to
eliminate SQL injection we have we
haven't incentivized it right
that we have some hard technical
problems but right now the constraint is
usually a lack of carrots and sticks
in fact we Define cyberpore the long
definition of cyberpore when I put into
policy stuff was uh one or more of the
following deficiencies insufficient
information and awareness and or
insufficient carrots and sticks or
incentives
and or insufficient resources
and many of these owners and operators
are critical infrastructure that are
really the government's job that have
been
delegated to the private sector
um we this public prior Partnerships now
got in the way because we've delegated
the operations but the government's
still responsible for public good so
what happens when you have a fiduciary
local responsibility to your
shareholders that's in conflict with the
public good of access to critical
infrastructure so there's some
uncomfortable conversations we had there
but back to this notion of do we have a
tale of two cybers
um I'm at I'm at this point I'm at hell
yes and I don't know what to do about it
well I knew what I do know is some of
our best and most talented hackers
researchers
and innovators many of them didn't even
get a college uh High School degree let
alone a college degree so we are a bit
there's a bit of an anti-intellectual
anti-professionalism bent also where
chaotic and rebellious and that's what
makes it so special
um
it's part of our power and right not but
and
um I there have been a couple attempts
in the UK and in Europe to add some
minimum professionalization requirements
for certain things
um and it causes convulsions amongst our
friends but we are invited to
participate in these conversations and
an embryonic idea I've had
is perhaps we should start to opt in
have an opt-in consequential cyber
security
uh designation where if you want to pop
off and rant and just try to sell your
wares or sell your services you're
perfectly fine to do it do that but if
you want a different if someone wants to
differentiate themselves as focused on
public good or consequential cyber
security then by opting into that
verified error you know you may be more
called upon
by Congress or by committees or whatnot
but but and you're opting into with
great celebrity comes great
responsibility and perhaps we could opt
into a professional conduct
class where
we're not just giving a hot take
or giving a conference stock that you
know precedes a sales pitch
but um we can differentiate those
focused on the private good versus the
public good and sometimes it will be
overlap but often some of our best
traditional speakers and thought leaders
and luminaries are giving
increasingly horrible
advice about Public Safety horrible
and um I don't think they're bad people
I think we should just be able to
differentiate when a public policy maker
is saying what should I do I'm hearing
competing things we should have a way to
distinguish what's good for the company
versus what's good for society
I don't have the answer but I think
we're increasingly coming to the point
where there's not just one cyber
industry
hi Leonard hello Mr Corman um it's
sort of an outsider I I do want to bring
a question to you because I think you
are used to thinking about impossible
things and coming up with creative
approaches
one problem I see in the policy space in
particular is
um working in an area where there aren't
any any metrics
there are things that become your
proxies for for metrics
um you know whether you successfully
promulgated a policy for example
okay sorry but the um
it seems that the
the question really is are we safer
right that's the question we we need to
be asking at the end of the day and
sometimes the policy maybe would make us
safer
um sometimes it would have made us safer
two years ago but it the lead time to
get the policy actually
you know
enacted
made it sort of more abund by the time
it was and maybe it would never have
made us safer but
I've always struggled with the question
at the end of the day
are we are we safer now
um and that seems to be the question we
especially in this space need to be
asking and I don't know how to answer it
all right I I'm taking a leap here and
this might not be your intention
um
I'll give you the clinical protoscience
answer and then I'll give you the
personal answer
and I'm smiling because I feel like
maybe you're trolling me a little bit
but um I don't think you are because you
look because there's there's love here
um
we all want a science we all want
metrics uh and you even heard Hoff you
know mentioning some of that this
morning if you oh you came late that's
right so in the keynote we heard some of
this you know
we don't really have good metrics yet
we're not good measurement and and some
people like Alex Hutton and Sierra the
Society of information risk into people
and people like Bob rudis or you know
the data scientists that are in our
field there's ways to measure anything
but we just
we were rushing so fast to do number
based things we went from faith-based
security to numerology you know faith in
random numbers
and we don't have
good reliable consistent metrics for
these things and I know that's not
exactly what you're asking but but the
more people get into that they quickly
discovered Thomas Coons which is the
structure of Scientific Revolution and
you don't go from like chaos and Buddha
and Witchcraft straight to you know NASA
science there's things like protoscience
in between and we do use proxies and we
use indicators or confidence building
measures or these things strongly
correlate to a better outcome so for
example that's what I focused on with
our hippocratical for connected medical
devices and the five-star Automotive
Safety framework was let's not write
policy like the PCI standard for credit
cards which is stale by the time the ink
is dried
but rather focus on Evergreen
capabilities to handle and respond to
failure so a device that is not
patchable is less safe than when it is
batchable forever not not like 10 years
from now but forever things like a
program that has a coordinated
vulnerability disclosure a company that
has according disclosure program is more
likely to learn of faults from
friendlies versus adversaries so that's
a confidence building measure things
like
um
can you produce a software bill of
materials if you can't that tells us
something about the rigor of your design
or your implementation and having one
doesn't make you unhackable it just
means you're in an Echelon now where
you're more conscious and aware of
managing these things so we're I think
we're in that middle ground of we do not
have confidence that we are
quantitatively safer but we are trying
to get to that produce past the voodoo
and Witchcraft or high priestesses and
Priests and you know sacrificial goats
towards
um
confidence building measures and
Primitives that allow us to be in the
game now the reason I smiled on the
personal note is for some people that
have known me before the Cavalry I gave
a talk
called are we getting better
why we don't know and what we could do
about it and that was before my mom got
sick and
my life changed
but if you go back and watch it which it
was focused on almost exactly your
question you can see how
the fertile soil for the Cavalry being
born was already there I just needed the
nudge
um but even now a decade later
uh it's very hard to answer are we
getting better but the ways I tried to
answer that are do we have more or fewer
adversaries
do we have larger or smaller harms do we
have
um
you know better or worse recovery times
you know so there are some ways you
could quantify and measure overall
impact performance and consequence
analysis even if you can't do the causal
linkages between this security purchase
leads to these better outcomes my
general belief is we are incredibly
prone
we've been in uh prey and we survived at
the appetite and activity of the
Predator's discretion and that I think
is exactly what's happening right it's
not like critical infrastructure all of
a sudden became unsafe it's that there
has been more Brazen and aggressive
activity
uh with Advanced Revolution where the
unavailability of anything can be
monetized and this is where I said this
morning maybe too quickly I think the
key dilemma here is the adversaries have
found a way to monetize the Cyber poor
defenders in the RSA or black hat have
not figured out how to monetize a
cyberpore
and given incentives are purely
Financial right now
follow the money there's no money and
actually I've actually heard VCS Turning
Away innovators from this community that
are trying to help the cyberport
hospitals I said you should pick a
different industry there's no money in
it
and that is the correct thing to do for
shareholders it is not the correct thing
to do for society and um so we need more
public good cyber
and we're not currently differentiating
those speakers those thought leaders
those initiatives for who's focused on
public good versus private good
sometimes they're the same advice but
oftentimes increasingly they're not
so I it's not even a close answer to
your question but it's
um these are things I wrestle with
because we aren't gonna
make progress or strides unless we know
what we're solving for whom we're for
whom we're solving and and the whole
Spirit of things like SOS and bad
practices and the free
system Services was to meet people where
they are
not giving platitudes
and some of those things are hard right
I recognize the contradiction I'm here I
am saying let's meet people where they
are where they have no resources and no
staff and I'm saying by the way it's a
really bad dangerous negligent practice
to run unsupported software what if you
don't have enough money to do anything
but unsupported Exchange Server I
recognize that apparent contradiction
but I'm sick of watching it happen and I
said let's at least stimulate and force
the hard conversations
um little inside baseball I guess while
I'm running on that thread
my key inflection point to cause bad
practices there was several reasons I
wanted to do it but the key moment was
when the Microsoft Exchange attacks were
happening everywhere Bob root is Chief
data scientist at the time at rapid
seven scanned the whole internet and was
looking for which versions of exchange
were out there so we could see
you know if people were patching he
wasn't looking for
how bad is it out there he was just
trying to see what are the patch rates
by version
and sisa Hill the public call saying
uh with Microsoft saying here's the
patches do you have any questions you
know how much exploitation is there
and when all this all the broadcasting
was done and the question started
rolling and people said well what am I
going to get my patches
and they said what do you mean we
already went through that and they said
well I'm running this version
and Bob quickly looked in his data and
the number one market share of exchange
on the Internet is unsupported
it's not an edge case it's everywhere
and I at the time made an emotional joke
and said we almost needed child
protective services that if you can't
take care of exchange we'll take care of
it for you by you know rolling you on to
you know at least Office 365 or or
Google Suite or something
and we went to some of the well-funded
hospitals I'm like you seem to be among
these ranks that are running wildly
unsupported you realize that if you're
compromised or exchanged the whole
Hospital's gone
and they said
Josh it would cost like a million
dollars to migrate we're never gonna do
that and it was sincere and I should
have empathy for their resource
constraints
and it's dangerous so what do you do
when it's common and dangerous so
this meeting people where they are thing
um it's not going to be take a
product designed for the fortune 50.
that only the Fortune 50 can use and
hope that eventually helps them down
Market if you require an army of
talented Engineers to operate it it's
not it's not a solution set
so I think the answer is going to be
when you're over dependent on a
Dependable things there's at least two
parallel paths one is depend less upon
them so wherever you can reduce your
dependence and act attack surface we
should
and
depend more uh demand more from your
suppliers that these things are that are
maintained and operated I mean et cetera
and then in the glue in the bridge in
between I'm kind of hoping tomorrow
reveals is can we make some open source
projects that are designed for the
cyberpore for people with limited staff
for the internet attack surface because
while anybody can get hacked most of
these ransoms for critical
infrastructure have not been targeted
they've been wholesale you know Kill
Everybody
Harvest later who we're going to
actually spring the trap on
um and if you can maybe take yourself
out of that low-hanging fruit pool it
might be the difference between water or
no water or Healthcare or no health care
for a bit and that's not the end of the
journey it's the starting line but if
you want to get people from here to
there they cannot kind of do it like
that we have to have a
a crawl walk run right Jen
uh it's part of Josh Corman Bingo cards
um okay so that was a long
improvisational stream of Consciousness
trying to string together several things
said here but I hope you heard that the
cyberpore is where I I'm feeling more
focused not just all critical
infrastructure but the sad rapport
uh and that they don't have the tools
the education or the assistance required
and perhaps we can help with that I
would like sister to do that I would
like HHS and EPA to do that I do not
perceive them to be willing and able to
do that job at the scale required yet
um so I'd like to help them get there
versus do it for them or watch it fall
and so perhaps we can be
public good augmentation
with initiatives like race that you're
going to hear about tomorrow
all right who else we have a little more
time anybody
oh before you go
because you might want to comment on it
I didn't want to completely respond to
your first thing you said but there's an
interesting dichotomy when I looked
across the 16 critical infrastructure
sectors if you take banking out of it
with banking the biggest players are the
most important the risk Aggregates
proportional to their size for the most
part
but for a lot of things like water it's
very diffuse
so what is it would you say 90 of the
water in the country is done by 10
percent of the municipalities
and it has a long tail for the
um others same thing with hospitals you
have the 15 that have a good staff of 50
people or more
and then everybody else has zero people
so um
not every one of these critical
infrastructures has cyberpore but
there's a dichotomy with risk
concentration because when you only have
four meat packing facilities
any one of them getting infected has an
asymmetric impact on everybody else
right
uh the downside of all these diffuse
Federated Target recycler poor is that
we don't really have a strategic
leverage point to make broad
improvements so uh channeling my inner
Dan gear uh monocultures are bad
and nature loves diversity but there can
be too much diversity so I don't think
we're gonna have a single TurnKey answer
for this but in some cases consolidation
is a is a good move in other cases we've
gone too far with it and my real fear
for healthcare specifically is that the
financial solvency of hospitals has been
further challenged by not having
elective surgeries and things and by
blowing all their r d money on Traveling
Nursing budgets and bonuses
so if we were already trending to Too
Much consolidation to too few
it's about to get worse in the aftermath
of the pandemic so we may see just
economic
survival the fittest kind of problems
worsen the consolidation that you're
referring to so I don't know that we
want to do the mama Bell breakups and
things like that but I think as a
national resilience strategy for
critical infrastructure specifically and
for things that affect the public good
we should have some deliberate
first principles that guide what is
healthy consolidation versus over
consolidation and how to make sure that
a resilient National critical function
is one that is not has have excessive
aggregated risk so it's I don't think
it's a no aggregation I don't think it's
a pure Federation
um I think in certain areas we have too
much concentration of risk food supply
is one that scares me
and I think in other areas we're too
diffuse
we had the 10-minute Warning by the way
um thanks for that
it's a it's a hard problem right so uh
there's there there is not really a
silver bullet one of the things I wonder
about
is
so when we think about
water on my water guy left
[Music]
um we when we're still thinking about
when we think about water we think about
municipalities we think about States
think about ciso what I'm wondering is
can we get
more people into the room and so here
I'm thinking about like
MSI sac
and in ciso to be able to
share the
share the information down into Biloxi
Mississippi and
small town from underserved State X
to
we we got a lot of different Frameworks
and a lot of different players in the
space but how can
how can we be smarter about
sharing
really good information
with what our historically the have-nots
um
I'm going to caveat this with I'm a bit
jaded after my federal service but I
found that the public-private
partnership
maybe with the best of intention
places a lot of confidence that the ice
acts and the sector according councils
represent all their members
but maybe by accident
they tend to be very dominated by the
well-funded
um they have cisos they have systems who
can spend
an hour a week or more on these
committees and phone calls
um so at least for most of the ones I
interacted with
um they'd probably in good faith believe
that they're helping the Cyber poor but
I had to keep helping and reminding them
that they weren't um and I and I'm not
there to do it every day anymore
um
so I believe we're gonna have to augment
the current definition and scope of the
public-private partnership although you
did call out one of the best ones the
MSI Sac the multi-state ice Act
um which is operated by the CIS the
center for Internet Security
um they
and the election security you know wing
of what happened there
um
out of necessity they tend to be more
focused on what might look like
cyberpore so I think they're more
attuned to the mission of all the ice
Acts
um
and as I indicated if you weren't in the
room all day there is no food supply
Isaac
there's a it ISAC special interest group
of a handful of players and that's it
so
um
whereas most the ice acts meet weekly
with their Federal Partners these there
isn't one to meet annually
so
and there is as you presented in your
session significant concentration of
risk
and if you combine concentration of risk
of the entities with where they sit in
the overall supply chain take the ball
bearings analysis that Michelle talked
about and your Consolidated risk point
and it makes me incredibly uncomfortable
at your turn
so I'd like to Pivot off of that
slightly the going back to perverse
incentives
um if you look at the U.N the hum the
human rights committee it's like
entirely made up of countries that have
horrible human rights records right like
like almost uniformly like if you if you
stack ranked it and inverted the stack
rank you it would be like The Who's Who
of like all the bad company other
countries so in the same way we we don't
have the right way like the people that
care the most about an issue are the
ones that benefit from the issue
and and most of the time that's going to
be the wrong people so so we need to
have like values-based positions and we
need to have like was coming from those
like perspectives we can't do it based
on who's gonna profit because they're
the people that do or almost always
going to be the wrong ones
um Goldman Sachs was recently in the
news I believe for saying something
about why are we trying to solve disease
when we can just cure it kinda
um you know if you heal people they
don't come back
so so keeping them dependent on you is
the way to like keep making money and
that's that's you know so it's like like
why would you make the infinite like
light bulb when you can keep selling
people new light bulbs right so I think
that the government does have some
reason to step in when it comes to the
greater good when there's not a
financial incentive because capitalism
Etc et cetera
um so so that's something where we do
need to think about what is what is the
policy we want and how does that help
guide the the checks and balances and
provide the incentives so that we say we
know you're gonna like
make insulin for cheap and like here's
how we're gonna make it worthwhile to
you to do it instead of charging a
thousand dollars a shot
uh hand in the back fit
we're in the five minute warning section
but we can keep talking tomorrow and
even at the bar tonight
to answer the previous one I don't think
that anybody can question whether or not
our security is better
because I remember back whenever we were
just trying to get people to actually
have a firewall
and nobody even questions that now I
also remember ciso's nobody even knew
what the hell it was and
you know now that now we're having
questions as to whether or not they
ought to be on the board or not you know
so we're at least moving in the right
direction whether or not it's enough is
why you're having a hard time getting
the metrics because it's not are we
making progress we are it's just isn't
enough and that's that's a different
question so that's that's one of the
things to help with that
but one of the things I'm listening to
everybody
it's culture
we all know the number one thing that is
difficult as hell to get anything to
change is the culture because people
hate change
I had an argument with a guy whenever I
first got into the Navy about whether or
not people like change knows also 20
years old and wanted change so I thought
change everybody wanted it no they don't
and culture is what is holding us back
I have dealt with a lot of HIPAA and uh
the problem with the medical areas is
the culture you walk in the door and the
first thing they do is ask you what your
social is in front of a room full of
people
what's your name what's your social
nobody the culture there has gotten us
so that we are used to thinking about
I got if I want my leg my leg broke you
know my broke leg fixed I got to give
out my social security number or else I
got problems and that's a culture that
that's just what they think about the
the military has the same issue I can't
go in and get anything from the military
without starting off with my last four
which is the only random part of it
and giving that the culture is is the
problem
and to your point whenever it comes to
government being able to regulate stuff
the fact is is that these the culture
behind water
it's not going to change because they
literally have no incentive which is I
think where you were going earlier they
have no incentive to change unless
somebody's going to go beat them up and
give them money for it
carrots and sticks or carrot shapes but
you know whenever it comes down to it
it's not just the money
it's America we got we got money
but the culture does not want us to
change
would you agree with that or I mean is
that it seems like yes I think it's
culture I do think it's incentives and I
think that's one of the reasons we
brought a lot of heart and empathy to
this instead of facts and figures I mean
the tax figures come as well
um and maybe just to end on a
it's a hard pivot from what you're
saying but maybe to pull some of these
things together in a positive note when
I ask what what did the world look like
nine years ago and what does it look
like now
um we were training towards increased
chilling effect on good faith research
we're in training towards
uh increased animosity uh between
government Partners in the hacking
Community we were increasing our
dependence on medical devices and cars
that were hackable
um and now you know the last nine years
as we skim the Treetops from this
morning
um
we have
every Federal agency has has a
coordinated disclosure program we have
an exception the dmca for good faith
research Leonard a a very bad
oversimplification what he was saying is
doj put out guidance to the State
Attorney General saying please pass on
Prosecuting good faith researchers
um
directionally similar to the dmca we
have initiating catalyze the first ever
set of safety Communications and recalls
for medical devices with no Adverse
Events or patients dying first so very
left a boom we were called upon uh when
there was Congressional actions on
things like Waste Water treatment on
things like ICS Sprints and to help
design and lead the cobit response for
the pandemic for hospitals so I I think
our level of Engagement is higher the
level of trust is higher
the level of
Common Sense first principles to be
patchable to avoid hard-coded passwords
to get things in executive orders
domestically and internationally we
didn't talk enough about International
Partners but sometimes when we hit an
obstacle in the U.S we go to our UK
Partners or our Japanese Partners or
emea Partners or and and we're kind of
flanking with a conspiracy of excellence
and I would not say these victories are
mission accomplished because in parallel
with those incredible breakthroughs
we have seen unprecedented adversary
activity and more Embrace and embolden
so
um I I said this in my Senate testimony
along with it here
um our adversaries have set the pace
we gotta catch up
right so yes we've done a lot of good
things there's much much more to do and
we need the political will and the
courage to do so and that means we're
gonna have to speak on a very human
level a very multi-stakeholder level a
very accessible level
and we're gonna have to
take people in uncomfortable areas
because these are the moments in the
Overton's window if you know that term
where there is political will to do
something and get outside the comfort
zone and challenge their conventional
preferences
and sometimes it takes really bad events
to catalyze really good progress and I
think we're on the cusp of that in some
areas but how this community that
started here nine years ago with
parallel companion efforts and sister
efforts um
you know we have a lot more to do so I'm
really really tired and I think a lot of
you are as well and
and let's finish the job so tomorrow
bring your best ideas any game and let's
let's figure out how to take this to the
next level thank you for your time today
all right thanks Josh uh and thanks
everyone I found that personally uh
really fascinating and uh I'd like to
thank Josh but also thank all you guys
for your input because I am taking a lot
away from uh from this but uh yeah make
sure you are here tomorrow we're kicking
off at 10 30. I believe uh in this room
uh Meet the Press sub is pretty well now
so gonna be another fascinating day so
thank you all for coming thanks for your
participation uh thank you Josh and uh
we look forward to seeing you all
tomorrow if not
at the bar today