our first speaker to kick us off in this
first return to in person besides las
vegas
is someone you probably know way better
than me
uh
he's someone many of you have probably
had announced the changes of your
careers in your lives ladies and
gentlemen please welcome chris hoff or
beaker to the stage
good morning
i thought i got out of this with the
speaker not working but unfortunately
it is
can you guys hear me okay with this bane
mask on yeah
all right fabulous
let's see let's see if this can get this
to work
all right cool so uh they asked me for
an abstract for this talk which is what
the
line underneath the fraudulence is i
took a word cloud of words out of words
out of my presentation and threw it at
them so it actually means nothing the
title fraudulence is a mashup of two
words fragile and resistant and
resilience
and there are a couple of takeaways that
i'd like to establish out front about
what this talk is about and why i'm here
and what i want you to take away from it
the first is i have not been able to
publicly speak in seven years that's
what happens when you get subsumed by a
risk-averse financial institution
so uh not only is it b-sides back but uh
i'm very thankful and grateful that i
get to
uh come up and and talk to folks and
have ultimately a set of discussions
after this um the second thing is i um
there's a bunch of points in this talk
that i think will come hopefully into
into uh cognition as we as we
run through it but it's about five
different talks crammed into one so i'm
making up for for for uh for miss time
when i think about infosec there's a lot
more art
and compliance than there is science
today
uh when we do make use of science and
when i and i use that term broadly it's
often very siloed we aren't very
organized
in terms of how we take advantage of
science we don't define model or manage
risk well at all
uh we are not agile
and our definition of resilience varies
and it is insufficient this word
resilience is sort of critical to this
conversation
uh instead of resilient and you some of
you may moan or groan when you hear this
term but we ought to be anti-fragile
and anti-fragile is an interesting topic
that i'm going to get into in this talk
because it talks about both the past the
present and the future of where
information security is headed
and hopefully the thought process is
here they don't pretend i don't pretend
to be right what i do hope is that we
start a set of conversations to get
people to recognize that things aren't
quite as bad as people make them out to
be number one and we have an awful lot
more at our disposal than most people
actually recognize
so with that this is not one of those
grumpy oh my god infosec has broken
talks
um although i it sounded like it from
the introduction
but what it is is a discussion about
words so there's a bunch of words that
get used interchangeably these days
secure or security resilience uh robust
survivable recoverable defensible
certain sustainable resilient has become
or resilience has become the new
buzzword of our industry a lot of it is
because of the types of attacks and the
outcomes that have happened so when you
look at things like supply chain attacks
nation states when you look at what
we're seeing with with ransomware no
longer is it about being secure it's
about being resilient and the definition
of resilient is is interesting um if you
look at what nist defines the um
the government agency ultimately that
that defines a lot of things for us and
standards that we use
these words are important the ability to
anticipate withstand recover from and
adapt to bad things from happening
the stuff on the left which will be hard
to read but i'll give you all these
slides later it just talks about the
context so you talk about network
security nation st are you talking about
um critical infrastructure applications
people etc
the table on the right which ultimately
came from accenture was about goals and
outcomes from from the perspective of
performance characteristics of what
happens if you do resilience well so if
you look at that chart you'll see oh if
you are more resilient you will stop
more attacks you will find breaches
faster you will fix breaches faster and
you will reduce breach impact
but the the challenge with what is meant
by resilience
came to a head for me about well not me
in this fictional guy we'll call chris
uh in in let's say a financial
institution about five years ago
showed up uh chris did uh to this uh
regulator meeting where they were
talking about
a horizontal across these gcps which is
globally significant financial
institutions systemic financial
institutions there are
eight of them in the united states by
the way they're not publicly named but
you can probably guess who they are
and the question that they ran through
this in terms of scenario modeling was
uh listen we understand what you do from
a security program perspective we
understand all the controls you have etc
we want you to assume that all of your
controls have failed and you are a
smoldering pile of rubble
and you have to rebuild and recover and
restore
and they looked at me and they said what
do you do and i said besides the normal
sort of cliche you know update my resume
and crack open that bottle of bourbon
was i don't do a lot i'm an infosec
besides securing the environment in
which the owners of applications and
services would restore like i don't do
much and they said well who does and i
said the application service owners in
i.t and they turned and i watched this
imaginary turret turn towards them and
they said okay so out of all the app and
critical service owners
purportedly in this bank which you know
who's the most important and they all
raise their hands
and they said okay we're gonna pick one
payments okay payments
who's the owner me this guy says he goes
which one of the sub-component services
do you get back up and running
and of course there's like 200 of them
and he couldn't really answer the
question that kicked off a set of the
portaly uh these things called mras
matters requiring attention across all
these banks that talked about you're
doing resilience wrong
which means you need to be able to
recover rebuild within these service
level agreements to make sure there
aren't impacts to the public
at the same time in the frb that was the
us base the bank of england was talking
about no no resilience means you should
never go down in the first place
so if you if you look at what we talked
about right anticipate with staying
recover from and adapt to adverse
conditions the definition by itself even
with regulators today that drives a lot
of what people do in terms of their
security programs is out of date and the
challenge is that if we don't understand
that word and it's supposed to be the
next evolution of security how do we
even know what we're aiming for
so a couple years ago
uh whether you're a fan of him or not um
nicholas taleb came out with a book uh
titled the black swan and black swan
events are events that
in the middle of things in the fog of
war that you could not anticipate ever
happening but in hindsight you're like
oh yeah of course we could have
seen that we could have prevented that
great examples the reason we're wearing
masks
pandemic 911 uh for example the
interesting thing is in hindsight planes
crashed into buildings like the empire
state buildings like the empire state
building we've seen methods but the
motive and opportunity and outcomes are
very different so in hindsight you look
at a black swan event it's something you
can't really predict and ultimately the
outcome is much more is largely greater
than instead of being proportional with
with with the event itself and so
hindsight is a very interesting uh
uh part of that conversation because at
he he uh talab went on to write a book
called anti-fragile and what he stated
in that book was the the primary uh
uh thing uh a part of of what is the
definition of anti-fragility which is
that some things benefit from shocks
they get better they don't just recover
human bones are a great example you
break a bone your bones actually calcify
and become stronger than they were in
the in the first place so anti-fragility
which is a huge part of the conversation
we're going to have is about getting
better in the face of stressors
not just remaining the same and that you
can visualize that by looking at this
graph
uh ultimately if gain and benefit is the
y-axis and and stress and change is the
x-axis
normally what you'll see when people use
the word fragile is it's a concave
response to stress you break and you
don't get better if you look at
ultimately resistance or robustness
which is a natural response you resist
you get you get a little bit better for
time but then you go back to being how
you were ultimately if you look at
resilient you recover
for and and you get better for a while
or you improve for a while but then you
ultimately go back doing what you want
the key here is that anti-fragile
fragility is convex in response
you get better
consistently
right you actually not only just learn
but you become stronger from the
stressor
so if you look at how anti-fragility uh
is more interestingly defined on the
right you have this notion of disorder
volatility and randomness and your
responses to them so on the side of
being agile and anti-fragile you
ultimately uh embrace change and you
gain or benefit from it you you
ultimately get better you absorb shock
and get better in the face of stressors
trigger word security is ultimately
all the way to the left in the most part
which is
we try to get to at least a base level
that we feel comfortable with we don't
like change uh ultimately we don't adapt
very well we resist change if you think
about controls and you basically stay
the same not that we don't learn and
ultimately incrementally get better but
we don't fundamentally change the system
itself does not get stronger
so with that the the notion here is if
you start thinking about what that means
to our practice and our industry
um you could you could uh posit that
that infosec is actually fragile but
without sounding like that's a terrible
negative thing there's a lot of
opportunity there and in fact those
opportunities have come from decades of
work that have been done in the past so
there was a paper written in 1999
that was titled information
survivability and it basically talked
about how the world was changing uh and
on the left you can see for example
systems are centrally networked and
under organizational controls they will
transition to systems that are globally
networked with distributed control
right the internet
and without barfing things like web3
you can go down this list and really
understand that at the bottom of it it
talked about that today security is seen
as an overhead or an expense versus
survivability as an investment and
essential to the organization and that
technology it-based solutions have to
become enterprise-wide and risk-based
now we look at that today and we go well
that makes a total bunch of sense in
1999 that was sort of heresy
but the people that wrote this
thought about what it meant in the
evolution from both secure to survivable
to anti-fragile and one of the
challenges that when i looked at why we
don't or can't or have a difficult time
getting better it's we seem to conflate
these
tactical information
frameworks sort of the what
with this set of guidelines and
playbooks that are linear in action
chains the how with decision systems for
complex system problems that actually
tell us about the why when and who
now that may not make a lot of sense in
one slide but let me let me let me
clarify that today if you look at this
this sort of um spectrum of of sensors
sense making decision systems and levers
and actuators we have an enormous amount
of sensors help take whatever you want
in terms of instrumentation or
observability and define it that way in
a shotgun across the stack we have
many different sense making capabilities
lots of consoles lots of ways of single
panes of glass that ultimately allow you
to visualize what you're seeing
we tend to skip decision systems
that allow us to make decisions on risk
and instead head straight towards with
the application of some level of
automation these levers and actuators
right and you'll note the words on the
top you'll see them again later probe
and sense categorize and analyze weigh
and decide and act and respond now i'll
say having run large-scale security
operations teams being able to have the
time and luxury
to make decisions in the fog of war is a
very difficult thing but a lot of that
has to do with the velocity the volume
and the quality of the data we capture
in the first place and we're going to
get into that in a little bit because
we're going to focus on the fact that
the reason i posit that we are largely
fragile
and not anti-fragile is that we don't
take time to invest in decision systems
to actually make risk-based decisions
in fact just the opposite
this is just a small sampling from a
company name a reseller called optiv and
these are the products that they sell
there are literally thousands upon
thousands of sensors sense making and
levers and actuators you can buy today
and each of them
claim to be open and integrated etc etc
but the reality is none of them really
feed into
a methodology that lets you make a
decision
so with that being the case
uh
just an illustration i went through and
i sort of did a quick inventory of a lot
of different inventory of systems from
it asset management to graph base uh
functionality in clouds to vulnerability
management platforms you name it there's
tons and tons of different ways we can
think about visualizing the data we get
from sensors we have the uh a linear
sort of view in lockheed martin's cyber
kill chain that says that well this is
the methodology by which every adversary
uh basically enacts his his or her craft
and it's always linear when we in fact
we know it's not in many cases it's
iterative
we have great tools like mitre attack
which allows us to talk about the and
categorize the knowledge base of
adversary tactics which lets us think
about how adversaries may indeed be
looking at exploiting us we have cool
things like detect and attack flow and i
think gabe bassett's giving a talk on
attack flow later which allows you to
visualize and map your defenses against
attack to know how well sorted you are
against a particular adversary and then
actually even visualize it
uh so go go look at gabe's uh go attend
gabe's talk on on attack flow later
interestingly we have the new cyber
security framework which again says you
should identify protect attack respond
and recover and it's always linear but
it's not in fact you go back and forth a
lot of times we have sunil u's cyber
defense matrix which takes the
uh inventory of nist from the
perspective of those categories and maps
them across domains and lets you
visualize where you have clusters of
technology
and or human-based responses to these
particular
sets of
of threats and allows you to understand
where you're weak you will notice that
in most cases if you were to map this in
your environment you would be you would
have very few things in the respond and
recover or at least in the recover
category because it's mostly people
focused
um we have great things in in the in the
vein of threat modeling we've got
structured processes to do this we have
pick your pick your favorite model
stride dread pasta you name it so we
have all the capability to essentially
be able to document how systems ought to
work
we have debiakio's pyramid of pain and
the effects and outcomes in terms of how
we could degrade deny destroy or
otherwise
disrupt adversaries based on the
availability or unavailability of
certain iocs
we even have amazing uh var model based
frameworks for doing quantitative based
risk management and risk assessment what
that really means is you're able to get
to and express dollars of risk based on
the probability and frequency
and magnitude of loss and actually
attribute dollar amounts to what a
particular event could bring you
so i just shotgunned you and fire hosed
you with an enormous amount of stuff we
have
and you would say well if that's the
case then why can't we make good
decisions quickly and a lot of that
would be answered by these four guys so
dave snowden not related to edward
snowden james rasmussen nicholas talab
and simon wardley incredibly smart
people i only share two
um
two things with them which is a receding
highlight uh hairline and graying of the
beard but i am fans of the work and
we're going to cover some of these in a
second in a very rapid-fire way because
i want you to think about tools and
whether you're even thinking about using
these tools so simon wardley
built this process and he open sourced
it called worldly maps and it's a way of
mapping strategy a lot of people use it
for business but you can literally use
it to map anything and it basically uses
a bunch of doctrines and rules to allow
you to understand based on a user's a
customer or user's needs chain a set of
needs and dependencies and components
what that allows you to do is make
really interesting decisions
um in a relatively short period of time
now there's a statement that says all
maps are wrong and some are useful and
this is a true statement because it is a
very uh we'll call it personal um uh uh
thing a map now maps are good if you
know where you are if you don't know
where you are it's very hard to know
even if you know where you're going how
you're going to get there right so
that's where mapping comes into play
this particular map was open sourced and
published on the web it was a team that
was looking at the executive management
as a decision maker or customer with
drivers like regulatory compliance they
need to prevent breaches detect reaches
and manage breaches and they took those
components over a level over an x-axis
of maturity of the component and and
that chain if you follow like regulatory
compliance
depends on having
automated control monitoring but that
particular component from genesis to
custom to product to commodity means
that some of that stuff as they grouped
it here would have to be delivered
in-house because it is not available to
be able to you know just buy you have to
build other stuff in their view was more
commoditized it became more product
oriented so you see things like
vulnerability scanning or attack
monitoring so mapping like this gives
you a view if you take like sunil's
cyber security defense matrix and you
say i have all these capabilities and
tools not all of them i'm able to
harness not all of them able to harness
myself how can i map those and make use
of them in my environment to make better
decisions
mr snowden is famous for something
called the conoven framework and it's a
welsh word which is why it sounds
nothing like what it's spelled like just
like comrie
and basically what he says is it's a
decision fabric that is based on four
different domains
simple complicated complex and chaotic
and in simple what you ultimately have
is a bunch of known knowns and so you
apply best practices you sense you
categorize you respond complicated you
sense analyze and respond because
there's a bunch of known unknowns things
that you know that you don't know
complex is a bunch of unknown unknowns
like you just absolutely don't
understand the space but you're able to
sort of probe sense and then respond
and then chaotic is where you ultimately
are unknowable unknowns really think
about that black swan events i was
talking about and you act sense and
respond the interesting thing about that
is it's a maturity of where you are in
the space that you're analyzing if you
apply this to infosec we tend to have a
binary view here of looking at things as
either being simple or complex where i
would argue that the majority of things
are more complicated i'm sorry simple
and chaotic where i would argue that in
many cases the majority of stuff is more
complicated and complex and the reason
that's important is if you're trying to
make decisions about things especially
in infosec space you have to understand
the space in which you are actually
afforded good quality data so if you if
you apply this to like the history of
our aeronautics
in the beginning it was very chaotic
somebody somebody said we ought to be
able to fly we don't know how and we
don't know what stuff looks like there
were weird designs with flapping wings
and corkscrews and a whole bunch of
other stuff
and people tried and iterated and failed
a lot right they made good decisions by
just trying things out complex after the
wright brothers made a plane that had
wings a propeller and a tail people sort
of knew you could fly it was a good and
reasonably safe plane but then to make
to make planes better they had to
ultimately iterate and test what was
already there years past you got to the
complicated realm where now you had
longer and more complex problems like uh
overseas travel which brought a whole
new set of challenges or problems to the
table i need to make decisions on
isolated cabins fusillage equipment uh
fuel efficient jet engines need to be
cost effective so in that particular
space and complicated you had to analyze
hundreds of materials
designs and test them to make sure that
they actually worked today in the simple
realm we already know how to fly there's
not a lot of magic like for the most
part unless you're optimizing for a
particular trait like speed or longevity
or
potentially outer space travel for
example if somebody needed to buy a
plane to build a plane today you could
pretty much take all the existing
knowledge and apply it now that's
important
i got lazy and ran out of time i was
going to do one for infosec but you
could you could you could map this to
any one of the domains you could talk
about perimeter security data security
you name it and what you would find is
that in many cases the decisions the
data that you have would indicate that
you would make different decisions
um and and what's interesting about that
is there's another field parallel field
of study called safety science and human
factors there's a guy named jen's uh
rasmussen he died about 2018 but he
talked about four different themes that
emerged in his work and this is the part
that in infosec we tend to leave out a
lot
and you can all let out a collective
groan about users and if we only didn't
have users security would be easy right
and at the end of the day most of the
stuff that we impose in terms of control
is to prevent users from doing bad
things we tell them not to click on
stuff we tell them not to do stuff well
what he actually said is that for for
example industrial uh scenarios like
nuclear power
um there are four things that you have
to think about human operator
performance results from behavior and
you can actually identify and model
behavior which is something we don't do
a lot of
human operators flexible and adaptive
they compensate for shortcomings they
cope with complexity by applying mental
models using this
the skills rules and knowledge based uh
system that he that he archetyped and
then risk management requires an
understanding of all of the inputs and
outputs and so the whole point about
this is it brings in another definition
of resilience called cognitive
resilience which is it implies a
practitioner's scope or a user or a
person's ability to cope with unexpected
events
so whether you're in security or a
particular user we count a lot on people
making good decisions which is a
challenge
so uh by the way uh who's seen soylent
green in the movie with char charlton
heston all the old people yeah so it was
set it was set in 2022 by the way which
is uh uh the irony is not uh lost on me
um so what do we have to do to apply all
this stuff in infosec so there uh
uh there's a really interesting uh talk
that mario plot gave recently on on how
do we apply um safety
and our thought about safety and and
you'll see some um like i am the cavalry
and a bunch of stuff that josh corman
and team have done around you know
medical devices in the same way thinking
about how we make sure that devices are
safe and high quality but there are
really different ways you can think
about different applying different
strategies based on the domain that
you're in
and i use this big giant modeled mess to
say look if you have a threat actor and
we have threat models and we have
ultimately situational context by using
snowden's mapping you take into
consideration human factors you map this
stuff out you can apply your models
ultimately what you get to is a way of
being able to apply stuff that we have
today but make decisions in a more
formulaic way now this looks complex and
it will be decades in the making and so
what i want you to take away from that
is a much more simpler view of what this
means to infosec and john lambert did a
great job of actually summarizing this
somewhat orthogonally in one of his
talks where he talked about info
advancing infosec towards an open
shareable contributor friendly model of
speeding infosec learning because
everything i just talked about is about
learning about your environment so if
you look at the left he said traditional
defenders defend a list of assets manage
incidents minimize risk by keeping uh
incident secret view pen test as a
report card and think about stopping
attacks
he implied that modern defenders defend
a graph of assets right you also heard
defenders think in lists attackers
thinking graphs same concept we manage
adversaries we maximize learning by
sharing incidents with trusted outside
peers we view pen tests as an input
comma to get better and we think about
the increasing increasing the attacker's
cost and time in order to attack us so
this is a little bit more simpler to
grasp because if you look at how we've
applied those rules and all that muck
that i talked about in the beginning
without even knowing what we're doing
today you see a lot of structures and
organizations of security teams looking
very very differently than they were
before we're seeing diffused and
embedded security teams especially in
places that build product you literally
have embedded security team members that
aren't part of some big collective borg
in the middle that is called infosec
we've seen the proliferation of
continuous integration continuous
deployment and now continuous service as
we integrate security tooling into our
dev tool chains
cloud and site reliability engineering
have really brought a lot of the
practices i just talked about about
secure by design and secure by operation
into fold we've seen the emergence of
whole new
sort of subspecies of capabilities that
we've put new names on like
observability and detection engineering
crop up which is about where we lay in
that sense sensors sense making decision
systems
timeline we've seen robust and threat
risk modeling start to take shape where
people are doing this stuff more
religiously chaos engineering has
entered the chat and we start thinking
about uh you know monkeys and the simian
army and turning things off and on and
looking at uh in a dot and adopting uh
cloud design paradigms like you saw with
aws when they came out a decade and a
half ago with design for fail which is
by the way antithetical to what we do in
security
and we've seen the emergence of a book
and if you haven't seen it you should
all run out and get it in my opinion
it's called team topologies it's about
how you organize
technology teams to really optimize what
you deliver and how so we're going to
cover off that a little bit by the way
my my uh
my little timer is not running what's
the time
9 55. oh fantastic all right i'll slow
down a little bit all right so wendy
neither
uh
the goddess of of all goodness and
security um came up with a term years
ago called about 11 years ago called
this cyber security poverty line the
visualization may not be accurate but
it's good for effect right where she
said basically big companies can afford
more people in technology and there is a
line the cyber security poverty line
where many of us are afflicted by the
fact that we can't and so how are we
supposed to defend things when we don't
have the budget and people to do it
a lot of this is
not because we don't have the
information or skills but ultimately
that that that poverty line is real so
we have to be able to think about how we
structure
and organize what we do without having
to depend on spending more money or
building more people and a lot of that
hearken back to the conversations that
we were having or the statements i made
about automation in the past
but dino di zovi in and i don't expect
you to read this i'll hit the high
points and his keynote at black out 2018
said look
software teams need to own their own
security now and security teams need to
become full stack software teams
let's sink in for a second right
basically what that means is from a
security perspective we need to be able
to deploy security at code and we need
to be able to inject ourselves into the
frameworks and methodologies that
developers use
it also he also went on to say that
security teams will become internal
security software teams that deliver
value to internal teams through
self-service platform and tools
now for those of you that look at that
and go that sounds great
um
what many of you have interpreted that
to mean is we should just call ourselves
now devsecops teams because instead of
being on-prem we've moved to the cloud
mario platt uh did another great talk
where he said
uh and he he ultimately uh captured a
bunch of input uh from the intertubes
that said if if your notion or strategy
mentions the word devsecops and you're
not understanding how the governance
teams need to deal with what that means
and thus regulators
you're you're not really doing devsecops
if you're not increasing the agency and
ownership of security across those that
own the product you're not doing
devsecops if you're not enabling the
best possible out of developers and
engineers you're not and all you've
redone is essentially all you've done is
essentially rebranded yourself
to look like you are relevant and in
fact the um the two little there's a
quote down on the bottom from uh kelly
shortridge who is uh who has lots of
spicy and snarky takes on a lot of stuff
and what she basically said was
devsecops is something that
most security teams think they can run
out and buy to make themselves seem more
relevant now that that seems sort of a
little bit gruff and in some cases wrong
but in many cases
just because you read it on the internet
doesn't mean that it's true and
how many of you have been in
conversations where the words site
reliability engineering have come up in
a conversation an sre
is now something that some manager says
that you ought to go do without really
knowing what it means and in fact
harking back to discussions that you
might have
around how it was implemented at google
sre is not
used in every software team it's very
expensive it's very onerous
and ultimately is it the right design
principle and a destination aim for sure
but in the same way that devsecops or
devops in that particular case means a
lot of things to a lot of people
simply calling yourself devsecops does
not actually get you towards being more
anti-fragile
uh in in fact the problem becomes even
more interesting there's a law called
conway's law that basically says for any
organization that designs systems you
ship your org chart
and what's funny about the pictures you
see there like amazon google microsoft
or the funniest one is oracle where
engineering's this big and legal is this
big right the reality is they ship their
org chart and the usability of the
products
really do reflect how the software
developers and security teams are
organized and that little graph for
microsoft on the right that indicates
how you ought to structure your infosec
team is incredibly complex
right so we are essentially applying
conway's law to security when the org
and engineering teams and business teams
are
look completely different from how we're
organized so there's a thing called the
reverse conway law which allows you to
basically say you really are ought to
organize yourself differently there's
this notion of team topologies i'm not
going to get into it in detail but if
you haven't read the book again i
suggest you do it talks about four
different types of topologies
streamlined enabling complicated and
platform teams they do different things
they provide different services they
consume different services and
ultimately they have different ways of
working with each other so you've got
collaborative models acts as a service
and facilitation and just really quick
take that for for for what it is
i i pulled down uh a an example uh that
docker has implemented in what they call
building stronger happier engineering
teams with team topologies and what they
had on the left was were very sort of
monolithic teams where if you were
building something like the docker hub
what you might end up doing is you would
have sort of a
a bunch of
a subordinate team that does ui
middleware back end and that team is
responsible for that particular product
and they would have to ultimately
jockey for uh time uh money and
resources to be able to get their
product done and there's a lot of shared
code there's a lot of ambiguity as to
who owns what so when the model that
they that they ultimately uh applied the
new structure
was one where they organized their
development teams writ large everybody
responsible for for example the in the
growth uh category which would be
account growth of the akap growth team
or a particular product like docker hub
had everybody they needed to be able to
bring that product to market including
ultimately security teams they build
these team apis that describe exactly
what each team does and how they
interact and why that's important is if
you take it to the next level and and
this next slide is something i added on
to
because they alluded to it but they
didn't include it in their slides if you
think about that from a security model
there there's this notion of a
complicated or acts as a service set of
core capabilities that aren't
necessarily engineering-centric so that
would be like grc incident response
incident um
incident response management um maybe
even vulnerability management that
provides a set of services with embedded
security engineers in each of the
product teams what that gives you is a
much more focused close to the business
way of thinking about from a decision
perspective what decisions you ought to
be able to make to bring that product to
market securely there are a number of
models that exist uh for example in
large finance and other industries where
the security teams are massively
monolithic
or they are very distributed
uh where ultimately the individual teams
are empowered to do what they want but
what team topologies has done is started
to be able to
align how security teams function
with the business and the engineers that
are doing it and and dino and i were
having a conversation along with other
people the other day and he said well
it's almost like if technology isn't all
built by one monolithic org then we
shouldn't have technology secured by one
monolithic org either
and that's a great summary of what that
means so organizationally um that also
sort of and i know josh's corman's
probably here and i put this in here
because he yelled at me though he's over
there the last time that i didn't
mention this in response to resilience
but um i don't know eight years ago
maybe more uh okay maybe even more than
that the rugged manifesto was really
aimed at developers but it talked about
um how you should take this mindset of
being rugged in software development
which um ultimately the important parts
down at the bottom it's not a technology
process model secure development
lifecycle organizational structure it's
not even a noun it's it's not the same
as secure this is a way of essentially
applying these rules to be able to think
more holistically and it really does rub
off on what i talked about with jan
rasmussen's safety talk about things
like this is the way we function this is
the set of services and this is the
ethos by which we we implement more
secure code
security is a byproduct of being rugged
right which rugged is another word for
resilient secure survivable etc or in
this case anti-fragile so you may be in
the audience and you're like well i
don't work for a company that develops
software
it doesn't matter the same things apply
you consume it and so the way in which
you think of applying these
these concepts
apply whether or not you develop
software or not now you also may not be
in a position where you can change the
org structure but you can think
atomically about how you ultimately
deliver services and part of the problem
that i that that i wanted to bring up is
that you know
security has a leadership dinosaur
problem and we're waiting for the
meteorite to hit right so most of most
of the people that manage and lead
security teams today in larger
established companies are old like me
now we came up from a time that was much
more complicated and or chaotic in as
much as security didn't necessarily
exist with all the frameworks governance
and tools many of us were network
administrators or system administrators
when the internet came online we started
doing security stuff and here we are but
we've ultimately been doing the same
stuff over and over again
that's starting to change as you see new
leadership and new blood and a lot of
the younger folks in the audience as you
come up you're the availability of
thought processes and tooling and
knowledge sharing these events didn't
really exist the same way they do today
when we were coming up so leadership is
an issue organization culture is another
one the the notion of security being a
control function and not an enabler at
the same point in time i sort of ralph
every time i hear somebody say security
should be a business enabler
it should be but in the context of how
you organize is important and the
culture we have is very punitive there's
a lot of there's a lot of noise and not
a lot of signal we get drowned with a
you know an awful lot from that sensing
sense making and lack of decision
systems um issue of cognitive load the
outcomes are really about let's just not
be any worse than we were
yesterday not how do we get better
uh we have a very punitive incentive
model right instead of stick versus
carrot or broccoli versus ice cream a
lot of what we talk about with
developers what you can't do not what
you can do and language is a problem
so from the perspective of how
militarized our industry is just look at
words like dmz and pen testing i mean if
you go into an environment with people
that aren't security people i mean many
of us have gotten on the plane on our
way here with
our disobey and defcom backpacks and
strange piercing and wi-fi devices and
we sort of look weird to people we're
not particularly accessible
i mean in in many cases we have over
militarized what it is we do which makes
it very difficult to communicate um in
in easy terms i mean somebody in my org
one day said jesus we're saving
passwords not lives uh so
uh
not unfair um so what does this mean
listen at the at the end of the day
uh we have uh we have an awful lot of
stuff uh at our disposal we have a lot
of data
we have a lot of
uh tools we have a lot of technology
but um
we we have ultimately relied more on on
art and compliance as the way in which
we operate versus science
a lot of what we do is siloed
places like this are fantastic because
we get to share what we do we get to
share our successes and our failures
we can think differently about how how
we're organizing and larger companies
will have a trickle down effect on all
of us as they display success in
organizing differently and operating
security differently
we cannot continue to simply be the
department of no i know we've heard that
a lot but a lot of the capabilities that
we have really um means that at the end
of the day being resilient meaning being
no
no worse than we we were being able to
bounce back but not actually learn from
and get better is not sufficient and we
we really need to be more anti-fragile
and again that means getting better
from stressors and adverse uh adverse
events so that was my my hope that i had
uh in combining five talks into one and
probably
annoying the crap out of you with
buzzwords um i wanted to to um
to communicate and at the end of the day
i don't think anybody said it better
and uh than dan gear which is
uh up on the screen work like hell share
all you know abide by your handshake and
have fun we can do all of that at the
same time as we make better decisions by
being
less fragile and more anti-fragile
this was not a talk meant to even have a
punctuation point it was meant to spur a
set of conversations discussions and and
perhaps research in a lot of those
strategies and things that i talked
about jens rasmussen's approach to
safety snowden's view of decision-making
systems etc and if i have time i'll take
questions as best i can but the point
was
i was hoping to spur a conversation not
make not not not end with a a big bang
so i don't think i ended with a big bang
so at least i got one out of two but
yeah you had a question
so that when the accident happens and it
might not be your fault it might be your
fault it doesn't really matter the
occupants of the automobile survive and
walk away right
we need to discard engineering our
security programs in exactly a great way
yes
let me replay that real quick for people
in the audience he basically is making a
a parallel to the automobile industry
and their advancement of safety and
safety science over time and they
invented things like seat belts or
actually gave them away
and crumple zones in the automobile
which is meant to protect the asset in
case of an accident uh and ultimately we
need to do the same it sort of ties into
a lot of what jens rasmussen said but a
lot of that is being thoughtful about
being rugged about being you know
anti-fragile in a way in which we think
about outcomes differently which is not
just you know i stopped
this
this particular event from occurring
what impact or outcomes did it not have
that
adversely affected the org yeah thank
you for that it was a good summary
all right uh yeah
unlike the automobile industry maybe we
should also be concerned about the
people outside
oh that's an interesting one unlike the
automobile industry perhaps we should be
concerned with people outside the car
uh well my my wife's uh fsd tesla is
certainly an indicator of that
uh she's hit numerous curbs luckily no
people but yeah i do think that the
system as a whole if you look at
snowden's thing about right the the the
environment as a whole is a very
important piece not just people we
protect but but unintended consequences
and if you need me to go you just give
me the hook i'll just keep talking to
them
all right
anyway i hope that was helpful thanks
for being with me i haven't talked in
seven years so i'm
a lot out of practice thanks
[Applause]