all right let's begin
they I want to talk about him I some
more separation research aren't saying
how are you so we can we escape
I'm a chance online from my only bark
and other plant her form was a very cute
and then now I'm more focused on aren't
a we saw like these and so quickly and
sandbox the second degree heat today
ah ok I want pool
pakistan machine about her a critique
all
Oh whenever you need here you that
heating it easy
it's a typo Lisa do you want a wannabe
leave your hands being a disclosure and
her last yeah
first I we all focus on what you told us
how much you know about her
st. Thomas I'm thinking about that and
the same technology and next I we all
details the city center . here and at
last I i we all talked to some
exploration technologies the end up
I also prepare a use of pollution a tank
we do and the and the last time out I i
we are played
ok let's go from beginning but then
prevent aids a opens also with an idea
to implant a performance and huh
oh aight her it was the start here by
always all I te Shan Yu service worker
and her coverage university here 10
years ago and now it has to be a virtual
productor many many cloud provider use
eat huh
sometimes I
AWS nino de and the robot series and the
our army and even clock
alibaba cloud
this is the simplest the same product
her
you are a moment mmm the have her weezer
the happier we store is a director and
the secrecy directly on the hardware and
her compared to pool cue em and compared
with Grandma adds a new cannot say how a
user is a newsstand on the line
os os cannot mmm but huh
the only how how implant here the same
power function just as he was 13 and the
memory management and the way I'm
control you know that he then it didn't
happen easter can either i use bar ranch
without her
r OS or hosted last so they host the
last is intentional
the Xhosa who's the last week are the
dominant 0 don't mean that dominates the
short of our Tommy . adami means that we
saw more chain so . so and that are
under day
no material other mr. took other
mistreat her to cool their control and
odds are a user domains and
if necessary it hold it hold up a also
has to be roughly the hardware
easy easy picture into the future too .
10 use the you know the saying special
to us than the tool ctrl answer Sarah
you started all means and the control of
divorce banger
based on our times throughout the series
when I when I do tell you how is our we
analyse cape
I I used to I used to the somewhat
different ways at all with that or the
implant gently pull on piety
we asked me to give oh that hand come
why would see do you use polarization
technology that eats a tool set her
every told me I i we don't you two hands
at the fall pretty easy to answer the
ultimate aero but her
the scenes and maybe it may be
competitive for you this week because it
because the day for a thought a user
Tommy if what if i use a dominant has a
a fall pro probably jesus answered 1 105
and has a missing some important huh
information starting into a tiny restore
the service is also a Poisson why not
able to see museum
I think it's her that way not a not her
we are we are usable we try and armies
are running different who
moda mostly the quoted padding in tool
toe taps p.m. and each we m , is up
heroin with all ideas are more chain and
it'll it'll pull around with a more
defined
West cannot and then the each way i'm
going to use the how do we are a seat
i'm here with all the ideas and other
days it's a time that you know her
entire exit are in her
the technology and that I it is a body
around with a comedy Anna Espinosa
sometimes a windows
mm that's that I did her
I mean our team how do you sort of have
about about that is higher ma'am ma'am
ma'am
mama many demand time
mmm the have a reason how is the memory
management is the mom I'll be tomorrow
compacts that because the easier it'll
continue the tour you are you support
eaten either to ensure are effectively
and he did hit you need to eat her need
a tool to asana ads are compact stands
for
hmm the day for each other for each one
would see how is our support for
different management memory management
and another do that
why is a shadow theatre table as a speed
here and another one
age is a however how to where are you
taking the MOU a terminology here we
call the euchy holiday
- um yeah
there is only oh why memory management
house agreement that we called around
the median far the other Hadean
development opinion means an huh - how
is that a lot of
I guess the last kernel the rapidly put
her is to pay tables at Monte a real
mm you so bad about half a better for
every every table after the needs of
ramen guess the words cannot a time
don't have her user master or the hood
you're having curry pressed so
oh so how how to haha how would he have
how is ur for the recording for a day
printable the updates that are so creepy
activity and see how is he i have always
argued some different huh
or data are are taking part in her
easy easy hamper easy how . call you
plant the why is the day
good here you guys close you were .
happens every more chain page frame
Master be a supposed to eat here the
weeds aware I was here follow pretty
tabs for you dump are the pages hey Bob
I mean that the level level that page
table
Master be all sweaty it was aight heater
with the PTR our 1p table
this type of anadyr . directly to a bar
Master also the 80 the weed today .
here's our to meet able to have only we
only a frame or associate he also said
associate her with a with our PT what
your people could be a man can write
about for a PS and any ads are tabs the
a tiny odds are people more training
period of three more wins a are with the
odds are have a taste of ads are . have
them for the only be a matter you to
know . guest
she got the . army ret read the bottom
that means a are any and if he guessed
my name . um you were the only how
rather upset poor towards the @one
pretty about me not always as they
appear out of the AGM memory mad money
demand her in pancetta
uh yeah may need to see for you
you are in 20 why is the guest OS me
always the create create her red red a
bar mansion for the outlet one . free
monster
you got that is that they are current
habitat and so I can her and other day
so I'm gonna it's a different my only
simply be it with has the winds your
reference the colonnades yeah
are any any paper anymore train . free
more
how are always a how r represents the
kana and the reference econo recalls the
ER references
not only is your references that either
0 that means the day . guess the car not
doesn't how any reference that all ate
her identity
Pedro Freeman would be translated to add
their people have also pay for
so if or are they for our page table of
people are marching page of prima
associate here we are
a pee p  two  r ry
paid hey what happened
the youth ET you could this be the uz a
. esta and a few guys that has a eat
references then the pretty table tabs
the printer for more cannot help be with
has go to our of a can be a be a
changeup or are you . here at or a table
page
the season mmm
the season your eyes a deer
since you warm at memory you see it but
I'm hardly but he was about him not
about not all limits you probably hated
his father and yeah I odds are sent you
sent it to your memory that that
sometimes the dbt our did he
ok and now we need help my our wanted to
know what your idea when I believe here
funny to buy this quarter by our team
that's the app mmm pasta
ricciardi la moda pay TMO Pedro moda
also prima the emma and i am you you are
me
our of fallen all marching frame will
use a user our washer or dresser it hell
we are
it also a certified from or see a three
and four are
normal PT muda it how we are end and her
PT page table PT the PT entries the PTU
we are
he was a information about is the
ability final page frame number and my
friend
so for our servers are paid a motor for
the for your damn hot for the apt e PS
flanger was said saying the MMU we are
not a sort of hard the next up here and
take a hater we are and and and her here
and the pd year
the DVD is the pdi-p it so we are all we
argue with the final pay to frame a
peter from Anambra ok
o our idea when I believe he's a wii
disc Laura that is a used a featured
then had a son and a PHS flag was the I
expect at all or at least value to say
to black
now we now we r do 2d we or we call our
cause
so supposing mp4 for our . esta avenue
in her its opinion
obviously there is a pee-pee agent
directory
t-boz the happier we start we are doing
some so much hair cut on the visa visa
functional m.o.d power to entry to this
function
they are either a sec the take back and
just that half of the packet slot is a
either around towards the current her
current her . ami or not if not her then
with her foster and this is a in common
any comments circumstances either where
we pass them at their next up the check
tool and it is a function we are txt the
new peds our people and for the people
angle with the said her it all we all do
next the much heavier and able to the
people angle words or colada and then it
was we are updated the entry directly
ok but her Oh oui oui
if we want for you to the day p do when
we master said that the people anger
toward a tool that
so has the table and a day
go to the next part but net and next
attack
this is terrible this function we are
data
comparative PD is a reserved word of
peace was said how are not her pay for
it harder said her because it is over
the bead so it will if we toured the
said her there a man you used to be
security
we are bigger
his passion so every day we don't
resolve with the beads will set her then
the function we all read her iraq and
the day for go to the next next
so far the this is though
DC is that are faster faster pencil for
update her
pd disadvantage and only only compared
to things that how are the periods
a mi find peace and add the new of Jesus
american beauty
ah you cannot and the order . p flanger
and the new P's a P flanger are you call
not much hacker attack poor window
within you within your periods are
people and other words the set weasel or
the periods of chief lanka also will
work with the two words to say through
the truth be said who won and order a
for a for wii or if I were all the
periods PA di that means a are my flight
peace what do you call a new key the
media and i have been beaten then the
faster as we are one either
and they are they give you and updated
the entry relatively and we are not a
good for the the check file check the
file well to some odds are already in
her start under their castle and God huh
but her it will are we partner we pass
the time
faster has the check our a coda floor we
are not go to the check foul it we are
and and her if we are done here that our
returns the other means the memory
allocated to the operation is a success
well here is the week of all a logical
so I need the tour triggered her a treat
to the diesel where we can all logic
O'Toole
I'm sorry memory read and write and yeah
and yeah some step so there's a lot we
are Locker a normal page
II the easy memory be around for the
current dominant and day they paint and
a new page
the new Peter we call them hate DPD's
mfa neither security vie de are
conditions and how they need to learn
how to use the time she beats all were
the PJ and my friend must be 0 that
means that if we are
that means that if we use the use this
and this with our address that and are
super Patriots and I get a master
mmm well it's a matinee tackle you and
your friends and her easy you use found
the ideal for is a tool to matter abuse
data for our use a little control and
that's all we know
a log on you . we had a baby . we also
need a tour and you find some conditions
and that means a the page be master low
located either use the full megabusa
memory Iraq
so then Axl will chase her away we just
started out as a pager pager beat and a
normal or PT and then we read the thread
yeah he paid a a normal
Peter normal PT no more teams are no
more candy
oh thank you note on her for any higher
. he baza the w flank right a flanger
rather flattered Kobe said who act and
this is this rental angle also put Abby
said 21
only then how is there only charity the
hour you how are you
I mean the pd pd is a writable flanger
it's a 10 if we say that the PA and PB
is a rather read about flanger towards
the arrow and they have a user would
another concern about eight
so now the ps4 anger is a zero
next we really ready to haul a week more
lovely and a set of the chairs and
appears flanger tool back and then
Amma Amma you in termina the final page
of free more by these PD and it had not
neither are new or on
Islands are you take off that so
because because of our PS appears
appears flanger is equal to or the set
and I
right above the water said we cool a
rather ball ran out of the ground ball
to your tormentor beat some memories and
knows her
there is a page table will help you how
to reduce their the pager eight and the
normal . table so we will now
now we have a week for the rather and a
right
the deep hatred Heba if we put the rapid
is it did he bought that mean we coulda
read that and our autumn more chain
memory
this belonged with the current her know
me and that this would be around for all
our drama and a decent may be buried on
me and better bury our memory any memory
we could a change to read and write
ok now other trees are the trigger
enhance the arbitrary mirchi memory
rather our time we need a tool use the
salmon technologies at all
hi Dexter control flow there are some
weeds
mmm this way is a comment
we do so we do so and the we seek our
page dissipated was what they use 18
needs the healings and if we hijack at
this page we coulda a four-hour coder
user model may be here we may be a good
with maybe room with the root of
religious and there may be with the
normal normal normal user privileges did
this is a Harper computer words you used
80 there
we need the . oh man , moda
so if we coulda had uh hi . at the half
a car
pager we could how would the
come on opportunities they have her have
her card table uses he needs they have
her weezer moda
so if we had your days at this table we
could a rat our special our payload our
so cool that easy
then how is our modem okay yeah I we all
know how about holiday
how car . he was your first what Harper
called a ball is a was a local a lock
with a local by a . cannot and it her
request that you have her weezer - II
neutralizer with the family have her
call pages double codes this topic was
addressing like her a dark just like her
we see the car cuda we seek our peter
kupaza it's a data are convenient how
far our guests the car not to use to a
tool to you at all to do our have a car
today
luckily every p we cannot only how have
her car
Peter so if we want to want to hide
we want to get her the bleep you II
guess the current or a privilege
we just the shots
do you have a car and have a coffee
jingle human nature and if we ando if we
modify and that they all original have a
hobby just a barracuda
then we will put a heck of a kind of
motor control flow
this is the house i'll call a pager
you need a night light Vijay
function we call this a I was garba cuda
and most the 22 by itself and the are
most the most of the hypercar hyper car
. estaba cuda are similar but heard the
at least these the how is that I I here
barbacoa de I more different day it is
at least a half hour with I I eat here
is a user for pjs the kind of world war
III IET operations at Oscar and normal
cannot use the iru constructions that
will read handful pretty worse and pre
was the is cruising muda for four years
and part three times with the user mode
that from on can also babies because it
was so wrong with these pharmacies cuda
week week with a conclusion and down her
the harbor , beauty - char data that is
the methods of bites the hypercore pager
baba cuda a deal why would they have a
core sample CUDA is an animal's the 22
or buy it sir
but her oh we could see it from my hair
than her
I realized that include me not you d 4 x
32 batter and the level words the what
the CC biter DC bad so what was the was
a for the by guess the . can order
where
after i eat her a lock or unlock my
locality have a carb heat with us at the
source of the human nature and her we
could all find all over the have her car
. and he means a week Buddha we could
allocate heater all a peewee guests . or
means that her
rania are the ante current her physique
, chain
ok because the hammer carburetor is a is
a normal teenager
it has either contains the fall thousand
advisor and and erase that i read the
Bible cool cool the animals the surgery
too bad sir
and the day have mr. only at most of the
how war64 have her cock
so the force out and the pirates are
only be used that I only be you only use
the two thousand batter and the these
patterns these tools out and about
I use them then if we hide a high do
control flow we do a pull-up lida our
pillars and here and here
ok this is the parallel to this holiday
is a very easy
uh up a little kanawha research how
would usually right about these two
codes we just tell her we just we just a
hi how are you hi jacket ease modified
these this instruction see the point
Ruxin now we're plating
replace the eighth help with a local
John for energy local down with a jump
jump to hear and the door hour and a
half hour special pillows for Steve are
here
here is a chance that either you're with
her crew than her
if we have heard that if we take her
the IR eat here i diii d a hypercar is
the one tool resentful
come on moda we we we we filled her hate
her because we want to really we want to
hide
you know we want was that addy control
flow into the user muda so only if
you're over there
I ruk hypercar want no one tool return
for your mother
if we are going through the go to hair
and that this this is our only a man
without kind of sbisa in for the user
mode and because a year after you some
more that it is a hard copy towards the
youth is 80 and cannot say is that if we
go to a user moda we're cool not cool
couldn't her continue your execution our
X accrued of our people with us so we
need of first any Saturday have her card
she kind of space that good you cannot
memories that into the user mother then
to use Moodle we've got far as a you are
fuck off hawkers is a car and a day
apparence I would have Parenthood
process go to hair and and the reefs and
we start with her
original date her and the run
continually rest of your body and our
children processor which we are good for
our real derecho de here is a a here is
a real Sara coded data based on our the
buffer to buffer mean i implanted ah ah
i implanted this
Koza with the support for and how we
coulda used a simple for to this day
it's area code just the receivable we
see war commander I and ran come on the
line and he will out of water and our
clear sir
if you don't cooperate the DA's
Wolverine and he will not handed her the
20 year did the real
I would have put ok
at the end i mean the summit and clear
no after we use of color are that is
when I believe he masama say that is are
several years or the innominate here but
her
when I do these slides that I used you
to get logged for two trees a coda and
here maybe more than half yards and see
this is there a week
ball logica maybe it's a sort of coda
has the trains though is the we print or
previously so but holla t it is also
cold day already
this is also could also we call and we
danced all
we don't know we just heard something
about up Huey how it will get her PE
Tommy with the cell and for each way I'm
we each one more user da me into a movie
esta for windows which is that including
the use of these technologies that will
get her
it's so with herself uh here is a demo
my mind has the environmental water or
the damn fault . far and away the day
hosted last it's a there is some kind of
my mikasa a pas de is the Easter other
way is a wa8 it the more hands of being
uploaded for your true
yeah
ok
how to look for the disa mouse at all
here
okay thank you
yeah
I how to put these on the pc windows to
these sorry i'm not a community is the
USC because our company use the another
devices then i use a wireless screen
ok that's what you couldn't
ok
yeah i mean the kind dominant visa
this is a function of all and not only
how or why you brought me and her and
hope you don't mean zero
now I created a new one . on me
you know . on me
Tommy idea is a citizen so not use that
how can sort of mana tool and her in for
the peed on me
ok now you now easy now easy user . on
me and I in her either
and r u8 not use a user use of you Tommy
Smith
I we also there we only we are we are
going to ski for a tanker and hair done
hbu that and the use of our micro muda
and create her do is this is a user move
the you put i rhyme or Randy pride
ok get our dominant ER or to sell
ok this is this is the hope why
come on this is the roof
yes it did you see the hardest
ok just is that is how it and X are you
full commander and her , I means and her
we have will act as execute heater
commander and her down with dro
I knew that we played
ok
then my properties and we all and any
other question any question
I knew his hands on it is on any
questions for God's no was clear
thank you please go to plus just Samson