you hey there we go I think this is
working here we go great thank you very
much as a lovely intro a good morning
amsterdam it's a great honor to be here
and kick off jack in the box 2016 with
you on
I'm going to talk a little bit today
about the history of the crypto Wars and
try to get you excited about what
what's coming up next as as you heard
the intro and really remember the
operations team and Twitter and later
worked on the information security team
is part of that team
one of the things that I do is I brought
Twitter to a hundred percent always on
SL and worked with some of the initial
law enforcement response when we were
very young company and you know I
learned a lot while I was at Apple
dealing with law enforcement and you
know it's it's a very difficult a very
difficult world when you
we run a start-up and you have to
interact with law enforcement you may
have never done that before and you know
all in all I've been at this for quite
some time and in a sword before I tell
you where we're going with the crypto
Wars I want to go back and talk about
where we've been and I think right now
security versus privacy is one of the
largest debates of our time and in
October of 1977
George Dava was an American computer
scientist and photographer who received
a gag order from the NSA and he received
this while working on a patent
application for a stream cipher device
and the NSA really only knew about this
because of a long-term voluntary
cooperation between academic researchers
and the and the NSA and this was known
as the invention Secrecy Act of nineteen
fifty-one and the Act gave them the
power to block patents in the interest
of national security and now under this
system the academics and cryptographers
would submit copies of technical papers
to the agency before publication and
this gave the agency an opportunity to
request the suppression of any sensitive
material and you know at the time model
mathematicians abided by this agreement
seeing it as a threat to the free
exchange of ideas and the free exchange
of ideas is what our industry depends on
to to be successful and to meet the
goals of cybersecurity and and other
requirements and you know
this sort of pervasive problem was with
us all the way through the eighties and
in the nineties in fact we share put a
book called applied cryptography and at
the time
um you know it was legal to publish
because of the United States having the
First Amendment and a right to speak
freely
it was legal to publish a book on
cryptography but if you would take the
same exact source code and put it on a
floppy disk in 1994
it was illegal you are not allowed to
actually shift that across lines because
it was considered to be ammunition in
fact last night someone told me a lovely
story that if you had taken the source
code of the of the book and you put the
book in a rocket and fired across the
border
it was the munition and at that point it
would no longer be illegal to transmit
anywhere because guess what you would
just find another country so it was fine
on the problem is is that the the NSA
tried to use export regulations and
later deliberately manipulated
cryptography to weaken it to create
multiple forms of photography some for
export and some porn on export and you
know if you were using ciphers above 56
bit
you weren't allowed to do that because
perhaps the NSA couldn't break the
ciphers back then on this all sort of
changes in the late nineties because
Phil Zimmerman comes along and releases
pgp and this limited use of strong
encryption are
this begins to greatly concerned the US
government because it's not about easy
access to strong encryption it's about
ubiquitous and simple access where the
world is encrypted by default and the US
government tried to publicly ensure and
retain its ability to decrypt traffic so
they fought us using technical methods
such as key escrow the insertion of
vulnerabilities into the commercial
encryption ecosystem and by directly
attacking systems networks and endpoint
communications at targets would use and
you know fearing the widespread adoption
of encryption
we had this in 1993 we had the Clipper
Chip and the Clipper Chip was introduced
by Clinton's administration and it was a
sort of hybrid a hardware software
device which used key escrow and it
truly express the intent of the time
which was that the FBI or other
companies would permanently have a
mechanism where they could have your
keys and an encryption should come with
a back door and you know George dominant
from the seventies
who is you know terribly affected by the
NSA gag order was a strong outspoken
opponent against this and you know this
is not the right way to provide strong
cryptographic tools to the public so an
immediate backlash from technical
experts privacy advocates and industry
leaders are bought this device and
eventually in 1994
the device was was broken at the same
time they took a different approach they
tried to sign into law a bill which was
eventually signed in with much
opposition called Kalia Kalia is the
communications assistant for law
enforcement act and that was signed into
law by president clinton and clear was
sort of a direct reaction to the the
changing tide of the telecommunications
industry the telecommunications industry
was then moving from old analog switches
to digital switches which are much
harder to wiretap it's not like I can
walk up and grab a pair of alligator
clips and clip onto a binding post and
hear your conversation anymore
the telephone companies had to
fundamentally redesign their systems and
if you go and look in like a cisco
manual today you'll actually see
references to kalia commands for for
intercepting communications this uh this
was expanded multiple times in 2004 it
was up
it was expanded to include ISPs and
voice over IP providers like skype in a
few years later the FBI began to push
legislation to try to expand this to all
online communications and this died in
very the set very similar way with much
uproar much fighting from the industry
and it it did resurfaced in 2010 and you
know we sort of Mark 2010 is the
beginning of the FBI is going dark
campaign and it came back again in 2013
and you know the problem with the
proposal as as the electronic frontier
foundation stated was that it would
allow the FBI to find non-compliant
companies for not providing back doors
and in 2014
you know we see this issue again with
them asking for a national discussion
about the use of encryption
so you know in 1994 we thought we had
won this debate already because
cryptographer mad blaze had discovered
holes in the Clipper Chip and the export
controls were relaxed and we started to
see increased security on the internet
where it suddenly you know hundred
twenty-eight bit 256-bit encryption was
available and you know for the most part
we thought this issue is just said and
done and the really interesting part is
that it's like did we actually win
because I don't think we did the the
impact of the weakening of our
cryptosystems at least in the last year
has introduced three major SL
vulnerabilities freak
log jam and round and this these
vulnerabilities would not have existed
if not for the fact that we had
government attempting to weaken SL you
know over 20 years ago and you know for
the third time in a year we have another
vulnerability and I'm you know these
restrictions were originally designed to
give them an advantage but the impact is
a catastrophic failure of security for
everyone and you know more recently we
saw in the 2013 sort of Snowden
revelations information about NSA bull
run an essay bull run was interesting
because we had one in the courts in the
eff and and US Congress and public
opinion had said no to the Clipper Chip
and no to weakening encryption but the
NSA was working on it all along with
projects like Bull Run which created new
vulnerabilities in mist cryptography
standards and the weakening of sort of
the global cryptography market and
attacking major libraries like RSA and
we still don't know the full extent of
what what this has done to us and you
know why why why continue on this is why
do i do I keep pressing this issue and
it's because if you look at someone like
Amnesty International
you know they believe that in a digital
age access to and use of encryption is
an enabler to the right to privacy you
know encryption is an enabler of freedom
of expression information and opinion
and it has an impact on the rights of
individuals and especially it's a
critical tool for human rights defenders
activists and journalists all who rely
on this with an increasing frequency to
protect security and others from of
unlawful surveillance and the real
question is what does what does that
look like if we have your biggest
question was it look like in the face of
terrorism and crime
you know in my home state in san
bernardino california a deplorable act
of terrorism was executed by seed fruit
and touchscreen Malik they killed 14
people in December second 2015 and this
is not you know this is an action from a
few individuals a few distraught
individuals and we cannot allow these
sort of activities to to dominate the
privacy and security of the many
terrorism is deplorable
it's awful it's an attack on our general
way of life but we cannot allow that to
remove our privacy for kinda iphone 5c
and the iphone 5c unlike the later
versions of the Apple iPhone had
slightly weaker Security and the FBI had
found one of his phones in the trash and
I asks apple through a standard court
order for his iCloud account backups and
any other data that Apple could provide
and out provided everything they could
but they did not provide access to the
phone directly because the device is
protected by a number of security
mechanisms which are introduced so
there's a brute force protection on the
device if you try to type in a code too
many times the device will self-destruct
of the operating system updates are
signed and you know in later models like
the the six and a success they have a
hardware enclave where your keys are
stored so the issue a court order on
your in figure 2016 the demands that
Apple build a custom build of the iOS
operating system to remove the automatic
eraser and pin limits that are on the
phone and if we kind of go back and look
at the history of crypto Wars
this is very similar to what was
occurring with things like the Clipper
Chip it's like you just just build us
something that we can get into
I'm interestingly enough they tried to
use a very old law from 1789 called the
all writs act to compel Apple is
unlocking the phone and you know the
Apple CEO at the time Tim Cook said this
is an unprecedented use of the law and
in fact we've seen the all writs a ques
many times to to compel companies and
it's probably not what it was originally
intended for
and you know the implications of this
are quite chilling so that the
government can use a single act to make
it easier to unlock your phone
they would have the power to reach into
anyone's device to capture data and you
know later
you know Tim Cook response is this would
set a dangerous precedent and you could
imagine what would happen if you know
you had like ass and a samsung smart TV
or a nest device and suddenly along
comes a and a court order to reprogram
your device to turn it into a tool of
surveillance in your home it's it's
really not acceptable
I'm and you know Apple could not provide
this would not provided and put up quite
a fight from you know the first part of
this year and they would not provide a
back door into the phone instantly
enough the FBI later claimed that they
were able to access the phone using a
currently unknown vulnerability and
there's a lot of speculation in March
what company had actually provided that
vulnerability whether i was celebrate or
other companies but currently we don't
we don't know what they used
um so you know it's very similar to what
happens in November 2015 with the Paris
attacks where the you know where ISIL
actually claimed that they had used
telegram to his telegram to announce the
attack and the idea here is that you
know
should these activities be used as a
pretext to monitor citizens and suppress
dissidents and you know I think it comes
back to kind of a central point which is
that it's not possible to make a message
in technology that secure for everyone
except for the criminals
it's just not possible this this is
different than the view that James
coming to visit the current director of
the FBI has to say because he believes
the technology is a tool for dangerous
people which I don't agree with you on
that and also the law has not kept pace
with the technology and it's created a
significant public safety issue which
they sort of refer to consistently is
going dark and you know if we look at
someone like Oliver day who wrote
securing change you know this is
encryption does it really make survey
targeted surveillance harder
you know we have cash with Barry Bonds
fake mustaches hats hair blankets hair
dyes there's many ways to hide and you
know here's a kiss
Snowden typing in his
announcer with a blanket over his head
which is kind of funny I'm yeah so um in
uh I guess sort of frustrated by this
problem the justice department tries a
new argument and they say you know what
law enforcement really needed was to
have us companies hold copies of
encryption keys that the government
could get your information from them and
you know the problem is the companies
are keeping stockpiles of encryption
keys it really increases the surface
area of the attack and if i'm able to
breach a single company i get the
encryption keys from many people and you
could imagine anyone from from you know
hackers to foreign spies and not the
good hackers in this room of course but
I'm you know but you know the same day
uh you know director , he said that the
administration had decided if they
should seek legislation or not which is
completely insane because they had been
seeking legislation since the early
versions of kalia to regulate encryption
and that the way the cyber security
community should should invent
mechanisms for the government to access
the encrypted information without
weakening security almost relegating the
problem
- you know - something that we could
solve all sitting in a garage and I
think at one point he actually said I I
think silicon valley is full of folks
who stood in the garage years ago that
they would never be told your dreams are
too hard to achieve
well unfortunately for the director
there's a difference between dreams and
math and math is what protects us
so his idea of going dark is not really
what's happening in fact we currently
live in sort of a golden age of
surveillance
there's more information about you on
the Internet and there's more
information about you and social media
and there ever has been to see the
decision to make a statement that we're
going dark
and in this world is not is not entirely
true
you know and the great irony of this is
that their quest to access the data
encrypted on one iphone made it such
that they open the encryption debate to
the world and you know this conversation
if it wasn't started years ago it's it's
going now
now the Department center for law
they release a lengthy paper on this if
you like to read it i'm not going to get
into too much detail here but in short
they cite the fact that end-to-end
encryption is unlikely to be widely
adopted and I think that it's beholden
to everyone in this room to make sure
that actually happens on you know this
that that software ecosystems that we
work in a fragmented
so you know for many years it was very
hard to encrypt information because you
had to fight with varying libraries and
all manner of problems and and now we
want to move to a world that has
encryption by default and you know keep
in mind that regardless of of what
changes at the end points that they
still have access to incredible amounts
of unencrypted made a data from phone
switches and other centralized
communication points that that they can
readily use and the other argument is
that this is this has never been about
one phone phones are not safe
they're not something that you can eat
you just crack into and that's it you
broke into one phone
we need technical solutions to break
into devices and that if we were to
create code that could open one phone
it could open millions of locks not one
and you know repeatedly we heard from
the FBI that that they were not they
were not trying to set a precedent they
were not trying to send a message and
that they could create this magic
targeted order that would only focus on
one phone and I think we all know that
you write software once it runs in a lot
of places you know later we learned that
there is 63 ongoing phone unlocking
cases in fact a hundred and seventy five
cases existed in New York on you know
and the request could come for
additional phones as well
and you know why why haven't we seen any
any new legislation about this and I
think it's mainly because we already had
this fight we had this fight 20 years
ago
you know there's a great tweet that came
up a while and it was like I'll please
give us all the keys
what could go wrong and then later we
find out that there's a group called apt
six that had spent years inside of US
government networks consult conducting
espionage and it's you know the FBI
isn't alone in this problem in you know
blackberry in april of 2016 and I
apologize because another sponsor here
but this happened
the reality was it is that there was a
global encryption key that was used to
encrypt many phones and they actually
made a statement saying that tech
companies should not refuse
a reasonable lawful access request but
the reality of it was is that there is
still a global key
so again we have a case a weakening
encryption to provide law enforcement
axis and this is not not okay
please if you build cryptosystems in the
future please don't do this please don't
make one key for everyone
um you know much of the legislation that
we talked about it says let's build a
weakness let's build a back door and and
the idea is that there's a there's a
belief that back doors will actually
work
we frankly have to believe that there's
a set of criminals that know how to hide
themselves better than the best argument
James Bond type person and hiding
yourself really isn't that easy
you know there's a number of places
where you can actually make mistakes and
you know give away information about
yourself everything from device back up
ski backups a lot of regulation right
now is focusing around touch ID and
fingerprint scanner so can you be
compelled to give up your fingerprint to
unlock a phone and an apple made the
change recently in the operating system
that if you don't unlock your phone in
like 48 hours
you can't use touch ID anymore so you
can imagine like your phone gets taken
away from you and then the the day later
when the court order shows up they're
not able to unlock your phone so that's
that's a good good work on the part of
Apple you know you may send uh
incriminating evidence by non-encrypted
means you might use cloud storage and
you might actually call someone and
leave behind metadata
I this is a lot to ask of your average
criminal
now despite that the encryption war
continues
you know some countries have already
gone ahead and outlawed encryption and
the new crypto Wars are pretty much
global there's at least six countries in
Europe to go after and and encryption in
the style of the way what's app works
Turkey has laws against that Pakistan
has laws against that there's proposals
in the UK which we'll get to in a minute
and then the net that the netherlands
god bless they love supporting at the
support encryption so it's fantastic and
you know the idea is that the encryption
genie has sort of left the bottle a long
long time ago
we're not going to be able to put
encryption back in the box and we can't
stop people from using encryption and
you know with encryption encryption is
our best defense against mass
surveillance
and as we have more mass surveillance we
experience less privacy and what the FBI
wants in the United States has been
achieved in some other countries much to
the detriment of privacy and security
worldwide
I'm when we go and look at these
countries you know China Malaysia Russia
really really bad that the levels of
surveillance are extremely high and we
have other countries which is slightly
better but the thing is is that are
still in in the United States we have
the NSA proposing that you know
ubiquitous encryption on the Internet is
a major threat to their ability to
prosecute and 22 monitor you
so you have to remember that this this
is the way that they view the world and
I I see these estimates and the the work
that they've done as you know like the
these revelations from from Snowden and
2013 they feel that it's put the sort of
encryption world forward seven years
that they think that we are in a
position now globally with the use of
encryption that we would not have gotten
to without the sort of leak of this
information and I I tell you that's
that's good because we should encrypt
all the things it's more of a more or
less to me it's a manifesto it's a to-do
list for us as engineers to to hurt the
ability of those that would take away
our privacy and our freedom
I'm so you know where where is this all
going
I think that there's going to be an ad
arise in additional encryption products
across the board
Apple's well on their way with secure
enclaves we're seeing more encryption
being deployed in fact if we look at the
let's encrypt project which I'll talk
about in a second
let's encrypt has been very successful
but the real thing is we also will
expect government to introduce more
legislation to come after strong
encryption and promote impossible back
doors and in fact we already have that
today
so in the UK there's been proposals for
what's called the snoopers Charter and
this is designed to make the acquisition
and disclosure communications the
government easier and it also pretty
much makes hacking of endpoints legal
for the government to do and the prime
minister david cameron wanted to say in
2015 that they wanted to ban and
encryption and they wanted to eliminate
any data that the government could not
actually read you know once again it
doesn't work this way
there's no such thing as good guy
encryption and there's no such thing as
bad guy encryption
you cannot make it work because math so
one of the other aspects of the snoopers
Charter was to maintain records of
everyone's internet browsing activity
social media email correspondence voice
calls internet gaming mobile phone
messaging services to store those
records for 12 months at a cost to the
country of 1.8 billion dollars if we
have true end-to-end encryption and
always on TLS this is impossible guys is
not possible
um you know going back to us for a
moment
ber Feinstein introduces legislation in
april twenty sixteen which is absolutely
ridiculous from privacy standpoint
everything that we expected the worst
things we expected we were not
disappointed
they wanted to make all online data
intelligible in fact in some cases uh it
would almost outlaw things like
compression like basic impression of
data are password-protected zip files on
the bill defines this is anything that
could be decrypted decipher Dakota
demodulated the obvious skated and the
the reaches of this is the very far and
it's currently written we believe that
it would actually outlaw forward secrecy
and forward secrecy is essentially
having a new key on each transaction
which no one can recover if the master
keys are collected but you know when i
go back and look at the netherlands once
again i see the Dutch government backing
strong encryption and condemning back
doors so Bravo
this has serious chilling effects across
major populations like for example in
the United States a staggering number of
Americans according to this washington
post article and stop using the internet
the way they used to
and this is because of things like the
revelations from Edward Snowden
pervasive monitoring by governments and
continued breaches of personal data on
the internet once again because
companies failed to encrypt and protect
data at rest and this limiting of ideas
the limiting of opinions that they may
express online is not the world that we
should strive for
so what can you do many of you in the
room develop and work with technologies
on a daily basis
i'm sure many of your own web servers um
if you're in charge of http-based
servers and and services i highly
recommend that you implement always on
HTTPS there are other technologies that
can enhance the security of your web
service for like example
hpk P&H sts a perfect forward secrecy
and there's a number of tools available
to you things like SL labs and you can
also get yourself added to the to the
preload listing chrome which will make
sure that the browser by default always
talks HTTPS and if you think it's hard
it's it's not um if you use something
like let's encrypt uh let's encrypt as a
service that simplifies the process of
deploying and installing ssl
certificates into web browsers and
Mozilla has graciously created a site
that will tell you how to configure your
software to have the strongest possible
secure cipher suites and this is
available online for free and you know
and it's been working
because when we look at let's encrypt in
the last days i think this is a almost
last wha
less than a year less than a year we've
seen 3.7 million certificates issued and
installed by let's encrypt and that's a
much greater much greater view of
security that we've seen in the past and
you know if you're not running a web
server in your developer you know
encrypt data at risk at rest encrypted
in transit
even within your own network and you
know one thing i see a lot that's a lot
of grant proposals were people try to
reinvent a secure messaging wheel please
please don't do that anymore
um I don't think that many people are
capable of writing strong end-to-end
encryption and there are open source
libraries out there for implementing
this and we should work together on
secure messaging we should not silo this
this knowledge if you're an end user and
asthma and all of us our end users
um no your vulnerabilities know your
threat model you know you will have a
very different world if you're a
security researcher
I or journalists working in a country
that's fighting for democracy there
it's very different you know promote
end-to-end encryption and the places you
work
use strong passwords use password
managers we've probably said these
things a thousand times in the in the
security community but we still need to
keep pushing these issues and you know
other options for you with things like
tour and HTTPS Everywhere that can
protect you and from political
standpoint demand your representatives
and governments block anti encryption
bills
you can help the eff you can help the
ACLU and other privacy promoting
organizations with your donations and
your time and while we can have this
fight with technology
it doesn't really end and so we solve
the problem with proper legislation and
pressing cases and I feel that in this
we can work together to make the
internet more secure and I thank you for
your time
it's been an honor to speak to you
yeah