thank you the subject of this talk is
cast aside
LOL attacks as an example of how CPU
design can become a security problem
about a year ago from now I was
preparing a talk about how to detect the
role hammer export and one guy on
Twitter tweeted that he could do it in
JavaScript which throw my plans to the
wind and I have to figure out how he did
it because i had to find out how I could
detect that as well and everything
looked like it was going to be something
good to do with a cash and so I started
reading up on caste side-channel attacks
and about four hours later i wrote my
first cast side-channel attack
the interesting thing here was that I
was actually running my row hammer
mitigation in the background doing
long-term testing of it and it triggered
it triggered I detected my cast
side-channel attacks a row hammer attack
and was like what's going on here
and that became the start of a year
researching what you can do with the
caches in modern CPUs and what you're
about to hear is the results of some of
the results that I've gotten in this
year
so when I prepare for this talk i was
thinking about what is it that I want to
bring across here so i made a gender for
myself and I decided to put it in the
slide and the first point that i want to
make is that hard way to sign a security
implement implications
what I mean by why that is is all in
fact a lot more than just that statement
the first thing is usually would think
that if the software is written
correctly we will be safe but that
assumption breaks when the hardware does
not do what it's what we think it does
and the second thing is when a throat
CPU design is the problem is
specifically chose the work design
because this is not about bucks
this is about a design decisions that is
made by implementing the future you
so that's one of the first thing I want
to get across the second thing I want to
get across is that cast side channels
are a real danger
I hope to show you that we can do lots
of crazy stuff with cast side-channel
attacks and that this is not just a
ticket
academic study filled with which has
mostly been until now and i hope to get
that across as well
third point is that despite that these
attacks are Hardware enabled we actually
do have a chance to defend against them
in software so moving on Castle channel
attacks are attacks that are enabled by
my critique architectural design of the
cpu what this means is that cast a
chocolate axe is not a an attack on it
on its own
it's a mythology what is actually
happening is is that we can figure out
how other software uses memory and we
can use that term for secret information
what I mean by micro tech chure
architectural design of the cpu is it is
not a requirement that the cash is
designed the way it is for the cpu to be
part of the family that is there is no
compatibility problems and in changing
the design
it's just plain design decision that
could be done otherwise and hasn't
cashed side-channel attacks are probably
the most important side channel in one
computers because of the bandwidth that
the memory subsystem hold because of the
size of modern caches that measures in
megabytes and the central position in
the computer system with the bandwidth
is just a matter of how much data you
can get a crack across your side channel
the size makes it more stay longer and
be able to actually get the data out of
the side channel and to understand the
central position in a computer
I like to compare it to a side channel
in the floating point unit that could be
a side channel and floating-point unit
the thing is you can write a software
without using the floating point unit in
fact most software doesn't but you
cannot write write a piece of software
without using memory
by extension the cast stop system so
this is why I think this is the most
general kind of factional attacker is in
one computers and its really really
dangerous because side channels are part
of hardware design they're notoriously
difficult to defeat
I don't see any chances that into oils
be sending me a new cpu anytime soon
at least not without paying for it and
it is possible that because this could
be fixed in microcode i actually don't
think it can but it's possible fact this
that
no wonder has defeated cast side-channel
attacks in and Mike road so far and it's
unlikely to happen
I think because say in to have been
doing like five six generation of cpus
without fixing this problem so we are
most more or less forced to move into
software mitigation forecast channel
attacks and I hope to show that this is
indeed possible
Who am I my name is and as fuck I've
been playing with malware since 1992 and
you can reach me on twitter or by email
and if you like to get hear more about
the stuff i actually blogged about it
you can get it there
so before we proceed I should probably
say that i will be using material made
by other people and at the end of my
slides which you can download after the
talk you can get the entire literature
list and see what's mine and what's not
mine
I don't want to take credit for whatever
other people did so you don't summarize
a year's worth of research in an hour so
i'll restrict the scope here to talk
about modern intel cpus specifically
send a bridge to shoot through skylake
probably the next generation will be
vulnerable to these attack as well
this means i three through Z honest is
affected
throughout most sellers are and some
atoms as well i will mention am disabuse
from time to time just to to point out
the differences
you can do catch on attacks on AMD CPUs
as well they work differently than they
do in dental casts on attacks will work
on other cpus as well has been
demonstrated that you can do
side-channel attacks on ARM processors
on mobile devices as well so there is
many caches and modern computers in the
translation lookaside buffer system
there's caches
I have a paper coming out soon about
abusing them for lots of funny stuff
there's a row buffer cache in the
diagram that you can use for
side-channel attacks
I have helped pioneer that side channel
tech and what we'll be talking about
today is the data caches what everybody
thinks about when I hear cpu caches that
is the cash between the CPU and memory
we were focusing on the shared l3 cache
and i hope you'll understand why when we
get to it
so here I want to show that the l3 is
might be a micro architectural thing but
it's not small at all
as you can see the cast is why the large
part of the real estate and the cpu
another interesting thing that you can
actually see and this shot is that it
looks like that
below each core there is a specific unit
for that core and that is actually what
is happening these are called slices
we'll talk more about slices later
so to have a home my point to that these
things are really dangerous
I ask myself why is this interesting
well cast a channel attacks do not
respect privileges they conducted
uncross cpu cross core
cross me and crush user out of sand box
if you get code execution basically you
can do a cast such an attack
it's pretty much that simple that can be
many uses forecast channel attacks
covert channels
first comes to mind that is where a
hacker has an implant on your virtual
server and is sitting on another virtual
servers it is extracting data through
the cash and not through the
tcp IP which of course means we cannot
be detected by P kapoor deterred by
firewalls and all this kind of stuff
now I think that's mostly mostly
academic but they do allow us to measure
the speed of the side channel and we can
actually stream 720p HD video through
the cash real time so i think that point
is that we have lots of bandwidth here
more important is stealing cryptic ease
you don't actually need an implant you
don't have to need to be on the same
trust domain as the key that is being
used just need to be on the same
processor
well not in that it just need to be on
the same computer to see your keys it
has been demonstrated that you can steal
on our sake 2048-bit key on and live
amazon server if you think that it's
going to be better with elliptical
protective you'd be wrong if you think
that symmetric encryption is as much
better
well is IE s has been broken as well i
should mention here
Castle attacks are attacks on
implementation are not on algorithms
that means that our say is not generally
broken but there are implementation of
ours a which will lead the private key
if you are on the same processor same
time computer risks as an attacker and
remember this can happen from inside a
sandbox as well so there's more mundane
thing like spying and keyboard input
mouse cursor on the screen and there's
the really weird stuff which i have been
involved with is breaking the colonel I
so are you can actually do quite a nice
Colonel hassel a break with cash on
attacks
so if you think this is a wide spectrum
it's because it is is because what we're
doing and we're looking at how
applications use memory and every
application uses memory and attend to
leak information about what it is doing
and we can use this and abuse this with
cash sexual attacks
so let's get technical
how the data cache works on in for
computers
imagine that core two does a member
requests for
request for memory well its first served
in the l1 cache if it's possible if it's
not possible it will be served in the l2
cache and if it's not in the l2 cache
will be served from the l3 cache if it's
not in the l3 cache it will be checked
if it's in the l three slices on the
onion on the other course and it's not
there either
it will be fetched from physical memory
what typically happens is that the
physical memory then written into l3 and
if the l3 is already full something
something will be thrown out
this is called eviction the second thing
we need to know about this cash is that
this cache hierarchy is that it's a
so-called inclusive caste hierarchy that
means that what data is in the l1 caches
has to be in the AL - what's in l2 has
to be an l-3 without three having this
shared structure meaning that an
attacker
if an attacker is able to put something
into the l3 cache it will be available
in all course if attacker is able to
remove something from the l3 cache
he will remove it from all course and
all caches on the entire hierarchy and
this allows him to manipulate the cash
we'll see how we can use that later the
last thing we need to see that the slide
is what's not there
you don't see any rings Colonel
privileges user privileges does not like
nothing like that
it's not because i'm lazy drawing this
thing is just because it's not there
and that's what effectively enable us to
do these things to summarize it
important cast features is almost any
memory right is placed in the cash
the cash is a mirror image of memory
activity on the computer
second healthy is shared globally across
all users and privilege levels and
finalists include the cache hierarchy
if we remove memory from all three
removed from all caches meaning we can
manipulate the cash so I was memory
stored in our three
in this problem here is it takes a lot
of infrastructure and time to keep track
of the position of each byte of memory
it will be anywhere in the cash so and
we'll have
made to design decisions to solve this
problem and the first is it doesn't work
on bites it works in cache lines a cast
line is typically 64 bytes of
consecutive consecutive physical memory
the second design decision is why i
should mention that
that of course divides the problem by 64
which is but not by Phi not enough to to
solve it
so into has made the l3 cache in any way
set associative cache
what this means is that any cache line
belongs to a cast set and the cassat to
which is belonged is determined by the
address meaning that from the address
you can tell we're in the cache active
certain cache line is going to be there
are 2048 casts its per slice meaning
onto course of us before 2096 each set
can store n which is typically 1220
caste lines depending on the total cast
sides
meaning that when we request memory we
have to search Ted 12 or 20 ways to find
our our cache line
actually it's not searching buds
it's multiplexing but it's the same
thing really
so we can look at this graphically here
on CNN bent down in the memory i have
given different addresses different
colors and these callers have to match
the color of the cast set that mean that
something is green it will be cached and
set one if something is blue it would be
cashed in and set 2048 something is read
it will be casting slice one and set one
right
what we also notice here is that
intel has chosen to distribute the caste
lines / memory so that they are not in
blocks but the spread out over the
system
this design decision is so that
application that typically use memory
rather in a local area will use multiple
cast sets at once and thus have the
ability to use more of the cash
so this is very good design for
performance
the thing is it allows an attacker -
look into sets instead of working with
the entire cache which makes the problem
for the attacker much more manageable
so here is a an example code which we
can attack
I hope there's no errors in there that
doesn't have to be the function that are
written here is purely made up
it's inspired by the GDK library
implementation of keep our handling and
it is that what it essentially does is
making turning keystrokes into into
unicode chars and here my simplified
version if it's other case it uses uses
a different function to turn it into
Nakota benefits lower case
so you have these two functions and in
all likelihood they will this will be
placed on different cache lines and on
in different cast sets of which we saw
before and this means that we can if
actually if we could see into the cash
we would see that calling this function
would place different material in the
cash depending on whether your password
uses an upper or lowercase letter
this is not a real thing the real thing
is much much bigger and actually leaks a
lot more data but it doesn't fit on the
slide but i will use this example 28 to
explain the catch on the tax to the
moment so if you try to remember
uppercase and lowercase different castes
different caste lines so common for all
castes on the taxes that we can
determine if something is in the cash
how this works is if we access it the
cat cached version will be much faster
typically around 80 clock cycles the on
cash going to main memory will cost
around 200 clock cycle so we are
actually have a pretty big difference
between how long it takes to access
memory told you before we can manipulate
the cash that certainly happens in one
of three ways the first eviction this
works by accessing memory and a cast set
until all everything that was previously
in there has been replaced with attacker
addresses
then there is a flush handle has decided
as to give us an unprivileged
instruction the seal flush instruction
which we can
used to evict individual cache lines
from the entire cache hierarchy and
finally there's prime prime works pretty
much like evict
except now we access memory and a patent
so that we act the attacker afterwards
knows which addresses are in the cash at
a given point in time so I like to think
of cash or taxes
there's three big cash attacks and then
there's a ton of variation of these
three
there are other cash attacks I will not
be talking about them they all work in
the same way the attack and manipulates
the cash to a known state and then he
waits for the victim activity and then
you get salmon that's what I have
changed to see the big three victim time
primer and probe flushing load the
primitives for manipulating the caches
first part of it
the second part is how we actually see
what's in the cash
so the victim time works in this way we
execute a function and it will set of it
set up the cash and so that the next
time you call this function will go fast
and then we time the same function and
use this as a baseline then we evicted
cast it that we think is interesting and
we time to function again
so if step two was faster than step for
the function probably used an address
can go into the cache 73 meaning in our
password case which is bit unrealistic
because you can't type a password and
such a function that would work but if
you could we would know if the user has
used another case letter or not
its password so it's a bit of a problem
using this function it limits the attack
so there is a more powerful attack but
alleviate this problem
it's a prime and probe the first step of
primer and probe is manipulate the
castro announced eight that is to make
sure that a cast it contains only known
attacker addresses
secondly we wait for just wait for
victim activity and finally we time
accesses time accessing addresses
through used in step 1
what happens is
if the victim used something and go into
the set he will occur
he will throw out one of our addresses
and we'll get a cache miss when we try
to pack up and we'll know he used memory
congruent to this cast set this house an
advantage because we can just repeat the
attack running over and over again and
will not only if we do it on both caste
lines in the example function will not
only get this is using low are other
cases but will actually get how many
charges using will get upper and lower
case and where they are in the password
since the GDK function actually looks a
lot more data than that
that basically means that we can reduce
the entropy of your password if you type
in analytics or whatever box that uses
the GDK library quite significantly by a
cast such an attack
flushing load work similar to my private
probe but instead of priming the cash we
flush an address that we know to be
interesting
this address has to be shared and shared
memory then again we wait for victim
activity
reload and we time access to the shared
address if the timing is fast and three
well it was placed in the cash by the
victim so basically same deal as primer
and probe for the rest and we'll move on
to comparing them so the second time the
accuracy you get is cast set congruence
and we require a function call this has
an advantage we don't have to
synchronize with the client we know from
calling and ending the function were
when the client is running when when the
victim is running a downside is that
this is post-mortem analysis we only get
what actually happened during the
function called not what happens inside
of it
we don't get any spaceship that temporal
resolution out of that I've used the
evicted time to break Colonel SLR and
doing a modified version because it was
faster but it actually you can use this
attack to break Colonel motive case our
priming probe again
accuracy is cached set congruence we do
live analysis this time we get the
entire password and the scary thing
about this is it works well in
JavaScript
why is this important well this is
important because browsers use java
javascript and this means that cast
side-channel attacks becomes a remote
executable remote exploit finally
flushed and reload the accuracy is on
cache line accuracy and we get this
accuracy because we share memory with
the victim again
it's live analysis and there's another
advantage of this attack that is it's
faster than private probe faster means
that you get better
temporal resolution when you're spying
meaning that if you're spying on a
cryptographer them and and want to get
real real nitty-gritty data you're
better served with fresh below than
private probe like a low doesn't work in
JavaScript
well it actually does but it's not like
it's very useful so I had let this .
stand in my slides shared memory is
unfortunately not as rare as one would
think
there are shared libraries think of
kernel32.dll in Windows the code of it
is mapped into all processes in the
system and and distributed to each of
the processes from through the paging
system so it's just physical memory
mapped into others
this is enough for us to do catch all
attacks on this actually happened to
every library reload on windows so
there's plenty of shared memory
it's not just windows the dust is most
operating system standard procedure
then there's another future this is
called deduplication this is where the
colonel or hypervisor searches for
identical pages and physical memory if
it finds wanted free is one of them and
uses the paging system to provide for
the client's needs throughout the system
this works even on virtual machines my
personal opinion is this should not be
used on any system for any reason it
just a security nightmare
it basically not only allows you to do
flashing below to tax it was only that
it would be bad but there's
deduplication attacks you can speculate
on doing row hammer across GM food
deduplication a recent touch paper i
think i read it monday use deduplication
to get an influence in the edge browser
and roll hammer its way out of the
sandbox
so you shouldn't be using the
application if you are well
all bets are off i think yeah
cast and side-channel attacks are not as
perfect as one would like they're
inherently noisy and the reason is there
is other code than the victim running on
on the computer
well that's one of the reason so so if
that code uses the same cache lines
it'll disturb prime probin and the
victim time if it uses the same casted
will disturb that
another thing is these are essentially
timing attacks and there are the shared
substance systems in the cpu and other
uses of these substances will change the
timing of the information
this is not particularly important for
for the basic comcast side-channel
attacks because the time difference of
hundred twenty clock cycles is pretty
substantial will take a look at that a
another kind of such an attack in a
moment of variation of flushing load
where the time difference is much
smaller where it becomes a real issue
then you have interrupt from hardware
and whatnot which disturb you
and finally you have the hardware
prefetcher both attacker and victim and
unrelated code can trigger the hardware
prefetcher to load cache lines into
memory and this of course will cause
false positives in the cast such an
attack the except for the hardware
prefetcher problem the solution is
repeat the attack and rely on the law of
large numbers of course you cannot ask a
user to enter his password 10,000 times
but you can expect that on a web server
your key will be used a couple of
thousand times it so we could get
results
so moving on to where the where a lot of
my worker lies is detecting cast side
channels
i'll be using such as loaded as an
example of how to do it it
the method actually does work for other
cast such as well first we have to need
need to know something about performance
counters performance counters are built
into the cpu we have 18 performance
counters on on mon lentils that we can
program to count my province
there's a lot of micro instead we can
count including destruction instruction
is decoded and interrupts received and
of importance to us all three cast mrs.
and l3 cache
references
now also you can optionally get an
interrupt when the counter overflows and
we can actually set the counter as well
which allows us to get an interrupt on
any instructor any instruction that
causes these events
this has two effects that is that we can
use this to keep track of how many
caches arrives in a particular time
segments and we can get an interrupt
frame and actually analyze instructions
that causes these events will use both
these methods to detect different kind
of side-channel attacks in a moment
on a side note here we can use
performance counters to look for
security related witness
it's not just casts a channel attacks
you can look for rootkits you can look
for brohamer for returned object of
programming and stuff like that
flush and reload here it is since shoe
to assembly code
first we manipulate the cash to a known
state with a steal for construction
then we wait wait for the victim should
probably won't make a common here in the
wait
save your trying to spy on a keyboard
there'd be no reason to be fast about it
you could wait a few milliseconds and
nobody actually types that fast
are you spying on crip to you probably
don't want to wait and all you want to
be as fast as you can be
while repeating this attack so what
essentially is happening is you're in
the race condition with the victim
you're running on different course and
you always want to be before the caches
is cleared so don't wait then the rest
of it is just timing acts accessing the
shared address i do this here with more
of instruction it could be any
instruction that a success ask access
memory the infant's instruction is
because the cpu is capable of
reorganizing memory requests and the
infant's prevent that the attack
actually works without it but it works
better with it and the rest is just
using the idea T&C instruction to get
time and depending on how long it took
that you calculate the information you
want
so how do we detect this
well the marv register shared address
when the victim did not use the shared
address we get to cast miss here
in fact if the victim uses to share a
dress that we just flushed will get a
cash is there
I think about caste mrs. is that they
are rare in reality real applications
and we can use this to Detective
performance counters my original
suggestion was to just interrupt
every number of cache misses and look at
how long it took and and just have a
value if it was too short while we have
a cast such an attack and that worked
pretty well on most guests a channel
attacks since then other researchers
have improved it somehow put the
performance counter data into machine
learning and find that works pretty well
others have just compensated for general
activity and memory subsystem by using a
proxy say
captions references or something like
that and this makes it a bit better with
less false positives and this false
negatives because mainly because that
when you have high activity and memory
subsystem you get in a cast mrs. as a
result that are benign now but in
general this works pretty well
so if you're wondering about the story I
told you in the beginning about Roe
hammer
if you look at this and remove
everything that has to do with timing
and do this on two addresses you get
this and that is in fact the original
code for the original roll him our paper
roll hammer was flush and reload
it's no coincidence that i actually my
role on my detection detected my flushin
reload attack
those are you interesting in row hammer
throw him a jas that I was trying to
detect replace the seal flush
instructions here which are not
available in JavaScript with Victor
teens that work just by accessing memory
in a patent which of course is possible
in JavaScript
so what often happens when you come up
with a good mitigation is that somebody
comes along and figures out how to
bypass it
and this time is no different I actually
had the idea before so when I was
approached by Daniel gross and Maurice
Clinton teen about how we go about
detecting up side-channel attacks that
doesn't cost as much cash mrs. i
immediately said all your your timing
seal flush and that gave me a the
opportunity to actually review the paper
on on flash and flash
so the basic idea about it is that
flashing an address from the cash is
slower than the cash when the address
you're flushing is actually in the cache
logic behind this is obviously that the
instruction can shortcut and doesn't
have to do as much work as when there's
actually something in the cast - so here
you have chute assembly code for the
flash and flash attack and the only
thing that's changed is that the math
instruction has been replaced by CL
flush the authors of the article called
this a stealth side-channel attack and
we can speculate about the reason and
the reason is flash and flash does not
have a reload face and that means
there's no mom no shared address meaning
we get no cache misses meaning that the
detection method that are originally
proposed is not going to work very well
so we can ask performance Candice's
useless
the answer is no we can actually do
something with them but i can just see
that i have enough time to
go off subject the flash and flash is
advantageous in many ways over the flash
and reload the thing is first thing we
should notice is the new seal flush
instruction is much faster than
accessing memory because it doesn't have
to access memory that means it's just
about twice as fast as as a success in
memory
this gets flash and flash bit better
temporal resolution when you do it in
attacks
the second thing is the seal Fletcher
instruction itself will actually return
the cash to a known state meaning that
if you repeat this attack
you don't have to go back to the first
year for construction you can just go
right to the way to face this makes it
faster again and this gives it a lot
better
temporal resolution and much more
bandwidth has a side channel
in fact the fashion flush the attack is
the attack
you know which have the colder side
channel which can stream video in HD
another thing about flash and flash
that's advantageous of explained earlier
that the hardware prefetcher sometimes
get problems and one of the good thing
is that the seal flash instruction does
not trigger the hardware prefetcher so
that that's a nice feature of it
it can be the victim still triggers the
hardware prefetcher so we're not the
problem is not solved but it's a less
relevant so returning to the subject
detecting flushing flushing the core
idea about detecting flushing flashes
that it always has a certain structure
it's a seal for construction bracketed
by high-resolution timers the oddities
the instruction in short sequence and we
can ask ourselves if we can detect this
and the reality of it is that we can
so before that we can go on to actually
detecting you know flash and flush will
need to know some things about how we do
it
and first I should mention that the this
detection does not work on cross DM with
deduplication enabled systems
it could mitigate the problem a tiny bit
so that the attack around and other vm
couldn't use kernel mode has to use
kernel mode to do the attack but he
could do that
I don't think this is a big problem
because I think you should turn off
deduplication and that solves the issue
so thanks for that we use to carry out
this attack is that the rtt SC
instruction can become privileges
privileged if we set a flag and CR for
registered the TSD flag
this will cause an access violation to
be generated every time but this year
the audience the instruction is used
we will use use this to get notification
of of DTC's and what we'll do is we'll
use the access violation handle to
emulate the RTC so that we will not
interfere with the nine clients also we
need to look at that we need to talk
about that attacker cannot spend much
time between the RTC and that is because
on on multi-core CPUs
there's lots of things going on and the
at this add noise to the channel
there is a significance to fashion a
difference to function load here
the thing is fluttering below you have a
hundred and twenty cycles of difference
in timing with flash and flash as much
faster the difference is much smaller
than just a handful of clock cycles and
as a fair bit of noise so will you
the attacker is not capable of waiting
too long before calling his next RTC
instruction to end the timing of the
attack
the final thing that we need to know
about this is that when a seal flash
instruction actually flushes and address
in the cache performance event is
generated and it's a performance work
cash reference event unlike cast mrs.
cash reference events are quite frequent
again this is a testimony to how well
the l3 cache actually works
performance wise but we can actually use
this for building a detection
so I have designed this detection to be
a two-stage attack a two-stage detection
I have two reasons for doing this
the first reason is that the second
stage is expensive
performance wise and thus we want to
avoid doing it on benign subject benign
applications
the second reason is that this two-stage
the detection method is pretty flexible
in terms of other
microtek torial attacks that due time
instruction timing and I have this weird
feeling that we're going to see more
attacks of this nature in the next
coming year
so I like to be prepared to detect these
as well
what we do in the first stage is that we
try to detect the bracket of ITC
instructions and here we use this year
for TSD flag to get an access violation
and count how many times do we see our
DTSC instructions less than type 2 micro
seconds apart the two microseconds a
tuning value to micro sections seconds
is a pretty conservative
- what an attacker can actually afford
to spend between our two instructions if
we get more than to work occurrences of
that in two seconds
well we should proceed to step
stage 2 which is detecting this your
first instruction if we do not we just
do it again to make sure that nobody is
starting a new york flash attack
so stage two
so here we again use the CEO 40s
deflector get on interrupt on RTS see if
we get this interrupt within half a
second of being in stage two
we know that it was not flushing
flushing we can safely return to stage
one
however it was less than that we
proceeded to set up performance counting
on interrupt references
now when we do get a reference on get an
interrupt on the reference event we will
use this in her up
we'll ask ourselves that we spent more
than two microseconds since the last are
DTSC and if we did we know that this
particular oddity is the instruction is
not part of your flash attack early or
it's the end of us your flash attack
so we'll return to the first part of the
stage 2 and to the next part is
instruction
if however it was fast enough after the
ITC instruction
well we'll use to interrupt stack frame
to find out where memory
these instruction across the cash
reference is placed and will read memory
there to check if it's a seal flash
instruction
obviously it was a seal flush it
instruction we will assume that this is
a flash and flash attack and that is
pretty fair assumption given that are
ttc instructions are rare and seal flash
instructions are really really rare
in fact swear i have not found a benign
program that actually uses one but
that's another thing if it's not caused
by a seal flash instruction we could
assume that the attacker has put in a
cash reference in an event to lead me
astray to upscale his attack and that's
the way reason that we go back to
setting up the for performance counters
to get an interrupt on the next cache
reference event and then we just repeat
from there
so are there any problems with doing
this
well causing interrupt penalizes
performance on benign programs using our
DTSC and programs using RTC is actually
fairly rare
there are some visual studio so it's fun
programming stuff like this when your
visual studio always crashes search
indexer stuff like that uses are you to
see but it's very rare
so we're not causing too much
disturbance in that direction but there
is another problem
possibly worse problem with doing this
since we are you spending time handling
our interrupt and emulating the idea to
see instruction we actually make the
timer less accurate for mitigating cast
such an attack that's actually a huge
advantage but it might not be for benign
applications which are also affected so
we should be aware of that
then there's the question of is there
any other time as the naughty tsc and if
there is how will that impact the
detection of that's pretty easy to
detect entire detection hinges on the
IDT she already is the instruction being
detected
somebody suggested that i could have a
threat running and in this thread that's
just count up an address until another
thread tells us to terminate
I've been playing with this I've been
unable in any way to show that this
actually is fast enough for accurate
enough in any way to do flash and flash
with it
I'll be happy to should be shown
otherwise I don't think it's happening
there are the colonel more times
including performance counters and stuff
like that or IDC could be lead from
kernel mode and that of course will
break my detection as well
finally there's a big problem with the
implementation and implemented under
windows and you run into this funny
thing called patch guard that prevents
me from looking interrupt my solution
was actually using windows XP for my for
my implementation of my generalized
testing
I have not seen too much performance
cost of this that's a about a percentage
but it's very very very much
across platforms the thing is i have not
seen a benign program that actually
makes it just to the second stage
I just not seeing it doesn't happen but
she'll flash dresses every time and when
you finish something like this you
always ask yourself can you do better
and I actually think we can and this
will be part of my research for the next
year and i hope to blog on it sometime
during this year
maybe it won't work so maybe you don't
see anything but maybe well so doing it
like this you actually have to admit a
lot of stuff and I left all out the old
all the gory details and that was
intentional because we don't really have
time for it
things i left at with things like how
does the process to decide what to
victim when we access other memory
called the eviction policy
how do we determine to which Kass said a
cache line is congruent
these are things that we can all do it's
all relatively recent at the reason the
reason that research that shows us how
we can do it in the past it has been
done by another side channel attack or
timing attack on figuring out of when
something gets thrown out of the first
things like that and i should mention
there's other mitigation forecast
side-channel attacks the sideline
this is as opposed to detection i'm
actually not aware of any other method
for detecting casa John attacks other
than the ones i've talked about today
now there is a future in modern see on
computers called cat
I believe it's short for cash allocation
technology
it's a performance-enhancing feature but
it can be used for actually providing
privileges for the cash
it doesn't work very well in my opinion
and and this is why I did most of
Wallace chose to ignore it while it did
a little bit
this stuff another thing you can do is
you can write branch free cast set aware
code
now what we saw in the example was that
we feature that allowed us to support
what was going on in memory was that we
branched and you can imagine things like
a raise and stuff like that
being being spybubble and if you to make
your chrome really really careful you
can actually make sure that you don't
read any vital information by being
aware of what Cass said you're using and
why and avoiding branches and stuff like
that
turns out it's pretty difficult to
actually do this
a recent example was that the openssl
library hot and there ra implementation
to be branch recast aware and as it
turns out somebody figured out a
different cache side-channel attack
which broke the new implementation
this was called cash bleed it's not like
we cannot file that as well but it is
quite difficult and I don't think it's a
method for for the broad things
it's not like we're going to have a
colonel that's branch free cash said I
where at any point in time it's just too
expensive and too difficult to write
it's not like we're going to see
application developers handling your
password in any kind of way
branch for you cast aware so it's great
for crip - but it's not going to solve
the problem
so I've about reached the end of my
presentation I hope that you have all
taken to heart that CPU design
we're talking about CPU design here that
it actually poses a danger to bug free
software
I hope you have all taken to heart that
cast side-channel attacks are actually
quite dangerous critters and quite
powerful and finally I hope that you
have a general idea that we can we can
do something about this in software and
we can even do something about this
software when the attacker is adapting
so my closing remarks will be that
defeat want one that's going to make a
closing keynote and she will be touching
this kind of stuff you can be sure that
you'll find me there
I hope to see the rest of you guys well
if your questions don't hesitate to ask
I to love talking about this stuff
it's a hobby of mine and I don't do this
professionally it's a hobby
this means that if you have questions in
connection with this talk please ask
them if you want to talk in private
please get hold of me if you want to
email me do so thank you
ok thank you for the talk
I'm sure we all learned a lot about it
and does anybody have any questions
hi Cheers I was just wondering what the
what was the rule hammer detection that
you were running that you mentioned at
the start
I'm on your own machine the role of a
detection basically it's the same as as
the function below detection I talked
about here basically uses performance
counters count cast mrs. and if you get
too many and too short . well its not
benign software it's going to be Roma it
turns out it could also be flushing load
but either way its not benign
it just doesn't happen on compute well
it can happen but it's really rare and
so for most people is going to be good
enough but there are false positives so
and things like lip quantum
like weird stuff that access memory and
weird patterns and a lot of time to hope
that answers your question
well how much will be having a shared
memory is a requirement to attack shared
memory is required for flushing the load
and variations thereof which includes
flush flush the thing is the reload face
you access memory to find out the state
of the cash after the victims run for
Prime improvement of it and and second
time we are using cash code congruence
which is a lower door criteria that
means that you actually don't have to
share a can access to memory
meaning that you can do cross DM attacks
whatever you really like you don't need
to know anything about that addresses
that is not your own to actually do this
so private probe for for cloud things
it's probably be one to go to where
Victor time is probably more of these
special use cases
you know the answer we talking about
physically tagged cache lines or
beautiful Italian - lines and not sure
about the Intel Architecture I wasn't
going to talk a bit louder
yep are we talking about physically
attacked cache line sort of usually i'm
sure it works on the only Intel our
collection
I know another stuff but the question is
that you have a our physical address
memory right
I want to talk about addresses i talk
about physical address ok
it's all about physical addresses the l3
and l2 caches are both driven by
physical addresses
which is a light which allows us to my
bypass the paging system the l1 cache is
a is a bit special in that direction so
running attacks on on the l1 cache is an
entirely different different story
doesn't doesn't disposed a requirement
that you know actually the physical
address of the day that you want to
attack
well it's one of the things that I
admitted what you typically do to find
out find out cash , congruence isn't the
physical address if you're using large
to make about Paige's the virtual
address actually leaks enough
information to do it but what you do in
in cases where is that you do a timing
attack on castro chrome gruen see
so by loading say in different addresses
and then timing what how long it takes
to to to access them adding one address
timing or 11 at some point you'll find
out
oh I created a cache miss and you will
know that you have within the set of of
data you'll have a set that is congruent
right
ok thanks also look ok any other
questions
okay . and then thanks a lot again for
the dark