who have you heard about me
before today makes you noted that's ni x
sending it yeah that's our problem so we
have a company we are usually found in
the Netherlands but the existing like
excellent since the eighties in Finland
it's so originally a US company that's
why they let us are eunuchs mangled and
make sure
and what you know about finished people
is they're not very outgoing exciting so
they do a lot of business and 75 years
and which I started the internet and
since ur exercise this first februari
what we want to be different it's we
don't want to like me but making out our
employees so we want to be a community
base and I don't know how to box instead
the netherlands and we try to share
knowledge fire
Thank You Barry pay attention Bobby fish
fish always the same people
ok so the issue is what want to share
and all that so it's about the people
getting knowledge and sharing knowledge
so our assets
Bobby please so our asset is the people
and we wonder in have two people
involved that that's why we don't do a
long time
assignments and we want to have no one
percent contracting because the people
should be involved in our assets are
people would evolve and we want to be
more like a community and also we have
to make money of course but sharing
knowledge is out . saying that's why we
were interested in hosting this concept
rack because it's all about natural an
error and knowledge sharing the whole
conference is I myself very much
involved in all ways with a notice for
free and it's a contract to be able to
have people here talk and get multiple
free
that's all we need to thank you