okay you guys can all hear me alright
great so i am going to talk to you guys
today about something called pentesting
chat ops
who here in the room actually knows what
chat Ops is raise your hands
ok so that's about the half of the half
that raise their hand is it because you
saw my talk before
I thought so alright so so chat Ops is
basically a really good idea that i
stole from github within the company and
it's basically about a sort of a CTF
like workflow that we use for our pen
testing company that works really
incredibly for us and I think also for
those of you who also do pen testing
here in this room I think it might also
work really great for you guys so but
first eight tiny bit about our company
so we're a bit of a funny
yeah Oh kind of weird thing I what we
are is first of all and nonprofits a
computer security consultancy company
sounds a bit strange but basically we're
just a commercial front end for a
non-profit back and the bat nonprofit
back and we support as the end on that
foundation but that's actually not
important for our story
what's important for our story is that
we have a bunch of a pen testers that
are actually distributed around the
world
ok we were purely with freelancers and
the head of my pen test team for example
is this dutch guy who lives in Brisbane
Australia
that's far away I've got some testers
that are located in a 12-person majority
of them are in the Netherlands and in
Europe
I've also got staff members in the
United States and you know so basically
we've got pretty much every time zone
covered if it you know
first which is both a blessing and a
curse right I mean it's a curse because
you know
it's really hard to have all hands
meetings not that I like meetings anyway
but you know but nonetheless you know
about and it's a blessing because of
course we can kind of go around the
clock go working on stuff without
overworking folks
so anyway what what
oops so the way that we actually work in
terms of a shout out is that you can see
right here
basically there is a in a chat room uh
you can see right here a list of a
number of the people that are you know
our staff members sometimes also
customers and basically we're using this
tool called rocket chat
ok raise your hand if you've ever used
slack okay let's have the people here
so basically rocket jet is an open
source self hosted version of slack
we absolutely love you no slack and its
functionality but of course we are not
planning on giving them our customers
pen test data if you know henceforth we
find a nice open source version so we
can host it ourselves but uh of course
uh well it means you basically have to
set it up for yourself and the but it's
actually been great because it's open
source we've actually been extending it
now chat Ops is basically a concept that
was originated by get hub and github
also is a globally distributed company
so I think that I mean they have some
kind of office and in Silicon Valley but
the entire rest of their personnel is
located everywhere
so the way that they work is they have
actually taken their entire DevOps and
they've actually are protected things as
such so that they can do their entire
DevOps operations from their chat room
okay with the idea that they can
literally you know deploys deploy UVM's
patch things basically do all kinds of
different upgrades configuration changes
all the usual DevOps you know chef huh
but Papa danceable you know who usual
them up stuff but the thing is they use
this chat but that's called Hugh bot
HUP OT
essentially it's just a chat bot to that
you can also use an IRC
you can also use it you know and
campfire slack you know a whole bunch of
other different channels and the way
that they actually had it set up was
that you can basically a you know do all
those uh you know operations and able to
do new deployments to their website i
mean literally they have all kinds of
continued to continuous integration
stuff you know that that's running out
of the chat they have network monitoring
stuff that's going into the chat if you
know so that a distributed team can
actually have full visibility on what
each other is doing well you know what
when I heard about them doing this
I was like well first of all I said this
actually sounds a lot like how a
distributed CTF teamworks thick because
of course actually a lot of what we do
at our os's is inspired by capture the
flag it and you know the end for the
rest
you know I figured you know this would
actually really work great for pen
testing if you know you're basically
having a distributed team and trying to
make things visible and other thing also
that is sort of an added bonus is with
radically open security we also have
this this thing that you know we're
really big on openness and transparency
what that means in practice is that we
actually invite our customers to join us
in the chat room now the really nice
thing about Chad Ops is it means that
any time we're working as long as we're
actually launching our pen testing and
launching our reporting and launching
all of our other thing parts of our
operations
it means that if a customer there is
there on the chat room they can actually
observe everything we're doing 50 which
actually has led to a really good
formula that customers are extremely
happy with who you know and that
actually really having this kind of a
chat
integrated environment really enables
which is actually much much harder to do
if you're just sort of working in the
office
50 you know are using other kinds of
other times of tools so i can give you
guys some examples basically of how this
works and first you can see right now
that
with you box so we basically renamed
this raw spot
of course if you know and we have
basically installed a whole bunch of
different tools all kinds of different
things that you can use from the chat so
it ranges from totally useful
I mean things like you know being able
to do various kinds of you know look up
some different kinds who is mrs. and you
know these kinds of things to you know
you know to to being able to launch
scans
you know four different kinds of pen
testing - you know the completely stupid
and inane like I mean you can't have a
chat without like cat photos or XKCD you
know
so we've actually got you bot scripts
for all of this
so we've also got a also sort of this
raw spot shell commands that we're using
four inputs and physician because of
course yes
like the day I installed this the first
thing my guys tried to attack it and
then the second thing they did was wrong
spot image me go to you at which point I
was like stockport the Channel please
put but anyway so
ok but but what that means is we can
actually though the way that it works is
you use a coffee script to basically
right to the integrations between
whatever script you would want on the
back end and then the chat bot
you know the actual interface and in the
chat and then essentially you can write
with this your script on the back end in
whatever language you're comfortable
with
if so so you know a really simple
example of something that we've
implemented is nmap you know good and
it's basically nothing more than just
being able to feed a certain number of
parameters to and map that are supplied
on the command line of course obviously
we do need to do input sanitization and
do other forms of access control because
if especially if customers are in the
channels with us we need to be a little
bit careful about you know who can
actually operate which you know commands
within our chat environment
so what
yes we thought about that as well so it
but but there's number of really weird
and wonderful things that we can do from
the chat now here's a pen tester knows
that the most annoying part of pen
testing is reporting that documentation
you know I mean I you know it's really
time consuming you know I mean we just
want to have the things you know and
then afterwards are like we really have
to write it up
yes you do but so what if you know but
of course us like any other a pen
testing company
we of course build our like a sweet to
automate this because you know i mean i
know that they're still companies out
there that are you know cutting and
pasting things into Word documents but
does it
I could but I tell you
yeah but i can tell you from like you
know the first couple months of our my
company's existence before we had
automation that doesn't ok cutting and
pasting stuff to open office is not what
you want to do so
so what we did is we wrote this XML
Swede
so what it is is there's xml templates
and the pen testers can basically just
fill in the templates and they actually
really like this because you know it
provides actually a structure for the
pen testing and sort of reminds them of
what kind of information they have to
write down as they're actually doing the
testing and then the also another nice
thing about with xml as if we have for
example common a sort of what we call
snippets so for example commonly
occurring
things like cross-site scripting you
always need the same description of like
okay this is what cross site scripting
is and this is how you remediated and
you know obviously we don't want to
reinvent reinvent the wheel so we have a
little snippet library which is actually
pretty soon we should be open sourcing
that they were so kind of collecting all
the snippets it together right now but
the basically just so we can also kind
of you know toss that you know into our
XML in the right place and so that if
you just need to compile that it just
sort of comes out correctly so another
thing about radically open security by
the way is that we're really into open
source
we love open source and what that means
is every tool and framework that we
build once it's ready for the light of
day we open source it
you know I mean so we basically just
trying to optimize for the amount of
self and you liked give away just
because we can so so r XM l a-- a pen
testing suite is actually in good in
github so if you guys happen to have a
pen testing company and you guys are
still working with Microsoft Word or
what not to feel free to steal our
system and use it
it's actually extremely useful if you
guys also want to do automated scanning
within a big huge mega corporation you
guys also need some kind of you know
system you can just basically steal our
stuff put in your own corporate logo and
it's actually really pretty easy to use
so this is not yet official by the way
but we're actually having discussions
right now with a loss about potentially
trying to also make it in a loss project
good so I think if it is hopefully will
be happening i think in the next
you know hopefully couple weeks so that
would actually be cool and further help
to spread and canonize you know the you
know the fact that this is sort of a
free tool automation you know for
everybody who does what and testing and
other things
so uh there's all kinds of documentation
now that we've written it's actually
quite quite decent and you can sort of
see right now
it explains how the reports are
structured you can actually see right
now an example of how we would be
writing up the findings we've got things
like section section ID
you know different cross references you
can see up here sort of like title you
know paragraphs images
you know well anyway set stuff
xml basically descriptions of of what
we're doing and then when we compile it
it turns into something that looks like
this yeah if it so that looks pretty
good
if it so um so what we do is we can
actually we've set things up so you can
actually compile this from our chat
environment
so the way that it works is and now
we're going back to the rocket jet is
you can see now we've got this a raw
spot shell command PDF build a customer
named blurred out of course
hey you know a pen test and then at that
point to what
what's happening is it says wrong spot
so first it's actually doing a git clone
i should also mention by the way that we
use a get lab as our primary means of
version control and sort of
collaborative editing it within our OS
on
we use get lab for our private stuff we
use github for our public stuff
obviously we try of course to to move
stuff over from get lab to get out of
this as much as possible so but but what
you can actually see is happening is
that when you type in that command the
first thing that it's doing it so doing
a clone from git clone from the gate lab
refill
now what it's doing is it's actually
calling the toolchain so we're basically
using a sort of xml xslt fault you know
that that whole system to basically
generate our PDF so you can see that
it's a compiling the PDF and then what
is actually happening is it's actually
committing the PDF that was created back
into the repo
ok and then what it's doing is its
spitting out a link to the PDF so
basically what it means is that
technical writers and pen testers don't
even necessarily have to install the
tool chain on
local machines all i want to do but
nonetheless
what it means is that they can be just
issue a command in the chat
it compiles it spits back a PDF they
click on it they see it easy
ok so so that's the way that we that we
have things set up so so really think a
lot of things are just sort of you know
interactions between you know from
rockets at to get lab handout sort of
and back
another thing i should actually also
mention that we've been doing I don't
have a slide about this but we've been
doing this increasingly often is also
even using Rock rocket chattin and chat
ops things also even more for not just
like you know also for our tools but
also for project management but and
we're actually using a were using Kanban
internally to manage our workflow for
our entire pen testing procedure well
process because of course we've got a
lot of members in the fire and we need
to like you know if you take care of
them
so what we're doing is we're also we
even implemented stuff you know from the
chat room that also even interact with
our the can board software that we are
using it so we can even be able to get
reminders and this is absolutely awesome
we're implementing right now we're a
reminder system so that if there is a
test on our can board that has been idle
for a week like for example if we sent
in a quotation to a customer and we
haven't heard anything back
it literally injects pings into the chat
room to remind us
yeah I am so it's really just turning
this this chat environment and to sort
of this you know control room if you
know for people distributed online to
just be able to you know kind of do all
this
for the whole pen test process and it's
really powerful and there's a lot of
something you can do that do with that
by the way also the reporting stuff this
is also just as quick screenshot of the
get left
I just you can also see how some of the
XML structure stuff is structured and
busy findings on findings report
oh it's probably a little bit less
interesting but in either case of other
things that we can do from the chat is
tools so we have already implemented
several kinds of tools of course we try
to open source them after we build them
one example of a tool that we
implemented the open source is a passive
scanning tool
so basically what it does is it takes
the outputs of showed on and also of
basically
well you see scans on iOS called census
now and what you can actually do is they
basically put in an IP address and then
basically you can spit out the
information that it gets from the
passive databases
you know a sort of passive recon wise to
you know be able to
well who is it I'll tell you you know
before you even start doing an active
attacks you know what some of the
problems might be because this is of
course useful stuff to report customers
you know the great thing about this is
if you can integrate the stuff of your
chat environment you can launch it from
the chat
you know it can run the scan it can
check the results in to get lab you know
and then we're also working right now on
basically some more basic scanning
good stuff we actually just a well-made
a partnership with sort of a large IT
insourcing company who also sort of
wants open source basic scanning and
we're actually trying to set up a bunch
of things right now with a whole suite
of the typical compliant scanning kinds
of tools like nmap nikto
you know just a well and SEO is a
checking ssl certificates you know these
kinds of things so that we can basically
do the scan checking in to get lab
trying like script you know right rights
and scripts to actually extract the
stuff out that we need and then put it
in the XML template so that when we
compile it can sort of put the right
thing into the right ways
so this is sort of the the automation
that we're busy yeah is he working on
it's a work in progress of course but
this is basically the direction that all
of our stuff is is going
and of course once its belt we're gonna
we're planning on open sourcing it
Oh another really novel thing that you
can do with this kind of a pen test
shadow ops environment is you can do
something called red blue pen testing
so what this is is I took with one of
our customers a development team for a
basically a software development team
for a product
ok and the software development team was
a number of coders number system mins
some dev ops people and what I did is I
split the team in half and I said okay
have fun you guys are the red team have
you guys in the blue team and each team
is basically guided by one of our
professional testers and we actually had
the customer do their own dentist
so we basically turned into kind of like
a CTF competition we gave a fight it and
we actually wrote our own scoreboard
that we use of course you bots for you
know the chat bot for so that if for
example somebody scored you can see
right now
like for example here a point for blue
for finding missing input validation
you know and so and then what we had
this thing is you could go good job blue
and then you can see now it says
incremented blue 24 points and then it
you know show you this like freaking
awesome
no rainbow unicorn I just perfect
you know and we basically had a pool of
images you know from the interweb so
does of silly stuff that we could spit
back to them you know what kind of a
game of light you know for what they
actually did something and we basically
it was a one-week contesto that we did
with the customer
we had 10 10 of their folks which of
course is a huge time investment for
them but you have to remember this is a
CTF exercise for them actually could you
know it's kind of like it's secure
coding training it you know in a way it
and at the end of the week they had
found 40 findings in their own product
they had found a full attack chain
through their own product ticket
you know and the best part about it was
they did it themselves
you know and and during the wrap-up
session with you know these guys
one of them literally said I am never
going to look at coding the same way
again
you know and that is precisely what we
want and we were able to do this
basically for the cost of a two-week pen
test for them you know one week of
actual pen testing of course one week
cleaning up the report that they made
because they made it incredibly
humongous mess out of it
it's not actually of course I just took
us a week to fix up the xml so we could
you give them a decent-looking report at
the end but you know that that's I mean
of course the real time investment for
them of course is that is the time of
you know 10 people for a week
if but you hope that the education that
they get out of it of course is it is
going to bear its fruits you know rather
continue to software development process
but this is really the great thing about
with the whole channel
I mean it really puts you on an equal
playing field just on an equal level you
know with your customers and especially
if you're online
geographically distributed team like my
company is it means that you know the
customers aren't even outsiders it's not
like were crowded in office working
together you can you know it's like you
know because our chat is our primary
communications platform it means that we
can actually fully adult and fully be
able to take along you know the customer
in a way that it's almost like
integrating them with our team and
that's only possible if you're working
online in this kind of chat environment
I mean even you know if you're working
in an office you tried inviting the
customer to your office i'm not even
sure you know to what extent that would
really be practical
you know but with this you don't you
basically all they need to do is just
have to have rockets at open and they
need to passively observe or actively
participate
so this is all really pretty great so
what else can we do
well you know there's a whole lot of
different things that you can integrate
with with chat
one example for of something else that
we did for our customers we actually
implemented a a spearfishing sweet
we're still cleaning it up at some point
when it's ready of course i also want
open sources as well but the point is
that what we're the way that it works is
that we had this number of scripts so
that we can do is actually instrument
create instrumented phishing emails and
then what would happen in
so the phishing emails would then have
links of course to something on a web
server Beckett clack click the track
interviews and of course also that could
attract a place and we actually had that
tied in with our chat environment so and
also the customer can even observe this
in real time so that every time one of
their employees either did an image of
you or click we were able to see it in
real time
so who you know and again instead of
giving a level of visibility into what
we're doing that is you know
cool quite frankly you know it's
actually it's fun because you can
basically launch launch it and then you
can basically just sit there and watch
you know the clicks come in
you know and watch the image of you to
come in so that's a that's actually
really pretty pretty fun
other things that you can launch of the
chat environment
I mean of course i already mentioned
they like scanning and exploitation
tools so any of your standard you know a
scanner scanning tools basically that
you would use your pen testing you can
probably automate it with rock with you
bought so that you can launch it from
the chat
so an absolutely three a sequel map I
drew for brute forcing stuff you know
this is all within the realm of
possibility
some of the stuff we've already
implemented from the chat other things
are on our to-do list
you know we're working on it but in
either case is what we envision things
like recon so who is google also as a
joke we implemented
let me google that for you but that
wasn't good enough then we had to
implement to let me . go that for you
so yeah and are passive scanning sweet
things like her biography
I mean things like hash cracking I mean
why shouldn't we be able to launch
you know hash cracking from from the
chat you know it's just convenient
so are other things that we can do email
and
SMS integration a wide region
spearfishing already
I mean basically anything in your in
your operations where you would need to
launch it and it makes it sort of
helpful you know if you can
another thing also is that if you have a
team working together
you know you're not going to get the
question of like hey what if you don't
already know and that makes also
coordinating a team really really easy
because they can each just look in the
chatroom see what the other person is
done looking get lab
another thing i should mention is we
also have to get look get hooks in the
chat room
so every time somebody doesn't commit to
get lab we basically get a report of
that
so both the you know the pen testing
team members as well as the customer
basically can see sort of blow by blow
every single check in that we're making
which means that we don't even
necessarily need to ask the question
have you already
you know done whatever because it's it's
just you know it's obvious from looking
fit
you know if so yeah so it just make
stuff really easy
anyway so this stuff is really at the
core of how we work
I mean I think it's a new workflow it's
an innovative work flow and it's one
that really is working extremely well
for us I hope you know hope we can
continue to you know be able to sort of
package these things up nicely and be
able to put it out there and get hub so
hopefully anybody can use it
I mean I would absolutely love to help
my competitors
ok you know that please use our tools
they're actually really quite awesome
you know if if if we as radically open
security can also help to make you know
the rest of the industry including our
competitors more awesome than that
that's even better
so I so please a you have a look at our
tools of you know and it's also open
source so if you guys do happen to use
it useful for you and you think hey this
is great but i really wish there was
also liked you know that are you put in
the future requests or even you know if
you do implement it you know
share the love and you know they can
give it back to us you know with a
suitable open source license as well
I mean it's basically just open source
so anyway this is going
I talk I hope you guys have thought it
but found thought provoking and I would
be extremely happy to answer any
questions
nope
how do we deploy it to ya
uh all right now I mean oh yeah I mean
we we just installed it there basically
on a vm so I mean it's not that we have
set up things have optimized yet to kind
of package it up so you can just at some
point that would really like for us to
use some kind of you know docker chef
and simple
you know that you know things so that we
can basically make it easier for other
people to set up of course right now I
mean we're still sort of innovating and
figuring it out so I mean right now
we've still been installing everything
manually several civilian and trying to
what Smith is ok sure
yeah contact me after please so what if
anybody else is actually interested in
trying out this stuff and working with
you know it i would certainly be very
happy
you know to work with you guys and think
along with you guys because you know we
ultimately it's better for us to do and
the more brains you have you
cool yourself one that being so are
there any questions
nope
ok oh yes I'm not as easy I'm just
wondering why I'm sure you know why
would I make it a non-profit oh I didn't
mention that because I was trying not to
make this is a you know a sales pitch
but doesn't know in a in a nutshell the
reason why i made our own is a
non-profit is because the market leaders
at least in the Netherlands for the
security industry are quite commercial
and not everybody in the hacker
community like that it you know because
hackers are very idealistic
I mean much like the open you know the
hacker community has a lot of close ties
with the open source community
we just want to make stuff better we
actually don't really care about money
not usually if you know you're making it
for our bosses that's completely years
so i think it is seriously so I wanted
to set up something that basically if
anybody got rich i really wanted it to
be a charity
you know something for the community so
I decided that we would support the NLF
foundation the internet foundation is
basically a foundation that's been
around for 15 years I have supported
projects like tour and eff & goo & jetty
and academic research and you know all
the kinds of stuff like makes the
internet better
good you know and we set ourselves up as
this thing called a fiscal fundraising
an institution and touch of disc golf
balls barefoot in spelling which means
that contractually we have to give
ninety percent of our profits to a
foundation and L that is that foundation
is actually a construction we stole from
the church's perfect seriously
because churches sometimes want to do
commercial spin-offs and then and then
they want to get the money tax-free back
to the church again
a famous example of this in the
Netherlands is a language institute
called a regina coeli and there's these
a nun's that are called the Nolan fun
food
it is actually this is actually the
language institute where queen maxima
learned and very much improved her Dutch
you know this is this is actually an
example of a fiscal fundraising
institution in the Netherlands
so we basically stole that idea but we
just decided to make an L met our church
so that that's a that's basically how
we're how are set up and you know and as
as for the rest of it openness
transparency open source i mean this is
definitely just like an attempt r OS is
an attempt to reclaim if you know
security consultancy for you know the
purposes of really making the world
better
through security because security is for
the common good
it should be for the common good you
know if we can optimize for helping
customers you know our employees and
society instead of optimizing for
shareholders and investors and founders
and you know I mean ultimately you know
we hope to create a vehicle that will be
better for society in the end also want
a meta-level the whole concept of a
not-for-profit company we figure if we
can make this work in the computer
security space
who knows median like four or five years
we might be able to also teach workshops
you know explaining how other people can
do physical fundraising institutions in
other fields like healthcare agriculture
but you know so if you can just
demonstrate this as being a new kind of
social enterprise
you know maybe it'll be a cool idea that
other people can run with surprisingly
enough
actually as strange as this all sounds
because this is all really strange and
weird and different
this is actually really been taking off
r OS is now two years old but we already
have 40 freelancers working together
and we've already had more than 30
customers but that a third of which are
repeat customers could you know and at
least that probably you know two-thirds
of which are sort of the usual suspects
in terms of light touch a corporate life
government you know you know the other
30 days are like little not-for-profit
hippie organizations that are willing to
help for Ospreys physically so yeah so
that's kind of how it's a gone
you know we're hoping to shake up the
industry you know with the way that
we're working because what we hope is
that when the customer can look over our
shoulder we hope that they're going to
get so spoiled
but if you know by having that kind of
view that kind of visibility that amount
of knowledge transfer into their
organizations that i am hoping that they
are going to go
they're going to go back to our
competitors and say hey radically open
security is offering this people for our
shoulder service
can you guys do that - yeah and then
there
of course gonna have a choice you know
they can offer it for their customers
might walk away you know and in such a
way
we're hoping to make the entire industry
fit more open and transparent but you
know we're trying to offer that
alternative and raise the bar for
everyone you know and I hope that we can
do it
so maybe that's it that's enough about
that
the company anyway thank you so much for
your time and if anybody has any more
questions for me to be happy to take
them afterwards
so thank you