thank you and
so my name is McMullin and i'm going to
talk today about the processes that I
use when I reverse engineer wireless
protocols and devices
I'm now on the security research team at
bastille networks that involves doing
protocol decoders reverse engineering
unknown protocols and implementing
software-defined radio decoders for them
as well as doing vulnerability research
I've taken kind of an unusual path to
get into the security space so i'll
provide a little bit of background back
in 2011
I competed in the DARPA shredder
challenge which was a competition to
figure out how to reassemble shredded
documents and until that time that was
the most complicated difficult project I
worked on but I discovered that i'm kind
of a fiend for these really hard
problems
so a couple years later sharp announced
the spectrum challenge which is a
software-defined radio hacking
competition and I didn't know anything
about SDR at the time but I signed up
after my positive experience with the
shredder challenge
I ended up doing well i'm bad and
through that competition i thought my
way to best deal where I am now and then
about 9 months ago I joined our
vulnerability research team
my first project on that team doing a
threat research turned into a mouse
track which is a collection of keystroke
injection vulnerabilities I found and
non bluetooth wireless mice and so the
context which I approach this is kind of
coming in from a relative outsider to
the security space and figuring out you
know how most efficiently can i tackle
these problems so we're going to start
with a bit of a primer on radio stuff
this is from you know my contacts as
somebody without the fundamental
education in that space then i'm going
to discuss how we can use open source
intelligence to increase the speed of
the reverse engineering process that
will be you know what information can we
get to take work away that we otherwise
would have to do and I'm going to walk
through the process of reverse
engineering the specific radio shack 2.4
gigahertz wireless mouse and then
finally I'll do a demo of a mouse track
attack which was
the result of these methodologies
so let's talk about radios so on high
level we have hardware and software
defined radio shows the hardware to find
videos that would be your your Wi-Fi
dongle is you are you know
bluetooth on goals your wireless mouse
on goal the cellular modem in your phone
and it's going to be anything that's a
purpose-built to do one thing really
really well but the problem with
hardware to find radio is you can't do a
lot of research things with it because
it's you know does one thing really
really well but if you don't know what
that thing is that you need to do
it's not going to be very useful so
software-defined radio allows you to
have a high degree of reconfigure
ability
so you might have a wide range of
frequencies you can tune to vary in
bandwidth but the drawback is that it
doesn't know how to do any one thing
so the SDR will just send this raw radio
data to your computer
I'm or to an fpga and then you have to
implement the functionality that makes
it a you know Wi-Fi radio or a bluetooth
radio or whatever but very useful tool
for doing this kind of reverse
engineering because you can reconfigure
it on the fly as you're figuring out
what it is that you're looking at
so modulation is kind of a fundamental
concept of how you modify radio carrier
wave to encode your data
so on this picture here it can't see it
very well somewhat blurry but this is a
FSK modulated signal from the hotel room
and it goes left to indicate a bit 0 and
it goes right to indicate a bit 1 and
this is a very simple type of modulation
but it's very common in these low-power
wireless devices because it's a
low-complexity receiver to implement and
therefore you don't need a lot of
processing power and you don't need a
lot of battery to implement the receiver
another common low-power protocol or
modulation scheme is oh ok which is
on-off keying this is also very
straightforward when the transmitter is
on
it's a bit one transmitters off a bit 0
also common in these low power devices
because it's low complexity and then you
have some other modulation schemes down
there you have
Graham an ofdm which are used in 802 11
as is DSS you have frequency-hopping
spread spectrum which is used in
bluetooth but the the gist of this is
that you don't need to really understand
the fundamentals of how these modulation
schemes work because a new radio you can
simply drag and drop blocks which have
all that detracted away and as long as
you know what modulation scheme you need
you can turn the radio waves into bits
so that is the concept of symbols and
samples and sampling
so a a symbol is you know one duration
and time that represents one or more
bits so for frequency 15 and on-off
keying each symbol is one bit because
you're either on or off or you're over
here to the right or to the left and
frequency but with the higher-order
modulations you can have you know two
three four five bits per symbol but
typically these low power devices have
modulation schemes with one bit per
symbol because again it requires you
know a poor quality receiver and easier
to implement
another thing to remember is that you
need to sample at twice your symbol rate
so if you have a frequency shift keying
modulated signal and each bit is going
to be one simple and because of math
which I don't understand you need to
sample it twice that
so you have a 1 megabit per second
frequency shift keying signal
you need to sample at to make a samples
per second and just knowing that you
need a sample at two samples per symbol
is sufficient to use your radio to
demodulate this data and we have
frequencies and frequency hopping
you know you can see in this context is
just a specific channel device operates
on a device might use you know one or
more channels it might hop between these
channels bluetooth for example will have
deterministic frequency hopping between
79 channels you'll have something called
frequency agility where a transceiver
will select the channel that has at
least interference but a lot of devices
we'll just camp on one channel and stay
there
then you have travel coding this is
adding redundancy to the data you
transmit and this can be either you know
adding additional bits adding parity
bits you have a RQ where the receiver if
it gets a packet out of order
it will ask the transmitter to send it
again and these are just mechanisms to
make sure that the data gets across one
thing to note from a reverse engineering
standpoint the channel coding that if
you're using you know a convolutional
code for example the bits transmitted
over the air will not look like the bits
that you're actually transmitting not
like the original payload and so if
you're looking for the original payload
and this demodulated data you may not
see what you're expecting it channel
coding is used so now we'll talk about
the process that i go through to reverse
engineer protocol and we have maps of
this is where where everything started
with mouse track i was looking at a
large number of devices in a relatively
short period of time and so is
approximately 50 keyboards and mice for
different families of transceivers and
around 20 different protocols and and
payload format papers because it was
such a wide range of types of devices it
necessitated being very efficient about
going to the process in order to not
waste time and so as a result of going
through all these devices
I've developed a fairly efficient way to
do this so there are a number of things
that were trying to get out when we
first enter your device
I like to think that there's both the
business and personal case
so from the business case you know we
want to see can you identify this device
what type of device is it is it you know
big to be a normal behavior or aberrant
behavior if there's an attack happening
can we recognize that then for the
personal case it's just very satisfying
to be able to reverse-engineer these
things and like it's no one you want to
crack it and you understand how
everything comes together it's it's
sprayed and so there's the kind of a
combination of personal and business
personal and business motivations that
go into this
so then we have kind of three cases of
devices that we want to reverse engineer
the top
you know fully standardized
that's not really doing any reverse
engineering because everything is
defined so the physical layer so the
modulation the frequency is a channel
hopping all that exists in aspect that
you can go read not to say that certain
devices will not implemented correctly
but the idea there is that everything
you need to know is available for you
already
now we have partially proprietary this
would be cases where you have you know
maybe a transceiver which is documented
so you might know what the physical
layer is so that the channels and
modulation
but you may not know what payloads are
being transmitted and then you have
fully proprietary devices where you know
nothing about it
so you don't know what transceiver uses
you don't know what protocol uses and
you have to figure all of that out and
the case with this radio shack mouse
it's fully proprietary and that there
was no information available not no
documented information available about
this to start with
so with this mouse
we really need to do some open source
intelligence gathering and find out what
information is available there to speed
up the process because it was starting
blind
it's a pain in the ass so we have the
five stages here we're going to start by
doing open source intelligence
this is going to be using the internet
to find out what we can about this
device and how it operates
we're then going to verify with the
spectrum analyzer that the information
we got on the open source intelligence
is correct this is going to be you know
visually looking at it and saying hey
this is everything up
you know make sure we're on the right
track so we don't waste more time then
arch the bites want to point out our is
what we internally call you know radio
wave source kind of a universal word but
in this context arts debates means
taking the radio waves emitted by this
device in this case you know mouse click
movement data and turning it into bites
on disk that we can then parse and
operate on
once we have those bites on disk we then
need to figure out what the format is at
the packets that were sent over the air
and then we need to figure out what
payloads are in those packets and what
is the protocol and behavior of the
device
so first we'll look at the open source
intelligence process
there are few good resources for this
the FCC in the United States has a
wealth of information and there are also
in a product specifications you can get
for certain transceivers
so you might have a case where a
particular device uses a transceiver how
they use it is proprietary
but the underlying physical layer
communication of the transceiver is
documented and so in that case it's
useful to find that spec sheet figure
out what configurations they might be
using you can save time then bye
you know narrowing down what you're
looking for and then the google is
fantastic it's I mean
enough said so if everything goes
perfectly
we really can learn all the information
we need to know about how this device
operates
that might be all the physical layer
properties and also might be the packet
formats and protocols behavior depending
on the device
but you know at the bare minimum we're
hoping to find at least you know what
frequencies to operate
what modulation doesn't use and what
channel which does use so we can turn
those radio waves in two bites
so in order to sell the device in the US
you have to go through the SEC
certification process so it starts when
you make your device you then send it
off to an accredited test lab the test
lab will operate your device in an
environment and it will basically see
what the RF behavior is that might be
things like you know what channels that
run on what's the duty cycle what power
is transmitted and then the test lab
generates a test report that then gets
sent to a telecommunication
certification body which says you know
did this test lab do everything
correctly
did they follow the procedures and so
forth that then gets sent to the FCC if
everything passes they get an FCC ID and
all these documents get posted online at
the FCC website makes available and we
can use those as a great source of
information that one thing to note is
that many devices will have one
certification for all of the regulatory
bodies so have an FCC ID
you know in icy idms ipid and so forth
and so for devices sold outside of the
US you can usually use
FCC if it's gone through the same test
procedure so FCC exhibits are what they
call the documents that are posted when
a device is certified and you have a
number of different types of documents
and you can get them by looking at the
FCC ID on the device plug it in at the
URL and they get a list like this
usually a bunch of PDF documents
so there are a handful of exhibit types
that are relevant to the reverse
engineering process a test reports are
the absolute best
this is where the art emissions are
evaluated part of the difficulties that
you have a wide variety of formats of
test report so you have you know 2500
test labs each one has different formats
and varying degrees of information and
there's no guarantee that any test
report will have any specific
information that you want but it's
usually a pretty useful source internal
photos is fantastic
you know they open up the device take
photos of it so you can look there and
look for no specific model numbers on
the RFI seas and that sort of thing
user manuals are interesting because you
have you know a lot of them are our
consumer facing nothing terribly useful
but some of them will have you know deep
technical information for whatever
reason schematics
usually these are kept confidential so
when you submit a device to the FCC you
can request that certain exhibits be
kept confidential either temporarily or
definitely some labs and pcbs well for
whatever reason leave their schematics
open in that case you can often get rfic
information and so forth and then
operational descriptions again usually
confidential but usually have some good
deep technical information so the test
reports
this is looking at you know that CCS
certain regulations for how a device can
operate this is evaluating for your
transmit power bandwidth frequencies and
duty cycle but often contains modulation
types frequency of information and its
interests and it varies between the labs
so this is an example of the test report
from Barrow veritas
they're probably the largest test lab
and they are nice because they have a
good amount of structured data
so in this case is from a logitech mouse
and we can see here you know that it
uses gfs k modulation but operates in
this frequency range tells us how many
channels
elsewhere the report tells us the
specific channels that are operates at
this is kind of the the best case
scenario for what you can get from test
report enforce the most will have less
information in this and also there's
that gives us there the transfer rates
we know that it's a to make a bit data
rate this is from the test report from
this radio shack mouse here it's do
clearly not as structured of data but we
can see you know
here we see Stephanie six channels 1
makers channel spacing
we don't yet know what the modulation
scheme is this is from the intertek test
lab and now the dongle in this case was
certified separately by neutron
engineering this case it's probably you
know some other ome the product and
whatnot but in this case we have more
structured data
unfortunately this is different
information than we saw in the mouse
so here we see thirty four channels
first the 67 from the mouse but we see
that mystery FSK modulation we can see
the data rate of one megabit and and
it's at you know these discrepancies
between test lab reports for the same
products can be kind of frustrating but
just have to kind of filter through that
and and get a consensus for the
available data so with internal photos
this is kind of a frustrating thing you
know some labs will have you know high
resolution photos and better than the
pdfs but a lot of them will have you
know propped or low resolution photos
sometimes I'll take a you know a
permanent marker and draw over the
markings on the r fic to make it
difficult to find out what's in there so
it's it's hit or miss but sometimes you
can get useful information
so this is the internal photo of a
Microsoft dongle in this case I can't
make it out there in the image on the
projector but it has the markings where
you can see what specific transceiver it
has this kind of the best case where you
have you can make out the transceiver
and it's something that's what
documented we can just
go and get the spec sheet and then
implement exactly what the spectrum
defines this is the internal photo from
this mouse
unfortunately there's no useful
information the RFI see is under little
epoxy mount there and so really we can't
get anything from this this is the
internal photo from the dongle again
no no useful data I mean this is typical
but you know sometimes you can actually
get out the arts I rfic model
information from that the schematics
this is really really hit or miss most
vendors will not make these available
but in some cases they are and so in
this case for the radio shack mouse we
can actually see the specific model of
the rfic unfortunate in this case it's
kind of a Western own manufacturer
called Mozart semiconductor who makes
this
they don't have any publicly available
documentation but it's still something
we can google for later
and most of the the big name companies
will not make this data available so
operational descriptions and user
manuals again
you're really hit or miss so the
operational descriptions will say you
know this is on high level how this
device operates
sometimes it will include transfer
information physical layer operating
characteristics but you know that as far
as I can tell there isn't any good
structure for what this data has to be
and user manual same thing I mean
oftentimes its customer facing how to
use this often times it has good
technical depth
this is the operational description from
the radio shack mouse
now here we have somewhere data so it
says on their 2.4 gigahertz bluetooth
module and it's likely not bluetooth
doesn't mention that anywhere else
again the case we have this deal while
be very in data between the different
available sources but it does say that
FSK which lines up with what we saw
elsewhere
it does tell us we have 67 channels
which lines up with what we saw in the
test report for the mouse and it also
mentions the same ma 4302 rfic
unfortunately no more detail on rfic but
it lines up with all you see in
schematic
this is from the dongle user manual
this is kind of an interesting case
where you have physical layer
information in the user manual
so this tells us again gfs krf I see one
megabit data rate we see this channel
range
apparently you can only use it and human
house it's unclear what that is intended
to mean
and so now I googled around a bit for
this rfic googling for the RFI see
itself yielded nothing useful but
searching for you know mouse plus you
know ma 430 to produce this product
which is this company sweex appears to
be a mouse with the same transceiver in
it
so here we can get a little bit more
data we can confirm that it's you know
FSK modulation in this case it says its
frequency hopping and we don't really
know if that's the case or not but it's
an additional information that we can
use to confirm what we've received from
other sources often times these type of
devices you'll have a purpose-built rfic
so this one seems to be made for my sins
so searching around for that you might
get some additional information
so now that we've gone through these
sources we have a fairly good idea of
what the physical layer radio
characteristics are for this device
so here we can say with confidence that
his gfs k modulation we can say with
confidence that this frequency range
we know that it has some number of
channels that will you still need to
figure out we know that it's a 1 megabit
data rate and it has said bluetooth and
frequency hopping but that's likely not
the case but will confirm that
so now that we have this information we
can have the device generate some
traffic in this case you know moving it
around or clicking the mouse button or
whatever and look at that with a
spectrum analyzer using a software
defined radio and with this we can
confirm whether or not the information
that we have so far is accurate
so there are number tools that are
useful for this kind of scenario and you
generally want a software-defined radio
that's hard to do without our testing
closure or Faraday cage is very very
nice for you know multiple reasons you
can you
get rid of any noise in the environment
and if you're buzzing and whatnot you
can keep that contained a new radio is a
great software suite for abstract away
all of the signal processing and radio
site of this and so that allows you to
not have any you know deep background in
this but still be productive and Angie
are false for is a spectrum
visualization tool that you use with new
radio a bob line is another spectacles
visualization tool with new radio and
then you need the device you're going to
look at
so for software-defined radios and i
like to use the u.s. rpb to tens is what
we have at work there
no great device there are a lot of
different options for SDR is that are
fairly cost-effective you can get
depending on what you're looking at you
can even get away with these little RTLS
dr down goals that are really cheap
they don't work in a 2.4 gigahertz range
but I'm very accessible for a lot of
projects and again with SD are we can
configure it to be you know whatever
physical layer we want so in this case
we can tune it to the specific
frequencies that the mouse is likely to
use and no define using new radio how
we're going to modulate the data so the
radio is a combination of C C++
libraries as well as Python code and it
has no modules or blocks they call them
for domoj elated all the different
modulation types doing you know error
correction time in recovery
there are new radio stacks for doing a
bluetooth and Wi-Fi and no - 15 for and
all sorts of things
I'm really great ecosystem around there
and that a really nice thing is that you
can you mock up a prototype very very
fast without much forethought
this is new radio companion this is the
user interface that sits on top of new
radio and this allows you to drag and
drop these blocks which do different
things and so you can have a block which
does your FSK demodulation i'm a block
which connects to your software defined
radio and so forth and so it allows you
to not really have to understand what's
going on under the hood but you can
still get done exactly what you need to
get done
this is a screenshot of gr for this is
the spectrum visualization tool
so here we are looking at frequency on
the x-axis and time on the y-axis and
services a snapshot of some LTE traffic
this is nice because you can tune your
radio to a certain frequency and very
quickly determine exactly what's
happening so you can say hey is there
something there is there not
it's kind of you know good for doing
these sanity checks
this is Bob line so bottom line is an
independent tool and then there's the gr
- ba zi new radio block or module rather
which allows you to wire up a new radio
- Bob line a bob line is nice because
you can pause the spectrum as it's going
down in real time and expand it so this
is the case of some FSK modulated data
and you can even see that it's going to
left for a bit 0 right for a bit one and
you can almost visually make out what
data is actually being transmitted
this is an example our test enclosure
this is what we use at work
these things are are really really
fantastic because you can put your
devices in there you know
SMA cable out to your software defined
radio USB out to your computer and so
you can interact with your SD r and your
device
the same way as you went out in the open
but you're protected from everything in
the environment and for determining
exactly what our devices doing this is
very valuable because you can know for
certain that you're not looking at
traffic coming from something else in
the world
and so this is a very very simple flow
graph which has our input from the
software-defined radio there you have an
output to gr foss for and this is all
you need to get up a spectrum this
visualization tool and visually verify
that the information we got from the FCC
documentation appears to be accurate
so this case were camped at 24 20
megahertz looking at 40 megahertz band
with because we think that there are 34
or sixty seven channels but we don't
know is it helping or not you know where
does align the spectrum we want to look
at as much as we can so we can you
quickly see what's going on
this is the set up inside the test
inclusion on the left that USB goes out
to the computer on the right that
antenna connects out to a
software-defined radio and then it has
gloves conveniently so you can operate
the device and interact with it just
like you would on the desk
this is the gr foss for plot from just
the dongle alone in the Faraday cage and
the idea is that the dongle is going to
transmit to the mouse either acts or
sink packets or whatever and the mouse
is also going to transmit to the dongle
so in order to be able to determine what
is coming for the dongle we first start
with that and we can see that it's
transmitting these packets at regular
intervals and that is camped at 2414
megahertz
because it's transmitting at regular
intervals we can infer that it might be
you know timing synchronization
information
the way a lot of these devices work the
dongle will decide what channel is going
to be on it will transmit this data than
the mouse will search around fine with
the dongle is and then camp there so it
looks like that's what's happening here
now we have the mouse and the dongle in
the cage that zoomed-in view over there
this is a 3 packet grouping when i'm
moving the mouse around so the
assumption is that the first packet is
that dongle sink packet the second
packet is likely the mouse data and then
it's reasonable to assume that a third
packet is a dongle acting back to the
mouth
so even though we're just looking at
this visually we can start to make some
assumptions about what the protocol
behavior is for these devices
so now we can say with some confidence
that we know you know that the
modulation
we know that is camped at 2414 megahertz
so now we can record some data and turn
that into bites using the new radio this
is another you know simple flow graph
we're using a to make it hurt sample
rate because we're a 1 megabit data rate
and we need two samples for simple
so we're starting with the usrp input
for demodulating the data were the
output of the modulator is one bit per
bite so either a 1 or 0 8 bit unsigned
integer so we're packing that into bite
so that we have eight bits per byte and
then we're writing that to a file so we
can run this it will you know capture
the RF data coming out of the mouse and
the dongle and the result is that we
have bites in a file on disk that you
know ideally represent what this device
is transmitted and so again you know we
want repeated sequences
I'm a packet so if we're looking for
something it's easier to find something
if it happens over and over and over it
so you know the dongle by itself it's
sending the synchronization packets and
so we can just put it in there and it go
for the mouse in this case I put my hand
in the club and just SAT there and click
the left button over and over again
so we could have the same packet
repeating in the output results
so now that we have these bites on disk
we need to investigate them and trying
to figure out what packet format is
being transmitted
because we know we can infer anyway that
the bites we have some of them at least
have come from the mouse and fungal we
have no idea what the format is so we
need to you know use you know common
tools to get that data
so there are a number of components of a
typical our packet you'll have a
preamble at the start and this is used
for clock synchronization and timing
synchronization
so you have a oscillator in the dongle
oscillator
mouse they're not going to be
synchronized because they're low quality
and so the receiver needs something to
lock on to you so you'll have an
alternating sequence of ones and zeros
for example and then the receiver can
look at that time its clock to match the
transmitter and makes it easier to
correctly to code the data
well then often have a sink filled or
start a frame delimiter this just says
hey the packet is starting here
sometimes the same field is the address
sometimes you'll have a cig field which
is static for a type of device and then
you'll have an address after that you
might have a header which indicates you
know what type of frame it is what the
frame length is and so forth and they
don't have to pay loads of the actual
data being transmitted that might be
just the raw payload or it might be the
payload that has been encoded some
channel coding and redundancy and that's
you know Peter missed if you don't know
what the protocol is you'll frequently
have a check them at the end you know so
you can know the correct date it was
received and then you also might have a
post animal with the post down below
this is for additional time and
frequency correction
so you can compare the preamble of the
post and once you've changed
I'm in further clock state of the
transmitter so I'm a big fan of abusing
these just regular linux command line
tools because you know you can just
really quickly get to the data so I you
know I start by using XD to turn the
light output from new radio into a long
text string and then we can wrap that
and do these normal things like we were
on the text file and it's a really makes
it easy to operate now
one problem is we're operating at these
bite boundaries so we've we've taken
these bit outputs and we packed it in
two bites but the start of a packet
might fall you know at one of these bit
offset so it might start three bits into
a bite
because of that we're not going to see
every single packet but the assumption
is at least some of the packets will
fall at a bite boundary and then we can
decode it
so preamble is often going to be a tone
which would show up as you know
00 or FX bites and also might be
alternating ones and zeros
which shows up as a a or 55 x characters
and so we start by simply grabbing for
repeated sequences of those characters
and seeing what shows up in a repeated
manner and in this case we have that for
F followed by 12 days which shows up
so the longest repeated sequence that
shows up quite a few times and so we can
make an assumption that that is likely
going to be the preamble that the dongle
is setting out with the sink packets
we don't know that for sure but it's you
know probably a safe assumption so now
we want to find you know what sequence
of bytes follow this preamble and so we
can just use grep again and we start
with the preamble
in this case we're looking for 4s
followed by either 12 days or 12 fives
actually you have you know FF and 12
days and you shifted by one bit you get
4 s followed by 12 fives and so we want
to cover all bases and then we want to
look for the longest sequence which
follows this preamble
so in the grip string up there there's a
16 at the end and that is the number of
characters following this preamble that
started you know a given number and so
in this case i started with one and work
my way up and tell at 17 characters
there was no longer repeated sequences
so you can assume that that 16 is
probably the falling of the packet
and now
these were the strongest thing packets
so we want to do a sanity check and make
sure that it looks like they're
following the behavior we saw in the
spectrogram so in this case we screw up
again and we have the be flagged
pasadena grab to give us the offset in
the file where these packets occur in
this case we can see that show up in
multiples of two thousand offset more or
less
so we have your kind of even spacing and
so this is probably a safe assumption
that these are the sink packets that we
saw on the spectrum analyzer
so now we can start looking at the
capture of the mouse + hangul in the
Faraday cage now because we made this
assumption that this byte sequence is a
packet transmitted by the dongle
we can just use said and remove that
from the output of the mouse plus dog
the idea they're being that if we have
you know whatever is left over was
transmitted by the mouse and probably
not the dongle
so we run said isolate the mouse packets
and then we go through the same
procedure looking for the preamble for
the mouse packet in this case we have a
potentially different preamble
we don't have the same 4s followed by 12
days or fives and it's it's not
immediately clear which one of these
might be the preamble
so we go to the same process of looking
for repeated sequences following these
and just go down the list and try each
one of them takes a bit of time but
necessary in this . so in this case what
works the best was 4 a's followed by a
number of bytes and however we don't
have just one packet that shows up
repeated a bunch of times we have this
list here and we see we have the one
character which varies so this is likely
going to be a sequence number
everything else is the same in the
packet up to that point we have that
vary in there and then we have these two
bites at the end which vary so that
tells us that it's possible that this is
a sequence number that when that changes
that were modifying a checksum at the
end so that you know when we can infer
then that we're probably going to look
for a 16-bit crc at the end of the
packet
and now we can do the same standard a
check the ellipsis in the grip there is
just a grip string for all of the
packets that we think we found from the
mouse in this case we see you know more
or less similar even spacing
they're spaced out further apart because
i was no manually clicking the mouse to
generate this instead of doing the
automated process from the dongle
but it looks like it lines up and so we
probably found packets coming from the
mouse
so now we have these candidates for you
know what we think of the packets
we have the dongle sink back it up there
that's the only thing we've seen
transmitted by the dongle that were
aware of
we then have this list of mouse packets
and we have those four bytes which are
the same between the dongle in the mouse
packet because we have that same in both
cases the assumption is that that is
going to be either a single word shared
by the devices and or the address and
then we have these preambles and post
animals both the dongle and mouse
packets and with FF and then we have the
for a preamble for the mouse packets and
then that 4s followed by 12 days
preamble for the dongle and now the
question is you know what is this 16-bit
see our CEO is it a crc could be
something else what is it
so that the lowest hanging fruit is this
tool called crc reg you can just pass
that a sequence of bytes experts in this
case and it will run through common and
then brute force uncommon CRC's to tell
you you know is the same crc at the end
of each one of these bites sequences in
this case as they were no no dice it
didn't find anything
and I've Stan frustrating but that
happens so now one thing to consider is
a lot of packets will be whitened
and this works by you know exhale bring
the payload of the packet or the entire
packet with some value
you know to avoid long runs of ones and
zeros and the data and so forth
there's no magic bullet here I just went
through and try deck serene you know a
lot of that common whitening sequences
so this case exploring the entire packet
with 0 x 5 a bites was a magic bullet
but then the last two bytes in the
packet the checksum where the first byte
order
so in this case explore the entire thing
with 0 X by the repeated and reversing
the last two bytes for the checksum
worked and then pass it into crc revenge
and then we see that is the X modem
variant of crc 16 ccitt and now we know
ok we have the full packet format more
or less for the mouse
so we know what has you know this
preamble
we are assuming those four bytes are the
address that may or may not be because
we only look at one mouse
so we can't say for certain that another
mouse would have the same or different
address value we know that it has a
payload of three bites followed by the
crc in the post temple
so now that we've figured out the one of
the packet formats that we can go back
and start to figure out you know what is
a protocol behavior here and so you know
this requires usually some additional
time and testing devices so the the you
know low hanging fruit here is just
getting another one of the same Mouse
and you run through the same procedure
and see what changes in this case the
second mouse had a second mouse and
fungal had a different for byte value
for that you know sink order address
so now we can assume that those four
bytes are in fact a unique identifier
for the mouse and uncle and are specific
to each device pair you want to go back
and look at other packet formats as well
so this was just looking at mouse clicks
we want to go back and generate the same
data by clicking the other button or
doing the scroll or moving the mouse
slightly left and slightly right and so
forth and just make work your way
through and and build out all of the
different back formats but then we have
these tenets relax and it was unclear
initially what those would look like
they were acts we haven't seen those in
the decoded data yet but we can do is
simply grab for the address we have now
that we know that the address
rep for that and the data outputted by
the dongle and the mouse in the Faraday
cage and we can see that we have that
for bite payload sequence
following the mouse packet by three
hundred microseconds and so this is
something
is that this is in fact the ack with
only four bytes
we force don't have room for crc but
going back and testing this with
different types of mouse movement
packets and clicks and what not and it
you know quickly became apparent in this
case that that was the act just not
protected by a crc so we have an idea of
what the packet for it is for both the
mouse and the dongle and now we want to
go verify what the timing is so the
Assumption here
based on the spectrogram is that we have
the dongle transmitting packets every 16
milliseconds just following every dongle
packet the mouse has an opportunity to
transmit a packet if it does the dongle
then acts a few hundred microseconds
later
and so knowing this behavior we can then
you know potentially build a father
start transmitting etc so we have
knowledge of the packet format but we
don't know what data is you know
transmitted in the payloads the skin you
vary wildly but in this case we know
what we're expecting to happen so we
know you know we can generate the same
thing over and over again for clicking
the movement and so forth and so we need
to simply collect a bunch of data see
what changes in the payload when we
change different behavior so different
cliques or Scrolls or whatever and then
based on that we can infer what the
format is of the payloads being
transmitted and so in this case we have
a sequence number which is one nipple
we have a one nibble frame type which
changes between movement first scroll
and click and scroll and click have a
button states that's going to be down or
up
we have a button type which is either
scroll wheel or a regular but you can
click and then we have the button
delimiter so you left right
scroll up down etc and getting this data
is just a matter of going through the
motion of you know literally moving the
mouse and seen what changes
so now we have a fairly good model of
both the you know packet payload formats
and protocol of this particular mouse
so we know we have for packet format we
know we have the dongle singing packets
we have the acts we have no movement
click and scroll packets
we know it's true FSK modulated at a 1
megabit data rate we know that at camps
on one channel in this case the other
mouse camp that I think 24 20 megahertz
and never changes
so it appears that for a lifetime of the
devices that they're likely at the same
Channel
we know that you know TMI information we
know the dongle transmits the sink
packets and so forth
we know that you know the mouse will
always follow the dongle sing packets
and this is not always the case but in
this kind of pdma setup you'll usually
have you know the mouse will get his
timing information from the dongle and
it were inferring that uses 34 channels
and the channels that we saw in use
were at and for megahertz offsets
so based on that it's it's likely to 34
channels that we saw in the docks and
not 67
I'm it's not blue tooth that's not
frequency hopping and we know that it
uses the export variant of crc ccitt now
this process for the mouse was you know
one way of doing things but then I've
also been looking at in my hotel room in
the past couple days this little tiny
quadcopter and for this I didn't have a
Faraday cage here just str my laptop and
so I was visually looking at the data
using bloodline
now here's what it looks like when you
have just this remote turned on you can
see with the remote on that it's you
know transmitting some kind of same you
know civilization burst or what not to
the quadcopter every 15 milliseconds and
we can see that that something is
happening there
now if we zoom in a bit
this is with the quadcopter on and
communicating back to the controller we
have those top burst in each set which
line up with what we saw with the
controller alone and then the second
more powerful bursts below so that might
be ax coming back to the quad copter and
the point of this is that you can do you
know quick visual analysis and get some
useful data without even having to break
out the Faraday cage and do anything too
complex and here we have zoomed in
further on the packet the controller the
packet from the quadcopter here because
we can actually see the frequency change
from a downed up 40 and one you could
actually you know work out exactly
what's being transmitted by simply
visually looking at it and writing down
you know what each bit position is this
is a little bit less robust of mechanism
but for you know quick and dirty
analysis of protocols
you know this kind of thing works works
pretty well so to recap the process used
here we start you know you are open
source intelligence we look at the FCC
documentation we Google around and so
forth and we find out everything we
possibly can about the physical layer
operating characteristics of the device
we then verify it with the spectrum
analyzer the Faraday cage it possible
and make sure that that information
it looks correct we then use your radio
to turn that into bites or bits on disk
now we can just grow up around and start
finding this packet formats
once you have a packet formats then we
can work out the protocol format or
protocol behavior and the payload format
for the device and this process is you
know pretty effective and for something
like this you know it's a few hours in
an afternoon to get a for model of how
it works and then once you have that
data then you can apply it to building a
buzzer or whatever your next research
steps are so now i'm going to do a demo
of kind of what the result is all this
research so Mouse track is a bunch of
key stroke injection vulnerabilities I
found and you know different types of
mom bluetooth wireless mice for doing
this kind of injection demo and i like
to use these Hardware to find radio
dongles
so in this case this is a dong goal from
the crazy fly which is an open-source
drone project
it's the same transceiver as logitech
uses in their wireless mice but also has
a power amplifier and low-noise
amplifier and this is nice because once
you know you know exactly how I device
operates you
do something like this and it does you
know one thing very very well it's small
compact effective cetera
with this we were able to actually do p
stroke injection from 225 meters away
using you know one of these and a
directional antenna so it seemed a
little device and so in the case of the
water attack attack
there are three vulnerabilities being
exploited there's a for sparing
vulnerability
so the normal behavior is you put the
dongle into pairing mode with her
software and then it stays in pairing
mode for 30 to 60 seconds and then you
compare your devices during that time
that turns out it's possible to also for
spare device at any time so as long as
you know the RF address of a mouse or
keyboard that is paired to it you can
pair your own device which turned out to
be a problem
another neat thing you need to pair a
keyboard with a dongle in order to
inject keystrokes
but you can actually structured the
pairing sequence in such a way where you
pair device which is a keyboard
effectively but shows up to the end user
as a mouse and you're still having a new
device paired not good people notice but
if it looks like a mouse
maybe it's no less suspicious and then
the you know that the really fun thing
is this unencrypted keystroke injection
so water tank and Crips the
communication going between keyboards
and the dongle using hundred twenty bit
yes but they don't verify that incoming
keyboard packets are encrypted so the
vulnerability is simply a matter of
sending the unencrypted equivalent of
what the keyboard sense and the dawn
goal gladly accepts it and will allow
you to inject keystrokes that way
logitech has issued a firmware patch for
the strong goal you have to use logic
devices
you haven't patched please do it's
important
so i'm going to plug a longer text on
goal into my laptop down here and my
other laptop
will plug in this crazy radio dongle
which will allow me to send the command
to execute the attack
just give me one second to get to set up
here
and so in this case this is just a you
know water tech and 510 mouse with the
standard in a water tank unifying USB
dongle
and there are one thing to note there
are two different variants of these
Logitech unifying dongles they have one
with nordic semiconductor transceivers
and another version with ti texas
instruments transceivers both versions
are vulnerable and both need to be
patched
so i'm going to open up the Logitech
unifying software so we can see that
were actually parenting advice
ok so here we have now this one mouse
which is paired with a dongle and that's
the expected behavior and now i'm going
to run a script on my laptop here the
other one and this is going to issue
commands to pair a new device with the
dongle the dongle is not in pairing mode
but in this case it doesn't matter
ok so we run that then we'll see our new
device show up in this case I david maus
track to make it visually distinct but
you can you arbitrarily set
what it's titled you can also
arbitrarily set what device type of this
you could have it show up as a mouse or
keyboard or trackpad or whatever
so now i'm going to sew the output of my
script here is the wireless address of
the newly pair device so each device
paired with the dongle has a distinct
address
so I'm going to feed that into another
script which will execute a keystroke
injection attack
this will bring up notepad and just take
a little bit of text
and you know I'm not next to this laptop
now but we've shown with range testing
and that you can do the exact same thing
with the exact same reliability at 225
meters away and that range applies
you know across the range of vulnerable
devices I've tested
it's a definite concern that you should
jump at your devices
the other vendors outside of Microsoft
right sorry outside of water tech don't
have the ability to update the firmware
on those devices and so if you're using
an on bluetooth wireless mouse and it's
you know not water tech or a lot of tech
and I'm patched and i would definitely
change your behavior and anyway that's
what I've got many questions
thank you
yep I guessed
yeah i was it thank you
and