thank you very much my name is
Mary or most of the people know me by
fish I do have a few logos i got a lot
of more but one of the logos is random
data which is a hackerspace in Utrecht
and since i'm also a dad
I was involved in the past five years
when my kids growing up doing more
technical stuff and I'm making my uh i'm
gonna i got a job with the s unit which
is the company's doing offensive stuff
and we break a lot of things and with
this we are also able to do these kind
of things
and as i said i'm part of the heb core
crew
i'm not i do we did not did not did not
start this project alone
I'm actually I spoke with with hero
which is over here
hero and I had a chat we had a phone
call
actually was not that phone wasn't here
ok
and we were talking about our kids about
that they are in school
well what kind of technical stuff do
they learn on schools and it was kind of
sad actually we had the conclusion that
hacking was not in a close yet so we
came up to the ID at the school fair 02
to run a pilot and we call it hack in a
class and during our journey we spoke
about with a lot of people about his ID
and everyone here
hey but this is cool i also want to want
to know about it and and so we are on
the beginning of a journey at a clause
is still very small but we have a lot of
people who want to have attention for
this and to organize a little bit you
know it's just it's not an initiative if
we just are starting on the school
running running a hacking class now you
have to think much different in their
way
like okay how we're going to do it
responsible responsible for example and
and how we're going to extend this and
and is it even our tickets waiting for
this or they are just bored and they
want to play there on the playstation or
whatever so and and this journey started
a few weeks ago and during this during
we thought about we need to grow this we
need to make this bigger and and and see
if we can launch this at least in a way
that is sustainable and more people can
use it
so what I'm going to give you I'm going
to give you an introduction
what about hacking a clause but we're
still in the it's still an alpha project
so we are on the beginning of the
journey and we need a lot of people
joining is and this will be the formal
announcement of hacking class but we
don't know where it's going yet and I
think that's a good happy way to at
least bring hacking to the classroom
I'm one of the things i will we were
working on is our vision
first of all we do see a lot of schools
trying and and see how they can extend a
lot of things but they don't know how
the second thing to get
it's also that we see lots of schools
are are are not able to go out of the
standard curriculum which means that
they are trying to give everybody a 6
plus or something like a 22 to gain
their to fix their access etc and and
packing is actually just outside these
borders it's it's behind by his lines
the second thing is we see the amount of
kids who are doing signs the amount of
it is really dropping at the moment and
we did a little bit research on my n one
of the main courses about this and don't
get me wrong on this but we do have a
lot of female teacher in primary schools
and these are very good and have very
good communication skills but usually
the dads and the men are usually more
into soldiering and breaking things and
and and and fixing your bikes for
example
it's not about all the women I want to
say but i would just want to say that we
do see a trend over there
so this gets actually two problems
first of all there is not enough cyber
hygiene in the in the classroom
kids are not going to beat each what's
good and what's wrong
and second to that is where were these
junior hackers are not activated enough
and its activation is needed
so this is the reason why we started
this journey so one of our missions is
to bring cyber hygiene to schools
you know i'm talking about using good
passwords I'm talking about not putting
everything on facebook you you don't
want to share in the future or and even
about thinking about what you think what
is security and think about do I want to
share this is this secure yes or not
this is not the real thing about
bringing hackers to classes but it is an
important subject and we also want to
cover this
so by teaching the teachers at least
with cyber hygiene is and so the kids
can learn it they can at least teach
others and even the parents what cyber
genius
what do I make a little bit clearer what
cyber hygiene is my way ok if you've got
questions just just breaking please
our second mission is to bring more
hacking tool kits and activate is in in
in these little brains
we are searching for those those boys
and girls who are exploring the world in
a different way
sometimes they're even one in a
classroom and they don't know how to
handle their selves and even after
teacher doesn't know how to handle them
there usually are are one of the the the
boys or girls who are difficult and we
don't know how to handle it and
sometimes they even go to different
schools for special kids
well I also think they're special but i
think there were full special instead of
you have to handle them with with
different hands or something like that
so if we take these two missions cyber
hygiene and go and and and our mission
is to bring more hacking to classrooms
we we defined a few goals and as I said
we are still in alpha phase and going to
a better face soon and it is better face
we're going to bring we going to outcome
a little more to to the world in the
alpha phase we are learning a lot of
these kits when the first time I went to
the classroom and I show these kids how
you have to Howard it's possible to
break the system and I saw the smiles
and if it are as possible and I
understand why I can this be scared kids
were really getting and lighted by the
fact that somebody was over sending in
front of the classrooms and and giving
them a lot of energy
i think the the first Clause we
reschedule about one and a half hour and
after three o'clock we had a story after
three hours really it really had to stop
them because i have to go home and they
also because they were they were going
home late but you were so much it would
they gave so much energy on this and
I've learned one thing about this
this is really important for me and I
want to do this I want to see those
smiles on those faces and having to feel
about uh the the energy growing in
themselves and see more future instead
of only having the feeling okay i'm
special and they don't know how to
handle me
ok also thing is we are doing and yes we
can make a lot of plans and and do
everything through through a project
system or whatever but do I have has
been a lot of initiatives already in the
Netherlands who are not making it this
way if we want to change the school
system it takes about 40 of six years to
change the school system and bring new
information and technology
- - to school of course there are more
initiatives and we also want to want to
bring these initiatives
- - to hack in the claws we want to work
together
you know i'm not saying we gotta we know
everything but I at least want to say
that we need to create a certain point
where all these schools and all these
teachers and all these kids can come to
and and learn from each other and share
it all this information
there's the community started balls are
coming
I would like to work together with a lot
of people and bring these initiatives to
do it with more people to these kids and
you know i'm working a lot of hardware
but maybe somebody else is really good
in fighting and can teach python schools
for example third thing is we need to
start of communication and this is where
where the goal is for me at the moment
we are starting up communication and
also going out reach the world and see
how who's interested to join hack in the
claws and see if we can can make this
pilot into really something else I want
to grow this community because I know a
lot of moms and dads who are hacker also
want to help out and bring this to kids
ok that this was the alpha phase and now
we're going to be bad at beta program
and is beta program is going to be a
little bit more outreach already
and we want to create the tools and
resources for schools to use it could be
it should be very nice if we can think
about creating tools and and or maybe
hardware which can be used by other
teachers for example and weak I'm sure
that we can make this information
easy enough so teacher can handle it in
the basics you know the teacher doesn't
need to be a guru on raspberry PI's for
example now but if I you know if he or
she knows how to bring this very Park
raspberry pi so the kids
these kids are going to be enabled at
least on these technology
if we bring arduino do them you know
maybe maybe they can start up to do
blink
but if they're if they wanna run a
program that shield is something
different and there is is is that's the
reason why I'm calling it resources not
only want to bring tools and and
standard ways i also want to bring
hackers to these classrooms and so if
hackers coming in these classrooms and
he gets already were playing around with
arduino in this case hackers can at
least say hey yeah but if you can also
try this
so I want to extend these classrooms
with external actors for example and
when I'm talking about hackers by the
way i'm talking about the good guys but
you probably know that the cyber hygiene
and hacker classes is is also one of the
things we want to put on but cyber
hygiene needs a different approach
because it's also approaching the other
kids and the other kids they may be are
not interested in hacking at all working
computers but it's still an important
thing and this is more we need to change
the curriculum of the dutch school
system with and this is going to take a
lot of more time but if we are not going
to show the people that it's possible to
bring it to the kits that we don't have
a sample to bring it to change the
school system in the Netherlands
so this can take some time and it's the
reason why I'm going back to my second
point again over there
we just have to do and talk to the
schools and bring it over there
the third thing teach the teacher we
already spoke to about a little about is
and teaching the teacher is about
it's all about you guys know the
Raspberry Pi academy for example for
those who doesn't Raspberry Pi Academy
is enabling teachers to play around with
his red berry pies
they're bringing the basic recipe for
information in the UK to these teachers
and his teachers are at least able to to
play around a little bit with it and i
think this is also a way to go in the
Netherlands but I as i said i want to
have these hacker extensions to to have
the kids who want to go further
at least you have the possibilities also
i want to share and improve i'm really
into open source of these kind of things
you know I don't have all the knowledge
and I think if we can make this open
sores people can at least improve it
use it and reuse it and create a Dutch
school curriculum
all I put it on the loss because i think
it's most important we just start doing
with each other but we still have to
handle a lot of formal stuff
okay where are we what we're currently
in the pilot face and I just took this
picture just for fun
because this is also a pilot that we
want to be a hat and we started already
with a school in him stadium and these
are this is just a small part of the
classroom who started working on
unpacking in the class who was that hack
in the box yesterday
ok i will spoil some kids walking around
and playing around and pulling
yeah we we also brought the kids to to
hack in the box and to show them how big
this world actually can be and how fun
it can be
they play around a little bit with
Arduino is on the hacker spaces
some of them went lock-picking and i
think one even state until seven o'clock
in the evening
of course we found his dad or mom to be
sure they was allowed over there
so which is coming me a little bit to a
timeline and and you know we are
focusing on on a longer timeline as i
said this alpha phase is 4 2016 to the
way to go and learn how we have to
handle this even further
in 2017 we on to roll out its beta phase
and at least be on at least 10 or 20
schools in the Netherlands with this
program and we need a lot of people for
that is so if you're a hacker or at
least technically oriented and you want
to go to schools with his knowledge and
and want to teach kids please let me
know because we need people 2017 2018 I
put it on the curriculum mainly because
we need to put a goal and I don't want
to have this six-year-old six years a
time off of changing the curriculum
I want to be positive but i'm not sure
if you're going to make it in 2017 2018
if we're going to start over there
I'm a really happy guy but we can start
teach the teacher teach the teacher is
is we already spoke spoke to a teacher
who was not that technical but X we
explain some things is it ok but I'm
able to tell this to two kids and I can
help this gets you to work on around
these types of things
so our teaching a teacher is something
we should focus quite fast on because if
we are able to teach these teachers we
can we can go more abroad during our
journey we also came through the
question what is good and what is wrong
and this is a difficult part maybe
because we have what
what's good on an ethical doesn't need
necessary to be good for a kid you know
main goals we don't want to hurt kit we
just want to give them more
opportunities and enable them
so um but by at least by discussing this
they are getting more rich they are
understanding
so I have to ask myself the question is
this good as his rider is wrong and
what's the good way but we also do
understand that you can't give the full
responsibility about ethics and these
kind of things two kids and this one of
the reasons why I was hacking a clause
to get over here oh we want to take the
responsibility and help these kids at
least discussing this
so one of the things we we we we just
started is to junior hacker hotline and
if these kids have just asked questions
yeah just dialed his number and they got
a they got me or hero on the other side
and they are able to at least talk about
the issue they have for something like
that you know it's mentioned as a hard
line so i hope they're not going to call
me in the middle of the night
but on the other side if they were going
to call me in the middle of the night
before they are going to because
convince a crime or something like that
I'm really glad to pick up the phone
maybe with my sleep he had a little bit
you know we want to be there for those
those kids
so yeah - come a little bit more - D -
the final stuff where we are now and
what we're going to do first we want to
continue our lessons you know if we
don't continue this
we're not learning and at least we're
not keeping the ideal life for the
moment we we we already broke some alarm
systems for example and show how radio
communication is working
we also want to go play around with
microcontrollers and let's show them how
easy it is to program these some of them
already played with arduino so we might
bring in some other stuff around that
maybe even bring some 3d printing in and
bring it to bring technology to these
kids
also one of the things we we want to do
is we are going to open a call for
volunteers and bring more volunteers to
pack in a class and see here we can
start of this community and and bring
more more people and get more
fully involved with this wood with the
project and for this we also need to
build some communication
so yeah accurately we have a placeholder
page on hacking a clause don't know
you know it needs to be filled and I
thinking about at least starting a wiki
so everybody can can change and enable
and started
also we we need to enable communication
of course in the form of twitter which
is going to happen actually today
because this is the first moment we're
going to outreach the outer world then
we also want to build a content and and
and charities content
you know the content i'm building i'm
going to share it anyway everybody can
use it and wants to use it but I hope we
got a lot of more people wants to wants
to join the initiatives and also want to
build content and share it and of course
we're going to share this information on
a CC license and you know the only thing
is why I'm not making a commercial is
because I think maybe a lot of hire
people they also want to use the
information in the boardroom and you
know which is fine for me but if they're
going to sell it you know i think it's
fine but I need to contribute a little
bit on hack in the class at least
so I'm coming to the end of my
presentation and the opening of hacking
class we did organize something which is
not in yet but we can at least at least
check because i want to thank you for
for listening and I hope you have some
questions and then and maybe you're
interested to come over and so we can we
can really launched a clause in the in
the right way so Cooper is a somebody
out there with something or not
ok they can come in to open hack in the
class I thought about affect you you we
should have a formal opening and we can
do this of course with champagne
what we are back in the class
and we are working with kids so I
thought about the fact well we should do
this at least with kids champagne so I
got alcohol free champagne and that the
bear will be available later
so I'm i see a lot of faces looking at
me and if you have any questions please
come over please show your hand and we
will the desert in the back
I i totally agree on you are on kick
starting in a way and work together
because there are already a lot of
programs and i want to i just want to be
the one to support all these programs
and also let me take one things
yep yeah
so let me repeat hero what we already
started and a half of a local agent
named state and and this is our pilots
or alpha class at the moment but we
already have two other schools who just
want to want to start with it so yeah it
does that answer your question
thanks for the lady in the front over
here and I'm definitely sure we will be
in touch and we also i work with your
internet the only one of those who curse
for example in and I'm a sport is also
one of them that there are more
initiatives but the problem I have is a
for the moment i do see a lot of
initiatives but there is no central role
yet and i think when we are if we were
able to create just sharing platform and
extend all these CDs these possibilities
together then at least a ladder is a way
to go
the second thing you spoke about your
female teacher yourself and i'm not
talking about all female teachers so I
hope
yeah I I was not meant to be offensive
but i just wanted to be clear on the
fact that we are losing bad ass and it
it's not pointing out to somebody bad or
something pretty good we just want to
change the system in a good way so and
so well for the moment we are not aiming
on primary or secondary school mainly
because we do see a lot of difference on
ages on the inner battle claws
we got a girl in their ages it's 10
years old she's already on the secondary
school but she's good enough to at least
play around already with these kind of
things
so I think you're ready when you're
ready and if primary school also want to
start already with it that i would be
happy
mainly because if we can bring all these
these information already two younger
kids they can already start growing from
a young age yet
yep yeah it's a secondary schools is
first I do have to say because it's also
about us learning
you know I is seriously don't know a lot
about how to teach for example and that
there's where there is where my learning
curve starts actually so so I
think we we do we're going to have to
make the toast at least on a cloth to
thank you all for listening and I hope
you're all going to support initiative
so cheers on a clause
not bad thank you very much thank you
all