i'm going to try and save an awful lot
of time
a fast and i know that i'm scottish and
have not turned on my microphone however
we can you hear me
yeah fine good rate we come here we come
closer so it's good it's no problem
ok so i have what we're going to talk
about is an advanced persistent attacks
and one of the reasons that we're going
to talk about it is a face that we keep
on here and over and over and over again
and it's a phrase that people cannot
define very well and literally I was in
the a top-10 bank
perhaps I don't know something's playing
what will I was in a top-10 bank the
other day and I actually had to explain
to them for appt store which is a little
bit worrying if you stop and think
I give any much perfect body
you're a piece of shit up in black but I
couldn't resist that bangle an anagram
McGovern right so I'm a little better
angle for you
it's got about 50 billion people in it
its core large steel manufacturing works
it's go ambitions to be a very large
superpower but it's got huge
agricultural second but all kinds of
problems and things like that
that's the Democratic Republic of angle
and that's the country that we're going
to be talking to make today I am right
now by going to apts people don't ever
seem to get the percentage is great
either
this comes from the cops right so I'm
not not just making a popular night
there they can say their name tte % to
be easy or moderate and they mean easier
more than a different sense than you and
I mean easier more than a little means
you by not the door and get the guy
all right but mark sometimes actually
believe it or not they mean they don't
have to put in a huge amount of effort
to get the particular criminal or to get
the crane right
what the car could really concerned
about is the two percent they classify
is more direct to heart and the group
them as apts and the three you mean
gripping the gate them are organized
crime intelligence services and
state-sponsored espionage and dusty
always be a nice it's done a
state-sponsored level and that is about
two percent what they're interested then
I am is corporate and industrial
espionage all the normal stuff that you
would expect they're interested
intellectual property they are more and
more interested in trade secrets
small things that you can extract
quickly from a network rather than tough
to download the plans for an entire
battleship
it isn't a much better to get the press
release in the battleship isn't going to
go to sea for another month because of
some sort of delay in and baddest the
country that we that's only one file to
extract rather
all the plans for the battleship so more
interested not the more than two
financial markets and market reporting
because they are beginning to hook into
these high frequency trading bots these
horrible things so that if they can get
PDF all of you don't go to announcements
or where
what is that noise
there's something new duties laptop is
making a noise i'm sort of as a problem
we'll just have to deal with it and help
you might be shot
haha you can never tell with these guys
and happy
so yeah look they're more interested in
this kind of stuff they are going more
and more after critical national
infrastructure I know you all know this
so I'm kind of preaching to the choir
here but pulling it all together and
actually seen it in front of you when
you think about it if you delete from
corporate and industrial espionage is
intellectual property theft is the next
thing
trade secrets man should market
destabilization of a country critical
national infrastructure general is only
three days worth of bread in the UK
three days you could start all the bread
get into the supermarket for three days
you would have riots in this streets
it sure its deadly true
and let's just all that we're all such
makes people that we would never do
anything like that energy and telemetry
data they're getting more into not right
disruptive technology anything
government military in GA has always
been a big fan of biotechnology underdog
state now do we know about big farm of
the drug state and how much it's worth
yes no
i'll give you but the small version of
it right when they make a drug
if one person doing the drug trial dies
the drug is scrapped so we literally
could be set within them in thousands of
ducks and that's why the cost of
bringing one drug to market is in the
billions
because if one person dies and they do
one thing wrong in the trials then is
that the window we could be sitting on
top of the cure for cancer because
somebody died in a trial
we're never going to find them so they
go as a rather sobering for have fun
and why financial gain
gdt gdp impact competitive advantage
cni destruction - that baggie fixing of
the futures of the energy market notice
the oil price came back up yesterday
- 52 but $52 are borrow front down from
a low of 24 and a high of a hundred and
twenty four
mmm and somebody had a meeting with the
Democratic Republic of Iran go ask them
nicely to slow that i would have been a
little bit of they could please
yeah all this is going on sectors very
much everything but particularly
particularly yeah you know this isn't
being live-streamed isn't it
happen I want a thing right so that's
not and no in all seriousness what we
are noticing as a company particularly
leading the stop technology right big
telcos big companies that are working on
new things like Tesla good example
unfortunately we were one of the
companies involved in the taste will
recall
so the more people keep on putting i
enjoyed into cars and can all agree that
is a very bad thing and we should be
putting more solid operating systems
like you an excellent choice in that
yeah maybe it runs the Eurofighter runs
an MRI i drive a car with you and exit
over a car with android in any day of
the week
you want to speak to that man there
anything leaving the destructive so
they're going after the star tops just
as much as they are the big bp's and the
SOS and things like that
they're going to take their stuff I at
the same time the level of bpt and the
level of script kitty are becoming to
meet each other and if you want an
example of that turkey me caps prime
example asked if he could not do what
you can do with me cats three years ago
to do can do notice three commands was
then you see you could
well have a competition later on I'm
hope I did see a train go faster less
it's not wash slide ever this is an
american fighter don't know which one
right there 14 or something in 1998
designed by Lockheed Martin the DoD and
NASA
this is the people's republic of congo's
version of the same plane
I am NOT a fighter pilot
they are the same plane
the unfortunate problem is the people's
republic of angle couldn't get the plane
off the ground because they didn't have
the tooling ability that Lockheed Martin
that which made them step up the game
and the game carries on it again
it was able to eventually hear that
right
it's good right it's not right but
initially the first three runs they
couldn't get get off the ground because
of the way the stoop
they couldn't manufacture the steel to
the tolerance which is ironic isn't it
there there bangle seems that was still
know how we got a favor google we've got
the Iranian centrifuges and then really
the whole point the slate is to assure
you that you know it started off from
silly funny things like stealing
people's jet designs and they were up to
CDs stuff that is across every single
sector here roughly the figures is a 12
16 billion drug trafficking sex hundred
billion
interestingly 5% of what would the g DP
and global cyber activity
I've made a small mistake here because
actually I should move the decimal point
up but as you can see the pretty close
to each other
global celebrity tivity is
and somewhere where drug trafficking
it's about half of it so not just not
include digital wires
so what's the ecosystem look like well
here is roughly how they do you have a
bag man
that's his job his job is just to spot
you to set and LinkedIn trained you to
sit and look at job I de veras and see
if you got that job trying to figure out
what technology stark use trying to
figure out who your Grannis trying to
figure out what charge your mom goes to
anything to create a Dorsey which willow
team e to send a potentially successful
phishing email the bag man
don't really do the initial compromise
once team again with ninety-nine point
nine percent retain my spear phishing
email first thing they go for his
persistence second thing to go for this
week on third and go forward without
expectation and they will be using no
one tools so they will be using things
out a cali that you'd recognize you were
taught your ideas with picking up it
hope things are well protected directing
course
favorite throughout the day today pero
tú command control center next time we
go up or is the critical assets
financial market data the 840 that then
back doors for persistence leave the
command and control computer going close
everything down just go nice and slow
and nice and quiet and wait until the
company makes an insolent or you want to
destabilise and do what you want to do
to them
so that's roughly the principal
we can do this one debt quickly
it's like teaching going to suck eggs
every I'm company and its supplier be to
make my new think my new fancy thing and
then supplier sees going to the building
technique ever any point it gets stolen
the IP guess stolen from these two
places that are weak
because they're part of the integrated
supply chain then Company B gets the
final product first and this happens all
the time
I don't think that it doesn't but it's
not going on every single day with
everything from pharmaceuticals to soft
drinks
ok we doing for time I started guys huh
really can be due to an American guess
it's time
ok cool sweet let's start boarding these
people
ok so here's your traditional way of
doing it that you you know you're
walking into the doji company and you
see you're getting all we've got
security because we've got antivirus
always your antivirus do
oh how she's known values of viruses so
they are all
let's all see it together one two three
traveling at all can put it up
i can . and then we can play when you're
done right IP addresses
let's all say it together easy fight
less thing
domain names one two three
yeah I think about it don't let you stop
going to doggie Lee these dark amor
you're actually in this city
maybe that's a load happen
networking Horst artifacts stuff that's
actually being physically put into the
system
that's where it starts to get annoying
because you can take the mochi how you
can never be a hundred percent sure all
the tools are challenging and I don't
know well as ttp it should see a teepee
see the ATP's of the tough ones because
they are coming in with their own tools
let me just go back up sight forgot to
see someone and not having this is
further on
ok so you can see next to that like you
don't use of your first line of defense
identification had good justification as
how good your network is this force
defending your there
your network your firewalls and
artifacts are defending you there
the this is the bit where people are
getting into trouble because everybody's
wanting threat intelligence center with
these wanted to have a shock but nobody
actually knows if you ever write
everything had a headache questioner is
anybody here Deitrick that I don't
offend them know myself so I can tell
this right are you f or guy
all right you know those books on you
have always right about the pediments
and you read you need that they've got
11 chapters and you need the first n you
go high the rocks are really beg
how did they move over the rocks and now
I'm only telling you this makes total
sense and the attempt to chapter 11 it
says aliens did it
this is the problem we have with threat
intelligence i defy you go get a threat
intelligence book it will tell you what
to look for
they are tell you how to do better all
that get to the chapter this is I know
what do they do with all the shit
totally bike
nobody figured that one out yet so you
get a good early warning system you need
a tacit alerting you need decent stock
services and these people need to be
talking to each other and a constant
basis physically talking not just
well done you can install spunk kind of
talking right here is actually an
example of one of the exploits that we
had that want to talk to you about
as you can see all the eye peas and
vangel
all right command and control centers
and vinyl thats its dns exfiltration no
it's not right they don't exist struck
out your head against them i would be
enough in our happen and that's pretty
much how are you - good
let me do show you the remediation
because it's quite a nice graph and it
kind of puts it into context
this took six months and cost the boat
seven million plants so you know when
you read the newspapers
it's a 10 million pone remediation or 10
million pound hack and it's going to
take nine months to fix
here's why . the house right
the attackers end and availability
Shuki dro efficacy doesn't exist in our
understanding the attack is that Taylor
or turquoise lying there we leave them
in the system after where people don't
get that why you leave them in assists
oh yeah rajuk catch a bad guy
did you know what the 11 less you can
snoop about and check and see whether do
believe in the system as we leave them
in the system we discover more about
their methodologies
sometimes the clock or nickname o'clock
in the morning and five o'clock at night
and vine in vinyl
I'm two hundred and then the only take
van Gogh national holidays
I was still a coif you the great country
once we've got to this point we know
what is our controls we need we know
what we need to start thinking about
doing but we can't do it quite yet
because their end
and they've got the back door as the
understanding improves based on all the
investigation the analysis and second
till I can find the UP button
it's a person that do to our lack of
understanding of what he's doing
I was not telling her or how he's doing
it
notice how the lines cross at this point
as we figured out what he's done the
controls that improved the more we can
understand about the hacker other one we
can leave them in the system the better
more efficacious we can meet the
controls that we put in place
improvements to the controls reduce the
attackers mobility so we start to box
the men but not so much that they think
they've been caught because then it's my
favorite better practice these active
course they do
and buying
that's the point of remediation that is
a weekend
no jokin whole company will be done in a
weekend
this is sex once planning leaving them
active gathering information about them
figured out of work where they're coming
from figuring out what tools they use in
figuring out what how we need to be
ready our rule set all I can enough and
then we'll actually we will kick them
out over the weekend or one of angles
many qualities
I'm boy did they ever surprised when
they got back to work on Monday the
remediation takes place quickly at two
to prevent a change in tactics
based on the financial impact either the
network of the cerebral access is
limited changes to the architecture play
this is a rock music is not rocket
science to you guys and . network
visibility must be in place or their
logins and play systems partly beltram
idiot remediated maybe is it new AV
signatures
you may as well have them for all the
good that area all controls are turned
up monitored aggressively
I would not start going into this that
someone's been spearfish then it's
probably time to the minimum bet money
and stopped raining
no more steady stick of operations we
are at the top here or working fine
they have been kept oh but the other and
advanced persistent threat to future
activities that was a terrible we can
quickly respond to them because the
slate I was trying to famed for you and
I'm almost done so if you give me a
second to find the bag man slide eagle
right ft me is kicked her out that point
of remediation that we saw
Team B or swing into action
that's what a persistent but comes in
Team B other guys that are older
the other guys that you know when you
hear guys that right now we're an
assembly
you know my god - no smiling at him and
saying you do so yes well done happen
nobody else in this room guy how so
yeah that's what team media does and of
course just to finish out the
presentation
figure 8 through the end of it but of
course the regulation as if there's any
team and it flows at B team
what's the obvious question I'll come on
think about her force
there's an ATM there's a BTM so is there
are sea team yeah and end people's
democratic republic of languor they're
married to each other and they are
considered military assets
I'm not joking the habitat account
I can show it to you so that's basically
mediation and basic ideas which I make a
bit of fun
I'm not going through the boarding
government stuff and stuff and like that
with you
are there any questions of trading
makers enjoy the kind for the end today
yes sir make it easy please I'm tired
yeah
it would depend through the are right if
the turn out to be they see the Russian
mafia
they know . and writing a letter to the
Russian police have to be a egg
we we work for the client right
we have phoned nation-state terrorists
script kiddies
anonymous see you later agencies in
places right
and if that happens we pick up the form
where before number how many should you
really be there a sort of sorts of some
kind of you know thing going on that we
don't know about
otherwise you've got 48 hours with about
to meet you at the system link in their
cells back and it's not a problem
that was harsh doesn't burst reality if
you had yeah yeah that sounds great yeah
go for the seconds
the c team i can assure you they seem
uh-huh
their blasters and angle right okay yeah
yeah
because the a team will be using script
kiddie tools out to a higher level way
there'll be mass . and stuff and things
like that but it won't just be hurtin
Armitage you know they will know how to
do you will notice the B team by the
network traffic and then eventually are
fighting their binary and you'll notice
that the binaries have been handwritten
right and then the answer to your
question is the c team as one level of
craftiness above that it's even harder
to find is even more obvious cated is
even Lord is even slower
yeah
any more questions if it is everything
better assembly i can only do your ex or
not I can do you mind as well but you
yes sir
well that's why i said education to be
on a strike is Mike
yep yep and it's crap
yes crap they do this if they do it for
pure tokenism had to be the right how do
we make it more bus
well I watched an education for 10 years
so the chicky answers you employ me to
write your security software security
training program for your company and
deliver and a bespoke manner
the other thing that we do is we do
constant checking and people right
people turn up to how many times you
been to a new job done the health is key
thing and then never done it again
alright so screen should be locked down
once or twice question should be asked
he should be warned once or twice
they're going to get internally freshed
then on the fourth time we should be
warmed and if we still have 400 people
and that link we failed and we need to
look at it from different angles so that
that's the way I look at it get a
baseline bring the baseline dough
you can literally put into calls out
figures and sitting watching CEOs and
boardrooms when you actually give them
the money that's that's that's the way
that that's the way again
sure anything else no no no comments no
and with different angle want to sue me
just now
that's exactly what I'm going to do
buddy Sally well noted that i sold
between brother you're faster or I on
fast i think you're faster
thanks very much guy has been really
lovely talking to you