put out too long
I'm simply one from Chiho series 60 and
this is my partner issue and today i
would like to share some thoughts about
the captain from talker and chem commun
mission and I and this speech includes
two parts
first I were introduced the door creaks
this gap technique and second our talk
about the communities kept telling you
that's belong to talk her first and
about docker
it's a contender technique based on
linux during software story
what doctor does is just like ocean ship
in our operation just like a copper ship
and every software working as a cargo
container this contenders are isolated
from others
users can easily combine the comments in
it together such as development
environment in their stories
the bases and so on technically speaking
containers mean multiple applications
running one unix operating system which
is America visualization however they
are different is to say not that much
power operating systems beauty walk hose
server to provide a lighter-weight
substitution allows multiple operating
those running on walls mission
therefore dr. Weir save a lot of extra
OOS resources compared to the
visualization system due to doctors -
features dollar has grabbed a lot of
attention from many famous service
providers and doctor has already been
widely used in cloudiness services such
as such as in past and proper camping
them as the next generation cloud
computing pattern and after introduction
dr. land now we continue to talk about
some key talker technics inning system
as i said before doc has isolation
feature that means each contain their
isolates from another one contender has
its own file system process ID user ID
memories if you set in other resources
for running and there's this fundamental
techniques are namespaces and sequels
these techniques to share the Dockers
isolation of process access permissions
resources and so on
SI group is a kind of mechanism provided
by an external sequence were divided
system task
in their tasks into different courts of
in other resources
normal speaking secrets could mean to
record isolated physical resource used
by process corpse to provide a guarantee
for container original equation actually
secrets are series of folks attached on
the process by Connor when the process
is one into schedule resources that were
trigger related hooks and it is where
help system to trace and limit its
resource
now I believe you have a brief
understanding talker
let's discuss power talkers when ability
at first about the talker images which
is used to english initialize a
container for example some developers
use docker containers as sand boxes and
some may think that process is inside a
container just our SF s processes in
virtual machine over there are some
people download on verified talker
images around them or host machine as
many samples
there are also several past services
providers allow their end users upload
they are on top of images and under the
multi-tenant environment
the main counter exactly know the source
of each image but these images could do
things by using the root privileges on
the host OS mission
technically speaking namespace technique
Mac dockers isolation come true in
traditional income system
katie is unique and isolated in normal
cases users watching separate AP IDs
however in talker we have namespace the
helps to less simpy I decreased in
different namespaces separately
are you dr. piecing as independence best
buy you names best but Phoenix Connor
cannot use mint
namespace even there are a lot of
containers are system course from a
container up or preceded by an express
corner
moreover models like system devices and
kind of models are not for isolated this
. spring potential risks to poker and
metalcore escape possible
inside Tiger container you skip attacks
have two ways long is from container to
host another is between containers the
after a skep
attacking containers can execute and
command in host machine as i mentioned
before our host operating system in top
of directories were be available by the
attacker especially under my attendance
environment when user ok that containers
privilege remotely it will bring big
risk reason that you know that it's
virgin talker
there is a massive security instance
that internal part of talkers warm could
be accessed outside from the internet so
attackers can use talk a remote API to
get into the docker container remotely
by topic amount without innocent 30
check this container share could be
controlled by the attacker then attacker
can get a host machine root privileges
inside the container by talker is kept
taking technique remotely best all
mentioned points before
let's talk about how to implement
talkers kept first I don't let me
introduce a container process creation
in unix the running environment of annex
process in course
rootfs user ID group ID network process
ID devices host info and so on a new
talker container process is quite by
according to fuck by this column here i
want to talk about their conflicts in
the fuck procedure which determine the
feature info of our thought processes
namespaces after that instead
inside the same long name space or
process encouraging and execution inside
a docker container we are you hurt
is these namespaces features when create
initial container process these blacks
were beset our talk about this flax
detail in the next structure the xbox
see is a running environment for current
container and the legs broken structure
of the container is learning spaces set
by the flags is into fog
this structure is the key for sharing
container works is important to know
that when we smokin new process inside a
container or is ensuring you for it may
need work at from the structure the
structure issues our definition about
the namespace it including the UTS names
best IPC namespace mountains best here i
want i want to introduce
autumns best among them space suppose as
relational linux OS faces and by
isolating file system on points after
isolation change of each far structure
inside my name's best are separated from
others only is on file system will be
affected by our month operations of new
generated the namespace and nothing to
do with outside and the rest is a PID
namespace in the network name space and
then was network them space is used for
the network resource insulation and such
as the individual network card and the
next structure i want to talk about the
tax tract the name is Connor manages our
process bite a structured inspector at a
subtractor intense kind of containers
process ID and other related info of a
container process
here are the structure membership we
shall close relationship talk at dinner
process has ever tracked and ex fiancée
and task group
in addition more important the task
struct of the container process is the
same one thing inside and outside of
poker and this is very important for
properties get a command line
CCS route is red to montanum space of
docker CS route is used to change root
directory and restrict the directory
access permissions to a process in linux
system default directory structure
starts from root directory
however after applying the short system
condemns static location as a root
directory timing of the ice road
containers could execute under different
root directory as in time
this guarantees that contain their own
may arise to execute your own directory
structure here for instance i have two
processes . one and tried to read one
look at outside of container apply to is
the inside of the container and a
directory structure can you want son
during standard such as route home time
but containers work directory is under
dr. Walker with FS
so the ward directory of pd-1 which is
outside the container is meaning
standard directory and it has right
except characters are under docker
actually walk directory of cattitude
stalker road ave s & cat - 10 have write
access in any directory out other DNS on
tree
this cottage cheese process is inside
container are independent from
directories outside the group in Jenner
the address which abstract the final
point two shoes info related to kind of
container process working directory
this means if the kind of process is
inside a container that is structure of
the container process is mapped to the
file system where is container mount
when created
therefore we can say that FS structure
actually can tease the kind of wrong
container process working directory and
it won't affect other processes inside
of them contender here i also want to
talk about the differences between the
fs structure and montanum space
the mountain namespace is a shared
structure this means for running
processes modern space has nothing to do
with them back before the focal new
process inside container or required
info for directory access privileges of
this process need month
namespace provide best on the about
analysis we can switch to our ideas of
us get the first step
make the container process get into
connor execution by special thanks
Colonel abilities inspiration
the second step change in Africa
structure or a cargo container process
that kinda . container process get
privilege for exciting roof our system
of the host operating system that means
get the F structure process one
the initial process of the host
operating system and finally continue to
achieve global skype by changing the
angle sporty namespace of the container
let's analyze the first step in Munich
step there is a type of an ability that
allows a local romper village of the
other two as escalate their
probabilities on the faces the honor
system by system call and in docker
container our system of course of a
docker container finally where p proceed
by unix corner of the house operating
system plans that as well as the
inability exists in this procedure of
this is something called the container
that can be used by a normal condition
the process so we can get into Kenora by
using these types of needs , petitions
exploration as we see a normal container
process can trigger the man abilities on
the nicholas culler why system call to
let the short code executed in color
mode and that means a continual process
can you excuse to the code in como
divided type of vulnerability after step
one is getting to step to make the
condom process had a global file system
access permission
that means we need to replace every
structure of the current process with a
constructor which has a global access
permission
so how we can get the unit process ever
structure which could access the global
system of the host operating system
the answer is in converging before 3.0
we can directly get it why the image F X
structure of the need to process in the
host of linux operating system and this
is a structuring units converging and
2.6 but after the 3.0 we have to find
another way because these structures do
not exist anymore and i have mentioned
before the task struct is the same one
inside and outside of the docker
container and also a strat is doubly
linked list the structure and in linux
operating system or processes are
generated from the initial process which
have the PID one
so after the process get into the corner
execution
we can get you need a struct by the
current data structure which PID is one
is next then get the F structure of the
initial process
12 and this is a code together a tree
structure of the first process of
nickels operating system
after that we can use whatever track to
replace the parent containers extract to
make kind of container process category
both I system access permission on the
host operating system
first we can call function dim light at
this track to replace a current
container process is abstract in
coventry up on six
however after versions thereupon vero
there's no longer this function corner
but we can also use functions written by
ourselves -
realize it after this step the container
process can get the four hour system
access accession of the house are
operating system and the final step is
to like the lid of the container is kept
as i mentioned before
inside one container our container
process referred to the same is Boxxy
went red
they are for after replacing X prophecy
which kind of container process pointed
we can escalate our containers privilege
to global here we replace a chronic
namespace by calling function credit
note new name space and switch task name
space to set of the containers thanks
proxy
this will help container to achieve
global his cap after this step a
container finishes is kept and the
inside of the container create a new
process means it has a 4 privilege of
the horror of the host OS higher after
conversion syrup on there of the
function mention that bad not your
walked met you to the security reason
when you can or fractions are not
because part in more by the developer
here we may realize the functions in the
. back but is there is not stable
usually a better solutions after the
Gherkin general process get into connor
execution and replace the RFS tracked we
can open shower or within a container to
execute the command to mount the
containers were passed to let the
container chillstep or escape and get a
grow box is privilege of the host OS
here is a demo video about executing is
kept inside of the talker
in this video first I check the process
in password directory on the host our
system and then I opened a talker
getting to talk with spanish and check
the percent in the password
next there were executed exploit inside
of the talker and get a room share of
the nexus system and after the escape we
can view all the processes including the
containers processes itself
ok
something very important
not notice inside of the doctor and the
next step is to execute the turkey
huh
and it only has two processes
and this is running the exploit
ok
now it's outside of soccer after we run
your hand exploit
now we can see that we run the PS and
can get are the processes on the host
nation including the talker process
itself
all of them
and that the user that is the topic set
is kept them on video and the next part
and I were introduced likes is kept
hanging from the official mission of the
km communal platform
first let me introduce a Kevin Camille a
kvm is the Phoenix color model that
allow a user space program to utilize
the hardware virtualization features are
wires processors
Kim you can make use of km we're running
a target of texture that is the same as
a host architecture for instance where
on your commute system x86 on the ACT
x86 processor you can take advantage of
the carom acceleration give you a
benefit for your host and your caster
system they are so remote switch when
Ronnie original machine on chem commun
linux is a guest mode user mode and the
common mode and our escape
we're based on the next four points in
the first one is Kevin commute memory
loud in the user mode of the house
machine and the second one is and where
to place the share code and the third
one is our PID control and the last one
is the exploited house first is a Kevin
commute memory loud
now this is a mint memory out of a user
mode Kevin pure criminal process by
executing a common line on the host
nation like this and in this memory out
the letters are w.e are represented
represented a read write and execute
attribute of the corresponding memory
area after the understanding of this
let's go through from the beginning of
the right pick the attached as the lab
em that this area's has four lines for
example the first line is a code segment
this area to be read and execute
but not right Bob the sig nine has no
ashfield the third memory area of lamb
will be used to place a global variable
usually the first area is a hip area
used by let them is really poor and
right ball
the map area is usually used for the
emulated device of the virtual machines
such as a five-hour floppity skin others
and the second user memory map area is
used for the physical memory area of the
virtual machine
the heap and the staff is a meat memory
area used by a human process and the
last is about a system called memory
area
well what interesting here is that this
area is a fixed area are in 64 picnics
virginal commute
i will talk about this later after the
understanding of the memory loud
where have we understand the following
memory area to place our exploits share
code
unlike local tradition Eric's operation
method we come to control the memory
advocate and a free of the host machine
inside of each machine
this course that we cannot use the
convention or hips / a method to put
this your code so we need to use the
information lick one ability and
unconventional methods to make our
exploration but due to the limit of the
information leakage one ability
exploration
we need to find more place to put out
short code and take a look at this pic
the physical memory area of a virtual
machine is created by memory map from
the host machine q process so we can
place a show called in memory area of
the virtual machine and find it on the
host machine by some fixed calculation
and this is a good place to put our code
we start a BM and allocated to G memory
area it by least common line and then
let's take a look as a memory loud a
virtual machine process on the host
machine is a printing that address
ranges 2gb and this area will be changed
when we operate a memory area inside of
the BM and let's check these and this is
the best address we get from the memory
layout
first we run the test code inside the
virtual machine
the code in Korean stirring like this a
second
we calculate valve set and final string
on the host memory area and this address
is the physical address of the swing
after all of these are who is a big
place to put our share code is hard to
get over
ability to lick the memory map area
Camille and there's a second where to
place our share code is a 50 of the
community the device
this area is also memory mapped from the
cumin process on the host machine
the venom vulnerability expression to
sign in the 15 is a very offense case of
the 50
this is pick where when we are very fine
the venom vulnerability the code right
number for the two piles of function out
p to the fifo and in the second pic we
can find the code 42 on the current
corresponding memory area on the host
machine cumin process and there are
other measures to place a show called
such as a simulated you are a network
device run is also the idea of memory
area in these two pics when we pin side
we can also find the string on the
criminal process memory after we put the
char code
let's take a look at the methods of the
ID control to execute our code
the first structure I want to introduce
is the argue step in commute which is
related to the carpet functioning in
this structure the q milagro handler is
punching excuse boy called area after we
control the hands are directly or
indirectly we can control the code
execution procedure and that is VIP
control and the perfect status is to
control the horrorcore structure in our
so the arguments of the hundred function
and that makes the expression more
effective and this structure is related
in visual hardware interrupt
we can trigger these types of an ability
pies are present on the community the
hardware of community inside a virtual
machine
look let's look at this function is not
a chamber language
this is our ghost hunter and
is a bottom is a cameo hander
and what we need to do is to write it RX
Platts 0 x 30 punter to let the accident
killed Bob and procedural change after
we rewrite the hunter we can color r PX
0 x u SQ than a memory area we want to
this is a similar structure can be used
to control your IP and the procedure is
similar to what i said before so I don't
don't talk much about the structure now
and there are more ways to control your
IP such as the vulnerability of buffer
overflow or use after Freeman ability of
commute
after introduction about let's take a
look at the exploited steps and the
exploited step is just like what i
mentioned about
first we place the shortcode second with
trigger of an ability to control your
key and third a bypass air as air our
NDP by the vulnerabilities and finally
executed a shark or to achieve our is
kept here we introduced to one abilities
cv2 son and 1575 all for ncc 2015 5 1 65
the first one is a type of car heap
overflow vulnerability
the second is the information liquid
ability or zoo when abilities can the
leak the right address we want in a
special version cumulus part of the
functions address offset is fixed so we
can get the past address to calculate
our other address of the functions we
want to pipe a cerrar and then construct
the arbitration use em project to change
the X execute attribute of the circle to
pass TP
now let's take a look at the hip / -
when a beauty
this is part of the code entry mover in
2.4 here the air power overflow four
points to the RQ structure when the use
of the buffer is just a for all 90
expert and that is what we need
like we talked before
and this link is the more details about
this and cv funded by our team and there
are other ways to exploit during our
research like the fixed address of the
system calls in queue process for these
addressed directly in charcoal that will
be matched up for our exploration and
this is a simpler of the shellcode to
car system call directly at we control
the RDX and the RX yet and the hair is a
demo video about escape inside a virtual
machine
ok m and the unit video we start our
Kevin communication machine and the
wrong exploit coding decided to let the
host executor of the shortcode to attach
to a remote attacker machine
and this is our machine first which have
if we are connected to the host machine
directly
it's done walk and next we started a few
meal with your machine
yeah
and we're on the exploit now the host
machine
there is some stream free and on the
attack or machine we can connect to the
host and around the share on the whole
mission
and this is to create a folder from the
attacker machine on the host machine
yeah
just
and that's all in the Christian time
thank you very much for your
presentation
are there any questions
is it possible to break out of docker
container f if processes are not running
as root and put your place out louder
is it possible to break out of a docker
container from processes which are not
running at roots so if you cut the web
server human and not a waitin is a con
our inability and because it is a design
architecture thickness of the talker so
we can make use of this
yeah other questions
lunch is already being served outside in
the expo hall
you can enjoy your lunch while you're
looking around in the Expos will start
again at two p.m. thank you