- the money
and
thank you boil in trees in our research
being the following are where we are
present
how to attack and restore were when the
bigger timing signalled
during this presentation where these
costs the and Peter were it's the bottom
model the reference clock
how to put becoming thinking on and how
to attack and Peter were normally we can
set and peace over for our computer to
synchronize time out magically sometime
our mobile phone also get it time for my
and Peter were these taps and preserver
is educated with our daily level
ntp servers are also widely used in
private networks that help our grades
and the real wave for example potpourri
have to synchronize their automatic
equipment in less than 10 millisecond as
we know our computer or phone can get
it's time for my NP summer but how does
then Keith over get its time
well according to in the end p protocol
to draw them level was the plane that
these things from the computer to in the
reference clock and reference clock is
as random download you is that is
accurate and the highly toe or no delay
associated the way they did random
little OT wise cannot be Yoda and then
to work
I think that they are directly connected
to life
random one entry server
i speared him along and be server X as
their primary time that time summer it
gets it's time for my reference clock
namely to them they'll be wise
ice cream as freedom to there were
either connected to ice cream in one
hour
oh we're at network pass last I threw
them too
there were get its time by sending ntp
pack the request for mice problem tool
that were and this up
I speed of those three separate cat it's
time for my to do them to sever and the
storm
so they are working more time sauce is
the reference clock in this presentation
we will discuss the reference clock and
their rhythm 1 and T server
well L this picture here old a lot of
mato and these are words I employ the
way that they open source and if you
working for some of the world from the
newest ntp working for source code
we know that and be working for support
almost bought the island types of
reference clock
the most common seal that are the WWE it
be that they have learned is there one
dy m SF and keep yes but white on a
stream 13 server use the radio clock and
the TBS as a reference clock in fact
they are three classes at all accurate
clock the atomic clock
gps and the radio clock the atomic clock
is a memory accurate but if the pen to
the gps satellite has that building
atomic clock and the broader constant
they time all this atomic clock needs
navigation data frame the timing to
ignore our reference clock is also
controlled
you also can call the bank at home
o'clock the hallways that their
broadcasts all native while he's timing
thinking all we can use that locals
everything were to get almost the theme
accurate time as atomic clock the radio
clock and the TPS have been widely yield
to be odd to treat more and keep the
server
well and there
NP website there's at least four it's
supported radio clock and the gps
receiver cause we can connect that with
regard to a computer to PR dies with
them along and there were very easily
and that they are also a lot your amount
of integrating the Supreme One and mr.
world that can be selectively for
industry old taking this product as an
example from its broad part description
we know that support TF don't get there
one
msf WWE B and BS every reference clock
now let's talk about how to 40 they
timing signalled
our aim into t ly I uniform dedicated to
trans meet all these radio clock signal
first let me introduce their thinking of
picture they wo wo would be timing radio
taking it operated by the UFA according
to eat to a encoding making them is your
different paths the wives to river and
different binary data feeds and this
church shoe if we amplitude either
reduce the for eight hundred millisecond
and the bank increase that by 200
millisecond they see you then mounted
special feat which we called have a
marker if its amplitude is reduced for
500 millisecond length
increase the x 500 millisecond
they think that data people with their
well you want
if it's the amplitude is reduce the poor
200 millisecond
thank you sit by eight hundred
millisecond
this is that they beat when their value
little and then the WWE would be Tammy
thinking or used a safety
hello has care
after eating the thing not to the
carrier with the amplitude received King
modulating if they interesting nor will
add a la la
it's a trying to meet the way we reduced
amplitude and when they in putting in or
Richard hi
it's a 20-metre whale for amplitude they
output of these things cause repellent
that ate the canary repeats marker one
they know and the one of the things the
one ring at the start already need each
brain can see it's all stakes of T beads
if the twins meets one piece per second
that ring start aways and marker be and
almost ends and marker Pete every 10
mins take every time second to reduce
error
egypt for any contains the means are
year they are mere and the weaker
they all week
the panel peed also either marker so if
everything would get to stick with your
marker repeat it means that a new free
me prepared to be resumed
well they could you wire it you're
taking you operate the pie and a
campaign
it's the encoding Maggie them is a very
similar to the wwp the difference
between them
I the different pathways of each Pete
and the different frame in Coney it also
your neck safety
crow has care
DTF 70 71 is operated by Cameron the
company in fact it's all so similar
ww-p exactly it's the old a 77 1.5 kilo
has career as we make it before the
career all do I
ww-wait be and the msf r6000 has wild
ATF 77 way you 70
since then . the final co-head we want
to t that I uniform taking it to keep
about of transmitting all the air
poverty clock signal so we use that
against module to generate career 50s
module can retire little 240 make her
hands away and the RT know there's an
open source driver it to make the whole
thing
I'll eat either
that the more you very simple taking the
video is an example when thinking marker
beat it will require thinking the camera
. to second of four amplitude follow the
pie .
eight-second reduce the amplitude in
this case . it requires you to reduce
amplitude justice you have time that it
is module when thinking the pic one
it will require the carrier . 5 seconds
of your attitude and follow the pie .
five-second reduce the empty dude
on their radio clock signal like WWE be
is the f 77 1 also can be implemented
with this way I get in this marriage
lipstick and dinner for my video wide
receiver module in fact this engineer
yield adding doctor
well connected with the proper capacity
in parallel
it can be used to transmit eat the 50
Cal ahead carrier when we want to try
and meet they guarantee their 1.50 has
kura you have to change to another
capacitor
they think the whole key to all the
young form 20-metre we don't yield any
empathy for our hair
it's a very simple you also can play
we'd if you want to try to meet over
long these things just 28 that power
mp4 and that began to know better
because ball of breaking the law
now they talked to Harry Reid o'clock in
the prepared and let how she feel how to
for gps ignore
but for me
oh thanks to you is introduced to the
GUI bird and apologize to our present
and so let me introduce how to attack on
TSN TV receiver so as you can see a ntp
server sir
cross-references not just heyy bird or
something else and mostly we will use
the past 30 chip to be a signal to a
receiver
so we were introduced the best of times
both in taking this waste and in detail
so firstly we will talk about the most
common to be as receivers and that we
were used and we can buy in China and
there are in order to make you guys
understand the words the meaning of the
source code which is right and we will
briefly introduce the best text
principal and our generate a real gps
signal to both the hour
divots receiver bird that we just about
it was just about and going to have a
try
and what is this attempt
we will still have some jerk Romans into
and the way and you cannot ignore them
so we're going to introduce how to
upgrade our to be a signal generating
generating a clear
so let's started and so here it's the
two guys receiver that we can buy into a
nasty market and actually easy to the
most common is module that we come back
looking like to come up so it goes to
multiply connecting all you can see the
interface we can fish
the real a real time from three ways
such as pcie and the USB also reports so
you know our situation and we'll just
this forward to and we will reduce the
serial port to get time from this and so
after after the ship it UPS and to be
delivered
and we now to briefly introduce the gps
tag so i don't know how many that you
guys a nosy detail of the gps type but
let me tell you it's but the principle
is really complicated complicated so
unfortunate easy but it but it doesn't
matter because i don't know whether your
guys listen to the presentation of this
trick to this trick yesterday and my
colleague and my colleague the top too
long and I just made a presentation
about the energy done great so but and
the hate and she's the opposite she's
the one who used to to give presentation
about how to make a GPS both signal last
year in depth on 23 and so it was really
interesting is the gps is pouring tea
house
I suggest you go to the YouTube and take
the video
mmm so here you see and that's back get
back to something serious and here's the
two pictures and the key information in
these pictures is a now we've got our
church pastor receiver on on the on the
ground and on the other unit skies there
is a lot of the UH that there is a lot
of machines that can see a center of the
signals to the gps receiver and what do
we do now
what we now to do is just to generator a
bunch of signals are in some in some
real formate and we can so so met Maxie
to get the receiver to think while there
are now we're up here is where i am and
what I'm I mean
and so uh that the important scenes that
is how we - is how we generator this
signal or you can see the oh you can see
the way
so is the second picture of Harry easy
of might of the best signal wave and
that there is a fivesome subframe and
their importance of that are easy some
frame - and some frame 30
there is a the information that can tear
cows a jet to be as a receiver where I
am and each you the front of the each
subframe and there is some information
is it can tell the gps receiver are now
what time it is
so uh the location doesn't matter but
the time is important and now we can
are there is the UH the the man appeared
on data we used to generate the GPS
signal
so firstly we need to get to the temple
and farmers raise the data and there are
two measures of 12 are downloaded from
NASA's you know a website and you can
record you too
but a and and and and I'd only yeah it's
the record it and so after you
after that you can use the open source
program or tssvar to receive the a
real-time GPS signal and the record
later and get a refresh data and oh so
after you get this
this data now you need to do is say to
the core into time and the current
location and the quarter our height of
that are that as is you know you want to
generate and uh oh maybe you guys it's
one way while they work well as these
things meaning but it doesn't matter
it's open source around a song
get out and if you guys are really
interested you can download the attack
the sea uh and and as a witch
well or which parameters is what with
was a rare meat of it
and so r is going to have a try after
these after we were we wrong least
providing mind that we were generated us
in all our that conclude to conclude
that the the time and the Edit ood that
we want and we put atsdr or you can see
a call you or you can say usrp and we
were generators the real sick real sick
gps signal so are absolutely wrong key
to enter the picture higher is if you
guys
download the the the PDF every time that
you can go meet and you can see the this
is the real time this is that are
exactly the time that we just a
generator on our on our-our-our isn't
cold and so here is the result the NT
server is Panik of it and as you can see
the easiest this is Sir sir line and
this is negative 4 hours into a ice
falls out in two seconds ahead
so why its connector
we were introduced better but a virgin
shooters later and but we will have
something more for something related to
introduce is how to up
update or you can upgrade to the attack
algorithm because if you got to really
wrong this
Metalab code that we just videos are you
will not we will find out that if you
want to generate a GPS signal
it causes so many times about 20 minutes
and the gala and we need a lot of our
story just a space such as
about four big bass and it's it's not a
real time that we want to attack 101 to
be as a weapon and observer and you now
to use the laptop and cause of 20
minutes
and because uh not exactly time that you
want
so are we need to upgrade update it so
are the cheapest generator of them are
so it's called we will find out where is
the CBS time that we used and the so
what we need to do is it a generator a
GPS signal and the final too where is
the gps time of by binary code is and
the replies late and the REE REE check
the party
so it's the principle is very easy and
what we what we need to do is just a
writer present and program and the
reason
read read the viral and rewrite eight
and you know we put it in the u.s. RP
and we played it and just that all fun
so after we introduce the ntp server and
over
not the the detail of the the detail
tech of the data why bird and the 80s a
receiver and let's get to let's try to
attack a real one and observer
so oh let's test the matter some
prototype and try to use it
so we need what are we now to do is to
set up an interview server and here is a
detail over here is the key . uh
of the gps of the mg ntp servers can
configure a complete prior
yeah and here is the gy uh-oh here we
set up it as a junior wipe a did wiper
and as it's a proper reference and here
is the screenshot and now we just set
the NTP servers IP address to the HP
servers that we just set up
so are what we use the washer to capture
the network traffic as you can see in
the reference variety is JY so that
means our of that observer is now
working
so let's can attack it so as we just
introduced us and now we need to do is
control our TTYL bird and ascend to the
data and try to meditate to send out the
signals and the two in influence the ntp
server so a better
what are but the thing is that matters
is can we inject any time
remember we just a generator GPS signal
and we will keep him a time that ahead
about a force out in two seconds
but the thing is the ntp server is just
crushed so of Harry's I think the ntp
server if you read is the source code
and we are noticed that if the time that
the and observer
just get it
from is from is a reference clock and
the the distance is really really big
so the ntp server we were just we were
crushed and i will panic and the uh it's
it's the limit
so what we need to do is just the
largest dinner came limits that we read
a reader source code and we accept our
exercise and we find out it's four hours
and if that means if you inject a time
that is ahead or behind the times that
of the ntp server Ruiz and the it is
larger than zero four hours and they
were panicking
so what we need to do is just her to a
dozen tests too short
the distance so it's not what we want
and are it's not whatever we want
so but one after we tried to try to
inject a one-hour that behind all you
can say is three hours and a real time
what happened at the end of the servers
called close
it's just a loose it lost please come
got connections so why it is that means
actually there is a lot of more limits
in there are we trying to find out i
know we find out the time upset is more
than one sound times
so the server we sat down it's not just
24 hours and the it's a and the four
hours is the first step
I first limiter then the next limit is 1
something times I was outlets Evans
that's the NDB implant intention it's
really really close and so now what we
can do is what we can do is just to
Maxine's a mix it's slower because if
you want to inject any time what do we
need to do is try to the that is the
first time we inject a time that is the
offset is a lot more than the one sound
a second and the statue is where you'll
see nine hundred seconds and after this
after this are after this step affected
and we will generally we were in just
another 900 seconds
so there's more and more and more mon
amour and this is quite a slope
and there is a little bit more short
Commons
that is the root of desperation and if
you if you try to do this if each one
try this again
I the this exercise there is a lot of
all limits things there because our one
we just have to capture the track the
network traffic
there's a reduced to a lot of different
route depression in 8r that is actually
not limited to to the server is a limit
to the kind the kind of we'll just order
to a calculator that the difference
between it of the local time to the
never more time
so when the weights why it's not you
know the this distance is large and as a
client we were just a close
it's a connection so here is another
limited so if you want to of what we
solve this problem is just something
negative more slower and a in our attack
script and we consider about of the or
Colonel patter the the ntp server panic
and the kind of closes connection and
it's a so after this hour are accessible
matter of fact
so if you guys want more details that of
of the the art work or request for
commander and are 59 old 05 are
let's decimate the medicine which hand
if you want to know about a lot more
details you can decorate it
so here's the hour or tech demo is that
we just to recall want
ok
so as you can see our this phone that is
you
we use a with snaps is and observer
address to the server that we just set
up and this clock
it means a real time and is not quite
clear
but if you if you see the smoke rose
closer and you can see the the the
numbers which is a typed only on the
other behind that means we just are we
are what we do is now we are trying to
control heated wiper and met each to
influence our uh our energy server that
is so you can see in and and is this
time there were yours is about a four
o'clock that way in the is after hunter
response
so . the influence that the real time is
about a two o'clock and the influence
their times about three o'clock
haha and are we now we try to control
try to matter it is about four o'clock
or so here is the this is a difference
and this is a difficult since that if we
want to Maxine's met met or would want
to change the ntp server and it will
cost the so many times and are we just
met this distance about our one hour and
we just use about 30 minutes to make it
come true
so uh what what what I just introduced
is just a prototype that I just said I
set up but in real time and maybe you
guys want to ask a why not why not just
a bio and the real and observer and just
attack a torso and the record a demo
so here is the thing is this until the
server is just so expensive
about 10,000 two dollars and eat too
much
so you guys know about some guys in this
and if the server
uh and and reserved comedy and you can
tell them we we can we are glad to offer
the attractive girls and tell them how
to test her retested there and you
deserve
so uh oh
there is a lot of TV service , de that's
a matter of days and the as you can see
we can we cause they at as you can see
we've got the enteric yammering but
bring Bob my burger place a large
companies had met and observer and such
as more product and the Heritage listing
sister were and s200 and are all this
choose our come from the foreign company
and our this released its more solemn I
is another and Harry's the observer in
China that we made
but and when we met converts it kind of
conversations with them and we were uh
we know that a lot of things about where
they use this
where are where they use the end of the
summer and a how many people will vary
by this and you surrender
where they want put in for it and where
they use it and after we a
after we met at this conversation and
the window all better
actually in China as there is in prizren
and playstation and the bank and
electronic system they use such as this
models and according to our tech of I
was bluffing attack and a their engineer
told us that are seriously their their
products cannot prevent from this time
smoking so maybe
oh we come close to Z to this place such
as a present such as bank and we met at
this attack
so this system just this system we were
just crushed and other week google it
and Harriet's the another are realtek
maybe an example are very test her
no it's about one guy and last year they
talk they just posted a heart article
about their bank and observer and told
us
are there any server they don't know why
that is Christ and of this banks only
use this one and observer as the root
and the server so updated Christ their
engineer has to update the time manually
and it's almost a disaster so
here is our reference and our most
thankful
uh the the author is our eyes my
colleague and at home and met a gps
spoofing and it's an instrument made us
and asked Walker more easier than the
europe and as a TTYL / and the DCF 7077
and so it's ok it's AC and after work of
presentation to give so your class
called planning for any question
go gators anybody have any questions
so you go further more questions we have
the first pages that were in marriages
so feel free to contact with us
no questions okay thanks a lot for the
donkey
yeah