welcome guys
so up welcome
up this topic is Title IX by some
hunting and mining the reason why we
chose this topic is because in this area
of cyber warfare
cybercriminals always use multi-level
attacks to penetrate on multi that
you're protected network infrastructures
we often see a PT attackers many plates
your day windows , pretty are and so
sometimes it might be surprising if we
do not see this kind of opportunity ,
pretty use in this kind of at our apt
attacked
based on our our analysis of past
everything attacked we realized that
it's possible to identify the
characteristics of this so they can no
longer produce inspire the apt attackers
so in this topic we will focus on how to
proactively discover and explore samples
or the potential stalker
so they can exploit in addition to that
I we also discuss some of the average
are evolutions of can exploit that could
defeat the hostage intrusion prevention
system host intrusion prevention system
used by some of those are software
security windows so a quick introduction
about yourself
my name is green i'm currently working
as a security researcher at 40 knots in
the last couple of years before joining
for the nets
I used to perform in that now research
particularly studying and he keeps
technique used by malware against our
behavior detection system and then
providing color measure for those
discover panicked but currently i'm
mainly focus on discovering zero-day
exploit assemble and also performed on
every research on microsoft office and
windows corner
so I'm as such I'm extremely interested
in anything related to exploit and one
at 3d research so feel free to contact
me if you have anything related to this
topic that you like the exchange ideas
with me
and this is my copies antibiotic and
he's currently working as a sec senior
analyst at circle apt and we used to
work together back in Africa lap so
let's go to a large end up with this our
talk is great
this top divided in two parts the first
part is about kind of expert mining now
in the second part but we'll discuss
some of the elevations of privilege
exploit anomalies that we obsess you spy
a so they can exploit that could be that
could be used or manipulated by us to
identify the assistance of can exploit
you first start by giving your contacts
of what is elevation of privilege and
user account control which is our
security feature into this by window we
started a book
typically this USC is something our this
USC is a security feature that limits us
application software to standard user
privileges and to Emily straighter
authorizes the elevations
for example are you will always see the
window seat a lockbox prompt that
require the user interactions in a way
GOP and USC has a common characteristic
which is always abuse by malware authors
so we will briefly discuss differences
between them and which one is more for
reporting others
discovering still they could've won that
BD true fuzzing black box white box that
the analysis and then developing an
expert really is a time-consuming
process so it is not surprised to see my
orders at that the open sauce can
exploit especially publish especially
those published by security researchers
based on the results of our current
expert mining and the pathology
you realize that most of the current
exploit use is leveraging the classic
right what we're primitive for example
the CD 2013 360 published by thomas on
Andy
who's been working as a security
researcher at google project zero this
vulnerability is still what we are
actively used by now we're all those in
terms of elevating the malware process
privilege
so it is necessary to understand what is
right what their primitive and put on
and then we could make us how can we
make use of this rather primitive 214 ,
xbox ember the next one is one of the
highlight of this top of in which people
share our methodology for current
experts and remaining
last but not least are we also discuss
some of the case studies of the column
our families that leverage GOP exploit
that this case study
I will only focus on a flight decks and
despite while you can get the tedious
for the rest of the amount of family
from the white paper
so in this light you may have noticed
that up
GOP seems to have more drawback compared
to user account control
there is a saying the great power comes
with great responsibility d this LP
exploit the expert rider has no
limitation at all because he is able to
achieve arbitrary clinical executions
however there is no guarantee for the
European exploit that the spotlight the
point is hundred percent reliable and
stable before single piece of
instability
it could easily cost system crashes like
the in famous blue screen of that even
though it is a golden rule of thumb for
export writer to write a reliable
exploit in reality it is very children
is very challenging to achieve that
that's the reason why we have been
observing the transition from GOP
exploit for us to buy plastic simply
because the u.s. you pass technique is
purely implemented in using the code so
at least it wouldn't cost them precious
in the event of program arrow
however there is an easy condemnation
for all the USA by plastic basically
what you can do is you can go to the
user account contrast setting and adjust
the setting to always notify after that
regardless of any USB past and that you
use or the melody . the user will always
receive these windows us if i pass our
review this us develop box from that
so at least it wasn't are at least it
gives the user a chance to deny the
operation and stopping now where
unfortunately it is something is not set
by default on windows and it is very
unlikely for the user to adjust that
this something because um I think that
it might be too annoying to get too many
splinters prom
whenever the user trying to execute some
programs that require any straighter
privilege
however be based on my own experience it
is not as bad as you expect that because
Microsoft has done a great job in making
this security feature less invasive
so it's only recommended to enable the
security feature immediately after this
top having say that are the UPA exploits
provide food system privilege
it means the expert process will be
running as the system integrated our
welfare the PSC plastic
it provides an administrator privilege
which is a high integrated level
so in a nutshell we can see that GOP
export is no public as compared to USC
by plastic that's also the reason why
are we have been observing a lot of our
families at that thing the European
exploit particularly those open source
one beep reliable successfully but
in fact to improve my best reliability
now we are others started to at that
office this elevation method at the same
time depending on the current user
permissions
there's a great based on this in
performance shop if the current user is
not running as an administrator account
the GOP exploit beauty . first otherwise
the inequality level of the normal
process with diamond in state a low or
medium integrating our is a typical
indicating lever used by our standard
Windows applications are that indicates
it does not have sufficient privileges
when they were the program trying to
access to some of the restrictor
resources if that is the case the USA by
passing appt . state in the event of
unsuccessful us to pass an appt . the
European expert will be tricker in state
before the moon papers is executed
keep in mind that this whole bunches .
by the arrow you only be taken if the
current user is administrator in other
words the USC pipe aesthetic is
applicable to demonstrate a colony
so that's the reason why the mail orders
at that perfect this elevation methods
at the same time to improve its
reliability and success rate of
elevating the mallet process privilege
so what is right about their primitive I
place some of you guys might already
know what is right by primitive because
we we want to do for contacts to other
photos to understand the current expert
mining methodology that we are going to
introduce later
it is necessary to discuss a bit but is
rather primitive so i would go through
this very quickly
basically whatever primitive is the most
commonly used vector it is a simple and
most straightforward concurrent
expectation packing
which is why we used by a spider
essentially a loss and exploit their to
start a specific value to a specific
color . address for some art and the
plastic pocket for rather primitive
scenario is how this page table expected
by an takuna and generally a traditional
color exploit could be constructed using
three symbols that first respo right
there could prepare using with powerful
to start the shark code if there is an
upbeat right corner on a pretty exceeds
the expert like that could use the right
while their approach to write the whole
dispatch table with a shocker address
that obtained in the first step after
that in all the treacle that shall could
from the colonel
the expert like that could call and
peculiar into a profile functions in
order to redirect the code execution to
the professional codes in the expert
program obviously
other primitive is the simplest form of
exploitation panicked but it has its own
limitation as well thanks to supply some
execution prevention and supplies and
Prevention's technology into this by
Intel since windows on both basically
machine and able that's not allow use
the mood memory execution from , put it
in the previous slide it effectively
means that is that where the expert
right there trying to trigger the user
more chocolate from the color is no
longer possible starting on B those are
both in the security security researcher
always come out to protect the issue
that encounter and there is no exception
for them as well they are very small
package to bypass map and one of the
good example is demonstrated by necklace
exploit in CD 2015 05 but in my opinion
there is a more generic method to bypass
map which is in which the expert right
there could locate economic executable
powerful replacing the signal path of
supporting the show codes which is well
explained by Alex and rescue from the
hip injury panic but keep in mind that
Alex time it can only work until windows
nevertheless what I'm trying
what I'm trying to emphasize here is how
permanent is right where primitive to
export right there because of this
simplicity but in fact not all , exploit
us while their primitive as demonstrated
by the expert in city 2014 for the
country and put us in 15 17 or 18
the fact that not all color exploit and
take you into the profile functions in
order to achieve arbitrary code
execution
so it may make our expert mining that
apology not generic enough to call
all the connects to assemble however the
use of this API function together
without the special is still available
to us in the event of mining and explore
assemble and it has been proven to be
successful are useful in discovering
something they can exploit some of the
success stories are for example that
discovery of hi-tech City 2015 series of
57 expert which was first reported by be
able to myself and the leader exploited
by fedex while there was no public
exploit available to you at the time
another example is the discovery of
other number family which the applicant
you'll be exploited as a result of our
expert mining methodology
so basically what how do we do that what
we do is we look for the windows api
function thing statically and
dynamically this will be a professional
most of the time happened that in the
binary and can be conveniently search
from process family
so this research from the process memory
true dynamic analysis system my sandbox
could come in handy in mining this kind
of contact for assemble
however there are some cases where this
function on a happier in the binary for
example they know where my you some
proper technique to implement its own
address routine and passed in portable
family in order to retrieve the function
address directly need to exploit to
address these pieces we introduce some
of the preeminent expert behavior
detection methods that will be explained
by brought in the anomaly sections so we
will first discuss the generic way on
how to identify the library
what we expect from december the
following the following screenshot
should be no stranger to anyone who is
family
and this is an example of video that we
implement that to look at that while
their primitive primitive experts ember
from static binary one of the pure
features of Yara is that it in able to
enable us to scan the string pattern
from the process memory as well
so to improve the efficiency of this
year against pack or and crippled know
where you might want to deploy this
Yahoo to the pilot system
haha as I mentioned previously the use
of their primitive is still available to
us in the event of mining majority of
connector assembly to reiterate again
after successfully exploiting the
colonel longer pretty the export process
you need to call and teacher into the
function in order to transfer the quick
execution for an arbitrary address under
attack this control which is already
have health especially while some
arbitrary like really pretty and you
might at the use of this antique Yuri
into the profit function is not common
to the file by using wood applications
hence
is safe to say that is this functions is
foul in a primary or process memory we
could say that it potentially contain
can exploit
howdy we are applying this year on
various total and the results quite
promising for you after eight
of course you can reduce the number of
first positive by any initial conditions
for example this keeps getting in this
before in this case which might have the
potential of using our calling this
entry into a powerful functions to recap
all couldn't exploit use while their
primitive
so how can we do it is other exceptional
cases in order to do that we need to
first understand what is the typical
posterior aspect pillow used by expert
process
traditionally after expecting a
crinoline 10 BD and export process will
typically Alex sighs persistent
privilege
true top and feeling in other words
people take advantage of the purpose
doing payload operations and this
purpose during operations could be
summarized interesting to accept this
the export process could get the process
structure of the system process we
process ID equals 4 and subsequently
obtained is responding as a token
address and after that the export
process we've got the impressive
structure of itself and then replaces as
a fucking address with the system access
token as a result of this type of
replacement is process will contain the
same successful as a system process
which is our forces and privilege
traditionally of this that
implemented in pure assembly code that
would require some constant after to be
used to find the actual access token
address which is one of the few from the
process structure and also travels
interactive process leads to find the
system process and also retreated to the
information but they're going to exploit
these days we'll use documented in the
patient's to implement a perform all the
steps to improve his resilience and
possibility
this is an examples of our privilege
elevation . routine taken from more than
exploit
obviously it looks cleaner and more
possible that these two pieces of court
trying to do here is that it first try
to call the document that Windows kernel
functions for ps4 process by process ID
later
adjust the offset of the e process
structure in order to get the address
which is one of the few from the
structure and usually the expediter will
use console offset
that's a party for emotions have been
this is alternatively from the special
on the right hand side that a more
elegant approach will be calling
PS reference primary topic api functions
with the e-plus structure as its press
input parameter that can conveniently
retrieve the topic address
for the respective export process and
the system process after the popular
address has been detonated the export
process will change is estoppel the
system is stopping to achieve elevation
of privilege
hence we introduce the second yahoo to
protect the subset of the export sample
that do not average
right what their primitive in this group
we take a one pitch off the top and
stealing operations that will that will
call the popular windows color
applications like ps4 process by process
ID and antiquated system information
which is typically used by also can
exploit to retrieve the interest in the
base address that will be required to in
passing the actual address for the
respective our printer function that
will be probably the exploit logically
this PS Vita process that process ID is
not allowed to be used by any
application correctly so the use of this
document windows kernel function by any
user application pending to exploit a
winter's color
celebrity could be a good indicator for
us it is also want to mention that this
is more aggressive but it is able to
find the purpose during operation that
presented from the speakers from
previously been additional condition can
be added to this room to make it less
expensive for example we have also add a
chat where the sample has imported GI 32
and use 32 libraries that contain the
Queen functions which are typically use
when exploiting win32 vulnerabilities
we also introduced a yahoo packed the
top of stealing operation that involves
calling and other documents at the
function called PS reference probably
talking
this group is identical to the previous
one except it is not specific
interacting exploiting vulnerabilities
as you can see in the condition part we
dropped the user input library checked
next we are going to pop some of the
case study of the Collins family that
leverage the European export this family
was discovered by the first child to be
introduced and the reason why we picked
this one of the people in our family
that we want to discuss here is because
it was the first know we're family that
exploits ed 2015 7 3 months of the
Microsoft patch the deputy in fact 2015
it is also want to mention that there
was no public exploit available during
the time so we believe that this therapy
exploit could be developed by try tax
office to patch analysis or the better
you will be exploited from the
underground market
none of us after the disclosures of why
I posts regarding the use of European
exploit by dr tax you realize that the
u.p exploit has been disappear from
tracks in July 2050
soon after that you'll need to discover
that this has been a rough it now
support modular architecture in which
the EOP exploit can be downloaded as a
model from the CNCs book five colony we
are actively monitoring the UPS . in
this side but the resource quite
disappointing because the UPS store in
the fight seems to be soon explore as we
first discovered by in a pro 2015
this is one of the good example to show
how in our office react to improve the
product as i mentioned previously pretty
impressed and now is will I PT is also
include the USB bypass technique in
addition to the European exploit in
order to elevate the process . x it is
us to pass more you can be downloaded
from the CNCs mouthful
fortunately it is commonly exploiting
already oh and Moon you see one ability
which is already patched by microsoft in
case if you're interested
the USC won a pretty is currently
exploiting is called at compact listing
the rest case study is this pie
I believe no one has heard about this is
not a family before because this is not
already have another family that first
appear in 2030 you know that is covered
by the first year that the introduce the
reason why this is my family stand out
from the rest of the family is because
it is interesting post after expert the
colonel on a 3d this but no where did
not elevate our process privilege
instead it uses a lot of your technique
rather interesting approach
so we started to ask yourself do you
really need to elevate the preachers for
the export process this question seems
to be unsurprised a factual in his
presentations of easy local in this
current expectations in his presentation
he introduced a couple of our pictures
for exploitation and when are these are
pictures such as that exploit right
there with not only for the SEO of a
security descriptor for a previous
Windows process after that medium
indicate the level of the export process
in jack is poor to a higher preacher in
this process without any restrictions
however these are pictures introduced by
is our children require some
modification to put a structure that
could be easy to pack that by security
suffer in response to this despite know
where decided to inject good to the
remote process from chrome or one of the
because of one which at this approach is
that
there is no modification needed to the
current structure and at the same time
in April good execution and the criminal
contacts basically how it works is that
after explained Colonel Brady the export
process could execute at MPC injection
Ricky and the kind of apparently and
this and the responsibility of this npc
injection with thing is to travel the
active process least to find the target
process which is very unlikely to be
monitored by hips
for example spc who's after the target
process was followed by process could
inject and a pc track for the pocket
process in order to run the main payload
obviously these approaches most happy
and based on our testing it is able to
bypass most of the solution by and
another endless you just last month from
my pro also discovered the similar post
color a sport payload use by lucky which
is our glorious somewhere in order to
elevate our process privilege
this is a flow of our despite this is
the popular export . despite this by
that is but now we're the first exploit
the one that will be specified in 2013
36 all
after successfully exporting the one
everybody it then transfer the contract
to Colonel and in the first locate the
corner powerful that you get poop after
the clip after is really then right and
prepare an npc injection routine to the
common kind of offer that you repeat
that previously after that
it transferred a good execution to the
tougher and as I mentioned previously
the responsibility of this pc injector
routine is to commemorate and find the
active svchost process and then in jan a
pc tried to the packet process and
finally the APC tried to be triple black
a in that queue a pc version that will
prevent the final order or proper
cooking
next I'm going to pass a stage 2 brought
to explain that you're the expert
anomalies that can be used to identify
their common with other color export
ok thank you take away
so now i'm going to discuss those
anomalies that may suggest that an
elevator elevated process is not
authorized
so first is the existence of user
process that had system integrity level
according to sdn the you sir are the
processes that are started by the user
acquired the acquired our integrity
level of the user only system services
are assigned system integrity level
so if we look at the normal system so we
will notice that only system services
have like system integrity low and user
process have like your integrity level
of the user for example let's say we run
calculator so it will have a medium
integrity level because by default
users have medium integrity low unless
there are they are
I've been users that have authorized
through UAC for example is we executed
again
but as administrator so now it is up
high integrity hello so now let us use a
local kernel debugger to emulate like a
malware which the kernel mode and what
we can do so in our case we want to
elevate this medium integrity level 2
system so as discussed by wing one of
the technique that is commonly used by
my where is to just steal the token of
the system process but before we where
we are able to do that since we're not
using the documented API so we need to
increment the reference count otherwise
we will release the screening the system
after our process terminates
so the reference count is located at the
at the object heather subject header of
the access token
so let's see
so it's located at offset 0 so now we
need to get the address of the access
token or the system passes
so this is the access so this is the
address of the access token of the
system process
so now we're going to need to get the
address of its subject matter
so it's located here so now we have we
want to change the value
it's ok that zero so yeah so we don't
know at this point we don't know how
many existing references are there so we
cannot simply just change it to 2d or
whatever but there's a brilliant
technique that was suggested by the
window is to simply set this to set up
with a value that is big
that way we ensure that the the access
token is not read even after our process
exits
so for example let's set it to 300 x so
now we can replace the access token of
our calculator to go to the access token
of these the system process
so first we need to get the offset of
the field so it is located at the
process object
so the token is located at offset f8 so
we simply need to get the address of the
calculator object in memory
- it's here so we want to edit
we want to change the token field which
is in off set of eight so we want to set
it to the token of the system process
so now when we when we restart like
process explorer then it should be a
system in time it should have system
integrity level
so now it has system integrity level
so what does this mean well it is just
shouldn't be there because obviously
it's not a system service and it is a
child of explore that XA
so which means its most probably
launched by a user but the problem with
this is that there's no definitive way
to determine whether our process is a
system service or not but of course
there are also ways to check like one is
the parent should not be explored that
XA or if it's if it's a system service
they should be its parent should be
services that XA but for this approach
then some
we need to consider that there are
processes that are started by windows
startup
so that means that some form of white
listing
I is needed so therefore i am ordinary
way I'm ordinary check that we can
yeah a more generic check that we can
use is instead of checking the process
name will check the integrity level
so if its system integrity if it has
system integrity level then its parent
should also have a system integrity
hello so for example like not a normal
process like svchost it has a system
integrity low so it's Carolyn
should have also have system integrity
level
so now cock a system integrity hello
but X its parent explore that excess is
only medium integrity level so we have
discussed like how to determine and
normally through integrity levels but as
we mentioned earlier malware it doesn't
really need to elevate to a higher
integrity level there are other ways
one of them is to acquire the directly
acquired the system the necessary
privileges
so let's use only the back for example
is the example so we have executed it as
a medium integrity low so it wouldn't be
able to
so it will only be able to access
process we meet you
integrity hello but now let us assume
again it was able to reach kind of load
through an exploit so it can reach the
kernel mode and able to acquire the S&ED
about privilege
there's even about privilege is
basically up basically grants a process
access to all process regardless of the
integrity develop so there are the
privileges is located at the access
token
so it's okay that offset 40 and it's
using this structure is called SCP token
public preview laters
and it contains the spirit present
which contains some value that
represents our with each beat
representing the privilege
so if we take quickly take a look in the
privileges of a ladybug
so the present meat-filled means like
what are the bits that are present or
but either privileges that are present
for the enable field
it corresponds to which of the bits are
unable to in this case it's a sea change
notify privilege for this one
so now we want to do some research by si
si cerrito it
apparently the present field is not
being check at all in the kernel mode
and the colonel and colonel in kernel
mode
so if we want we just need to set the
S&ED about privilege in the enable field
so now let's get the the access token of
holy fuck
so that's the access token and we want
to set the privileges which is in offset
party
the two we want to set the modified the
privilege just field of the access token
and then the enable field of the
privileges soap
it sort of set ate the bird is a mug
filled this is ed bug privilege just
field is big number 20 so that's
equivalent to one thousand one hundred
thousand X so in this case we just need
to or it so basically that's equal to
900,000 x
I precomputed it already before coming
here so now when we go back to only then
it has access to all the process but
it still has the medium integrity level
in normal
in normal circumstances are let's just
close this
in normal circumstances i put a process
that have medium or low integrity level
are not able to be are not able to
acquire admin privileges
so we have a test minor here for a demo
by are here so it will try to acquire
the SE debug privilege using the I just
token probably just API socially
for example we run it with high-impact
integrity hello
so high integrity level if we quickly
take a loop it has the S&ED bug
privileges present present but it's
disabled by default so if we let it
continue
if we check again then it was able to
acquire a privilege but if we run it
with run it with medium integrity level
then it doesn't even have the S&ED bug
privileged preview they just present
so eventually so if we let it continue
of course it will fail
so what this means is that we can use it
as a check
there shouldn't be any process that have
admin privileges but only has medium or
low system integrity level
another thing that mower can do without
elevating to our to our higher integrity
level is still up a company with the
protection of the target object so let's
yourself
actually I that was mentioned by Wayne
earlier so but that's to our demo so
let's use let's say that's our launch
calculator is our target
so it is in high integrity level
so now if we launch all the bug with a
medium integrity hello
so naturally it won't be able to access
calculator because it's in a higher
integrity hello again this is a shoe
with the Molly are we
it was able to reach kernel mode and
able to tamper with the security
descriptor of calculator
so basically security descriptor
contains all the security information of
an object or in this case of calculator
the security descriptor is located at
the object head object either
yeah
so is it it it's located at offset 14
yeah according to msdn the security
descriptor
when are a non security descriptor
practically once everyone access to the
object so in our case we want to set the
security descriptor of our target which
is calculated at exit 20 or two not so
when we need to get the calculator
process object so
we need to now we try to get the address
of its object either so it's located
here now we want to set the security
descriptor field which is in upset 14
now we set it to 0 if we quickly take a
look
at the permissions of course it has no
permission set now so it practically use
anyone access to it so that means like
when you come back here we reload it
then card is already accessible even
though it's in a higher integrity level
where am I
so therefore i did a more generic then
so as a summary
my lord does not need to elevate to a
higher integrity level they can just
either are acquire the necessary
privilege just like the SE develop
privilege or it can also temper with the
secure or remove the protection from its
target object there could be other there
could be other techniques that have not
been discovered yet there for a more
generic check is to simply check for
process it process trying to access
objects that have higher integrity level
because that is the core of the windows
integrity mechanism so if some something
is violating that one that it means that
something fishy is going on
so when a normally success
specifically we have elevated process
that are not authorized
it means that if they were able to
acquire them illegally for example they
exploit that vulnerability
Colonel vulnerability so this means that
the process of finding this process also
assist in the hunting process so as a
conclusion
it usually means game over when someone
which kernel
the kernel mode because we've been
talking about anomalies but once the
malware which color mode
they can practically do anything they
can remove all the anomalies but this
would it already take them more effort
and more time
so for for us we should not make it easy
for them so we should try our best to
take advantage of these anomalies as
much as possible as long as possible and
find this sample to come up with a
solution
so I hope you find our and i hope you
find our presentation
interesting so thank you
protoc
any questions for both work and wayne
from the audience
so the the technique with the APC where
you're you know that you just launched
on a pc in a privileged process
I've ever seen malware that just stays
in a pcs that just keep set leaving
through a pcs rather than injecting
insert into a process like it executed
on a pc then it spawned another a pc in
the same process and keeps on going that
that is an interesting idea but are you
haven't encountered any are at least
based on my knowledge I have encountered
any real world now where that they're
doing this at this moment but yeah it's
quite interesting
the idea yeah well yeah I have no strong
opinion
any other questions
nope thank you guys thank you thank you