hi everyone thanks for coming to our
talk
now we are going to talk about new
methods for exploiting or injections
vulnerabilities in and java applications
let me try and introduce myself my name
is Mikhail
I'm a security researcher and back
hunter from Russia
currently I work for ingram micro our
cloud as application security engineer
my daily duties to perform our
penetration testing of software service
automation software we develop at ingram
micro cloud
my name is Sergey I work focus personal
up as head of security operations center
and research is not connected to my work
is Robert Bobby and I with my hope is
music
I present a treater and have a personal
blog where I discuss my thoughts about
information security and human
psychology psychology and all that stuff
that directly or indirectly corrected to
IT security but unfortunately all this
stuff in Russia but thanks google it's
not a problem now
ok here you can see a engines of how to
get consists of four main parts
it has entered an election part will
should shortly talk about our or enemies
the next spot is about orem injection
vulnerabilities basics as a majority of
slides are devoted to exploitation
techniques we are covered in a different
order and libraries and and kind the
last part of our talk we will summarize
our techniques and presents them with
the form of tables for your convenience
I want to say that last year on their
own rights conference in Russia we
already presented some exploitation
techniques for a hibernate or M our
library
and I in this talk we will present new
methods for new techniques for
exploiting or injections in hibernate
and also will cover as a forum libraries
Houston shower
let's talk about forum in a general orem
stands for object-relational mapping
it's a program in a technique for can
load for converting data between
relational databases and an
object-oriented programming languages on
this picture you can see RM r is the
question box in the middle between a
database management system and java
application RM r communicates with a
database management system are vicious
data from tables and are all
automatically converts of these data
into java objects here on the slide you
can see it some of the advantages for
using our am in your job application of
course you can use a plane
jdbc and implement every scene by
yourself
on application site and in some cases it
makes sense when you need specific
functionality or our performance is very
critical to your application but for the
majority of cases in using orem our
library in your application gives more
benefits them in implementing everything
from scratch
are Y plane GBC ok
what is GP GP stands for java
persistence api it
standardized api which is exposed by
orem our library
so our job application communicates with
RM through this API
there are three main versions of GP and
most orem library support GP 2.0
there are a lot of orem libraries in job
on the slide you can see our for
libraries that are used mostly in
practice and in brackets you can see due
to the application services that are
shipped with the particular orem library
so in our research we focused on this
for libraries but I'm pretty confident
is it based on techniques we have
discovered you can find similar
exploitation techniques for other orem
libraries orem our libraries utilize a
special acquire language with which is
called Java persistence query language
it is used for for mapping data between
a database tables and java objects and
for historical reasons cabinet or amuses
different language which is called
cabinet query language and H grill is su
percent for GPL
and since GPA 2.0
are there is a criteria API
this is a set of interfaces and classes
to construct query our programmatically
so in your job application you can you
have two alternatives
you can use a string gpo queries or you
can construct where is programmatically
why our criteria API and great your
queries are checked at compile time so
it is so the code becomes more safer
because developer
it's harder for the developer to
introduce a security bak
I want to explain briefly what or
injection vulnerabilities and the world
limitations i exist for its exploitation
we can also name or injections GPL
injections or each kill injections when
we talk about 7-8 order and we can see
that or injections are similar to a
classic SQL injections in how their
looks like in the source code of the
application here on the slide you can
see an example of functions that is
vulnerable to orem injection so GPL
queries constructed by string
concatenation there is a static part and
it
I concatenates with the name of
parameters it is controlled hour from
outside of the function then the square
is used to get data from database and
construct a list of java object of class
post
I want to emphasize that SQL injection
and a GPL injection are similar in how
they're introduced in the source code
but from exploitation perspectives they
are completely different here on the
slide you can see a SQL injection
scenario attacker can inject customer
skill statements through injection
vulnerability in a job application and
updating data from database
so in this scenario he can communicate
with database directly through injection
for or injection a scenario there is
orem library in the middle between java
application and database management
system
I take a can inject GP kill or hkl
queries and to obtain our java objects
from orem library in this scenario here
cannot communicate with database
management system are directly and all
around with the main obstacle of those
attacker he has to buy this unequipped
tackle are likely full frustration
trying to exploit or rejection and there
are three main reasons for that and GPL
or h kill
you have weird unlimited syntax
so not all SQL statements will work for
example a GPL doesn't support unions and
database so far from typical query you
can't access arbitrary tables you can
access tables in databases that are
mapped directly to entity our classes if
you will try to access table that is not
mapped you'll get exception from orem
and the certain reason is that your
favorite tools for a scholar direction
exploitation will not work with or
rejection
ok in java developers might argues it
and practice nobody writes gpo queries
by using a string concatenation and
vulnerability is more artificial and
theoretical and practical but i want you
are but I want to convince you that it
isn't true
so here you can see the short list of
vulnerabilities for the last year
I'm aware of our first example is H cool
injection I have found by myself now
internally when I performed security
assessment of our products next example
is HP rejection in a open Brower erp
system and the third example is a bitch
: injection in our no also desk software
for studying or objections we developed
a long horrible job application which is
available on github
you can download and play with it
before in discussing exploitation
techniques i want to show how in general
orem library works there are three main
steps or phrases on the first step
orem library parts parses GP or h kill
query and builds a GPL or a squirrel
abstract syntax three then on the next
step
it translates typical st into a scale HD
and finally now it builds a school query
from school aced you
now i want to give the term to my
colleague
I said gay who he will start to talk
about exploitation techniques
ok let's start with a click link or ram
chips link is the modern persistence
framework that is understood ship of
eclipse foundation
it is designed for use in Joe
environment including java platform
standard edition job platform enterprise
edition
sorry
diving into the communication we have
found that these are M has a magic
function and just know how cold cold
cold function this function that worth
noting that is function exists because
of reported bark developers complained
that we need a functionality true are
called arbitrary database function and
now this function is present and the the
thing is that it is it works rather see
Lee it takes first its argument as
function name database function name and
all other arguments put in into round
brackets to form a database function
call on flat you can see how it works
and exploitation is rather silly
are these techniques works for any
database management system and this is
example for both gray squirrel and green
asterisk shows custom injection . and
now let's see a small video how
exploitation looks like okay we have our
wonderful application school playground
returns JSON when working correctly
ok let's put our our magic function into
URL and see what will happen
ok its internal server error or let's
see what expression cause this year oh
you see it seems to be a function called
because we have opened and closed around
brackets after this expression
let's get somethin to URL to form a well
it is a base function call
let the length and of course the best
well its argument to length
it's 3 a and Blanco free a is free so
now it works working well and you can
form our true and force expression to
exploit our planned sequel injection
oh ok that's all we have to copy this
and put into our squirrel mob specified
database management system to connect
with blind and before that means
retrieve banner need to specify custom
injection . it's very the same place
where we changed 12 true to form a
true-and-false output or actually that's
it
knowledge you should receive Bennett
this is not the first time I see this
video so I'm sure where they will come
so ice cream upset that it it was found
asterisk and it public parameters
vulnerable and we can see man
so what happened we have honorable
application and object model database
but because of vulnerability
we have access to the database band arm
but bernie is not interested in and
let's try to retrieve something more
convenient for example let's try to
marry databases and see what will happen
actually it works so it's informations
kima PG catalog public the most
interesting for us is public because all
of this and default progress tape
databases
let's marry tables from database public
again the same questions astrix yes
ah so we have posted users tables
let's dump user stable because it seems
to be interesting people
specified
capital T flag users table and flag down
ok
all right you already seen this but
believe me this box
ok let's continue the second our patient
is toppling quorum and it's very simple
to eclipse link and it has a function
with another name but the same
functionality and hear that here you can
see x abstract from documentation that
explain why we have a square function
I actually and documentation for this
function is very useful if you want to
figure out how to explore this very
vulnerable to just look into the
documentation and vulnerable example
writing implementation
so this is an example of true are this
example false and exploitation is
completely the same this technique works
for every database management system for
any different system because it's so
boring picture
ok open GPA open should be a is open
source implementation of to be
distributed under a perpetual license
and this around found powerful abilities
with quote the first one we called wrong
single quotes processing and we called
our method in the same way
the problem here is that this RM
substitute all sequences of two single
quotes by one single quote and this
strange behavior
I can allow to hide select statement
within strip documentation looks like
you can see this this line and we have a
string is a single quotes that correctly
skate but because of this functionality
is wrong single course procession all
sequences of two single quotes will be
substituted by one single quote and the
meaning of this expression you will
never be changed completely on wed you
can see how to form true expression and
force expression for planned sequel
injection potential looks like this and
this technique works for every database
management system and on slide example
is for dresses are another interesting
feature about apache or one
GPA is it was vulnerability that we
called quote indifference the problem
here that it allows to limit our strings
are with a different kind of courts for
example are you see on slide stream that
starts with a double quotes and every
single course and this is correcting
definition and of course that case can
be explored exploded and explored looks
like this or MCs in this line string and
in double quotes with single quotes
inside it but because of this feature of
course indifference database management
system finally gets completion a and a
and select statement
compared to use a eight so the meaning
of these expression changed completely
the rotation looks like this and again
this technique works for every database
management system and here example for
possible squirrel green asterisk is
custom injection . for escort mom
hi belated cabinet is the most
interesting or M this because we didn't
manage to find universal gravitation
technical but I'm forward five different
techniques for our different databases
there's always management systems
ok we need the first technique single
course keeping the technique works for
my skill database management system only
it talks because my school and hibernate
process of course keeping differently so
we can see that in my scale to skip
single quote you must use / a similar
before the single called but in
hibernate
you must double single quote to escape
it
we can use / simple ways to subsequent
single quotes characters to bypass a
hibernate and reject arbitrary SQL query
so you can see is it a hibernate will
treat / with two single quotes as a
slash with escape single court but my
skill will treat this as escaped quote
and single quotes that terminate the
string and I was a part of the strings
that comes after / with two single
quotes is treated as additional
condition by my skill
if we inject following expression into
vulnerable our parameter we will get the
following each girl query which is a
process by hibernate and hibernate a
process injected expression as string
what when why I skill gets a SQL query
or why GDC after school query was
processed it will obtain a mutated SQL
query with additional now select a
sub-query to exploit a skill injection
when my skill database management system
is used to you can use the following
scale map command line
we called it
door quarters dreams method was
presented for us by Padre Square + H -
it's worth noting that these two
database management systems allows
dollar quoted strings constants so on
slide you can see streamed or a a quote
BB door it's a correct string definition
for these
very databases on the other hand are
hibernating or and allows identify is
starting his door and here you can see
fragment from a hybrid grandma
specification conversion all these facts
together we can make a clock
suppose this string
I each girl understands as completion
reuses identify a dollar dollar is
string that started with double dollar
but a square understands the same line
differently
it understands our string quartet with
double dollar science compared to concat
function and exploitation of this idea
looks like this again this techniques
works only for both gray squirrel or h2
who allows the basic allows a double
door quoted strings and green asterisk
as usual our custom injection .
the third method we named named it magic
functions method and it works against
the database management systems that
have magic magic functions that we can
use in SQL expression and there are this
magic functions evaluates SQL query from
string parameter passed to this magic
function and there are magic functions
for post grad school and oracle and the
reason why this technique works is
because happen it'll allow us to specify
arbitrary function names in h girl
expressions oppose gray scale has a nice
built-in function query to xml it
evaluates SQL query from string
parameter and returns
xml object that XML object represents a
query execution results but we cannot
use square root xml directly in HK will
query that is why we need to surround it
with express and very upper function or
call calls
additionally so if we use following
expression shown on the bottom of the
slide in h kill query weekend in for was
a SQL query much yellow returns 0 or
morals
so we if we inject into vulnerable
parameter following expression you can
see is it opposed great skill will get
SQL query with a query to excel function
call
you can exploit army our HTML injection
I when I was gray scale and is used by
using the following
ah school mop command line in my youtube
channel you can find the video about how
this exploitation method works for
oracle there is get xml magic functions
if you inject following expression into
into hkl always and real to charge and
get xml functions you can influenza
select queries that is marked yellow
return 0 or morals to exploit each kill
injection with oracle database
management system you can use fall in
our command line next method his name a
unique old
I turns out that some database
management systems allows to our use
unicode the limiters like this in your
code similar 000 as a token delimiters
in SQL query so we found that microsoft
SQL server and h2 databases allows allow
our unique old delimiters so in a school
server of this to queries are works the
same in the first query you can see is
it
we use a unique old limiter with Scott .
000 there are many unicode symbols in LA
that works for Microsoft the school so
as Stoke in the limiters about for
exploitation of these two works
this two symbols work this is a no
brakes place and I do graphic space
let's see why it does this method works
on the slide you can
see the snippet from each girl grandma
and rule that is marked read on the
slide tells us that and hibernate allows
I to use unicode symbols in identifies
so if we inject fall in construction
interval honorable a parameter we will
get the following a SQL query and the %
c 2 percent a zero is a URL encoded and
you to utf-8 encoded no break space
unique code symbol here is a bottle of
hqla steam here is HQ st falls apart of
skill
accor is it contains our unique old same
old
see most of this part is Mark teal or on
the bottom of the slide we can see in SD
on not who is a land our function called
then are not with nested function call
which has a name that consists of one
unicode seemed always got . 000 and this
nested function here
his argument I identify and not in this
identify we hide
SQL query by using our unique all
delimiters that is how we bypass
hibernate with Microsoft the school so
unfortunately we cannot use skill mop to
exploit
now all I SQL injection are using this
method
so first time we wrote a simple perl
script for exploitation but it has one
drawback it works against our test
application
so if you want to use it you must
unit r it is available on get help and
you can watch the video how talks
what we did not give up and decided to
tune
I skill mop are we wrote cabin eat the
py temple script and modified queries
not xml file you can find these two
files on github to extract something
from a database using a unique old
method we use squares that are similar
to the squares so here we extract first
eight rolls of column
our bus w from table users and these
squares have special form because we
must convince a habber needs that we're
performing a function call
inside this function called we before
mr. function call with some arguments
that is why or we cannot use equal or
not equal operators we use like and not
like instead let's see how to exploit
each girl injection with unicode method
and a scale map
first you need to copy carbonado p way
and queries . xml files and place them
into a school map home directory then
you need to find injection
using the first command lion and finally
you exploit or a skill injection using a
second come on lion and let's see the
video
how it works ok as usual I show video
competition looks like
she's nothing ok this is our water
application
let's try our long you'll be seein you
call and here is a true changing where
condition we can get false
ok that's it we need to copy this Apple
first of all you need to copy happened .
py into a temp folder in his court mom
home
sort of Russian windows I mean it's
slightly different queries so we wrote
our queries . xml and you need to put it
into xml folder but will come into to
preserve the original one
this is Miss copy
so we are prepared now off your step
let a schoolmarm to find an injection
this is the command
ok all the second step we need to
specify our temper script
you see flag tampa tribune net right
near the these bullet is and you can see
bena as usual but better as usual is not
interesting
let's try to numerate data with a
database horse's name
it's LA but the hpc s coil express slot
with Russia name by the way it's my
father-in-law computer are now we
already enumerated in databases and its
master time to be a model is dbh cool I
the most interesting for us is H cool I
because all others are default database
for sequel server
ok let's elaborate tables from which
call a database
it's bossed users are as usual the most
interesting for as these table users let
simmer eight columns from user stable
and unstable has the username column and
press ward
unfortunately our method allows to jump
our data from table only field by field
but my mind this is better than to use
custom perl script because a square map
usage gives us the flexibility to
specify a row noon of that we want to
dump
we need to set environment variable for
our temple script set on 21
this and again we specify table name old
name database technique is blind
oh where we okay
ok
and ok username is admin to get password
you need to set a capital C flag -
passport and you get something very
interesting
okay to get another string are trying to
get another or from database
you need to flash session before so this
is a comment that flash session
and after that you need to set
environment were able to to to dump
another roll again if I user name
gee Joe and capital C passport dumps
passport
ok that's it actually we can go to our
database management system and find the
slot see school I database that has
these are stable and
it was dros exactly the same day time
ok
the last method we want to present this
cult and Joe Constance method this
method works for the most database
management systems except my skill but
it heavily depends on classes that are
on the class pass of the application we
are taking the reason why this method
works is because cabinet results are
results are fields of our public static
classes are through . delimited
identifier so we can specify for example
Java that long . character . sighs in
our age girl query and however need to
will replace it
- 16 if we are reference in our public
static fields of type string
Archer a hibernate will additionally
surrounds them always to our single
quotes are so Java . long that character
. meanwhile you will be replaced with
just two single quotes so to use this
method we need glasses on our class pass
that have a public static fields of type
Charles strings that have a single court
so
now for example a public static field of
type string that contains one single
quote a suitable part of each kill
queries that ends with a single quote is
also suitable for exploitation or char
char fields are also suitable in the
slide you can see five different
representations of single quote for
chart type all you
you can use interface class with static
field so the public is not mandatory
because in interface class all fields by
default are a public
we searched through and java libraries
to find suitable field for exploitation
and we found two very popular libraries
this is they are ICU for g and blocked
back
this libraries have glasses with public
static fields as a suitable for
exploitation with name single quote and
single culture and
as I said this is to a very popular
libraries and it will probably likely
that the will encounter in as a class
plus class pass of the application you
are taking now let's see how this method
works in I details so we inject
following expression into vulnerable
parameter in this expression we multiply
java constancy underscore underscore 1r2
result of a function called his name x
and this function has a string parameter
so on the bottom of the slide the other
is a h kill queries that is processed by
Hal Berney
here you can see H kill SD for the part
of each girl queries that is marked
yellow on the bottom on the slide and
contains Joe constant here we can see a
joke constant are not in the st mark's
green and also we see on a string or not
that is marked read after cabinet parses
hpl query it builds HQ st and then
translate this HD into SQL SG here we
can see a SQL st for the skill
eh girl query so we can see that notes
Joe constant note and string not not are
a translated to unchanged air into a
school st and we see that Joe constant
is not yet resolved and on the final
step
hkl translates SQL st into a skill query
and on that step in and Joe constant is
replaced with three single calls and we
seize it
SQL sub queries that was concealed
inside string parameter of function X is
exposed and just a quick check when we
add wear clothes that is always true
r to the skill sub-query we hide inside
a string parameter function X
application returns one road to us but
when we change this close to always
false it returns nothing
this means that our technique worked to
exploit each kill injection with Joe
constant Smith method you can use
following the school mark command line
and quick we do creator with John
Boston's so please forgive us i know we
all hungry but just this is with db2
example
so we're very good database
so again our application
this is our long URL is a job a constant
so again this is true
changing we can get false copied this
again true corporation square mop
database here is to be true technique is
blind and here it is our custom
injection .
actually that's all we get better
my name is not interesting let's dump
databases are needs to be true
there's a lot of the places because its
default date the base installation a lot
of examples and all the other
interesting materials but the most
interesting for us is to be 2 into 1
so which is our database let's retrieve
tables from these data base and as usual
to be true has a lot of tables but it's
really interesting to see how is climb
up works in multi-threaded more sexually
it's so broken
can I hope somehow
Oh
pro-ject a lot of tables it's exactly
the b2 example tables post this outpost
to do that is month to our application
and this is users that we're going to
dump in our final command
ok t users dump
anderson who will be good I know
name
it's called name a sport
that mean
virtuelle so thankful password actually
space for patient
the second row the alien who doesn't
know his name
just ask me
ok extra day
that's almost it just a second
ok
and some final verdict from Michael
yes and here is the final part of our
presentation where we will summarize our
techniques for its rotation when you
have found or injection before
exploiting it you would probably want to
know what
orem library you are targeting so we can
use the following table
you just paste payloads different pills
into vulnerable our perimeter and see
what up a load
returns a valid response from
application and here this is actually a
final slide because we gather together
all method we preserved represented in
our presentation and this table shows
each method works on each or M database
combination
I hope this table will be useful for you
because it contains all roads we have
just said and we call power findings
will be useful for your future work and
if you have any questions we will try to
answer
thank you for coming to our mission
so we have worked that time for two
questions and then actually started and
we go to answer two questions
so oh it's it's interesting how you how
you figure out that you have on
aureum injection compared to an SQL
injection how old and how you to take
them like once a day
the majority of job applications now use
lorem libraries so it is incorporated
into g2e application so so if you can
see that you are facing
for example jabe also white why you know
that this application will probably use
or and library all that how you know
that you have an order an injection like
you detect been detected in the
beginning
are you detect it is just
I skill injection
so our boolean stop you just like yes it
could be error based but it works
exploitation message was the same so it
will be faster than our error based
technique will morph rosters and blind
technique
oh you can use the following table just
waste this and to figure out how much
are amused
yes and if it is a school injection that
you will always get invalid response
from application because save my life
yes yes yes
one more one last question in the
audience know guys that I invite you all
to attend lunch downstairs
thank you