hi everyone ah we have so many panelists
awesome panelists on this panel is
probably more than the audience which is
fine because we want to use this
actually as an opportunity to talk with
each other about what works so maybe I
can get all of the panelists up onto the
stage and we can begin I think we'll add
in another chair or two that's okay and
we have also an additional panelists
from India please come and join up
it's really like really Jeff
okay so i think we're going to we are
going to film this session I think it's
fine by everyone
paparazzi Leah
okay so it's it's an absolute honor to
be here with this group of people this
session is called postcards from around
the world and literally the people on
this panel are doing extraordinary
things in their national jurisdictions
in their environments I think what we'll
just start off by doing is doing a quick
like literally just my name is and my
country so you get a sense of the
geographical spread and you also get a
sense of like the names of the people
and their identities and maybe even if
you want to speaking on that in your
native tongue please go ahead um but we
often talk as a digital rights community
about our problems and there are many of
them as we've talked about throughout
the day the focus of this session is
actually trying to frame it in terms of
solutions in terms of what's working for
many of us many of these people are
gathered here actually it can be a day
to day struggle and it can all and you
can feel like we're losing we're
constantly losing the battle and we're
trying everything sometimes radicals
sometimes conservatives sometimes policy
papers to marches on the streets or
online activism you name it whole range
of different activities in order to
ensure the defense of the protection of
digital rights but what we're trying to
do is look at what's working and I think
often people here who are often isolated
in their own space not necessarily
isolated but focused on their own space
it's also an opportunity I would love to
have this almost as a private round
table as well so that you guys can share
and we're going to start off I mean
after we just do a quick hello we're
going to go straight to India they don't
know if the message has spread through
the conference to in the lat good
decision that has been sitting with the
Indian Supreme Court for the last two
years but the case has been going on for
many many years related to that
from the Aichi act in India and the
Supreme Court they're just handed down
an unbelievably positive decision so
it's super excited about that but let's
just get which will hear about what so
we're going to go and say to you but why
don't we just do a quick hello and just
hi I'm cows to buy work for an
organisation called tactical tech and
I'm coming here I'm a toric Shalaby
revolutionary socialist from Cairo Egypt
being Duchess on for domonic YouTube
Nigerian I am Abraham something yeah my
name is huy train I represent voice a
civil society group working on Vietnam
hello everyone my name is Miguel I come
from Lima Peru and I work in if Rho a
civil a society group working on
internet rights hey salam alikum my name
is annie and i work for a sore 19 a
group that works on Iran my name is
Shigar available i'm from india and i'm
representing the organization called s
offense tequila shot for software field
of law center and we work around million
right sir internet because i'm from
pakistan and i work for digital rights
foundation focusing on internet be so
sure good why don't you start off and i
think this is an example of using the
court right so this is about the better
shield back in 2012 now set the
provisions of the IT Act of such that
you could get arrested for three years
if you send a message online would be
annoying or inconvenient when you like
it the provision used so this was filed
in 2012 and then there's another thing
that we had five maybe two
intermediately liability online so what
back then it provided for was that an
intermediary would be mandated to take
down Clinton on deceiving a complaint
from any tire with a party Louise life
so we were walking with mouth shut calm
which is an intermediary linger it's so
it's a biggie website
and so we challenged the intermediary
liability rules and just like he died
like in our bag the Supreme Court has
declared both those provisions
unconstitutional and to be like down
completely so that's that great moon
coming from the end yuddam of expression
on that I mean just to underscore we're
talking about a billion people in India
subject to I mean the internet
population is a couple hundred million
talking talking about basically
offensive language could be taken down
and and and Endocyte offense if you be a
few expressing offensive language online
then you can be prosecuted and there are
a number of people currently detained as
a result of that and then also the
intermediary liability issue here which
is a when is the platform responsible
for the content both of those provisions
being knocked down is incredibly
significant for the hundreds of millions
of internet users India and it's the
interesting use of the court right we
haven't some of us we haven't actually
initiated actions but they haven't
necessarily gone to the Supreme Court
yeah and it can be a very very long and
involved process and as anyone else here
using the courts and center so we when
Sutherlands became a surveillance we
became an issue Nigerian it will a330
what we did was start by writing a
freedom of motion you know request to
government to basically say because the
government wasn't acknowledging that
they were doing this it was an
investigative report and they were not
going to accept that they were doing it
and so we sent that and our case was
struck out of the court because the
George used this phrase useless word I
we're busy bodies and we had no you no
right to ask questions but went back to
court and i think the the success from
the story is number one the george was
petitioned so this was a George would
clearly was against general expression
and was leaning towards Security and
government and he was partitioned and
good thing is that the cases that is it
was involved after that had a more
neutral position because was very
careful because we did cancel get that
and the second thing is that because
we're spinning so we we had
about two years when we were told to
wait and like I said it's a very very
long process so now we're back in court
and if you sean has not been made in
fact we don't think it is wrong with me
very soon because we're you know we have
elections there 11 and so after that
maybe would get it getting cold but what
it has done is it's put us in a new
position that instead of asking the
question or saying don't do this don't
do that we don't like this all the time
we can actually be proactive and the
side one wants to do so yes we don't
want mass surveillance but what exactly
do we want and that led to the work that
we're doing now on the digital rights
and freedom feel for Nigeria so what
we've done as an organization is to work
with other organizations and say hey
well we don't want this we don't want
that but what do we want so what we want
i will put together in a field and so
the deal the first draft of the deal was
ready to go and what we're doing now is
because waiting for the election so
whoever wins to go into the National
Assembly will approach them and we're
basically same to them guess what you
don't have to do any work we've done all
the artwork we've written the view just
take the credit right you know you're
the legislature who sponsored the
digital rights and freedom feel foreign
land here and I think that's very
interested because we have people who
have said our sponsor the deal but
they're very careful because they have
when they going to win I'm on every
level or not but if you have a few
people who might or might not win so if
they win then we already have people who
already you know so forget yet of
positive rights and so because you know
you
they're everything very it's great where
you have a song like that but it can be
frustrating when you're told you is him
party and you're told your kiss is going
to happen in two years exactly one we
have a chance to live
to a duel once it's already been asked
and today we too cute et cetera
or do we also have the opportunity to
create the bill and then I'm really
excited to hear that there's this like
proactive step civil society not only
like lobbying legislative but actually
watching model legislation which is a
great great thing I think in the US
where we've been doing quite a lot of
the work as access we've also been in
the development of these new cyber bills
information for us and trying to work
within a committee and in the
legislative process to ensure that the
Lords of the past create an environment
in which you guys did you want to jump
in on any other as you mentioned about
drafting our data related to cyber
constant government has been working on
us a Bakr and let play ah the thick ah
oh it was like really driven and civil
society authorized they cooperated with
international organizations like article
19 and Philippines and ash
so they considered the recommendation
and the drop because society had
concerns and the woman wants you to work
on its own right now the thing is that
it was very it was a big successful
thing that we work with the
international oops like article 19 arm
they did our capacity building and
analyze the law under the national under
the international standards but right
now the thing is that um after a huge
terrorist attack in Peshawar on a spool
government came up with the National
Action Plan of terrorism and they said
that they are not going to consult any
civil society for now the most
concerning thing for them is to combat
terrorism so this is a very you know and
i think it's around the globe the trend
to look into the laws dropped in the
laws under the international action
policies of terrorism so that that's the
challenge but there are solutions as
well that we are working on it so it's
interesting that we've talked about
judges a few time see as well and i
think what we're seeing is that the
judiciary actually don't understand how
the internet works fortunate to hear
that the Supreme Court really in India
don't have some kind of understanding
certainly of the impact of what these
provisions mean in the digital
environment and in the offline world um
I'm wanted to add here that that's a
very good precedent that that has been
set by young Supreme Court for four
neighboring countries like Pakistan
which actually copy pasted the entire IT
Act for our cybercrime legislation and
we really had a hard time to resist that
legislation so I think that's a very
good president said father yeah and
actually a rip well about what works in
terms of civil society action because do
we know that certain countries in
certain regions have great it in patent
act they set the standard for the region
and we've seen in the European context
that you know the data protection
without a retention standards have been
copy and pasted throughout Africa for
instance so we can you know if we can
have an impact in one jurisdiction of
it's another jurisdiction I'm interested
in this question of that judiciary is
anyone else is anyone working on like
judicial education really important
process that we can undergo because
understanding to interpret legislation
depends on the prosecution and the
defense is to what's before them often
these judges are old and they need to
understand what the rule of law looks
like in the online world how to have
digital due process yeah so I just
wanted to add that YouTube is a lot in a
sample for the last few years because
the anti-islamic on then so the sick of
this case before I the petition I think
that didn't go anywhere but one of the
civil society member she she's working
on the Canon policy she became the
amicus to the judge and she I'm a lot in
terms of understanding you know cyber
issues around the world and also the
international standards have a loss so
that's really helpful if civil society
and the activists who are actually you
know know about the subject and also you
know reach out judiciously to you know
do the capacitive o think that I'm gonna
bring in a beer here because I think
many of us are working in different
environments some pre-revolution and
some post-revolution as well via from
chin ECR and maybe you can just give us
a bit of a sense of like how things
might have changed since the revolution
and how activists are operating in the
different space or not or how
legislators of working any different
space with respect to digital rights
about four years ago we all stood under
the regime of the farmer visible finale
finale we experienced the mass of
lessons are shaped by the government and
unfortunately it was lunch but the
governor envelope at a lot of website is
like it's cool in motion to set her up
and I was I personally I was affected by
the by the censorship when I was working
as a lot a lot developer by trying to I
wouldn't I couldn't use like basic
functionality by after and YouTube nick
is or watch I would turn and it was
really frustrating also our son subject
pieces and this yeah we created anything
our Authority utterbol distance oh yeah
a mark for 150 reference for its
answered website error message so like
yeah also I would develop are like so
just i want i want about 8a agent which
is vision internet agents who is mission
to promote remote internet in the
country but it was evolved to kill
production by answering the median
javascript age and as ultimate Reich
will open cultures of those not said
that it's called wat really either
altered and here it was assigned of
lethal theta
also the government used it like
specialized and by Asian who tap phones
and to make this packet inspection and
even who all sorts of emails yeah it was
done with no notes elation like Anthony
and after the Revolution hopefully the
internet censorship defeated like
because the interim government remove
that conference from Peter network
networking websites and that like after
that we have got we have leave it an
open internal when that allow it to
flushing creativity and innovation but
are in the same time like last notice we
the same time after the Revolution the
government rate in new entity valid ATT
people telecommunication agency and the
protects to contractor in but there is a
lot of worries about the real role of
Austin and we hope not the government
trying to grip tight if I like try to
make surveillance for the political you
like this song so and thanks a lot for
that because we're also going to hear
from correct as well as from eg and many
people say that the tree shion story is
an about the six
success story of spring and we talk
about what works is it the revolution I
mean like we've talked about like
incremental change but actually what
happened in 2011 was an overthrowing of
the government throwing out of the error
404 regime the establishment of in the
Constitution and political process but
maybe depressingly we start to see the
weeds kind of growing again and the
creation of this you surveillance
interview with inches here let's jump to
tarik and here you about in the context
of where we are and alia the story from
this morning and other colleagues in
prison like the concerns of the problems
of the Arab Spring maybe what's happened
there but maybe some green shoots as
well process it might be positive and
what has worked either through that
initial purchase or now it's a lot
easier to talk about what hasn't worked
for the art Arab Spring I think and
that's pretty much about everything he
tried to do has worked obviously we were
very inspired very inspired by the
Tunisians we celebrated their
independence like it was ours and it was
it was it was incredible it was very
interesting that leading up to the
revolution the president's son who was
obviously Mubarak son who was one of the
leading figures in the leading national
democratic party he had a press
conference when sand and someone from
this audience basically one of his
guards was saying what are you gonna do
about the young kids on facebook and
these people these young revolutionary
movements and then he laughed it off and
the whole room was laughing for a few
minutes and then you know a few months
later it was those youth who supposedly
brought down the regime not that really
has happened but that's what the
intention was and I think it was an
indication of how the regime did not see
them this internet as part of the of its
open policies open economic policies for
the international community to come to
and exploit Egypt part of it was to
build Internet infrastructure and they
didn't see that the threat in giving a
voice to the people to be able to
communicate that way that's not to say
that the social media is what made
revolution in Egypt
Arab Spring like a lot of people were
saying that's not to say that but it's a
tool that they weren't very aware of and
then with time they start realizing that
this is very powerful and they started
actually using it and because the
counter-revolution across the Arab world
but particularly in Egypt is so
organized they know how to make use of
this technology to so that to serve
their interests so even though it's us
young revolutionaries on the internet
they're the ones who are organized to
have proper pages who are communicating
we have proper surveillance I don't know
what they're doing and the coordinate
what's going on offline with online we
can talk all you want online and talk
about how much we hate the system and an
insult the the leader and feel like all
rebellious and stuff but we're not
getting much done without organization
so I think right now that we don't have
this censorship on the internet but we
do have massive surveillance and
actually the Egyptian authorities had
put up to public a request for proposals
for IT companies around the world to
come and offer mass surveillance
solutions and that they were going to
choose the best one out there and then
we didn't hear about what happened
afterwards I mean they were just so
public about their rfp and then they
just went to this and no one heard again
and and while obviously being monitored
and and so obviously the situation now
is very slick is horrible because the
counter-revolution is back all of our
friends and and colleagues are in prison
we have a military dictator who was kind
of the prodigy of Guevara in power and
we have a problem that the entire Arab
world is facing is that either go with
the military and the brutal the brutal
force or go with radical Islamists who
are just as opportunists and are just
aiming to be exactly like the military
in the brutal force and the
revolutionary movements are so weak and
non-existent that were actually left in
this binary system and we can't get out
of it so that's where we are right now
okay awesome that's really positive so
let's turn to the audience we've
obviously got a whole range of panelists
to get through I mean I want to talk to
to Iran obviously when we talk about
dictatorships and regimes and the
digital response and Hawaii as well from
the
who's experiencing who's aaron singh n
any real time let's see if there's any
questions or any comments from the
audience just I have just one small
comment to add with the regards to the
judiciary and Egypt and talking about
education i'm sure will agree that it's
just not possible to educate the judges
because they are em you know elitist and
they do not accept any anyone telling
them anything indeed so basically if you
want to teach a judge about the internet
and what it really does just going to be
thrown out so that possibility isn't
there i think maybe pelican expect at
this point um in the panel yeah yeah
yeah i want to when I relate to think
about the how sometimes to the car to
educate judges so we've seen that into
as well but we're taking like a more
broader approach and we say okay maybe
we're not going to give classes 12 12
judges but why not talking to young
lawyers while not talking to law
students to jump professionals so we've
been starting this this work it's really
really as a small work join a class
after class introducing issues like
human rights the internet their ethics
and technology what lawyers or engineers
and we hope this will create like a
chain effect so in the future in 500
years people in on Boone important
positions we listen civilized with
issues of the worker yeah so this idea
about investing in the future like how
do we prepare for the future leaders how
do we become future leaders and get in
power influence future leaders and I
think we're talking about this is this
conference as well as like many startups
were here talking to the big companies
the yahoos and Google's and trying to
get a sense of like when they create
their terms of service make it writes
respecting now when you have thousand
users as opposed to when you have
10 million users because it's far more
difficult when you you know when you
have that kind of scale and scope let's
move to Allie let's hear about the
microphone from either side let's hear
about some of the challenges and some of
the solutions in the context of working
really with you know in the context of
the regime and as a diaspora as well
well I want to highlight that how do you
know that Iranian Iran is on the Western
sanction and one other thing that work
in artist was collaborating with Western
governments and companies which is in
the spirit of this conference bring
these little society and companies
together to explain to them that some of
these sanctions didn't make sense some
of these services actually we're
limiting freedom special access
information online so I small structures
that have we had last year last library
US government came with exemptions for
some of the sanctum and the other words
and governments in EU and Canada follow
fortunately he said they were exempted
from Sanctus and many companies reduce
or stop over complying with these taxes
and many services are available to
Iranian Internet users like anywhere
anyone else many of those sentences
simple things that we take for granted
so that's one positive development
another one which is again in the spirit
of this conference is our collaboration
our group collaborate with cipher is the
private company and they have a very
popular geometrical de Navarre the
collaborate together we localize they're
cool and now the truth is very
accessible to users if they have
questions and safe are available if they
need some educational resources
available so i just want unfortunately
didn't I we don't have that access to
you are knee-deep in system IOC unfit
you have an exploded here for
collaboration with private companies and
Western governments yell to some
positive people yeah so it's really
interesting here because what we've
gotta like digital activists who outside
of Iran
who are working together with activists
inside of Iran I'm trying to influence
the tech sector with tech sector
basically working within the condition
said to them by the US government these
US sanctions that were past that were
just so incredibly like negatively
impacting the people they were trying to
help as a result of Ali and a number of
other groups the US government changed
its policy enable personal communication
services not to be caught up by the
sanction regime and then work very
closely with the tech companies like
Microsoft Google Twitter and Yahoo say
it's changed now you can now unlock your
services in Iran which means the people
on the streets of Iran are now using
Twitter Yahoo I mean using sir
convention tools as well but using yahoo
and twitter etc ways that they weren't
able to do so so it's a victory I I mean
it actually is a victory and I think
we've seen some real movement and some
sense and certainly some appreciation
from people within Iran um but a very
very very very long way to go I tell us
about Vietnam and and what's working
there and what's not well unfortunately
Vietnam is nowhere near India Pakistan
or even Egypt or Tunisia we are very
pre-revolution we only started having
really Stephen society working together
for years ago in 2011 and that was
thanks to the rise of the Internet's
first and then income was getting bad in
Vietnam and therefore thanks to the rise
of social media sifu society started
developing Vietnamese do at an early
stage however there are a few things
that I've been working or continued to
work I could just say one simple thing
that five years ago you wouldn't have
right now more than 10 activists from
Vietnam sitting in this room being able
to leave it now whereas right now you do
have more than 10 activists from Vietnam
coming over here and that was thanks to
not only the rise of the internet so
people know more about their rights and
therefore they have left less fear but
also it connects people social media
connects people so now there's a
situation where in Vietnam most of our
activities are done online whether it is
from political prisoner family making a
visit and then posting the the visit and
the harassment that they they meet right
online and then so everyone then can
follow in terms of figure for example
right now Vietnam has about 90 million
people but we've got 30 million Internet
users and out of those 30 million
Internet users we have about 20 million
people using facebook so Facebook
becomes a very effective tool for
activists to not only post their
thoughts but also where they rally for a
common cause of course the count the
government tries to control and
surveillance and persecute people for
that but it will continue to rise it
rises up to a point where now even the
government has to use Facebook so for
example the minister of health now has a
paste facebook page and and thanks to
that therefore unlike in China where
they can effectively closed down
Facebook and use an alternative where
they can control the content in Vietnam
they can't if it rises over that tipping
point so I think that is a great thing
that is working right now and because of
the online activities that are so
vigorous and so I would say so active it
feels to offline activities so the
online activities supports the offline
activities for example two days ago
hanoi city decided that they're going to
cut down 6700 trees in hanoi well people
went on social media
facebook said not that's wrong and guess
what within like two days 500 people
went down on the street first time ever
for a course like that have people go
down the street to protest unheard of in
Vietnam but guess what be there for the
Communist Party chief of Hanoi had to
stop that policy after like two thousand
trees being cut so it is all online
activities that forces the government to
listen but thats moves out to the
offline activities so those things are
working and it also working because then
people get to know more we have 4
million overseas with amazed who then
can help connect with the Vietnamese
from inside the country and bring them
out here for training and for other
activities for advocacy purposes
possible Ally let's hear affecting you
about I mean we saw obama and rouhani
like tweeting at each other and like how
important is the digital space for
offline social change begin Iran is it
actually is there a connection there
online so like online action like these
kind of examples of why talks about
where you've got you know people were
activating online they can stop those
trees from being chopped down in the
middle of I don't I think the best
example is probably 2009 contested
election that the Iranians used like
Vietnamese and like Egyptian certain
they use social media to mobilize and to
organize them Falls and spilled over
from online we do this week but I can
the offline space we can vary buying it
and also the online space the our
targets were also smart in way of using
that space to identify people so I think
it had a pampering tech and speed slow
down on everything so I can't say it was
positive or negative but I I just want
to highlight that although all these
platforms are officially sensitive on
Facebook through many people use it and
also Iranian officials are on
platform for example Iran's mr. find
their peers has a verified Twitter
account so that's another double
standard that the political elite keep
themselves access to this platform to
reach out but they don't let the
ordinary Iranians I back and had a
Iranians respond to that inconsistency
from one of the better word many people
are online but what you have to pay
attention if they want to come online
they have uses accommodation to the ends
are very popular so they have to pay for
that so I mean yes from outside we see
the ones who come online but I'm use
Twitter and Facebook but probably a lot
of people cannot afford to pay for a VPN
on a monthly basis to have access to a
lot of that work that you do is actually
connected to this it's like how do
people get online and how do they get
online safely tell us about that yeah so
thanks for being patient as well okay
yeah so I just just a little bit of
background about something that happened
in India recently uh in December last
year of the ministry of communications
and I to you in India phosphor about
attitude a secret order to every single
internet service licensing in the
country and ask them to block 31 URLs
and some of them were popular websites
such as github com vimeo com the emotion
faced him um and this was issued after a
police complaint that said that these
platforms were working you to incite
terrorism in the country um talk about
yeah so if there's a lot of campaigning
going on climate change legislation
today we are all really celebrated
because because of the 66 especially the
patient et cetera Indian idea I'd being
struck down by the supreme court I can
do a little bit of background about what
that is an active seventh minute but um
I think what's important is that there
is really very little transparency in
terms of how
how come you typically implemented or
conducted and something that we did
after the block in December is a did a
lot of technical analysis in India and
publish a lot of these sensitive reports
it is kind of and because there is no
transcript it's important that
technologists can get involved and fine
look at how different title it does to
think if one helps us create well create
more data sets about what is being
censored how is being censored what kind
of inconsistencies exist across is peace
in the country when there is no
standardized way for comment or the
judiciary to ask for a takedown or or
specify order the censorship so it's
important to try and collect this data
were also as to developers it helps us
make sell convention tools better
actually understand what time the petals
in touch it gives be implemented and how
can we actually get around it um there
are some amazing tools which basically
build it you bypass pretty much any sort
of censorship a person who really could
exert the best example for that is
probably a tour and it's a and we found
when we were you were testing in India
that there was nothing that tour could
encirclement so but also there's various
different kinds of fit in the pipe porn
circa mention food which antis be able
to generate more of the technical data
helps us can I just check who here uses
tour who here doesn't know what toys
actually the founder of toys here as
well I'm Roger dingledine it's the room
that is here but essentially it's a
circumvention and anonymity tool that
enables you to browse the internet and
to communicate online without being
identified and it also enables you to
jump the firewall so so I mean a beer I
think you you on the digital security
helpline you're recommending tour as a
tool for people to use
yes also in Tunisia a sense a lot of
websites what's answered like you use it
the VPN and third to open this those
website is and also for the moment we
try to recommend those tools especially
for at-risk youths and the girls and
especially for we are leaving and and
secure communication we need to raise
awareness about all those yes these are
security and let's jump back to India
because I want to hear more about the
case and see whether we can take some
lessons from it yes so yeah today's lamb
our judgment it's making us really happy
because some one of the sections of the
IT Act that was shut down is a version
called 66a in the face of it this that's
a provision has existed to prevent
innocent users from online harassment it
is also extremely wave inverted if you
it basically ties things like anything
that is offensive illegal meant of
menacing character or grossly offensive
annoying yeah all kinds of these really
vague term which mean em basically yeah
anyone can go hate this firstly because
it's annoying me or this is this is
offensive to me and and file a file a
complaint and and this is not just
content being taken down but leads to be
tainment arrest and the problem with the
66 a has been that it's be heavily
abused by politicians over the last
several years one of the one of the one
case that caused a lot of public outrage
was in 2012 when a powerful politician
val thought they died and the city of
mumbai was shut down after for a couple
of days and
oh and one of the one of the men was
arrested are basically posted
complaining about the shutdown of Mumbai
and other women like the force it both
were arrested the other yeah yeah yeah
yeah so someone shared a comment and
someone like that comment and table with
you detained and arrested and that's not
the first time the 66a has been a beaut
by a powerful politician and obviously
it's it's been misused and that's the
reason that the Supreme Court today has
decided to strike it down but also its
it has curtailed freedom of expression
and in and has been used as a at
something it they people from being able
to express themselves freely on the
internet so it is actually a big
landmark judgment I am NOT opposed to
the idea of laws that prevent people
from being harassed but this definitely
was not a solution and we've seen it we
steam that it hasn't been for years and
it's yeah it's made in both and when
these operators use the most of most of
you that you actually saw coming from
the political side there were a lot of
people being arrested for have expecting
of course accordingly you know the tire
against bar the next thing that people
that's very saw most of them is wiggity
nothing soil see I will talk about the
petition electrified so they are I think
four cases throughout India remote with
everyone and it's most definitely again
and then go over it started the audience
questions comments yep using like
I check to save that one
oh very much not yet sorry from you on
I'm Iranian it's in the United States I
have a comment alice is here on out the
sanctions fortunately we got the general
license d one last year and now we are
in this stage that we are trying to
share our experience with other
communities at first we reached out
through Sudanese than Cuban fortunately
Sudanese guys and we got recently their
license the same license Cuban be
resolved completely Obama resulted in
fundamentally but now we are in North
Korean stage I would like to ask this
community if anybody knows this
committee we should talk to them and
share the experiences that they can
exempt ICT stuff from sanctions us
sanction that suffering the citizens so
the other problem for implementing this
license is as Ali mentioned is about the
company's unfortunately some companies
just they ran the event then they talk
and share their values but they don't
response even to the government about
the complying with this and this general
license you are witness that we send a
lot of letters to for example Microsoft
will just see the microcell
representative just this event until
next event we won't get any answer
official answer but versus this kind of
company we have much more responsible
companies like Google and I would like
to thank them they are they are more
responsible and every day they respond
to you and at least we know that what's
there are obstacles and how can we help
them we understand them and they also
understand that this is the main problem
that some company unfortunately don't
comply with this licenses in order our
license that we have so the last point
is that even if we
encourage this company to go the
countries like Iran in the school to
make theirs in the country but be warned
them we urge them to be careful if
you're going to enter to Iran like
previously in China happen for google
they give you her permission
conditionally if you give the
information of the users whenever they
want and as much as they want so you
should be careful about that and we just
want to make sure that this company they
won't actually give this kind of illegal
information of the users to the
authorities without any you no legal
reason this is my points thanks finale I
mean I think there's a couple of points
that have been raised there that are
worth highlighting and one is I just
want to pay tribute to the point that
you made about a lot of work was done to
try to influence the US government with
its sanctions on Iran the general
license was issued and then the Iranian
community helped to influence the US
policy with respect to Sudan and the
Sudan community was successful and
helped to lobby the US government on
Cuba and I think that kind of inter
group solidarity can be a really
effective tool if you want to jump in on
any of that also with respect to the
company he's Anthony were sort of thing
some more like I remember when I first
made contact with somebody at Google it
was back in like 2009 after we were
working on the green movement revolution
and I wrote to to a friend of mine
working at witness and I said do you
know anybody at Google like yeah I know
one person and it was Nicole Wong who is
actually i think the other I don't know
she works in the White House issues the
president's advisor an IT anyway and she
wrote back to me and I was like oh my
god i just got an email from google and
now i think we see this is every day
like we have like their departments
within these tech companies that are now
understand the human rights implications
of their platforms
that is a relatively new thing and it's
a great thing so again I think there's
progress it is a long way to go as I
mentioned there are many tech companies
who are not here but now we are seeing
progress within the tech companies where
they respond to us when we have concerns
we've seen their over compliance on us
sanctions for instance but they also
here to discuss with us and hear what
are the issues that people are facing
for example real name policy with
Facebook is an issue that's still very
very light will be discussed
continuously this conference on it stops
yeah well the preferred solution I think
as I said before we need your I raised
the people or NIST about physical and
risk physical and moral risks related to
privacy security because there is a
relation between those two points and
here we have two actors like internet
users and government for the government
but the government we should I think
push and make pressure for example by
making online pressure or our try into
who critical part c litigate some
Tunisian parliament members to be like
digital human rights defenders so they
can help us to write new digital rights
laws and at the same time need to work
with Internet users by letting them know
about their digital rights which they
wished which digital rights they have
and they should head for example can
mansion natural tea and open Internet
also I think should let people know how
to use their devices with pure way and
how can how they can be anonymous and
the internet and unclip their
communication because here there is like
a mass of internet surveillance and we
need to counter that thanks very much I
want to pick up on the issue of
terrorism because it's being mentioned
four or five times they got well how
what is the solution to this problem I
think we're seeing it everywhere how do
we actually work towards the respect for
freedom of expression privacy and
Association online in the context of
counterterrorism which is being used by
governments across the world and
particularly in your country I don't
think so i don't i don't see anything
you should do it right now because in
Pakistan this narrative around national
security and terrorism and I can see in
other countries as well it's actually
increasing and I would like to talk
about the role of companies when these
governments send them a takedown
requests and asking for users data they
actually cite national security and
entire anti-terrorism policies and these
companies most of the companies comply
to them but I think the only solution i
see is to interact more with these
companies and I think these are the
rights phone and the other conferences
these are the spaces where digital
rights activists and organizations
working on internet freedom I mean they
can interact with them and tell them
that what actually they mean by ramilo
and national security and terrorism and
most of the time they say that it's a
blasphemous content and in Pakistan we
have seen that on Facebook lot of pages
were removed by the company because it
was the political content and by the
activist and descendants so I think it's
really important to interact with these
companies and the Union you know their
policy teams that what actually
government mean when they cite these
laws are up but it's a growing and
increasing narrative which is like we
feel really hard to tell them yeah I
just want to add add to that in Egypt in
the 90s the word terrorism was very
widespread was used by the media lot and
obviously back in the 90s you still
didn't have internet and regular
landline TV which everyone got had the
same rhetoric and it was very controlled
very centralized now after the
Revolution after the Muslim Brotherhood
were ousted by military coup and they're
all thrown in prison this terminology is
back again and a lot of Egyptians are
sucking it up and it's true however i
think we with the authorities will never
serve us we will never get to the point
where they're going to do us a favor
there if you want our rights we're going
to be doing pressuring them and they're
going to be doing it it's despite the
fact that they don't want to do it now I
think the best way to get rid of that
obviously is to to empty this word of
meeting so that it no longer has any
meaning for the people so when they say
terrorism is like all else it's
it's what they're saying all the time
does it mean anything so in that sense
while we're trying to do here is you're
trying to reach out to the people and to
say hey you have the military who is
throwing up on Prison is cracking down
there raising prices they're controlling
the economy in the ministries we have no
freedom whatsoever and then you have the
Islamists or just like them just like
beards right and those are the two
groups they have available how about
this I'm talking about minimum wage
about progressive taxation on the rich
about services and help for the poor and
these are things I want to talk about I
don't care about terrorism or what have
you these are things I want your
everyday life to be better now the thing
is we can't get access to TV it's very
controlled by a small group of
businessmen we can't get access to the
radio which is controlled by the
government and by by the army you can't
get access to the billboards which is
controlled by millionaires who are
siding with the military for obvious
reasons however and I hate the sound
like orientalist but the social media is
a platform like Facebook at least the
is a platform that we can use we have 25
million users in Egypt on Facebook the
last breath next president of Egypt can
have his his or her campaign his or her
as if her as a possibility campaign on
facebook and he or she can win the
elections purely by Facebook campaigns
now what I'm trying to say is we've lost
the the struggle to control or to reach
out via any sort of media however
alternative media basically facebook in
egypt is the one tool that we can use
and in order to use that we obviously
need to work together because the
counter revolution is using is s just as
much all the ministries have facebook
pages or the army their president every
all have facebook pages and they're very
active with it we as political political
groups and as activists and youth
revolutionaries need to be using that to
reach out to the people and say hey you
know the hell with us the misspell with
with with the with the army let's talk
about your rights let's talk about
moving forward of this thanks and it's
interesting you kind of sound like a sub
cyber utopian in a way it's like that
the solution to all of these issues in
the context of the radio the printing
the television being controlled is
facebook and the Facebook guys in here
but we've also talked about the context
that Facebook's a private company which
you know responsible to its shareholders
after I feel and like so how do you
reconcile that as as a revolutionary
social I I never thought you would ask
that's a good question please look in a
minute because I also want to give
people an opportunity to close off yes
if Facebook is one of the companies you
want to get rid of right so when the
revolution succeeds we want to get rid
of facebook want to get rid of Google
you want to get rid of all these sons of
bitches make the one percent who are
controlling every aspect of our lives
and our siding with armies and the
military's and what not to crush us
because we're asking for bread freedom
and social justice however in order to
get that we need to work step by step
and so what we're doing is we're using
the tools available so right now we can
use Facebook once we have a true open
source Facebook or we're going to torch
the hell out of facebook we're going to
be able to use our tool and you know
what with the billion people on Facebook
hell this should be ours it should it
should have belonged to a bunch of rich
businessmen who control our information
make money out of it it should belong to
the people and we
using facebook because it's ours awesome
thanks very much i knew we invited you
for a reason banger let's hear from you
you know so it's interesting that and
put that ipad away i can get it done you
know so you've got you've got people who
already use this as the rose there is in
laws to clamp down but i think we've got
a group of countries that I in
transition that's in part of place where
nigeria is where we don't now we have an
on terrorism law but it's about now that
government is using the excuse of and
it's always excuses it's not because
government wants to make the country
safe and secure it's just the excuse
that yes there's terrorism there's poker
online or not so let's let's do the
things one to do so we've got a chance
the good thing is we knew they were
coming and so we measure when the room
when the composition was happening and
every time where the National Assembly
and the conversation went towards
terrorism we also talked about rights
and one thing I was up for was that when
the conversation was always about
terrorism they thought asked government
people who would always be there when
you point it out to them that if you
start mass surveillance today when
you're no longer the president or when
you're no longer a politician you will
be a subject of surveillance you should
see the reaction on their faces because
they literally go like wow this is that
going to happen and that has been a been
a bit of cool enough in the conversation
so 44 countries in transition I think
this is the time not to allow anyone to
blackmail you Lucien elite because the
thing was always that when you had any
conversation people ask me questions
like I use a lot of terrorists and and
the I think it's important to push back
and say this is not a conversation about
me supporting terrorists but it's about
it a two-way conversation yes there is a
security you know question and this is
good conversation but at the same time
there is the fact that I have a
constitutional right to my privacy so
we've we've got a chance to have that
kind of conversation right now
unfortunately it's it's to Ted not watch
government so we
we had the original meeting recently
where someone from the government ghana
you know by the way which is seen as
more open than many other governments in
the region actually talked about
security and said if you have nothing to
be afraid of why are you so worried
about you limited freedom my response
was very simple if there is no agenda
then why are you so concerned if I would
openly protect the kind of things I say
in the name of security and as also i
think that there's some countries like
nigeria others that have the chance of
having this conversation right now but
reality is the conversation between
security and rights and freedom is not
balanced in fact what we need to do is
to have a lot more conversation around
rights and freedoms to even have
anything close to balance in this little
kind of sweet conversation i mean i
mentioned this before in the
government's meeting that happened
earlier today is that in many
governments that decisions are still
being made like we think about I mean
some governments its it is kind of
monolithic perhaps in Vietnam and right
but they still like progressives they're
still moderates even in actually in Iran
and Vietnam so decisions are being made
and then there are also distinctions
between like agencies as well so
sometimes we've been in meetings where
we sit with the the person who is
responsible for human rights and the
person who is responsible for cyber and
those two people often have never met
each other that's often the person who's
the cyber guy who's like and is
generally a man who's like got all the
arguments and got all the statistics and
is able to like basically obliterate the
human rights person or the human rights
advocate often it's a debate within
government as to get getting before they
get to that policy I really take your
point about transitional States or
transition like we are at a moment of
transition there are norms that are
being built right now in all of our
countries even in Australia where I'm
from we're seeing government the
government making decisions on data
retention absolutely like crazy and it's
all again in the name of national
security and the protection of borders
etc but those decisions are being made
right now and I am then I'm really
glad to hear what you said because I
think that what with what we need is
good argument like we actually need
really smart good incisive argument face
that's cuts upset on data as well like
we need data we need information which
actually identifies what is taking place
in the t2 environment what sort of
censorship there is and then to be able
to provide that as part of our arguments
so that we can tip the balance so let's
move to a beer because your balance is
the balances undecided in Tunisia as
well you mentioned that we have and I
think this conversation is somewhat
turning to terrorism but I'm I'm pleased
that it is because I think that we do
this is like the defining feature I
think when we looked at what happened
after Charlie Hebdo you know one hand
you had all of this the heads of state
walking down the street arm in arm
talking about freedom of expression and
at the same time they're instant
shooting counterterrorism laws through
the parliaments so like how do we get to
this point where we tip on the side of
rights as a place on the side of terror
of counterterrorism any perspective in
this final round yeah i think that the
government always use terrorism excuse
our argument for survive i think that
then we need a institution like control
every life surveillance the government
are are like try to make for our target
like we need some control someone
control those surveillances because if
we stay here just listening about
surveillance without doing anything like
the things are going to be like the far
you know and just to pick up on that i
think this idea banger which you
mentioned before about
infrastructure basically all you're
saying is we're creating a surveillance
infrastructure it can be used against
you once this surveillance
infrastructure is in place whether it be
legally or technically we're in a place
where it's extremely hard to roll with
that we need like legal tix our noise
about those actions that the government
are making we need laws to protect the
internet users activist so so we can the
pants it's a government try to like Jade
someone so we need like focusing a lot
of those things and and trying to build
strategies like you want to finish up on
some of the things that have worked for
you and in the terrorism context or
otherwise right i think that vietnamese
still at an early stage and we now
actually doesn't need to talk about
terrorism before it can silence dissent
if you are found guilty of conducting
propaganda against the state and you
thrown in jail so you don't even need
terrorism per se however despite all the
difficulties I think that there are
still enormous opportunities because of
the rise of the Internet the rise of
social media and especially also because
of the fact that never have been amazed
or even Chinese gone such a great chance
of learning what's happening around them
and not just online but also offline I
give you ten years ago if you travel
from Saigon you fly for Saigon to
mandela it would cost you six hundred
dollars a return ticket now will cost
you hundred fifty bucks on Cebu Pacific
I'm just mentioning it because not only
that it's online activity is that are
now cheaper easier to use is not just
facebook but it's blue sky viber
whatsapp you name it it's much easier
for
people to connect not just with each
other but also between countries for
example Vietnam because its joint the AC
on now Vietnamese can travel within AZN
without needing a visa so that is an
enormous opportunity for Vietnamese and
other nationalities to get together and
and overcome all the problems that they
face with the government so yes it's
difficult but there's also some really
great life at the end of the tunnel nice
hi yes whatever we we do have some
really broad anti-terrorism laws but
usually what is being used in order to
introduce surveillance or in order to
reduce in order to make us look some
digital rights is the argument of
security as a general so I we always
raised like two points the person first
went to advocate for evidence supported
policy and many of these ideas about
collecting all kinds of data or a survey
survey intrusive method surveillance
they do not hold that they do not have
like a case studies where they been able
to prove effective against you know a
security incidents and you on the other
hand you need to be able to have a well
educated public that is aware of what it
is that they are losing when they are
doing this trade-off against losing
their privacy against getting more
security there there there may be some
some particular cases were that afraid
of this is valid but as a general point
of view people if they are able to
understand what they are about to lose
they should they should be much more
resistant to this kind of policies under
tension between national security and
individual sec we do individual rights I
want to encourage you want to
collaborate with David Chi UN Special
Rapporteur on freedom of expression I
used to think that UN was just talking
and nothing will come out of us but I've
seen great
coming from you know special rapper to
Frank LaRue and new rapper to David KY i
also want to mention that we have an
election coming up in Iran next March
like a body there from here every time
an election comes up it's like a testing
place for the best little of control and
another settlement in there I think
you're on n gamma is going to deploy
their best techniques and if you know or
if you are involved in q2 or good data
that would help us to mitigate or to
work get deployed epi and then all right
yeah so there is no api and we you know
of good methods of dimension or you have
access to network data with help us to
document information control i like to
hear from you and come help us for the
next village so apart on the judgments
which is being used for today i wanna
say like a five-star wailing for i think
that needs to be a little more
transparency so at least we know or what
what is I understand the risks of that
but we leave the bar the entities that
are involved in this then you have some
sort of legal sanction and you need to
know a little bit more and like you said
about this message that is absolutely
what I'm silence even their side even
that is the area of control as of now is
the website is blocked and you go that
you can do visit it all it says this is
being blocked first and two orders from
the car 2030 community I think he
doesn't know any more about why this was
done in the first place and the reason
and chillin what Einstein with you
whatever with you can search it on thank
you yeah i think i have already shared
my pots around terrorism anti-terrorism
not at the event but i just want to
mention that i think more collaborations
and partnerships are needed among the
you know of activists who are working in
the country and international
organizations and the foreign
governments was a particular idea of
internet free
dump some more collaborations more
partnerships and that's much needed n to
piece together thank you I mean I've
just been scribbling down a couple of
things here along the way I know we've
had a very wide-ranging conversation on
a number of different issues but here's
some of the things we've come up with so
premature I saw international pressure
and collaboration transparency of
surveillance and since it's using the UN
system including the Special Rapporteur
educating the public about their digital
rights regulation and good laws the
creation of them challenging them when
they're bad using the courts digital
rights awareness Freedom of Information
acts judicial education writing policy
ourselves in creating good legislation
which we can provide to talking to young
lawyers and young professionals if we
can start up community using facebook if
you believe in it using Facebook and
other online tools for activism engaging
the Diaspora technical analysis and
exposing processes and data collection
for tools creating good arguments that
you can use in lobbying and advocacy and
engagement deep engagement with the tech
companies so on the basis of all of
those strategies let's use them going
forward and let's have a round of
applause for the panel