I need this book if I don't really know
so good morning and thanks for coming
along too you see this talk um this talk
is sort of grits actors and capabilities
so it's going to be oriented towards
security talk that sort of about the
security requests that face many human
rights activists so I'm going to talk a
little bit about some specific threats
and actors in the region and my name is
moon but those who are aware i'm
currently the director of security at
first look media which is probably its
most famous product is the intercept
sort of BS north reporting and
publishing documents that leaked by this
man it would slow down so it's sort of
glenn greenwald more poitras during
escape and so forth i currently worried
about their mana port security concerns
which is a completely serious job prior
to this i was senior security engineer
google six years and i work desired
penetration tester for a security
assistant security firms love having
really bland names for some reason like
it's really reassuring so like there's a
lot of the limits of a security system
that sort of thing um i also have
affiliations with the number of
organizations a lot of the work that was
done in this presentation was done in
affiliation with Citizen lab out of the
University Toronto and some of it was
also done would be electronic frontier
foundation in San Francisco I also
advised reading the foundations and
yoona Crete which is united nations in
to reach or any justice institute um so
a lot of us talk Tuesday actually get a
beer around surveillance software um
because of my background which is a
security engineer I will probably use
sort of terms like spelled software
implant and malware almost
interchangeably I'm assuming most people
in the audience would be loosely
familiar with these concepts largely
based on kind of stuff like this right
like most people have been on the
internet for any period of time
probably learned have sort of this
cursory and you're worried about viruses
and not wearing the way what I'm
actually talking about today so when
people ask me so what malware is I like
to tell them that it's sort of any
software that shows up on your computer
without an end user license agreement so
if you can click on it to say yes I want
to install this then it in its malware
but for the purposes of this discussion
we're talking about software that
essentially record stuff that people do
on their computers documents they type
conversations they have communicational
video chat and so on and so forth I mean
laughs lightly all the things that you
might want to surveil someone's online
act now let's go on mobile and obviously
so whose governments fire and topless
for Watson I've seen Suites of
commercial soft we have a little psycho
enforcement that offer spying here hello
days apart and a degree in Windows
Mobile they they support you know all
folk or commonly going to use and they
provide all sorts of interesting
capabilities you know logging your phone
calls and text messages usefully
tracking a fuser location by the GPS
tomorrow and probably most creepy
believe the ability to part like the
phone and so you know the phone sort of
still looks like this but it's ambient
leaving everything arise itself um we
kind of sort of odd doing research on
this because I was sort of looking
through sort of addie compilation of the
code in this particular type of empire
theme of the actual function that the
the developer used was called spike or
um and when I looked in her eyes with
this done it sort of led to this odd
distance between myself and this is
device which I'm quite close to so you
know I wake up in the morning and like
lots of pic addicts I get straight on
Twitter you know and all of a sudden I
found myself looking at this and I was
like yeah maybe I should she put this in
the freezer and also I was like never
become one of those people
so yeah it's talking to be a lot about
really cheerful stuff I'm the last I
have a sort of a background in doing now
a research I add some the last really
big thing that I did was I released an
analysis I released the south to
download a bunch of spy software that
was used by primarily the GCHQ which is
Britain's communications surveillance
establishment is equivalent to be in SF
bay and it was used in attacks on the
European Union and Belgian home by the
buyers and so I released this really
intercept now this is this attack I've
got a sort of considerable amount risk
because there are some people who felt
that you know the five eyes in the UK
particularly spying on the closest
allies and the European Parliament and
also Belgian was a little beyond pale
now because of the amount of press like
this type of attention has got its kind
of oddly skewed people's perceptions of
threat and risk now for people in this
room the NSA and the GCHQ probably like
your biggest probably maybe I don't know
maybe you guys have stacks of it Soviet
newts that they aware of but but again
you know but what I wanted to do is I
actually wanted to sort of discuss risk
and threat in a way that I thought would
help people with their security problems
rather than actually hinder them so most
people model threat really really bad
and it's kind of like we actually and
this this isn't just online this is in
real life right this is why we're
worried about terrorists but not drunk
drivers we're worried about getting a
bowler but not heart disease you know
who's we worried about like really
visceral things things that in news and
so I've spent close the two decades now
worrying about security problems I spent
a lot of time tracking nation-state
attacks against high-risk users so I
have a very regular understanding / what
a lot of these types of streets look
like and actually valid does of them
frequency
oh and that means because of because of
the news and get people are like so I
read this thing about the NSA the other
day and now I am super worried about all
of the low-level firmware on my computer
being convicted by the American
government you can you help me check for
it like you have any give outstanding
operations that you're committing again
singer together you're like a nice day
any reason why you would think that
you've Utah article yeah other them this
does happen um sigh Mina not look
another interesting next what's right
what your your cellular phone it's the
vignette so the slogan is actually
feeling system right and it's IRS a
Qualcomm signaling lady ears stop
I haven't actually watched the show but
as far as i can tell for like six
seasons he just ties people with chairs
and tortures them right and then this is
sort of like the final in what actually
happens if you know the information that
the state wants or whatever your try to
get it they cut they can't get it this
this is this is something like the final
end of what could happen now this is
really really expensive because you need
you know in theory you need black sites
you need people that are willing to pull
out other people's TV and then it's not
it's politically difficult like you get
Obama standing up television like I'm
sorry we tortured some folks you know I
don't actually you know you just
generally don't like admitting to
torture and then you get people from
this kind of crowd really human rights
activists and it's a nightmare right and
I'm not actually an expert in
information extraction through torture
so we're not going to dwell on listen
this type of actual anymore but but what
I'm going to get into is I want to
discuss now let now we've talked about
sort of different types of actors that
you said that you're worrying about in
your security model what I want to do
now is actually talk about the players
like who has these capabilities because
now you know the types of attack that
might be brought to bear advanced you
chances are you probably know who you're
worried about so let's talk about what
those people can actually do so this is
this is the GCS cheering and this is a
reality outside cheltenham and this is a
drawing by banksy british graffiti
artists so this is a poem group the
bunch of governments groups you know
attempt to the attached phone with and
it works better the National Security
Agency obviously and so what these
high-end actors right and so the five
eyes this is Israel
just sort of taught me an actor so does
this does this company does this country
have a large military industrial complex
do they have a Silicon Valley a large
getting a little screen perhaps but like
this sort of stuff doesn't spring up
overnight right like this is is you know
50 year ramp up times to developing this
type of capability not so much an into a
software but in terms of like a culture
right so they may act as an old small
batch you know the spokes valence
software coded themselves and house you
know and the people that write it better
probably feared you know smoothies and
get facials while they write they kept
Linnell it's all very lunch you've got a
kind of a second-tier right and and
these are these are governments that
have cash but don't necessarily
traditionally have the in-house
capability to create these two so tools
right like they're just trickle the last
few years realize they really want on
this highly desirable so what they're
going to do is they going to buy them
and so primarily what this does is it
means that governments are purchasing
primarily from Western contractors so
you know people gain this capability by
working for Western governments and they
leave send a private companies to make
you want to make money and then start
selling this type of technology to other
governments and so this is type of
middle tier it's a commercial market
this type of software is frequently sold
to law enforcement intelligence agencies
and countries that don't have the
capability or right to stop themselves
and occasionally it's kind of gross you
sort of see it's all to security
companies that will do things which
might beep instead of juubi three
difficult and this type of access
service is a pay for tools strider
vector after this what you have is you
have a strata that I'm getting I'm
calling for the purposes here Simon
resonates so you'll get groups and I've
seen groups in India Bangladesh like Leo
impact and appen and that sort of thing
that you can you can hire and they
actually have websites right you can
hire ethical hackers as digital private
investigator
we have a think about a little bit about
what that actually means so frequently
what that means is say you have a court
case you really want to know what the
other person is holding higher this
digital program is together to you and
they'll hack the opposing counsel and
steal their emails doctor that's given
to you right I mean these guys are
legitimate risk especially for people
that are bringing all sort of important
suits against against government actors
they we've seen seen the use of these
plans in areas like Angola and so forth
so you don't even really want to pay for
tools right this is a paper job style
scenario right like you don't have an
infrastructure to build your own tools
you don't actually really buy these
tools to service but you have stuff that
you need done right now and then is this
this one that like this is what the
security industry is traditionally been
really worried about right and this is
cybercrime and this is sort of the
Russian business Network these are
people who like to steal banking logins
on mass and that sort of thing in your
you're essentially monetizing cybercrime
on the internet now you know this is
this is all about getting paid so for
all these actors actually the equation
is kind of the same and that's the
resources that the attacker has this is
the amount of money that will cost to
carry out a tab this is the value of the
target and it is this kind of one room
is a strata that doesn't really fit this
and that's a disinfecting business and
black hats right and that's just these
people operate largely based on ideology
um and their motivations a personal
frequently pity and in the case of
blackheads and their frustrating because
you read what what type of research
expenditure this person will spark in it
do as as a as a former corporate
security person I found yet be like
without with the government attacker you
do you know what they want what they're
trying to get how much if it they'll go
to to get it with the sort of the
dedicated black hair or activist this is
a lot more nebulous
so generally generally I put this group
into like you should just not piss off
people in that last category but the
former category you may not have a
choice based on the type of work that
you're doing but this is all you know
sort of a very business see transaction
right like this isn't always how you
need to think about security how
efficient can we make these attacks
against our targets how much do they
cost for me soldier
it's a fantastic idea it performs a very
specific function it won't solve all
your operational security worries so I
kind of want to finish before I want
people to ask questions and that's a
thing but I want people to start
thinking basically it's one thing like
thinking not what your reverser II could
do rather know what they must do right
so sure you can be freaked out about
spice space aliens drones baseband
exploits robots from the future and that
sort of thing but if you think a lot
specifically about when you're trying to
protect that's that's a great place to
stop um so yeah I hope that occasionally
the tools I give and the sort of like I
come to you with problems not solutions
kind of things I've never really done
that today um so yeah if people have
questions I onion anyone I mean let me
shy because generally what happens when
i get these sorts of talks is that
people sit there silently and then I get
offstage and there's like a line of
people who like nowhere what but now
what's happened is that that we will
start encrypting traffic right now just
wondering is it possible to get invented
in the middle so it is I the question
you get to now I mean it is under
variable circumstances it becomes more
difficult and more expensive like once
traffic is encrypted the circumstances
under which you can attempt to attack
that encrypted tunnel based on a variety
of environmental factors for instance
say you are watching youtube using a
chrome browser google actor youtube is a
google property google also distributes
chrome and they actually know what their
properties are supposed to
so functionally it should actually be
incredibly difficult to attack better
having said that to use another example
if you are using you know browser X and
looking at a random property online and
your government actually had the
capability to coerce so Mikey signing
Authority for their countries or one of
the political is of trust but that
centralized model of encryption online
then it is indeed possible that they
could read this encrypted traffic and so
I mean again like encryption is in a
universal panacea it's a really good
idea and you should definitely be using
it um but yeah let's see we can talk
more about that off petition like that's
sort of like yes but yeah other other
people couldn't so so what the question
was a cricketer straight the question
was that this yeah it isn't there a move
yo away from storing things in the cloud
and you know doing things online and
that sort of thing does that I swoop um
I think there's definitely a lot more
discussion about things moving in that
direction like I've done a few
journalists security conferences
recently where I've had journalists say
things like oh we need move back to the
old school way right we we meet sources
dark and garage you know probably
wearing a trench coat and and the issue
I have with that is I'm like right you
make sure you both drove there in a car
that doesn't have GPS writer and you let
your phones at home and your Fitbit and
yeah you know um sorry it is this this
difficulty
try to roll that time obviously right
and there's there's an experience to
online communication especially I mean
is meeting ass awesome person really
safer for them for the source probably
not but I mean did I think this is
definitely a massive and powerful
international discussion about whether
or not we should be moving away of
storing data clouds two countries have
local rock piles decentralization data
localization there's even sort of panels
and debates on this at this conference
so I think I can bet that discussion is
definitely occurring in a really
important way at a macro and is again a
lot of this boils down to convenience so
I have a colleague with whom partner in
crime if you go with Myron many papers
on state spying and he he means my love
of Google logs he just he just bubbles
his mind kateri writing stuff on site
spying why are you writing is a google
doc it's just so convenient like here in
italy you got here but you want to send
file it back and forth and tween us are
over to email what is this my god sorry
even even sorry i mean i know i should
be doing that this and so you know like
this is this that that friction between
convenience and security that I think a
lot of a lot of communities that have a
very real reason they have these
discussions like this one obviously
having those discussions right now well
maybe we shouldn't be doing this maybe
we should be doing that much yeah the
alternative sucks or really want to use
the cloud on sets are basically aiming
this is the sort of guess we'll just
sort of going these days color so what I
like this is this sense of a cost model
capitalism of libraries so I was
wondering if you could actually sort of
pre address three points within the
cosmos a baseband exploits course it
women s associated in addition fake
starts and then the adobe flash from
their pop-up thing could you could you
sort of reframe those but they're not
possible oh okay so Colin wants me to
reframe to SS a cost for a price point
what was it it was being the cost of
coercing a certificate authority to give
you that's the type of key to play to
read in traffic or certain type of your
traffic the cost of a baseband exploit
and sort of the p/e for a flash holes
for will repeat history model so um the
use of like we'll talk about base to end
exposure to second for us so this is
this is a certain type of zero debt
specialized type of zero-day exploit
right these are actually quite an
experience there's being significant
discussion about them in certain types
of communities over the last couple of
years actually the sale our exploits by
researchers to the government which
imagine into a lot of people thinking
that they constantly targeted by Sierra
takes place from time these are actually
reasonably expensive when every time you
use the negatives so as I sort of a
general price point like a zero-day
exploit and proto probably about three
hundred thousand years dollars I'm
according to Christ's that I've hug then
privy to recently and so I mean again
this is this understand I is that you
know this is this is mallory is the
active attacker underscore money now and
you're like baseband exploits know quite
expensive degree bespoke is not many
people selling them the likelihood that
you'll be targeted one because you might
be kind of interesting to the government
is highly unlikely like you would
probably definitely have to be a person
of interest and so you notice these
multiple policies on this the cost of
reversing a certificate authority inside
your country I mean again this
essentially speaks to a plan to
landscape right because what you're
essentially doing is you're all meeting
at capabilities of you right like you're
already your abilities to collect
encrypted traffic already there and they
basically free what you're trying to do
now is I just read it all right so you
want to coerce people that hold keys if
they're inside your country then
disconnected you're relatively cheap
thing to do it can evolve a specific
type of threateningly document however
reminders of all Jack Bauer depending on
how you actually operated something the
costs can be different it can actually
be incredibly cheap however if your
country the person you're trying to
coerce is not inside your country then
what you do is now now you actually have
a situation like Mallory and is actually
happened where the Iranian government
road
but we Google traffic that they were
interesting thing when I can scoop up
because Google Facebook right now other
people they were intercepting in country
does this one complex multi stage and at
that point it doesn't actually start to
cost resource right um the final one is
these are kind of killing the final one
is Columbus that are asking about that
that big flash player pop up that we saw
now the interesting thing there is that
it's actually sort of a cheap way of
carrying out a certain type of attack
and that's so this is this is mallorie
this is an active team must cost money
and in terms of this rig right like you
your most interesting people's
trafficking and injecting things into it
however in this case you're actually
attempting to socially engineer the user
you
it will work even if people at the
trained not to be aware of these types
of things because I mean everybody in
this room cares about security some
extent which is why they're install
they've probably been given a lecture on
not clicking on strange attachments and
unsolicited emails i got an e-mail or
hey you're awesome really great so you
get this talk such dad my clothing you
know we've really like you to come to
our conference and we're prepared to
offer you 25 thousand dollars speaking
fee and business class flights and we'll
put you up a five star i finally
recognition any of it comes through your
attendings actually click of a sort of
thing it's it's largely about
understanding the motivations type right
like in that sense do you play on a
sense of entitlement and a likelihood
that you know someone someone who does
these conferences actually receives a
lot of legitimate emails fighting the
conferences so i mean that that sort of
thing does work is reasonably to perform
in a reward way obviously you know if
that's how you're planning or
compromising a specific individual you
know then it becomes more expensive
because you're going to start collecting
information about that individual like
your success in this is based on large
about how welcoming type and so hoping
someone an adobe flash update is a
pretty generic way of trying to do this
and it's i would describe it on the sort
of the cheaper end of the spectrum i I
think this is sort of a reasonable
suggestion and someone with like I'm not
going to do that so yeah I'm mentor
answers your questions but if they see
once you start getting infinite I said
it does sort it's a blended landscape
why do you think the dual it's balanced
or twist and I sorry I see this is a
two-part question right sir so one is it
was basically like most of the
government's in the Southeast Asian
context fit into a second tier at the
sort of second-tier approach some tools
and the the second one was yes what do
we see it as inevitable as normal
governments will also create bespoke
tools for surveillance purposes and so
the first question is interesting like
we've certainly seen governments as
areas assets of Indonesia Malaysia
Vietnam purchasing commercial
surveillance tools for all misdemeanors
for these years having said that Vietnam
actually has a semantic security
conference from ian's if they actually
have a couple of different groups of
sort of security researchers that are
reasonably high profile they have a
couple of antivirus companies they have
a gaming industry what will the sudden
if you actually start looking through
like Microsoft advisories for Vietnamese
researchers you'll actually see that
there's people developing high-end
exploit and that sort of thing which so
it gets sold throughout the region so
not not all the countries in this region
necessarily in the second tier right as
to the cecum christian like I I think
there is an inevitability of and health
tool development however that's actually
just because it becomes cheaper to
develop these things all right so I mean
originally the
as as the popularity of these types of
tools increases sort of more tools with
the creation of these tools like you
start being creative right so a lot of
stuff that used to be done manually and
now we done in automatic fascism it
actually becomes cheaper for people to
actually start rolling out this type of
capability themselves so i think we'll
definitely see more of that that's just
the the price point of like bucci
capability is starts driving down at a
time right so you know I just think way
to look at it might be at the rate at
which attacks that are considered to be
academic or implemented so for instance
a NSA maybe two or three years ahead of
Republic what's not whereas we take you
know sort of other countries with less
money fewer homes I grad students or
this type of thing the rate at which
they do implement theoretical academic
attacks might be actually like five or
six years after you know these these
things that first become public so I
think that will probably space or a
static based on the resources of the
country however it is becoming cheaper
and cheaper to write sort of thing in
certain areas so yeah I mean I think the
countries in the region will inevitably
be enhancing their capabilities which is
as better I guess an outcome of the
Snowden revelations that I did not
initially anticipate which is it has
actually done a lot of great things for
people selling surveillance technology
because there's been looks like the NSA
has all these toilets we need more
budget we got to get some of this play
come on guys that's that's a real thing
and that's been happens I mean I think
that they'll definitely be this sort of
a difficult inimitable increase and
desires balance capabilities please
okay hi I'm busy first we'll be is still
releasing original recording based on
the Sony files are there steps that
first of all he's hating as a news
organization that are unique to sort of
having that responsibility of having
those documents that people in this room
may not be able to do or is it just a
combination of all deploying all the
tools that are available to your typical
news organizations were not profit you
know it presented the Gemalto story that
came out recently with your health and
it's basically that these files are
still there are still being discovered
and released so just curiously in from
that are there any lessons that Eagle
group are necessary funded by the video
tape onto themselves that's that's
that's a really good question I'm some
of it I'm not going to answer and like
so the question is kind of so-so my
organization is publishing and doing
original reporting on the Snowden
documents which which we still releasing
more of he mentioned the camel toe tax
story recently even and this was when it
was shown that the NSA and gchq
compromised the world's largest sim card
manufacturer in order to just steal the
keys sim cards which the room yo greatly
enhances their their cellular
surveillance capabilities and so his
question was you know have we done
anything special in order to yeah
because because there's obviously so
much sensitivity around some the
documents that hold so I thought I mean
you know what what advice can I give to
sort of other organizations human rights
of journalism and this research and
reporting on so now just here we've
definitely definitely been a bunch of
specialized in deep
some things that did not at first of all
I would hope sort of otherwise maybe my
job is giving tours from experian but
but yeah the we actually have a security
team at first look and then actually
enables you I mean security is not
surgery is not about tools rights
curious about procedures and
infrastructure and you know software and
two chains and it's about a variety of
things and so I this actually sort of
gets in many ways to the heart both of
what I was trying to do here that I
actually feel that this community does
have a very tool based approach to
security right which i think is because
it means that you don't sort of obviates
the need to have specialized resource
right which which I think we're very
uncomfortable recommending that we need
so what we're doing it first livers we
actually have security engineers not not
people who have kind of an interest in
security but actually a background in
human rights but they learn how to use
p2p like no like I mean I spent five
years breaking into computers for money
and I spent six years on the Google
school we had actual story engineer
strike and and I think that this is I
would love to see more organizations
that money and resource to that which is
kind of an ugly thing to say us what we
really want to hear is that the open
source community should write a few more
schools and they sneak a better you eggs
and then everything's going to be great
and that's just not sure and so I mean I
think that and if I wanted to be cynical
I could say that it's probably easier to
get two hundred thousand dollars to pay
for a conference and fly a bunch of
people and to really have a discussion
about security than it is to pay for
security software if I was being really
cynical but everyone so um so I mean I
might think that organizations need to
do is is sure I mean I think there's a
lot of value of education so I mean
internally at first look we have all of
our internal email is pgp encrypted OTR
is the department that everyone shares
all of our phone calls
by using signal we also do a lot more
stuff that I really necessarily
recommend that organizations do without
dedicated security resource now that's
that's not available to some groups for
sure it is available to others for
instance I have been fighting this fight
with regard to news organizations and
that many many news organizations do not
have dedicated security resource and yet
they owned by conde nast or Rupert
Murdoch or you know and these are
actually giant international
conglomerates that that could be doing a
lot more particular users so I think in
some ways it involves like a perspective
shift on how we actually see security
rather than you know security is using
for but but how that's done in a
cost-effective matters is differently
challenging please and thanks for the
talk getting small organization based in
fresh and to understand the way to my
consciousness in Syria and do you have
any interest in 22 yeah thanks to
understand the risk and start looking at
constitutions right oh and my did admit
to being the kind of person okay
everything um so that the question was
you know what you say to organizations
that are working and probably comparably
safe geographic location say you know
the UK or you risk something and they're
working with groups in potential hot
spots like Syria and that sort of thing
I'm how do you convince these groups
that yeah sort of security is is really
important without sounding like paranoid
not um something like I think this this
is this is you know really sort of hints
than they
did I think a lot but for this community
I actually had a very visceral
real-world example this way I was giving
a talk a little bit like this one but
actually a lot more focused on actually
the nuts and bolts of malware of
government spying and how it actually
works and I had gentle and what got to
me out of the tool and he said that
happens to me what happened was like
yeah so I got this email and it was
apparently about the human rights report
on china and you know I opened it and
they liked it it was just like the
document was blank and nothing happened
and then I sort of ignored it but I'm
thinking about and I have a look at I
was like wow this is actually Chinese
government now I like you you're you
will do and it turned out that he was he
was a loyal and true to prosecuting
human rights abuses will try trying to
do so I was actually sent his belly way
he was actually be really concerned that
this attacker just look huh what is that
baby my god this is this kind of thing
like you seem very very relaxed about
this um and and actually in order to get
through them I was like as a lawyer
would you not just be furious if you
found out the Chinese government had
sent spies to your office physically to
break in and then go through your filing
cabinet look you outrageous that's
exactly what's happening wait you know
so I mean like even even actually
explains what the significance of being
targeted in this minute is can actually
be challenging um and I think I mean for
protecting sources or you know people
particular people are supposed to help
this is a very interesting problem
especially in areas where operational
security failures on your part might
have drastic consequences on their end I
think we're getting better at that as a
as a community I I really do
I mean I thought that this is probably
quite a lot of practical examples I
think I think staying away from from
freezer phone mentality is really
important because it's it's nothing much
just makes you sound paranoid it's also
kind of paralyzing because then people
like oh I'd love to do something but I
heard that the NSA has actually put
implants in all of my pets friends so
like what can I really do at this stage
like I'm just going to notice right the
the way I could try to do this is to get
people to like to I guess judge how much
security willingness I think
organization or a group of people has
and then try to pitch to that rotten
like I am going to drag these people
kicking and screaming through all of us
like well maybe what I can do is we go
and like well you guys are all in
Palestine and you drive through Israeli
checkpoints constantly have you thought
about just encrypting your computers and
products but I mean that's like a
one-day one offset I mean so i guess
like sort of picking the security
willingness of the organization will try
to pitch what you think you can get done
it's probably a great first day anyway
yes this is an atmosphere true with the
release recipe by admin assistant just
can't risk factors like christianity
listen Sam Stockbridge can use till they
see things like hacking team in bishop
on Jana to recommend that and I'll truth
you're not exactly we'll look at those
basic kind of things no tools there do
everything for you which is the point
size are your to meditate right now
detect is actually an interesting tool
to cheat is is a very specialized tool
for doing a very specialized thing the
check is designed to see if your
computer your Windows computer is
infected with finfisher or remote
control system just written by hanging
uh there's there's no harm in using it's
a tool you simply have to know what
using it actually means and it's just
here at this specific moment in time
that your computer is not infected by
these two specific strains of lawful
intercept malware that are used by
governments that doesn't say that you're
fine it doesn't say that you will be
final Egyptian like it's simply like
your it's like getting a blood test or
two very specific diseases right now so
you're like well I went to this country
do I have west nile virus you don't so
something like I think I think using to
take is very useful if you have very
specific wiring and I think that that's
good knowing knowing why you're using
the tools you can usually supported I
think is sort of something I've been
trying to emphasize your hands for so
you having detectives is useful for
checking for that specific types of
malware I don't know the tools that i
recommend I mean to be honest I'm not
sure I recommend any any tools that
aren't already being recommended by the
meanies with capable digital security
trainers in this place because obviously
when you're deciding to recommend a tool
there's this sort of balance of you know
what is it dude vs. how hard is it to
use our way you know there is one that I
really like I try to get everyone's ears
as if I can't do it so my phone actually
and and and i love it specifically
because it's great so it has the best
user interface any security product i've
ever seen this you can see my phone it's
currently off right the hips buns oh my
god it that's what we pay I've run out
with my subscription basically what this
is this is a VPN software and it has one
button and the button does on and off
which is freaking fantastic so so I
actually you know when people like oh
you should use the VPN that's that's
actually great out here and a BP
is an encrypted tunnel so say you don't
trust the Wi-Fi and the hotel or airport
or wherever else or stain you can use
this virtual private tunnel which will
tunnel you out somewhere on the internet
matter that's a good idea and you should
use these things this I getting people
to set them up and configure them etc it
has historically been an awful drag I
don't like doing it on a phone this was
also because you have an on/off button
and it just goes um the downside is it
does cost to all of which i discover i
have just what but I actually think
that's actually not a bad price like
this is cool freedom freedom within a
young agent so freedom um so yeah I was
going to say like in terms of a tool
that I actually don't feel I know the
guys that wrote it as well you know but
they're pretty sane so I mean I guess I
am duly disinclined to recommit tools
but but that's not a bad one as this
comber alright so given that that's
that's a really it's a really tough
problem right because is there any way
to secure a smartphone like the
difficulties that you don't have much
control over your force I mean in some
ways Linux is infinitely securable which
is infinitely tin horrible that's not
necessarily great as anyone from this
real preserve a long-term linux user
knows you can spend forever to agreeing
with your linux box and the value so
it's hard because frequently your
problem is that you're your mobile
service provider is not working in your
best interest from a privacy
anyway I think it was actually though I
think that the quote that you know sir
that information is the new oil or
something like that was actually the
horizon executive right and yet in
aggregate of course not detailed matter
but you know you you can tell
advertising companies that yeah we've
learned from you know the people at
access I cellular towers with their
phones that you know this neighborhood
is largely african-american between the
ages of 20 and 35 and 62 mm you know
right like I mean they they do keep a
certain amount of granular data on your
movements and that sort of thing and
this is no real I can't think of a
single like privacy free mobile provider
like I don't think there is one that's
actually come out and see what yeah we
put for the users that's that's a tough
problem right light and that is leave
many people I know choose just the
moment security problem is untenable so
I mean having said that there's the
other side of things I think one of the
most interesting battles to come out of
the Snowden revelations is actually that
that's occurring between US intelligence
and law enforcement and primarily Apple
actually because apple recently Anna
will during Lee also move they made I
message ng and encrypted now I message
like the default messaging app on your
iPhone writing since what handles it
takes mr. leskovec so it's got some
problems like you can't verify keys and
blah blah blah so it doesn't pass that
the end of the sort of a paranoid crypts
are in the test but what that means is
that all the sudden you've got 500
million users are using into in
encrypted messaging it's crazy you can
see why the US government was like oh
right and there's a big fight going on
at the moment where you know if bi
director has been
Apple is helping the terrorists and
they're trying to get there to change
the software really hard because it's
actually real crypto on a commodity
devices transparent visit um I mean
that's actually a really interesting
fight to watch to unfold so I mean yeah
that the cellular problem is a hard one
and you I mean in a lot of ways this is
a toast to write you buy an appliance
you given it you getting a mobile
computing experience right it is not
really a general-purpose computing
devices we understand it and so these
simple things and some bad things with
that the bad things is obviously that
you know I'm Apple what kind of jokes
about that we've gotten thinning your
mobile service providers terrible people
that want to give all of your data to
governments and advertisers having said
that you know in the case of Apple and
is it you actually have a reasonably
widely distributed easy-to-use into
messaging platform but they haven't even
told you this information corrected it
just is and that's actually a great way
to get people to use encrypted
communications so all right I think I'm
going to wrap this up now thank you all
for coming and I'll be around if you
want to walk across Christians help you
to post them in the circuitry