>>Hello >>Hi >>Welcome to this
presentation there was a few of
you still filing in um but just
sit down find a seat sit down be
humble [chuckles] do what
Kendrick Lamar says. So instead
of having a normal boring like
here’s our history basically our
CV on a slide uh what we have
instead is a more or less
summary of of our lives but I’d
like to read you the bio that we
submitted for this talk because
I think it’s one of the greater
literary works of the 21st
century. We were raised by
computerized wolves with a
pension for fine art and rum
based cocktails while tik-
technically from different
mothers and also sides of the
world we formed the first cyber
wolf brothership shell bent to
[inaudible] the state of
targeted malware implants to
support the ongoing war against
the institutionalized mediocrity
of the corporate shadow
government working in tandem
with dolphin researchers funded
by the oligarch llamas we found
a way to synthesize powdered
ethanol into mechanical pony
fuel. That’s it [applause]
[coughs] So clearly we’re here
to talk about some gun it’s made
of meat it shoots bullets of
malware but before we do that
I’d like to just give you some
background of the the reason
this is here and the reason is
that this is a tool for red team
by red teamers to solve some of
the headaches and problems that
we have in our day to day
operations because we wanted to
be able to focus on the
challenges that really matter
and not all the really like
annoying stuff like like
reporting not being very good or
having to go spin up a bunch of
things so also if you’re asking
do I mean pentesting? No, no I
do not I don’t mean to start a
holy war here but it’s not a
pentesting tool I don’t even
think we do pentesting anymore
it- it’s- it’s red teaming but
this tool isn’t going to help
you penetrate anything this
isn’t a hacking tool that has a
bunch of exploits in it this
isn’t something that is going to
like I don’t know penetrate a
network in any way for you it’s
um it’s a tool for red team. So
fundamentally it’s a framework
for creating, managing and
interacting with stealth
implants that support persistent
adversarial operations you still
need to have those implants you
still need to be able to get
them in the environment somehow
it’s basically just a shell you
know? Management portal. So um
red team operating paradigm we
th th- more background on what
we do and how we do it so when
we- when we do scopes we try and
scope it so that it’s any
systems, humans, processes,that
are employed by the target we
call this yoloscoping. We choose
the targets for ourselves as a
red team and we try most of the
time pretty successfully to set
the rules of the engagement for
ourselves and we never time box
it right? We- we set the amount
of time we need as well and it’s
it’s however long it takes
because that’s how the
adversaries work too and if
we’re going to simulate
something accurately, it’s
however long it takes, not you
have two weeks to hack us or
else. Pfft. Also um sometimes we
do steal stuff for real and
because of that instant
responders, they respond for
real, they treat us like we’re
real, and because of that we
have to try really hard not to
get caught, and we have to pull
out any stops necessary. We try
and read out our results to
large audiences as well too not
quite as large as this one but
um it’s it’s it’s about trying
to craft propaganda and craft a
change for security to uplift
things, right? It’s not- It’s
not just about HA HA it’s hacked
here’s your list of results so.
A bit of an origin story
starting out basically, new job
they say hey hack stuff also
cause an impact also don’t get
caught also do you have shell
yet, wait, do you have shell
yet, do you have shell yet? So
after a few weeks of do you have
shell yet? I’m just like fine,
I’ll just go get some malware
and that sounds easy enough and
and I’ll craft a social
engineering campaign and I’ll
just get someone to run my
malware except most of the
decent malwares was for windows
and anything that was for osx
either didn’t have encrypted co-
communications which is a no go
and you have full network pcap
it also maybe didn’t have like
persistence mechanisms or the
shell wasn’t even interactive.
So write your own. My first
malware dot jpg basically it’s
just a python script that makes
reverse SSH tunnels happen,
pretty rudy- rudimentary tried
to put some cool tricks in there
like using Twitter to resolve
C2s, random scheduling, things
to try to thwart our blue team
and it was obfuscated and there
was a nice script to try and
like generate it different so I
was able to try and be
adaptable. And it worked good
for like about a year maybe this
this was a pretty effective
piece of thing because when you
custom write something it works
good >>This is my favorite gif
by the way I think in the whole
presentation >>Second favorite
[laughs] but this comes with
some problems, first of all blue
side, they don’t like getting
wrecked by a python script um so
naturally because it’s an
adversarial game they start
writing specific detections for
red team and specific-
specifically to detect the exact
techniques that our malware
deploys and because of this the
attribution of the red team gets
really good so our ability to do
things like not tell them it’s
us and have them believe that
it’s not us goes down big team
and suddenly we are getting
attributed all over the place
and we can’t be good boogeymen
and plus we still have this
thing that’s like mostly
spaghetti code ‘cause I wrote it
and I’m crap at that so we
iterate new team members you say
hey like one of the first things
you’re gonna do, write some
malware, and she writes a java
SSH full implementation, goes
both ways, does pretty much the
same thing but looks totally
different and that works for a
bit then we have to iterate
again we a- get one that’s
written completed in bash and we
add some new tricks to it we’re
just like yes this is great new
malware, new tricks, we’re like
DJ Khaled, we da besss
bar-war-warr [sings] right? It’s
great except the status quo was
that we ended up rewriting ou-
our malware each time that we
wanted something new and we had
to stand up all our own c2 each
time as well and we had to
manage and configure it all as
well this kind of sucks and we
have to manage the keys and the
certs and it took a lot of time
and effort and this is prone to
errors because of the time and
effort we start messing up we
accidentally reuse a C2 that
gets us attributed that’s not
what we want maybe things get us
caught sometimes we- one time we
accidentally connected to it
from like the the internal
corporate network now you see C-
C2 and also red team laptop
connecting to the same thing,
yeah, owned, right? This was
painful because their stuff is
unreliable it’s impossible to
maintain, it’s impossible to
truly iterate on it, and it’s
really hard to add features
because again, spaghetti code,
>>Spaghet >>So wouldn’t it be
nice if you didn’t have to write
things from scratch every time.
Sorry [laughs] cutting new
malware implants only took
seconds, and you could pick the
features you wanted for that
implant and the C2 server
infrastructure setup happened
automagically for you and each
sample was unique so when you
take an MB5 of something you
upload it into Virustotal that
means nothing and each C2
endpoint was unique, these are
operational things that we want
so bake them in right? And you
didn’t have to manage the keys
for those servers because you
know that’s hard and wouldn’t it
be nice if the malware was just
super fugging awesome and each
time you added new things to it
it just got better because you
actually had a system to iterate
on it? So let’s imagine I- I
want you all to reach under your
seats, underneath there we’ve
placed like on the Oprah Show,
an imaginary thinking cap for
you [laughter] >>You’re not
reaching under your seat >>That
guy! Thank you I knew I could- I
knew someone would do it, so
we’ll put on our imagination
hats and let’s imagine a world
with better malware for red team
operators like us where it-
there’s a framer let’s imagine
that we build it in a way so
that we can build the features
we need. So we have a core and
the core we probably want to
bolt on some modules to it maybe
things like how to connect to
network and this could be
something like as simple as a
network connection or as complex
as Reddit posts or Youtube
comments or Twitter things
right? >>It doesn’t necessarily
only have to be one either you
might have multiple different C2
methods >>Right >>And you can
have all of those in the same
malware implant and then swap
between them or- or send
fragmented packets across all of
them. >>Which would be really
hard to do with spaghetti code.
And then we can also have things
like persistence modules because
we want to run long term
persistence ops. Bad guys
already have this stuff just no
one really shares it right? But
we can do better simulations if
we had this right? Maybe we
wanna have like a dropper right?
And we [laughter] the- the
spoiler alert is I don’t think
we have this yet but we’re-
we’re building this for the best
case scenario for the future to
scale for like our own
capability so maybe we want so
that when a system is infected
it takes little information like
hardware ID’s of that system,
submits that to the server, and
then the server says, here you
go just in time copulation of
your malware, it’s encrypted for
your system so when you pull it
off that system and you throw it
in your automated sandbox
[smacks lips] it doesn’t work
>>And even if blue team kind of
know that you’re doing this you
can randomize the metrics or the
the IDs that you’re using on
that system so they still have
to put in some reversing if it-
to work out you know what you’ve
actually used that time >>Yeah
so we’re we’re we basically
wanna be able to change our IOCs
programmatically, right? >>And
then uh because you’ve got all
of this in the one framework you
can then start to do more
advanced things like have threat
profiles for a specific
operation so maybe you know this
time you want to spin off your
C2 this way and you want to have
it in on on this cloud provider
and you wanna have um like this
particular configuration for it
well you can do that in the
framework and you can start to
simulate that with multiple
operators all at the same time
they don’t need to um manually
do that it just happens
automatically whenever you spin
off that C2 and every yeah >>So
you can also probably do things
like if you’re you’re a red team
right? Part of what you’re
saying that you’re doing is
adversary simulation so this
could give you the ability to
say, okay I’m going to add a
network module in and that
network module is going to
dictate how the traffic looks on
the wire so even though you get
to use your shell like whatever
you could say let’s mimic this
threat actor based on a pcap get
it in and get that type of
traffic >>Yeah you can look at
the the frequency of uh uh
packets you can look at the
average size of packets and you
can look at the average length
of connection and then you can
use those types of connections
in the network, split your data
across multiple ones of those so
when the blue team is looking
for data being exfilled it’s not
being exfilled over one
connection but multiple
connections that all look like
common traffic on that- that
system. >>So let’s keep
imagining alright? It’s nice
that if we’re gonna have more
things we’re gonna have more
things that we want to
cronenberg altogether and we
don’t wanna have to rewrite all
these different components so
let’s just let that be anything
else and also we should probably
write it in Golang right?
>>That’s sexy these days >>Go-
golang is sexy right? Yeah >>Who
likes golang? >>And this all has
to work together and it needs to
come together as like a singular
atomic unit like the things that
make up our bodies and our ever
expanding universe and it should
probably adapt to any situation
like Macgyver like work on
different Os’ do things like
that it doesn’t need to be tied
to a certain thing and it should
be designed eloquently >>Yeah,
like Taylor >>Like Tay tay
[chuckles] This guy loves Taylor
Swift like for real [applause]
like >>Cool so yeah that’s what
we built >>Well, the beginnings
>>So let’s have a look
>>[laughs] No it’s done >>So, So
we start with the core that you
kind of saw before we need
everything to- to kind of be
oriented around this so you- we
can bolt the functionality into
a common- common uh yeah a a
centerpoint. It’s essentially a
microkernel so you’re managing
execution flow between all the
different modules and and
whatever their functionality
might be as well as passing data
between them and then saving
that and returning it to the C2
network. So the core is gonna be
in a specific language uh right
now our first core is written in
golang and you can attach golang
modules on to this uh and the-
the core determines what
platforms it can run on so in
this case golang is trivially
cross platform so you can run on
uh Mac, Linux, and in- on
Windows. So when you want to
execute some part of that module
functionality how does the core
manage to do that? Well it uses
two specific things uh to manage
execution flow one is an event
loop where modules can register
themselves to handle specific
events uh and it’s it’s if
you’ve done any OS programming
it’s very similar to like a
standard OS event um when that
gets signaled by any module it
will then trigger the the module
which is going to handle that
functionality. And we have a
scheduler loop maybe you wanna
have some code that’s going to
execute every hour, every day,
or every week, uh well in this
case the core will handle that
for you as well. So if we look
at an example of a module the C2
module is going to start with
because every core needs to have
a C2 module in order to connect
back to meatpistol. So this is
our C2 module it’s job is to
without the core needing to
understand how it does it
connect and disconnect from the
meatpistol network and provide a
method for the modules to
communicate data or transfer
data back to the C2 network for
the operators to use. So how
does the core know how to use
that? Well once again it comes
back to the core knows that if
it triggers a C2 connect event
that the C2 module will do
whatever it needs to do and then
report back on whether it
succeeded or not. So in this
particular example C2 connect
and disconnect. Alright. But a
malware implant that only has a
C2 connection is not very
exciting so why don’t we add
some persistence to it or why
don’t we add some file
capabilities to be able to put
files on that system, grab files
off that system, download files
from the internet, then we
perhaps we are doing a whole
bunch of common activities every
single time we compromise the
system to exfil chrome cookies
or you know to see a password or
whatever it is you do when you
get on that system why not wrap
that up into a single command
that can be executed on demand?
And then of course we need
shells, so we need an exec
module and then you can start to
think of a whole range of other
modules that you might be able
to use with the framework for
example you might have a module
that regularly detects um if- if
anything is being scanned on
that system if- if there’s
responders looking for that
malware so you can clean up and
get off. And you can see- I mean
with all of these different
kinds of functionality
meatpistol gives you an
opportunity to pick and choose
the things that you want for
each implant. Not just across
the entire operation but for
every target system that you
drop it on you can customize
this it’s like a malware buffet
>>Sounds delicious mmm [smacks
lips] [audience laughter] >>So
how does everything communicate?
[laughter] >>Do that again
>>We’ve spoken about how it
internally communicates but how
does it externally communicate
with the C2 network? Well we’ve
implemented uh like client to
client Uni-directional data
transfer which kinda sounds like
half a TCP connection [laughter]
so I mean that’s some impressive
control flow there but uh
[laughter] you know. Alright but
we need this to be persistent as
well because our operators are
connecting to the the master C2
and the implants are connecting
to the master C2 but they’re not
necessarily online at the same
time or the implant might come
and go as it- as it pleases so
we have to persist the data
there so that whenever they’re
both online they can get what
they need. And plus at the end
of the operation you wanna have
a record of all the things that
you have done on that target
system for analysis for next
time, for >>For reporting!
[laughter[ >>For reporting, or
cleaning up. Alright so here’s
our- here’s our persistent
storage and we also wanted to
achieve the greatest level of
hacking excellence ever
displayed [laughter] >>Finally
the dream is reality [chuckles]
>>I know a lot of us haven’t
quite got there yet but uh we-
we strive for it every day to
have hackers that can have two
hackers on one keyboard
[laughter] >>It’s real guys
>>Yeah. So with having many
readers and many writers on
these channels, you could have
two operators on different
laptops in different parts of
the world operating on the same
shell in the same system at the
same time. >>So this is actually
really useful because you used
to be like in your shell, in
your session, or whatever, using
whatever tool you’re using but
you want someone else to be like
hey jump in my shell and like
ride along with me, maybe
they’re a new person, maybe
they’re more senior and you need
their help so now you can have
someone just like in the
framework jump into your session
with you and they can type or
takeover but you can both see it
so we used to accomplish this by
like setting up shared screen
sessions that we’d all jump into
at the same time but >>And
importantly uh even if you sp-
uh spawn multiple shells on the
meatpistol framework it’s not
spinning up not connections it’s
all multiplexing all of that
data across the one connection
so you can control how that
occurs, so if you have C2 and
you want to fragment that data
up it’s fine you don’t have to
like open up new connections
that uh blue team can see. And
to achieve that we needed to
introduce some additional
blocking semantics which uh yeah
uh allow you to to block at the
end until the the whole channel
is closed which gives you an
interface that looks a little
bit like this. The important
thing in meatpistol is to push
all the complexity not at the
not at the module level where
you wanna write as many modules
as you want and you you want
them to be simple and easy to
implement, you wanna push all
that to the service side. So the
module just sees something that
it can read from it can write to
it can attach and detach which
is similar to a normal file open
and close and then a close which
essentially says there are no
more writes ever going to occur
on this channel, so if you read
to the end it will return the
EOF finally instead of blocking.
So that’s how one client to
client communication works, how
does the whole meatpistol
network look? Um well this
pretty much sums it up it’s not
too complication, there’s two
important things that I would
like to point out here, one,
it’s a red team, it’s not a red
person, so we have multiple
operators all connecting to the
master C2. And they’re operating
in the same state, with the same
implants, at the same time. And
then the second part is the
infected hosts you see down on
the right hand side are all your
implants but they’re not
connecting directly back to the
master C2 because this is
obviously trivial to attribute
instead we have a proxy C2 layer
in the middle which you know it
it could be a a simple dumb
transparent proxy which just
forwards packets straight
through to the master C2 or
maybe it’s a more intelligent C2
that will take fragmented
packets and then decode them or
whatever and then pass that data
back. >>This this design, this
model is for Opsec for teams
that have to operate internally,
right? Because you have all
these strange things where like
the real adversaries they don’t
have this problem, this is- this
is a design paradigm for red
teams because you might be
internal to your company right?
You might work somewhere or be
on site. You want it so that no
one ever sees you talking to the
same thing as the infected hosts
talk to. >>Makes sense >>Yeah
makes sense, right? I see a lot
of nods so >>Cool, okay, well,
what does it actually look like?
>>Oh S**t, okay we’re um we’re
gonna switch to mirror mode and
not have any speaker notes or
anything for the rest of the
talk, you guys are okay with
that [chuckles] we’re we’ll be
fine >>This is fun [pops
mouth][sings under breath] >>Um
alright, I’m in, I’m in
[inaudible] >>Is it good?
Alright [inaudible] >>Is that
visible? >>Can you guys see
that? Want it a bit bigger
[inaudible off-mic comment] Oh
rea- I’ll spoil the end
[laughter] Alright oh! Re-
>>Wahhh >>Sorry I’m gonna have
to quit and restart I need a
Taylor quote, there we go >>Okay
[laughter] >>So we’ve just
gotten into meatpistol we’ve
connected to the server if- if
you had connected to this Fuzzy,
what’s- what’s the first thing
that you kind of would wanna do?
>>Well you know we set out to do
years ago was like let’s make a
thing that let’s us build
malware >>Cool >>Without being a
headache so maybe we build some
malware? Let’s make some mother
f**king malware >>Alright >>Oh I
got that right. >>So we’re gonna
create a new blueprint we’re
gonna call it Taytay because I
think that’s been very well
established by now [laughter] A
blueprint is uh a set of
configurations for a specific
implant. You can create multiple
blueprints at the start of an
operation and it’s- you can save
that for later, you don’t have
to keep building the same types
of implants over and over again
by reconfiguring them every
time. So first of all to build
some malware we need to create
some modules, so we need to add
modules to the blueprint. We
only have four at the moment but
they- they implement what we
need so let’s add all of those
to our blueprint. [mouse
clicking] >>Na, na, na, na, na,
na no- you know we co- how we
could do this faster if we could
both type on the same keyboard
[laughter] >>I know right, we
need meatpistol for our
meatpistol. Alright so now we
have a look at the options that
we can configure based on the
modules that we’ve added. Fairly
standard fare here uh you can
set your C2 host in port because
the C2 module that we’ve added
is a GRPC, standard TLS
authentication, etcetera,
etcetera, etcetera. Some of the
other options there you might
not be familiar with. Darken is
a custom golang or post
copulation obfuscator um which
we’ll go through and strip out-
>>It’s a, it’s a regex >>It’s
pretty much >>Sorry, it just
regex’s stuff out of the binary
but with ra- random bots. >>And
then the uh the packer yeah
there’s nothing fancy happening
there either, it’s just all
different options that you can
set. Importantly here because
it’s on Golang at the moment,
you can set the OS in the
architecture and it will compile
for whatever you want just by
changing a string like yeah, I
love Golang >>That’s cool >>Yeah
so we’re gonna set debug to true
so that you can see the output
in the demo. Uh and now we need
to spin up a C2 for this. Now
what we could do is we could say
spin up. Meatproxy is an alias
for an image identifier so and-
think of any instance online,
think of, an image that you’ve
created, you can alias that
instead of having like the i
dash blah blah blah blah blah
Couple of seconds later we have
our C2 ready to rock n’ roll
that’s what you need to do no
logging in and having to two
factor through Amazon and then
find out you’re in the wrong
region or you know whatever um
cloud provider you’re using.
>>Que this IP address getting
like DOS’d off the Internet so
[chuckles] >>But I mean eve-
even that would get a bit
tiresome having to spin up your
own C2 every single time like if
you’re gonna automate things why
not go the whole way? So let’s
set our C2 host and C2 port to
be auto. And now let’s build it.
So in the background >>I was
gonna- I was just going to
comment on the names like you
wrote this thing so it instead
of having like terrible like
UIDs for everything it just
creates these crazy things and
one time it created a a really
useful malware implant for us
and it was called Cottage Wife
it was really [chuckles]
[audience laughs] It was with us
for a long time, cooked us bread
[laughter continues] >>So yeah
as you can see now it’s finished
it’s- it’s got the C2 it’s
automatically spun that up and
configured the malware to use it
um I know some people in the
audience are probably
downloading this right now but
don’t bother uh it’s not that
exciting um alright woop [mouse
clicks] but I mean you still
have to build every single time
you have one piece of malware.
Wouldn’t it be cool if you could
just like build more of them.
And in the meantime we’ll
download the first one that we
just created. Now you can get
this on the system anywhere that
you want. Uh if you’re red
teaming the whole point of
meatpistol is not to compromise
the system it’s to manage post
compromise of the system so >>I
told you it wasn’t a penetration
tool >>Yeah. And you- so you can
see the first build of the
malware has come back here as
well. Justs gives you the link
and the C2 that it spun out for
you. So the- this is good if you
wanna do something like a USB
drop you wanna se- uh set 10
USBs or whatever, copy all that
across and then you’re good to
go you don’t have to like sit
there building all of them.
[mouse clicking] Alright, so
then we run the implant, we get
the connect back. And you can
notice it’s coming from the C2
that was automatically spun up.
So now let’s have a look at the
implants we’ve got. We can see
we’ve got one connection from 9
seconds ago, AptlyBasil. So we
can select that implant and now
we can start to do things with
it uh this is similar to like a
um what- I mean yeah- you can
pretty much do things with it.
So the first thing you might
wanna do is maybe pop a shell
and so now we have a shell now
this is not just- it’s not a
dumb shell you can you can do
pretty much anything you want so
if you want to go into vim you
can go into vim I’m in vim.
>>The test for this guys
interview was write me a shell
that’s actually fully
interactive. In a day. No. It’s
probably important to note that
the things that you can do right
now is dictated by what modules
you chose earlier. Also we have
tab complete I know like any
tool if you don’t have tab
complete it’s like garbage right
like it’s the- the metric that
everything is judged by >>And
we’ve got history. And then you
exit out and you’re back in the
framework again. So at this
point you might even be like oh
yeah that’s great well that’s a
shell like I can literally do
that in every single tool that
I’ve ever had before. Well we
also have this. So remember how
I said that all channels are
persistent? All channels are
persistent and that shell
session, every read and ever
write is recorded, with a
timestamp so that you could
literally ask ecinema your
entire session on that box. If
we wanted to view what happened
in that session sorry there’s a
little bit of a- there we go.
And we have the full session
that we just showed you, but
saved. >>That’s not useful at
all right? ‘Cause no one here
ever forgets to like start their
terminal logging or you know
take a screenshot or anything
like that, right? No >>And you
could also do analysis on that
at the end of the operation if
you wanna do like smart
detection of like certs or or
keys or anything in your ce- uh
shell sessions you can do that
at the server level without the
operator having to- to manually
do that. Uh you might also want
to you know tell the implant to
sleep for a little while maybe
you- yeah if you- if you’re
gonna do this manually it’s not
quite as useful but what you can
do is automate this process so
if you can say I wanna have a
shell herder which will- within
3 hours I can have one implant
in this particular environment
and then the framework could
sleep all the other implants for
you so you’re having minimal
connection back to the C2 until
you need something and then
you’ll trigger it and it’ll wake
up for you. >>I know sleep might
sound boring, but imagine you
wanna go home for the weekend or
the night, right? You’re not
working anymore, it’s off
business hours, you don’t want
any network traffic going to and
from the systems because that’s
really anomalous right? So sleep
sleep’s actually useful. Go on
>>So I mean there’s a whole
bunch of all the commands that
you can do here um but we’ll
we’ll leave that up to to people
to kind of explore. >>That’s
meatpistol basically >>That’s
meatpistol >>yeah, so, uhh
[applause] Oh [applause] Hmmm
Surely our presentation’s
somewhere [chuckles] there it
is. Cool. Okay so one thing you
should know like I mean this was
and still is very much alpha as
fug >>You know >>And I mean
that’s just how it is so but the
thing is we’ve used this on a
number of operations now and
it’s solved a real problem for
us malware implant creation with
like jenky scripts that we were
writing it used to take days
because you had to test it you
had to figure it out and you had
to try and develope something
to- to manage this and it didn’t
scale from one thing to another
you had to constantly redo all
of this stuff. Now it takes
seconds for us. >>And the
important thing as well is in a-
in a red team operation you want
the experience for the red team
operator to be the same every
single time so they can get used
to the workflow but you want
your actual method of operation
to be totally different from the
forensics side. So with a
framework like this you can have
a a- very familiar face for the
red team operators while
changing modules or changing how
they’re configured for example
like different C2 or whatever it
might be to have a very
different experience on the blue
team side when they’re looking
at the malware you’re dropping
and how it’s communicating.
[sighs] Yeah so once you get
locked into a serious malware
collection the tendency is to
try and push it as far as you
can. >>Yeah so about a week ago
maybe less than a week ago um
>>It was like four days >>My
like house got turned in like a
weird scene from Silicon Valley
there was like 3 people sitting
on my couch and like
contributing because John had a
bright idea he’s like maybe we
can get someone to see if they
could like write a new core in a
different language so, why do we
have a Python core? >>Yeah, well
yeah, it’s- it’s- it’s- one
thing to kind of write something
for your own internal use,
getting people to be able to use
that and understand how it works
is an entirely different thing.
So we thought it would be cool
to to throw it out there as a
challenge to some students to
say hey you know write a Python
core for this before our talk in
4 days uh so a big shout out to
Glen and Shawn, are you guys
here right now? Yeah >>It’s
their first Def Con yay! >>It’s
their first Def Con [applause]
>>Gettin’ shout outs on their
first Def Con >>And in four days
time uh after being bribed with
uh an a lunch in West Oakland
>>Fancy! >>And uh yeah they they
managed to get a Python core up
and running and working with a-
with a shell module and
everything so kudos. >>Cool. So.
What’s the best way to increase
this? Right? Um Obviously like
the more you get the more
capability we get to do
different things, to simulate
different stuff uh the idea
would be to share it or not
which uh sharing it was our
intent um I messed up a little
bit we >>WE >>messed up a little
bit >>we messed up a little bit
>>Uh I didn’t realize there was
a um an approval process in
order to open source things and
I just didn’t do that like I was
told about it like today and um
so [sighs] uh we- we can’t. But
um we’ll- we’ll go- get back
>>We’ll come back to that
>>We’ll probably. Don’t worry.
Um I’m gonna do whatever I have
to do to to make this thing
reality >>We, we >>We will >>We
will [laughter] >>So you’re
probably wondering about the
name. So of course any good tool
has like a you know a
backronymed name um and it needs
to it needs to be self
referential I think that’s what
recursion is right? Is that
recursion? >>Yeah, yeah >>What
is tranal? >>So we were thinking
meatpistol maybe like we’re
throwing this around some idea
meatpistol enthralls angry
tyrants proposing intimate
sexy-times teasing oligarch
llamas but then we also thought
maybe marginally erect alpacas
tactically pursuing
international slave trading
oligarch llamas would be a good
one too [laughter] but but then
we though you know maybe it’s
just a modular embedded
adversary tooling platform
>>Yeah no- nobody cares >>Yeah
[laughter] the point is we
called it meatpistol because we
can and also I mean like maybe
you got you picked up on that
[laughter][applause] It’s- it’s
an homage to an awesome tool,
right? And we had to call our
thing something. So it’s natural
for people to wanna compare this
tool with other tools because
like we understand like there is
a lot of really cool stuff in
the ecosystem of offensive
tooling that you can use and
we’ve- we get that question a
lot I mean we’ve been
socializing this with other red
teams in the industry to see
like what is it- what should we
work on this, should we develop
it and most of the first few
questions are like comparison
type questions and so we’ll just
address a few of those before we
have to answer it a million
times offline. People as us
how’s it different from
metasploit, right? I um I don’t
want to start holy war again um
so if you disagree with me right
now just sit down be humble for
a moment don’t throw anything
and uh we can talk about it
later but I think metasploit is
a tool that is inherently
fundamentally designed to ta- to
be an exploit database where you
can pair an exploit with a
payload and then having whatever
auxiliary models you want right?
To weaponize things, to
penetrate, to-to-to actually be
a pentesting tool. It’s
definitely grown into much more
than that but we have no
intention of being an exploit
database. People also ask is
this the same as Cobalt Strike?
And I mean no it’s obviously a
different tool, but Cobalt
Strike I see as something that
really helps you simulate
adversarial scenarios, right?
You can do spear phishing, you
can do pivots, you can visualize
the network, it’s really really
cool but it’s visualization, its
automation, ours is just give me
malware. ‘ Also they’re like did
you hear about Empire and I was
like yeah and then I was like
checking it out and I like as
I’m looking through the models
in Empire and I see that like
one of the post exploitation
modules is like giving me credit
I’m like what the s**t so I was
like super flattered and
flabbergasted by that but it’s a
really it’s a really cool tool
um it’s a post exploitation
agent believe that’s what it
says on the Github page. Ours is
make me malware, manage C2,
manage infrastructure. And then
um actually the Def Con CFP
panel asked us this they’re like
they just demped fuzzbunch does
that make your tool irrelevant?
And I was like s**t does it make
our tool irrelevant? And so I
went and and like looked up the
fuzzbunch stuff and I was like
pfft this is all Windows stuff
and they’re like it’s a really
cool bag of tricks but it is in
no way something that’s gonna
help our team run operations.
Perfect. So meatpistol not an
exploit database, not click to
win automation, it’s not post
exploitation agent, it’s not a
bag of cool tricks, it’s it’s
obviously a meat cannon that
shoots out malware implants. No.
Meatpistol is a framework for
red teams to create better
implants over time to manage
them in a more professional and
less ad hoc crazy way it’s an
efficiency tool cause we want to
be the best red team we can be
and we think efficiency is the
way to do it. It’s also
multi-user implant management,
an interaction portal, a single
place to do everything make your
stuff and interact with it. It’s
also an offensive infrastructure
automation tool I think that’s
one of the ways it started.
>>It’s trying to strike that
nice balance between having that
commodity malware and that
custom malware cause nobody has
time for custom malware every
time >>So the point is
meatpistol is something that has
saved us a lot of times and and
pain. And now it could be yours
in the near future but while
while we ca n’t open source it
today uh we do have some
t-shirts that are pretty cool
>>Yeah >>So there’s a bit of a
challenge here. If you can
figure it out, you can have
meatpistol t-shirt. So thank you
that’s, that’s our talk. >>Woo!
[applause]