>>Hey how's everybody doin'? So
just a quick survey, uh, who
here likes hacking? Who thinks
hacking's interesting? Yeah. Few
people? Alright. How bout who
thinks guns are kinda
interesting? H**l yeah. A
handful. [cheering] Alright. How
about hacking guns? Any uh any
interest in that [cheering]? Can
I hack some guns. Good. Cause
that's what we're gonna talk
about today. Uh, we're gonna
talk about popping a smart gun.
So, we're going to... what is-
what is a smart gun? Um so a
smart gun would be a gun that
can be fired only by an
authorized user. Uh I think that
a lot of the um mentality around
gun-uh smart guns has been
shaped by Hollywood in
particular the movie Skyfall.
This is a Bond film a couple
years ago. Uh in the film Q
gives Bond a modified Walther
and it's somehow uh associated
with Bond's grip uh some sort of
biometrics and in the movie uh
Bond can shoot the weapon but
when the assailant gets the
weapon and tries to shoot Bond,
doesn't work. And then the
assailant gets like killed by a
Komodo dragon or something. But
uh anyhow uh we're a little ways
away from that for now but we do
have several smart gun uh models
in development in the- that are
biometric based so this would be
things like fingerprints or palm
prints. We also see ones that
use things like magnetic rings
and then things like RFID and
RFID wristbands. That sort of
thing. Um now there's a lot of
controversy around smart guns
and this is largely due to a New
Jersey law that was passed in
the early otts and this law said
that after three years - three
years after the first smart gun
becomes available at retail,
only smart guns could be sold in
New Jersey and so gun people
were a little upset about this
thinking that they would no
longer be able to buy non smart
firearms and as a result they uh
started to kind of protest when
gun stores dis-discussed even
carrying smart guns um up to the
point people were getting death
threats and that sort of thing.
Now I'm-I'm not quite. I'm not
really that extreme. I think
that if you want a smart gun,
you should be able to have a
smart gun. Um I like guns. I
like shooting guns rifles,
pistols, shotguns, I think if
you've never shot clays with a
shotgun you-you should give it a
try. It's fun. Um I do think
that if you are going to buy a
smart gun you should be able to
get what you're paying for.
Should be- It should match
what's on the label. And also
yeah if-if you should be able to
buy a smart gun but not limited
to only smart guns. Alright so
if you do care to buy a smart
gun, the only one you can buy in
the states right now is the
Armatix iP1 and this is a uh
fully uh from the ground up
smart gun design it's not like a
modification of some other
model. And it's made by a German
company called Armatix. It's a
twenty-two caliber, uh semi
automatic, straight blowback
action, hammer-hammer fired um,
holds ten rounds, um takes two
AAA batteries. So you know.
Have-have batteries for your
gun. Don't wanna have that run
out. [laughter] Um it has two
components. The pistol and the
watch and the way that it
authenticates its users to see
if they're authorized is by
communicating with the watch.
So, give you kind of an idea of
how that's supposed to work. Uh
what you would do, the user
would put the watch on the wrist
and then enter a-a pin on the
watch and then select a period
of time between about one and
eight hours and during that
period of time the watch will
allow the gun to be fired. And
so during that period of time
you might draw the weapon and go
shoot something and you would
squeeze the grip. You'd squeeze
the back strap on the pistol.
And when that happens the pistol
will signal the watch and the
watch will check to see if it's
authorized and if it is it will
send a token to the pistol. The
pistol will say "yep I'm here"
and the pistol will uh allow
itself to be fired with
that-that token from the watch.
That only works if it's within
about a foot so it needs to be
within about twenty-five
centimeters or a foot um to work
like-like that. So um let's see
how this works. With the uh the
caveat that this is not my
computer so we'll see-we'll see,
doo doo doo. So the first thing.
I'm gonna show two videos. The
first one is if you don't have a
watch on and oop hold on a
second. [clicking] Oop oop Hold
on. Hold on. There we go. In
case you were unaware they were
having AV difficulties in this
room all day so um. Alright so
here's what happens if you try
to fire the wea-Armatix iP1
without a watch on. Uh, What
you'll see is that when you pull
the trigger the hammer will fall
and the gun will just go click.
Nothing will happen. Alright. So
that's without the watch. Now
the normal operation with a
watch is you pull the trigger
and it goes- [gunfire] it goes
bang. Alright. So pretty
standard. That's uh-that's how
it's supposed to work. Hmm hmm
hmm. Alright so last year I
spoke at Defcon about side
channel attacks on high security
in the electronic safe locks and
so y'know that happened and it
went well and I cracked some
safe locks and that was great
and so then I was looking for
what to do next. And I-I kind of
thought back to this thread.
This was a thread on a uh a very
pro gun forum um about a review
of the Armatix rP1 back when it
was released around 2015 and
the-the people on there were
kind of uh- y'know maybe mocking
it like one person in particular
this guy named Sky Hawk said
"yeah could you imagine what the
guys at Defcon could do to the
uh iP1." So I thought well uh
I'm a guy at Defcon I guess. And
so y'know. Le-let's see what
happens here so um I got one and
I thought "oh y'know um I wonder
how hard it will be to hack
it-it'll be a really good
challenge" and then I-I hacked
it three ways. So, um we are
going to show th-all three of
these today. So the three hacks
to defeat the proximity
restrictions so instead of being
within a foot you're able to uh
extend that range significantly.
Secondly to be able to prevent
the weapon from being fired even
when it is otherwise authorized.
And third to fire the weapon
without authorization. So the
first of these, the proximity
restriction is uh normally
twenty-five centimeters. Uh
again about a foot and to
understand what this is you have
to look at how the weapon, how
the pistol communicates with the
watch. And it does this on two
different bands. One is in the
nine hundred megahertz ISM band
and then the other is down in
the five point three five
kilohertz using inductively
coupled communications. You have
two coils essentially. One is in
the pistol and one is in the
watch and uh when the pistol
wants to signal the watch it
will generate a signal, a
carrier at five point three five
kilohertz. That will be coupled
through from it's coil to the
watch's coil and that looks like
this. If you hook up a coil,
another coil to an oscilloscope
and place it near the pistol
while it's attempting to signal
the watch, you'll see something
like this. It's a five point
three five kilohertz burst for
about one and a half
milliseconds. Uh carries no
information on its own. It's
just a pure carrier. And so all
this does is signal the watch
that it wants to communicate on
the higher nine hundred
megahertz band. Now critically
this is how it knows that it's
close to the watch because of
physics the coupling only
happens within about a foot um
it falls off much quicker. Its
not-its not a propagating wave
or anything. So I thought well
y'know that sounds like we could
just make a classic relay
attack. Mmm so I whipped that up
um. This is a block diagram of
the device I made for that. So
to kind of walk you through it.
On the one-there are two half
parts to this device, or two
devices rather. One goes near
the pistol and the other goes
near the watch. On the pistol
side you have a tuned coil,
tuned to five point three five
kilohertz and the coil there
listens for the signal from the
pistol. When the pistol has its
backstroke squeezed it'll
generate a five point three five
kilohertz tone which will be
coupled into the coil which will
go into a band fast filter or
amplifier, go to the micro
controller and eventually be
make its way into our nRF24
which is a uh a nice little two
point four gigahertz
transceiver. Really easy to use,
cheap, all that. That signal,
that trigger is in uh
transmitter of a two point four
gigahertz backhaul to another
two point four gigahertz device
another nRF24 which goes to
another microcontroller and-and
this time goes to a coil driver
so essentially it's going to
transmit at five point three
five kilohertz. Into another
tuned coil. Tuned LC circuit. LC
tank. And from there. That
couples into the coil in the
watch. The watch receives that
signal. Thinks "hey I'm talking
right to the pistol" and
generates the token meant for
the pistol to authorize it for
firing and um that gets
transmitted back in the nine
hundred megahertz band. Now the
nine hundred megahertz band is a
true propagating-um has a true
propagating wave so it gets uh
much further than the five point
three five kilohertz would so it
can go directly from the watch
to the pistol um at least about
three meters. So you've extended
the range from about twenty-five
centimeters to about three
meters. Alright so, um the
hardware itself, pretty simple.
It kind of uh s-I built the red
boards on there um, whipped them
up in an afternoon. Uh not-not
too hard. The uh the way I
designed it is to have the
hardware be reusable for both
the pistol side and the watch
side and just populate different
components to uh to and act of
the different functionality. Um
those nRF24 little receiver
boards. Those are-are great and
they're super cheap. They're
like five bucks a piece off of
Amazon. So if you're looking for
something like that th-that's
great. Um here's a little pic.
Sixteen F, Eighteen three
twenty-four microcontroller.
Y'know. It's like less than a
dollar. Super capable. Love that
too. And uh circuit boards also.
Man circuit boards are cheap
these days. Like you can get
those from China for nothing
like uh I des-I ripped up the
design, some of the Gerber and a
week later they're in my hands
and it's super cheap. So twenty
bucks for the relay, for the
custom hardware and load from
firmware for it and all that.
Alright so, um let's take a look
then at what the relay attack
looks like. Doo doo doo. Yeah.
Okay so the-a little bit of
context here. Um what I'm doing
right now is I'm picking up uh
the pistol and I don't have the
watch on. You'll notice the
watch is down at the bottom on
the table. As you can see-yeah
on the table. And uh it's well
out of range-normal range. It's
about three feet away when I go
to shoot it and as a result when
I pull the trigger it's just
gonna go click so you'll see
that happen. [click] Alright so
just click. Now what I'm doing
is I'm taking the one half of
the relay the part that goes
near the pistol and y'know hold
it up to the pistol and you'll
see right next to the watch on
the table there already is the
other half of the relay and
that's going to communicate
that-that trigger signal to the
watch then so when we hold it up
to the pistol and pull the
trigger this time [gunfire] it
goes bang. So there we go.
Defeated the uh range uh
restriction with uh with the
relay attack. Classic. Um, yeah.
So let's see here. [applause]
Thanks. Now part of the reason
why this works is because it has
a-a very lax timing requirements
um with the- just this one built
it actually tolerates at least
six hundred and thirty
microseconds of delay and um
that's kind of surprising. And I
was expecting a much more- a
much tighter uh timing
requirement. But like here are
the still or uh screenshot. You
can see the blue trace which is
when the pistol is transmitting
its y'know normal five point
three five kilohertz tone. And
then you have the uh the relay
generated tone down below and
that is separated by about six
hundred and thirty microseconds
and it seems to handle that no
problem. So one of the things
they could do to- to kind of
improve on this is really
enforce tighter timing
requirements um you might not
the-the distances involved here
like a foot is so short that
you're talking about like sub
nanosecond times for the speed
of light but you could at least
tighten things up for in terms
of tolerance um if we -if it-say
if it had tolerated uh a
microsecond of delay that would
have been much harder to-to
mount and attack on so uh it
would be even better approach
would be to not rely on nRF at
all if you needed proximity - if
you needed defense proximity you
might want to use something that
has physical contact. It
actually ends up being a tricky
problem actually applicable to a
lot of industries. You'll find
this a lot with cars for example
and you'll see other talks
including here at Defcon this
year where they talk about relay
attack and in other context. So
classic relay attacks it's kind
of a hard problem to defend
against but y'know it still
requires that you have access to
the watch and that could be kind
of tricky and you have to kind
of like have contrive scenarios
where that would be relevant.
But I got to y'know build some
hardware and write some firmware
so I was like y'know Yeah.
Pretty happy about that. Um so
the next attack is denial of
service. So we've- this is when
you want to fire the gun and you
are authorized to fire the gun
but you can't fire the gun uh
because of some external
influence. So you can kind of
imagine a couple different
scenarios here where this might
happen. Perhaps an adversary
wants to prevent you from firing
your gun or perhaps there's
somebody who say doesn't want
any guns fired within a-an area.
Or perhaps there's not
intentional at all. Maybe it's
just somebody's grandmother
blabbing on the cordless phone
and nobody knows why she still
has a landline but y'know it's
there. Or maybe a baby monitor.
There's actually a lot of
devices that operate on this
nine hundred megahertz ISM band
um and tho-a lot of them have uh
modulation schemes that will
allow, potentially interfere
with what the iP1 uses and so to
uh-to test against this what
they should be doing during
development or prior to
releasing this product is they
should be doing what's called
EMC test. This is
electromagnetic compatibility
and this tests for two things.
Uh especially for part fifteen
devices like this. One, you want
to make sure that this device
doesn't interfere with another
device. And two you want to make
sure that other devices don't
interfere with your device to
-to the extent possible anyway.
And so uh one of the great
things about this testing and
the FCC certification is that
you can go look up all this
information online. It's all-
it's all public record. And so
on all these devices that have
uh FCC IDs you can go to the web
and enter in that FCC ID and
pull up all sorts of useful
information about the bands that
the devices operate on and
things like internal photos
sometimes schematics and uh
fortunately for this one it was-
they had a just a wealth of data
in the FCCs certification
database. Including, uh, some
great photos and from the um the
inside the pistol and the watch
which is useful because it's
otherwise uh podded in epoxy and
I would have had to kind of
destroy the- the gun to extract
it. That showed the transceiver
that they use. They use a
transceiver from a company
called Marada now uh part of our
FM. And it's the TR1000 and so
this transceiver operates at
nine hundred and sixteen point
five megahertz. Uh, it's a
fully, uh kind of integrated
transceiver but um and it-its
not too advanced for its on off
keying and amplitude modulage
and amplitude shift keying. Um,
when you want to transmit data
you would feed it a-a bit
stream. Kind of a base band
signal and when you're trying to
have received data from it you
receive essentially a-a-a simple
bit stream. Um but it isn't like
decoding it down into it
like-like the packet layer or
anything like that. So, uh to
kind of understand this- what it
gives you back on the receiver
side which is then to understand
why we can attack it. Let's
learn a little bit about why the
IP1 encodes data and um this is
about- this is Manchester
coding. Manchester coding is all
about the edges. About the
transitions like from low to
high. That would be a one. And
from high to low would be a
zero. Has some great aspects.
One is that it is- it has a zero
DC value so that simplifies a
lot of design. Um, one thing
though is that you have to have
a good slicer level to decide
what is high and what is low and
if you have the slicer level set
incorrectly you might miss a
transition and then you'd lose a
bit and then of course your
data's corrupted. So here's kind
of an example of that. In the
top we have a slicer level
that's set sufficiently even
though our second little rise
there is a bit of a runt pulse.
It still gets high enough above
the slicer level that we can see
that edge and decode the bit
stream into one zero one one. In
contrast on the bottom, the
slicer level is too high and we
miss that- that transition on
that runt pulse. It goes high
but not high enough and we-we
totally miss that bit. So, we're
not able to decode that bit
stream successfully in that
case. So, with that background
in mind here is what a- an
actual authentication tooken
from the watch to the pistol
looks like. Its nineteen bytes
long and you can see each of the
individual bytes grouped in
these little bursts-these little
jagged bursts and most of this
data is a combination of
constant and static data. About
half of it is constant. Half of
it is dynamic. The dynamic data
contains a uh a time dependent
token and that will allow the-
the weapon to be fired. They
have to have synchronized
clocks. And also importantly it
has a checksum. And-and there's
a checksum not a CRC and it
notably is not a error
correcting code. All it can do
is detect errors it can't
correct them. And if it detects
an error it will retry about
four hundred milliseconds later.
Or rather the pistol doesn't act
the watch, the watch will retry
four hundred milliseconds later.
Um, but if you have both of
those are corrupted you-you're
kind of up a creek. So, I looked
at that for a while and uh- I
came up with a- what signal it
would be most susceptible to and
this is a uh pulse data and it
is- this is a view of it on a
spectrum analyzer set to a zero
hertz span. This is kind of a
way to make a spectrum analyzer
behave in the time domain
instead of how it normally
operates which is in the
frequency domain. It can be
pretty useful and so the uh
the-the signal the base pan
signal I found to be useful
wa-has a thirty-three
microsecond period of carrier
followed by a three hundred
microsecond period of no
carrier. And so the full period
then would be three hundred and
thirty-three microseconds. And
if you're saying "well y'know
where did those numbers come
from it seems oddly specific."
The answer is the thirty three
microseconds is about one bit
width in the uh in the-the token
being sent from the watch to the
pistol and three hundred and
thirty three microseconds is a
little bit shorter than one byte
width. And so- or one byte
period. So if you overlay those
two you can see that
the-they're-the very steady
repeating pattern is the-the
test signal and the kinda
smaller pattern is the-the token
from the watch and if you
overlay those you can see that
the-the test signal happens to
hit at least once in every byte,
um, and so that's important
because of the different ways
that the test signal can
interfere with the signal from
the watch. The-the the desire
signal. Uh a couple different
scenarios. So we have three
different scenarios and uh
regarding relative signal
strengths. So uh first scenario.
Interference is much greater
than the signal. Much-much uh
stronger. What will happen in
this case is the TR1000 will set
the slicer level to a point six
DB down from the peak of a
recent signal. It sets it
automatically um and one of the
things that even the TR1000 data
sheet notes is that it will do
that incorrectly in the face of
pulse interference. So we're
making some pulse interference
in setting that slicer level
incorrectly. Uh and what will
happen then is we have our
slicer level way too high and
it's well above all of the
desired signal and so we totally
miss all the transitions and the
desired signal so we totally
miss all of the bits in that
signal and so we don't get the
token. The second scenario is
when the interference is roughly
the same as your desired signal.
In that case the interference
would fill the gaps in the
signal because again we have
this pulse happening about once
per byte and what will happen
then is you're filling in gaps
so you are causing again missed
transitions. You're still seeing
some of the transitions because
the slicer level is set
correctly this time but whereas
since Manchester encoding relies
on those transitions, you're
filling in the gaps, it sees no
transitions, and so you lose
those bits again. As before you
lose even one bit you lose the
entire byte. You lose the byte,
you lose the packet and the
token is no good and the gun
does not fire. So, third
scenario is when the
interference is somewhat less
than the signal. When one of the
strange aspect of the-of the
byte stream that you could see
in the uh some of the period
slides is there were kind of
gaps between each of the bytes
it's like bursts and it kinda
looked uh, oddly separated. And
what will happen if this
interfering signal is low and
happens in between those bytes
is you'll interfere with the
synchronization of the bytes and
so the TR1000 will be tricked
into setting the slicer level a
little bit too low and think
that the byte is starting and
you'll get this uh corruption
again in the bits because your
timing and synchronization is
off. As before you lose the
bits, you lose the bytes and you
lose the token. So, so I built,
had experimented with all of
this and with using some-some
lab equipment. Using a signal
generator and an arbitrary
waveform generator to hone in on
what was kind of the right
waveform. And from that built a
test transmitter. It's very
simple. I didn't bother with a
circuit board this time. Just
built it on some strip board. So
what I used here was actually
the same module that they use in
the pistol and the watch. It's a
Murata TR1000 again and driving
that with another PIC16F for the
base fan signal so that drives
the transmitter and the
transmitter drives the antenna
and we get a portable little
test transmitter to kind of
simulate what would happen if
you had uh some other adversary
or just an unintentional
interference again like a baby
monitor or a cordless phone
potentially. So, that works
actually really well. Up to at
least-up to from at least three
meters onto about ten meters. At
three meters rock solid. And
this is just at uh par fifteen
sort of output levels. Its works
kind of reliably up til about
ten meters. It depends on the
relative orientation of the-the
watch and the pistol and the
transmitter and so forth. But
the bottom line at three meters
of rock solid um interference.
So this is, it's kind of
surprising that it worked. Cause
it could have caught this sort
of thing during, again, y'know
EMC testing when they were
testing for uh susceptibility to
external devices. External
fields and so forth. So let's
look at the denial of service
attack. So, okay so what's gonna
happen here. I'm gonna fire it
normally. [gunshot] Alright. So
the gun fires normally. And now
what I'm gonna do is I'm going
to go over and take off the
transmitter and turn it on. So
this is the same transmitter
that I was just showing. And I'm
gonna try firing it again.
[click] [click] [click] and it
doesn't fire. So, yeah
[applause]. So, um, so that,
y'know that was kind of
interesting. Y'know. What could
they have done to defend against
that? Well one thing would have
been to use more transmitter
power from the EMC report about
the pistol and my own direct
measurements found that they
were transmitting at about minus
twenty BBM which is about in
round numbers about twenty BB
below the PAR 15 limit. So
holding all else equal they
could have used a lot more power
but they chose not to for some
reason. Um, the- an easy
software fix. Well maybe not
easy, but a possible software
fix would be to use error
correcting codes. So right now
you have a single bit error and
you lose the entire token. You
lose the-the whole off. So if
you had error correcting codes
you might be able to tolerate
more bit errors and as a result
be able to get the token that uh
authorizes firing through
without uh without failing. Then
of course uh using more robust
modulation might be another
approach. Instead of on-off
keying and amplitude modulation
maybe consider something like
spread spectrum. Something that
is inherently more immune to-to
uh to interference. Plus a
spread spectrum you can use more
power than megahert- nine
hundred megahertz span. Alright
So, I so I-I had to thought
about the third attack. So this
would be how to make the gun
fire without authorization. And
so I was considering all sort of
interesting angles on it and I
was thinking like oh how can I
decode the tokens from the
watch. And how can I maybe like
a replay attack or maybe you can
just sort of generate my own
tokens or maybe there's some
sort of side channel attack. Or
something really sexy. I mean I
was going for something really
technical and sexy and I was
really-really gung ho about that
and eh making a little bit of
progress but not-not as much as
I was hoping for. So I took a
step back and I pulled up um
some patents that our Armatix
had filed and it turns out that
they had done a pretty good job
of explaining how the gun works
in their patents. And you know
kudos to them for filing a
patent that they actually use
but um in any case it provided
some insight into how the
mechanism would be weak and how
it could be compromised so I'm
just gonna go into how-how the
gun works internally to give me
an idea of where we were gonna
be going with this. So
internally if you imagine that
you're looking down the slide of
the gun. So this is the top part
of the gun that slides back and
forth. It's the part that has
the barrel on it so imagine
you're kind of looking in line
with the barrel from behind the
hammer. So from the back of the
gun. You're kind of looking
longitudinally down that and
you're looking at the firing
pin. Now, ordinarily the firing
pin is blocked. It has some-you
can imagine having some lugs in
the side and those not matching
up with sort of a-a uh a holes
in the s- in the slide. So you
might have this mis fashioned uh
the lugs to the wards and if you
were to strike the firing pin
with the hammer it wouldn't move
and the gun wouldn't fire so
that's kind of what you want
ordinarily when you're not
pulling the trigger for example.
What happens is when you
partially pull the trigger you
move that uh mechanism a little
bit particularly you rotate the
firing pin slightly and those
wards or those lugs become
closer to lining up with the
wards. Closer to uh matching and
allowing it to slide but not
quite far enough. So you pull
the trigger and pull the trigger
halfway and you would get a
little bit of movement on the-
the firing pin but not enough to
fully unlock the device. And
that's kind of just the-the
scenario you have if you're if
you're not authorized to fire.
Like lets say you pull the
trigger the full way. Nothing
happens because its you have
that mismatch. However if you do
have - if you are authorized to
fire then an electromagnet is
turned on by the microcontroller
in the pistol and that
electromagnet will pull on
another piece that's connected
to the firing pin. This is a
little bit of a ferrous metal
which means it can be attracted
by a magnet. And when the
electromagnet pulls on that
ferrous material it will align
the lugs with the wards in
the-in the slide and at that
point then the firing pin can
slide longitudinally so when the
hammer strikes the firing pin
the firing pin will move, strike
the primer in the cartridge and
the gun will fire. So um this is
actually a-a shot of the patent
which was great. See patent
y'know eighty-nine, sixty-six,
eight o three. Good tip if
you're looking for patents that
companies have filed. They don't
always file them in a way that
there as easily searchable so
you what you wanna look for I
found is to search in the
company name and then pull the
patents they have filed in their
name and then pull up other
patents that are associated with
the inventors on those patents
and sometimes you can get a much
uh greater breadth of
information than you otherwise
would, even if it doesn't
mention the company by name
those are their patents. In real
life this is what it looks like.
This is a view into the gun from
the top. This is, imagine you've
taken the slide off of the
pistol and you're looking from
the top down into the gun. So
this is uh you have the barrel
on the left and you have the
hammer on the right and kind of
in between them where the arrow
is pointing you have this little
circle and in that circle there
is an electromagnet. It's the
electromagnet from the diagram.
Now that lines up with the
components in the slide. So this
is the slide and you have two
views of it here. The profile
view and the bottom view. Or-or
from the bottom up. You can see
there is uh a little piece that
the cam would press on when you
pull the trigger partway. When
you pull that trigger partway it
will lift up on a linkage and
move that piece of ferrous
material down a little bit
further into range of the
electromagnet. And uh then
y'know operate as before. If the
electromagnet is on it will be
pulled-be pulled further. Unlock
the firing pin. And if not it
will just uh not fire. So one
thing you can see easily on this
paired view of the profile view
and the bottom view of the slide
is where the ferrous material is
relative to kind of markings on
the side of the slide. You can
see it's kind of uh near this
detent on the right side. So
keep that in mid for a little
bit later. Um, y'know I thought
I thought gosh an electromagnet
I-I could just put a big a**
magnet next to it right and
like, uh they make those. And
y'know pull the same way and so
I went on Amazon and I'm like
y'know "Big A** Magnet" and its
like this huge hockey puck sized
nudenium magnet. Uh so I was
like y'know y'know overnight
that or uh two day it and um I
got it and I-I uh I slapped that
on the side of the-the gun and
it did not work at all. I mean
it was dead. That was way too
much magnet. Like it was. That
was just. [laughter] And I could
kind of just imagine kind of a
sucking sound. Kind of a [makes
sucking sound] of all the
components in the- in the pistol
being kind of pulled to that
side. It was uh, yeah nothing
that you couldn't pull the
trigger at all. [laughter] You
couldn't like, it was just like
way too much magnet. Um so never
thought I'd say that, yeah. Too
much magnet. Yeah. Uh so I- I
went back to Amazon and found
some smaller magnets. These are
some again nudenium magnets
about an inch and a quarter by
about a quarter inch and you
need about three of 'em. They
come in four packs but you need
about three of them so you need
about fifteen dollars worth of
magnets. And I got those
together and I picked up some-
some scrap wood dowel and uh
stainless steel screw. Stainless
steel so it wouldn't uh be
attracted by the magnet
depending on the alloy. And this
is the magnet tool. This is the
fifteen dollar tool to defeat
the fifteen hundred dollar smart
gun. Um you can see a piece of
wood with a screw in it and some
magnets stuck on the end. Uh
it's kind of good that I needed
exactly three magnets because
there's no way I'm ever getting
those apart again. Like they
are-they are really stuck
together. So the way you use
this tool. Pretty simple. You
just align the magnet right
there. Remember from the earlier
slide you have the ferrous
material that was aligned
basically where that arrow is
and so again what you're doing
you're just pulling from the-the
outside standing in for the
electromagnet and uh that is
most easily done actually at a
slight angle. I found that if
you-you had kind of uh the
magnet just right on the edge it
would uh kind of pull too hard
but in a little bit of an angle
works a lot better. Let's see,
so you slide the magnets up
there. Oh one other thing to
notice about this. You'll see
this in the video too. There's a
red light kind of near my-my um
uh wrist sort of on this picture
near the back of the gun. When
the gun is authorized for firing
it'd be green but in this photo
and ththe video that we're gonna
see in a moment it will always
be red. It's always be
unauthorized to fire. Not
authorized to fire. Alright, so
let's look at the demo of the
magnet attack. Firing without
authorization. [click] Okay
again with a little bit of
context. I'm gonna do- pull the
trigger a few times to show that
the gun won't fire ordinarily.
So right now I don't have kind
of the watch nearby or anything
like that. No relay attack.
Nothing like that in place and
so you'll know it. If you-It's
kind of hard to see the red
light is on on the back
indicating it's not authorized
to fire. So pulling the trigger
a couple times. [click] [click]
Not working. So then we'll take
the magnets. Put them next to
the gun on the right spot.
[gunfire] And it fires.
[applause] Thanks. So then
y'know a couple other instances
of this. I fired it again uh or
I clicked it again showing it
wouldn't work [click] put the
magnets up and [gunfire] fires
again. And you know for- how
bout a, how bout a first person
view? Alright so we're gonna go
and- and take that and [click]
oop nope doesn't fire. Oh no. Oh
no. [click] Actually this time
it didn't work the first time
but that's okay we'll just put
the magnets back on again and oh
there we go [gunfire]. No
problem. No problem. So you take
the magnets off. Put em on.
[gunfire] No problem. Pretty
easy. I actually showed, uh.
[applause] I-I so I showed uh a
couple people how to do this and
they they caught on pretty fast.
Um in fact for the wired video
piece the-the videographer I had
him I had him shoot it too to
show him I wasn't full of s**t
or something so um the, yeah so
y'know it. I know what you're
thinking. Y'know. F**king
magnets how do they work? Um
it's a miracle. It's a miracle,
yeah. I-I honestly didn't know
it. I had no idea what anyone
was talking about and everyone
kept being like "F**king
magnets." And then I'm like
"what are you talking about." I
had to Google that one I'm
sorry. I'm getting old. Um the
magnet defense however. How do
you defend against this sort of
thing? So basically uh don't do
this. Don't rely on solenoids.
Don't rely on DC magnetic fields
and we see this thing, this sort
of problem repeated again and
again. Like there was this
classic case a couple years ago
about Sentry safes. So this
particular model of Sentry Fire
Safe was susceptible to a magnet
attack uh you basically would
just put a magnet a magnet up on
the- the door and it would move
a solenoid inside the safe and
the safe would open so, um,
pretty pathetic and the-they
kind of made the same mistake
here and so I would guess they
aren't the last to make that
mistake either. But basically
don't use anything that relies
on DC magnetic fields. Instead
consider something like a motor
drive. So in better safe locks
like the ones I talked about
last year. You'll find a motor
and it'll move like a bolt on an
acting screw for example. And
this is much harder to-to
in-induce from outside of the
safe or outside of the gun or
externally anyway. And um that-
that sort of uh that's one
approach. Another option would
be to design a system that would
detect an attack. So that would
have some sort of relocker. So
like it would say oop there's
some sort of external magnetic
field so as a result we're going
to activate a secondary lock and
there are a variety of clever
implementations for this sort of
thing but um again the the idea
is that any sort of external
magnetic field would in-induce
some sort of secondary relocking
ideally without any sort of
electronic interventions so that
it would still work with the
power off. So uh y'know y'know a
few- a few thoughts finally um.
A-again I'm not against smart
guns. I think that if you want a
smart gun you should be able to
have a smart gun but you should
get what's on the label. You
should have one that actually
provides meaningful extra
security. And I think this fell
short. I think the the iP1 um
fell short and uh it was kind of
a dis-kind of a little bit of a
disappointment. I was expecting
a greater challenge. Actually
when the magnet thing happened I
was really hoping for a y'know a
Defcon talk. I was like "oh no
magnets." Like that's not gonna
fly. Like that's too simple. So
I'm like "Oh no magnets" but
then uh, it turned out to be
interesting anyways I thought.
Um there was also kind of an
ethical dilemma and I went back
and forth with the media
actually about this because they
were worried about teaching kids
how to do something dangerous.
In this case how to fire maybe
their parents gun. And y'know
it's always kind of tricky and
you- you see this a lot with
with hacking and so forth in
many contexts. Is it better to
kind of sit on the information
or is it better to share it with
the world. And I took the
opinion that yeah, you might be
sharing this information,
teaching a kid how to fire their
parent's gun but on the other
hand you're telling their
parents that this exists. You're
getting the word out that these
things exist and that we can fix
them and then we can make future
products better. Y'know.
I-i-it's probably. Y'know I was
talking to somebody else about
this and he pointed out that
it's good that this sort of
problem was found now before
anybody's died because of it
than in the future when somebody
might discover it because of
some unfortunate accident with a
kid or... So anyhow if you have
any questions I'll be out in the
hallway and uh thanks for your
attention and have a good
evening. [applause]