>>Hopefully you guys, uh, will
see this as, uh, as a nice um
talk, for setting the stage. Uh,
the original idea was to have it
as a very indepth, very long too
panel talk. I think that, that,
uh, that was very, uh,
optimistic. Uhm, so this will be
hopefully a cool talk in kind of
the history and the, uh, the,
the field of programming
analysis how we got where we got
and where we came from. Uhm,
let’s see, we're almost there.
Is it nine? >>Yes, sir. >>Do we
have a countdown? [laughter] It
is set? Alright! The stage is
mine! Psych, I'm not talking
about programming analysis.
We're gonna look at cats, all
day! Uhm, but in all
seriousness, uh, when I saw that
it was the 25th anniversary of
Def Con, uhm, I had this thought
because it, just the week before
I read the, the CFD, I was
reading some paper about
programming analysis. Uh, that
was published in the 90s and I
was think that, you know, wow!
These guys had like a lot of the
same ideas that we're having now
and they were talking about this
in the 90s. I wonder how much
other such history has kind of
fallen by the wayside. Uh, and,
uh, so I started looking a
little bit. Digging through. And
I wrote this, uh, proposal for
this CFD, uhm, to kind of go
through the last 25 years of
programming analysis and then
when I was putting together the
slides I realized that
programming analysis goes way
farther back. So, uh, where
does, you know the 25 years, uh,
number come from? Uhm, and I
thought about it some more and
realized that 25 years is
actually my involvement with
this programming analysis. 25
years ago my grandma gifted me a
book called 'Professor Fortran's
Encyclopedia' which had like a
cat named 'X' and, uh, a
professor named Fortran, and a
caterpillar named 'Caterpillar'.
Uhm, and it, it went through
their adventures in computer
land and, uh, taught kids all
about computers - I was, I was
crazy about this book. I ditched
classes in first grade to hide
in the stairwell and reread this
book over and over. And I
learned basic from it, and then
later on, uh, moved on to, to C
and so forth and I realized very
early on that if I, you know,
make a standard program that
asked me for my name and my name
is too long, my last name by the
way, Shoshitaishvili, so I
actually triggered bugs with
this last name. Uhm, then the
program would crash and so then,
you know, then that turns out to
be a buffer and so forth. And
then I started realizing that
it's incredible to look at a
computer program try to
understand how it really works.
I mean that's a whole different
world in there, right? A world
of ones and zeros...and uh,
assembly instructions and logic
gates and somewhere along the
line it becomes alive. And it
becomes behaving, it starts
behaving in ways that you don't
quite understand ahead of time.
Uhm, and that's manual program
analysis - understanding how
this works but then you can take
that and make it automated. You
can create programs that can
understand programs. And it's
like a whole level of, uh
craziness. That's like creating
some sort of intelligence almost
and, and that's what fascinates
me about program analysis.
That's what's kept me, uh,going
down the path I've been going
for the last 25 years. And so,
uh, this talk is about, you know
the history of programming
analysis and it's about, you
know, why we wanna do
programming analysis in terms
of, kinda, the dry things. Like,
we wanna, you know, hack
programs. We wanna make sure
programs are safe. But, uhm, try
to approach this topic from the,
sort of, kids perspective... Of
discovering a whole new world of
how programs work. And how
programs might understand other
programs. Uh, program analysis
is useful but it's also kind of
magical, in a way. So, with that
said - let's move on to
technical issues. Hhm, hold on,
boom! Success - let's move on to
programming analysis! Uhm,
program analysis is a, uh, field
that has basically three parts
to it, right? You wanna analyse
a program but you always want to
analyse a program to figure
something out about it. So, for
example, you might want to make
sure that a certain
specification... Of the program
holds. The program doesn't
crash; the program doesn't allow
random people to unlock your,
uh, smart key your house. Uh,
the program doesn't allow, you
know, for your breaks to be
remotely controlled and so on.
Uhm, and, uh, you have a, a goal
that you want to achieve with
that specification. So, for
example, if your specification
is a, I, uh, don't want this to
crash, you could say I want to
make sure that, that, uh,
specification holds always. Or
you want to say, you might want
to say I want to make sure that
specification does not fall, I
want a crash, right? So, kind of
- are you looking for bugs; are
you trying to make sure things
are safe? And, uh, then of
course once you decide what you
want to do you need to decide
how you want to do it. What is
the technique that you're going
to use to reason about a
specification on your program.
Uhm, and with these three, kind
of, categories in mind, I'm
gonna run you through the
history of program analysis and,
uh, where along the line we
collected different, uh, items,
kind of different instances, uh,
of these three categories. Uhm,
and so we're gonna commence of a
brief history of computing
starting in the 1830s with
Charles Babbage. Uh, Charles
Babbage created the analytical
engine, it was a mechanical
computer - super far ahead of
its time. Uhm, and he wrote a
bunch of programs for it, uh, by
all accounts these programs were
actually really buggy. So,
that's really interesting, so,
uhm, the first computer
program's written, were already
buggy. We didn't have that term
yet, I'll talk about that later.
Uhm, and about a decade later
Ada Lovelace, uh, published a
series of notes, uhm, and uh,
more reasoning about this
analytical engine - including
the first program, the first
complex program for one of these
machines. So this is Aida
Lovelace's, uh, description of
the trace of, uh, the, the
executions traits of this
program. Right? The program
computed bernoulli numbers and
so she goes through instruction
by instruction and says how, uh,
variables change and so forth.
And this was in the 1840s,
right? Uhm, and so that's where,
uh, things started, in, uh, 1947
about a hundred and five years
later, uh, we got the term bug.
Grace Hopper found a, or people
working with her found a, uh,
actual moth inside a computer
causing a computer error. So, a
hundred years roughly after the
first instance of, kind of, a
computer in the semi-modern era
we have, kind of, this official
term for the word bug.
[background noise] Uhm, and this
very quickly, uhm, started
getting people thinking about
how do we, kind of prevent
actual software bug. The moth I
guess technically was kind of a
wetware bug. Uhm, how do we
prevent bug in our software? And
one of the kind of early, uh,
visionaries here was, uhm, Alan
Turing, uhm, who's known... Of
course for the Turing machine;
but also cracking enigma and,
and, and onwards and onwards.
Uhm, but he also had the first
paper that I could find that
talked about - 'Hey, maybe we
should try to make sure the
program is correct', right? Uhm,
and he published this in 1949 -
so two years after the, kind of
invention of the term bug.
People start thinking about how
do we, uh, make sure that their
are no bugs in the, in a
program. And this, uh, creates
the field of program
verification - so, program
verification says like 'Hey,
given a program and it's
specifications we wanna make
sure that there are no bugs in
this program. That this program,
uh, carries out the computation
it needs to carry out and so
forth and, uhm, and doesn't go
astray'. Uhm, so, as an example,
here's a, a simple program that,
uh, has a crash but that crash
is not reachable, right? So, if
you give this program, uh, the,
uh, somehow three numbers that
add up - a plus b equals c, but
then c minus b i not equal to a,
it'll crash. And you wanna see
if this program is safe. You can
run a program verification, uh,
on it which will identify, you
know, hopefully that, uh, this,
uhm, condition can never hold
and will produce a proof that
will tell you that the program
is safe according to your
specification. So that's great
and if everything worked like
that in the real world, uh...
Then we might not have bugs.
And, and in, in, in certain
cases it does work like this,
uh, in the real world. So, there
is formally verified hardware,
according to a specific
specification of course, so it
things that the specification
does not reason about, you know,
maybe still can go wrong with
that hardware but, uh, thinks
that, uh, are, are, uh, covered
by the specification don't. So,
there's you know, hardware that
can provably not contain, uh,
timing side channel attacks for
example. Uhm, and there's
verified software, uhm, I heard
recently that Google for example
is switching over to a formally
verified crypto, uh, system.
Uhm, and so the problems of
course come when, when the
software kind of becomes bigger
and complexity starts getting
introduced and, uh, verification
stops being able to reason about
things very effectively. So, for
example, here, uhm, we have a
different type of program,
right? And,. uh, this program
also doesn't crash. That, uh, a
cubed plus b cubed equals c
cubed - that's from Arzela's
theorem, right? That is not
solvable, there's no solution.
Uhm, but it took humans hundreds
of years, uh, to figure this out
and the, uh, computer
verification tools, unless
there's a special coder for this
will, uh, also be unable to
handle it. So, it will kind of
see this, uhm, condition, it'll
say 'Okay, well, if, uh, if this
condition is true then the
program will crash. Can I prove
that the condition is always
false?' And if it can't prove
false it has no choice but to,
uh, alert that the program can
not be verified. So, uhm, that
happens to that, right? So then
you have to go in and you have
to start looking at, uh, the
program manually and, and
finding bugs and if anyone's
used kind of commercially
available, uh, static analysis
tools, uhm, you're very well
familiar with the false positive
problem, right? You open up a,
uh, binary or a, a piece of
software and the tool pops up
alerts all over the place, and
uhm, some of those are actual
bugs but you spend a lot of time
chasing down the alerts. Uh, so
when we've looked at, you know
software, open sourced software
for example, uhm, we often see,
you know, security check done
twice. You know, the same check,
you know, if a is not null, if a
is not null. Why is that check
there twice? Because for
whatever reason, a, uh, program
verification tool alerted that
there could be a bug there and
the programmer figured out some
hack to make it shut up.
[laughter] So, program
verification, while it's a very
useful field, like I said there
is verified software and
hardware out there, uhm, it's
not kind of the, the, final
answer on it's own. And we also
at some point need to have kind
of the flipside - so program
verification can say 'That is
safe but', you know, after that
it says 'Okay, I, I, I can't
really reason about it'. So, the
flipside is you have a technique
that says 'That is not safe, I
can prove it. But I can't really
prove, you know, if it is safe,
but you know, if it is not safe
I can give you a counter
example'. Uhm, and the way this
works is, uh, by, you know,
finding counter examples; do
whatever technique, uhm, so in
this case with a slightly
different, uh, uhm, condition.
That is, uh, a squared plus b
squared equals c squared - a
technique might find a, b, and c
as three, four, and five as a
counter example that will
reproduce a crash. And, so, this
is, uh, there are many
techniques that, you know, will
be mentioned later that, uh, can
be used to do program testing.
But one of the very early one,
the first instance of, uh,
program testing of this style
that I found was in the 1950s -
which is about four decades
before I thought that this, uhm,
kind of idea was, was, uh
created. Uh, programmers in the
1950s would program in punch
cards and, uh, to test their
code it was common practice to
dig punch cards out of the trash
and feed them as input to your
program. This unexpected input -
just random stuff and, of
course, if I ran random stuff
your program shouldn't crash. So
this is kind of an early, uh,
uhm, example of the sort of, uh,
kind of institutionalized
testing, uh, that we're, you
know, only seeing come back,
uhm, recently. Uhm, and so, the,
the, these early developments -
verification, testing, the, the
creation of those two ideas,
uhm, and then, uhm, the idea
what you might check for so, uh,
the , uhm, you know. Uh, Turing
reasoned about, uh, ensuring
logical properties. Uhm, but
this was all done manually so
this kind of our first, uh, set
of tools in our tool bag and
they're manual tools. You have
to dig them out, uh, okay, yea,
let's get our trash, uh, you
know, cards, this one's got
eaten by something and you know,
put in the ones that won't jam
your machine and, and, and, uh,
try them. Uh, but none of this
was automated and so, uh, as
computers became more and more
ubiquitous the need for
automation started showing
itself. Uhm... So, again. The
we, uhm, uh, a mention of Grace
Hopper here, uhm, because she
not only found the first bug but
she also invented the compiler.
So, Grace Hopper in 1952
published a paper saying 'Hey,
what if wrote in kind of higher
level languages and you know, it
got squashed down to, to
computer code.' Uhm, and, uh,
this took a little while to
catch on and the reason it took
a while to catch on, well, one
of the reasons is that, uh, the
code that was generated by this
compiler was very slow. It
couldn't be, uh, you know, it
could be optimized as well as
hand-written assembly could at
the time. Uh, and so this, uh,
identified another need, another
goal of programming analysis -
transformation of binaries into
something different, something
faster in this case. Uhm, and,
and in the modern era, you know,
you can transform binaries for
example or transfer programs to,
uh, ensure that they're safe.
You can transform programs to
meet any sort of specification
to run on a different set of
hardware. Uhm, and so, uh, now
we needed to optimize code
because, you know, people write
slow code when they're writing
source for whatever reason. Uhm,
and, uh, another thing happened,
people started realizing that we
have all these, uh,
architectures with, uhm, all of
this data floating around in
them and if you're not very very
very careful some data could be
read from or written to a
different location than
intended. And, uh, the memory
could be corrupted. So, I just
played, you know, two days of a
CTF full of these errors of
course, memory corruptions, uh,
bugs, uhm, and, uh, this was
first described in 1968, in 1968
there was a paper saying hey,
you know, we noticed that, uh if
the kernel, I think they called
it a monitor at the time,
blindly trusts everything that,
uh, you know the user, the user
space sends bad things can start
to happen. Uhm, and so this
paper introduced this concept.
It's also the paper that, you
know, one of the early works in
memory protection, uh and
virtual memory and so forth.
Uhm, which is pretty interesting
the immediately they realized
this was a problem. And, uhm, a
little while later... Uh, there
was a, you know, Ken Thompson's
reflections on trusting trust
for the very reason that you can
build in a backdoor into a
compiler that could build in
backdoors into sensitive code.
And so, suddenly we have, uhm,
two more things that we need to,
uh, worry about in terms of
specifications. Uhm, or even
more, but, you know, including
memory safety; information
disclosure; uh, and
authentication, right? So, now
you might want to verify that a
program doesn't have a backdoor.
Uhm, or you might verify that a
program will not leak your
private sensitive information.
That is; that one is, uh, very,
uh, relevant today with all of
our phones having all of our
information and, uh, very little
control over it. [sneeze] Uhm,
and so, the need for automation
was pretty well established, uh,
by the kind of, turn of the
century for sure, uhm, but even
before that, uh, those papers
were like in the 19- you know
60s or something, late 1960s and
very quickly. Oops, sorry. Very
quickly, uh, people started to,
uhm, meet this need. The
research community started
pumping out automated approaches
and so I'm going to introduce a
couple of these automated
approaches. Uhm, and, uh, before
I do so, I want to make you
guys, uh, experts in program
analysis so that we can reason
about what's going on here. So,
uh, we'll talk about a couple of
prerequisites, right? So, let's
say you have a program, so, on
the top right there's like a
little python program already,
uh, that, already a vulnerable
program, by the way. Uh, and so
you have this program, uh, and
you wanna analyse it. So you
have to reason about a program
in a slightly different way as
computer than as a human. So,
for example, a program is viewed
by a computer as a set of basic
blocks. A basic block is a piece
of code that is executed, uh,
all together before passing on
control flow somewhere else. So,
uh, in our case, we'll pretend
that... Input is, are the basic
blocks of this x equals input
is, uh, a single basic block and
then it might branch depending
on the input. Right? So, if you
put in '42' it'll do one thing;
if you put in, uh, something
else, it'll do another. And so
this is the end of the basic
block and then the result of
that IF statement is two other
basic blocks - the true case and
false case. And each of these
has, uhm, a, uh, constraint that
has to be met, right? In order
to go down one path you have to
put in 42; in order to go down
another you have to put in not
42 - as these are called
constraints. If you then, uh,
look at all of the basic blocks
of a program - this is called a
control flow graph. Uhm,
because, that's, uhm, you know
these are basic blocks and
control flows between them. And,
uh, if you look at a path down
this graph - no in this case the
graph is nice and simple but in
reality it could have loops. A
path might hit the same node
multiple times and so on. UIhm,
and then you look at the
contraints all along this path.
These are the path predicates
that, uh, uniquely identified
this path. Uhm, so if you
collect all of these constraints
and you, uh, say x is not 42 but
x is 1 43 7 that input will, uh,
any input that matches those
constraints will take the same
path through the program. Uhm,
so these are kind of the, the
prerequisites of our program
analysis technique so now we'll
go through three of them
actually, for time reasons we'll
go through two of them and
mention a third. But we'll start
with symbolic execution. And
symbolic execution got a lot of
hype, uhm, recently especially
with stuff like the cyber grand
challenge, uhm, uh and so on a s
way for, uh, machines to reason
about program code. Uhm, and
you'd think that this is
something new but it turns out
that it is not. It's, uh, quite
old actually, so 40 years ago,
uh, little bit more, the first
symbolic execution paper that I
could find was proposed. Uhm,
and there were, there were
several actually, right, in one
year basically. So, this idea
had some prerequisites that were
met and then it exploded. Uhm,
and so the symbolic execution
engines were developed that, uh,
could then symbolically execute
force ran code. Now we have
symbolic execution engines, uh,
that you can download off GitHub
that can execute binaries, Java,
uh, Android, whatever you want.
Uhm, and, uh, this is kind of a,
a fairly powerful way of
reasoning about programs. And,
uh, let's run through an
introduction of it with a
slightly more complicated, uhm,
example than, you know, what we
learned about binary - uh,
program analysis with. Uhm, hold
on. [pause] So, here's a program
that has several bugs, right?
Uhm, one is it, uh, well, it
definitely has one bug and that
is if you enter, uhm, a, uh,
username of 'service' and the
command code of seven it'll
crash, right? [audience noise]
Uhm, you can imagine that
instead of this crash it does
some system, uh relevant stuff
so it could be a backdoor. And
so - instant memory corruption,
but basically we have a program
with a bug... And we would like
to find this bug. So, I see how
some of you might approach this
problem with symbolic execution,
right? Uhm, so, first let's look
at the base, uh, the control
flow graph of this program -
starting from the beginning. And
the control flow graph is, uh,
made up of basic blocks and the
control for transitions between
them. So, we start at this
input, uhm, if the input is
'service' it branches. If the
username is service it branches
into one side of the, uh,
equation where it, of the
program where it, uh, checks for
the command code being seven.
And if it is it crashes; if not
it prints unknown command. Uhm,
and then it, uh, exists. On the
other side of the branch it, uh,
checks - asks for a, a passcode.
If the passcode is invalid it
prints 'Invalid passcode'
otherwise it calls the
authentication function and then
it prints 'exit' and exits. So,
this is our, our control flow
graph and how would we, uh, use
symbolic executions to try to
find that crash - to try to
find, uh, the ability to read
the crash. So,uh, we would start
executing the program in an
emulator and in this emulator -
instead of ones and zeros we are
working on, uh, 'x', 'y' and
other symbols, right? So for
example 'username', uh, is a
symbol in this, uh, emulator, so
when we pull in an input it will
produce an unconstrained
variable called 'username'. And
you don't know what username is;
username could be anything. Uh,
because, you know... That is,
you know, how our, how we
increment our emulator. Uhm, and
as we check for values of
username, we create what are
called 'constraints', right? So
these are the exact constraints
of the basic block checks, uh,
when it pushes execution
forward. Uhm, and we collect two
constraints in this case, on the
one side 'username equals
service' and on the other side
it 'does not equal service'.
These are constraints and we
continue, uh, executing both
sides of the If statement with
symbolic execution. But then we
hit something that is very bad
for symbolic execution. We hit,
uh, for example string
processing functions. So, a
string processing function like
'a to i' might check a given
byte. See if it is a number, if
it is a number it'll do one
thing. If it's not it'll do
another, right? Or if it's a
certain number it might be one,
if it's not simple number it
will do another. So, it'll keep
branching - the symbolic
emulator at every, uh... I'm
sorry... [pause] Oh, awesome.
It'll keep branching the
symbolic emulator at, uh, every
if statement; at every check I'm
this number until we get into a
situation where there are just
too many checks, right? So,
it'll try to check for a command
code of, you know, uh, ten bytes
with, uh, arbitrary values of
nine bytes and so on. And
there's exponential, uh, path
explosion here, uh, and there
are some approaches in the
symbolic, uh, execution world to
kind of deal with this sort of
path explosion. But, in general
these approaches boil down to
the requirement to remove paths,
right? And lose this
information. And so, in the end
the symbolic execution engine
might, uhm, only find certain
paths and not others and miss
the bug because we had to
simplify to keep things
tractable. So, that's symbolic
execution. It might find a bug -
if we're lucky, right? But if
you're not and it has to
simplify, uh, it's state space
essentially, uh, as it's
executing there are certain
things that it might miss. Uhm,
so my execution was proposed as,
uh, you saw, in 1975, uh, but
the interesting thing is that
in, uh, Ada Lovelace's notes
from, uhm, 1942, we can see that
she did a symbolic trace of the
execution of her program. So,
in, where she has this sort of
program execution, uh, log in
her notes, she writes down the
symbol, the, the equation for
each, uh, uh, variable as, uh,
the program progresses. And this
is the first symbolic trace of a
program - done in 1842 back
before computers were invented.
So, that was a pretty
interesting thing to find, uh,
and kind of a nice point of
history that we can put as the
start of program analysis, in
this sense - 19 - uh, 1842. Not,
you know, 1975 or 1949 or, uh,
any of those much, much later
dates. [sniff] And so symbolic
execution, uh, is a kind of tool
in our tools set. Uhm, that, uh,
we can use to achieve, uh,
either verification or
specification but testing that
specification , uh, or to
support the transformation of
code. Uh, of course how you
verify a program for example
using just symbolic execution.
Uh, is a pretty complex, uh,
thing with the symbolic
execution style that described -
the sort of program you're
testing it generates inputs to
find vulnerabilities but it
can't prove that there aren't
any. Uhm, but, uh, that's kind
of a - you could go down that
route for an entire semester
course and not just a, uh, 45
minute introductory talk. So,
I'll leave that as future
research for you guys. [audience
noise] And we'll go on to static
analysis because static analysis
can, uh, show that for example a
program is, uhm, immune to a
certain class of vulnerabilities
or, uh, so, properly implements
a certain specification. Uhm,
static analysis, uh, or at least
one of the very, uh, common ways
to do static analysis which is
abstract interpretation, uh, was
proposed in, uh, 1977 shortly
after symbolic execution. And,
uh, abstract interpretation
looks at the, uh... Oops, that
should say 'abstract
interpretation', uhm, looks at,
uh, control flow graph. The,
the, the program as a whole,
essentially. [background noise]
It, uh... Doesn't have to figure
out how to reach a certain, uh,
basic block to reason about
properties of the program at
that basic block. Uh, which, is
the the problem that symbolic
execution had and, and, and, uh
the reason symbolic execution
could not find the bug in our
example. And so, uh, static
analysis with abstract
interpretation might be able to
find that - probably will be
able to find that bug if it is a
simple bug or, actually, I
should say WILL be able to find
that bug. Uhm, because if it
cannot prove that a piece of
code is safe it will, uh, raise
an alert. The problem is that,
as we talked about, there are
false positives so in our
program it might think that
function has a bug even if it,
uh, doesn't alert on that and
eat up time, uh, for a human to
go through and verify all these
results. Uhm, and so through it,
abstract interpretation we've
got a way to, uhm, perform
verification or specification on
a program. Uh, in 1977, 40 years
ago. Uhm, and then we moved on
to, uh, fuzzing and so fuzzing
is kind of one of the uh, uh,
biggest ways to find
vulnerabilities in modern
software and it's actually
surprisingly simple, uh,
proposed in 1981, initially in
its most basic form which was,
uh, hey, uhm, let's throw random
input into our program and and
see if it crashes. It's evolved
quite a bit since then and so,
the specific, uh, implementation
of fuzzing that I'll describe
here is implemented by American
fuzzy loft, uhm, it's a fuzzer
that mutates its inputs when it
detects differences in program
execution. And so, let's see how
it would run on our program
here, uhm, we'll start with, uh,
some randomly generated test
case or human-seeded test case;
so a human might input a user
name of ASDF and a password of 1
1 1. And, uh, that, uhm, input
will trigger certain basic
blocks to be executed, right?
And so it executed the user name
input, of course. We executed
the chat for the, uhm, kind of
service username that could lead
to the crash. We did not satisfy
it so we took the else branch,
uh, read in the passcode and,
uh, error'd out on, on invalid,
uh, passcode. Uhm, and exited.
So we triggered those basic
blocks. And so the fuzzer starts
mutating this input, right? It
might make the lowercase d a
capital D or something or it
might, uhm, or it might mutate,
uh, input in a way, uh, passes
another check. So it mutated
input in a way that, uh, passes
that, uh, passcode check. It
actually doesn't because there's
another bug in the program that
I didn't notice before. But, uh,
let's pretend that it, uh, uh,
it, it creates a valid, you
know, size of a passcode. And,
uh, triggers that authenticated,
uh, authentication function,
right? So that is a new basic
block that it triggers and now
we, with fuzzing we've, uh,
triggered a block that, you
know, symbolic execution before
us wasn't able to trigger. Uh,
just through randomly mutating,
uhm, inputs. But then we get
stuck because through randomly
mutating inputs we are unable to
satisfy complex checks, right?
We need a username of 'service'
and we have randomly mutated
usernames. The chances are that
it'll create the string service
are very slim and we'll keep
guessing and guessing and
guessing. Of course, in this
specific case, you could seed
the fuzzer with the string
'service' and you could scan the
binary for, or the program for
all of its strings and, uh,
automatically, you know, make
the fuzzer pass this check but,
you know, screen checks aren't
the only complex checks in
programs - these are hashes;
there are, uh, complex, uh,
input formats, uhm, dependencies
between different input bytes
and so in the general case we,
uh, cannot guarantee of course
with a fuzzer that we'll find,
uh, code that is protected by
these complex checks. Uhm, and
so, you know, fuzzing with this
random data, of course is a
throwback to this trash stack
concept. So, you know, fuzzing
was invented in 1950 - not 1981
- uhm, or at least manual
fuzzing. Uh, so, again, we find
that, you know, program analysis
techniques harping back to the
middle of the century, uh, and
even, and sometimes even farther
to, uh, the 1800's. Uhm, so now
we kind of have this toolbox of
a bunch of specifications that
we can enforce, uh, a, uh some
goals that our analysis could,
uh, try to achieve and the
technique through which we, uh,
can achieve them and, uh, next
we should evaluate them and
understand how these, uh,
different, uh, understand how
these different goals, uhm, or
how these different techniques
help us, uh, achieve program
analysis goals. And, uhm... As a
scientist, you know,uh, if you,
uh, uh, start thinking up an
approach and you have a cool
idea and you have, uh, a new
program analysis technique - you
want to evaluate it. So, you
wanna take, uh, programs and
specifications; feed them into
your technique and see how well
it does. This is my clipart,
uhm, slide by the way, so
hopefully my clipart game is on
point. Uhm, so, you, you run
your analysis; you get your
results; and you're happy,
right? Well there a number of
problems with this - one, is
that the analysis is more
complex than you might think
because any program analysis has
to deal with the environment of
the program it's analyzing. And
environments like Windows, MAC
OS, Linux, uh, mobile devices.
Uh, cyber physical devices -
they have really complex
environments and having to model
this environment even before
analyzing, uh, understanding how
much better your program
analysis has to be unique; is
than previous techniques is
quite a big investment that, uh,
people often don't make or, uh,
make in a kind of, uh, very, uh,
fast matter. Another problem is
finding a good dataset... To
evaluate on, right? Uh, there's
not really a good dataset for,
or there wasn't great dataset
for vulnerability research -
this problem is actually being
worked on and new datasets are
being created as I'll, uh, talk
about. But you need a good
dataset with, uh, ideally known
vulnerabilities, so you can
reason about how many of them
you'll do bug finds. Uh, and,
uhm, with a variable
vulnerability and different
programs, so, you're, uh, your
technique isn't, uhm, you know,
specifically tailored for, uh,
one style of vulnerability that
you happen to detect, uh, or,
one specific program that you
have to be very good at
analyzing. Uhm, another problem
is these specifications, right?
Specifications in the real world
are very complex, uh, where as
specifications, uhm, that you
might want to use for your, uh,
analysis tool initially in the
early stages of development need
to be fairly simple and ideally
be provided. I mean if you're
looking at the, uh, analyzing
something like Chrome and your
specification is that Chrome
should not leak, uh, user data
to someone that should not get
this user data. That's
impossibly broad and impossible
to enforce. Is your bank allowed
to have your, you know, various
cookies or, or, something along
these lines? Uhm, so, you need a
very good dataset - standard
dataset or a very good, uh,
standard implementation, uhm,
uh, standard set of
specifications so that you can
analyse how well your technique
runs compared to, uh, uh,
different work and compare those
results to prior work because
that's a very important part of
science and technical
development is understanding if
you're making an improvement or
not. [sniff] Uhm, and so we had
problems as a, analysis
community in, in meeting all of
these goals [sneeze] And having
a good dataset of application
with a good set of
specifications on a good, uhm,
environment that wasn't too
complex to, uh, implement and I
could produce results that we
could reason about; that we
could say okay, you know, we
have ground proof data for the
vulnerabilities that are
actually in this dataset and uh,
we detect x of them. Or we, uh,
manage to rule out
vulnerabilities in code that has
no vulnerabilities and, uh, you
know, so our program
verification is correct. Uhm,
and, and so there, like I've
mentioned there have been
several, uh, projects to, uh,
solve this problems or create
these data sets. And on of
these, uh projects essentially
with the cyber grand challenge.
If you guys were here last year
you probably saw all of the, uh,
cyber grand challenge, uh, you
know, hoopla, uh, where for the
first time in history seven
fully automated program analysis
machines, uh, fought each other
in a game of 'capture the flag'.
So, the same game that I spent
the entire weekend, uh, playing
and only got four hours of sleep
- is the game that machines that
didn't need to sleep - played
yesterday, uh, last year rather.
And, uhm, these, uh, machines of
course suffer from all the of
the problems I just talked
about. The environmental
problem; the specification
problem. And so the cyber grand
challenge created a custom
operating system with very
specific vulnerability
specifications to, uh, evaluate
these systems. Now, for the
actual competition of course the
source code wasn't available
since then, uh, they, uh,
released source code so you can
really look at the source code;
understand the vulnerability and
then reason about how well your
tool finds certain
vulnerabilities. Across 249
binaries - so it's, uh, it's a
249 programs; so, it's a dataset
that has a, uh, lot of variants.
There a lot of different types,
uhm, and uh, different
difficulties of vulnerabilities
and, uhm, all of this is freely
available for, uh, people to
analyse their tool and
understand how well it does.
That's my other piece of
clipart. [audience noise] Uhm,
so the cyber grand challenge and
the, the programs that, that
were written for these - the 249
programs making up the cyber
grand challenge dataset, uhm,
allowed us to, uh, do what I
call; to perform what I call the
program analyses nursery
experiments. So, I see the cyber
grand challenge dataset the
nursery of program analysis
where you can reason about
different improvements for
different techniques. So, for
example symbolic execution on
the entire dataset finds nine
vulnerabilities - the symbolic
execution as implemented in
Anger which I'll talk about in a
sec. Uh, which is an open
source, uh, binary analysis
program available on GitHub.
Uhm, but symbolic execution on
this entire dataset finds nine
vulnerabilities. That's not a
lot, right? There are
vulnerabilities in every program
of these 249 programs - it only
finds vulnerabilities in nine of
them. Uhm, of course we can
optimize symbolic execution
using various tricks - anger
supports, for example, concrete
execution when there's, uh, no
uncertainty in this state; when
all the data is known. Uh, or
when there are constraints on
all the data and so by utilizing
all of these optimizations, uh,
we can get 26, uh, crashes -
crashes in 26 binaries. Uh,
utilizing static analyses.
[background noise] Sso, uh, uh,
combining symbolic execution
with vary-testing which is a
technique by Carnegie Mellon
University, uh, that utilizes
parts of abstract interpretation
to help with symbolic execution.
We can push that up to 31 - so I
should say here that this our
implementation of vary testing
and it might be, uh, suboptimal
so, there varied testing might
be considerably better. Uhm, but
that all pales in comparison
with fuzzing. This seemingly
simple technique of throwing
random data and seeing what
happens, uh, finds 106 crashing
binaries in the dataset. Uhm, so
this gives us an idea of where
program analysis is and, and,
this is a good showcase for the
simplicity of, of evaluating,
uh, all of these different
analysis on this dataset and
reasoning about the results.
Because now we can look at them
in terms of, uh, you know,
summation numbers but there's
also some subtleties there -
they find bugs. [background
noise] Different types of bugs
in different binaries. So, uh,
we can look into that and make
inferences and try to create
new, um, approaches. So, for
example, we looked at the
difference in the types of bugs
that symbolic execution found
and that fuzzing found. And we,
uh, realize that they have very
different coverage. So, the
types of; the basic blocks that
fuzzing can trigger are very
different than the basic blocks
that symbolic execution can
trigger. And sometimes one finds
a crash; sometimes another finds
a crash; sometimes neither of
them finds a crash. In fact,
very frequently. And, so, we
uhm, decided to combine them in
a very, uh, straightforward but
careful way. Uhm, the idea is as
follows. We begin by fuzzing the
binary; this is nice an fast and
achieves decent code coverage
but as we discussed eventually
gets stuck on complex checks.
And then we use symbolic
execution to find a constraint
that can get through that check
but possibly suffer from other
limitations in symbolic
execution and not find the
actual bug. And then we
synchronize that back into the
fuzzer - we synchronize the
knowledge of how to bypass the
complex check back into the
fuzzer and it continues to
mutate that input until it finds
the bug. Uhm, and we do this
iteratively, or, uh, back and
forth between the fuzzer and the
symbolic execution. So, by
implementing symbolic
assistance, for the fuzzer in
this way, uh, we achieve - on
this entire dataset - 118
crashes. Uhm, and an interesting
is here, here is that we have
this 118 crashes in the dataset
but, uhm, if you find the union
of all of the different
techniques - all of the
different techniques have
crashed, something like this
from memory, 150 to 160
binaries. So, there's a lot of,
uh, uniqueness between the
different techniques used here.
Uhm, driller, uh, the
applicability of it varies by
program whether or not there are
complex checks, uhm, we can run
through a quick run here. So
this is a control flow graph of
an example program and driller
start in the top left corner
there. And, uh, it first starts
by fuzzing a portion of the
program before it gets stuck in
a complex check. Uhm, and this
is the basic block coverage on
the right in this graph here.
Uhm, you can see it just kinda
flatlines, right? So, then if we
run the symbolic execution
engine to, uh, help the fuzzer
reach extra code paths, uh, it
allows us to find just a little
tiny, uh, bit more basic blocks
in the; uh, execute some more
basic blocks in that, uh,
control flow graph with the
program. And if we keep, uh,
invoking the symbolic execution
engine to help the fuzzer get
unstuck every time that, the,
the coverage flatlines like, we
eventually drill into the
program deep enough to find the
bug. And so that's how it really
works. Uhm, there's still a lot
to do, so there's this whole
red, uh, area that, uh, however
many programs - about 100
programs that we have never
exploited before. Uhm, that
we've never crashed before using
any automated techniques. Uh,
which represent, uh, missing,
uh, tools, basically that
humanity has yet to develop, or
at least we have yet to develop.
Uhm, and so if this all sounds
interesting to I encourage you
to join in. There's several ways
that you can participate in
program analysis research. One
is you can contribute to open
source frameworks - so, uh, we
run one of these frameworks,
uhm, in our research lab - it's
called 'Anger' go to Anger dot i
o. There's a lot that, uh, we
could use help with -
documentation; environment
support; uh, better techniques;
uhm, and so on. Uhm, and the
other is that I am always
looking for students. I'm
starting as a professor at
Arizona State University, uhm, I
just finished a phd at, UC Santa
Barbara and both of those places
are incredible places to go to
if you want to do research in
program analysis or in general
security. So, if you're thinking
about graduate school, or, uh,
you are, uhm, curious and want
to do an internship uh,
reach out to me - I'll put you
in touch with the right people.
Uhm, and, uh, you can explore
that. Uh, the presentation is
available online; all my contact
info is right here and I guess
we'll do questions in the hall.
Awesome, thank you guys!
[applause]