>> My name is Omar Eissa. I am
here with Wojtek, we are from a
security company based in
Heidelberg, Germany and today's
talk will be about network
automation and a specifically
autonomous networks. So what is
it about? Haven't we all had
that problem that we send a
technician to the site and he
doesn't have the running
configuration for that author?
Haven't we had this problem that
while configuring something, we
had a type of mistake that we
kept troubleshooting for days
and days? What if I said to you
this is now from the past? What
if I said to you that now
there's a technology that will
make you use your routers and
switches as if you are using a
USB? You're just connected and
its starts working. This is it.
You can build networks of
hundreds and hundreds of nodes
just me- an- a-, just a matter
of minutes. While this would be
the first part of today's
presentation, I'll introduce to
you a new technology that will
ease your life. But this is
technology is introduced from
Cisco. Everything is proprietary
and we cannot understand it and
we cannot see what's there in
our network. And this would be
for the second part of today's
presentation. We will reverse
engineer everything in the
protocol and we will understand
everything. If you are
interested in attacking, hacking
and crashing devices, the third
part will be for you. We have
multiple demos, we have multiple
vulnerabilities, so we hope you
enjoy it. [applause] So
everything started by IBM 2001.
So they had the idea that
systems are getting more and
more conflicts by time and we
need system that can manage
themselves. When we thought
about it or IBM thought about it
it thought that we need system
that can configure themselves,
you don't need to configure
anything. They can optimize
themselves. Optimize their
running resources, they can even
secure themselves. We don't have
any problems in that just the
machine will do everything for
you. Yeah, this sounds a little
bit optimistic, but in 2013
Cisco and people for ITF decided
to make this into reality.
Decided to implement something
which we call autonomic network.
What's the idea of autonomic
network? It's just one device.
One router. And anything that
connects to this router after
that will be configured
automatically. You don't need to
configure anything that far, but
the question comes like how many
configuration commands do I need
to write on this device? Do I
need to write everything that
will be on the other devices?
No. Its just five commands. You
just write five commands and
after that everything connected
to your device will be up and
running. K, what if I have new
device? How many command do I
need to write? None. You don't
have to write anything at all.
What if I have an old device
that has a running configuration
from before? Then it just one
command. And after that, once
you connect your device to this
one device which we call the
registrar here, it will have a
basic configuration. Yeah, I see
this sounds a little bit
optimistic, but let's see it
live. So Wojtek if you can help
me with that. We have here. We
have here one new device for
people who are aware of Cisco
this is like what you get once
you buy a totally new device.
And you just remove the whole
configuration. What we'll be
doing here, that we ask, I ask
Wojtek here if he can connect it
to the registrar and see how it
will go. So we will just raise
our hands, we won't configure
anything and we will just watch
whether anything will happen or
not. So as we see here, device
started to be configured on its
own. We see that some files or
some configuration things are
being transferred to it. We see
like some inter- and some
interfaces started to come up
and we can see that there some
sub interface and other
configuration things. So for
this. Yeah. Hello? So as we can
see that we got like basic
configuration we would see what
basic configuration would do, we
mean about here. So first of
all, we can see that I'm getting
some keys, I I see here like now
I'm getting like three thousand
seventy-two bit key. I'm being
I'm being uh like having new
interfaces that come up, but in
order to see this live, we will
just now try to type like show
IPv6 interface brief. Autonomous
networks run on IPv6. And as we
can see here, we have like
multiple interfaces which are
up. We have like now our
autonomic network interface, we
have like uh the load back
interface also will come up. So
if you can run the command
please again. Yeah. So we can
see like the network interface,
the configuration came up, we
started to get some IP
addresses, we started to get
some information. So what
happened here and what is the
basic configuration we mean
about where we speaking about
once we connect this device and
what we will get. That's what we
will see throughout the
presentation. Or the first part
of the presentation. So if you
can take me back to the slides.
And so. Well, what are the
implications of this? Now once
you connect your device to
another device you will get a
basic configuration. You will
get interfaces connected to you.
You will get like tunnel
interfaces which comes up for
you. You will have an encrypted
and secure between you and all
the devices within your network.
What you need to configure for
that? None. Totally none. You
just need to write five commands
on one single device, which we
call the registrar. And after
that everything is configured
for you. To understand what
happened in the background and
what is the communication flow
that happened, we can see that
Cisco started or wanted to
divide the connection into three
phases. Something we call
channel discovery, adjacency
discovery and after that secure
channel. While what does that
mean? Well, Cisco decided that
for the first time, devic-
devices need to see each other
on the level two lay- oh- level
two uh yeah, level two layer. So
what they start to do that the
registrar start to send probes.
Saying like, is there any
autonomic device around? Can we
get any configuration? Is there
anything reachable? And once the
device, once we reach the
device, it starts the second
phase. We call it here adjacency
discovery. What happens in
adjacency discovery, its like
after that we go from layer two
to layer four communication and
what happens here that the
registrar, registrar starts by
saying well, I support this
domain name, I support this
network. Would you like to be
part of my network? How do we
define whether the device can be
part of the network or not? We
check like the whitelist. What's
the whitelist that we have here?
It's just the serial number of
the devices. Because we are
speaking, about totally new
devices that first I am like
booted. So if you are rejected
then we would just be neighbors
on level two. If you are
accepted, then perfect. We would
issue for you a certificate.
This certificate will be as the
ID for you for any further
communication. We can use this
certificate after that just to
act as like uh for any secure
connection because we would have
your private key or we would
have your public key then. This
is a UDP service that run on
port four nine three six. To
have a small diagram in order to
understand what we are speaking
about here. We can see it as the
following. The registrar starts
by saying, hey, this is the
domain name that I support, this
is the configuration that I can
provide. This is the network
name and the enrollee response
saying well, this is my domain
name. If the domain name is
empty, it means that this new
enrollee just would like to be
part of your domain. What will
you do after that that you will
check your whitelist. Is this
device allowed to join my
domain? And this is the security
mechanism that Cisco chose in
order to protect any malicious
devices from connecting to your
domain. So you are accepted
perfect. This is my domain
certificate. This is my ID.
Let's issue for you one too.
Please generate the key. Once
the key is generated here, and
send back to the register, we
will start by issuing a
certificate. We can understand
the certificate as just an ID
that you are part of this. Who
will issue the certificate? It
depends. Either the register
itself or if you have a cert
like a- a dedicated certificate
authority within your domain it
can do such a function. Finally,
we have done the certificate, we
send it back to you and that's
it. We are just speaking about
somehow like five packets.
Within this category and you're
done. After that, we will the
secure channel. We will some
type of interfaces so we can
communicate together. What are
the available technologies to
secure the tunnel? Well, we
already have the IPSec, but in
Cisco's perspective or autonomy
perspective this is backwards
comfortably, this is a backward
technology. Cisco introduced
something new which we call Dike
and Dike is for the data
internet gate exchange, it's
based on iv2. It has the same
characteristics as IPSec, but
it's only the second phase, so
its much much much less
overhead. We are speaking about
point five thousand and its
always the one preferred over
IPSec. The idea of autonomic
networks that people are the
problems so in order to avoid
such a thing, everything is
automated for you. You cannot
change this, you cannot even
change it order, you cannot even
favor like IPSec over Dike.
There is not even a command for
you to configure Dike on Cisco
routers. So what's the
configuration of the registrar
then? We said like we need like
five commands and everything
would be working after that. Ok,
we said that, from adjacency
discovery we need to have like a
domain name. What's my network
name? And this is the first
thing that you write by like
domain ID and you write your
domain name. You have like an
option of command that define a
whitelist if you don't define a
white list, everything connected
to you will be accepted within
your network. We can have like
after once you get like the
certificate or once you get the
key, who will issue the
certificate? And you, this by
like, defining which set of
serial you will use. If you have
a dedicated one, you would just
write it's IP address, if its a
local one, so you say like, say
hey local, local means that the
registrar will be one who issues
the certificate for you. And
finally, you just started the
services by writing autonomic.
This is all. No much hassle.
Nothing to write. Nothing to do.
What's for the other devices? If
its a brand new one. None. If
its just a router with a
previous configuration that you
had a configuration from before,
just one command. Autonomic.
Start the autonomic services. So
we are speaking about basic
configuration. What do we mean
by that? Well what will happen
that, you will get like three to
four interfaces configured with
ipv6 address for you. This ipv6
address is based on your domain
name. You will get, like you ll
start generating the key a VRF
will be created on your machine
and the triply will be allowed
if you have a cis log a tfpt
server with the newer network it
will be ded- uh it will be like
find automatically, you don't
need to configure anything here.
You just say like you have a
tftp, but it within something
called dns, this is a protocol
with an autonomic network and
this server will be like found
automatically, discovered
automatically, you don't need to
write anything. Everything will
be now like you're like create
this server if you a radius
server, now you can only access
your device in a secure manner.
So this sounds good and if you
need to have like further
configuration, if you'd like to
have with like an access risk or
something else you can put this
configuration on the tftp server
and the machine will just grab
it automatically. We are not
speaking about technology from
the future we are speaking about
technology that has been into
the market at least three to
four years. And the question
here after that. Are you really
in control? Now you understand
the technology. Now you have a
rough idea how it works. But are
you really in control? Do you
really know what's running
inside your network? Well, I
wanted to see how it looked
like, the this packets of
autonomic networks under
Wireshark. And that's what I
have seen. And LLC packets for
the people who are not aware of
LLC, LLC is a layer two
technology. Honestly, I didn't
expect to see something like
that. At least I expected to see
like UDB service. I expected to
see Dike or IPSec, whatever it
is. But I expected to see
something more than just layer
two. And here comes the
technology. What's really
running within our network? And
to know something like this, we
will reverse engineer it
together. This is the first
frame that we see once we start
the wireshark. This is what it
looks like. That question, how
is how we store it. How we store
it to reverse engineering this.
And the first idea comes that
well we all started by an
ethernet frame, but which one of
the ethernet frames that we can
start with? We have like three
types of ethernet frames and by
checking those bytes, we
understand that this is a not
not an ether two net frame and
by checking this we understand,
this is is a snap frame. So at
least we understand the first
few bytes within this frame.
This is like a snap frame
modifier or a snap header. So in
order to understand this, we
start by the following. This is
this nation mac and the source
Mac, we have the length and um
here we can say the snap frame
identifier, we can have the
organizer unique identifier and
finally like uh autonomic
protocol ID identifier. The
question comes after this, how
we proceed. This uh proprietary
protocol, Cisco said how the
technology works, but it didn't
say how, what's the content,
what's the significance of the
packets. After reverse
engineering for some time, then
after tests for sometime, we
believe that protocol is based
on this header. Well, hmm. This
is the header that Cisco used to
or we can use to analyze the
protocol it has some fixer
queries and after that some
TLVs. For the people whom are
aware of TLV principle it's the
idea that to define a type
against a variable type, a
variable lens, the you put the
value of it. We will see that
throughout the presentation
here. So, the version of this if
we are speaking of the channel
discovery. The first thing that
we start with is version one.
And some reserved bytes and
after that we start with the
state. State means which part or
which phase are we in with the
protocol. Well this is Oh-one,
this is vary basic beginnings so
it's Oh-one here. After that we
have some factory full bytes and
after that we can have uh the up
codes. What's uh the up codes?
The up codes mean uh what's the
significance of what we are
seeing? What does this frame,
what's the value or what's the
importance of this frame? And
for the available up codes, here
are they. So one is if its the
first announcement, after that
for the reply and even if its
like just keep alive. If you'd
like to continue analyzing we
can see that what comes next is
the factory like uh some factory
default. This is the header
length I see here and after that
that's some reserve bytes and
type and length and value. So
you start by, identifying some
specific types with the length
and put whatever value it takes.
For the availability of these
for this, we can see that for
the only channel discovery
that's what we have. What we are
trying now to do is trying to
understand the significance of
what passes within our network.
At least with make sure that we
have control. In what we see.
After that comes the adjacency
discovery. Well this is the
framework adjacency discovery.
Its quite big. We suspect there
is a UTP here but why Wireshark
cannot analyze this. This is
because there is an additional
header that Cisco decided to
add. We call it layer two point
five, which is the autonomic
layer. We will see that. So same
idea, we have just a snap frame
in the beginning and after that,
we have this. This is a
customized channel discovery
header. This is what stops
Wireshark from analyzing and
understanding the packets.
What's in the difference between
this and the last stage? Um, can
we do anything with the slides?
Can we just...[inaudible] So
what's the difference between
this and what we used to have?
Well we can see that the state
here is oh five, not oh one like
it used to be. It means that
this is an adjacency-adjacency
discovery frame. And there's an
ether type. Ether type that says
what comes next is an ipv6. So
at least we start now to
understand why Wireshark cannot
analyze this. What comes next as
we said, ipv6 header and from
the ipv6 header we understand
what comes after it is UDP. And
the question comes after this.
How we can analyze that? Ok,
it's the same header, same
frame, but different types,
different values, different up
codes. The version here is two,
not one, like the one you would
used to have and the state here
is oh two. Because now we start
the booting phase. The idea of
getting certificates and stuff
like that. For the adjacency
discovery we have like three up
codes. Or three states. One for
the just booting up, whether you
are like accepted or rejected
within the access list or within
the whitelist and finally if we
would like to be a secure
channel. After that there are
some reserve bytes. And the up
codes. As we said, up codes,
what is the significance? And
importance of this byte that we
see or of this packet that we
see. Here are the available up
codes, it's a little bit bigger
here. And come after that just
the header lines, same idea. And
some factory default reserve
bytes. And type, length and
value. Same idea. So for the
available types, they are quite
big, it will have taken three or
four slides just to put them
here. But you get the idea. And
now starts the fun part. We have
a secure channel. What if we are
interested to know what city
you're being sent inside of this
secure channel? Well, this is
what's sent. This is an
encrypted thing. How do we know
that it's Dike? Well, just from
the port. It's five thousand.
But what is this packet? We
don't have any idea about. How
we get information about bei-
what's being sent really inside.
Well who can solve this problem
is this device. How's that? Well
this is one of the first devices
that support autonomic network.
It starts supporting autonomic
network since 2014. But how can
it-how it can help? Ok, comes
that question is, if we have an
IPSec, it means maybe like
wasn't supported from the
beginning. Maybe there are like
IPSec is backwards
compatibility. Ok, how IPSec can
even help? Because Cisco is a
closed box device, you don't
have access to anything. But
from the RFC you have IPSec
null. IPSec null is the idea
that you don't need to configure
any encryption, you just
configure like integrity, uh, on
the packets just to check its
correct. So you don't have any
problems, now you can send each
and everything in just plain
text and you can see everything.
And well this is one packet,
that can only be encrypted, can
only be seen inside the tunnel.
Its the RPL and this is the
interrupting protocol of the
autonomic network. And we can
see here this is DSP and this is
exactly like from the inside the
tunnel. The question comes after
that. Is it secure? We now have
a little bit of idea whats the
technology is. We understand
whats being sent and
significance of each and every
byte. But is it secure? For this
we would have a live chat with
uh a guy from the support who is
responsible for this, if we have
any problems while we are trying
just to check our devices. So
the first idea that we had is,
well, as we understand from
autonomic network, everyone has
their own domain. So if there
are two domains, they never
could connect with each other.
This shouldn't be under any
circumstances. Ok, let's try to
put this into practice. So
Wojtek if you could just go to
one of the code devices that we
have. Yeah, this device code
different domain. It just from a
domain different than what we
have. We can know something like
that by writing short autonomic
device. And we can see here that
the domain name is code or the
domain ID is code different. And
what I will do here is that I
will connect it to this
registrar which is from a domain
code ERNW. So please connect it
to it. Well I expect that they
will be just neighbors on their
two level, but nothing more. No
certificates, no configuration,
no tunnel interface. Nothing.
And that's what, the documents
say. Ok, let's see, I see, uh
ok. I see lot's of
configuration, I see that, the
certificates are being valid,
which shouldn't be shouldn't be
at all as printed off of Cisco
but could you just run like
short number control please. To
see whether they built radial
tunnel? Ok, I can see the the
tunnel here has been built. Hmm.
Well. This shouldn't be.
Shouldn't be at all from Cisco's
perspective. So let's go back to
the support please. Well, we
connected two nodes from two
different domains and they
worked. They connected together.
This shouldn't be. Uh Cisco has
been very responsive to us in
some of the variabilities that
we have reported here, you will
see that Cisco responded quite
quickly honestly. And there are
sometimes that, not that fast,
but we would see. So the first
thing that the business unit
said that they would check with
the uh like we would check like
with the business unit, the
people that wrote the documents.
If that can be allowed. And what
they came back to us with, that
well if they are connected from
two different domains, but we
have the same CA sign both
certificates. Then they can
communicate. But this is, again
its the documents, a know, this
is shouldn't be because they are
two different domains. How that
can be? Ok, if this is a feature
that we added in the future. Ok,
not a big deal. Uh I understand
the problem, maybe it's as very
important. But you know what,
even if it connects to mine I'll
just revoke it. It's not a big
deal for me. So if you can just
please go to the registrar. And
we will just try to revoke this
certificate. Uh the command for
revoking certificate is um
crypto PKI a n uh PKI server
a-n-r-a dash c-s and we write
revoke. So and after that we
just type the serial number of
the dev- or the serial number of
the certificate. Well it
shouldn't be a big deal, it
won't cause us any problem, we
just won't revoke it here, but
once we test it it didn't work.
So we return back to the support
saying, oh. Yeah. We return back
to the support saying well, we
tried to revoke the certificate,
but it didn't work. They said,
did you try it like on local or
an external. We said, well we
tried it on both. If it's local,
they said, well we didn't
implement it here. Said, no
problem. We tried it on external
too. They said, ok, then this is
a CVU then. So yeah, we
understand from Cisco
perspective that certificates
revocation does not implement
it. An other way that there's no
way-no way for you to throw any
malicious or compromised node
from your network. Once any of
your nodes has been compromised,
it's game over. It will always
be there, except if you have the
courage to destroy the whole
network issuing new certificates
for everyone, then build the
network. No white list can stop
anything for that because if you
have a certificate, you are not
checked by the white list. You
just pass. You are a VIP. Yeah,
so yeah. Maybe it's a problem,
but you know what, I have full
control over my network. No one
can touch my network, no one can
touch my devices. Everything is
safe somehow. So I'll just go to
the registrar again and write
something like show autonomic
control plain details. And as we
can see the communication has
been up here I I think like
three four minutes. So the idea
that nothing can affect my
communication and nothing can,
you know, attack me. And it's
not a big problem that, the
nodes just you know some nodes
are will be compromised. I see
Wojtek is typing something here.
He's resetting my channel. Huh.
It's not that simple now. Um,
what you are doing uh, if you
can show the people what you are
doing please. Here I'll just
take it a little bit. Uh. So
what you read just my
communication. Everything went
down. Eh, eh, this shouldn't be
at all. Like an attacker cannot
do something like that. And even
he's writing like check your
Wireshark. Let me say what's
there Wireshark. ok. yeah. So.
Just check it. Mm hmm. Ok. Just
ok. The idea here that even if
you check Wireshark, it looks
like there's a problem here with
the packet sniffer. That even
the RPL packets which should be
sent totally encrypted format,
they are just sent in plain
text. So somehow if you manage
to reset the configuration,
reset the channel, not only you
break the communication itself,
everything which is encrypted is
flushed in plain text. You can
see the whole configuration, the
whole everything running inside.
The RPL, your routing
information. Everything. So
please can take me back to
slides. So once we said that to
Cisco, we got a new CVE here.
Yeah, Ha. [laughter] So what's
the implications of this? Anyone
can reset your connection?
Anyone can attack you? And once
they reset the connection, they
even know what's confidential
things you are sending within
your channel. Uh this is litt-
little bit scary because anyone
can make a deny of service on
me. But at least my devices are
up. My devices are strong enough
that they are working fine.
Correct? Ok, I see Wojtek here
is showing me a video. And what
he is pinging is I see is trying
to reset it. Yeah, man I
understand my communication is
not that strong, I understand
that you can reset it, but you
are doing thing, are you
implying that my device will go
down? Huh. It's not that simple.
Not by I mean, not by resetting
the communication or resetting
the channel multiple times. Then
all will crash. That will go
down. I don't think so honestly.
Yeah. I don't know. Yeah, you
see. You are still pinging.
Everything is up. Everything is
working. Come on you cannot
challenge me in front of them.
My uh- my presentation yeah. Ha.
Yeah, I'm just waiting. Just for
your sake, you know. Mm Hmm.
Yeah. Still second reiteration,
you see. You are pinging
everything is up. Everything is
fine. There is nothing to worry
about here. A- A I know. Ok.
Eh-. This node crashed. Eh ha ha
ha. This shouldn't be. Shouldn't
be at all. Now you- not just
reset my communication, not just
you take the like channel down,
you even take the device itself
down. Take me back to the
support. [laughter] Um. Just is
someone keep resetting the
communication then all
eventually crashes and for that
we have a new CVE. [laughter]
[applause] Yeah. What's
implications of this? Anyone can
crash your devices. This attack
takes um somehow about fifteen
minutes. That's why we just have
a video here. Ok, this a little
bit scary, so, you crashed my
devices, but you know what? My
registrar. The controlling point
of the network. The strongest
point of the network. Show them
how long it has been up. Show
them. Like show version include
up. Yes. It has been up for
forty-two minutes. Nothing can
attack it, nothing can do
anything to it. Yeah. Crash.
Crashing my register. No. It's
not like de- [laughter] Even my
registrar crashed. [laughter]
Uh, like that, I don't have
anything in the network
remaining. Like the device
itself can be crashed, the
registrar itself can be crashed.
So there is no network at all.
Uh just take me to the support.
[laughter] And for that we have
a new CVE here. [laughter]
[applause] Lots of implications
of this. The controlling point,
the main point within the
network can be easily crashed if
you send like null or space byte
within the network. As a ERNW
name. Ok. Then I have no other
option, sorry. I'll just disable
autonomic network. And I'll just
run my ipv6 normally happy
without any problems. So please
Wojtek. Yeah. Yeah, this is
different domain, this is the
old device that I had, just go
like into configuration one and
just write no autonomic and
that's how we disable it. And if
we would just give it a simple
ipv6 address while writing
interface get zero or zero zero.
And we will give it like two
thousand and one slash two.
Here. So star sixty-four. And
even I will also go to my new
device so if you can go to the
new device also Wojtek please.
Just go to the new device. So it
looks like Wojtek cannot connect
to the first device. I don't
know. It looks like it crashed
on its own when it sees like
other device crashed. It just
happens. So at least now you
know what I'm safe. Literally
safe. Please write to us. Safe.
And yes with yeah, exclamation
mark. Nothing can touch my
devices. Nothing can do for me
any harm or any problem.
[laughter] Hmm. We didn't
configure anything. It's just an
ipv6 address. We disabled
everything even. Yeah. Take me
back to the presentation. This
is what's I love to call the
death case. [laughter]
Regardless you have an IP or you
autonomous servers or not, you
are vulnerable. Just the ID that
your sub, you're operating
system supports autonomic
network makes you vulnerable.
Just knowing your ipv6 address
will crash your network. Even if
you don't run the technology.
Even if you disable everything.
What's the implications of this?
Just one packet can crash
everything you have. How to stop
it? Just put an access over each
and every interface you have to
block post four nine three six
and four eighths. If you have
for any reason running autonomic
network on your network uh in
your system, just upgrade your
system. To conclude today's
presentation. We have spoken
about the autonomic network. We
have analyzed its three phases.
And after that, we had um,
spoken about the reverse
engineering of each and
everything and after that we
introduced five new
vulnerabilities. One of them can
crash just the devices by
knowing their ipv6 address. You
don't need to know anything
more. Finally, if you would like
to get your hand dirty start
working autonomic network. While
you're at it is the first uh
application to use our analysis
into this. And um you can just
also if you don't have Cisco D,
you can download the image which
is called CSR one thousand V.
And start working on that. I
wouldn't have done it without
the help and assistance of
[00:36] who helped me so much
with the protocol analysis. And
finally, if you would like to
have more information about
network or autonomic network, I
have written like three blog
posts on insinuator dot net.
Well, in the end, thank you
Wojtek for attacking everything
that I have and thank you for
attention and that's all.
[applause]