>> What an honor it is to be
here um at at Def Con, I'm
grateful to uh be able to share
with you some research. We're
going to do three things. First
uh we're releasing a tool to
attack next-gen AV and you can
find it GitHub address. I'm
gonna describe it today and
demonstrate it and and show you
how to use it. So uh first,
let's uh set the stage. Today
we're going to be talking about
uh evading next-gen AV that uses
static analysis for detecting
Windows PE malware. And uh to
motivate this, let's first talk
about uh rules and how one might
write a rule to uh to detect
malware. So on this little chart
here, I've plotted a bunch of
totally fictitious red dots and
blue dots. Which are meant to
represent uh files. As described
by first um, file size and
second by the number of registry
keys contained you know strings
containing the file. Um,
[laughter] A feature of this
presentation. And then I'm gonna
just by hand create a yara rule
which I have in that black box
there. That sort of defines this
region of this feature space,
file size number of strings,
that cordons off all of the
malware in my data set. So this
is nice but of course it's real
easy to break. And and if I just
you know take my my malware
sample and maybe add some bytes
to to the end of the file that
has no uh d- d- does not break
either the the format, the PE
file format and doesn't break
the function of the malware,
then then I can break this rule.
So what makes machine learning
maybe harder to break? Harder to
attack? And um I guess there are
a couple reasons and and one is
that you you can kind of think
of uh the machine learning as
the much more sophisticated and
and graceful rule and uh it
learns these complex
relationships from the data
automatically and uh it it and
further more it kind of instead
of presenting this sort of
brittle uh cliff from malicious
to benign, there's sort of this
smooth territory where uh the
the machine learning uh model
can uh tell you about its
confidence. Uh that that a
sample is either malicious
benign. And this is important
because um this allows sort of a
graceful degradation if one
modifies a malware sample,
there's sort of this graceful
fall off from malicious to
benign. So that that can make it
hard. So can we break machine
learning? Uh well the the short
answer is, yes we can. But the
idea for a windows PE is that we
like to uh input a file that are
model knows is malicious with
high confidence. And make a few
subtle changes to the bytes on
disk modifying elements that
don't break the PE file format
or don't break the behavior of
the malware. And then trick our
model into thinking that's
that's benign. So, it's actually
become quite fashionable to
break machine learning. In uh,
in recent years. And uh this
will be a constant reminder to
keep me on my toes. Look at how
fast at that. If you haven't
seen this image yet, this is
sort of famous in the uh image
domain that one can take uh uh
an image of a bus for example
that uh uh image recognition
computer vision model knows is a
bus with high confidence and
change the pixels ever so
slightly and now even though
there's no difference to your
eye now the model thinks it's an
ostrich with high confidence.
And uh this is you know fun for
images, um but there's kind of
three take aways whether images
or not from this kind of
adverserial machine learning
research. And the first is that
all machine learning models have
blind spots. So nex-gen AV buzz
word uh we do it at my company
Endgame uh they have blind
spots. Number two is depending
on how much knowledge an
attacker has about your your
model, they can actually be
really convenient to exploit.
And um, uh the the talk we're
we're doing today, the research
I'm presenting to your today is
actually the in in the category
of in the least convenient, the
most inconvenient spot for the
attacker to attack. And uh sort
of a third attack take away is
is a little scary and that's
that if I find for my model this
sort of bus ostrich confusion
example, there's a decent chance
that it will also work against
your model. So then the attacker
doesn't really need often need
to attack your model in order to
find some success for the
invasion against your model. And
that keeps people up at night.
Alright so, that's for images.
That's for images for bus
ostrich. The thing about this um
really how this works is that in
most cases there are two things,
the attacker knows everything
about your model. He sort of has
the source code to the model. He
knows the weights, he knows the
parameters. And in fact it has
to be a special kind of model
like deep learning and neural
nets that are fully
differentiable. And given that
for my image of a bus I can
actually ask the model, what
would confuse you the most? Tell
me which pixels I should change
to confuse you the most. And
will happily give you an answer.
And buy changing those few
pixels the good news is by
changing pixels I have not
broken what it means to be an
image. But let's think about
applying this now to PE malware.
If I were to present some model
with bytes from a malware system
and ask it what bytes or what
feature should I change, and I
you know I I change those bytes
on disk, well at worst I've
totally broken the PE file
format. And at at best I've
broken what the malware was in-
was intended to do. So two
things, requires full knowledge.
You have to know everything
about a deep learning mode and
um the samples it generates are
not necessarily malware in fact
are not necessarily PE files. So
kind of cooler attack that's
based on a black box so it
doesn't need to be deep
learning, it can be any sort of
machine learning model that
reports a score to you. Has been
investigated by my
co-researchers at the University
of Virginia and essentially it's
based on genetic algorithms and
just in a nut shell, you know
these are based on the
evolutionary principles of
survival of the fittest and I
start with uh uh a big batch of
malware and um and sort of breed
it with benign ware. So elements
of a malicious sample will will
take structures or elements in
this case for for PDF malware.
And it will insert elements
randomly. Mutate sort of the the
DNA of the malware and uh pass
it back to the the machine
learning model and if I see that
this decreasing it's score, well
then I'm gonna keep that malware
sample around for the next
round. The the next generation
of of breeding. And um after
doing this ya know for two weeks
you can evade these kind of
classifiers. Now the the
difficulty of this however, two
things, I have to have a model
that reports a score. It has to
give me a number between zero
and one. Not just malicious or
benign, it has to say, 90
percent malicious or 20 percent
malicious, right? And secondly,
um there in this process, it's
very possible, quite possible
that some mutated variant of
malware actually doesn't co-
doesn't do the malicious
behavior. So uh my colleagues at
University of Virginia have used
um a sandbox in Oracle to make
sure that before mutation and
then after mutation that
behavior is not changed. And
that can be quite expensive and
is why why this kind of attack
can take so long. So I'm setting
the stage here, I hope you
realized, uh I'm trying to paint
a picture by why this is hard
for PE malware to attack machine
learning, uh we want to avoid
requiring full knowledge about
um, you know a deep learning
model or any other kind of model
in fact we don't want to care
what kind of model we're
attacking or even that it is a
machine learning model. Secondly
we want to make sure that
whatever malware we produce by
attacking this model maintains
file format and maintains
functionality. And thirdly, we
don't want to, we want to avoid
the the expenses of running
things through a sandbox to to
to check to see if they are uh
where possible. So our goal is
to de- design an AI buzz word in
the title but true. Design an
artificially intelligent agent
that will learn to byte, it will
play a game against your machine
learning model. Um it will it
will choose mutations that are
known to preserve file format
and function and uh for this
we're gonna turn to
reinforcement learning and to do
that I'm gonna hopefully not
insult your retro childhood or
or current retro lifestyle and
explain to you the game of Atari
Breakout in uh two sentences. So
this is a game where you uh move
a paddle left to right and um
you you hope to to bounce a ball
with your paddle and uh make it
launch towards a brick and every
time you knock down a brick um
you you get a you get a reward
for for knocking down that
brick, right? So um how would I
build an AI agent for this based
on machine learning? Well one
way to do that that has been
done by the folks at open AI is
to wrap it in so called uh a
reinforcement learning
framework. And it's actually
really simple. So I've got a a
screen shot from my you know my
environment that includes the
display of the Atari uh output.
It includes an ability to
manipulate the paddle left to
right or do nothing and there's
some scoring mechanism. It gives
me a reward every time I know
down a brick. And then I train
an agent, on the on the bottom
side. And here the agent learns
through some sort of delayed
feedback. So given a state of
the environment which is
literally like a screenshot of
the of Atari game place, where
it supposedly can learn the
position of the ball and of the
bricks and of the paddle, it
needs to choose the best action.
Choose to left or choose to
right. And based on that
eventually it may re- receive
some sort of reward for for
doing an an action that resulted
in in a a reward. So um the the
basic idea here is after playing
thousands and thousands of
games, then the agent can learn
and answer the question, you
know, what action is most useful
given a screenshot from Atari
game play. So this is uh a fun
problem and is, you can actually
go and download uh an AI for
Atari for from that website at
open AI that will be better than
you at Atari Breakout. Um we're
gonna change this to play a new
game. Let me first describe to
you the why we we've wrapped
this in uh reinforcement
learning. So in the Atari
example, when I move my paddle
right there is no reward for
that, I get no points, right?
But I move it again right by by
chance um move it left you know
by chance, move it right and and
by some stroke of luck the ball
bounces of my paddle, again no
points. I move right again but
eventually that ball goes and
breaks a break and I get some
point. Now in isolation, none of
these moves were actually useful
and resulted in a reward, but
because I got this sort of
eventual reward for all of my
moves, I'm gonna distribute and
I'm gonna sort of reward that
sequence of actions as having
provided some kind of useful
benefit. And so this is the same
things, this this very same
concept we're gonna use to break
next-gen AV. So here's the new
game. Instead of a screenshot of
Atari uh Atari pixels, we'll
have a malware sample. The
scoring mechanism will be my
next-gen AV. It will give me a
score uh sorry instead of a
score it's going to say, yes, I
believe you're malware or no, I
believe you're benign ware. And
the agent now will learn to
select from a buffet of options
that are known to preserve the
file format and the function of
the malware by manipulating
static the binary and disk. And
by playing thousands and
thousands of games, the hope is
that that uh the agent can sort
of, sort of learn like basic
ideas that given this kind of
malware sample I should um add
an import or I should append to
the overlay or I should um you
know I should create a new entry
point and use a trampoline to
get to the old entry point.
Things like that that can sort
of hide the the presence of
malicious activity by sort of
creating camouflage in the
binary. So we are releasing a
tool um to to do this and you
can go to uh GitHub endgame inc
gym malware and download some
very rudimentary code to do just
this. Um we have provided the
following sort of uh the the
following elements of this game
play. This literally is a gym
that can be used in the open AI
framework for creating your own
reinforcement learning agent.
And we provided some uh some
some very basic ones in there to
begin with. But it works like
this. So in the case of Atari
the state was a screenshot. In
our case the state will be a
feature vector that sort of
summarizes poorly, but you know,
uh coarsely the the state of the
malware. So what is what is the
malware look like that that I'm
using to attack the the next-gen
AV. That's that feature vector
is based on you know, general
file information, header info,
section characteristics,
imported strings uh file byte
and file entropy. Things
actually that are often used in
in uh static malware
classification by next-gen AV.
Now we're gonna feed that into a
neural network that will learn
this uh state, so given this
state what's what's my best
action. The actions that I can
choose, right now we've included
just you know our buffet has
just a few options. I can uh
create an entry point, create
session, I can add um add bytes
in places that don't break the
file format. Uh or
functionality. Or modify things
that are not know, so you know
these um item potent operations
of of uh packing and unpacking
don't change the behavior of the
malware, but change how it is
presented to a to a malware
classier. And we're using the
the very cool tool called uh
LIEF, the library to uh
instrument execute formats by
Quarkslab, so shout out to them.
And um finally, we are also you
know included in this free pose
is sort of a toy next-gen AV you
know, it's a decent toy. It's
worth while to attack and see
how it performs. Um the key here
is that this game doesn't care
what you put in that black box.
It could be our toy model, you
could rip it out put in your own
next-gen AV model. It could be a
traditional antivirus agent or
whatever. At the end of the day
you just have to retro fit it so
that it will report a zero or a
one. One for malicious. Zero for
benign. Alright so let me just
demonstrate how this worked on a
on a a some samples here, but uh
first, just to drive home how
hard this is, you know, I have
the agent has a very incomplete
state of of the world. The the
malware he inspects into a
feature vector that is that is
and and not at all perfect, um,
uh he uh his actions are are
still caustic in nature. So for
like Atari game play I can say
move right, but I don't know how
far the paddle's gonna move
right. There's a similar thing
here, I'll say add an import,
but it's going to choose
randomly from a list of known
benign imports. So there's this
random nature and um and further
right I know nothing about the
model I'm attacking. So this
might be a little bit like you
trying to um solve um you know a
maze, or traverse a maze without
a map and wearing kaleidoscope
glasses and um and while
intoxicated, which which I
probably described a lot of your
day jobs. I don't know, but.
This is a really really
difficult problem. Nevertheless
we hope that we can we can
learn. So uh, you can probably
can't see this. I'm gonna dist-
whoa. I can hardly see that, so
what I'm showing here, this is
the output and and I two
examples at at first the model
is just total totally guessing
at random and getting no where.
And after I wait for several
minutes, the model through his
exploration process catched a
lucky break and he creates a new
entry point which evades the
machine model on that malware
sample and he updates how he
learns to evade that model. And
by getting lucky enough many
many times over tens of
thousands of games, then you
know, with this sort of
rudimentary model that we put in
place, um we can begin to learn
to break next-gen AV. So here
are the results. In one minute.
Uh given a batch of malware
samples, that neither the agent
nor the model have ever before
seen, we could modify those
samples with our agent that has
learned to play the game against
the next-gen AV. And 60 percent
of those snuck past.
Furthermore, do you remember
how, I don't necessarily have to
attack your model? To bypass a
different model? We uploaded
those samples to virus total
both the pre-modification and
the post-modification.
Pre-modification, 35 out of 62
caught those samples. After our
agent got a hold of them uh
there were 10 additional
antivirus engines that whiffed
on those malware samples. So
that's pretty cool um we also
ran sort of random mutations. We
want to make sure our agent was
learning something and not just
getting lucky all the time. So
we did the lucky experiment and
you know it turns out lucky is
pretty good to, but we uh the
agent's about 50 percent than
lucky. Alright, we're done. The
summary is this. You can go to
GitHub end game inc. gym malware
and try this game for yourself
uh no knowledge of the target
model is needed. Will manipulate
raw binaries and produce new
binaries this world has never
seen. Um some fraction of which
may evade your machine model. I
hope that people contribute and
make it better. We use these
things at end game to help
Harden our models. Um stepping
back a moment, it turns out that
machine learning is actually
fully robust, even under direct
attack, the machine learning
models warded off most of these
attacks. Nevertheless, all
models have blind spots. So
don't buy into the hype. And
with that. Thank you. [applause]