>> Um, so back in February
basically, I wrote er a
decompiler because everybody was
talking about ethereum. Ah, I
wish I’d bought, er, coins
instead. I would have made more
money out of it. So, just to
give you a quick introduction,
um, if you don’t follow me
already on Twitter this is my
handle, I’m also the organizer
for a conference in Dubai. I
didn’t come to Vegas since 2011.
I took a Vegas break. No, it’s
okay I’m fine coming back again.
Um, and my new claim to fame is
to have been called a ‘fun guy’
by er the ShadowBrokers.
So [laughs] so just so you know
er, I won’t be talking about
what, like blockchain is, Merkle
Trees is um, er all those things
and er we’re going to focus on
Smart - Contracts, er how to
decompile them as er Windows
reverse engineering. I thought
it was interesting to analyze
like the er VM itself. And um,
I’m also using a tool which is
going to be open source, so, I’m
going to give the link at the
end, and er, yeah, and of course
the tool is not perfect so
you’re more than welcome to
contribute and er and give like
pull request. Um, just like a
short overview of what we are
going to be talking about today.
We going to be talking about the
EVM, its memory management, ah,
or we can do like type discovery
which er is important, er
especially with er many like
static analyzers but also like
if you’re building a decompiler
obviously or, it can be used for
like static and dynamic
analysis, um and the known type
of er class of bugs we know of
so far, and what to expect in
the future. So, how many of you
are familiar with er Solidity,
er please raise your hand. So,
basically er, Solidity is er the
decompiler for Ethereum so the
way Ethereum works is like to
execute the Smart-Contracts is
basically like a software layer
on top of the blockchain. So as
a user compiler of Solidity
which is translating er code
which is er written in a
JavaScript like format into
bytecode. Um, and Porosity’s the
tool I’m going to be describing
today and releasing. Um, so, if
you’re familiar with like
chemistry and physics, it is the
exact opposite of solidity. Um,
hence um the name. So, so far
like there is a lot of high
counts on Ethereum, there’s like
millions of them and if you look
at the actual number of er
contract accounts, er it’s
almost one million - probably
it’s like one million by now.
But the actual number of
verified contract is very small.
And the definition of er, what’s
a verified contract is very
obscure, um but basically it
comes down to if the source code
is provided, um so when it comes
down to reverse engineering,
like usually don’t care if you
have the source or not, but it’s
interesting that since this
software layer has been
introduced with Ethereum ah, we
see like a need for reverse
engineering. Um, and especially
since Ethereum introduce a
concept of ICO, to leverage the
use cases for Smart-Contracts
we’ve heard a lot of stories
since the beginning of the
month. I think here I’m
mentioning like two, but I think
three different stories happened
this month, including er, one
with er CoinDash. Er, which is
like the first one. Someone
changed like the address where
it received the funds and most
recently, er Parity which is a
project, um, started by um, one
of the key developer of
Ethereum. Er, at a vulnerability
with one of their Smart-Contract
and thirty million got lost and
few days back something happened
with, I don’t know, their ICO
and ten million vanished. Um, so
that’s basically what happened
when you like writing software
to store money but don’t have
proper security checks. Um,
small damaging then a blue
screen of death, it’s like a
wallet of death. But er, so, the
EVM, so the Ethereum Virtual
Machine, um so for like each, um
like you have three concepts:
Accounts, contracts and
blockchain which are
interchangeable. Um, even like
for a person like me the
difference is like quite obscure
but I’m mainly focus on the
actual bytecode which is stored
on the actual blockchain, so a
Smart-Contract it is basically a
synonym, in more fancy word for
bytecode. And it’s stored inside
the blockchain and um it uses
(one sixty) 160-bits addresses
and addresses correspond to an
account. And one of the
specificity or so of the
Ethereum virtual machine is that
use like (two fifty six)
256-bits registers. Um, but they
don’t really have like registers
like you would know in
traditional infrastructures,
like F eight six for instance,
so I like this concept of
virtual stack. Um, the more you
look at it, the more you see
like it was kind of their trying
out different things, still like
the outcome is pretty good, but
if you going to be like, going
to be like a virtual machine,
you know, a lot of the things
are a bit, er, a bit shaky. Um,
so for those who are not
familiar with Solidity, it’s
basically what it looks like um,
on the left that’s a simple
like, um coin contract so it’s
very simple, usually you have
few returns, some storage
memory, um and even like the
instructions themselves um are
like quite straightforward. You
do like many, um, you store like
um, an integer, you do
subtraction, addition er, that’s
pretty much it. So, er like the
level of complexity of a
contract is um, very far away
from the complexity of a kernel
driver, per se. Um, then you
compile it using Solidity and
then you get like all that
bytecode, which is going to end
up on the er actual, er,
blockchain. And at the same time
you compile, it also saves the
um, interface which is going to
be used for like um, all the
Smart-Contracts to like to call
that, er, specific contract. So,
we’re getting the memory
management. So you’d have like
three different type of memory,
um that are significant. So the
first one is the the stacks that
I was mentioning before, um like
under traditional architecture
you would use like the stack to
push arguments, at least with F
eighty six, with 264-bit
architectures, you would use the
stack to push arguments to a
function. So, here you push
arguments to opcodes and then
there is like a limited size to
the actual stack which is, um,
one thousand twenty four
elements, and then you would
have like two type of storage so
like a Persistent one um which
is designed er, as it name says
to retain data and another one
er which is like more volatile,
that you can identify easily
from the instructions. So, the
volatile one is interesting
because it’s basically what we
would use to like store strings
um, but even if you look at it,
the way it’s done it’s a little
bit dirty but it does the job.
Like I was saying,
Smart-Contracts are like very,
er, er, simple, very simple per
design. So, if you do a static
or dynamic analysis, um control
flow graph and especially if you
write a decompiler, one of the
most important thing to
understand is the actual like
control flow of your program.
Um, so the first thing we need
to know, is basically or to
identify basic blocks. Um, so I
guess in that case, with
Smart-Contract, it’s so much
easier than a traditional
architecture. Um, because it’s
not hard, this concept, of
confiscation um, and everything
don’t really exist yet with
Smart-Contracts, er for sure we
expect them in the future, but
it’s not like um present yet.
So, in most of cases the start
instruction is called JUMPDEST,
which is indicating like the
beginning of a new block, um in
most of cases, I’d say like
eighty five per cent of them, um
you’d have this instruction at
the beginning of each block and
then you have a bunch of
different instructions, er, for
like conditional jumps, so very
traditional jumps. Um, the
difference with traditional um
architecture, like you’re on X
eighty six for instance, er
you’d have your opcode and then
your destination, right? In the
same, em, in the same opcode.
Um, whereas, like here, they
first push it on the stack and
then execute the opcode for the
that. Um, but the main
difference is, sometimes you
just going to push it at the
beginning of the function to a
bunch of instructions. So you
would like totally forget which
er, was like the destination
address. So that’s why you’d
have to write the pseudo
[inaudible] that you would have
to emulate most of the
instruction to keep track of all
the destinations. And, er,
basically it one of the main
limitation of static analysis of
Smart-Contracts also as like
most of it could be done er
statically. Bust because of
those like weird scenarios where
like the destination is stored
beforehand, um, you have to like
emulate like certain basic
blocks in order to like keep,
um, the er, destination of er,
the basic block. Um, for stack
manipulations there is basically
like a few instructions where
you have duplicate, SWAP and er
POP and PUSH. It’s pretty
straight forward. Um, when it
comes to the actual opcodes of
Ethereum, you can have different
um categories, so obviously the
main one is for like arithmetic
functions, um, um, it’s mainly
designed to deal with money to
store, to create like wireless
for transactions. Which makes
sense, right? And then you have
like the block environments and
the environmental informations,
where you would have information
like the sender, the person
receiving it and then you have
all the memory, um related
operation plus logging
operations to keep track of
certain events. So, like I was
saying before, the main thing
here, er just as an example,
where basically like opcodes are
more like functions because you
need to push the arguments on
the virtual stack. Um, so here,
um, you find that addition you
would push the two valuables
that you want to add, then you
would retrieve the arguments,
not in the register, but in the
first item of the actual stack.
Um, so that would come like that
if you would write it in a EVM
pseudo code um, and then you
have like um EVM calls, so those
are like pretty interesting ,
they allow you to like call a
different contract, um you have
multiple types of calls. You
have the regular code, also like
delegate call which is what has
been abused like recently in the
Parity, um contract. Um, which
is also interesting from the
perspectives that basically you,
call like third party libraries
that you don’t necessarily own.
Um, so this is also an
interesting context, um so it
leaves a lot of um,
opportunities for undefined
behavior and um when it comes to
um, static analysis, dynamic
analysis, or even like trying to
define your scope, um once it
creates a lot of issues. Um
there are like four exceptions
for like out coded contracts
including for SHA2 to identity
function and er for RIPEMD
functions. So like the er,
contract addresses are like one,
two three and four. So whenever
you look at the actual bytecode,
you would, um, notice like those
static addresses. Um, so when it
comes down to user defined
functions that are exportable by
default by each Smart-Contract,
you would easily recognized how
many parameters they have based
on the call data load
instruction which is basically
reading the um, um, environment
information block which is
basically, um, like like a like
a buffer contents or the inputs
parameter including the hash of
the function we want to execute.
Um, so the structure of that,
um, block is pretty straight
forward. Like the first four
bytes, would be the hash method
of the actual er, function which
we are going to describe later.
And then it would be followed by
the arguments. So, if you look
at the actual like pseudo code
here, so basically, if A and B
are being recovered and the
first parameter is the actual
offset inside the block, um and
then for the addition, um that’s
what you would get. So, that
function is like very simple -
so it’s an addition, right, um,
but it’s basically what it would
look like in a pseudo EVM, um,
code. So, when it comes down to
type discovery, um the main type
you will see, the main type you
want to recognize, er are
addresses. So, if this is like
the address of the er, sender,
this destination of the wallet
of another contract. Um so it
will be um uncoded one sixty
bits, right? And most of the
time, every time you need ah,
something which is not on two
fift- two fifty six bits, you
will see a hand operation, so in
most cases you will see like, in
some cases you gonna see it like
out coded, but in most of cases
you going to see like some EVM
assembly, like um, optimization
, like here, the following one
where it’s using like er, it’s
computing like the mask
dynamically. Um, so there is
like few of them that we can
recognize like very easily. And,
again, like er, if we do like
type discovery while emulating
the code, we would actually, um
we would even be actually able
to just check the mask
associated to the instruction.
Um, so now, that we have seen
all EVMs is kind of working. Um,
let’s talk about the bytecode.
Now, so you can have two
different categories, so you can
have like the Pre-Loader code
and which is going to be in
charge of copying the actual
Smart-Contract where like all
the interesting stuff is, er
inside the executable memory and
then, which is er, basically the
Runtime code of the contract.
And then, um, so the runtime
code, which is basically what we
want to analyze, contains all
the information that we want to
ask, spend the time on, so it
would contain, er, the whole
class, the whole contract so
each function. And which is
basically like the er, what had
been produced by the uh solidity
compiler. Um, so this is what
the actual like pre-loader looks
like, so there is instruction,
code called CODECOPY which is
basically taking charge of like
taking the actual bytecodes of
the contracts that we need to
put it inside the executable
memory. So we can, er, execute
it after at the offset zero. Em,
once we enter inside the actual,
er, Smart-Contract there is like
a dispatcher, which is in charge
of, em, splitting all the
different functions. So the way
it works is basically like giant
switch instruction, so it would
first like recover the hash
method from the code data load
instruction and from that, um,
so here you can see em, when the
code optimization is basically
just like first reading two
fifty six bit register. And
then, from that it would like
er, apply a mask to any extract
the first four bytes. So, that’s
basically like the hash method.
And then you enter in a switch
statement, which on each switch
statement is corresponding to an
actual function. Um, in some
cases you gonna also have a fall
back function, so for each, er
so if there’s an unknown method
which is not recognised by the
Smart-Contract, it will just
executor method by default. Er,
some in cases, um, like in the
case of the Parity contract,
which is, which is what we are
going see after also, so um, it
redirects like a call blindly to
another contract. Um, well it’s
not the kinds of things you’ll
see it not doing, you know,
people will start to freak out
to be honest. But that’s
something that seem normal to
some people writing
Smart-Contract. Um,some of those
things, to be honest, seem
obscure. Like, er, I don’t
really understand why you would
have a fall back function, so I
mean, I understand why they did
it, because of like this thing
like they want contracts to be
like backward compatible and
forward compatible, but the
source of so much problem, like
er, by design, if you think of
security. it doesn’t make sense
to be honest. So, um, function
hashes, um the way I compute it;
basically take the function name
and the parameter of each
argument, and then er, just like
stick them together and compute
the share free, um of that um,
impute. And the result of the
first four bytes would basically
be the hash method. So, it’s
pretty straightforward, um so um
if you have like the um ABI, so
the actual interface of the
contract, um, you can easily
like recompute it. Um, but if
you don’t from the actual switch
function, you like just extract
the actual like hash method, um
from the um runtime code and you
can create um, um like a name of
the fly, like you would do like
with either way you just give
like um a sub-function with the
actual offset of the function
when you don’t have symbols. So
like with the ABI, justifies the
equivalent of symbols for
Smart-Contracts. Um, here is the
instruction I was mentioning
where we basically extract the
four bytes. Um, and then um,
that’s like the pseudo code for
it. So here is a compare reason,
if you purely do like static
control flow, um like our
reconstruction, um you try to
emulate, you can see in some
cases, er, you really need to
emulate the code to keep track
of all the actual like
destination, um and pointers.
Um, so that will be like a
simple contract where you would
have like two functions, um,
which is here. So, once you can
start to analyze the actual like
runtime code from that, um, like
I was saying, it’s basically
like a giant switch, each case
of the switch is basically a
function for it. Um, and then
once we decompile it, we get
something closer to what’s on
the er, right of the screen. Um,
to go into it in detail, um the
runtime code. So here, for
instance, the double functions.
In yellow we have actual hash of
that function, then it’s going
to jump to the offset like at
twenty four. Um, which is marked
with the JUMPDEST instruction.
And then it’s pushing, um the
um, argument two, then we arrive
in a new block, so here in that
case, there is like a JUMPDEST
but it’s not in the new basic
block, but it’s used by another
function , it’s a shared basic
block. And then you going to do
just like the multiplication and
something with the tripper, we
going to see is going to read
something again like the impute
parameter sha3 and then execute
like the multiple instruction.
So, if we go back to like the
initial source code of it, um,
it’s basically what it was
doing, um it was pretty
straightforward. So if we use
Smart-Contract that, I wanna
say, like way more complex than
that, but more complex than
this. It was basically to
illustrate how easy you can
decompile the actual code. Um,
if we look at the, er, bug I was
mentioning before, this is the
Parity Bug that happened like a
week ago. Um, remember when I
was talking like before, it was
like a different call, you have
like a call, it allow you to
call like a third party
contract, um, and then in some
cases you have like um, a fall
back function that allows you to
execute a contra- um like
execute code if the method is
unknown. So,um , here, like the
address, um in the constrictor
the address was opcoded and, um
you know it’s green, it’s
computing the actual hash method
dynamically, and then the code
is going to execute that
specific function. And then for
some random reason you ad, er,
like a fall back function, that
was basically like allowing you
to call any function inside the
wallet library and to pass
function or parameter you want.
So, this is why I was saying,
like some concept obscure,
basically like the er, actual,
er, reason for the
vulnerability. So obviously, now
looking at it it, it’s obvious,
but that’s a new type of bugs
that have been er, discovered by
the architecture. That’s, er, a
pretty good find. Now once you
know the type of bug it’s
pretty, it’s pretty obvious. Um,
so like those fall back
functions, so if you have like a
switch with executing code with
er no actual hash, so that’s
what your fall back function
would be, um, so I mean then
it’s a design issue, right? So
the main reason for that it is -
keep in mind, so it’s adding
like a software layer to the
blockchain, right? Um, but also
means that if there’s a security
bug in it, while you cannot
patch blockchain, right? That’s
the main thing about it’s like
retaining data, moving it
around. Um, that’s the main
reason.From reading about it,
it’s backward and forward
compatibility. Because of this
lack of capability, to apply
patches, um to be honest it does
not make sense. I think it’s
stupid, but, er, whatever. Um,
it’s not like you can design a
language which is verifiable
because you have like too many
unknowns, if you like start
calling libraries you don’t even
know what’s it going to be
called. You have to predict all
contracts, all er, future
contracts, and like imagine if
your kernel would be doing the
actual same thing, that would be
nuts, you’ll see people rioting
in the streets, you know? Well,
I hope so. Um, so the actual way
that bug was fixed was basically
like some of the function where
the design to be prevent
function. um, so when it was
able to em, call the library
again directly, any function,
the actual constrictor. Um, it
could even recall the actual
constrictor because it will not
even check if it was initialized
or not. So this is the type of
bug you would see in
Smart-Contracts. It’s very far
away from the er, classical bugs
you would see with buffer
overflow and everything. Um,
there is another example of er
like er vulnerable contracts.
So, that’s similar to what
[inaudible] was using. So like
here the vulnerability was
basically here, um, it’s similar
to a Race Condition so basically
same thing - it comes down to
like a fall back function being
reused. So, er, that would
create a Race Condition, where
like the balance would not be
initialized on time. Um, so for
that type of vulnerabilities,
the good thing is, because there
is not many instructions, you
can like tag each basic block to
see what they are doing. And
every time there is a call with
an external contract, you will
track at as either a warning or
as a neuro so in that case, um
we could see that the SStore
instruction was being used
after. So, it would like be easy
to analyze. Um, going to show
you a quick demo. So, um, that’s
um, that’s um, like the actual
Smart-Contract itself. Er, so,
so to call the tool you can
basically provide the you only
need to provide like the actual
bytecode. Um, if you have like
this symbol, so like the ABI
file you can just pass it. And
then you just like run the two
[pause] and once you give it a
name to the tool you can easily
reconstr- reconstruct something,
er, very close to a the, er,
actual source code, so And if
you had some like features,
because to build a compiler you
basically build everything you
need for dynamic analysis and
also static analysis we can
easily, easily um, oh I didn’t
see the title there, that’s cool
um, you easily like use it to
track potential vulnerabilities,
just like you would have with
most of compilers now when your
prefast or per visual studio er,
you have a lot of like static
analysis tools that can be used.
Um, whenever you are writing
code, right, so, now if you look
at like the actual
Smart-Contract community, um
they are still like building all
those tools, it’s something very
new so a lot of the tools that
we would find pretty obvious
with GCC, your visual studio
compiler are not present for,
er, those type of software. Um,
so because like the whole
concept was to introduce a
software layer to it, but it
comes without a lot of testing
tool, um which would be required
for enterprise softwares. Um, so
so far a few um, class of bugs
that have been detected. So the
first one was like the Race
Condition USD DAO, then Call
Stack Vulnerability, um there’s
some good papers about it where
er, like I was saying before,
the virtual stack is limited and
when you use all of it, um, it’s
not even returning an exception
and for a while some issues with
like returning exceptions,
reverting like a state of a
contract as well as like
concepts that are very new, have
been introduced recently. Um,
Time Dependency vulnerability -
while some of the actual like
um, instruction give you like
some time information with the
ability to block, um, so you can
easily like get get call with
what happened with the parateer
contract. Um, so there is a fork
of Ethereum called Quorum
created by J.P. Morgan which is
um pretty interesting. The main
reason people were a bit worried
or so with Ethereum was
basically um, um if you are an
enterprise you can’t just have
everything like return like
transparently, so they
introduced this privacy layer,
and er, permissions to our
Smart-Contracts which is pretty
cool. Um, like the Quorum team
is here, so I don’t know if you
guys want to stand up? If people
are going to see?But er, that’s
a pretty cool project. We see a
lot of stuff happening, um
around like Ethereum, which is
pretty cool and, er, this week
like er, Quorum just released
um, [inaudible] to Porosity
which check like nodes inside
the actual network. So, that’s
pretty cool too. And like I was
saying, the main thing, which is
a bit worrying, and what we er
hear many like er, stories about
the er ICO’s hack, and why for
sure we’re going to see more of
those stories of the summer is
mainly because there is no
proper like testing tools for
that new like software layer -
which is pretty nuts, you know?
You, you guys have seen how long
it took for traditional software
to get like proper security
tools Um, er, to be tested, even
like, er Azure stuff, this tye
of like high level framework,
um, while we’ve -
Smart-Contracts is pretty much
ground zero, I’ve never heard of
it in most cases, which is why
there’s a need for search tools.
Um, here is some like screenshot
of the current Porosity
integration. So, then it can be
integrated in the actual
workflow, um, which is um pretty
good at least to think of
integrating, um, tools like
that, um in the actual workflow.
It was very fast for the actual
Quorum team to do the
integration, um, they have a
pretty good framework so they
can like really add more and
more tools very quickly. It’s
pretty good and, in my opinion,
it’s a requirement if people are
going to start really using
Smart-Contracts especially to
store money. Um, again, like if
you write a Smart-Contract, most
of the time you’ll use it to
store money, right, not to
browse YouTube and watch cat
videos um, I mean, yeah. You
know if you find like a zero day
like in a web browser, then you
would have to struggle to where
to send it. While if you found a
bug in a Smart-Contract, you
just like take the bank, you
know? It’s like being Lazarus
Group, but for crypto currency.
Um , so like I was saying, for
sure we will see more and more,
um tests, um, testing tools and
like we can definitely expect by
the end of the year issues like
ICO’s hack, since like it’s like
a new thing, everyone wants to
like raise money with ICO’s um,
we’re getting the tools also -
so like some improvement
required for like um, um fall
out of the conditional statement
and um when it comes to Ethereum
and security, like I was saying,
there is like a fast growing
community, especially like the
main incentive is, why either
you want to steal money or you
want to protect your money,
right? So it’s pretty
straightforward in term of, er,
motives if you want to get into
like Smart-Contract security.
Um, and like I was saying, when
I initially looked at it, I was
like, why is everybody talking
about blockchain, it sounds like
really boring, um, then I saw
like some virtual machine
around, ah maybe there’s some
interesting thing to do. And,
for those who are like familiar
with virtual machine
vulnerabilities, um well QMUs
has a lot of them, but then you
have like, you know like talks
like CLOUDBURST that like
happened many years ago, um, I
think it was Black Hat 2010 or
something, um, where basically
you would be able to do a VMS
escape, and now VMS escape are
becoming more and more common,
even like Microsoft with their
IP vulnerability would be
raising their bug bounty. Um
well you can be sure if you have
your own virtual machine you can
also expect bugs in it, right?
Um, then the whole thing of
claiming it’s sandbox does not
really apply. Um, so the
question now is: Is Ethereum
going to stay alive and if their
virtual machine is going to be
the main virtual machine, or if
we’re going to select more
providers for Smart-Contracts
with their own virtual machines?
Um , I was looking at the
roadmap for next year and I saw
there are, um planning to use
WebAssembly. Um, I had no idea
what was WebAssembly, and then I
looked into it and basically, um
so it’s being described, it’s
portable low time efficiency
format, so have like your own
bytecode um, that can be
executed by most of the
JavaScript engine like V8 or
Spidermonkey, er, and so they’re
planning to use a VCM engine
that will send your browser to a
Smart-Contract, um I don’t know
if it’s good, I guess from the
fact that it’s also going to be
used by all the platforms, it
will also benefit of the
auditing of that specific
language. And in terms of
performance, I’ve seen some good
stuff. Like if you look at the
er demos online, the guys are
like running almost like video
games with V8’s they can like
almost make compile. I don’t
know if it’s a good thing or
not, but you can like compile
like code, C++ code into like
WebAssembly, um for an interface
it seems a bit confusing to go
from like, I think a VM with a
specific set of instruction to
like being able to compile C++,
um, so I don’t know to which
extent it’s going to be used in
the Ethereum VM by next year,
um, but for sure we would see
like stuff, um leveraging that.
Um, there were some people I
wanted to thank, worked with me
during the paper, so um
including like the DefCon review
board, because er, initially I
was just like sending the
decompilers, - um, can we use it
for security? I was like well,
it’s a decompiler, so you can do
anything. So they kinda pushed
me to do a security analysis for
it. Um, so if you want to
download like the slides and the
actual white paper, which is
more complete, and, um, in case
you didn’t understand my French
accent, which I can understand
but bit what I can say? I’m
French, no, not going to
apologise but er, you can
download via the actual tool and
the rest and yeah, if you have
any question, you can either
drop me an email or we have
free minutes now so I don’t know
how it works for like Q&A here?
But er, yeah if you have any
question, let me know.
[applause]