>>Okay so I wanted to welcome
you all to Def Con 25 I'm really
curious, show of hands, I know
it's not perfect but this hotel
compared to Paris Bally's, who
likes this one better? [crowd
cheers] okay I'm glad you like
it 'cause we're here next year
[laughs] [cheering continues] If
you didn't like it I don't know
what I would have done. And I
I'm told that the escalators
will be fixed by next year so
[laughter and cheers] Um so
before we get going I just wanna
start acknowledging um a lot of
the hard work a lot of us went
through to- to make this event
happen um and some of you might
have seen a tweet about the- the
drama we had with the bean bags,
these are the last two surviving
bean bags, right near, the
others have been kidnapped or
'bean' napped or something um so
he's gonna take this bean bag
swirl it over his head and throw
it into the audience on this
side and uh just to give you a
heads up I don't want a lawsuit
so somebody on this side will be
the proud owner of a bean bag
and uh somebody on this side
will be the proud owner of a
bean bag [cheering] here we go-
and this is to- this'll be the
second year that we have had all
of our bean bags disappear
[laughter] go for it! No you're
gonna throw em, you're closer to
the uh the people. [cheering]
[speaker laughs] [crowd cheers]
Oh right on! Okay Paul, yeah go
for it. Yeah let's see how far
you can hurl the- [crowd cheers]
[applause] So some of you might
have noticed that we weren't up
to our normal standard of super
cool badges this year because of
uh an emergency uh with LostboY
which is- we really wish him
good luck and I don't know if
you saw the we uh- 'bring back
Lost' badges that were going
around so I've been talking to
Lost he's- he's he's all in so
don't worry next year we should
be enjoying some masterful Lost
electronic construction
[cheering] so that'll be good.
But it really turned out that um
badge life really became a thing
this year, it really seemed to
be the tipping point and so even
though we didn't have a super
construction other people did
and I really just want to just
call out Def Con 25 I think was
really the birth of this badge
life so that was awesome!
Everybody who's designed a badge
give it up to them. [applause]
It's always tricky every year
because we have, as you know, we
don't do pre registration so we
don't know how many people to
expect, how much to buy, it's
really like uh- a lot of
guessing um and so this year we
completely sold out and we want
to really think swag team
working really hard we- we moved
more inventory on Thursday then
we did on Thursday and Friday
last year so it's just really
worked out to be pretty popular
and of course the shirts we
didn't think would be popular
were popular and vice versa and
uh the speaker control team
really chipped in and helped out
so I just wanna acknowledge how
a lot of these teams work
together and it's just a great
community [applause]. This is
how many goons it takes to pull
of an event this size it takes
us back in world domination
headquarters planning about ten
months out of the year and these
are all the teams that uh manage
and operate the con, there's
over 380 goons to pull this off
so if you're a goon stand up and
let's acknowledge your awesome
[applause] [cheering] Right on.
[applause continues] I wanna see
if you organized a contest, an
event, or a party that any
attendee could enjoy stand up
because you are the ones that
gave us all the enjoyable action
[applause] yeah! Alright and
this being Las Vegas um where
they're very concerned about
safety and security I've just
been informed that the fire
marshall would like us to stay
in our seats [laughs] so we will
now be waving our hands or maybe
like the IETF we'll just snap
our fingers or hum loudly.
[laughter] If you are a goon
that is either a first year goon
or a retiring goon let's just
have you wave your hands
[laughs] Thank you! We try to
make it really easy at Def Con
for people to come and go and so
we try to make it easy for you
to help out and if you get busy
with life or burned out or you
need to move to some other
country and you can't quite
attend it's okay right? People
come and go through Def Con we
try to make it as easy as
possible for people to
contribute when and where they
can contribute and so um I just
would like to thank those- of
those that are retiring I just
want to acknowledge all of their
past contributions because
that's really valuable and it
really helped get us here I mean
we're really on the shoulders of
giants. Also this year the
Hacker Tracker App became
official, it is now an official
Def Con app and we're helping
provide them some support. Okay.
Who here downloaded this thing
and really thought it was
useful? [cheering] Yeah! This is
awesome. We're just going to
keep growing it and we're gonna
do what we can to provide them
support and next year it'll be
just that much better so I think
uh that's really- been really
really cool. Okay so I'm gonna
pass the microphone off we're
going to give you the quick low
down on what's been going on
with NOC this year Luis is gonna
talk about some great new
equipment we had and he'll run
some statistics so Luis
[applause] >>Thanks Jeff! Hello
Def Con 25, it's awesome to be
here. I've been on my phone
because I heard the streaming
was down but now it is up,
thanks VideoMan. [cheering] So
I'm just going to go through
some slides, this is mostly for
a historic purpose and we so you
can download from Def Con
networking dot org later to see
the statistics I'm not going to
go through the whole thing, but
if you don't know what we do
here, the NOC does the whole
wired infrastructure uh which is
listed on your left and then for
most of you what matters is in
the brave and then once they
patch their phones for wifi
vulnerabilities um it's the the
wireless network and this- we're
going to talk a little bit about
this and the DC TV we also do
that um VideoMan and Sarif they
do a great job making it work
and trying to keep it working
that's been the- one of the
challenges we have this year and
we appreciate the patience that
you guys have with us. So a
quick run down on the network um
we have a 10 gig backbone uh
within the hotel uh the hotel is
awesome. The hotel IT and Encore
staff, that is the company that
helps the hotel and us, they
are- I can not express how much
uh we appreciate their jobs so
please give a hand- handout to
them. [applause] As for the gear
that we have I'm not gonna go
through the whole thing, as I
said you can download this
later, but we have a whole bunch
of stuff, we have some
enterprise class stuff and some
non enterpri- enterprise class
things that we make everything
work uh wanna find out the
wireless would mean using a 7210
Aruba Controller and last year
as you can see the- the second
line there we had a whole bunch
of AP models and stuff, this
year we uh Aruba facilitated for
us, seventy five new AP's so
this year we deployed 69 AP's
throughout the convention center
and we had some spot- spotty
coverage and stuff like that but
uh thanks Aruba for helping us
for the long term. [applause] As
for DC TV last year if you
remember or if you download the
presentation from last year we
were using raspberry pis this
year we changed to OIDROIDs And
the number, the odd number there
uh is because we were streaming
to Paris and Bally's which is
gonna be on the issues uh slide
but it's it worked was the first
year um it's gonna get better.
This is our network design we
can look at it later. [laughter]
K [laughter] so DC TV as you
know we had last year was the
first time we were streaming in
H- HD. Uh so we capped that
makes the end- the little
devices that make the conversion
sometimes a little upset and
overheat and lock up but we're
gonna keep doing that it looks
nice. I had a chance to watch a
little bit on my TV uh in the
hotel and we had this year so
five channels here at Caesar's
and four channels at the other
hotels for because of uh
hardware limitations beyond our
control. This is the timeline we
showed up a couple of us on
Saturday start working on Sunday
and for the first time ever by
Wed- Wednesday night we had
everything done. Everything that
was on the list [applause] Then
Thursday shows up and then we
have the last minute requests
that are very uh usual and it's
it's good that we got stuff done
before so we can cater uh those
that are- like room changes
there's there's a lot of things
once we show up on site not only
us from the NOC but everyone
here the- the dynamic is good,
love the dynamic of working with
the other groups- the other goon
groups it's been a great year
for us and now we're on Sunday
we're gonna tear down and
tomorrow we go home and start
planning for next year. Issues,
bandwidth, I love that you guys
use a lot of bandwidth but um
that's one of the issues that we
have and we're gonna try to fix
that in the future, right Jeff?
>>Yes, Oh yes >>Jeff says yes.
And DC TV we have like a
combination of things right?
When we try new things it's very
hard to uh sometimes pinpoint a
problem uh but we worked hard as
I said before, VideoMan and
Sarif they do a great job and I
really appreciate what what what
they do to make sure that this
is going on right? This is going
on the internet right now so for
those that couldn't be here it's
awesome to be able to to send
this information to them and yes
that IP address is from that
movie back in the 90s. Um Wifi
stuff uh amazingly enough like
clients people really like to
jump on the open network and do
bad things or not so good things
and but almost half or more than
half use the the secure network
and we have the wifi reg and
stuff it's very interesting to
see on the destination that
people use, you're still here
and using Facebook. I hope
you're- I hope you're posting
things that you're learning
during the conference. Not gonna
go through the numbers here but
we used um I was lazy and I used
the slides from last year so you
can see that we used a little
bit of inbound traffic we went
up as expected seems we have
more people outbound also a
little bit more but not too much
and the most important part here
was that for the first time ever
we had more than two thousand
users on the wireless at the
same time, so that's pretty
awesome [applause] This is our
team, the break down, we have
twelve people total for doing a
conference this size it's pretty
amazing. Uh shout out to our our
new member of the team uh Nancy
she's awesome she brought a lot
of good energy to the grumpy
guys that we are so that's good.
[applause] and we also invited
Richard Cheese to be a part of
the team but he was busy
preparing for his show. Really
special thanks to Jeff, he
anytime we need to jump on a
call and get stuff resolved, he
helps a lot, Charel, without you
this wouldn't be possible, Will
for getting- buying all the
stuff that we request or almost
all the stuff that we request
but we we work together really
well >>Yeah we had to turn down
the giant electric cat >>yes
[Crowd 'awes'] >>Yeah I know
you. You know I wanna see a
giant electric cat next year you
know >>Yeah! [crowd cheers]
>>Yeah! As I said before
Caesar's IT, Encore you guys are
awesome, Source of Knowledge
that does all the transcoding of
the video that hopefully is
going to the internet since I'm
not checking my phone um the
guys that for the past five, six
years bring us snacks to the NOC
they worked in the NOC or SOC
before they know how good our
lives are. The press goons they
helped us a lot this year so
Melanie and team, thanks so
much, Capitan Obvious from
Caesar's IT we love you uh Micah
from Apple we don't love you
[laugh] The Machine and thanks
for you guys behaving on the
network as much as you can
thanks so much [applause]
>>Sorry I was mesmerized by
those numbers uh let's go to the
next one okay so here are all
the villages we have at Def Con
there's quite a number of them
and if you remember back in the
day when uh Russ Rogers came to
me and he said you know we gotta
do something more than just
having these speaking tracks um
and so he came up with this idea
of the village and then quickly
the very first village you can
see here 10th anniversary
Hardware Hacking Village, they
were the very first one and
they've been keeping it real
ever since, every station was
busy and next year we're going
to grow more stations for them.
Lockpick Village is also in the
10th I don't know why it's not
on here but Lockpick Village is
also on it's 10th anniversary
and Tool and all the volunteers
that make the Lockpick Village
awesome that's just an
incredible learning experience I
remember I was in there and
there's like I don't know twelve
ten year old girl and you could
tell that she was very skeptical
cause her dad was there and kind
of trying to force her to do
something she didn't want to do
she was kind of like messing
around with this lock and then
all of a sudden like the lock
po- it was like a master lock
and her eyes, the lo- the lock
popped open and her eyes are
just like [sound effect] like I
did that? You mean locks are not
secure? You mean I can like take
over the world? [laughs] I was
like mmmm. [Cheering] [laughs]
And that was just like the most
immediate feedback I could watch
her like calculate calculate
calculate it was like her
perception of the world changed
right there and that was thanks
to the villages and this year
there's two new villages that
are joining. When we moved from
Paris Bally's we were just out
of space, we didn't have enough
walls, this year we have more
walls we have smaller spaces
more areas that we can break
people out into and so we added
two villages, the Recon Village
on open source [applause] right
on Recon Village really I mean
you guys were like you were not
a first year you showed up and
were almost feeling like almost
like a third year event that's a
village that was really well
done and the Voting Machine
Hacking Village which was a
runaway success we didn't quite
expect it to be so crazy and it
was crazy by the end of the Con
every voting machine fell and
that's like two and a half days
[applause] So this just kind of
gives you an idea and then I
also want to call out the ICS
village um they weren't here
last year, but they're back this
year having a great time so it's
really nice even when villages
can't make it one year they can
come back we're really welcoming
and so we're constantly on the
lookout for new ideas and we
were gath- we were joking around
earlier getting ready for this
and um and I was saying you know
what you know on Sunday we have
so few people that buy badges
from us on Sunday we should just
close the registration
department and stick the badges
in a vending machine. [laughter]
Vending Machine Hacking Village
[laughs] [cheering] >>Woo!
>>'cause we all need potato
chips. Okay um just some quick
statistics the Data Duplication
Village um near and dear to my
heart um you can see this year
uh we broke last year's record
we've pushed more data. Look in
the lower left hand corner, you
can see the drive types and
their failure rates I don't know
who Mediamax is but they really
need to fix their S***t it's
like 43 percent failure rate,
you know? And it's too bad that
HGST is around 18 perfect
failure rate it's pretty clear
that the best ones are Toshiba
and Western Digital um anyway
the info con stuff is online as
well if you want to download it
I just thought that this
community would like enjoy
statistics >>Yeah! >>[laughs]
Okay so I'm gonna pass it off to
Grifter here for all the events,
contests and parties he's gonna
kind of run through what we've
got and we're going to start
calling out some of the winners.
>>Hey how's it going? >>Woo!
>>Ow! Oh my gosh Def Con bleh!
Um so so this year new venue new
insanity um so thank you to all
of the organizers of villages
events contests that um put up
with well all of our bulls**t um
and and figuring out the new
space uh genuinely we thank you
uh so as far as events um we
have we have a lot of return
events here where we have
friends of Bill uh Be The Match
all those guys came back I think
um hacker karaoke thought for a
minute they weren't an event
somehow like a message got lost
somewhere and then three weeks
ago when we said like oh hey we
still have some more space does
anybody want to do something
they submitted again even though
they'd already been accepted
[laughter] so they were super
stoked uh and it was sick if you
weren't if you weren't at hacker
karaoke this year it was crazy
but thank you to all the event
organizers genuinely we really
had a blast and we appreciate
your efforts. Um so let's get
into contests >>woo! >>woo!
>>That's a lot of contests um so
you guys like to do stuff when
you're here you know no idle
hands right? Uh and here's the
thing though this list is just a
little bit smaller than last
year so we had a couple of
contests that were like for Def
Con 25 we just want to kick it
and we're just gonna hang out
and enjoy the show and so a few
contests that have been around
for awhile um didn't return
which means we have some
openings for contests so please
if you're interested email
contests at defcon dot org let
us know what you wanna do not
today [laughter] like like give
us a little bit. I plan to sleep
for the rest of the week so but
seriously hit us up tell us what
your ideas are um we had- we had
contests this year like the tin
foil hat contest was something
that they just walked up and
said like hey we're like yes!
Over there tin foil hat
[applause] Like it was just one
of those things where we're like
how the hell have we not had a
tin foil contest- hat contest in
twenty five years and they were
like no it will be super simple
they will just make hats and the
best hat wins yeah [laughter]
yeah alright done um So yeah
tons of great contests if you
were in the contest area it was
always hopping obviously we also
have contests that go on the
villages that uh that have a lot
of effort put into them as well
so thanks to them uh and then I
just wanna say to my uh to my
team thank you to my contest
goons I know they're around here
somewhere >>woo! >>Yes, yes
[applause] special- special
thanks to- to Zant and to
Stomper and to Drist uh for- for
handling all the bidness um and
then also I wanna throw out uh a
thank you not just not just like
to the contest folks but also a
special thanks to Nikita sitting
over here Nikita helped
[applause] pull us out of many a
hole this year um also I don't
know, I don't know- I don't know
how many people realize like
Nikita handles every single
submission that comes through
Def Con so if you submit to the
call for papers like she has to
deal with your crap some of it's
crap let's just be honest um but
a lot of it requires feedback
which means that as the review
board asks for questions she has
a dialogue back and forth with
whoever the submitter is and so
we're talking about a thousand
submissions and an additional
hundreds and hundreds of
contacts thereafter so can we
please get a round of applause
for Nikita? [applause]
[cheering] and Nikita's baby
[chuckles] alright that's enough
sit down um Alright let's get
this thing rollin' so here are
our black badge contests uh for
Def Con this year we're gon- so-
we don't announce which contests
are going to be a black badge
contest until essentially this
morning, every Sunday morning,
and here's why, look at that
list. You're not all getting
into Def Con free for life like
I'm sorry it's just- it's not a
thing uh however we we have a
few badges that we give out and
we don't want it to be something
where you know that a certain
contest is gonna have a black
badge and so that's the contest
that everybody focuses on and
maybe a contest that's new or
just starting out gets
completely ignored so at any
point we will decide this
contest is doing a killer job
they're gonna be a black badge
contest even if they have no
idea they're in the running uh
we just pick them out so that
you as attendees will just go do
what you love or go learn
something new and we don't have
to worry about having new
contests that have two people
playing it so just get out there
and play the contest that you're
going enjoy that you'll learn
something from and maybe you'll
get into Def Con free for life.
[applause] [off mic comment]
>>Okay Um also that means that
contests sometimes that do get
black badges may not have one
the next year I just want to
point that out that it doesn't
mean that that contest fell in
quality or anything we just
again we can't give them to the
same people every year so um
before we get to this I'm gonna
let Jeff say a couple of words
about the uber badge so >>Yeah.
Hey so um because we had our
badge construction problem this
year same thing we had a problem
with the uber badge construction
and uber badges are are pretty
awesome and we had like ten days
to create an uber badge which is
pretty difficult to do um and so
we thought we had a great
solution we had this awesome
solution we figured it out it
went to manufacturing we got the
proofs, we validated the proofs,
we approved them, it went to
final production, and it got
shipped out Fedex Saturday
delivery and they checked Fedex
overnight normal. >>Boo! >>So
the uber badges will be here
tomorrow at 10am [laughter] just
in time! And the person who
checked the box wrong realized
it immediately, tried to fix it,
I guess once you've checked that
box you're done it's like a
blood contract you cannot change
your Fedex shipping um so we
have one badge I'm holding it
right here this is the one uber
badge to sh- to tease you to
tease the teams of what they're
going to be getting so what's
going to happen is the team's
win get acknowledged everybody
exits to the left we're going to
record who gets the uber badge
and we're going to send it to
you so hopefully I wanna sh-
hold this and hopefully the
camera can put it on the screens
if we can video switch um can
you switch to me please
[laughter] 'cause this is really
small nope um and then hopefully
people will be able to take
pictures nope? No video
switching? We even talked to you
about this [sighs] [laughter]
Okay so what I'm holding in my
hand [laughter] [cheering] This
is- This is thirteen hundred
dollars of pure gold >>Woo!
>>This is a Def Con 25
serialized gold uber badge with
a platinum metal surround
holding it and they're
individually numbered >>Is there
a Trump on it? >>So it doesn't
say Trump on it no [laughter] um
so I'm gonna just kind of put it
here everybody can like look at
it and drool on it but you will
get your own if you've won a
black badge contest this year so
I'm gonna just put it right here
for everybody to drool over
thank you okay >>Woo! [applause]
>>Yoink! Uh so without further
ado, Social Engineering CTF
>>Woo! Yea! >>I love you Grifty.
Okay so this year social
engineering capture the flag, we
had an amazing turn out we never
had a year like this before, we
had over 250 submissions for the
SE CTF which was crazy and 50
videos uh the 14 people we chose
got given the gaming industry to
keep with the theme of of Def
Con um so we called 2k,
Activision, Blizzard, Bomb Dye,
Bethesda, Disney, EA, Hasbro,
Mattel, Nintendo, RockStar,
Sega, Sony, Ubisoft, and Warner
Brother Games were our targets
for um for the uh CTF we had
three hundred and eighty one
pages of OSINT submitted by our
fourteen contestants in their
three weeks of time doing there
uh gathering our second place
winner which is Rachel Tobek
give her a round of applause
[applause] she >>I'm too short
>>You can lift her up there we
are okay there we go [laughs]
she in her report she got 21 out
of 30 flags uh during her call
she got 28 out of 30 flags she
spent one hundred hours
preparing for the SE CTF from
report writing and and OSINT
just just amazing give her give
her a round of applause
[applause] that's for her Okay
and our first place winner he
spent sixty hours preparing his
get over here Chris Kirsch he
spent sixty hours repar-
preparing his seventy page
report I don't do this for a
living I had to read that
[laughs] okay. Sixty hours on
OSINT he got 28 out of 30 flags
on the report and 21 out of 30
flags in just one call just one
call it was amazing [applause]
good job >>thank you >>good job.
He gets this awesome one in
addition everyone that knows me
knows that I love whiskey so we
had a special bottle of whiskey
from Glenfarclas engraved for
him too so you get that
>>alright >>and of course you
get the oh wow! I know you can't
see that because they can't
switch cameras but that is
beautiful. So there was a black
badge [laughter] no I'm kidding
kidding [laughs] wouldn't it be
cool if I put a fake one there
and actually swiped it? No no-
not cool at all [laughter] okay
I think my two minutes is up
thank you >>Thank you so much!
>>thank you so much it was
awesome >>right on >>Good year,
it was a good year guys thank
you, see you next year!
[applause] >>A few more minutes
of hugging? Yeah >>Yeah yeah
yeah >>A little man >>Just
keeping it weird, just keeping
it weird. Alright uh up next
this is very high alright up
next Crypto and Privacy
Challenge. That's you [laugh]
[applause] >>Hi wow the lights
are bright up here holy crap
[laughs] um wow so first let me
thank DT, Nikita, Zant, and
Grifter who have um been so
wonderful to have the Crypto and
Privacy village for the past
couple years and have dealt with
me being you know the over
organizer so you know herding
cats of hackers has you know
been a thing um but this year we
had a puzzle um at- that was
designed by Straith and Maya and
myself um as well as a badge
that Karl Koscher put together
and we had a puzzle two years
ago and I thought no one's
solving this like why do it
again and three weeks after the
conference a team finished it
and we sent them their prize la-
last year I thought well we do
all this work we're not really
sure anyone is actually solving
this and the team came back and
said where's your puzzle and I
was like errrm like sorry
[laughs] that was cut uh so this
year we designed a puzzle and it
was quite a challenge and the
same team that won our first
year and asked about it our
second year uh won this year and
it is such a pleasure to give
them six of our badges as well
as a black badge um and some
special gold shirts we made for
the winners as well. So thank
you ROT ROT who solved our
Crypto and Privacy Village
challenge [applause] they are
just amazing and the reason like
we went extra to design a puzzle
this year so I'm so glad they
won and um so yes, thank you.
>>Right on [applause] [off mic
chatter] >>Oh man, shiny!
Alright >>You guys can fight
over who gets it >>[chuckles]
yeah, that's the real challenge
[laughter] we're just DT super
trolling the teams this year so.
Uh >>Grifter I love you! >>I
love you two, he whispered
[laughter] Um alright so from
the uh- from the IOT Village,
SOHOpelessly Broken [applause]
>>Thanks again for having us
back, really appreciate being
here and thanks everyone that
came out to play and participate
in our track zero so far we have
tallied a total of 109 new
vulnerabilities, things like
buffer overflow and command
injection and for the actual
black badge contest I will let
Josh announce the stats on that.
>>Hey everyone. Uh so
SOHOpelessly Broken it started
out in 2013 with a coworker of
mine he did a research study
into routers he found that
everything he looked at was
vulnerable to something and he
decided well why not turn it
into a CTF and have it at Def
Con so uh we we've had it since
then and last year was our first
time as a black badge contest uh
so after that we were like oh
how are we going to top
ourselves this year uh but I
think we did a really good job
we had 93 teams compete and over
half of them scored a flag so
good job guys [applause] yeah
give yourself a round of
applause [applause] Um thanks to
everyone who helped out and um
[clears throat] and I'll I'll
announce the winners so third
place we had Team VERT, second
place Team Secarma and first
place the winner of the black
badge team Wolf Emoji [laughter]
[applause] >>Alright they're
going to let me talk into this
microphone, it's crazy. Um Just
want to thank uh Devil's Ivy and
Samba Cry for getting us on the
board and the Mirai Botnet for
uh getting IOT Security in the
you know forefront of normal
people's minds. Uh and thank you
all for being here. [applause]
>>Thanks >>Thank you guys!
>>Mister Grifter >>I'm right
here >>Okay >>Alright up next uh
from the Packet Hacking Village,
Capture the Packet [applause]
>>Super weird hug, yeah!
[laughter] >>Always got a mess
with Grifter, what's up Def Con
[few members of crowd applaud]
Aw that was co- so pathetic,
come on! What's up Def Con!
>>Woo! Yeah! [applause]
>>Alright, I'm Riverside my
partner in crime CDaas couldn't
make it, he's back in the
village which takes hours and
hours and hours um so we had a
ton of hands on stuff in the
Packet Hacking Village and it
takes an army we had over 130
volunteers help us out and I
just wanna thank all of them
they're awesome thank you all so
much [applause] let's give them
a big hand [applause] Um one of
the things that makes our events
and contests that we have going
on there especially capture the
pack so- uh- so awesome is our
uh boss DJ code, the wall of
chief DJ community and I wanna
really think um Freekosha Jerk
and TenseFuture Um they were
awesome they made it just rock
in there so thank you all guys
[applause] uh alright so as far
as capture the packet we had
over 600 people this year play
capture the packet and uh it was
intense round after round after
round and that's why it took so
many volunteers but it was epic
and uh the team that won this
year with uh 3200 points leaving
1100 on the board to be got
ooooh! [laughs] were able to get
a good junk of the really
intense stuff but we rolled our
own crypto this year we had
insane steganography, x-fill
from all sorts of different
methods, brand new malware that
you guys are playing with in in
your real lives and a whole lot
more so uh thanks to uh a-
especially packet sled that gave
us that thing we get these
freaking badass laptops for
these guys >>Woo! [applause]
>>And thanks to DT and crew they
get a black badge which is
awesome right? [applause]
alright so that is it I think I
got my two- oh wait let's start
with the alphabet I've got two
minutes, A, B, no I'm good
alright thanks everyone
[applause] >>Alright so this
next contest is actually one of
those situations where again
they- they never intended to be
in the running they just created
something cool and we heard so
much about it over the course of
the weekend uh that we
eventually got together with
them and said, how about an uber
badge and they were like sure
[laughter] so here they are
Telephreak [applause] >>Okay uh
so wow this is bright up here um
on Thursday the first time at uh
Telephreak for a a company- in
this- uh pardon me the first
time at Def Con for a company
happened and this happens a lot
you know employees of companies
will come to Def Con and
sometimes they'll get a little
bit drunk and maybe they'll say
too much or or do something they
shouldn't so [inaudible] mineral
company came to Def Con on
Thursday they all go really
drunk and lost their badges just
all around the Con area and uh
those badges were actually the
entry point to the Telephreak
puzzle this year so uh we run a
puzzle pretty much every year
last year it was based around
old school hacker floppy discs
and this year it was based on
phreaking so uh our winning team
um actually solved the puzzle
using only telephones and you
know that's one thing that we
tried to teach hackers this year
'cause we always have an
educational component to the
challenge is you don't need
MetaSploit and Shodan to hack
there's actually tons of stuff
out there that you can hack uh
without the tools that many of
us use uh so with that uh I'd
really like to congratulate the
Psychoholics they went through
an absolutely insane challenge
[applause] they dialed into our
uh they dialed into our system
hacked through 3 different
departments voicemail boxes,
listened to all their
voicemails, uh, you know,
figured out what was going on in
the scenario, literally got a
shutdown code for the Gibson
which um and and you know they
shut it down over a phone uh you
know using a PDU alarm code so
you know this was actually um
something that could be done
without a computer but we did
put a three hundred bod
recording just to mess with
people and they successfully
decoded that too so uh
congratulations guys [applause]
>>Alright uh this next contest
the if you were around on Friday
morning the line just to get in
and get a badge and compete was
so big that it caused a crowd
control problem so [laughter]
like thanks for that [laughter]
>>You're welcome! >>The Darknet
Project [applause] >>The Darknet
Project is an interactive game
that takes our players through a
bunch of challenges that take
them through lockpicking to web
cracking to web exploitation and
this year we had an amazing turn
out, lots of players, and um I'm
going to turn this over to
Samosa to talk a little bit
about the next part. >>So uh I'm
the one responsible for the uh
crowd control problem we uh make
our contest bigger and better
every year, this year we started
with our badges uh we moved over
a thousand badge kits for our
Learn to Solder kit um we had
five hundred unique players and
they completed over the course
of three days nine thousand
quests so it was a really big
contest this year [applause]
>>So I was on stage just here
during the closing ceremony and
not as a staff member but as a
Darknet winner and the one thing
I have to say is that Darknet
made me feel like a part of the
community and we want to keep
this feeling and make everyone
feel this way so this year and
it's the first day- it's the
first year we're doing this we
include the names of three teams
that we feel embody the spirit
of Darknet onto the next year's
badge and the teams are,
Dissazea, Stickers, and Tits
[laughter] [applause] >>Uh but
uh but- besides the the first
second thir- um third players
and what they're receiving we
had swages, badges, reputation,
experience, that was handed out
to players, reputation, um built
on the etherium chain and pretty
crazy things that were happening
um our third place- third place,
second place, and first place
are also receiving a pre
released signed tenth
anniversary edition of the
Daemon written by Daniel Suarez
who sort of inspired the
competition he signed them and
he was wandering around the
conference. Um Our third place
winner was Kexel our second was
Concil Org and our third place
winner, winner of the black
badge >>First place winner
>>first place winner was Gate
Herder [applause] >>Hey guys so
I I agree with Ohai there that
Darknet is amazing, it's fun,
it's a community, uh, I'm a
hardware guy not a software guy
and and an- I came to Darknet a
couple years ago this is my
third year trying because I
don't know this stuff and so I
came to learn it and I- I played
hard and uh I want to thank
first of all my lord and savior
Jesus Christ, without him I
wouldn't even be here, second I
want to thank my wife and my
family because without them I
wouldn't even be here, third I
want to thank Dissazea the guys
who brought me into their wings
a couple of years ago and said
hey come join us and uh I
encourage everybody to do
Darknet next year, thank you.
[applause] >>So Darknet is
obviously a big contest that's
really important to a lot of us
it wouldn't happen without a
whole slew of volunteers working
year around to try to make this
whole thing happen. Between
designing, kitting, selling, and
then assembling thous- uh over a
thousand badge kits, we had uh
our badge designers, we have
volunteers that help us put all
of it together and um then HHV
allowing us to take over their
entire village so that we could
solder all of these kits, thank
you buddy, we appreciate you
very much. Um as ZeroA
mentioned, we wouldn't be here
without all the volunteers in
the thousands of hours they put
in to design all of our content,
build all of the physical
hackables and integrate with all
of the other contests that we
have going on here at Def Con,
third we have Daniel Suarez the
author and creator of the Daemon
universe that inspired the
Darknet and he's actively
involved in everything that we
do and finally to all of our
amazing players, if you
participated in Darknet raise
your hands everything we do is
for you guys and we look forward
to doing more of it next year,
thank you and we'll see you in
July [applause] >>Alright this
next contest uh is a personal
favorite of mine, these guys
come with a bunch of mini
challenges, it's a CTF but done
in a very unique way lots of
different skillsets and if you
get stuck on something you move
on to the next challenge and
you're not just out of the game.
Um one team gave me some
feedback they said hey we were
gonna try to do all of the
challenges and they're like yeah
we're doing, this we're doing
this, and they showed up the
next morning and these guys had
created ten more so they were
like come at me bro! uh Warl0ck
gam3z [applause] >>How's
everybody doing this afternoon?
Alright bout ready to get out of
here right? Um so we uh had
several events this year we
always try to introduce
something new um we're always uh
looking for new and innovative
ways to get folks involved uh
this year we opened up the board
the hands on downloadable
content kind of thing, security
practitioner, malware analysis,
packet analysis, from there we
moved into physical security and
then uh yesterday we ran uh
essentially a spy room like uh
an escape room uh where
contestants had five minutes to
go in there and find all sorts
of neat spy related stuff uh
which equated to points on the
board collectively all of that
led to our leader board. So
without further adieu uh I've
got all my teams up here um and
in third place I have team
Ambush, in second place I've got
uh Team Sophia, and the black
badge winner this year is going
to be Team PTFS [applause] >>Uh
hey uh I just wanted to say um
uh thanks uh Warl0ck gam3z Def
Con it was great, good fun and
uh thanks to our teammates who
can't be here with us right now,
early flights and whatnot,
thanks you guys [applause]
>>Thank you >>Alright so thanks
to DT, Def Con, and again we
hope to see you guys again next
year, thank you very much
[applause] >>Alright Wireless
CTF where you at? Don't go slow,
these are your two minutes >>I
said stop [inaudible] I was
trying to be good, I was trying
to be good. Alright so they told
me to talk about nothing but my
sp- alright darn I was gonna
steal that >>Nooo >>I'll let you
guys see it I'll distract you
the whole time >>Oh wowww >>Look
at that, look at that love >>So
I was going to say something
negative because at Def Con 15
there were actually three
villages that started up and
that was Hardware Hacking
Village, and Lockpicking
Village, and the Wireless
Village, but to be honest uh you
guys gave us double the space
this year and we packed it and
we had more contestants than
ever at our game so I'm just
gonna say thank you instead,
thank you, that was- this was
the best we've ever had and we
really appreciate that, so thank
you to Def Con for giving us
such a space [applause] So ten
years in we decided to do uh
something special the same thing
we always do we had a big
contest, Wireless Capture the
Flag with all manner of stuff,
we had a bunch of epoxide
transmissions, slow scan TV,
sorry about that if you decoded
it seriously uh [chuckles] we
also had a bunch of wifi
challenges, radio challenges, uh
for the second year in a row
nobodies broken into our walkie
talkies which is kind of fun for
us so uh yeah it's been a lot of
fun and all kinds of different
wireless stuff and we really
look forward to doing this again
so I'd like to uh thank the
twenty-ish teams that were
playing, really appreciate that
uh and from new players to old
players to returning favorites,
to returning people that are now
banned from the game uh thanks
for playing uh third place is
Dale's Pale Ales, uh second
place was the DIEPOLlar Bears
that- that's DIEPOL you know not
anything negative and then uh
these guys up here which had to
call themselves, What Does The
Fox Say, not only did the vast
majority of their points come
from literally hunting people
down at Def Con they did across
wifi, bluetooth, and software
defined radio so if you saw
weirdos running around with
Yagis that were pointing at
everybody it was probably one of
these guys because they won
almost all of them. Uh as a
matter of fact this fine
gentleman who I guess will go-
we'll go with Justice Beaver, he
uh, he was on the winning team
last year mind you he's got a
new team more or less behind him
but he was on the winning team
last year so he's officially
retiring whether he likes it or
not because he's joining our
ranks so we were five and now we
are six, so welcome to the team
buddy [applause] >>Justice
Beaver! >>Alright first I wanna
say thank you to my team uh
these guys I could not have done
it without them uh everybody
contributed no matter what um
and I guess the only thing I
have to say is uh you know three
years ago I was a noob and now I
stand up here in front of all of
you guys for the second time so
uh if you have questions ask
anybody find a mentor and mentor
somebody else. [applause]
>>Thank you! [applause] >>Get
off the stage >>Alright from the
Car Hacking Village, the Car
Hacking CTF [applause] >>Oh yeah
definitely, definitely very
bright alright thank you guys,
thank you. Um hi I'm Robert and
actually I'm- I'm CarF**ker and
as CarF**ker I'd like to say
thank you to everybody who came
out to our our village and thank
you to the teams who
participated in our CTF, this
year we had 171 teams a
significant number of teams uh
hacking cars so that was kind of
cool um we actually had a actual
real live car in our place to
hack uh we had a bunch of
hardware um so I'll just go
quickly through the teams real
quick, um number three was
Trashcan, number two our friends
uh Sec DSM [applause] >>Yeah
>>Yeah, go Sec! They already won
a black badge so that's cool um
and I'm gonna totally totally uh
f**k this up um Rob- Robindires,
robanderos, uh close enough, it
means stealing shit in Spanish
um um so it was really close uh
the top two teams were exactly
100 points from each other and
this year the implication of
that means that one team gets to
take home a truck and the other
does not cause we uh decided to
give away a truck and a black
badge yes, a Def Con truck, it-
it's a 2017 Def Con um we have
if you- if you- if you'd want to
check it out we'll put pictures
up and um if you guys really are
interested in the scoreboard um
here it is it's right there I'll
zoom in it's right there you
guys can see it I'll tilt it to
the left, everybodies got it,
yeah, I'll yeah I posted it on
Twitter at Car Hack Village um
and uh I guess this is a good
time to sort of say thank you to
uh my friends over here and kind
of give them the keys to the
truck but I thought you know
what that's not fun, that's not
fun, why don't I give it to you
guys instead, who wants the keys
instead, [cheering] alright! I'm
kidding, that's not the keys I'm
just f**king with ya here's the
keys [laughter] thanks guys!
[applause] >>And and- real- real
quick, real quick, Shawn wants
to say thank you too Shawn, go
ahead >>Just wanted to thank
everybody for coming and playing
with all our toys, breaking our
stuff, we had a great time and
we're going to bring some cooler
stuff next year, so thanks
[applause] >>thanks guys
[applause] >>Alright uh these
guys if you've seen their
contest it happens on the
contest stage uh in the contest
and events area uh I see the
wifi cactus walking through
[laughter] see it's a wifi
cactus um >>it's like a shark
>>Yeah it's like ooah okay um
>>Dun-nuh duh-nuh duh-nuh
duh-nuh [singing Jaws song]
[laughter] >>Um so these guys
have their contest up on the
stage, it's a lot of shenanigans
these are sanctioned and not
unsanctioned shenanigans and
they drink quite a bit actually
so much that they ran outta beer
ten minutes before the end of
the contest and we kind of
looked at them and went I- like
we had no reason to think you
would drink that much um
[laughter] and so uh let's hear
from those guys Crash and
Compile [applause] >>So yeah
Crash and Compile is basically a
ACM style programming contest
combined with a drinking game so
we give you a problem you solve
it in code and yeah if you took
the code didn't compile or you
don't get the right answer you
have to take a drink so our- we
had the hardest year by far uh
this ba***rd created some
brutally challenging problems uh
and we had some amazing teams
who uh uh competed this year so
uh >>How many teams? >>We had a
total of 51 teams try out for
our qualification round and then
uh from there 9 teams go on to
the final round uh so our third
place winner was uh
VolatileConsis second place was
Mobius Ring and then our first
place winner is Gird Your Loins
and so for winning [applause]
they get this giant metal D20
made out of 12 gauge steel it
weighs about 14 pounds good luck
getting it home [laughs]
[inaudible off-mic comment] uh I
don't know how many beers they
had I know we drank all of them
[laughs] so and I guess they get
a black badge too that's kinda
cool so um but yeah we also made
a second one and we auctioned it
off for the EFF and we raised uh
four hundred dollars for that so
thanks everyone [applause] >>So
uh again if you guys haven't
seen the contest they have
another team on there called
Team Distraction which is a
supposed to try to get people
distracted from what they're
coding or looking at and uh
Nikita joined for a little bit
on Team Distraction and
pretended to go into labor
behind a guy [applause]
successfully distracted
[laughter] >>Alright uh this is
the 20th an- this is the 20th
anniversary for this contest, 20
uh it's one that I actually ran
myself for several years back at
the Alexis Park uh we love em
they keep it weird, the
Scavenger Hunt >>Yeah! Woo!
[applause] [inaudible audience
shouting] >>Hi there! Uh I'm
Evil Mofo and uh I run the
Scavenger Hunt um so since I
winged it a couple times I kinda
wrote something to slightly
follow um so we keep Def Con
weird that's our- our goal and
I'm fairly certain we
accomplished it this year uh we
had uh 3 turn ins of carbonated
siemen >>Woo! Yeah! >>3
streakers in the contest room
>>Yeah! Woo! >>And one marriage
[laughter] uh [applause] so I
wouldn't be here if it wasn't
for a couple people uh as as
Grifter mentioned he kinda ran
it but before him came Penguino
with him came Hectic, Grifter of
course, then there's Siviak and
then he handed it off to Salem
he was too busy gooning so I ran
it but I've- I've taken it over
um so uh we we tried our best to
invite all the winners in the
past apparently my predecessor's
weren't good at record keeping
so we only got some of them but
we got most of them um and so
this year we had a great
competition we're gonna go
through the top 5 cause they
were freaking amazing. The fifth
place Nah HawkDog came in with
two carts worth of items as we
were closing the table and it
shut down we had to reopen just
for them just to take in their
items for a half an hour and it
didn't get all through their
items uh they came in fifth with
48,978 points with with some
decimal precision um then we had
uh Butterbeer [applause] in My
Bag Swag sh**t [clears throat]
one second I had one- >>don't
f**k it up! >>I had one job. I
had one f**k >>Don't f**ck it
up! [from audience] >>Alright
anyhow Butter Beer in My Bag Sw-
My Swag Bag was uh fourth place
and they fffor f**ks sake
[laughter] there it is and they
came in they were a two pers- a
two women team who came to Def
Con to play The Hunt >>Yeah!
Woo! >>One day! >>One day!
[applause] >>They were only
competing one day! >>Wait for it
wait for it they left on
Saturday at 10:15 or so in the
morning they came in fourth
place with four thou- forty
nine- 4318 points they were on
trajectory to win but they had
to catch their flight [crowd
awws] >>They f**ked it up!
>>They f**ked it up. Um third
place goes to Neg9 [crowd
cheers] with 46,778 points get
the f**k up here with the
quickness uh the second place
team was Team Amirica- Ameerica
>>Yeah, woo! >>A three woman
team and and they- we- we we-
keep telling them that they
should've joined forces um not
my problem um and finally uh did
I not- oh they got 96,500 and
points [laughter] and first
place, first place, [crowd
cheers] and a black badge goes
to Temple OS Fan Club [crowd
cheers] with 101,404 points
[applause] >>Yeah! Woo! >>Yea
hahahaha! Yeah! Oh Grifter!
>>Good job! I told you they
would keep it weird >>Hold on
one second >>What >>So I uh-
>>I'm not a first time speaker
you don't get to interrupt me
>>I- I- I'm not- I'm not giving
you I- I- I- told him that if
you went past two minutes I was
going to put him in a ditch and
use his black badge for hookers
and blow later so if you wanna
play along at home with the next
play >>Awkward um alright uh
these guys were right center in
the middle of the contest area
this year, we put them there for
a reason uh it's always
entertaining and out of control
Hack Fortress [crowd cheers]
>>Thank you Grifter. PWCrack
said I could go as long as I
want so if the fires could bring
me the Everclear that'd be
appreciated um Bob's gonna kill
me uh so this started out
actually as uh I think in uh
Defcon 19 I got scheduled for
the 10am slot at uh Sunday um
and I decided to make it
exciting and I had a lan party
that I tried to organize at nine
o'clock um beforehand and like 4
people showed up we had 2
laptops so it wasn't a very good
lan party um and we decided that
what was interesting was the
audience really enjoyed watching
it so we thought well we should
do something kind of hacker
oriented and we already had uh
Hacker Halo back at ShmooCon in
DC so we took Hacker Halo and
Team Fortress 2 and jammed them
together into these kind of 30
minute hacker TF2 furnetic round
based things um and someone
inspired by the Ghetto Hackers
um and their badass crate that
they used to bring all their uh
oh thank you it's not Everclear
but it'll work uh but the Ghetto
Hackers and their badass crate
that they used to have in the
middle of the CTF room we
brought in our own Hack Fortress
crate it was like 8 feet tall
and wobbled around and shit um
but that was uh 6 years ago so
we've been doing Hack Fortress
now for six years uh it's just
TFT and a little bite size
hacking competitions like 3 to
10 minutes things uh it's fun to
watch this year for the first
time we streamed on Twitch um we
had a few hundred people watch
on Twitch Daku and Cisco uh the
man with the beard there we're
doing the live stream uh so that
was cool so if you're into
Twitch and like under 25 'cause
I guess you have to be to use
Twitch um it's- sorry old gamers
um first I'd like to thank the
staff um all the uh uh Hack
Fortress staff they do it both
here and at SchmooCon they have
to make new challenges every
year they do a great job, thanks
Hack Fortress staff wooooo!
>>Wooooo! [applause] >>I'm sure
it was clean um I- I- can kill
it? Great! I will kill it thank
you um and then finally so uh uh
final round uh came down to Easy
Baby and Team Not Ready For This
uh Team Not Ready For This won
for the third f**king year so uh
>>they're ready! >>They're ready
for this! They're absolutely
read for this the explanation
point comes off next year so
congratulations team not ready
for this and Batman you want to
do your dance can you do it real
quick [applause]. Yeah, that's
what put him over the top was
that dance right there so thank
you very much
[applause][cheering] >>Thank you
>>Alright and of course last but
certainly not least, Capture the
Flag >>Woo! [applause] Ow!
>>Good evening the last five
years of Def Con Capture the
Flag have been an incredible
fide for us, for our competitors
and for the larger Def Con
community. After five years
dozens of challenges, hundreds
of binaries, and tens of
thousands of hours of work we're
passing the torch to the next
organizing team whoever they may
be there are still amazing
opportunities to grow Capture
the Flag and with the skill and
creativity of everyone in this
room we're sure the contest will
end up in capable hands that
will raise the bar even higher
we'd like to thank everyone who
made the last five years
possible, the Dark Tangent and
the entire Def Con staff for
five years of incredible
support, the Def Con goons for
keeping the Capture the Flag
rooms afe and drama free for
five years straight, all of our
competitors for five years of
excitement, and most importantly
the Def Con attendees and CTF
players around the world for
five years of this incredible
game we couldn't have done this
without all of you. [applause]
>>Woo! >>[sighs] [laughs] Hi
everybody. So uh last year I
stood in front of a room it was
a little smaller than this one
and uh I announced that this
year we would be running the Def
Con Capture the Flag on an
architecture of our design about
six mon- er- about four months
ago DT called me and he was like
hey are you sure that the teams
at the CTF are going to be able
to do something interested in
the 72 hours of our game I was
like oh yeah man I'm sure- sure
they got this uh I'm happy to
report that the teams not only
succeeded but they absolutely
crushed it >>Yeah! >>This year's
game used the clemency
architecture an all new 27 bit
with 9 bit bytes [laughs]
computer designed by our own
Lightning >>Woo! [applause] >>Oh
also Middle Indian it was great
Thursday morning we released it
to the public along with a
processor manual an emulator and
a debugger and that was it
Friday morning the teams came to
play and the amount of work they
did to build the tooling they
needed to succeed in our game
was incredible. We had teams
with Ida modules overnight,
binary ninja modules overnight,
some team built a uh clemency to
arm transpiler and then used an
arm decompiler to lift up to see
it was- it was incredible we we
didn't expect anything like that
[applause] so I think it's fair
to say that the teams have ri-
risen to the challenge and
developed new tools for reverse
engineering, patching, and
attacking our crazy custom
architecture. As usual the
winning team for the Def Con
Capture the Flag will receive 8
uber badges and 8 black leather
jackets >>Woo! [applause] >>What
was that? [applause continues]
We hope the new organizers
whoever they will be will
continue to honor the tradition
of inviting the first place team
back to defend their title next
year [applause] In third place
from uh China we had A*0*E
[applause] In second place from
Taiwan we had HitCon [applause]
[whistle] and I'm almost tired
of saying it at this point, but
the winners of the Def Con
Capture the Flag this year was
PPP the Plaid Parliament of
Pwning [applause] [crowd cheers]
>>Woo! [inaudible off mic
comment] >>Uh No, sorry >>Hi
>>Hey >>Thank you am I supposed
to talk? >>Sure >>Oh alright
well I'm a little sick but uh
first off thank you so much to
Legit BS when we heard they were
doing a custom architecture we
pretty much thought that's gonna
f**king fall on it's face
there's no way it's gonna work
and we showed up on Friday and
everything ran it was incredibly
smooth especially as far as CTFs
go um all the teams were
attacking us all the teams were
patching stuff, everyone had
tooling, it was incredibly
impressive so thanks everyone
yeah >>What was your- [applause]
>>Oh [inaudible] I don't know
[inaudible] alright >>Okay so as
a it was elluded to um we are
also going to acknowledge the
incredible hard work that uh
LegitBS has put in for five
years and so um not everyone
knows this but we're going to
give all the ten core organizers
they will all get black badges
>>Woo! [applause] Woooo! >>So
they have I believe they've ad-
helped advanced the state of
capture the flag and just really
kept it true to what we want at
Def Con which is just a really
offense defense driven head to
head combat kind of game and so
with that I really thank LegitBS
and we're gonna rely on them to
help vet the next team that we
accept so thank you very much
you guys just you guys knocked
it out of the park, thank you
[applause] Alright so we're
gonna open a call for organizers
for Capture the Flag um we're
gonna do it in two weeks and
we're gonna try to select an
organizing team before the end
of the year uh and we'll just
like the last call for
organizers we'll provide a lot
of information you'll be able to
interact ask questions with
LegitBS and past organizers um
and so uh we hope to really
create the evolution of this and
so if you're interested or you
know people that are interested
give some serious thought to
potentially organizing or
encouraging your friends to
organize the next generation of
Capture the Flag. Alright what
is next, we thank them, we thank
them, oh my super secret
announcement um before we do my
super secret announcement, for
those of you who have been
coming for awhile I always save
my weird secret announcements
for last just because you guys
are the most hardcore you've
waited the whole weekend you're
probably exhausted and you're
just toughing it out and you're
supporting us and you're
providing the energy and so I
always like to reward you with a
secret announcement [laughter]
[applause] So one of the
announcements is everybody
always asks well how many people
came, how big are we, like it's
some sort of contest um and it's
really hard for us to tell
because um we don't really go
through all the numbers until
next week but we have some
indicators and so I am guessing
at this point I was projecting
if you saw me on Twitter I was
projecting a certain amount of
growth, I thought 6 percent, and
6 percent of a large number, is
a large number, and we were at
about 20 percent >>Wow! >>Which
was pretty awesome and so we
probably broke all in probably
[applause] >>Right? So that's a
lot of cats to herd um and I
wanna just invite CJ to come up
this is a new thing we're gonna
start doing every year to just
give you a little bit of
transparency in what goes on
behind the scenes just some
rough numbers with what we have
to deal with every year so CJ
[applause] >>Alright thanks
everyone a big part of this is
for us keeping you guys safe is
one of the most important things
we do. We take complaints about
harassment, we take people
behaving badly really seriously.
We want to encourage people to
come forward and this idea of
transparency is people have
asked us to be open about what's
going on so we're going to do
that, we're going to show you
what kind of things we're
dealing with and we're going to
welcome advice from the
community to try and improve
things. So this year out of
of harassment, 9 reports of
medical uh situations and they
ranged from someone who sprained
their ankle while skipping uh
[laughter] an unfortunately
named person called Skippy
[laughter] there were 3 thefts,
1 vicious dog, 3 adorable dogs,
5 cases of vandalism which
included some bright spark who
thought he could put a piece of
paper on one of the Caesar's
palace walls and then write on
it with a Sharpie, guess what
brainiac, it goes through.
Please don't do that again,
because Caesar's is going to
hunt you down if you do. Uh
there was 2 cases of trespass on
property, these were people who
decided to go back of house,
just like it's the most stupid
thing possible to go and hack an
ATM on the casino floor because
it's got the most cameras on the
planet pointing at it, the same
goes for back of house, they
have a lot of cameras there and
they recognize who's supposed to
be there, it's pretty much a
fast track to being kicked out.
So the results of all of this,
we had 4 people transported to
hospital, uh including one
person who had a large piece of
masonry fall on his head, uh we
had 3 people who were banned for
life, and we had 2 people who
were unbanned for life
[laughter] [applause] >>Woo!
>>We're gonna be changing things
up a lot there's gonna be uh a
few new processes and a few
announcements over the next year
about how we're gonna work to
make things more inclusive, more
safe and more diverse and one of
the first things I want to start
with is please if you want to
help come apply to my team we
are looking for all of you I
want this team the Goons the
guys in red shirts who run
around as well as the staff at
Def Con who all run around to be
honest I want it to look like
you, this team should represent
the community because the
community serves the community
[applause] thank you! [applause
continues] >>Fantastic, okay, we
also have uh in years past, we
used to try to run around and
calculate the amount of
donations that you all give to
various groups and organizations
and nonprofits and this year
there were so many groups uh and
so much fundraising just out of
your own pockets supporting the
causes that you wanted to
support um that it was two hard
for us to get an aggregate
number about how much giving
actually occurred but to Mark's
point about community, we really
are a community and I want to
invite up one of the original
groups that we donated to, the
EFF uh Kurt and he's just gonna
talk a little bit about this
process and how well the
community has been supporting
them [cheering] >>Thank you,
thank you very much this has
been a- we're oh so glad to be
back here in this community, it
is such a generous community and
this year has been an amazing
year for fundraising, I want to
thank this community for
contributing people who came by
the booth became members renewed
their memberships, got our
tshirts, got our stickers, those
who contributed through the many
uh fundraisers like mohawk con
like buying the Benders badge
like contributing through the
beard contest and so many other
fundraisers out there, this year
has been our best year ever and
thanks to the generosity of this
community we have raised over
going to use to fight for your
rights online, we love you so
much and we will see you next
year, thank you again. >>Right
on, thanks so much Kurt, right
on. Okay so now we're into the
final stage boss round where um
I have made the decision to give
you my super secret announcement
uh I've been agonizing over this
for awhile because it's kind of
uncha- uncharted territory for
me and it's also uncharted
territory for Def Con and um you
know I've been really thinking
about that that we're really a
global community and if you look
I just raise your hand in the
audience or cheer or whatever if
you're not from the United
States [cheering][applause]
right? And if you guys saw the
sign that was posted on
Promenade level with the global
map and you saw where everybody
came from right? [cheering]
>>Yeah! >>That was a brilliant
idea, right there, I want to get
a picture of that before you
guys disappear because it is
amazing, I want a picture of
that. And it was a global map
where people would mark where
they're from and I really
thought that you know it's
getting harder and harder maybe
for people to come to the states
and we're and we're a global
community and I've been thinking
about potentially growing Def
Con and I even um dropped a
little hint in the program about
three years about we did a
Tribeca Film Festival and we
brought the Hacking Villages to
a completely new audience,
filmmakers, and writers, and
actors and we did that 2 years
in a row and it was amazing and
then last year we seriously
investigated bringing the
Hacking Villages to another
country um and that really made
me think that you know what I
should just try a beta event, I
should just try taking the kind
of culture of Def Con the
Hacking Villages and going to a
new location and trying to build
community and where would I do
that. So yeah we've we've got a
location and I'm gonna bounce it
off you and you tell me what you
think of it but if I am- I am
finding incredible energy, I'm
finding incredible creativity,
and no kidding I'm not joking,
I'm gonna try a Def Con beta in
Beijing. >>Woo! [applause] >>And
you know if the hackers can't
come to us, the hackers will go
to them. And we're gonna create
or help build and foster a
global community of these kinds
of beliefs, of these open
exploration, the discovery, the
puzzle solving and uh and I
could fall on my face and it
could blow up and it could be a
disaster or it could be an
awesome beginning of a new
chapter. So we're gonna find
out, so if you're interested, if
you run a contest or a village,
and you're interested maybe in
travelling overseas um or if
you're a speaker and you think
you've got something up your
sleeve and you wanna go speak um
you will see a call for papers
and call for contests in the
next couple of weeks so that is
my super secret announcement
thanks for sticking around for
it and I'd love to get your
feedback and with that I'd like
to call Def Con 25 to close.
[applause] Woo! >>Woo!
[applause]