>> So um good morning, thank you
for attending a Sunday morning
uh talk. So today we’re going to
talk about Android packers, how
do they work. And we’re gonna
analyze a few of them and um I’m
going to show a method we
developed a tool that can handle
most uh uh it’s a generic way to
handle most of the packers in
the the market. So who are we? I
am Avi.I’m uh currently a
founder at myDRO but uh I was
formally a Mobile R&D Team
Leader at Check Point for a few
years and this is where I did,
did this uh research. And before
that I was in security research
in Lacoon Mobile Security. And
uh unfortunately sla.. Slava, my
uh co-presenter could not attend
today. But except being a very
uh talented researcher and a
good friend, he also did a lot
of the heavy lifting around this
research. We miss you Slava. So
uh let’s go to business. So uh
Boxing Apps. Okay, so Malware
authors use various uh boxing or
packing techniques to prevent
Static Code Analysis and Reverse
Engineering. Uh Malware author
invested a lot of time in
developing his cool Malware. And
he doesn’t want you know uh
security guys to understand
what’s happening, detecting it
through, they’re using their
automatic tools or uh with
manual reverse engineering. This
is the same as in the PC world
where most of the packers and
most for he malware today are
packed. So how can one um
protect his code. So they can
use a proprietary technique or a
third party software that can uh
protect the apps code. So what
does this software should do? So
this includes code protection,
anti debugging, anti tampering,
dumping, all of the methods that
would prevent the security guys
um the static code analysis
engines, the reverse engineering
from understanding what’s
happening inside the app, the
malware. And what was our motive
to this research. So in the
PC..PC world it’s it’s for years
now that Malware’s are uh uh are
uh packed by uh different
packers. Also we see this trend
rising in the Android world. And
this is a snapshot of an
analysis done in a checkpoint
system from uh May. And we saw
that almost 25 percent that the
packed apps were detected by us
as malware. And we asked
ourself.. can we um improve the
detection, is this really the
amount of malicious apps from
the all the pack apps or maybe
we’re missing something because
we’re not going and doing static
code analysis or fool static
code analysis for this app.
These apps because they’re
packed. So this was our motive
and saw uh in order to
understand how packing works and
to find a generic way to unpack
them. So uh what techniques
exist to protect an app’s code.
So let’s talk about the main
three. We have Obfuscater’s,
Packer snap Protectors. So what
is Obfuscation? So Obfuscation
is um adding redundant code the
uh to the main app’s code. It
doesn’t affect the functionality
of the app and changing the
function name and the variable
names and this is done in order
to prevent or reverse engineer
to understand what’s happening
inside the app. And uh today in
the Android world there’s a
default uh obfuscater tool
called ProGuard which comes with
Android studio and used by most
of the Android developers. And..
but I have to say it’s not the
best obfuscater in the market
and for uh.. really not really
experienced reverse engineerer
it shouldn’t be any problem to
understand what’s happening
inside the app. And another
method which we are going to
concentrate here today in our
talk is uh Packers And what
does Packing do So let’s say Ive
an APK, an Android app. And it
contains um a DEX file. What’s a
DEX file? It’s a small byte code
that what’s happen..happens to
the.. the code after it’s being
compiled. And um this is what
Android executes. So I have the
original uh code and what does
the packet process do? It takes
this original code and encrypts
it, packs it in some in some
manner. And the way it opens it,
it adds a packer loader which
will be the now the entry point
for the execution of the app and
once the app is executed the
packet loader will take.. take
the bundled original encrypted
DEX file and load it to the
memory, unpack it and load it to
the memory so it can be used by
the app. And um. there’s also
Protectors. That. uh that
works. uhh in a better or
different way. They take the
original DEX file but they don’t
only uh encrypt but they also
modify it. Uh why they’re doing
that, they want to add another
layer or protection. Let’s say
one of the protectors uh that we
saw uh in the wild adds an
encryption in the class level.
Meaning if only when the class
is initiated, uh eh hmm.
lovely. Um, the encrypted uh,
only when a class is initiated
it will be decrypted. And what’s
surprising here that we didn’t
see.. see.. saw uhh a large use
of protects, protectors in the
wild. And our, what we thought
is it might because it might
effect the.. the logic of the
malware. Malware offers uh don’t
use it as much as packers. So we
decided to concentrate in our
research on packers. So in order
to understand more on how
Packers work. We need to go back
a bit to basics and understand
some things about uh Android. So
let’s talk a bit about ART. The
Android RunTime VM, this is a
schematic of how things looks in
Andorra 6, which is good enough
for us to understand this world.
So what happens? How does
Android uh RunTime Vm works? So
the Android RunTime VM can work
in two modes. One, interpreting
the small byte code and the
second is working with a
compiled byte code. Ahead of
Time compilation. That was
something that was intercede in
Android 4 point 4. And what
happens is when you install an
app, it goes through a process
of compilation and then the VM
will work on a compiled uh ELF
code. And while this was done
and this allows to gain uh a lot
of improvements in ram, battery
uh performance, and run time
start up run time of the
application. But it’s important
to remember that the VM can work
in both ways. Interpreting a
[inaudible] code or what uh a
compiled eh native. So what
happens when you load a DEX
file? Uh when you start an app.
So uh you trigger the zygote
process which is an empty
process that contains preloaded
classes and it’s diagrammed to
show the startup time of the
app. And what happens the cyber
process forks itself into an
empty app process and loads the
app code.. the uh uh the OAT
file. But what happens if the
OAT file is missing? So what
will happen is it will trigger
DEX2oat, that’s the process that
compiles the DEX file into an
OAT file. And we’ll use the oat
file in order to execute the
app. So I talked a bit about Oat
files. So let’s try to explain
what what is it? So Oats file is
basically an ELF file with some
uh added sections. One of them
is Oats data which contains the
original DEX file and one of the
is the oat exec which contains
the compiled version of the DEX
file. And both of this sections
are used uh by Android the ART
Vm when executing an app. One is
for uh creation of different
headers and one for
inter..interpreting the app. But
it’s important again to note
that you don’t have to have the
native file. All of the Oat exec
in order to execute an app. You
can back fall uh to the
interpreted uh to the smaller
version and interpret the code.
So now that we understand a bit
more about Android. Let’s try to
think about ways to unpack an
App. So the first one can be
finding the algorithm. We can
try the different packers. Try
to analyze how do they pack an
app, which algorithm do they
use. And do the back steps in
order to decrypt the app. The
problem with this is this
doesn’t scale. You need to
understand each packer, how it
works and even if a packer only
do uh a minor modification to
the packing algorithm, the
script will break and you need
to start your research again. So
this is not the way you want to
go. Another method could be
extracting a DEX file from the
compiled OATs. As we said we
have the DEX file inside the
OAT. But what we saw in
different packers is you don’t
have to have the DEX file inside
the oat, you need only part of
it. So some of the packers
delete the DEX file from the
Oat. So you can just take it and
use use the DEX file. Another
method might be just dumping the
DEX file from the memory. But
again this is not uh uh always
work, does not always work
because uh the DEX file the DEX
might be missing and the packer
will use the oat file. So we
wind up thinking about using a
custom Android ROM. Which uh
this is something we already do
in Check Point. We have amec
analysis engine and uh maybe
introducing a few modifications
to the custom Android Rom that
will allow us to dump uh to
place a few hooks in interesting
places. And this will allow us
to dump the DEX file and pass it
to our uh static code analysis
engine. So before continuing on
I want to uh talk about a few
notable works that was done in
this area. One of them was
Android Hacker Protection Level
uh Zero and it was presented
here at Def Con a few years ago.
And it was a very goo talk that
talks about the different
packers and protecters uh in the
wild and they also released a
few set of scripts that dumps
uhm that work on some of the
packers and dumps uh DEX file.
Another very interesting talk
from the guys that released the
DEX hunter tool which is a
modified version of Android
Dalvik/ART VM and it really
reconstructs a new DEX file
from.. from the memory. While
this was a very interesting
project, it was not what we
aimed for. We wanted to get the
original DEX file before the
packing process was begin uh
was began in order to have the
same hash as the original file.
So we want to go in a different
path. So what was our approach?
We wanted to find a solution
that would require minimal
changes to the Android source
code. So it will be portable.
And it will work on most of the
packers. So how how did we do
it, how did we address the
problem. So we took the most
popular packers that we
witnessed in our systems and
reversed them. We additionally
analyzed the way Android loads a
DEX file in order to understand
truly how it works. The results
was a patch of a few Android uh
lines the Android runtime that
will allow us to dump the files
and uh analyze it in our static
code analysis. So what were the
analyzed packers that we looked
on. So the most popular packers
encountered were um Baidu,
Bangle, Tencent, Ali, and 360
Jiagu. And what’s uh Baidu is
the same huge Baidu Chinese
company that you know. They also
have a packing service. It’s a
web service, you send an APK and
you get the packed version of of
it. It was very surprising to
see that they offer this kind of
service. So in this talk, I am
going to talk about Baidu and
Bangle. And what’s interesting
about them is they work in a bit
different method but covering
both of them allowed us to find
a solution that works on almost
all the packers we encountered,
encountered. So let’s try to
think about the abstract way in
which a packer should work. So
um as I said, you have the
packer loader it will load the
bundled packed DEX. So it will
load the DEX, this will trigger
libart, the ART VM um to uh
work. And opening the DEX file,
map it’s data to the memory. Uh
then you have the DEX in the
memory. But something is missing
here, where does the unpacking
process takes place. So what we
thought is that most of the
packing uh unpacking process
will be inside a native a
native lib function and uh file.
And why? Because reversing of a
native file its it will be
harder for uh reverse engineers.
So it’s a good idea to put your
unpacking logic in an obfuscated
and protected manner and for
that you need to not do it in
the in the java byte code
packer loader but in a separate
native file. And what does this
native file do? It needs to
interject itself somewhere so it
could decrypt and unpack the
packed file. So he will do it
with hooking. It might hook lib
art lib c and uh during now
when lib art will open the file
the unpacking process will take
place. And then libART will eh
get the original DEX file that
it can execute. So cool. Now
that we thought about an
hypothesis of how packers should
work we want to verify if it’s
really what we see in the field.
So let’s look about uh the first
packer, Bangcle. So in order to
identify Bangcle it.. its very
easy it has uh uh various
classes we chose in every packed
up by Bangcle. And um different
files. One of them is the native
packer which is used to unpack
an app. And the packed version
of the text DEX file which is
Bangcle classes. And this is a
snippet of the java loader
implementation. And we can see
that Bangcle loads a native
lib a native lib file. And calls
fu-JNI which is a bridge between
java and uh calling native
functions to uh functions from
this native file. And then it
loads the DEX file which will
trigger uhh libART SO. So we
wanted to understand what’s
happening inside the native
file. So we try uh.. open it
with IDA and it crashed. And uh
this is one step afterwards and
uh we could uh after we fixed
it, I’ll explain in a second how
we did it. Uh but what we
noticed here is we didn’t see uh
any mapping between the native
functions and the functions uh
names in the java interface.
Meaning something is missing
here where does this mapping
happens? So what what we needed
to do is understand the mapping.
So I’ll take a step backwards
and I said that IDA crashed, why
did IDA crash? We know that this
file is in use so it should work
but when we dumped um the file
headers was using, the file
headers we saw that some of this
uh some of the segments were
missing. We didn’t see the text
segment. So um eh what we
noticed is it defined in the
dynamics section and we had to
manually reconstruct the
different sections in the file.
Um from the info we got from he
dynamics section. And then we
could eh eh analyze it in IDA.
But that wasn’t enough because
even uh when we uh. opened the
file in IDA uh the entry point
was not valid. It didn’t point
to anything interesting so uh
something else is happening
here. So what happens here is
there’s a call to an INIT
function eh from the dynamic
section. What does this INIT
function do? So what it does is
the native file contains a
compressed section of the code.
And the INIT uh function
decompresses this uh code and
overrides the text section. And
now the entry point, the
original entry point of the ELF
is valid. And what we saw is
that one of the functions inside
the native file is JNI OnLoad.
And JNI OnLoad provides the
mapping between the functions in
the native file to the JNI, the
java. So now we can understand
what does uh what does the
function do. Okay. So, now let’s
see how Bangcle works. So um the
first function, extract a file
from the assets. And the second
one, which is the interesting
one uh forks three different
processes. The first one is just
the apps uh process. The second
one is an anti debugging process
which does different tricks in
order to prevent us to uh
understand what’s happening. And
um. the fourth third one only
executes when the OAT file does
not exist. And as we know this
mostly is the first time when
the dynamic uh DEX when the DEX
is loaded. But it doesn’t
executes DEX2oat uh in a regular
way but it uses a LD preload in
order to hook some of the
functions in DEX2oat and create
a special kind of version of uhh
an oat file. This oat file will
later be used by RTM when
executing the file. I hate
windows. Okay, so what does the
hooking and uh and uh in Bangcle
do? So um on the left so uh it
hooks 8 different functions and
we have here an example of one
of the functioned hooks and the
way it hooks them. So we can see
it on the left uh an open app
fun..function uh without any
hooking. And on the right we can
see uhh.. the uhhh the hooked
version and we can see that the
first bytes were over read and
um the what it does it changes
the PC register in order to
change the flow of execution to
the pack unpacking process of
the app. So let’s do a recap of
Bangcle and how it works. So it
creates a stop.. a packer loader
as a Java activity to load the
native library. The native
library is protected with
different anti uh research
techniques that we have to
bypass and what it does it hooks
libc and uh for um for the
unpacking process and what it
does is when a libART encounters
the OAT file it will unpack it
and provide an unpacked version
to the libART VM. So we
understand how Bangcle works.
Let’s look at Baidu. So again
for classification this is
pretty straight forwarded, we
can see that if we have a stub
application and the stub
provider and again a native lib
and uh the packed original DEX.
And again the same we couldn’t
see um the mapping between the
native functions used in uh in
the loader to uh to the
functions in the native lib and
uh you can see that uh that um
again uh by the used the INEX
section in order to decompress
some of the code. Because again
we couldn’t see it in IDA and
only after the decompression we
could understand whats happening
inside the file. And uh again
it’s using the JNL OnLoad
function to provide uh to
provide the mapping and do some
uh other interesting stuff. And
these are the things it does. So
it has an anti-debugging
technique that I will, I will
elaborate. And uh registration
of the native methods meaning
the mapping between the JNI and
the native functions. And it
extracts the packed DEX from the
assets and creates an empty DEX
file, not an OAT file but a DEX
file.And provide the hooking. So
what are the anti-debugging
techniques used in Baidu so we
have obfuscation, uh log
disabling, uh it checks that gdb
isn’t executed and JDWP isn’t
executed and a few uh more other
anti-debugging techniques. And
we can see that the hooking and
libART in Baidu is a bit
different. It hooks the Android
log print function in order to
prevent any logging so uh if you
try to debug it, you can’t. It
will be harder for you to
understand what is happening.
And uh it hooks the EXECV
function. Uh and when DEX2OAT is
executed, by Android, it
prevents the compilation of uh
the DEX file. Meaning the Oat
DEX section it will be it won’t
be empty but uh Android won’t
use it to execute the logic of
the app. It will fallback to uh
the file encode. And it hooks
the function open. Meaning with
Android tries to look for the
one dot jar file instead it will
decrypt the uh packed uh DEX
file and supply it to libART VM.
So again, let’s see what Baidu
does. So it creates a stub in
the Java activity. It uh The
native lib is protected with
different anti research
techniques. And it hooks libART
for handling, opening of the DEX
file. Well this looks familiar.
But this is a different packer
or almost a different packer. So
uh what’s.. what can we
understand from here. That most
of the pack.. unpacking process
might be generic with a few
minor changes. We can see that
the trigger for the decryption
by the different packers is uh
when the..when libC opens the
file. And in Bangcle it’s when
it’s opening classes an OAT
file. In Baidu it’s when it’s
opening the DEX file. And if a
hook plays hooks in the first
places in uh the libART VM
process when uh it tried to open
a OAT file and a DEX file. And
dumped the files, we should have
the decrypted version, the
unpacked version of the DEX
file. So that’s exactly what we
did. We understood the way an
app is loaded uh by the artVM
and where is the first places we
can place a hook uh in the VM uh
in the code uh in the flow uh of
loading. So we can dump the the
files. So one function in the
OAT file loading process and in
the DEX loading process. And as
you can see it’s only a few
lines of code. One is three and
ones a few more And this
allows us to dump the decrypted
version of uh packed filesPacked
DEX files. So let’s see a demo.
Okay. I’ll try to cool. So this
is a demo of a tool we created
that uh that will can gen..
generate and unpack most of the
packers. And what you see now in
the in the background we open
now an app which is packed and
you can see by Bangcle and you
can see the DEX file, the packed
DEX file. Which you can’t really
understand what’s happening here
because it’s packed. Now we
execute our app. And uh it’s our
tool which is uh uh a forked
version of the AL spawn of
Android. And I’ll try to fast
forward this and unfortunately I
can’t so we’ll have to wait. So
what’s happening here is Android
emulator is loading and once
it’s loaded we will uh load the
app and our hooks our two
different hooks will dump two
versions of the DEX file. One
should be valid and one should
be not. It depends how the
packer works. Some the packer
hooks in both places some of
them hooks only one of the
loading uh in one of the loading
uh flows. But this enables us to
unpack the apps. So um well this
will take a few more seconds. Um
sorry. Okay. So how are you guys
today. [Audience Repsonds] Um
what I can mention is the
hooking used by the packers is
not persistent they placed the
hooks during the loading process
and then they remove it. It’s
it’s. it’s a good uh it was we
had to really understand when
the hooks are placed so we could
decrypt uh dump the DEX file in
the right time. Because trying
to connect uh later on uh with
GDB and dump the memory or
execute or just dump it in uh
afterwards after the app is
already uh executed won’t always
work. So it was crucial for us
to understand the DEX loading
process. And um.. wow Android is
so slow. [Laughs] Oh man.
[Audience laughs] [Laughs]
[Clapping] Okay you’ll believe
believe it it works but you
don’t need to believe me. You
can download the tool.. uh for
yourself from our repository and
uh it’s it’s it’s not a compiled
version of Android but a patch
that you can apply and the
script that wraps the unpacking
process. And you can go over
them, uh execute them and see
that it works and uh uh enjoy.
So uh sorry, so we understood
how the packing process works by
different packer and we only
introduce a few changes over the
ART VM. And this enabled us to
work with like 90 percent of the
packers we encountered in the
systems. And what was very
interesting we quit this uh
change allowed us to uh to send
an unpacked of the DEX files to
our static code analysis systems
and we got a 50 percent increase
and detection of malciusouness
of packed apps from this uh from
this feature. Which is uh was
very good for us. [Applause]
Thank you thank you, you’re far
too kind. [Applause] And uh
that’s it um if you have any
questions um feel free to ask.
[Applause]