>>Yeah we're long time Def Con
listeners, first time Def Con
talkers >>Yeah >>So I like that-
that our slides are cut off
cause it just says the internet
already knows I'm x and you can
fill in the blank um in this
case it's pregnant um but that's
historical I'm wasn't drinking
while pregnant, just so you know
[laughter] So I'm Kashmir, I'm a
journalist, I've been writing
about privacy and security for
about ten years and I'm a new
mother which is relevant
information at this particular
time >>Uh and I'm Cooper, I'm a
technologist and security
researcher at EFF uh I'm a
privacy activist and I also care
about privacy and security
issues for people that have
wombs despite not having one
myself >>Woo! Yeah! [applause]
>>Uh so we paired up for this
particular project um I I'm an
investigative journalist so I'm
good at reading documents, and
talking to people, and I'm also
an immersion journalist, I like
doing the things I'm writing
about so when I wrote about
bitcoin I lived on bitcoin for a
week, it was hard um in the past
with Def Con speakers help I
hacked a smart home um so yeah I
like to do the things I'm
writing about though I did not
get pregnant just to do this
talk [laughter] >>Uh and I
didn't either. So uh I'm a
hacker so my skillset involves
apparently seeing dogs and
blondes in the matrix um but uh
uh so I got interested in this
um originally I ha- when I had
um advised another journalist on
an article about anti-abortion
groups using uh geo targeting
advertisements to target
anti-abortion ads at women
inside of Planned Parenthoods.
>>So you'd be in Planned
Parenthood planning to get an
abortion, you fire up Facebook,
and you get an ad telling you
that you're- you know killing
your fetus. >>Yeah. And so uh I
met Kashmir and she uh pitched
this idea to me um after uh she
had unsuccessfully looked for a
real security researcher for
many months um and we settled on
me so uh >>And beyond being
pregnant I got interested in
this um a few years ago I uh
we're on the wrong slide, next
one, oh we are missing the
slide, anyways, a few years ago
I helped popularize the story of
uh the Target story. Um doe- is
there anyone in here who doesn't
know the Target data mining
pregnancy story? Don't be afraid
to raise your hands. Okay I'll
tell it. Um almost everyone
seems to know this story and I
hear it come up at every single
security conference, privacy
security conference I go to so
I'll be the one to raise it this
time. But this is a story that
came from an article written by
Charles Duhigg who is a New York
Times journalist um he did this
big article on how companies
learn your secrets and one of
the anecdotes in this story was
that Target did really excellent
data mining, it would look at uh
the shopping behavior of women
to figure out who who- early on
who is pregnant and it would be
like they bought unscented
lotion, they bought a blue
carpet, they probably bought
prenatal vitamins, which is like
the big give away uh and so
there was this story about how
Target sent ads to this woman
for all kinds of baby products
and it turned out this woman was
a teenager and her dad saw the
ads and got really mad and went
to Target and and was yelling at
them saying are you trying to
encourage my daughter to get
pregnant and supposedly this dad
called Target back a couple of
weeks later and apologized and
said there were things going on
in his home uh that he didn't
know about and that his daughter
was indeed pregnant. So some
people don't want uh the
internet to know about their
pregnancy um in particular
there's a Princeton professor
named Janet Vertesi and she
wanted while she was pregnant
for the internet not to find out
about it. So she went to great
lengths to hide her baby bump
from the world of big data. She
looked at baby sites, baby
product sites, using Tor uh her
husband went to uh the drug
store, paid cash for gift cards
when they wanted to buy baby
products they would do it with
these gift cards and have it
sent to an Amazon locker so it
wasn't associated with their
home address and um she said she
successfully hid it as far as
she could tell because she never
got online ads um uh targeted at
her based on her pregnancy. I
decided to do the opposite. I
just told everybody I was
pregnant [chuckles] I downloaded
while I was trying to get
pregnant, downloaded all of
these period and fertility
tracking apps and then once I
got pregnant I entered into the
apps I was pregnant and I just
used an email address that I- I
don't usually use in order to
track what happened cause I
wanted to find out who was going
to sell me out to retailers who
was gonna figure out that uh I
was expecting. >>So uh this is
the list of apps that we looked
at uh and we looked at about err
a little over 20 different apps
um and they have all of these
names a lot of them are named
similar things like my calendar,
my time, um [sighs] and uh >>So
here's the first privacy issue
>>Yeah so >>Once you put this on
your phone and somebody is
shoulder surfing, do they know
what you're doing with these
apps? >>So there's one set of
logos that are very discreet,
like you know, letters, numbers,
this could all be pretty generic
applications, ridesharing or
something, there's the next tier
though that involves a lot pink
flowers and silhouettes of women
>>I've never had so much pink on
my smartphone [laughter] >>Uh
and then there's yet a third
tier of weird images of fetuses
[laughter] >>At least the last
one doesn't give away what the-
the sex is of the baby >>And
then of course the grand winner
is this one [laughter] >>No I
mean you don't necessarily know
what this is, it could be like a
porn app >>No, but it's called
'Get Baby' [laughter] so yeah a
little on the nose for this one.
Um >>So I think that there's
probably a few dudes in the
audience who maybe haven't used
these apps before and you may
wonder why it is that women
would want to tell their smart
phone uh when they're having
their period uh so these are
some of the reasons why women
use these apps uh the screenshot
on the left you can't quite see
it, but it give you options for
for why you're using the app, it
can be that you're trying to
avoid pregnancy. So some women
are using this as a
contraceptive to avoid uh I
guess the sperm getting to the
egg during a fertile period. Um
using it to get pregnant, or if
they're getting very expensive
IVF treatments, they can use
these apps to track what's going
on with their body. Uh once you
get pregnant you can use these
apps to track the human science
experiment that's inside you uh
the the main thing that the apps
tell you about is what size
fruit the fetus is in your body
[laughter] which is super weird.
>>Uh one of them told us that
the baby was the size of a
cheesy mango [laughter] which
I'm not clear what a cheesy
mango is >>[laughs] and it told
us, it was not our- it was not
our baby [laughter] >>No, no,
yeah, [laughter] we should
clarify >>[laughs] and then the
other use for these apps is they
have these community forums
where women um talk about all
kinds of things sometimes it's
stuff having to do with
pregnancy and fertility uh
sometimes it's completely
different, there's a lot of
discussion about people's sex
lives uh in the screenshots I
have here it's about I can't
even remember oh baby bump
selfies, those are really big,
oh there's somebody saying why
is my period greenish black,
which you should probably get
out of the forums and go to the
doctor [laughter] and then in
terms to the kind of information
that you give these apps um you
might tell them what your
vaginal discharge looks like um
you'll because their fertility
apps a very important piece of
information is how often you're
having sex and when you're
having sex. Once you're pregnant
you might tell them the physical
symptoms that you're
experiencing from you know
headaches to back aches to not
sleeping a lot uh and then the
apps are helpful in terms of
getting you to do things that
you're supposed to do when
you're pregnant like take
prenatal envir- uh prenatal
vitamins, do kegels , which if
you don't know what that is you
can look it up up [laughs] and
just track your sleep and your
weight like the usual kind of
health tracking stuff. So I
downloaded all these apps um who
figured out I was pregnant? So
one of the first uh one of the
companies that figured out I was
pregnant um was Twitter so this
is from a uh a Twitter account
that is associated with the
email address that I used with
all of these different apps and
I don't know if it's included in
the screenshots but they figured
out that um this is from there's
like a an interests page that
you can get to in your Twitter
settings and it tell you with
like what advertisers know about
you, how they're targeting you
so I have been uh successfully
associated with baby products,
childcare products, and very
specifically it says, dem- in my
demographic information that I
have one child. Which is true.
Also all of these people figured
out I was pregnant. Um this is
my inbox at six months and um
luckily again I was not using my
usual email address uh but I had
ads from pottery barn kids, uh
What to Expect which is one of
the apps I signed up for,
Huggies and many many more. So
this is where we get into my
specialty um of reading
documents so I wanted to figure
out you know how these people
had gotten this information, uh
there was a technical way to fi-
find that out and then there was
just a read the privacy policy
way so one of the uh- and I- I'm
only going to be give you a few
of the privacy policies but the
first one was What to Expect.
This privacy policy is 4
thousand words long which is 8
pages if you print it out, and
2600 words in it very explicitly
says you know we when you sign
up we give your registration
information to select partners
and there's a little link there
that you can click and then it
gives you a list of the partners
um when I first did this it was
like 8 different companies but
when I went back to the
screenshots for our talk it had
expanded to I think 14 um it
includes pottery barn kids,
huggies, uh, some of the people
that you saw spamming my inbox,
and the privacy policy said, if
you don't want us to tell these
companies about your- your
pregnancy status uh don't use
the app. Uh you know this can be
worse than just getting spam in
your inbox uh sometimes they
send real mail uh similac is a
baby formula maker and they're
one of What to Expect's select
partners and uh so they get
information from What to Expect
and other um companies that they
wouldn't disclose to me uh and
they will send a woman baby
formula a couple of weeks before
her due date so that she
helpfully has baby formula
around to feed to her child uh
this can go very wrong because
not everyone who gets pregnant
stays pregnant so in one
particular example a woman named
Amy Pitman from Washington got
pregnant, was excited about it,
put it into the apps, um she
didn't like the What to Expect
app so she deleted it, and then
she had a miscarriage, and uh a
few months later, or I guess
like 8 months later, she did get
baby formula in the mail. So
there is serious privacy harms
here when you miss identify or
correctly identify a woman's
condition but then don't know
what happens later. >>And it
seems like a lot of these apps
are not keeping in mind people
who might be outside of the
majority use case the average
users story or the average
threat model so to speak which
is a theme that'll come up again
>>Okay, so privacy policy number
2, this was The Bump uh this
privacy policy was 4700 words
which is 10 pages printed out
>>Yeah and so for reference,
this is the same length as the
entire report that I wrote about
this problem >>[laughs] And so I
was reading this privacy policy
and I was really surprised to
get about halfway through it and
I discovered baby's first
wiretap. Which [laughs] which I
use facetiously I don't know if
a lawyer would approve of
calling this explicitly a
wiretap but [laughs] it had a
feature um it re- it told you
that if you made a call from
within the app like you um
identified a vendor that you
wanted to do your baby registry
on. If you made a call from the
app it would record the call um
it would record any message that
you left, it would um collect
the phone number, the location
where you were when you made the
call, etcetera, which I just
thought was insane, like I've
never seen anything like that
before with an app. And so I
called up, I- I reached out the
The Bump and I said you know,
WTF. And they informed me oh you
know we're not recording phone
calls, that's legacy language
for a contemplated future, for
the Knot which is an app that
they do uh for planning weddings
and uh the press person was like
I'll send that to our legal team
right away eh so this proves
that no one reads privacy
policies, not even a company's
own lawyers [laughter >>And the
line >>They removed it from the
privacy policy a couple days
after I reached out to them
>>The line of uh this bad thing
you found was was uh just a just
a test, how common was that
>>Yeah I mean I'm sure of many
people out here who have reached
out to companies about privacy
or security issues often gets a
response of it was just a test
or we were just temporarily
doing it. I don't know I hear
that all the time. >>That was
response from about half of the
companies we contacted I think.
>>Okay this is the last one. Um
so this was Ovia which is an app
uh a company that makes a
fertility app, a pregnancy
tracking app, and even a child
tracking app, their terms of use
um uh are 6100 words which is 14
pages printed out. Um I don't
know if you can see it in the
screenshot but this is an app
that gives you like a really
helpful fertility score like
your score is high, do it, your
score is low, nothing's gonna
come of it [laughter] and
[laughs] when I went through
their terms of use they uh you
know a lot of these apps they
sound like they're they're kind
of like giving you the kind of
advice that a doctor might give
you um but many of the apps warn
that they're not really giving
you medical advice and this one
explicitly said you know this
app might be- might have errors,
may be inaccurate just so you
know we're not responsible for
that. So I went back to look at
their website and um oh yeah you
can see it good. So in the
advertisement for their
pregnancy app they said they'll
give you real time alerts when
your symptoms are dangerous and
right above that is like the
little medical symbol. So I
don't know it sounds like
medical advice to me. >>Sure
seem to be trying to imply that
it's medical advice. >>Right.,
So these are some of the issues
that we ran into um when it
comes to inaccuracy the warning
that they gave uh is warranted I
found out that a year ago th- uh
three doctors looked at a bunch
of apps, 33 of the most popular
ones on Android and iphone uh
and they looked at their
predictions for the fertile
window and of those 33 apps,
only 3 apps correctly predicted
the fertile window um and we've
got their results there. No one
was completely off but they
would just be off by like a few
days and um interestingly the
month that I got pregnant uh
most of the apps told me I'd
missed my fertile window so uh
my husband and I were excited
when we found out that in fact
it had worked. >>So if you're
using these to not get pregnant
uh it might not be the best
method >>Yeah, please don't use
these apps as a contraceptive.
Um so so far I've talked a lot
about a one person that's
involved in this in terms of
privacy um there's- there's two
people involved and so that was
definitely on my mind as I was
doing this project is that um
well basically I've- I was
tracking my now uh my now in the
world daughter, online, since
she was negative 8 months old uh
[laughs] so I'm just wanted to
say a public apology to Ellev.
>>uh >>So so that's like a lot
of what I was able to [laughter]
[inaudible] [laughs] So this is
uh- this is what I was able to
learn just from um basically
tapping into skills that I have
as a journalist in terms of
reviewing privacy policies,
reaching out to companies, I
also used an a-um an um an an
app I guess called Recon from
Northeastern University uh that
monitored the kind of
connections that my phone was
trying to make and that these
apps in particular were trying
to make and so it told me
essentially that there were a
lot of advertisers that were
getting information from the
apps um but I felt like I needed
more help in terms of really
digging into the the the
technical side of this and
that's where Cooper came in.
>>Yeah so I wanted to give sort
of a hackers side of this and
see what we could find out about
uh the network traffic what was
what sort of API calls were
being made, whether encryption
was being used, um, whether the
APIs were written securely and
what- what other companies were
getting the data and what sort
of data exactly they were
getting. So uh >>Also Cooper is
really good at finding memes
[laughs] So you'll appreciate
the next few slides >>So um the-
one of the first fun things that
I discovered about these apps is
that uh they- they give you some
pretty specific advice this one
told me that I had a 2 point 6
percent risk for pregnancy,
which is large considering I
again, don't have a womb
[laughter] >>So there is no
option in these apps to say I'm-
I'm a dude >>Yeah [laughs] um no
so I used uh pretty typical
reverse engineering methods, uh
static analysis, dynamic
analysis, uh and some other
tools um so for static analysis
I used a tool called JADX which
is a decompiler for APK files uh
produces something close to the
original java source code it
also uh extracts the resource
files uh and then I loaded that
up in android studio where I was
able to do some similar things
like what you can do in Ida I
was able to um rename function
calls that were obscured, track
flows of functions, see where
permissions were called, why
they were called um so this gave
me a lot of good insights into
apps that I wasn't able to get
just from network traffic um and
this is how I got network
traffic so for dynamic analysis
I used a tool called man in the
middle proxy or MITM proxy um
and what MITM proxy does is it
intercepts SSL traffic you uh
install a special root
certificate on your device and
then you connect to the proxy
and you can see um content,
headers, and everything else,
for HTTPS traffic and it also
allows you to replay requests,
edit requests and replay them so
it was really good for uh
looking at the APIs figuring out
who was being contacted and what
they were being sent. Uh and
then the other tool I used is a
proprietary tool called
Kryptowire uh which they donated
their services to us for this
project uh so Kryptowire it does
a combination of static and
dynamic analysis uh and it
allowed me to quickly um w- to-
do sort of a quick triaging of
about 40 different apps uh in a
couple of hours to see uh sort
of a high level overview of
which ones might be worth
looking into further. Um and you
can see here this is kind of the
like high level analysis screen
of one of the apps uh where it
told me that it was leaking uh
personal information um so yeah
so one of the main things that I
found in most of these apps was
uh just lack of HTTPS um so
meaning that content- important
personal content was sent over
plain text html >>And so you
might wonder like okay we're
talking about the privacy and
security of fertility apps,
who's gonna attack these things
like who wants to hack these, so
let's think about um what kind
of information is going into
these apps, women talking about
their sex lives, um, or the
kinds of things that they're
writing on the community forums
where they're talking about
issues that they're having with
their pregnancy, medical
information, um, again a lo- a
lot of them talking about their
sex lives, strangely a lot of
women talking about um their
experiences being sexually
assaulted that was like a very
common um topic of conversation
so this is all being sent in the
clear um and you might it might
be intercepted by somebody who
shares uh a network with you
>>Yeah >>which could be your
partner, uh could be your
restrictive father, uh thanks to
congress deciding not to move
forward with privacy rules for
ISPs this means your internet
service provider could get this
information and this would be
more uh more information used to
target you with ads. >>Yeah um
and then the other thing about
this is of course that somebody
with man in the middle position
could inject uh an execute
javascript on a lot of these
apps which used the uh web kit
framework to render pages um
related to that uh we found a
number of issues with uh account
hijacking ala uh firesheep so
four of these apps would have
been fire sheepable um so they
were- which is to say that they
were sending authentication
cookies over plain text so Pink
Pad, Webmd Baby, My Calendar,
and The Bump um all were found
to send authentication cookies
over plain text >>So >>The top
three have not fixed this >>So
if you're using these apps and
you're using Def Con wifi don't
do those things at the same time
>>yeah [laughter] probably just
don't use the wifi [laughter]
even if you're not using these
apps. Uh we also found a lot of
personal information leaks. So
uh for Pink Pad and another- uh
so Pink Pad is made by a company
called Alt12 we tested two of
their apps uh and both of them
send your exact GPS coordinates
to the Alt12 server every time
you start the app um and why the
hell does a period tracking app
need to know your location?
[laughs] >>And it's in their
privacy policy it's so they can
provide you with location based
information, and ads. Location
based ads. >>Yeah. uh so they-
we also found a number of other
things like email, name, gender,
pregnancy status all being sent
and I don't think that Pink Pad
was the only one that was
sending location uh a bunch of
these apps requested the
location permission but what we
found w- uh through static
analysis was that a lot of them
were encrypting the data that
was being sent uh to advertisers
and to other people, Pink Pad
was just the most obvious about
it. And if we had more time
maybe we would have found
others. >>And so again thinking
about the threat model here, I
actually want you to put on your
William Gibson hats um and think
about the possibility for um
what what could be done with
information about women planning
to be pregnant um or thinking
about pregnancy um who are
giving up their location details
all the time um so I think at
the beginning of this talk we
made the point that advertisers
um aren't just creepy because
they get a lot of information
about you and they're trying to
get you to buy something um in
the case of knowing a woman's
pregnancy uh status it can be
very malicious where we had an
anti-abortion group targeting
women that are in a Planned
Parenthood waiting room so just
think about some kind of a
policy group who wants to target
a bunch of women who live in a
certain neighborhood um and tell
them that they shouldn't get
pregnant, like all everything
that's bad about it or try to
encourage them to get pregnant.
>>And uh I don't know if Cory
Doctorow is in here but if you
write this story, we want
royalties. [laughter] Um so uh
and there were other information
leaks too like uh this text file
that was dropped on the SD card
by one of the apps so this
contains a log of the entries
into the app every day uh and uh
j- January 18th was a uh >>Like
a really good day [laughter]
>>But um this this this file
being on the SD card means that
any other app could read this
file and furthermore it means
that anybody who gets ahold of
your SD card or the data
partition on your phone is going
to be able to read this file as
well. So it's a pretty big
privacy leak um and then of
course third party tracking is a
super common problem with all of
these apps I think all but one
of the apps that we tested
contacted several different
advertising servers um and it's
mostly the same stuff that you
see online uh the majority of it
is Google, Facebook, um, Amazon,
and um A- Adobe's various
publishing networks and then
there's like a long tail of uh
just random advertisers and data
brokers uh that are you know on
one or two of them. >>So I think
it's safe to say that Google,
Facebook, Amazon, and Adobe know
more about who in the- who in
the country is pregnant than
Target >>So one feature that all
these- or that a lot of these
apps have in common is this pin
lock screen um and it's kind of
interesting presumably to keep
somebody from just picking up
your phone and looking at it uh
but they're not implemented very
well uh they almost all have a
for- 4 digit limit um and at the
time that we looked at this none
of them had any sort of
protections against brute
forcing so you could guess as
many times as you wanted without
any sort of slow down uh when we
notified the companies one of
the companies P Tracker did
actually uh decide to fix that
issue and implemented a uh back
off for the number of times that
you could enter the pin code uh
but the other thing about these
is that they don't have any sort
of- they're not any sort of
protection for the data at rest
so they don't encrypt the data
in any way, they don't do
anything to actually protect it
on the drive, they're just a uh
intent that you have- that
triggers before the app starts
so all you have to do is get
around that somehow and one way
to get around that is to click
this link that says I forgot my
code so for at least one app uh
The Bump when you click this
link it sends you an email with
a code- with a temporary pin
code that will unlock the app
>>And and where do those- you
know where does email tend to
go? >>And so email tends to go
to your phone so if >>So if
you're on the phone trying to
get into the app and you can't
because there's a pin on it
>>Just send the reset code and
uh check the email because you
already have the phone and there
you go so >>And when I- when I
was using these apps I was not
using pin codes I wasn't
particularly concerned about um
uh somebody getting into the
apps uh but if- but if somebody
does feel a need to use the pin
they may have a very legitimate
reason like they're >>You may be
in an abusive relationship, you
may be in a restrictive you know
or a religious household, or a
religious society. >>They're
with somebody that they don't
want somebody who has access to
their phone to have access to
their sex lives and so these
pins should be stronger. >>Yeah
and if you're relying on this
pin code for security uh I don't
recommend it uh you- you should
um take better- other steps. Uh
the other issue- another issue
we found was files not actually
being deleted uh and so again we
only found this in The Bump but
this is also largely because we
ran out of time to do this
research and this is probably an
issue in other apps. So what
happened this case is that um
The Bump encourages you to
upload poto- photos of your
pregnanc- of your pregnancy
progress. So a photo of your
belly, a photo of um your- uh
ultrasound >>And so what happens
on a lot of these apps there's
actually some apps that
explicitly discourage this and
say no posting any personal
information in the community
forums um but I guess The Bump
didn't' have that prohibition so
a lot of women like to post the
ultrasound and share it so you
can see the development of the
baby but ultrasound pictures
usually have uh the mother's
full name, the hospital where
the ultrasound was taken, the
date, so a lot um of sensitive
information so a woman might
post that to a community forum
and then realize all that she
shared and delete it >>But when
you delete it it turns out that
it simply unlinks the photo from
your account but doesn't
actually delete it from the CDN
server that the photo was
uploaded to. So if you have that
original URL that URL still
works to see the photo for the
rest of time um and we thought
this might be a caching issue at
first but the photo was still up
for a week after I had deleted
it from my account so definitely
not a caching issue, just not
even considered that a user
might want to actually delete
things when they say delete. Uh
and then uh the other thing we
found was just a crazy amount of
permissions being requested uh
it seems like the Android
development philosophy is it's
better to ask for all the
permissions than for any
forgiveness. Um no that was bad
alright um so locat- so ten
different apps, half of the apps
we tested requested the location
permission and again >>Everybody
wants to know where you are when
you're pregnant >>So again, for
advertising right? But this
harkens back to the story that I
was working on earlier about uh
women being targeted in Planned
Parenthoods through location
based advertising. This is
incredibly personal information
and there's no reason that any
of these apps should have this.
Um also a quarter of the apps we
tested requested your contact
list >>Just in case they wanna
like inform people about the
pregnancy >>Yeah they might want
to text everybody you know that
you're period is coming up.
[laughter] um also five or six
of the apps requested your
device ID which is like a uh
cookie for your phone it lets
advertisers uh link your uh
profile between different apps
um and then the phone permission
let's them do the same thing but
using your IMEI which is like a
hardware serial number for your
phone. Um and then Pregnancy
Plus requested the SMS
permission and I have no idea
why but it also has the contact
permission so maybe that thing I
said earlier about it texting
everyone [laughter] anyway the
other interesting uh so we found
one interesting security feature
was that four of these apps,
Glow, Nurture, and Eve were all
made by the same company and
Clue all implement certificate
pinning uh so this is where you
hardcode the hash of the SSL
certificate that you want to use
for your uh HTTPS connection
into the application um and it's
pretty cool this- so this
prevents somebody from doing a
man in the middle attack on
HTTPS like what I did with MITM
proxy um and I mean it's a nice
feature to have my bank doesn't
even do this which would be
great um but it's kind of extra
like I don't >>We're not- We're
not security shaming >>I'm not
security shaming, I'm glad they
did it, but uh TLS man in the
middle seems like to not really
be in the threat model for uh
the use of these apps and it
seems like maybe a better use of
their time would be to implement
something like two factor
authentication uh which none of
these apps did or securing that
pin code thing. S- um so after
finding all this uh we reached
out to the- so we reached out to
the vendors separately >>We
reached out separately >>Yeah,
so Kashmir reached out to them
about the uh privacy issues and
about the things in the um terms
of service. I reached out to
them about the security issues
um this is how I felt about
their response [laughter] um and
this- this this dog will always
be relevant forever [laughter]
uh so I contacted uh nine
different vendors um and uh all
these guys and also The Bump um
and we received a response back
from P Tracker, Glow, and The
Bump which isn't up there
because we got a response back
from them uh just- just after we
finished these slides. Um who-
so P Tracker and Glow fixed the
issues that we found uh The Bump
promised that they would fix the
issues um and everyone else just
completely ignored us once
company sent us a form letter
saying they- they appreciate
that we like their application
[laughter] >>I had a different
experience and this is where
it's just is different being uh
a security uh technologist
versus being a journalist. I
heard back from everybody that I
reached out to um except for
Everyday Health um which makes
the What to Expect app and Alt12
uh and people you know
acknowledged the problems with
uh the privacy policy and
changed it um I just- I got
responses and uh companies
definitely seem to pay attention
to journalists I think that it
helps that they like press
people set up particularly to
receive our um our inquiries and
also I think they better
understand what journalists are
asking them and sometimes they
just have no idea um what a
security technologist is sending
their way. >>So maybe the lesson
here is that if you want
companies to take your security
issues seriously either work
with a journalist or tell them
that you're a journalist >>Yeah,
I definitely endorse this pair
up you should definitely pair up
with journalists if you're a
technologist and vice versa.
>>Um yeah so and on that line uh
what can hackers do, what can
you all do uh to improve this
situation and one of the best
things to do um is uh to pair up
with a journalist and I might do
these in kind of a reverse
order- is to pair up with a
journalist uh the combination of
a hacker and an investigative
journalist is a really powerful
combination um you can- we can
find these problems and then we
can tell the world um and we can
through shaming these companies,
and through getting this
publicity out there, convince
them to take these security and
privacy issues more seriously.
Um and we're also- hackers are
really good at threat modeling
and we can think about uh threat
models outside of sort of one's
standard deviation from the
average user so we can think
about threat models for people
that are in abusive household or
people that have a stalker,
right? These uh should be pretty
common threat models for
somebody writing one of these
apps but they're apparently not
>>I think one thing that was
obvious to us at the end of this
is that people that these
companies hadn't necessarily
thought about um kind of the
abusive edge cases um and
actually a year ago Glow had a
really big security issue that
consumer reports discovered
where Glow had this feature
there where you could invite
your partner um to kind of
monitor your fertility or
pregnancy with you and the way
they had set it up was such that
the woman um would would uh make
the invitation to somebody but
um after she did that anybody
who knew her email address could
then monitor um what she was
doing within the apps and so it
was just this kind of huge
security hole and only
discovered because consumer
reports decided to look really
closely at the- at the app.
>>But Glow did take that issue
seriously and did fix the issue
and had- I think is why they
were so responsive to the
security issues that we found
because they do seem to after
that shaming er after that
publicity >>publicity [laughs]
not shame >>Not shaming um but
after that publicity they
decided to take these issues
seriously so this is a great
illustration of how publicizing
these problems um is a effective
tactic for change. >>Um >>So
Kashmir what was your takeaway
from all of this? >>Yeah I mean
my firsthand um opinion on all
this like I hate to admit it but
I really enjoyed using these
apps um while while I was
pregnant um it's super weird
being pregnant uh it's like
unlike anything that's ever
happened to your body before and
you- just- you feel like a
science experiment for 9 months
and so I appreciate the
information I was getting from
the apps uh but if I decide to
have more children I don't think
I would use the apps again cause
now I kinda like know my way
around it um so any any future
children I would have the only
priv- privacy invasion they'd be
subjected to in utero would be
the ultrasound which I like to
call baby's first privacy
invasion. >>It's always hardest
on the first child isn't it
Kashmir? >>Always hard- we're
both first children, it's the
hardest. >>Anyway um and so
that's all we have. We wanna say
some thanks to- uh thanks to
Kryptowire for donating their
analysis services to us uh we
really appreciated that and it
helped us out. >>Thanks to J-
Dave and Jingjing at
Northeastern for their help with
Recon >>and uh thanks to Gizmodo
and EFF for continuing to sign
paychecks to us >>[laughs]
Thanks to Def Con and then
thanks to Ellev for inspiring
our research [applause]