>>Okay thank you for come today.
Um, our talk is on, uh, hardware
tol-tolerant uh hardware. Um,
that’s tolerant of Trojans and
uh we’re gonna talk a little bit
more on that and supply chain
security in practice. Um, so the
highlights of this talk is uh we
start first discussing the
private life of keys um there
are some weak- also some weak
links on the supply chain so
we’re gonna bring this up. And
then we have the, some lessons
learned from airplanes. And then
we’ll see how can transfer this
crypto hardware, uh then Dan is
going to do a demo and describe
the architecture we came up
with. And then I’ll describe the
protocols some mods and and some
magic stuff we do. And finally
uh we’ll close the presentation
with, uh, some talk about
politics and how we can explode
this to crypto hardware. To
begin with, um, there’s this
thing that we have priv-private
uh key and public keeper. Um,
how do we generate that? So
first someone somewhere in the
developer design house, uh,
designs an integrated circuit
which is then fabricated to a
foundry somewhere else probably.
Um And then this integrated
circuit is delivered to the
hardware vendor to that actually
ordered it. Uh, the vendor then,
um, loads it’s firm--firmware on
it and assembles the actual
device that’s gonna use it. The
integrated circuit. And um then
the device is sent with the
customer that bought it. The
customer use it-uses the device
to generate and store, uh, to
generate and store the key.
Only, um, the problem with this,
uh, the life cy-cycle of keys is
that, um, in practice if any of
these, uh, steps, gets
compromised or an attack happens
in them, the final key’s weak or
compromised completely. Um, and
this is, um, for this reason we
have hardware security modules
so, um, hardware security
modules were built with a
purpose of, um, um, protecting
keys and tech performing audio
prints for the device. So it
provides very neat features.
Some of them are, uh,
cryptographic key generation,
storage and management. A lot of
these things happen on the
device. And then they have a-a
whole set of features that have
to do with, uh, tamper-proof,
tamper-resistance, and, uh,
tamper-response. So what they do
is basically if you physically
manipulate, uh, a HSM, um, then
this is gonna be, uh, visible to
the owner of it. Uh, also the,
uh, manipulating physically any
system to retrieve the secrets
of uh, that sort of thing.
Inside that’s not trivial so
they provide tamper resistance.
And then tamper response means
that the actual HSM, actually
the HSM can take action if, uh,
detects its being manipulating
so it may raise the keys or lock
down completely. Um, so this
makes it very hard for the
adversary to retrieve what’s in
there. Um, plus for companies
that want to check all the
boxes. They HSMs are usually
certified with a very high
level- really high level of
security. And then,
valida-validated for it. Um, the
bottom line for HSMs is that the
all the impressions are being
carried out on the device so the
secret keys and all the secrets
stored inside never have to
leave the device. And the- for
this reason because they provide
really high security they’re
using a very um, in lots of
publications where high service
is needed. So like public key
infrastructures, um SSL
connections, accelerators, um
payment systems is very popular
and actually vendors are willing
to pay the very high cost that
comes with them, um ten k that
we have here on the slides is
the very very low um end of it,
usually it's much higher. And
then there are lots of other
costs that usually um are hard
to quantify but they are- they
are quite uh high uh that have
to do with integrating the
actual HSM once you buy it and
then uh operating it and
supporting throughout the years.
Despite the the high cost HSMs
protect only the last few steps
of the um private key life cycle
so the-the top four um are also
are still exposed. And um,
there’ve been cases where we’ve
seen, um, things going wrong in
the first four steps meaning
that the actual security of the
device is being completely um
broken and nonexistent. For this
reason and because people know
that they try to come up with
solutions and there lot-there’s
lots of academic literature on
it actually. Um the most popular
of those are trust foundries so
this means that you sent your uh
circuit design to a foundry or
factory uh that you completely
trust not to insert any Trojans
in it. Um this, the problem with
it is that it’s very expensive
and of course mistakes can still
happen during publication. The
other approach is more academic
it’s split manufacturing. There
should be few um foundries that
support that. It’s still
expensive and again errors may
happen. And the final one is the
post fabrication inspection so
what happens is that you order
your credit, check it um they
manufacture it, you get it back
and then you run some tests on
it. The problem with this is
that it’s expensive. You need
expensive tools to do that. You
need to constantly retool
because the connects uh uh
advanced uh and then it's a huge
pain because if you’re there are
like a thousand a few thousand
chips you cannot test all of
them. So it doesn’t scale very
well. Um, in general overall um
it's an arms, an arms race
because because uh hardware
Trojans connects are constantly
advancing and uh adversaries are
always and will be always a step
forward. So you can never be a
hundred percent certain that
nothing went wrong throughout
the process. Even your trust
foundry may sometime uh betray
you and cooperate with uh
someone. So another note there
is another community. A fault
tolerant community so not
security but had a similar
problem and they solved it uh
using um tandem systems.So what
they do is basically uh instead
of using one integrated circuit
they use three coming from
completely different supply
chains and uh the they build
therefore they build either dual
redundancy systems which allows
them to detect if one of those
two circuits is misbehaving uh
and detect errors in the final
results or a triple redundancy
systems um where all the
computations are being
replicated between the three
different um processors and they
in the end they perform a
majority vote about what the uh
correct output is. And this is
actually used in the autopilots
uh on uh commercial aircrafts
and uh I think also they use it
in space. The problem with uh
fault tolerant systems is that
uh they are they are built for
safety and they do their job
very well for that. But um for
complicated they replicated
computations but for security
tuh they don't transfer well at
all. Actually they’re bought for
security because what you end up
having is a system that has
three processors starting your
secret key. Um Meaning that uh
if one of your uh processors is
uh compromised and then um uh
you're prone to attacks so
instead of actually improving
your security you increase your
attack surface. For this reason
we came up with uh the solution
where we represent today. Which
provides protection and the
option for uh first steps of
these uh life cycle of keys. I
am Vasilios uh I did this work
with George Danezis, Dan Cvrcek
and Petr Svenda. And here are
the ingredients of our solution.
So we have two ingredients. One
of them is a hardware components
and the second is a
cryptographic protocols. And we
need specific things from uh
these kind of uh from these
components. So for ICs we need
the independent fabrications so
they must be fabricated in
different facilities and the
supply chain leading to them
should, their supply chains
should be non overlapping. Uh
they must be programmable um
hopefully affordable and if they
are commercial off the shelf but
that’s actually even better. Um
for cryptographic protocols we
want protocols that uh all the
parties that participate in them
are not trusted. That the
secrets are completely
distributed and allow them to
perform operations um in a
distributed matter instead of a
centralized one. And they’re
provably secure meaning there
are maths that support their uh
security. So, our um hardware
components are smart cards.
Because you have many dependent
manufacturers with who have
their own facilities to produce
smart cards. And the supply
chains are indeed disjoint. Both
in terms of locations, design,
and the foundries. They’re
programmable and they certify at
a very high level, high
standard. And they’re commercial
off the shelf and pretty cheap
actually. And then for the
protocols we have um multiparty
computation protocols which
allows you to do um distributed
operations meaning that the key
is not on a single point at
anytime and you can generate
random numbers in a restricted
matter. Um key pair do key pair
generation which is what we are
interested in. Decryption is
high which is what we are also
interested in. Um the two nice
products of those protocols is
that they allow you to be
securing cases where all but one
of your components are malicious
and they cooperate with each
other. Or they allow you to be
secure in cases where all your
components are malicious but
they don’t cooperate. So now Dan
is gonna take over and he’s
going to introduce our prototype
and then move on with our actual
demos. >>Alright thank you.
[applause] So with help of Jack
I’ll try to show you some live
demo. Uh and what was so far
pretty much slide here I’ll try
to turn it into a product. And
reproduct look about this. And
we got one prototype or one one
one piece here on the table and
I will try to use it for to show
how the multi party computation
security of the design actually
works. Uh so what’s inside the
box, uh we got many smart cards.
This this particular one has got
one hundred twenty of them. Uh
and the we were able to use them
in groups of three to basically
shows how scalable it is in
properties of protocol that we
designed. Uh Probably you say
well smart cards is pretty slow
cheap device. Well we can talk
to them directly at about one
megabit per second so in the box
basically we are talking for
than one hundred twenty megabits
per second to smart cards. So I
don’t see how one hundred twenty
megabits is really that slow
even today. Um there is FPGA to
connect all the pins together
and those ports are connected
with standard ethernet to
through some internal hardware
in mine internal port. And just
put it to a rack and use it in
scale. So here’s just the main
the main parts. So hundred
twenty smart cards. Use
JavaCards because they are easy
to program. And we need some
department for JavaCards so we
can use really very easily
JavaCards from different
manufacturers. Something
presented earlier at Def- at
Black Hat. Uh, so each smart
card gives you physical
security. Very good. Several
layers of physical security that
makes it very very difficult to
get inside and extract any keys.
Command of those things uh all
the memory and addressing in the
smart card is encrypted so just,
uh, deleting one AS key
basically destroys all the
information uh and makes it
basically random data. Uh we’ve
FPGA. That basically connects
JavaCards. All we use here are
protocol to [indiscernible]
JavaCards into basically TCP
packets. And then you got
internal network hop and main
Linux server that runs for us
basically on untrusted restful
server that allows connectivity
uh to outside. So we got three
demonstrations. Uh, so I will
try the first one which is about
showing geographically disputed
uh control of integrated
circuits. Uh what I will use is
my laptop. I will use a black
box that is next to me. It’s got
one hundred twenty smart cards
inside and runs the RESTful
server. I will talk to but I
will also try to connect to
instead of one hundred twenty
smart cards that are just now
sitting in our Cambridge office
in UK. So if everything goes
well. So we’ll load final
reports. So as almost all grey
or red because we don’t have any
data here yet. Let’s start uh
the root connector connect
RESTful server to the
ritualization report and now
let’s reach the pond. Now you
can see that what I actually did
is I started the server with
integration that shows two IP
address feeds that hide two sets
of smart cards. One is local
that goes in the server and
there’s one that goes all the
way to uh to the UK. Uh, through
some commercial ISP uh this is
an enumeration of the smart
cards. What it’s opening now is
basically the uh the RESTful
server uh should be starting any
second. So what is happening
when we look at the server try
to connect to all those smart
cards. It takes longer than
elsewhere. Still not-not
started. [inaudible off mic]
Yeah here we go. So it took a
while uh but again we go there
so now you could basically
available two hundred forty
processors that are each able to
basically run uh multiparty
computation for us. So the nice
thing about the system as we
designed it is that not only you
can use uh micro control
different geographic locations,
but each multi party
computation, each group can
contain processors that are in
different physical locations so
you can run that com processor
here in the room, another
processing Cambridge that one
actually can be JavaCard
simulator. And as such on any
platform with its own Intel and
SPARC so it gives you really
wide range of options to provide
different supply chains and
complete independent
manufacturing processes so
basically the only come on
point. When you start using
crypto-generated keys is a lot
of key stop generator key. So, I
will quickly switch pond off so
it should be much much bigger
now I go basically just local.
Local. I press for abort in
here. I change different report.
Also put. So something there
already and what I’m going to do
now is um use my laptop as a
low-low generator. I’m start
running the request against the
smartcards. So what I’m going to
do is basically create circuit
independent groups of smartcards
with search different keys that
can basically uh surf different
customers at the same time. So
instances been allocated and now
basically this is uh
transactions per second. We run
for about a minute. If I just
sort of bit of context imagine
that use bit chain or bock chain
uh technologic and you’ve got
five ten parties in a private
scheme and basically each
transaction needs ten signatures
by ten parties. What you can do
with this, this computation is
basically involve all those ten
parties but it will result in
just one signature. But you know
the signature needed cooperation
of all of them. So it’s much
easy to verify signatures cause
instead of going to ten
different uh lectures, you’ve
got uh just one, uh one master
copy that you could replicate
and verify independently. Right,
so this basically just
demonstration of the throughput
of the whole system. And the
scalability and the
possibilities will show a bit
more uh uh veros about our
previous tests. Uh that will it.
So the last demo is actual
showing how someone can try to
attack the whole system. But he
needs to put a lot of effort
into it to actually succeed. So
again just one server that is
running here. Uh A laptop
connecting it to it and I will
have a small group or chart of
smartcards that have got
backdoor inside. And yet I will
try to use a RESTful server, the
thing that is facing the
internet. I will try to set the
key that I will use to some kind
of default value so it can
easily decrypt data.So I gotta
change the dashboard to
something new. So I’m using
dashboard uh and also uh no
threats to basically connect uh
all the flows and show you
something meaningful. Oh it’s
bigger than I thought. Um anyway
there are two main flows. One is
to generate key. I don’t know
how well it is-it is visible. So
this is to generate the key and
then I got three triggers that
will allow me to compromise card
one, two, or three. Uh how it
happens is uh each time I’ll
need to create uh a RESTful
request that will allow open the
backdoor that will part in the
chip and then basically I will
try to generate key and see if
the key uh is all that I can use
and I assume that I expect so I
cannot take the whole system. Of
the first one will be, so let’s
go in slide on the dashboard. So
we’ve got sort of an initial
state. So now there are three
cards used because we needed
some extra than before. All is
green but you see that there is
no key and there is no-no group
that we can use. So let’s run
create. As a result I got now
three addresses so I can
certificate address for
integrated-integrate,
uh-integrated uh-uh circuits
that I will use. That requires a
little bit of clicking. What I’m
going to do is basically do all
that CR tech would do figure out
which of the uh processors uh
that he wants to compromise. So
this is the first one done. So
it’s second one. And the last
one. And I’m almost there. Bear
with me. So last bit I need is
to say to tell the key generate
algorithm which uh which group
of cards it should be using. So
confirm deploy. Make sure that
we’ve got all cards that there
are. Uh that they are secure.
Now we try to generate new key.
We got some delays here so you
cannot show the switch quickly.
So you see that there is now
public key and it’s different
than the fixed key that we know
the attacker set uh and wants to
wants to wants to run the chips
to share. So the first one that
is to compromise card one. So in
the inspector. So the card is
compromised. Takes a few
seconds. And now basically the
new uh new cards new
configuration will generate new
key that is changed. But you can
see that it’s still green. It’s
still secure. Uh imagine that
basically to get this it is
either easier to change the
firmware that can be uh verified
by us or controlled by different
parties or have to compromise
manufacturing of the chips
anywhere. Uh doing their
manufacturing process so if I do
part cards two. So compromised.
Now imagine that all those keys
are elected curve to two five
six bit keys. And if at least
one part is secure we’ve still
got two hundred and fifty six
bits of random data, random key.
So second attempt still didn’t
succeed. I’ll try finally the
third card. Now basically expect
assume the CR tech are
compromised three different
places, three different chips
that can be under control. Three
different parties. Manufactured
or running on different hardware
from-from chip manufacturers.
Now only that many does all
three of them you can see that
the keys as expected and now you
can basically decrypt all the
data that we’ve tried to encrypt
with the key. All for the
signature. On the other hand, if
I expect that this can happen
and regularly try to refresh the
uh the chips that I use. If I
refresh just one of them and
turn it into secure state then I
gain- get key that is absolutely
secure from uh cryptographing
point of view. Alright, so that
was bit of long demo and uh
Vasilios will tell you what it-
what is actually doing inside.
>> [applause] Kay thank you
again. So yes we build that
system um however in um so in
for our demos we used um a group
of cards that uh had three cards
inside to do all the
computations. However someone
for whatever reason he may wants
to use less or more cards so we
tried to obtain other protocols
rescalable. So for assigning a
decryption we do super well.
This means that uh you can use
as many cards as you want and
the processing time doesn’t
increase. In the processing time
cooperation. Uh for keys in
relation because we need very
high assurance. Uh this is not
the case but as you can see the
increase is linearly so it’s
it’s nicely it’s not like you
get a devastating delay. Uh for
scalability uh on our hardware
here we used a hundred and
twenty or two hundred and forty
if you use hardware remotely.
You can have as many um
processors as you want. As you
can see both operations
decryptions in signing signing
uh the throughput increases um
linearly so the more you add the
faster you become so depending
on your need you can uh you can
needs you can uh decide how many
processors you can you want to
use. So a little bit more about
the magic that’s going on behind
the scenes. Uh I keep I kept it
uh extremely light in terms of
mathematics. So there is nothing
there. Um so there are three
plus one key points that uh we
wanted for for it so far in the
algorithm you use. So the first
one is that there must be no
single processor handling
sensitive stuff such as secret
keys or anything else at any
time. Uh the second one is that
uh if one of the processors is
misbehaving and is trying to
actively attack other processors
or trick them into doing stuff
uh honest ones, honest
processors can detect that. The
third one is that if one of the
honest processors is being
excluded from the protocol
execution uh the user can
actually tell that this happen.
And finally if we could uh-uh
come up with a protocol or an
algorithm that’s uh is doing
well in terms of performance
which we did. So a little bit of
a side note, um secret setting
is a very neat concept. So
imagine you have three people
and they want to share uh a
treasure map. Uh the simple
solution would be uh so that
they can retrieve the treasure
only if all of them uh get
together again otherwise no one
can actually retrieve the
treasure map. So the nice
solution would actually be to
actually uh cut the uh the
treasure map in three pieces and
then uh each one of them gets
one of the pieces. However there
is a problem with this because
each people is leaking uh part
of the information of where the
treasure is and someone may be
able to successfully use this
information to retrieve the sec-
the treasure by himself. So we
use there are some schemes
called secret setting schemes
that they allow you to split the
secret into shares. And then you
they allow you to recombine the
shares to retrieve the original
secret to reconstruct it. Um but
they have this very neat
property that allows- that is-
that each share doesn’t leak any
information about the-the actual
secret. So as long as not all
shares um are present you learn
nothing about the actual secret
that they are hiding. And then
there are two parameters that
they usually can actually chose
to tweek. One is how many shares
you split the secret into. And
the second one is how many of
those shares you need to
reconstruct the original secret.
So you may actually cut the
treasure map into hundred shares
and then you need only three of
them to reconstruct the original
uh map. But in this case for our
hardware we use um three out of
three um scheme. So this means
that we split our secrets into
three and then you need three uh
processors to uh come together
to reconstruct them. Okay so
here are the operations. Classic
key generation. You go to the
HSM. You-you inquire a new
private key for yourself. If the
HSM um responds he generates a
key internally, stores a private
key inside, pretends to use a
public key. The problem is that
if the HSM has a malicious
processor this means that uh the
processor gains full access to
the private key and then the
public key that you are getting
back you have no idea if this is
uh some sort of a weak public
key or there’s any other problem
with that. Instead what we’ll do
is something different. So we
have three processors as you can
see the bottom of this slide. So
on the step one uh you inquire
them to generate the public k-uh
public private keeper. So they
generate the public keys and
then through a process they
combine them to form uh the
common public key that you can
see on step four. So what’s
interesting about the common
public key is that despite the
fact that all the keys except
one may be compromised as long
as the-as long as there’s one
key that’s strong uh the final
key is uh maintained and
secured. So going back to the
key points that we evaluate
algorithms with. Um we have all
of them except the one that uh
accounts for performance and
this is because on the step, on
step three there is no
interaction between the
processors so this means that
there is some slowness there.
We’ve seen it previously on
the-on the graph where we saw
how it scales. So then we have
decryption. Pretty similar
process. You go to the HSM. You
say I want to decrypt this
email. HSM knows you’re a key so
it decrypts the email for you it
tends to do in plaintext. Again
this is problem. The HSM needs
to have in a single place your
full key. Uh instead we do
something else. We do
distributed decryption so in
step one inquire uh from the HSM
to decrypt your ciphertext. Uh
what happens in the second step
the different processors
generate what we call decryption
shares. So the decryption shares
hold no information about the
plaintext. They are just shares
that then they send to-to Bob
and Bob can then combine them by
himself to retrieve the
plaintext. So the reason I
didn’t benefit from that because
the HSM never sees the actual
plaintext. All the decryption
process happens actually by the
user himself. Again we have all
the key points checked except
there must be having a processor
one. Because there is no
interaction between the um um
processors in this protocol it
makes no sense. I mean if you
misbehave then the cipher the
plaintext in the end will make
no sense. And it seems silly the
Trojan, the hardware of the
Trojan hardware will reveal its
existence and then the user will
know that something is going on
with his hardware. Um then we
have classic signing. Same
process. You supply plaintext
and you say I want to sign the
plaintext um the IC again needs
full access to your private and
then it returns you the
signature for uh for the
document you provided. Instead
uh what we do is a bit
different. So there is a first
step. Um or step zero. Which is
casing. So when you set up the
device you do some casing uh you
do this once for thousands of
signatures. So you takes uh
about um few minutes and you do
this only once in the lifetime
of the user. And then you move
on with the actual protocol. So
this is what you execute when
you want to sign the document.
What you do is you send the
document to the HSM. They
generate the signature uh
signature cells which are then
step three returned to the user
and the user combines them to
retrieve the signature for the
document. Again we’re very
efficient and at no point no one
learns uh the full um private
key of the user. However, so far
we’ve discussed cases where you
have only uh three processors
interacting but our hardware
uses many more so we have the
problem of how to make that
thing scale. And by scaling is
basically adding more groups of
cards. So we ended up adding
forty groups of cards and then
we had this key- this problem
with a key that yes, it’s card,
it’s group of cards can generate
its own public private keeper.
The problem is that how we can
make that key be consistent with
what’s the public key of Bob. So
can all those groups serve
request for- coming from Bob.
And we had to come up with
another protocol if that’s that.
And this is key what we call key
replication. So the naive way to
do that is you have let’s say
group A and group B. Group A has
the key for Bob. Um and then uh
the the processors inside the
inside the group serve um the
key serves with the processors
inside the Group B. On a one to
one basis. So this looks fine
however what happens is that if
processors um A1, uh B2, and A3
which we can see here is
malicious uh collude, they all
cooperate then they can retrieve
the actual secret. So this is
really bad and we don’t want
this to happen. Uh so this is
not clearly- Clearly this is not
the right way to do key
replication. What you do instead
is you split um each of the
processors is splitting its
secret with three secrets and it
distributes them to um um a
processors of Group B and then
this is how you do that uh in a
secure way. I’m not going into
details. It’s pretty easy from a
mathematical perspective but we
don’t need to know that. Um
what’s important is that both by
the end of the protocol both
groups A and B or whichever
other groups you may have. We
have forty here. You can have
more. Uh can serve requests for
the same public key that belongs
to Bob or whoever else. So now
the politics part of the of the
uh talk. So initially. So so far
we’ve been saying that our
system provides security as long
as there is at least one
processor in the system so you
can have many malicious ones but
if there is one that is not
honest them you’re okay. However
this is not always the case or
you cannot always be sure that
not all your components are a
backdoor. And to be to be um
accurate. The adversaries that
are capable of introducing
hardware backdoors or Trojan
horses are mainly governments
and because they have access to
deep access fabrication
facilities. They use very
sophisticated techniques and
they-their Trojans and their
techniques are very hard to
detect. And if you detect
usually you’re not sure if it's
an error or a bug or a
manufacturing mistake or an
actually malicious act. However
they are very secretive and all
those things are highly
classified and there is no
chance that they will share the
details of their backdoors with
anyone. And we were thinking if
we could exploit this and how.
So what what this entails is
that we are unlikely to collude
or cooperate with any adversary.
Uh any other adversary. So if
you remember the um uh MPC
protocols, multiparty
computation protocols provide
the security guarantees against
another class of adversaries.
Adversaries that are all
malicious but they don’t
cooperate. So in this case what
you can do is basically you can
buy processor from the US,
another one from China and
another one from Russia but they
are fabricated there. And even
if all of them are backdoored
you can be certain that they
will never cooperate and they
will never reveal their
backdoors um one to the other.
So you’re safe and secure
despite your hardware being
super compromised. So concluding
this talk um we yes we
introduced the hardware that can
tolerate faulty and malicious
hardware. Uh we have decent
performance that we have scaled
nicely so you can move this uh
you can serve as many requests
as you need. Um we use uh off
the shelf components and this is
neat so we will show you later
how this is very nice. And then
all the techniques that we’ve
discussed about trusted
foundries, split manufacturing
and these kind of things um you
can of course uh source
components that manufacture
securely to increase the
security of the system. We’re
not competing with them. We can
actually use them. So what’s in
this thing is that yes we took
it to an extreme. We built a
hardware but what you can do is
you can build your own um
hardware tolerant device. Uh
it's pretty easy. Uh you can buy
USB hub and a few card readers
depending on how many processors
you want to have. Uh you can
download our MPC applet. Buy
some cards from different
countries. Do your research
there. Where they’re-where
they’re coming from. Which
manufacturer has its own
fabrication facility and where
this is located. Uh some of them
are actually um providing um
details or you have to pay a
little bit more and then they
are produced in specific
fabrication facilities. So
download your applet afterwards.
Review the code. Please do that.
And then uh yes we upload your
applet in the cards and you have
your homemade HSM that can serve
not many requests but I don’t
expect that the single user will
generate thousands of keys per
hour or something. And yeah.
That was it. Thank you.
[applause]