>>Uh, topic of this talk is opt
out or deauth trying. It's going
to be anti-uh, tracking, bots,
radios, and keystroke injection.
It's going to be throwing off
brick and mortar stores. Um, the
ways that they're tracking you.
Um, everything from billboards,
um down to the the basic uh,
analytics and information that
Google collects when you do
searches and things of that
nature. I'll have the slides in
one second here. [mic bump]
Sweet. I will get this playing
here. [chuckles] Ah, there we
go. Awesome, now you got some
visuals to go along with it. So,
as I said my name is Weston
Hecker. Feel free to follow me
on Twitter. I do a lot uh
research during the year and uh
I love helping people with
projects and just security
research in general. I'm going
to go into a little bit of
detail we’ll make it a little
bit quick here. Um, about
myself, I’m 32, work for NCR
live in North Dakota. Any other
North Dakotans? No OK. [laughs]
[audience laughs] There's
probably six of us >>WAHOO >>ah
yea, OK There's one or two of
them. Uh, let's look ahead. This
is my fourth year in a row
speaking at DEFCON, uh, spoke at
Hope, um, Black Hat last year,
lots of conferences, so I love
getting out meeting the
community. That's the reason I
do these talks is to meet people
like you guys. So, and I have
been doing uh 12 years pen
testing professionally and uh 13
years of research programming.
Things along that and uh, I did
a lot of ATM car hacks, um
several IOT projects going on
right now. Uh, reverse
engineering malware things like
that. Um, I'm going to be doing
an uh, cool uh, attack on
vehicle the, does anybody have a
push button start car? You
should definitely come down to
the car hacking village. I'm
going to demo um, uh, how to
stop the relay attacks where
pe..it it's a bas- basically
people are using software to
find radios to actually steal
vehicles. So, I'm going to go
into how the actual attack
works, then I'm going to go into
uh, some two factor
authentication that I added
that's built on a 12 dollar
arduino project. So it's very
cool. And uh a little bit about
this research and what led to
it. Uh, so as you can see
Microsoft, uh, Window 7, end of
life was all announced and uh, I
mainly use Linux uh like a
majority of the people here
probably do, but I am forced uh
to use uh, Windows for some
applications and I had a quick
uh, question I called one of my
buddies and I'm sure everybody
has that buddy that you call
them for that simple about uh,
um a some pr- uh some concerns
and things like that and they'll
uh talk your ear off about
chemtrails for the next hour and
a half. So, [laughter]. He's a
very, very paranoid guy. Um,
he's usually right though. Uh,
he's uh, added uh validity
several times when I've talked
to him. So, and he's helped with
uh tons of my research
especially my uh, cell phone
hacking one I did in uh, DEF CON
22. So, which, yeah that's
basically I did as research I
started uh, installing Windows
10 in most of my machines. And,
uh, yea. [chuckles] Explains, uh
what systems I've used in the
past. Uh how they do in store
tracking operating systems uh
switching to Windows 10 like I
was saying which is kind of
scary, scary thought and uh
searching search engines spying
uh uh Google. I know they track
all your analytics. Uh Bing
probably does too, but nobody
uses it. So [laughter] [laughs]
And I'm going to go into actual
uh billboard spying. Um there's
a couple proto type billboards
and I'm pretty sure I fried the
one in Minneapolis in 169. Uh, I
was doing some research on it. I
had permission at that time. So,
it's uh something that they want
They're actually tracking
vehicle TPMS sensors so tire
pressure monitor sensors and
they're profiling people off of
vehicles and the actual
advertisements so and yea, yea
that's pretty interesting stuff.
so, um, uh, just privacy is
disappearing so I thought I
would do a privacy talk and uh,
yea. Explanation of the targeted
personalized advertising so I'm
going to go through a lot of the
advertising um, personalized
ads. Um, they're getting really,
really creepy. They got really
creepy for a while there and
then they realized that people
were getting creeped out and
they kind of backed them off a
little bit. Um, behav- behavior
advertising cookies, um, I'm
going to go into they track you
on, basically, what your
hobbies, automotive,
electronics, travel, where
you've been, things like that.
Um, collection of non
identifiable information, so
they tell you that it's a lot of
it's metadata but there's been
plenty of talks in the past of
how to reverse um, metadata.
There was actually some medical
ones where they had people that
had um, diseases and things like
that that they were actually to
reverse able to reverse those
two specific people once there
was an actual uh breach. So, yea
and uh real time bid information
which is one of the buzz words
that's out there so basically
people are buying us like we're
cattle and uh this is basically
geared at jacking up every
single analytical they use for
it and making the data
completely useless. And, uh, yea
so they have software
advertising displays. Um, uh
private marketing um, PMP. Uh,
basically wasting um,
advertiser’s money and yea,
there's uh explanation of
technology uh tracking online so
I'm going to go through some of
them. I'm gonna explain how deep
and dive in the operating system
are and when you try to uh, uh
neuter Windows 10 how it fights
back. [chuckle] because it is a
very, very intrusive operating
system. Um, yea it's it's uh
what's to be expected when you
know they are pushing a lot of
those updates and stuff like
that. So, how it impacts the
users. How it impacts the
business. Um, I know that's
something where I don't mind if
you know they know what my
mother's doing on a day to day
basis or I'm sure she doesn't
either, but when it's your
actual employees, um, if anybody
is in the sys admin or security
uh admin role and uh it makes a
lot of these call in services um
hard to track, especially when
we're trying to see if things
are calling out or Trojans or
droppers or any kind of malware
is calling out and stuff like
that. It adds a lot of tr-
.unnecessary traffic. And I'm
going to go into GPS tracking.
I, uh, off of IP addresses, uh
so on the whole they'll track
what an entire company is doing.
If they have one IP address, so.
WIFI Beakuer- uh beacon
information. So how they uh,
actually go through cellular
tracking and um, um turn on WIFI
for accuracy. Obviously, uh
everybody has their WIFI off
here, but uh, there's you know,
on in the average world when
you're walking around the mall
it's amazing to me the
information they collect . And
uh, yea, arts, entertainment
this is some of the actual
breakdowns of how ads are
personalized and uh sales a bit.
It's very, very boring stuff. I,
I feel, [chuckles] that I don't
need to go into much detail on
this and I'm sure I've got a lot
of you guys have have done a lot
of research on actually running
ad blockers or black holing
advertisements. Um , I recommend
that for everybody, not only
just for security purposes but
even legitimate web pages can
have drive by attacks um, there
are several exploit kits that
um, um have had have drive bys
in the past on legitimate web
pages, place- pages that I would
visit without any hesitation
normally. So, and yea. So there
are some uh good ways to stop
tracking uh right now and I just
wanted to uh uh give a plug to
some of these they are all open
source. Uh They're all free. Um,
so they have ad blocker apps.
They have um, actual black holes
which basically the advertisers
don't know that their ads aren't
being showed, which is a little
more stealthy. Um, Trackmenot is
the actual uh hypervisor version
that I wrote as a plug in for
um, uh, the uh actual program at
this IO address. It's pretty
amazing it literally crawls the
entire web [chuckles] web page
that you send it to and it will
click all the advertisements. In
a safe manner obviously. Uh, but
it basically jacks up a lot of
it and I actually added a
hypervisor version because they
banned this plugin on Chrome. So
I got it so it's working on
Chrome again and it actually
does um uh lots of XML injection
er um a keystroke injection into
the actual browsers themselves
so it's something where um it
happens at a later where you're
not going to trigger a lot of
the uh, I'm not a robot and a
lot of the security features. So
that is something I'm also
releasing open source and it'll
uh, I'll have a working version
for uh VMware, that once it's
out of the beta phase here,
everyone will be able to
download it and if as long as
you have VMware workstation or
um some of the open source will
also work for it. So the OVAs
you'll be able to launch them
and uh, I'll go into a little
bit of uh, other things that I
am actually blocking from
Microsoft. So, and uh yea. The
e- uh- Privacy Badger is a
really good EFF loves porting
them. Uh, there's paid VPNs uh 4
dollars a month. You can get a
decent VPN service. Um some of
the free ones, who knows what
they did. It's uh, [chuckles]
probably worse than uh letting
them know your advertising is
some of the stuff that those IP
addresses were previously used
for. So that's something that I
would uh definitely recommend
that you do your due diligence
when you're checking into that
stuff so. And it's all a very
good start um tackling some of
the call homes um doing a uh
actual blocker on the hosts
files so it blocks a lot of uh
Microsoft call home type stuff.
Uh, turning off your peer to
peer networking um for updates
and stuff like that. So and uh
what do I have against Ads
Weston? That's uh that's what my
wife asked me and, uh [chuckle],
yea I know it's something that
um I don't mind at all. I hate
having advertisements. Anytime
they offer something like uh, uh
youtube red or something like
that where it'll they still
collect a lot of information but
it's something where if I don't
have to see an advertisement I
will gladly pay for it. I'm not
trying to uh, that's the way
that the internet is free, I
understand that. Um it's all, I
will I will gladly pay for a lot
of the uh, uh, premium services
and anything that's ad free and
uh even some of the android
stuff it's uh amazing that you
can't actually you know turn off
a lot of the tracking and it's
something that, um, as the more
and more they they can snag you
with the convenience and then
they add some of the more
intrusive stuff and that's just
been happening over uh the last
few years. So, yea and um I'm
going to be able to um, um
should go into some yea uh
disable some of the browsing
tracking. They let you know
there's cookies. They try to do
all these things to let you know
uh, what they're doing or make
you, make them look like they're
more of an accurate and good
demonstration of what they're
actually doing but uh in a lot
of cases, um, it it needs a
little bit more intervention and
that's why I love that there's
uh tools like on these last page
here that people can actually go
out and do this kind of stuff.
So, and yea, so basically drive
by attacks, like I was saying
even legitimate web pages um,
uh, there's a lot of them that
even the uh New York Times is
one of the bigger ones that
comes to mind. Um, that page
they uh literally send out
Twitter saying that their actual
um page is breached, please
don't visit it. So, uh yea that
was a drive by I believe it was
a java or a flash drive by
attack. so it was literally just
by visiting the page it would uh
actually execute some of the
code on there. so, uh since the
late 90's it's been one form or
another in tracking and uh
they're um yea their uh deep
diving they're getting their
analytics more tight and uh it's
been used in stores. Uh, the
act- actually the brick and
mortars I'm sure everybody in
2012 heard about these you know
they're tracking everything and
the stores that were doing it
got a lot of feedback that was
negative so they quit doing it
and then they tried it again two
years later, heh and uh they're
right back up to the same old
tricks. so that's something
where um, in the in store
analytics it's no problem at all
I have no problem at all if
people opt into it, um that's
definitely like something if
somebody wants to save 10
percent, 10 cents on their gas
or something by all means if
that's something they accept, I
have no problem with at all with
that, but it's when um, uh they
actually you know start tracking
cellular beacons of how many
customers walk by, their
attention rates, their dwell
times in the store and things
like that. I'll actually go into
some heat mapping analytics and
things like that. So, which
that's uh, yea I have no problem
at all with opt in programs.
That's one of the biggest
things. so they uh track some of
the bluetooth cellular beacons,
uh, wifi, uh, infrared and
motion sensors, Um, yea, several
years they began getting
negative press like I said so uh
there's been lots of of
resistance on all forms of
tracking. Apple and a couple of
other several manufacturers are
doing very, very randomized
beacon information which is
awesome to see and uh it's
definitely been a long time
coming for it. So uh, UK and
other uh areas in the world been
less resistance from what I've
seen. I know a lot of uh, um.
actual tracking that they have
out there is pretty, pretty
readily available. So, I'm told
it's been turned into meta data
and I've already explained about
some of the weaknesses in
metadata and reversing it and uh
this the 45 dollar device that
uh everyone single one of you
should bring and go to the mall
with you every time cause uh,
this actually, uh basically what
it is it's a huge uh wireless
beacon generator and it actually
it can generate up to a 150
beacons, um and they can be one
of several things. It can either
be, um, so it can either be uh,
cellular beacon, so they make it
look like a customer's walking
around they can actually be
rogue access points, they can be
pretty much anything you can
generate cellular with a laptop
you can now generate with these
and uh I actually have a program
called Groundhog's Day where it
replays the exact same days
worth of traffic so it looks
like the same people are walking
by and uh, huh huh, it is a
pretty neat neat process and
actually jacks up there uh in
store analytics, their retention
rates, all the heat mapping, uh,
cause uh with the more advance
version with the actual
Raspberry Pi attached to it, you
can um actually change where
people are dwelling in the store
and stuff like that so it's a a
really really cool project and a
a that's all going to be open
source on my key lessons I will
release how to actually build
one of those. Um, I highly
recommend it. They're pretty fun
uh if you haven't played with
wireless before. So [off
microphone statement] Oh, sorry
about that, yea thank you. And
um metadata is used to change
the store lay outs. So, say for
example, if uh everybody goes to
the front panel they're going to
you know start throwing the more
high price items there things
like that. Um, if they realize
everyone is going back to
electronics right away they're
going to put a lot of the stuff
to try to sell to people with on
the way there. And more
specifically lay lay outs
increase sales and make us more
along the lines of uh just
consumers. So, and using regards
programs um yea like I said opt
ins I have no problem with that.
Uh I did a little research on
some of the coupons that are
pushed and some of the actual
bluetooth tracking. Um, those
things are literally built for
like the year 2023. They're uh
not impossible to break but I uh
did not have the time the uh
free time this to year to
actually start uh dabbling with
this. Uh, last year I actually
did um some uh ticketed
injection but I did the
responsible disclosure with it
so it's something where I
wouldn't yea it wouldn't work
anymore so nobody would really
care. Heh, for the majority of
it so. So they increase how much
they >>Move the mike closer.
>>Oh, sorry about that. Yea,
here we go. And uh yea so
basically they can increase how
much they charge for certain
store areas if people have it in
there. So [audience laughing and
clapping] Sorry about that guys.
Heh, heh. Yea, thanks for the
brave soul that told me to a
bring it up a little closer so
uh. So uh yea it changes the ad
placement in the physical and
the web because they are
tracking across platforms. So,
and they have all the collection
on the cellular bluetooth
beacons so they're collecting
all DSN information um they have
actual they've weaned away from
this one big time because it's
uh very very intrusive and um
some of them have pretty decent
ranges on them so um they're not
as um acceptable for as far as
if people are going through
actual uh communication with
them. So, and uh how do you
harden the communication best
practices? Um, yea that's
something I will be going
through here in a little bit.
So, and uh who knows what TPMS
sensors are for vehicles? Yea,
there's been lots of really
really cool research. Um, uh so
they have smart billboards. Uh,
they just throw the word smart
in front of it and charge people
for it but it something where
gonna basically be tracking
beacons. They'll be able to
profile the you know that that
guy driving that 2015 Jeep
Cherokee or whatever. They'll be
able to tell that that person's
most likely a white, 32 year old
male and they will be able to
answe..uh uh get more of the
advertisements or they'll be
able to uh you know generalize
how much they're actually are
able to charge for some of the
information, be able to track
people a lot more and uh in the
US uh after 2007 they required
it it in a majority of the
vehicles except for special pur
uh purpose built vehicles. Uh so
basically it uses unencrypted RF
um 350..um 314 uh majority of it
so depending on the actual
vendor. Anytime you go over 19
miles per hour it will do a call
home feature, so and um I'm
going to be actually [mouth
sounds] uh demoing the uh in the
car hacking village I have a
TPMS sensor where you can
actually add 3 sets of tires to
your vehicle so that's something
that Ford owners have not been
able to do without going into a
dealership all the time. So it's
something where you can have
your snow tires, racing tires,
but I, and your um whatever you
know whatever other kind of tire
other tires you want. Um and
something that um I actually
made it so my wife my wife's
vehicle every time it starts up
it will actually generate a new
uh TPMS sensor and it will flash
it into her cam bus so it will
it's pretty hard to actually
track the vehicle and it's just
one step further uh hopefully
people will adopt those kind of
things uh once they start
tracking more of that beacon
information. So, and uh
yeah, that right now that's one
of majorities that they're
actually testing and I'll be
doing the demo of that on an
actual car hacking village. So
yea and everybody's for the most
part I don't need to go into
social media. Uh, that is
literally just that is pretty
much nothing but data
collection. Um, there's been
several jokes. I love one of the
Onion ads where they had Mark
Zuckerberg is like an FBI agent
and it's uh heh heh yea they got
some pretty accurate stuff like
that and it's uh abused in the
past um it's just they're
literally just tracking
everything on it and it's it's
something that we that they
willingly accept to be able to
uh you know send cat memes and
things like that to each other.
So, and uh, reversing the
randomness so when I went
through an actual pages it was
pretty simple. I uh start with a
dummy account on a VPS and it
would start searching a specific
dialogues um of things that I
would think that people's
personalities. I would think of
a friend and then I would think
of things that they would search
and I would think of that age
right now. I would think of my
niece and things she would
search. What my cousin would
search. What my uncle would
search. A lot of that stuff, so
that's something that where I
was kind of looking at what they
were reversing and what they
were advertising with. So I
built out a huge uh spread sheet
that is actually gonna be
something else I'll also be
releasing with these tools. Um
and it basically shows that what
what what you're profile and how
to build a profile cause that's
actually what the uh program
that I made is you can set
yourself to say for example the
example I was giving was a 12
year old girl who likes horses
and uh you you'll be looking at
how to flash um a firmware on it
ubertooth one and the next thing
you know she your searching if
does he like me you know where
are the best horse ranches.
Things like that. so, You will
be able to throw in some pretty
random details and it's actually
a plug in for uh that amazing
program that I was talking about
earlier um they they do a very,
very good job at random stuff,
but uh some of the random stuff
that you gets thrown into
unlogical bins where they don't
even get advertise to or they
get very very low resale. So
these actually keep you looking
like a real person on the web uh
because eventually when enough
people start using blocking
services like that they're going
to start actually deep diving
into a little bit more into the
actual uh details and the
software of it. So, and yea back
into the old XPDs uh they really
didn't store store much
information. Huh, huh. and uh
yea 1984 style moving into
Windows it's literally amazing
the uh amount of information
they collect and I have been a
huge fan of uh doing
misinformation type talks like
the the one that I actually did
was um uh injecting fake credit
card numbers for credit card
skimming software. So, like it's
like it's all about like if I
can't have my data, nobody can
kind of situation. So, it's like
it becomes so useless they won't
actually want it anymore and
that's kind of the thought in
the process behind it. And, yea.
An explanation of attacks so
blocking the billboard spying um
I'm going to go through that
with a TPMS sensor and uh
explaining the actual main
attack surface of the past
several monitoring systems. So
how brick and mortar stores are
spying on people and how web and
OS are spying on people, so that
will be the next phase of this.
And uh some methods of stopping
some billboard spying. Since
billboards there >>Louder! >>Oh,
they're picking up uh this, this
microphone. I apologize really
here. So, [laughs] so, smart
billboards they capture the
wireless sensor information. Uh,
they capture all but based on
the model year of the car, the
age range, income range. Uh, if
you're if you're driving a brand
new Lexus you're most likely not
a McDonald's employee and they
like to profile it like that and
that that's just one more of the
things where it dehumanizes a
lot of the information. So, and
uh passive and opt in programs
once again like I said uh people
have a lot of applications for
tracking through a lot of the
extra moldings uh uh public
transit systems and stuff like
that so and like I was saying uh
you can add um a lot of the not
not necessity of having to go
into a dealership which is
really really nice because um uh
Ford and Lincoln vehicles is the
one that have the tool that I'm
working for now and it's nice to
actually be able to install um
uh like a Groundhogs Day type of
situation, so you cycle through.
The one that I have that would
be more practical is adding a 10
tire TPMS sensors and cycling
through them. Uh so that's
something where it's not
randomly generating them uh
because that is a bit more of a
lengthy process especially um uh
once a week you actually have to
do a hard flash uh to actually
add some of your TPMS sensors.
So, and yea, so what's being
collected and then what allow
them to uh profile me online
that was one of the the biggest
things that was uh the
collection of the information
once I logged it all uh it's
something that was it was pretty
interesting. Um, what slight
changes would uh change in
advertisements and things along
those natures especially when
it's starting to getting into
getting into higher profile
travel um you can also see where
people are spending a lot of the
money, uh, for actual click to
pay advertisements and stuff
like that. So, uh, how do they
use it? Uh, who who is it
interested to? Who's buying it?
Uh, how is the information held
against people. They've uh done
there's actual FBI portals uh
and things like that for you
know a lot of this information
so they don't have to actually
submit warrant er, they have to
do warrants and everything like
that they have to do the the due
process. It's just something
that they actually have to uh
yea they have to keep it up so.
And how's that yea all the
information for portals for law
enforcement uh one of the
biggest ones I have known is the
the ones for an actual cellular
communications. So, and yea, um.
So basically injecting the pulse
data, uh, changing your profile
um how much information do you
have to do to combat your years
of of profiling. Um, one of the
biggest things I did a couple of
years ago was I started like 3
Google accounts and then I
switched in between them. Didn't
even trick them because of a lot
of the information that they
picked up they still profiled it
as the same person. Um so I'm
going to go into a little bit of
the profiling changing and
actually throwing off some of
the lower level analytics and uh
who knows what type fisting is?
Huh, huh. Yea it's uh like a
World War 2 based on when people
did the tap the actual morse
code and stuff like that It's
something where they would have
been able to tell where somebody
was in Germany based on the
actual way that they typed their
information and that's one of
the actual analytics set up that
uh that Windows 10 is collecting
so that's part of that
hypervisor that I built is it
actually collects your all of
your keystrokes and actually
injects them out and into the
operating system or whatever
your selected tab is and uh in
for and um 38 you can select the
stroke per minute depending on
how fast you type but it
basically pops it out so there's
no type fist so it can't tell if
it's you using your computer or
your wife using your computer
and uh there's a couple other uh
ways that you could do a lot of
this stuff um it can be used for
injection of typing um you can
do um I'm working on mouse click
uh emulation and simulation
that's undetectable and things
like that, so, it will be a a
pretty decent project once it's
uh plea..complete so and then
we're going to go through
through the browser bot and uh
how to not get det..detected by
search engines and web browser
programs that was one of the
biggest things uh right away it
was uh kept busting me and it
just was a little disheartening
at first so but yea uh so yea. A
lot of the r..um, I'm not a
robot uh who who saw that
originally they got like how
hard can that be to beat, then
they try to beat it. Huh, yea
it's actually huh a pretty well
thought out process um uh so a
lot of the it's not just about
the clicking it's about the
naturalness of how it is clicked
so that's something that we're
um if you're able to push mouse
clicks from a hyper visor um
it's a lot more uh accurate in
detail and you can tune it a lot
better and it also makes it so
that everybody can use it you
don't have to have low level
details of actually how to um
program a lot of the stuff so
and yea and so yea you can
basically um go through the joys
of watching your advertisements
change first hand. You can throw
off your analytics a little bit
and um based on your actual
advertisements you can reverse
that to what they profile you as
and as that that's actually
pretty creepy uh based on the
actual data based information
you can actually see that they
know that you're, you know, in
your mid 30's and you love
vehicles and computers or
whatever your ser..uh things
are. So there's ways to actually
go uh the reversing process it's
uh it's a pretty decent process
if you guys haven't ever mapped
anything out like this, um
search engines are really really
easy to do and it's uh
definitely something if you're
wanting to get into a data
project with some of your
friends. So, and yea, basically
uh yea. This mal ware can
actually be used to uh do bad
things. So you could actually uh
like a hypervisor like that I
was looking at that where
somebody could actually use it
as frameware. They could make
people visit bad web pages
things like that so that's one
more reason that you're going to
want to integrate something that
will keep track of what your
actual analytics are and what
it's actually conveying and you
can actually frame somebody uh
it could basically damage
somebody's life or even worse it
could like Nickelback on
Facebook. So, [audience
laughing] Huh, huh, I just had
to bash on Nickelback because
they are the worse worse thing
to come. but yea, and uh there's
basically a um yea yea it's also
used um if you want to do some
testing for malware a lot of the
mal ware looks to see if the
virtual machine is used and it's
something where you can get some
actual um real real world case
usage um I know it's something
uh without paying you know
really expensive BMs that are
specifically for bursting mal
ware it's something you could
make virtual machines look like
they have daily usage in them.
So it's something where you want
to kick a payload off or where
it kicks off 3 weeks later or
something you would actually be
able to do a bit more research
on it, so, and yea basically
it's the operating systems and a
yea. So how I tried to make
Windows 10 uh go off the grid,
kind of, uh was basically by you
know redoing some of the hosts
seeing what it's calling out to
Um, others have done that in the
past others have failed um I
failed the first few times I did
it um there's actually very good
tools um out there for blocking
a lot of days they get turned
right back on as soon as you run
an update though so that's
something where uh I'll be
posting some of that research
and a little bit more about uh
deep dive into the operations
systems of uh cause I'm sure a
lot of you guys are adopting
either for your actual users or
for your actual self uh
switching over to Windows 10
from Windows 7 and uh actually
injecting from the hypervisor
and how much information the
actual uh OS detects before like
a lot of the um errors and
issues and things like that will
actually submit those um and
there's uh pretty much anything
that was getting sent home to
Microsoft I have made a way to
send them bulls**t. so it was a
pretty fun fun it was a fun
project and it was uh I love
watching actual responses of it
so and uh yea. IP version 6 and
how it changes spying on us uh
some of the real time
communication um that is uh yea
some of it for as far as it like
breaking um anonymity on the web
there's lots of actual
information out there for it so
yea screen sizer uh screen
sizing and browser information
that was uh one of my bigger
breakthroughs when I was um
going through how they were
actually uh tracking a lot of uh
uh um um details from some of
the posts and get requests and
things like that so and uh type
fisting is something that um yea
it's basically uh something
Windows 10 they've been uh
collecting I don't see any
reason that they would need to
do that uh aside from per user
basis. Um there's some pretty
cool uh research on people like
being able lock machines if they
feel that somebody else is
typing at the machine or
something like that uh so I've
seen a couple of programs like
that and a type fisting app
would be able to be a pen
testing tool for something like
that but but yea no so we do the
XML and HTML injection uh yea
and it's basically a macro based
injection so um I add the most
simple simple version of it is
ghost writer if you want it to
literally inject things out of
uh uh text file you can do that.
Um you can use some of the plug
ins for some of the other
applications that are out there
and uh yea there's like I said
it interacts with other programs
by um if they're brought to
front or if they're a select a window
and you can change a lot of the
functionality with that um there
are some CV plugins that people
have um for desktop support uh
applications and I'll also be
posting and referencing to so um
and can Windows stop this and
it's easy to use so it something
that um I have not seen um
Microsoft combat any of the uh
actual anti type fisting or any
of the hyper visor inner
intervention. That's something
that where it also does a lot of
really really cool stuff like
blocking um some of the hid
attacks like human interbase
stuff like device attacks it
blocks like some of the bash
bunny attacks uh because it
basically hijacks any input um
quite literally any input unless
it's uh uh pre detected device
so and you can uh also have it
released so it's a very very
cool concept and yea I'm excited
to see people's feedback on it
and yea be able to grow it and
see what other people do and
maybe other people can clean up
the code. There's a lot better
programmers out there than me so
and yea basically blocking out
the outputs from your phone
there's a couple programs out
there that um uh are pretty nice
that you don't have to actually
rip you phone which is amazing
because I know several years ago
if you wanted to delete uh the
foot like the like I know there
are some guys that are computer
guys and football guys but I
have no interest at all in the
NFL or Nascar or some of that
other stuff they have loaded
onto my phones and it's just
nice to have be able to have uh
yea uh basically it frees ways
to get rid of all that
information so and um yea so you
can generate um also there's um
a lot of applications that will
read 50 SMS messages a day or
they'll read 50 emails and uh
they have their end user license
agreement or EUA 50 uh where
they have the they basically
read your emails so they can
better tailor uh either your
typing or your auto completion.
They'll give you a lot of
examples like that but it's uh
most likely for other uses so
yea and airplane mode um working
on making uh I have an HGC1 or
HGC 10 now and I I did a PRL
hack so it actually doesn't
attach to uh fake uh fake cell
phone towers. and also I'm
having a DEFCON mode and I'm
sure a couple of other people
have the switch on the side of
their laptop that they used as
DEFCON mode before but yea
basically it turns off your
radios does not allow you to uh
turn off your radios it reminds
you a week before to change all
your one time passwords call in
information so and yea I'm going
to go over the actual hardware
that I'm going to be demoing
here in a second and uh this is
actual look into the in store
tracking systems. So heat
mapping so they track how many
people walk by the store and
they see how many people
actually walk into the store.
where the people actually dwell.
Um so this device actually I
just ordered as many radio 8 O 2
11 compliant things as I could
and started slapping them on an
arduino and it's a pretty fun
project I definately recommend
you build them you can build
them for around 35 to 45 dollars
and uh it basically um..uh
there's a collection mode where
you can collect the beacon's
like I was saying for a
Groundhog's Day type attack or
you can actually ee edit your
own text files and then you can
pop in your own beacon
information so you can basically
have it look like hundreds and
you know if you built one bigger
than this or you actually got a
full blown boards on these ones
you could actually build it out
to the point where you could
have uh 3 to 400 access points
so or beacons or whatever those
things and uh heat mapping. Uh
so there's an actual threshold
um so there's basically they
attract people there’s classic
people tracking awesome OK yes
there's classic people tracking
and it's going to go through um
you know actual infrared. It
will count a ticker it's
literally just as if somebody is
uh tripping an I beam. So I
actually built an infrared
blocker for that. A heat mapping
my actual application when you
hook it up to Raspberry Pi you
can make it look like people are
walking in a circle in a store
and it is really really creepy I
couldn't use the actual software
uh because I would most likely
get sued or at least get a cease
and desist letter uh but yea
it's uh pretty interesting stuff
there's um uh older software
that is really really fun to see
the reactions of it so and yea.
I'm going to be uh er..the
actual device that's going
through here so you can ba..
basically um look at the strange
responses from the uh uh the
actual system and it will uh do
some of the uh re-beaconing and
some of the other device
reactions so and this is the
actual radio that we're going to
be demoing here and yea this is
a CB based so yea they basically
uh you peel the threshold with a
really really high powered
infrared laser uh you can
basically um yea. It basically
makes all the uh actual
analytics shut down um so after
about an hour of this um it had
useless data after 3 hours it
literally made the entire store
black like that . [laughs] and
it yea it was pretty decent so
but yea I'm going to go into the
actual demo here um yeah I'm
going to actually let it uh lay
waste to the actual um software
find radio or I got a actual
capture of of the wireless
packets so I'm going to go
through that here in a second so
I'm going to go into the actual
demonstration and then uh yea.
I'm going to do the Groundhog's
Day attack and then I'm going to
do the dwelling time attack so
it's going to jack up all the
dwelling time and um on this
computer here I will show uh
while I'm getting this demo
setup I will actually show you
uh, which is not that
interesting of a demo, but uh I
will do that while I actually
set up the software finding
radio demo so uh and yea. I
would just like to give thanks
to my work, um my kids, my wife
who’s very very patient with me,
uh Jesus, my Uncle Staci for
giving me my first Zenith easy
PC, um DEF CON for having me
speak for the fourth year in a
row. It's an honor and uh
audience for listening to me and
especially when I have to bobble
a microphone in front of me. I
have to I apologize for that and
I can't wait to hear the trolls
on youtube on that one so..
[laughing] huh,huh hey they
already said I sound like Beavis
and Butthead on my last talk
because I have nervous stuff
that comes out but yea follow me
on twitter guys and uh
definitely uh thanks again
audience it’s uh you guys are
what make DEF CON and I really
do mean that so and yea I’m
going to kick off the demo here
so [silence] so here we go, oop
[microphone sound] let's get
this here yea so this one
basically is uh uh one of the
text implementations of the
actual uh Word profile so this
one is a plugin for uh this
application here which basically
uh it will go through and
literally troll all the pages. I
did not write this program it's
something that uh I um am a huge
fan of supporting and I
definitely want to plug it on
something where it literally
goes through and clicks on all
the advertisements. Um they used
a randomness that was something
that I saw as a a eventual
weakness, but it's something
where um you can now actually
load your own profile in there
and um you can build um sur
channel on actual uh yea so
that's basically gonna go
through here what it actually
will track here. Let's see. Yea
so you can go through all the
settings it's an amazing tool
and it's uh very very easy um to
actually modify if you guys
wanted to start injecting your
own profile information. I'm
going to be releasing the actual
app for that here soon so. Let's
see. Yea I'm going to be
powering up my radio here and uh
yea. I’m going to get my Cali
machine going so one second
[microphone sound] here we go.
So I’m just going to get airomon
running here in a second Here's
what an idle DEFCON looks like.
Here we go. [off-mic comments]
>>OK If you guys want to open up
to questions too feel free to
approach the microphone
[coughing] [tapping sounds] Come
on There we go and we of course
my screen jacks up but I can't
actually see it
here. Yea we should have uh
SSIDs start popping up and uh
there's going to be tons of
actual beacon information going
out right now so so basically
this is making uh like I was
saying there's the Grounddog's
Groundhog's Day scenario where
basically it replays the same
day so you can actually capture
information that’s why it
actually has two radios on there
uh that are full blown uh dab
boards for radios then the
actual other smaller antennas
get passed off to a delay where
they will pop the beacon
information that was passed off
from the initial radio and uh
like I said I will be releasing
the actual code for this so and
I'm glad my demo didn't blow up
and you should see a couple of
fake access points popping up
here and uh there's tons of
beacon information if any of you
guys have uh scanner on hand so
[inaudible off-mic comment] uh,
what's up? >>Hello, Wesley. Nice
talk >>Oh, awesome. [laughs]
Sweet. Huh, [chuckles]. Yea I
knew as soon as I boot, I hope
they keep it appropriate
uh, huh but no as soon as uh I
booted up I should have known
people were going to mess with
it, but, [laughs], [audience
laughs] Anyways, it works really
good in stores cause when you
walk into a retail store
there's’ not usually a hacker
waiting with a laptop booted up
with Cali on it so hehe
[laughter] so but yea I
appreciate you guys coming and
listening to me talk and uh yea
I'm glad the demo worked this
year and yeah [clapping] thanks
guys [applause]