>>And my name is Daniel Bohannon
uh I’m a a consultant
[inaudible] I’ve been doing
instant response [mic quits
working] been doing instant
response consulting with
Manidant for the past 2 years
and uh actually recently
switched over to a uh senior
applied security research
position. um so getting to do a
lot of this stuff more which is
really exciting I’m also the
author of the Invoke-Obfuscation
and Invoke-CradleCrafter um
powershell obfuscation
frameworks. >>Thanks, D Bo!
[applause] Alright so to kind of
just hit the stage here we’re
gonna talk a little bit about a
treatise on blue team follies.
So as it stands today you know
the the majority of people use
just regular command line
logging, they look for processes
for example powershell launching
with malicious encoded commands.
What we’re gonna do is we’re
gonna go down some of the depths
of how that can be dangerous,
especially when you’ve got some
bad assumptions going on. What
we’ll do here though, of course,
you can’t get any of this
intelligence unless you’ve got
logging enabled. So for sure
make sure that you’ve got
command line logging enabled
that’s 4688 you can also get it
from Sysmon, and then also that
you’ve you got the PowerShell
scriptblock loggings enabled
because powershell version 5 has
brought in tons and tons of
awesome security stuff and uh
attackers aren’t in the habit of
enabling this stuff for you, so
if you care about it you might
as well do it first. So let's
talk about what people do when
they’re actually trying to do a
sort of detection sort of based
on malicious powershell. So
you’ll see here maybe they’re
gonna look at whenever I see
powershell dash command I’m
gonna take a look at those
encoded arguments and try to
figure out and write some
detections based on those. Well
powershell help, much like
everything else is the best in
the business. Turns out that you
don’t only have to use direct
input to the powershell dash
command. You can also send in
the those commands through
standard input like many other
automation tools you’re used to.
So here’s an example of using
this technique if you do this,
if I’m taking some powershell
commands and I’m dumping them in
through powershell standard
input if all you’re looking at
is the content in the powershell
command lines you’re gonna miss
the stuff that went in there.
However we’re a little bit ok so
this is what it looks like when
you look at the 8th command line
logs for powershell itself. You
don’t see the actual command
that was run, I have one little
note here this little blue
shield this is stuff that will
still show up in your powershell
logs so while this won't show up
in the 4688 this will show up in
the powershell logs. However
that looks like it’s kind of bad
but what you do see here is if
you look at the parent process
command line the cmd itself
you’ll see that somebody was
trying to jack a bunch of input
into powershell and so maybe you
might start thinking about doing
some detections based on that.
So here’s a question do we start
to maybe key anytime that cmd is
calling powershell, that might
be useful. But here's the thing,
cmd you can also declare in an
environment variable what
process it should call. So
here’s an example of setting
powershell as chunks of two
environment variables and then
having cmd call that. So you can
do all kinds of obfuscation with
environment variables so just
doing detections based on cmd
that way, you’re at some kind of
risk there for sure. This is an
example from FIN8 a financially
motivated attacker, doing a
bunch of this stuff here with an
embedded in a VB script VBA ring
a bell? Yes, absolutely that’s
what you just saw. They’re using
late bound command piping into
powershell to get their stuff
done to avoid this command line
detection. But you don’t only
have to send things in through
standard input, here’s an
example at the bottom here of
just using an environment
variable directly in having
powershell invoke the content of
that environment variable.
Kovter uses this as well so if
you’re only looking at
powershell command line that
means you’re kind of screwed.
Where will the clipboard? Here’s
a good example of just using the
clipboard as a information
passing mechanism. You do see
these things in the command
lines but this is start starting
to get really really really
tough. So you might say here
what happens if we just start
applying detection for whenever
a cmd is calling powershell
maybe what I’ll do is I’m going
to start doing detections based
on that process chain, that’s
the kind of thing that you see a
lot of times in hids and that
kind of thing. But here’s the
thing when I run this sort of
launch technique and dump
anything into into powershell,
what if an apparent cmd I set an
environment variable I tell uh a
child cmd to run the thing that
was in the environment variable
and that thing is the thing that
actually calls powershell so if
you’re doing anything that was
just cmd calling powershell yeah
you’re gonna miss that so this
would be kinda cool if that
works. Nah not quite, nearly but
unfortunately we’re not gonna
get there. However with the
magic of cmd escaping all I need
to do is escape that one last
pipeline so that that initial
cmd stops interpreting it. There
we go! Yeah! Cmd that second cmd
you can’t tell what it’s doing
and then finally somehow
powershell is getting involved.
So obviously what we’re gonna do
here is recursively check all
the way up this parent process
tree, combine all of those
command line arguments, get rid
of all that obfuscation and
figure it out, like that’s the
natural thing we’re gonna do and
then we’re gonna save the day
and be good. Unfortunately not,
there is a ton of ways to give
input to powershell that do not
involve any source of parent
process chain. What if you set,
for example, you launch one
window and set the commands in
the window title, launch another
window to scrape that window
title as a kind of a sibling.
You can use files, you can use
reg keys, any sort of
information passing mechanism
that you can imagine that’s not
just environment variables
that’s gonna blow through any
sort of parent process tree
detection. So the good news as
we kind of mentioned back there
was the scriptblock logging and
powershell will catch all these
shenanigans but if you’re in an
environment where the defenders
are only looking at the command
line logs you’re done. However
there’s another thing we’ve just
been talking about at this point
we’ve just been talking about
looking at process command
chains. We haven’t even talked a
little bit about the powershell
content itself and it weighs
through that. >>Yes, let's uh
let's look at this content,
itself so again we’ll see you’re
really um on top of things
you’re looking at all process
command lines you’re also taking
into account powershell
scriptblock logging um are there
any pitfalls that we might need
to be aware of as defenders and
are there any uh tools that you
can use as redquimer to evade
any evasion that you’re going up
against. So we’re going to take
a quick example uh a very rapid
fire example looking at what we
call the remote download cradle.
Now the top here this remote
download cradle is basically uh
it’s copy and pasted everywhere
it’s in all the major frameworks
that you can think of attackers
love this stuff it’s a one liner
that will remotely - it will
download a remote script in
memory and then pass it to that
invoke expression or iex which
is basically like powershell’s
eval statement if you will. So
what what let’s play a little
red team, blue team here we have
our attacker command on the top
this remote download cradle and
as a defender, if we if we what
if we say okay I’m interested
when I see invoke-expression new
object system dot net dot
webclient and download stream
http would this catch this
command? Um it it will catch
that command right here but lets
lets go through a little
obfuscation exercise and see
what pitfalls are out there. So
first whatever we see system dot
that’s really not necessary in
powershell. Um powershell will
automatically pre pin that
system dot for the dot net um h
class so if an attacker doesn't
have to have it in their command
then as a defender uh we
definitely don’t want to make
that assumption in our um in our
trigger terms down here so we’re
gonna remove that from both. Um
next, the URL this is uh this is
the string so you can do stuff
like I don’t know [inaudible]
you’re also not to double quotes
you can use single quotes you
can put whitespace there you can
also set it as a variable
elsewhere there’s a lot of
things you can do here so we’re
just gonna remove that http part
from the download string portion
of the detection. So let’s keep
going, download string. Um so
download string is actually one
of many methods in the net dot
web client class and it’s the
most common one that we see
attacker's using but it’s
definitely not the only one.
This is just part of the list
download string, download file,
download data returning in
obviously different formats, um
an expression, a file on disk,
download data is bitarray, um so
maybe as a defender we say okay
let’s just shorten it to dot
download and make sure that we
capture all these options up
here. So that’s what we’ll do.
Um also uh this parenthese isn’t
really necessary we can start to
chop up this powershell command
and set pieces of it in
variables so for example from
frameworks out there will will
say new object net dot web
client let me put that in a
variable typically called wc for
web client, and then you just
have variable name dot download
string so let's remove that
parentheses from the dot
downloand portion of the
trigger. So now from a
powershell perspective um why
why would this dot be
problematic? Why how could an
attacker get around that dot
download to evade this detection
that we have um well download
string from a powershell token
perspective um is actually a a
member um and so somethings that
we can do with member tokens in
a powershell command so we can
just throw single quotes around
it we can also throw double
quotes around it and if you look
really closely at download
string I promise this next slide
works, but what we can do is
just add a tick mark and that
still runs now why the tick
mark? What is this? Well the
tick mark is the escape
character or the grave accent
character I like to think of it
as a grave of a lot of grave
defensive ideas I thought were
really good ended up that they
get broken by this. So we can
actually put these uh in front
of any character that has no
escapable meaning um and you see
the the 8 characters here um
again like ‘0 is null ‘n for new
line that sort of thing but as
long as we place the ‘ before
something that’s not one of
those characters then we’re
good. If you’re like me and
you’re really OCD and you really
wanna put a ‘ in front of those
characters all you have to do
just uppercase them and it
totally works so now we can put
tics in front of any character
that we want in the method as
long as we have double quotes,
now here’s the scary part is
that those tics are in the
command line logs if you have
some real time agent they’re in
the command line uh the argument
details itself and they actually
persist all the way into
powershell script block logs,
now uh the place where uh this
obfuscation doesn’t have any
effect is in powershell module
logs so the 4303 uh or 4103 EID
so powershell’s log is really
really robust um sometimes you
just have to look in a lot of
different places but all the all
the evidence is there. So as a
defender we can try to RegEx all
this stuff to catch all these
tic marks or maybe we should
just give up on this, I don’t
know, if you’re really brave and
wanna do a RegEx make sure you
keep in mind this open read
method um which will return as a
byte stream instead of a byte
array or an expression um
however I wouldn’t recommend
doing a regex because if you
throw parentheses around this
you can then treat it as a legit
string and start to do
concatenations, set a chunk of
variables, reverse to do
whatever you want. Um and this
dot invoke that you’ll see in
these two examples that’s only
required for powershell 2, um
it’s not required for powershell
3 or later so as a defender if
you look at invoke obfuscation
it uses that dot invoke to make
it um work on powershell 2 or
later but you actually don’t
have to have that, so make sure
as a defender you’re not basing
your defenses on that dot invoke
portion. So let's just remove
that uh from our indicators. So
net dot web client, really
briefly this is um from a
powershell token perspective
it’s an argument the new object
command let we can do double
quote tic marks we can put
parentheses and catenate it,
chunk it in variables, tons of
options we’ll just go with the
first one. There we go. New
object now powershell is super
inviting um to newcomers to
learn the language because there
is so many aliases so for
example if you wanna list the
files in the directory you can
use powershell’s get shells atom
if you’re lazy you can just say
GCI or if you come from a
windows background you can type
der if you from a lenox
background you can type ls and
it all works so as a defender we
have to be really careful to
make sure that we’re
understanding the the all the
options that are available in
powershell just from a pure
syntax perspective regardless of
any kind of obfuscation the nice
thing is that new object has 0
aliases so initially I thought
hey this is gonna be a really
solid indicator as a defender,
however uh powershell uh is
really good at helping you find
stuff that you know is out there
but you can’t remember the name
of so for example, if I’m
looking for a command that’s new
dash p something, I can just
type get command new dash p
wildcard and it will return in
power shell objects all the
commands. So, if I return just a
single object, then I can
actually pass to invoke
expression, um and that will
automatically convert that
command name to a string and
then invoke it. However, uh as
an attacker, we could be a
little more creative than this.
Instead of that invoke
expression, why don’t we use a
dot or an ampersand? And what
are these guys? They’re
invocation operators, and when
this happens, it’s actually
taking the powershell object
return from get command and
invoking it. However, we can get
even more fun. So, remember
those wild cards? That is new
object, as is that, and as many
combinations as you can think
of, as long as that get command
is returning just new object,
that suckers gonna run and as a
defender you’re not seeing new
object anywhere in command line
or in script block logging,
pretty crazy right? Actually,
doesn’t stop there cause get
command has an alias of GCM and
it also has, if you promise not
to tell anyone there’s actually
an undocumented um alias here
for get command and that is
command, because powershell
again, it’s like it’s your best
friend, it’s really, really
helpful, it doesn’t want to make
you look silly, so if you just
type command, it’s just gonna
check hey is there a get dash
command? There is? Solid, that’s
what you were looking for and
that works. So, anytime you’re
running defenses based on get
dash something, make sure you
don’t count on that get dash
being there because it
absolutely doesn’t have to be.
Um, in addition, forget command
if you don’t wanna use wildcards
you can set the command lm into
uh variables like this,
powershell 1 dot oh syntax. If
you’re a defender and you’re not
looking for this automatic
variable of execution context,
you absolutely want to be
because it is really, really
awesome. And, if you’re a red
teamer, you definitely want to
check this out. Here’s just a
couple of ways, you can
basically call get command or
some of its similar counterparts
using this 1 dot oh syntax. In
addition to all the get command
stuff we just said, you can do
the exact same thing with get
alias, GAL, or get alias’ alias
which is called alias. Uh you
can use that against the alias
name instead of the commandlet
name. So, there’s a lot going on
there, why don’t we just choose
this GCM w dash o example, right
there. Um, so, it’s getting a
little crazy, um, in addition to
all these things, we can throw
tic marks in front of them
because they’re a commandlet and
that’s something that’s
available there. Um, you could
also just use the indication
operators against the string new
object, and can catenate it or
use what’s called a dash f
format operator to literally
reverse or not reverse, to
literally reorder um the
substrings that you just chalked
up, so some people well, I’ll
just remove all special
characters from command uh from
event logs and that new, new
object can catenate it if I
remove the quotes and remove the
pluses,the new object will come
back together. However, that’s
not foolproof because these
reordering techniques, you’ll
never see that string new object
come back together. So we can
try to regex all the things, or
just give up. So, I’m wanna be a
realist here and just go ahead
and pass on this one. So, we’re
left with invoke expression,
which is a freaking awesome
indicator, especially on the
command line. IE turn invoke
expression, you definitely want
to be looking at this. What are
some things we need to keep in
mind with that? Well, uh it has
an alias of IEX which is
typically what you see. Um, the
ordering doesn’t matter, you can
say invoke expression
expression, or pipe an
expression into invoke
expression. You can throw tick
marks because it's a commandlet,
uh you can use the invocation
operators and use catenation
reordering. Um and fun fact, um
in part of our research we’ll
talk about here in just a
second, we assembled a massive
powershell corpus uh just a lot
of scripts, we’ll get into the
numbers in a second. But,
basically only 3 percent of the
scripts actually contained IEX
or invoke expression, pretty
interesting. But, one thing we
have to keep in mind is that
invoke expression has a cousin
that is called invoke command
which is quite interesting. So,
invoke expression is expecting
an expression and invoke command
expects a script block, and
typically it’s used to run a
command on a remote system, but
if you never specify a computer
name for that remote system it
runs locally. So what does that
mean from a defenders
perspective? Well, with invoke
command, we have the alias of
ICM the dot and ampersand
indication operators also work,
and then you have things, you
have methods like dot invoke,
invoke return as is, invoke with
context, uh etcetera. A lot of
options there, but typically
you’ll see script blocks in
curly places like we see here.
Um, in addition powershell 1 dot
oh syntax, there’s that
execution context thing I was
telling you about earlier right?
Um, it has an invoke script
method which can handle both
expression and script blocks.
So, let’s add in tick marks to
all of these because there
commandlets, but how in the
world as a defender can we start
keying off of an ampersand or a
dot? That seems like it’s uh
really be bound for false
positives. So what if we say
okay I’m only interested if
there’s a dot or ampersand and
there’s also a curly braces
because curly braces are the
only way you can denote a script
block in powershell. If only it
were that simple. Because, you
can convert an expression to a
script block, and here’s two
examples of that using the
script block class and create
method or again execution
context powershell 1 dot oh
syntax for the new script block
method, and you can obfuscate
all of these just like we’ve
been doing all along. So, every
single layer can be obfuscated
to the extreme and it sticks,
the obfuscation is there and the
command line arguments and also
inscript lock logs. Um, in uh
invoke cradle crafter a tool I
released a couple of months ago-
>>Thanks, D-Bo >>hahah, sorry
Lee, um, I have to deal with it
myself actually so we’re in the
same boat there. Um, but uh it
actually has over 10 different
indication options, so there’s a
lot of cool stuff there.
>>[sigh] that is brutal, can you
imagine trying to defend against
that? God. Well, now that you’re
done with that let’s [phew]
that’s brutal >>yeah,
fortunately, that’s really the
extent of what you can do with
powershell obfuscation. Nah, I’m
totally kidding, there’s way
more. [laughter][applause] What
if we just take that. So, after
all of that what if we then say
hey totally screwed up, f’d up
uh powershell command, why don’t
we make you a string and then
just reverse you on the command
line and be reversed in memory.
Here’s some examples of that.
Um,we can also put garbage
delimiters in the command and
then split, basically split and
join removing those. We can use
replace uh methods to basically
remove and replace those garbage
delimiters. We can do any kind
of decatenation that we want. Um
and wouldn’t suck if there’s a
tool out there that did all this
by default. [laughter] Horrible,
horrible ha. So, uh anyways,
invoke obfuscation may or may
not do that. So let’s take the
same uh download credit we
started with, and instead of
going through this I don’t know
10 minute example of all these
different things, we can
literally at the click of a
button say yeah just randomly
obfuscate all the tokens in
there, produce something like
this. You could then say, if
you’re really twisted, let me
take this and then do some
string obfuscation like that
reordering right there. Fun
fact, I spent a lot of time
recently decoding this stuff
because APT32 uh a nice uh
Vietnamese uh APT group also
known as OceanLotus happens to
like this combo quite a bit.
They’ll do one layer of string
token all and then they’ll do
like literally 5 or 6 layers of
this string stuff. So, uh, I’v,
I’ve gotten a lot of practice
Lee, um- >>You make your bed you
lay in it man >>I’m telling you
man, I’m telling you. Um, invoke
cradle craft or how might
obfuscation with this look
different. Um, in invoke cradle-
>>Thanks D-Bo >>[laughter]
Invoke cradle crafter actually
doesn’t use any tick marks, um
it will use uh substitutions, uh
it will basically say instead of
if we have download string
instead of catenating it or
using tick marks, let me
actually enumerate all the
methods available to new object
net that web client and maybe
like the 37th uh one actually
half resolves to the string
download string and so it using
all that kind of substitution
there. So, wouldn’t it be
terrible if there was actually
new and worse obfuscation
techniques that just hit the
market like three days ago.
>>Thanks D-Bo >>[laughter]
Sorry, uh I’ve been sitting on
this one for like 6 months so
I’ve gotta get it out there,
what if it’s all special
characters? [laughter]
[applause] Now, I-I have to say
up front, kudos, this was not my
original idea, uh um a Japanese
security researcher back in
twenty ten wrote hello world
using this technique entirely in
special characters named uh
mutaguchi so props to them, this
is really, really freakin cool.
Um, but all these, it’s
basically just alot of different
variables, definitely really
interesting to read his blog
post of how he came up with
this, um those variable names
could also just be different
amounts of white space.
[laughter] And then I was
chatting with Casie Smith, our
sub tee and he said oh well that
looks kind of similar to like
white space encoding. And I
said, say what? He said, yeah,
you know whitespace tab
encoding. And I was like, that
sounds amazing, let's do that
right now, so that’s the second
one I released [laughter]. So,
the entire command is either
white spaces and tab delimited
or its tabs and whitespace
delimited and they have this
nice little stub decoder at the
end. Um so, that that’s out
there now. And this is pretty
much what defenders feel like
right? [laughter] an, and I am a
defender, this is my job to come
up against this stuff but uh,
>>as you can tell he’s a noted
blue teamer. >>hahaha [laughter]
>>you're a masochist
>>[laughter] So, uh, I feel
really bad now, I feel a guilt
trip, like is there anything we
can do for defenders out there?
>>I guess not, we’re uh, hold
on, we’re just getting into this
presentation, I think there’s
some stuff we can do. So you
might think, hey like, how in
the world as a defender looking
at your logs are you EVER going
to find any of that stuff? Hands
up, you're kind of screwed. So,
we decided to dabble a little
bit. We’re not data scientists,
nothing like that, we just
decided to play around a little
bit. Here’s a core point though,
you don’t need to detect all the
stuff in there. All you need to
know is that it exists. All of
us looking, we take a look at
that, and it’s obvious that
that’s not normal stuff at all.
What, what attackers are using
as this amazing cloak of
invisibility, we can do some
smart stuff and turn that into
like a shining laser. If you see
stuff like this in your
networks, your screwed, you
should take a look, you don’t
need to have the logging tools
or the rajaxes telling you what
it’s doing, just apply a bit of
wet ware and you’re going to be
in good shape. Now, how can we
do that thought? That sounds
simple. One of the cool things
you could do is simple character
frequencies. So, as we were
talking about the uh big
powershell corpus we made, so
here’s an example in the right
hand side where we did some
character frequency analysis
against all of the scripts in
posh code which is a popular
powershell script sharing
repository. It looks kind of
like English if you’ve ever done
any simple crypto or anything,
you kind of recognize those
character frequencies. On the
left hand side, you see some of
the obfuscated values of the
scripts that we just showed.
Very, very, very clearly
different right? You’ve got a
bunch of backticks and square
brackets, this really, really
stands out. So the question is,
like okay, yeah it’s a list of
numbers, how am I supposed to
figure out how similar those
list of numbers are? There’s a
tool out there! There’s a whole
community in the world called
information retrieval, and they
do things like search engines,
where they’ll go off and analyze
things like web pages and
documents, and they’ll figure
out different features and
different numbers, and then what
they’ll do is they’ll compare
those big lists of numbers
together, to find lists of
numbers that are similar. So,
we’re used to this from high
school and stuff and graph
paper, you’ve got two numbers
that represent a line, another
two numbers that represent
another line, and then the angle
between those is the cosine and
then you could do some little
math here on the right, it makes
us look smart so we’ve got it up
there and I’m pretty proud of
that, um so you could do some
comparison on that, those lines
to figure out how similar they
are using the cosine. Turns out
that the information retrieval
guys like to do this for more
than two numbers, so more than
two dimensions, more than three
dimensions, maybe like a
thousand or two thousand
dimensions. And at that point
you’re talking about kind of
like the angle between a three
thousand dimensional line. I’m
having a hard time picturing it,
but it’s possible, it gives you
a number. So, here’s an example
of actually running that. You
don’t need to read all of the
powershell, it’s just
powershell, but, what you can
see here is we’ve got a huge
grouping near the top, most of
these things have a a very
similar cosine similarity. But
then you also have these
obfuscated ones are sticking
right out, 0 point 157, 0 point
379, this is an atomic bomb.
Take a look at the average
similarity among all of posh
code, there’s a massive grouping
up here. If you take a look at
everything below 0 point 8 and
then we did, these things are
almost all obfuscated. And when
they weren’t intentionally
obfuscated, there were things
like a code golf competition,
where you know people just do
garbage anyways. So, if we could
somehow automate this cosine
similarity, like problem solved.
Run this on your logs, run this
on your network and you’re good
to go. >>So, these data points
are generated again from all the
scripts on posh code which is
what 3 point 4 thousand I
believe, uh so we really wanted
more data and microsoft has been
thinking about this for a while
and so even looking last spring,
they ran a little contest called
underhanded powershell where
they uh invited the red team
community to basically submit uh
obfuscated and underhanded
powershell commands to perform a
very specific task, that got
around uh the certain script
analyzer um detection rules that
were in place. Um, so that was
kind of neat. Um and then on top
of that data there’s a lot of
powershell script out there in
the community that we wanted to
gather. Um, we created a
ginormous powershell corpus.
>>ginormous >>but, since we’re
both gentleman, we did it
politely. Now, what do I mean by
that? Well, this is a code that
Lee wrote to actually scrape
github for example, and if
you’ll see those little blue
portions, that’s the code that
actually downloads the script.
And, all those red portions, are
blatant Canadian, cause Lee is
Canadian and it’s very polite,
throttling, ah it’s so nice, so
kind. So, anyways, we politely
scraped. Um, actually fun fact
here, you were scraping for
quite a while on github. >>Yeah,
mad props to github. So, we took
a look at all the repositories,
and figured it would take about
you know a month, so we, there
was like 11 million repositories
to scrape through, [clears
throat] started going through a
month straight just downloading,
downloading, throttle;
downloading, downloading,
throttle. A month later it’s
like, look at my repository
index, 12 million, 13 million,
doesn’t make sense. Go off and
look again and I was off by
order of magnitude, a hundred
million repositories, and I was
like we’ve got something to do
man, we can’t be rescheduling
this to December. So, the we
reached out to the github guys,
they went, zipped it all up, did
a little bit of a back down,
back end query, sent us a zip of
all the powershells, so mad
props to them. >>yeah, big
thanks to them. Uh, the really
big thanks though is to all of
the contributors out there. So,
if you wouldn’t mind raising
your hand if you’ve ever
contributed a powershell script,
a posh code, technet, powershell
gallery, github, github gifs are
there any contributors in the
house? Awesome, please give
yourself a round of applause
because you made this research
possible [applause]. So, when
you assemble a very large corpus
of powershell scripts, you're
impelled, compelled to look at
them, and it’s very interesting
when you start to look at all
these scripts. >>I will never be
the same man- >>hahaha, so some
of the stuff we found was uh
honestly, just really sad.
Remove games dot ps1, um the
author, oh wow, looks like it
actually says Matt Graeber, I
don’t know if that’s right, but
basically it goes through and
kills any running game processes
and then, to top it off actually
removes the directory, so I
don’t know where the high scores
are kept there, but that’s
pretty cold though, kind of a
buz-- >>depraved depraved man
>>mmm, but no in all seriousness
though, actually in this
process, we did come across some
that were, that were uh a bit
more serious actually we came
across one plot to overthrow
some really interesting people
and power and um that was this
down with SOPA script. Let’s
fill the US and senate servers
with the message that we don’t
want SOPA, uh stop online piracy
act tends >>resist >>yes, so a
lot of fun stuff in the corpus.
So uh getting a little more
serious, there’s a lot of
powershell scripts, to be exact
identified roughly 1600
obfuscated scripts, uh um in
this data set and then we
scripts using uh things like
invoke expression or uh sorry,
invoke obfuscation, invoke
cradle crafter and ISE steroids.
Um, the important thing here is
that uh we actually, manually
looked at and manually labeled
>>That, that sounds pretty
tedious, why would we do that
Lee? >>People, people think that
uh, hacking is amazing and fast
paced, but it’s not. It’s a
notepad window popping up, you
closing it and saying “that
wasn’t obfuscated.” Notepad
window pops up, you close it and
that was, and you get a big
spreadsheet, so mad hacking
skills. But here’s the thing,
why do we do all of that?
Remember I showed this a little
bit ago? The, the similarity and
how it kind of nailed it on the
stuff below 0 point 8, Ryan Ka
did a pretty good analysis
afterwards kind of doing uh I
think real scientific method of
can we produce these results,
does it show uh the kind of
obfuscated stuff they were
talking about. And they did find
that hey you do have a, a kind
of a balance between that that
magical number 0 point 8, false
positives, false negatives. So,
mathematically, this is what it
looks like. When you run that
algorithm against the powershell
corpus and all of this labeled
data so you know we, I showed
you back there, two obfuscated
scripts. But, what if you know
powershell scripts are
obfuscated or not? So then you
can start to get some really,
really good numbers, so the way
that the uh information
retrieval and data science
community talks about this
stuff, there's two main metrics
here, one is precision and one
is recall. So, prision-precision
says, any time the tool says
that something is obfuscated,
how often is it correct? So, in
that situation that was 89
percent. So, all of those things
below 0 point 8, yeah, you’re
pretty good, 90 percent
effective at getting obfuscated
powershell. Recall though,
that’s where it takes a dive,
what we didn’t analyze was all
the stuff above 0 point 8. Turns
out that was hiding a lot of
stuff that later you would
consider obfuscated, and that’s
reflected in kind of a merged
score that people talk about is
the F1 score, just kind of
averages the precision and
recall. So, some super powerful
stuff, unobfuscated but it's
really got some opportunity
here. This is powershell though,
the most powerful scripting
language known to man, we have
the power, we can do better.
>>So, instead of just looking at
the character frequency of an
entire script, um powershell if
you think about any uh any
language, it has to basically
interpret and see what am I
actually looking at? So, this is
an example here of uh powershell
tokenizing the command. Um and
so basically you can see get
command is a generic token, the
dash name is a parameter token
uh may the format operator
string etcetera. Um, however,
what we have at our fingertips
is not just the tokenization
that powershell can provide, but
it’s also a tree. And this is
called the abstract syntax tree,
or AST. And not only does this
identify all the tokens, it
actually identifies the
relationship with, with those
tokens in the entire script so
now you can see okay there’s a
format operator buy what’s on
its left, what’s on its right?
What kind of, how many objects
are there? And so this allows us
to get a lot of interesting um
features, now if you want to
easily view this um there’s this
awesome gooey, this uh AST
powershell explorer, which you
can actually get uh um it’s
hosted on the powershell
gallery, so you can literally
just type in install module show
psast and start running this
right away, it’s a really,
really nice gooey interface to
explore, AST. Type in any
command on the right, check out
the AST. Now, why do we do this?
Well with the AST we can get
extremely granular, so for
example we can say let me just
group the number of all the
different AST types. So maybe
this one script is 33 percent
string and that’s all it is, or
maybe 99 percent of the script
is a massive array. We do things
like looking at array size
element array, maybe that’s
shellcode in there. I, I don’t
know that’s pretty large. Uh
also we can do things like look
at language operators, so
looking at assignment operators,
binary, unary operators,
invocation operators. And then
for every single component that
we did that grouping on, add in
an additional layer of feature
extraction, basically saying
okay for all of these types,
lets then do character frequency
analys-analysis just on these
types. So, for example, all
commandlets in one group, all
strings, all methods, all
members and we’ll do things like
looking at character frequency,
entropy, whitespace density, the
length, the maximum, minimum,
median, mode, range and average
length on top of that. And then
also the percentage of character
casing, you look for
randomization and character
casing. So, it actually produces
that's kind of rough, I don’t
know >>yeah, it is, what do we
is a bad realization when you’ve
you’ve got stuff in there that’s
awesome, what do you do with it?
So, there’s a common method out
there, to uh kind of classify
data, it’s called a linear
regression, that’s kind of the
example there in the back, and
the left hand side, so what you
do is you kind of have a big
math equation and if, if the
number is above a certain
boundary then that’s obfuscated
and then if it’s below then it’s
not. Now, the thing is these the
AST features we were talking
about, they really let you
figure out a bunch of the
techniques about obfuscation
itself, and not just simple
metrics. But, they kind of end
up being rangy so like some of
them end up being really large
and really small, and so what
you do is put them through a
logit function and that
basically scales them between
zero and one. So, all those
features that we extract now get
scaled down to between 0 and 1,
you combine that, and that is
what is called a logistic
regression. That’s a really,
really, common thing, so for
example, excel let’s you do a
lot of these things as well. So
you have all, all of the
features so F1, F2, F3, and
every them have a weight, so I’m
gonna add up a feature times
what the weight is going to be
and another feature times what
that weight is going to be, big,
And if that result was greater
than what we consider a limit,
then that’s, hey that’s
obfuscated otherwise it’s not.
But here’s the big issue, like I
kind of dodged the question,
features? Chris, back there in
didn’t know what to do, this is
what you’ve got to do. This is
called a gradient descent and
the idea being that you don’t
necessarily ask D-Bo, like hey
D-Bo, how important do you think
a square bracket is and he’s
like oh that’s an oh point 2,
like I know an oh point 2 when I
see one. But what you don’t know
there is what’s that going to do
to your false positives and
everything else, so what you’ll
do with the gradient descent,
remember we had all that
labelled data. What we can start
just run a simulation and see
how good they are with
classifying and if you run a
simulation and you're way off
what you can do is feedback that
error back into all of those
weights. So, if you had a large
weight, it’s going to get
adjusted very appropriately,
more significantly than small
weights and if you don’t make a
mistake well then those weights
don’t get adjusted. And over
thousands and thousands of
times, this is kind of just
automated statistics, over
thousands and thousands of
times, you end up optimizing
yourself towards a an algorithm
that’s really good based on what
you measure. So here’s the
question, like, you felt kind of
like a pit of despair when you
saw all that stuff, all that
obfuscation and everything. Now
when you start taking this
logistic regression and gradient
descent, you know you might be
happy if that F1 score, remember
we were down at like 57 percent,
wouldn’t it be nice if we could
get to like 60, 70 percent? How
about 95? [applause] Using,
revoke obfuscation, you can
detect 94 percent of in the wild
obfuscated powershell, with only
1 percent false positives, that
is literally 10 times better
than cosine similarity, with
half the false positives. And,
we can even do better, what
about like that was in the, in
the wild, obfuscated powershell
and those kind of tend to be
like everything to the wall
obfuscate all the things, but
what if you start some stuff
that just feels kind of sketchy
right? Where it’s like you know
on that left you see that
there’s massive, massive
obfuscation, yeah absolutely
like yeah that's an easy target,
but this example on the right
that’s not really obfuscated,
it’s just kind of using unusual
powershell, it’s this big uh,
select object with a bunch of
hash tables, like that’s a
little bit out there, what could
you do if you started applying
revoke obfuscation to just
mildly sketchy stuff, you know
this is an example of you’re in
an incident response or your
suspicious you want to kind of
widen the net a little bit. On
sketchy still, it’s really
really great. It’s able to
return 89 percent of all sketchy
stuff, so you’re 88 percent of
all sketchy stuff with very very
low false positives. But what’s
even cooler is that, that bucket
now, when you start talking
about in the wild obfuscated
powershell, it goes from 97
percent recall, so revoke
obfuscation all by itself, 97
percent or 94 percent of in the
wild powershell, obfuscated
powershell, bringing it now to
97 percent, of in the wild
obfuscated powershell. Super
crazy this is a nuclear bomb
against anybody trying to use
obfuscated powershell in an
engagement, a blue teamer or a
defender, this thing has got to
be in your arsenal. So logistic
regression and gradient descent,
that’s not the only thing out
there, there’s other cats in the
game, there’s boosted decision
trees, there’s port vector
models and all that kind of
stuff. So, one of the cool
things that we got out of doing
all of this, so this was a hand
implemented algorithm, in c
sharp based on some cool stuff
shared by James Mccaffrey on
msdm for example. Uh, we
compared it, we just had a big
csv of all this stuff and you
can actually do it, like upload
it to as your machine learning
and see how this thing performs
in other algorithms. So, [clears
throat] revoke obfuscation had
very, very, basically, uh
equivalent functionality to this
same function implemented in a
commercial machine learning
system, but then you can apply
to others and you know the next
closest one was the boosted
decision trees and those things
had about the same accuracy, and
two of the other algorithms that
we messed around with had much
less. So, what we’ve baked into
revoke obfuscation is a really
really top end model for you.
>>would anyone like to see a
demo? >>yeah [applause] >>yeah
[applause] >>So, I’d like to
think that revoke obfuscation is
a really clean a pure commandlet
approach, a lot of the tools I
write have ASCII art like this,
um so- >>console gooeys for the
win >>ha, ha [applause] so
actually what we’ll do here is
the first one is me getting out
all of my ASCII art in a
completely separate function,
that basically performs a nice
little analysis here of the
script at the top pulling out
different features or attributes
just to kind of show some of the
levels of the stuff we’re doing
average less than 300
milliseconds for extracting the
features and measuring it um and
here’s just a menu, this is
completely for fun, and for
lulls, there's stuff like uh a
tutorial, if you like a colored
version of the readme, basically
that’s what it is. Uh, there’s a
lot of fun facts, again, a lot
of interesting stuff that we saw
um in um some that we’re ashamed
of, that we saw in the corpus
there but anyways we felt like
yeah we should be open and
transparent so you can look at
fun facts and see some stuff
there, um you see a lot of
really interesting ASCII art
when your going through all
these scripts, so, randomly see
some ASCII art, uh and actually
show you the project that it
came from. Uh got some set of
fun quotes and also some credits
again, if you’ve ever
contributed any powershell, um
to get however other sources,
like your name is actually in
this code and if you run that
enough, then you will see it.
So, onto the stuff that you know
actually does stuff, um, most
people don’t have you know a
huge uh you know directory with
every single powerscript they’ve
run in their environment to
analyze here. Um, in revoke
obfuscation we’ll handle both
command lines and scripts um and
so we’re trying to make this as
operationally friendly and easy
to implement as possible, so
let’s say um that you just want
to query your event logs using
get winevent, sim sweep, I mean
you just want to clog the raw
ebtx files, that’s totally fine
because we wrote a function
called get rvo script block. Um
rvo standing for revoke
obfuscation, it will basically
ex um ex, uh extract all of the
uh script blocks and actually
reassemble the script block that
fall across multiple script
block uh entries there. Um, so
basically what’s really nice it
you want to uh start with event
logs, what you can do is say let
me get all these event logs, let
me pipe you in to get rvo script
block, um let me retrieve all of
the scripts from that, and then
we can pipe it in to measure rvo
obfuscation and there it is
churning through them. >>Thanks
D-Bo >>ha, ha, [applause] and as
you can see, it caught our fun
example of all special
characters there, with a nice
obfuscated as true and as you
can see, all the script features
are there and everything. The
amount of time it took to
extract the features, the
measurement, uh and, and all
that stuff, um so, the very last
thing I’ll say here, is that
again our, our desire is not
just for this to be uh something
uh that is used in research, but
we want to make it accessible to
any organization, we want people
to be able to take this and
literally run it like, like
within minutes. Um and so to
help facilitate that we actually
have this hosted uh on on this
github right here, it’s also
hosted in the powershell gallery
which literally gets you fire up
powershell and run install
module, revoke obfuscation, and
it’s there, it’s locked, loaded,
ready to go. And uh, and the one
last thing I’ll say, is again,
to make it operationally
friendly, we’ve added several
different options for white
listing, so again if you start
to set this up in an operational
since in your environment, if
you start to see uh these
scripts come in that are flagged
as obfuscated you can quickly
look through and say oh no this
is actually good, let me just
drag this into the whitelist
folder, maybe you can also
content um string whitelisting,
regiqua-, regex whitelisting
etcetera, again, we want this to
be as accessible and easy to use
in an operational sense as
possible for any defender out
there. And that, is our talk.
[applause] >>thank you >>thank
you [applause]