>>Uh. Alright, ya. I’m, uh,
Jason- Jason Haddix. And this is
JP Swagnetow. And today we’re
going to talk about, uh, a tool
that we created, uh, an
extension for Burp Suite- really
two tools, uh- called HUNT. Um.
So we weren’t the only ones who
did this. Uh. Our security
operations group, uh, Fatih and
Ryan and Vishal also helped us
with, uh, with some of the data
pulling and everything like
that. Mostly we work for
Bugcrowd that runs crowdsourced
pentests and assessments and
responsible disclosure. Uh. But
all of us are bughunters and
pentesters and code analysis
people. We’re also really big
fans of Burp Suite. So, um, we
spend most of our time hacking
web apps inside of Burp Suite
all day. Um. And so we wanted to
create these two tools to kind
of extend us and, uh, kind of
the knowledge to people who are
either new in application
security assessment or are
looking for a different kind of
coverage in application security
assessment. So the three
problems that we’re trying to
identify with the two tools that
we made. So, uh, so applications
are getting completely large.
Lots of parameters. Um. And you
don’t know really where to
start. If you don’t have a large
domain, uh, that maybe has like,
you know, 150 dynamic parameters
where you’re supposed to fuzz
with, uh, you know, different
fuzz strings, it can get
unwieldy. Um. And you don’t want
to rely all the way on something
like a scanner. Right? Uh. They
don’t have full coverage.
They’re just fuzzing things
until they crap over or
something like that. So we
wanted something to alert us
when, uh, there are potential
issues. Specifically, uh,
parameters that might be
vulnerable to certain classes of
vulnerabilities. But it’s for
manual testing. It’s not for
automated testing. Uh. We also
noticed that there is this lack
of tribal knowledge, um, for
younger testers. Right? So, you
know, JP may have been doing
this for ten years and knows
that, uh, just by the name of a
parameter it probably interacts
with the database or a
templating engine or something
like that. Uh. But he knows to
fuzz for certain vulnerabilities
in that place. Uh. But me, if I
were a new tester, um, I
wouldn’t know to look there
unless I had his expertise. Um.
So we wanted to kind of level
up, uh, the testers, you know,
who were at that skill level and
transfer that tribal knowledge.
And then we also noticed that
there’s no intel workflow for
web hacking methodologies inside
of Burp. Right? If you do web
hacking and you want to record a
large amount of data, you have
to do it in a third party tool.
Uh. You can do it in Burp notes,
but, uh, it’s kind of unwieldy.
Um. There just wasn’t something
that fit kind of what we were
looking for inside of, uh,
inside of Burp. So the current
kind of solutions for, uh, to
effectively find security bugs
in web locations is, you know,
you have a bada** hacker who can
kind of eyeball parameters that-
or input places that, you know,
where are vulnerable. So, um,
they can find security bugs.
They may or may not use a
methodology. Uh. They definitely
have accrued some tribal
knowledge of vulnerabilities.
Um. And you can do this as a bug
hunter or consultant or
something like that. There’s
also the solution of a dynamic
scanner which just throws
limited test cases at parameters
hoping that either an error
occurs or a response occurs that
it parses there and then that
there’s a vulnerability there.
Um. But those are cost
prohibited because a lot of
those good scanners cost a lot
of money. Uh. They’re limited in
their detection cases. Um. They
don’t handle dynamic pages very
well. They don’t handle non
generic errors very well. And
they don’t handle authentication
very well in most cases. So, um,
we wanted to be able to give
people a way to manually test,
but know where to manually test,
uh, a-and have some data behind
it. So we built this into, uh,
HUNT. So it’s, uh, tribal
knowledge passive alerts. You
get alerts when it sees
parameters that are most often
vulnerable to certain things.
Uh. You get methodology inside
of Burp. And you also get a
whole bunch of references that
we added. So, uh, the Burp, uh,
advisory is our- really their
writes up on the
vulnerabilities. Um. But the
best methods and the best stuff
usually come from blogs. Like
the cheat sheets that Pentus
Monkey has, you know, for sql
injection and stuff like that,
um, or just, you know, members
of the community. Uh. We found
that we weren’t using, you know,
uh, certain references inside
the tool. We wanted to bring
them inside the tool so that
when you’re training up a new
application assessment person,
they have all those links and
resources right inside the tool
and they can get -s, you know,
started as fast as they can, you
know, manually testing some of
these vulnerability classes. Ok.
So the first tool is Scanner-
HUNT Scanner. So before we
launch into what it looks like,
you have to know kind of how we
gathered the data to make these
alerts. Um. So we we are
Bugcrowd. We do a lot of, um,
bug bounties. Over 600 run right
now. Um. And so basically this
is just some fuzzing math. But,
uh, programs that we have, if
you times those by two targets,
we average two targets per
application. Um. And these are
usually targets or either
subdomains or fully qualified
top level domains so like
dubdubdub dot Def Con dot org or
forms dot def-def con dot org.
Anything that really, uh, gives
you different application
functionality is going to be a
target. And then we averaged
about every one of those things
had about fifteen dynamic
parameters- unique dynamic
parameters per application. Um.
over the kind of data set that
we were looking at. Um. So what
parameters is reduce them to
parameters with vulns on them.
Um. Which was mostly all of
them. And then we reduced it
again to things that had P1 and
P2 vulnerabilities on them which
are high and, um, critical level
vulnerabilities. These are
things that let you read the
file system. They let you, um,
execute arbitrary code. They are
a configuration vulnerability
that allows you to see credit
card information of other
people. These are those types of
bugs. Uh. So we reduced it to
those bugs. Uh. Then we started
sorting it for recurring
instances. So really, you know,
fuzzy data science. Uh. But it-
it works. Um. So then we include
the top five to ten recurring
instances of parameters to start
alerting you when they fall
through your Burp traffic. Um.
And then we actually reviewed
the top 100 possible
cummercations with some of
these. Um. And then we manually
added some of these ancillary C
data so the fuzzdb project,
seclists, and just some
parameters that our buddies that
work as pen test consultants
were like we see this all the
time with this vuln. Um. So we
added some stuff to this data
set as well. So just, you know,
a quick refresher for, you know,
what we’re talking about here.
Uh. This is an example of a
parameter in orange here, right?
So this is where, uh, after the
equals sign you’re going to fuzz
for, in this case, probably sql
injection. The ID parameter, uh,
most often, is associated with
the database. So, um, this is
kind of what this talk is about-
is- is getting to this. Right?
When you see ID equals one, you
put tips. Right? So, um. This is
the essence of Scanner. Alright.
So this is what, uh, Scanner
looks like. This is a- a totally
separate tab. We didn’t want to
pollute your already made, uh,
Burp instance. We didn’t want to
pollute the, uh, advisories of
Burb Scanner or anything like
that. So we made a clearly
different tab. Um. And we
started with, uh, I think seven
or eight classes of
vulnerabilities that were P1
worthy. Um. So here you can see
on the left hand side, uh, we’ve
funneled some traffic through
Burp. And it’s already starting
to alert us on common parameters
that are vulnerable to service
site requests forgery on the
left. Um. So here you can see
the requests end up inside of a
sub tree on the left. Um. You
can see the kind of parameters
we are talking about here:
destination, dir, uri, path,
continue, etcetera, etcetera.
Right? These are all things
you’re going to want to fuzz for
service-side. Request forgery,
uh, probably URL redirection,
things like that. Um. So you’ll
have the requests and the
response and you’ll also have an
advisory that we’ll go over in a
second. So here’s the advisory.
Um. You can see here that, uh,
we added just some general
stuff. But this is all
customizable. You’ll be able to
customize it yourself with your
own built in methodologies
inside of Burp. It’s very
editable. So if you have a team
and you have a resource list or
a cheat sheet of some sort to do
these things, you can add them
now inside of Burp in your own
advisories. So you have the
location. And then for this one
obviously the SSRF are viable
for this class of vulnerability
is probably one of the best
resources you can look at for
SSRF. And there’s a couple of
other resources that we think
are worthy, um, to manually test
vulnerabilities against a class
of vulnerability like this.
Alright. So we’re going to talk
a little bit about the data that
showed up when we parsed all
that stuff. So this is a
sampling of the sql injection
data that- that we pulled out.
Right? And so if you look at
this table, these are all the
parameters that normally had
critical sql injection on them.
So if you take nothing else from
this talk, if you hate the
extension, you probably use the
data in some way in your
testing. Um. So id, update,
sort, process which you’ll
notice when you start reading
these things is- they’re all
related to database stuff. A new
tester might not know that some
of these things are related to
databases. And they might not
test there. Um. Custom headers
showed up time and time again.
Um. JSON and XML web services we
can alert on types. Uh. But
really we’re tr- we’re mostly
alerting on regexes of- of
certain parameters means here.
So column, code, field,
etcetera. So this is the data
for, uh, file traversal and
directory traversal. So, um,
things like file, folder, roots,
style, load, location. Um. This
is where you’re going to try to,
uh, change paths or include
files that aren’t yours or, uh,
cost dependent error in that
area of vulnerability. Uh. This
was actually out of the Bugcrowd
data this year. This was the
highest, uh, critical
vulnerability that we found, uh,
over and over again. So service
side request forgery that
allowed local file reads. Um. So
this is This parameter set and
we also found that it crossed
over a lot of the filing
includes in the directory
traversal parameters so we
actually alert on both data sets
for- for this bug. A lot of
money has been made off of SRF
this year. Uh. OS Command
Injection- a smaller list.
Things like daemon, execute,
upload, download, dir, uh, log,
things that are related to
Commandline, uh, and stuff on
linux usually. Insecure direct
object reference, things that
are usually related to kind of,
um, the, uh, the state of a user
traversing the state of an
application. ID, account, order,
dot, emails. And then this is
server side template injection
and, uh, debug parameters. Uh. I
didn’t make a nice table for the
right hand one. So, uh, service
side template injection, uh,
obviously template, preview, id,
view, name. Uh. I would verify
with this bug that you’re
actually targeting a template
inject- or, uh, template engine
before you fuzz for these. But
still useful to have. Uh. And
then on the righthand side
there, the JSON Schema is
actually what this looks like
and I’ll show it in a sec-second
how you go ahead and edit your
own parameters. Um. But, uh,
that’s the list for debug
parameters that indicate, um,
things like logic
vulnerabilities or special admin
parameters that let you do fu-
special functions and things-
things like that. So access
admin, debug, edit grant test,
altera clone, etcetera. So these
are all language things that
relate to vulnerabilities. So
the implementation of the Burp
Suite kind of, um, APi we used
is iScanner check and iScanner
Issue that makes a new tab. Um.
If you want to edit or make a
second tab to have for alerts or
for anything like this, it’s
really just, like, one block of
code. We’ve provided that. Uh.
Pretty easily editable here if
you’ve ever made a Burp
extension. It’s in Python so
easily extendable. And then
we’ll do a quick demo. Alright.
So... Uh. Here we have tesla dot
com which is a Bugcrowd customer
and they have a bounty. Um. And
so I’ve hooked them up to Burp.
And on the left hand side,
traffic has started flowing from
tesla dot com through Burp. Um.
So the first thing that you want
to do with this is make sure to
set your scope. But I’ve already
done that. As you can see on the
left hand side, traffic is
already starting to go through
tesla dot com which is what it’s
going through right now. Um. Now
if I go to HUNT Scanner up here
on the right and I collapse
these, you can see that it’s
already started to tell me that
there’s some places that I
should look manually for these
vulnerabilities. Um. So here I
can see, um, things associated
with sql injection, things
associated to Debug and Logic,
service side requests forgery,
etcetera. So we’ll go here. Um.
And if we click here, now you
get, uh, this instance. So, uh,
this domain had, uh, the page
parameter on it. You can see the
advisory for service side
template injection, the request
here, the response here. And
then let’s say you check this
manually and it’s not vulnerable
to anything You can actually
remove it from the list by just
checking it off and clicking up
here. Um. So, uh, it allows you
to remove the stuff that, you
know, you’ve already tested. So
that’s just a quick overview of-
of HUNT Scanner and how HUNT
Scanner works. Let me get back
to slides. Alright. So the next
tool is the GUI and the
methodology part of it.
>>Alright. So we’re talking
about the GUI methodology. So
I’m sure a lot of you guys are,
you know, pentesters,
vulnerability assessors, and,
you know, when you’re doing your
testing you’re actually going to
be doing, you know I’m going by
a methodology. Unless you’re
some kind of, you know, yellow
swag-god hacker, you’re going to
be going by a methodology. And
you’ll be using things like, you
know, the OWASP Testing Guide,
the Web Application Hacker’s
Handbook, or you might even go
by, uh, standards like HIPPA or
PCi. So, um, that’s what I’m
talking about when I’m talking
about methodologies. Uh. For
those of you who aren’t, uh,
professional pentesters or
vulnerability assessors, uh,
why- why would you want to use a
methodology? Because this is
what you need to prove that you
did the work. So kind of like,
you know, in second grade math,
they want you to show the work.
This is how you would do it and
we actually put that into, uh,
Burp Suite so that it’s easy to
get, you know, your request and
response pairs, uh, within
there. And then when you’re
going to generate your report,
it’s already in there so you
don’t have to go through the
hassle of copying and pasting
and all that nonsense. Right? So
the first thing, uh, that we’re
going to talk about here i-in
terms of the GUI is that you can
have a there’s a right click
centa methodology section. So
from anywhere in Burp where you
have a req- request and response
pair, you can actually just do a
right click and you can see, uh,
there’s, uh- there’s a line
there that says “send to, uh,
HUNT methodology”. And then it
has the subfolders and folders
where you can actually put, uh,
that particular res-, uh,
request and response pair after
you’ve a-actually done your
testing to show that you’ve, um,
done the work and proved that,
you know, there is a
vulnerability there. Or, you
know, if you have your POC in
there, that’s where’d you’d put
it. So this is what it looks
like in Burp as far as the, uh,
methodology window. So you’ll
notice a few things here. On the
left hand bars, you’ll see that
there’s a- there’s a file tree
there. So essentially it’s the
methodology that you’re going to
be using. And then we break it
down by functionality. And, um,
for this one- this is the actual
default, um, kind of JSON file
that we have included within
HUNT- and it breaks it down by,
um, areas of the application
that you generally are testing
for vulnerabilities. Things like
the account- the account
registration, money
transactions, authentications,
search, contacts us. Those are
usually the places we’re going
to be testing for
vulnerabilities and where you’ll
definitely find vulnerabilities
of certain types. So for
example, uh, on the account
page, you’re going to be testing
things like iDoor. Or a pro site
request forgery,
auth-authentication bypass, and
stuff like that. So this is how
I have it layed out. But if you
have your own methodology, you
can also just, um, do it
yourself and it’s a simple JSON
file, uh, and we’ll get to that
in a second. And you can, you
know, put in your own
methodology. Everyone has a
different methodology that they
follow. But the important thing
here is that we wanted to make
it easy for the pen tester to be
able to actually put that
methodology in, uh- in Burp so
that they’re, um, going through
it and they’re efficient at
doing their work. Um. So here
you see that there’s a
description. So, um, not just
for the season pen tester, but
again we want to address that
tri- tribal knowledge, um,
aspect. So if you have newer
members on your team who aren’t,
um, seasoned or, you know,
aren’t, uh, used to doing web
hacking, um, for a particular
testing here. So let- let’s say,
you know, for authentication
bypass, I don’t know- I don’t
know what the hell that means,
um, I would see here on
description that, ok, I would do
this- this check for this
particular type of
vulnerability. The next tab here
is called Bugs. So, um, we do
multiple request and response
tracking so you might have, uh,
multiple, uh, requests and
responses for a particular vu-
vulnerability, and they might
be, um, different, uh, attack
vectors so you keep track of all
of that here. And then, uh, when
you go generate your report,
boom. You already have, um, all
of your work there. No copying
and pasting; that’s disgusting.
Um. Next thing here, uh, the
resources. So again, just like
in the Scanner window, uh, we’re
going to have the resources for
you. So, again, you can put all
the resources here. Sql
injection for example you’re
going to do- you’re going to
use, like, Pen Test monkey,
stuff like that, or you might
even put in, um, you know, how
to use Sqlmap on there. Stuff
like that. And then the notes
section. So we also have a notes
section here so, you know, whe-
when you’re doing your work you
might- you might go off and
start doing sql injection.
You’re not- you’re not finding
it or, you know You have the
error, but you can’t get, uh, a
proper POC for it. Um. And you
want to- you want to work on it
later. So. Uh. You can leave
notes for yourself. You know,
try to break it manually. Uh. If
I can’t do that, then use
Sqlmap. And then if all else
fails, I’ll send it to Bob or
I’ll send it to Jason because I
suck at sql- sql injection. So
the next thing here is that, uh,
with the notes, um, you can send
your actual, uh, JSON file to
other people and they can load
it up in their- in their Burp
for instance. Or you could even,
uh, you know, you can save it
and then have it for your
reports. So, um, just like in
that instance with notes, if,
you know, I want Jason, for
example, to check my work for my
methodology- it’s, like, my
first week on the job and I
wanted to make sure that I’m
doing it right, he could go
ahead and look at it in his own
instance in Burp and it’ll-
it’ll have all the requests and
responses. Uh. And he could do-
he could check that. If, you
know, I need help with sql
injection from someone on my
team who, uh, is much better at-
at sql injection than I am, they
can go ahead and do that, get
the POC, and then send it back
to me, and then I can k-keep
doing my work. And this is the,
um, implementation, uh, within-
within Burp itself. Uh. So we
used ExtensionStateListener,
IContext, um, MenuFactory, in
iTab and then that makes the
Burp tab, uh, HUNT methodology.
So, um, if you were to edit this
and then, um, you know, add your
own stuff here all you need to
do is open up the code and then,
uh, go into the create menus
function and then mess around
there. And then we’ll do a live
demo. Let’s see So let’s say,
you know So we’re using, uh,
the HUNT Scanner and the HUNT
Methodology contraption. Right?
So, uh, let’s say I send one of
these to Repeater. So you can
actually, um, you know, send all
these requests and responses
from Scanner to things like
Repeater and Intruder. And then
you can continue your work
there. So let’s say I send it to
Repeater, and I have one set up
here So I do- I do my hacking
on here. I do my manual, uh,
tests. And then I find that it
is, uh, vulnerable. Let’s see
this one. Um. And, you know,
it’s there. I want to send it to
my methodology now because I’m
done. And I want to prove my
work. So, um, right click here.
Send to HUNT Methodology. Let’s
say I’m testing for iDoor. I’ll
put it right here. When I go
into methodology, I’ll go into
functionality and account. And
then it’s in- it’s within the
bug so I- I can also, you know,
just close it if, um, I don’t
want- I don’t want it in there.
So that’s the, uh, typical
workflow for, um, getting stuff
in Scanner and then doing the
testing in Repeater and
Intruder, sending that all into,
uh, the HUNT Methodology. Now
let’s talk about the actual
plugin installation. So, um, as
we were talking about before,
this is- this plugin lives
within Burp Suite so kind of the
installation is that, uh, you
know, we’re using Jython so the
actual, uh, code is written in
Python and then we use Jython to
be able to use it within Burp
because it’s- it’s using the
JDN. So what you would do is
here in this, uh, Python
environment, uh, you would go on
the Jython website, uh, get the
latest standalone jar and you
would actually put it in here so
that when, uh, Burp loads up
the, uh, plugin, it’ll- it’ll go
in there. Next is the actual
installation of the plugin
itself. So you would go into the
extender tab and you would add
it as a Burp extension. Uh.
You’ll notice here that there is
an extension type. I set it to
Python and then I set it to the
actual extension itself. So
then, uh, wherever that’s
living, select it and then
you’re off and ready to go. But
more of the setup of actually
using, um, HUNT So, uh, those
of you who have used, uh, Burp a
lot know that, um, the passive
scanner can be, uh, pretty
noisy. So depending on how you
have your scope set up, you
definitely want to do that. So
you can see here, um, like with
the example Jason gave earlier
with tesla, you would add the
in the target window, add Scope,
add tesla here, and it will only
get tesla, um, hostnames, uh,
that match. After that, you
would go into Scanner. And then
you would, uh, select a use
suite scope on the live passive
scanner. So the- the scanner
actually uses the passive
scanner, but none of that
information will show up on- on
the actual passive scanner
window. It’ll be in- it’ll be
within HUNT. And, uh, kind of
the effective way that we-we’ve
seen, uh, this used and how we
use it ourselves is that within
the target window itself, you
would go in there. Um. Click,
uh actually spider all of those
items so you can get a lot of
coverage for all the things you
need to test. And once that’s
all done, click passively scan
selected items, and all of that
will end up in the, um, scanner
window. >>Cool. So another thing
that we wanted to make sure, uh,
was that it was easily
extensible. So, um. So both, uh,
Methodology and, uh, Scanner,
uh, can easily be extended to
accommodate something like a new
CDE that comes out tomorrow.
Maybe Burp doesn’t have to check
for or a specific vulnerability,
that maybe you guys see in your
environment but wasn’t in our
data set. Um. So the scanner
sensibility is just a JSON file.
It’s called Issues dot JSON. Um.
And so you, uh, define, uh,
something in this kind of schema
With, uh... Here you can see IOS
injection is the one that’s
listed. Uh. And then all you
have to do to add, um, a new
parameter alert is just add
something at the bottom here.
Here you can see under, uh,
download I’ve got sexyparam. Um.
So this will now alert in the
HUNT window. Methodology is very
much the same. JSON file. Um.
You can set the top level pieces
of the methodology, um, in the
schema. Um. There’s a ray and,
uh, you can set, uh, texts about
it. Uh. You can set notes with
it that automatically pop up
with it. Resources bugs you
can load them automatically, um,
by filling out this JSON schema
as well. So we’ll go ahead and
add something really quick. So
here we have the issues JSON
file open, um, for my loaded,
um, HUNT scanner. Um. At the
top, the first one is insecure
direct object reference and I’m
just going to add a custom
parameter here. So, uh, I’ll add
beefcake. Alright. So I’ve added
beefcake to, uh, the list. And I
will just save that. And now we
will reload, um, HUNT Scanner.
So you do that through Extender.
Uncheck Scanner. Recheck
Scanner. Cool. Now we’ll go to
our site and we’re proxy8 still
and here we will change this
too. Hopefully this works. So
this obviously doesn’t exist,
uh, but it’s still going to
trigger the Scanner. Hopefully.
Alright. Uh. So let’s go to
Scanner. I think that was in
iDoor, right? Yeah. There’s
beefcake and there’s our request
and response. And then we could
send this to either Methodology
or Repeater to continue testing.
So real easy to extend. Um. Both
the, uh, the methodology and
the, uh, issues in this. There’s
also the checklist and, um, we
included two methodologies with
this so, uh, if you go into the
default it’s checklist dot JSON.
And here you can see this is
kind of the schema. I’m not
going to type up a whole new
one. But, uh, pretty easy to
just copy and paste one of these
blocks here, uh, and create new
methodology steps for your
testers if, should it apply to
your work if you do something
different or, uh, you don’t like
the methodologies that are
included. So Cool. Um. So stuff
we want to do that we haven’t
done yet. Um. So, uh, we want
more methodologies. So we
included in this one- we
included, um, the application
functionality map, uh, that we
tested. And then we also
included the web application
hacker’s handbook methodology in
the back of the book. Um. So
these are things that we want to
kind of improve on. This is all
on Github. We’re looking for
people to help with this stuff.
Um. So PCI, HIPPA, CREST, OWASP,
PTES all have, uh, methodologies
or reference each other for
methodologies and are kind of
modified. Um. So we would like
to port these into that JSON
schema so we could support, uh,
using methodology for those. Um.
We like Burp but a lot of people
like Zap so we’ll probably port
this to Zap at some point in the
future. Um. More scanner
vulnerability checks and classes
with data sets from not just us,
uh, from other people. Um. More
resources, uh- more testing
resources from new people
getting into application
assessment so cheat sheets, uh,
guides on exploitations- good
ones, um, internal methodologies
for testing certain, uh,
vulnerability classes, etcetera.
Um. Dynamic JSON structure
source. So we’re now in the, um,
methodology, you can only have
two nested methodology pieces.
Um. And you have to sport the
rest to be in notes and tabs.
Um. It’s just something that we
haven’t been able to get around
right now so we want to figure
out that problem. The GUI is,
uh, not up to par. We would like
to make that better. Right now
it only supports, um, uh, param
equals value scanning. So we
would like to support rest
scanning at some point as well.
Um. So rest URL support. Um. And
then there was you noticed we
did the right click, you only
saw Intruder and Repeater. We’d
like to include, um, some of the
other full Burp helpers like,
uh, the rest of click menu that
you get in Targets, uh,
searching and highlighting,
etcetera. But those API’s are a
little bit harder to bake into a
custom tab window. Um. We’d like
to be able to, um, do some, um,
file name analysis instead of
just parameters, but we don’t
have data on that yet. We can
parse it soon. Um. So instead of
parameters like, uh, resource
name or script name or something
like that, uh, most vulnerable
classes there. And then alert on
content types, etcetera. So
there’s still a lot of work to
be done here. Um. But, uh, but
yeah, it’s pretty good. And
then, uh, responses on errors.
So, yeah. So that’s, uh, that’s
the jist of the tool. [applause]