>>Um [laughs] So yeah Def Con
has a long standing tradition
and uh ya know if uh- it’s a
speaker’s first time on stage,
then um they do a shot. So it’s
not about uh alcohol although
you know [applause] yeah, it’s
a- it’s a tradition that’s
intended just to honor our
speakers and uh Def Con you know
from from times of yore so
anyway this is Matt Wixy and uh
he’s gonna do a shot with us
>>Cheers! [applause] [laughter]
>>Alright so please welcome Matt
Wixey. [applause] [computer
start up noise] >>Hello Def Con.
Uh. So this is, um, “See no
evil, hear no evil- Hacking
invisibly and silently with
light and sound.” Um. My name is
Matt Wixey. I lead the
vulnerability research function
on, uh, the pentesting team at
PwC’s UK. I also run something
called The Dark Art Lab which is
a research blog looking at the
more esoteric aspects of
security research. Uh. I’ve been
a PwC for about a year. Uh.
Prior to that I worked in, uh,
law enforcement in the UK for
about eight years, uh, leading a
technical and research
development team. So today’s
talk is split into four parts.
Um. First I’m going to show you
three custom tools I’ve
developed to, uh, use light and
sound to jump air-gaps. I’m then
going to talk about, uh, laser
microphones, two different kinds
of, uh, infrared motion
detectors, and different ways
you can disrupt and disarm them.
Part three Bantz. Um. I’m not
sure if that term’s made out of
the UK. Um. But it roughly
translates to lulz so it’s kind
of stuff I’ve found during the
course of research- the term,
um, has made me, um, laugh more
than anything else. Um. Rather
than being kind of practical
use. Um. And as you’ll see
throughout this talk, that’s
quite a l-low bar. Um. But
hopefully you guys will enjoy as
well. And then I’m just going to
sum up and give some ideas for-
for future research. So a couple
of disclaimers. The views and
opinions in this talk aren’t
necessarily those of PwC. Um.
All the content is for
educational purposes only. So
please check legislation. Get
permission. So on. Uh. This
presentation isn’t about, uh,
exploiting vulnerabilities per
say. It’s about manipulating,
uh, the inputs and outputs of a
system in order to have a
desired effect. Uh. And lastly,
I am definitely not an
electronics expert or a physics
expert at all. Uh. In fact I’ve
only been in security for about
six or seven years. Uh. My
bachelor’s degree was in, uh,
English Language and Literature,
uh, which has been really
helpful. Um. [laughter] So, um.
Yeah. So just to give you an
idea, um, I kind of regularly
still poke myself over resisters
and drill myself with soldering
irons and, uh, I see magic smoke
so much it’s not even magical to
me anymore. [laughter] It’s
just, uh- it’s just I call it
routine smoke. Um. [laughter] So
this is where I am on the- on
the Dunning-Kruger Curve. If
you’ve guys are familiar with
this. [laughter] Um. So I don’t
want you guys to think that I’m
kind of presenting myself as an
expert on this stuff. Um. But
what I’m going to do at the end
of the talk is, uh, put my
Twitter handle up and email
address. And please do get in
touch if you- if you think I’ve
got something wrong or there’s
something that could be improved
or you’ve got any ideas or
suggestions. That’d be great
‘cause, um, that’s what Def Con
is about at the end of the day.
Right? Um. So let’s jump
straight into it. So the first
thing I want to show you is
this. This is an example of
Li-fy. Data transmission through
lights. Uh. In this case, the
data is music. And this is, uh,
adapted off of, uh, Schematic on
GitHub. And the, uh, the link to
that will be in the, uh,
references part at the end of
the deck. Um. But it’s
basically, uh, what we’ve got
here is, uh, a phone that’s
playing music. The headphone
output goes through a breadboard
of LED’s which are going to
modulate the music data that is
going through. And then you have
a photo vinod hooked up to a
speaker, uh, that’s going to
play the music. [music plays]
[laughter] Um. Yeah. So that was
my impression with that actually
worked for the first time. Uh.
And then I did the same thing,
uh, with infrared LEDs as well.
So exactly the same setup. Even
the same song. It’s just
infrared LEDs instead of white
LEDs are modulating. [music] So
that got me kind of thinking
about air-gaps and different
ways you can jump air-gaps. And,
uh, I’m going to assume that
everyone here is kind of
familiar with the concept of an
air-gap. Um. There’s been a lot
of research on how to jump them.
And they all come with caveats.
So, um, the first caveat is we
assume the attackers have
managed to infect at least one
host, uh, with a bit- a bit of
malware. Um. That the attack has
physical or near-physical access
to that affected host because
we’re talking about quite
primitive inputs and outputs to
a system. So we’re talking about
like heat, sound, light, um, uh,
EM radiation, that kind of
thing. And then linked to that,
um, the exfiltration of air-gap
systems is going to be really
slow. Uh. And it’s going to deal
with quite small pieces of data
because typically we’re talking
about two bit channels, um, so
high or low states. So this is
some of the research that has
been done in this area. You guys
would be familiar with a lot of
this already probably. Um. All
the way from Van Eck phreaking
back in the 70’s which is EM
radiation from, uh, CLT
monitors. Um. There’s been some
great work done by guys at
Bangor University in Israel, uh,
on jumping air-gaps. Um.
Particularly, uh, using heat.
Um. VisiSploit which, um,
encoded data as a kind of QR
code. Flashed it up on the
screen. Um. The attacker would
then film the screen, um, and be
able to decode it. And Hasan and
others in 2013 gave a really
good overview of some of these
techniques. Um. And one I think
that they proposed was using
ambient light sensors from
mobile devices to be able to
control smart phones, um, by
flickering overhead lighting.
That kind of thing. So the first
technique I want to show you is
using ambient light sensors. Um.
So ambient light sensors are,
um, essentially hardware
components. They’re found in the
frames of laptops, smartphones,
monitors, that kind of thing.
And they’re normally, um, uh,
photoresistors, photodiodes,
something like that, that
increases or decreases
resistance according to the
amount of light that hits it.
Uh. And the idea there is you
just screen write this according
to the amount of ambient light.
So it’s quite, uh, um, um,
benign, uh, thing to have. Um.
And you can interact with it
programmatically, um, through
the Windows API. So, um, my plan
was to create a malware that
could read in light intensity
values from, uh, an ambient
light sensor on a Windows
workstation, um, and then
execute different commands
according to the amount of light
that was hitting the ALS and the
kind of changes in, uh,
frequency- oh, sorry- in changes
in intensity. So a couple of
problems is that, um, you have
to try to make this like a
covert activity because you
can’t just shine a massive
flashlight, um, uh, a laptop.
And you need some kind of
exfiltration capability as well.
Right? Because, um, being able
to control malware is fine, but
for an air-gap system ideally
you want to concentrate on, uh,
exfiltration. So, uh, I’m going
to be brave and try to show you
a live demo of this. Ok. So I’ve
got a laptop here, um, that’s
got an ambient light sensor. The
ambient light sensor is just
here. And what I’ve got here is
an infrared torch. So if I just
turn this on, you shouldn’t be
able to see anything besides
like a red glow. But for
unfiltered cameras, um, they’ll
be able to see them. So I’m
going to run the malware on this
laptop and then introduce high
values through the ambient light
sensor. And that then, uh, pops
up a calc on the screen.
[laughter] [applause] Ok. So,
yeah, in terms of exfiltration,
um, optical channels, um, for
air-gaps are quite difficult,
um, optically. Um. There have
been some things suggested so
VisiSploit like I mentioned
earlier, that relies on the, uh,
attacker having a camera, uh,
inside what is probably a secure
area. So I came up with this
instead. Um. So the idea here is
that the malware when it wants
to exfiltrate data, it will read
in a file, uh, convert it to
bits, uh, and it will then make
very subtle changes in the
screen brightness, um, to
represent that which then can be
picked up by an external sensor.
Um. So the easiest way to, um,
make screen brightness changes
is with WMI. Um. Unfortunately
that requires, uh, admin
privileges. However changing
gamma values and displays
doesn’t. So you can use a set
device gamma ramp with a Windows
API, um, and you can make very,
very small changes, uh, in the
gamma value of a display. So
the- the device I’ve got here,
um, is a light to frequency
converter. And this is much more
sensitive than a typical
photodiode or photo sensor. Um.
It can actually pick up changes
in the bioluminescence of
bacteria. Um. It can read light
intensity changes through-
through your hand. Um. And it’s
connected to an Arduino nano
here. So what I’ve got here is
a, um, the circuit connected
with a microsoft SD reader
writer module. And I’m just
going to do a test of this
exfiltration function. So the
malware is going to read in a
file. And it’s going to make
very small changes to the- the
gamma value with the display.
Uh. What the malware actually
does- it takes likes a baseline
before exfiltration. Then it
makes changes, um, uh, increases
or decreases according to
whatever. So one over zero. And
then after exfiltration’s
finished, it will return it
back. So you might be able to
see that, um, the very kind of
slight changes there. Um. But
from the attacker’s point of
view, it’s actually quite
obvious whether it’s, uh, a one
or a zero being transmitted. And
then what you can then do is
demodulate the data and retrieve
the original bits. And, uh,
that’s not particularly covert.
Kind of just plunking a
breadboard down to a screen so
this is a more, uh, covert
application. Um. So what we have
here is the same, uh, light
sensor, light to frequency
converter, an Ada Fruit Flora
board, so an air conductor with
a conductive thread. And then
you have, uh, the same SD writer
as well. Um. So the idea is you
can exfiltrate data or an
attacker can exfiltrate data
just sitting in front of a
screen and wearing that tie. So
the second thing I want to show
you is Dreadphone. Uh. So
Dreadphone is commander control
using near-ultrasonic sounds. So
by near-ultrasonic, uh, what I
mean is sounds that are, uh,
typically not able to be heard
by most adults. Um. So the
theoretical range of human
hearing is 20 hertz to 20
kilohertz. In practice, most
adult humans can only hear, um,
up to about 16 kilohertz. So 16
kilohertz to 20 kilohertz is
like near-ultrasonic. At most,
adults can’t hear that. It’s
perfectly within the
capabilities of a normal, uh,
laptop soundcard, uh, speaker or
microphone to transmit and
receive audio, uh, in that
range. So there’s been previous
research on this. Uh. Toftsed
and others and Hanspach and
Goetz did something similar. Uh.
One problem they’ve come across,
uh, is this. So this is, uh, a
recording of near-ultrasonic
sounds being played. [computer
audio] So while you can’t hear
the tones there, what’s actually
happening is that there’s
electrical discharge on the
soundcard, uh, which makes those
kinds of clicks and pops. So,
um, what I did with Dreadphone
was I pre-prepared 16 wav files.
Uh. Each one represents a
different ultrasonic tone, uh,
in increments from 18.5
kilohertz up to 20 kilohertz. So
16 in total. Each one
representing a hex, uh,
character. Um. I applied
multiple fade-ins and fade-outs
to those. Um. So it kind of
smooths the, uh, the input into
the sound card. And then
amplified it. You end up with
this. So this is Dreadphone
running on two laptops. Um. This
is the victim. And the attacker
is here on the left. So, uh,
this is monitoring the- the
microphone input. So what the
attacker is going to do here is
just tell the victim to pop
calc, um, which means it’s going
to send a sequence of those
pre-prepared wav files and the
victim then, um, executes that.
[laughter] [applause] Ok. So
the- the next thing, um, is
exfiltration. So this is, uh, a
txt file. [laughter] It, uh So
Batman would be a really good
movie if Bruce Wayne was
actually true to the type and
communicated with people at 45
kilohertz. Um. [laughter] The
attacker’s going to exfiltrate
this, uh, this txt file. So it’s
just going to send the
exfiltration message. And I’ll
stay with the attacker here. And
what you’ll see is a different
tone start to come back. Now
there is a case study of this
technique being used in the mode
Um. I haven’t gotten a copy of
the malware so I haven’t been
able to verify it. But BadBIOS.
You guys heard of that? Um. So
that, um, whilst infected the
BIOS, um, of machines it also
communicated with other infected
hosts uh, there you go um using
near-ultrasonic tones.
[applause] So, um, Dreadphone is
fine for like small bits of data
and small strings and stuff like
that. But if you want to
exfiltrate, um, uh, more
content, say images for
instance, you’re a bit more
limited. But you can actually
use a technique that’s been used
in popular music before. Um. And
it involves spectrograms. Uh. So
a spectrogram is a visual
representation of the
frequencies in a piece of audio.
Um. And, what the, uh, what
these musicians have done is
they’ve read-in an image file.
They’ve iterated through the
pixels, got the pixel values,
and then they’ve written out,
uh, frequencies, uh, to a wav
file that corresponds with those
pixel values. And when you view
the audio as a spectrogram, uh,
you end up with, uh, an
approximation of that original
image. Uh. So in this case you
have a face on the left and a
cat on the right. So these are
both, um, uh, examples from
popular music. Uh. So Let me
try another demo. So let’s say I
have an image like this that I
want to exfiltrate. This is a
spectrogram tool that does that.
So it reads in the image and
then you can specify a minimum
and a maximum frequency. So I’m
staying with, um,
near-ultrasonic again. If I
generate that, it writes out a
wav file. If I try and play that
wav file, you shouldn’t really
be able to hear anything unless
you’ve got really good hearing
or are younger than I am. So
some of you might be able to
hear it. Um. But if I view that
in a spectrogram, you can
recover, uh, the original image.
[laughter] [applause] Now the-
the, um There are tools out
there already that will let you
do this. So Coagula,
Spectrology, that kind of thing.
Uh. What spectrogram also does
is it let’s you merge your
secret file with a legitimate
audio file. So, um, in case you
have got your kind of younger
people working environment that
are able to hear that. Um. So
I’ve got a normal, uh, wav file
here. [music plays] So it just
plays kind of ordinary music.
And I can merge my secret file
with that. And that writes me
out a new wav file. So if I play
that, um, you just hear the
ordinary music. You can open
that merge file and still
recover, uh, the original image.
[applause] Ok. So in terms of
mitigation for this kind of
stuff and jumping air-gaps in
general. You’re looking at
things like TEMPEST standards,
um, removing and disabling
ambient light sensors if they’re
not required or covering them
up. Um. Privacy filters for
laptops do a really good job of
muting, uh, screen brightness
changes. Um. And in terms of the
ultrasonic stuff, um, you can
look at things like white noise
or ultrasonic detectors. Um. But
ultimately, uh, if you’ve got
any kind of input and output to
a system that’s not necessary or
not integral to the operation of
that particular piece of
equipment, um, you’re probably
better off just disabling it. So
part two. Uh. Surveillance and
counter-surveillance. Um. So
first thing is a laser
microphone. Um. Just a quick
hands up, who’s heard of a laser
microphone before? Ok. Quite a
few people. Um. So, uh, for
those of you who haven’t, I’ll
just quickly explain what it
does. So imagine that you’re
doing, uh, surveillance on a
group of people across the
street from you. And those
people are behind a window. Um.
Let’s say the- the glass is
soundproof so you can’t hear
anything. Um. Let’s say they’ve
drawn the curtains so you can’t
video them and do lipreading.
And assume you don’t have any
bugs or anything in the room.
What you can do is use a laser
microphone. So you shine a laser
at the window and you capture
the reflective beam with a
photodiode or a photosensor. So
what’s happening is as those
people in that room are talking,
the air is vibrating. It makes
the glass in the window vibrate.
Which makes your reflected laser
beam shift slightly. And as that
moves across the surface of your
photodiode, it of course shifts
in voltage which can then be
converted back into sound. Uh.
So on the right here I’ve got a
really cheap laser module, um,
that’s hooked up to an 8 volt
battery. And on the left I have
a photodiode. Um. This is
actually adapted from a circuit
that did something else. Um. The
output goes through a 3.5
millimeter audio jack. So, uh,
to demonstrate this So I have
the laser. I’ve got the listener
hooked up to a speaker. Uh. The
laser is firing at a, uh, phone
that’s playing music very, very
quietly. Taped to the back of
the speaker is a bit of
reflective material. And at the
moment, there’s a bit of
obstruction between the
reflected laser beam and the
listener. If I remove that
[music begins to play] So um
[laughter] [applause] So that
obviously like a really cheap, a
really simple sort of model.
And, uh, that only cost like 25
pounds, the whole kind of setup.
Um. If you obviously had a bit
more of a budget, you could use
like interferometry. Um. You
could experiment with using
infrared lasers to make it more
covert. Um. ‘Cause nothing says
“I’m using a laser microphone”
like shining a really highly
visible laser. Um. [laughter]
You can kind of filter
interference use [mic crackles]
kind of stuff as well. Ok. Um.
So moving onto sniffing,
analysing, cloning infrared. So,
um, I imagine a lot of people
here will have done, um, or will
have experimented with, like,
cloner replay attacks using a,
uh, SDR with RF signals. And
infrared’s very similar. Um. So
with infrared signals, assuming
that like fixed codes- they, uh,
will use things like byface
market coding, manchestering
coding, that kind of thing as
well. Uh. They use a carrier
wav. Um. Normally 38 kilohertz
but it can be other frequencies
as well. So we need a way to
listen to the signal. Uh. Then a
way to analyze it and then a way
to replay it. Uh. And if you
guys are interested in infrared,
there’s a really great talk, um,
from Def Con in 2005 by Major
Malfunction. He found a way to
compromise hotel payment systems
by messing around with infrared,
uh, TV remotes, uh, in hotel
rooms. So the first thing you
could do is just use an RTL-SDR.
So these things still have an
infrared sensor in them, um,
that you can actually use to
sniff infrared signals. Um. It
just returns you like the raw
post data so it’s completely
undecoded. Uh. But you could do
that. You could use a dedicated
infrared receiver component like
Arduino and then you can use the
IRLib library. And the nice
thing about this library is if
it’s one of, um, kind eight or
nine popular consumer protocols,
it will actually tell you what
protocol it is and decode it for
you. So then this is the standby
signal for my, uh, TV remote. So
it tells me it’s using the NEC
protocol and then tells me what
the value, um, of that code is.
And then you can also use the
listener, um, for that laser
microphone. So that will do it
as well. [computer noises] And
then you can expect the- the-
the- inspect the signal visually
which is quite nice. In terms of
replaying it, if it’s a known
protocol like NEC or something
like that, you can just play it
back. Um. So in this case I’ve
used the IRremote library. Uh.
You can just play it back with a
normal consumer protocol. Uh.
Like RF, however, if it’s
unknown, um, then you have to
replay the raw array, um, that
you’ve managed to sniff. So
applying this practically, um,
to, um, motion detectors. So the
testing I’m going to talk about
is a passive infrared motion
detector. So these have a
passive infrared sensor in them
that respond to changes in
infrared radiation, ie. uh, body
heat. So there was a talk, um,
at BlackHat 2013 USA by Porter
and Smith where they talked
about different methods to
defeat physical security and
they mentioned passive infrared
sensors. Uh. And you can do
things like move really slowly
so the changes in body heat
aren’t registered by the sensor.
You can, um, coat yourself in a
reflective material. Not the
most practical approach but, uh,
it works. Um. Or you could
overwhelm the sensor with heat
so like a flame. Um. So I think
in their talk, they used a
lighter to do it. So here’s an
example of a passive infrared
motion detector. Um. So the gray
sphere on it, that’s the actual
sensor itself. Uh. The red
window to the top, that’s
actually the receiver for that
remote control. So the remote
control is used to arm or disarm
the main unit. Um. Quiet-wide
I’ve used infrared to do that. I
don’t know, um, as opposed to
RF. Um. And then on the right is
a circuit board I can use to do
a simple clone to replay attack.
Uh. I just clone the disarm
signal, uh, from that remote.
[alarm noises] So it’s now on.
They’re just tested works. And
then I can use my evil device to
just clone the disarm signal.
And that’s now disarmed. So
there’s nothing kind of
particularly innovative or
interesting about that. It’s
just the normal clone and replay
attack. I suppose the one thing
that is interesting it’s
infrared. Um. But there’s two
big flaws in this approach. And
the first is how do you get the
disarmed signal in the first
place? Assuming it’s- because,
you know, it’s infrared. You
have to be quite close to it.
Um. So you’re stuck with having
to like, um, have a device in
the vicinity or steal a remote
somehow and capture the signal.
And the second problem is how do
you get close enough to disarm
it once you’ve got the disarm
signal, um, without setting off
the main unit. So I bought nine
of these. Um. They’re
manufactured by the same
manufacturer but sold under the,
um, different brand names. And I
captured the signals from the
remotes. And here are the
signals from the first six.
[laughter] Ok. So straight out
of the box, um, regardless of
what main unit the remote was
first used with, it will arm and
disarm any main unit. So here’s
all nine. [laughter] So I just
picked the remote up. [video
playing] [laughter] And then
pick another one up and I can
disarm all of them. [laughter]
[applause] So I’m almost like
embarrassed to present that at
Def Con. [laughter] Now, so
that’s the first problem taken
care of. How do we get the
disarm the signal. Second
problem: how do we get close
enough to the main unit to
disarm it without setting it
off. Here’s the first solution.
[laughter] Um. So this is a
Drone to clone to pwn. This is,
um, the disarming circuit
powered by the drone’s internal
USB port. The reason you can use
a drone is ‘cause the lithium
battery in it doesn’t get hot
enough to set off, um, a motion
detector until it’s been in the
air for about 45 seconds.
[laughter] So here’s the alarm
in the foreground. You can see
I’ve dressed up for this video.
So if I arm this and then try to
walk up to it, it detects me. So
you’ll shortly see that my drone
piloting skills are about on a
par with my fashion sense.
[laughter] Ok. So we’re going to
fly the drone over and it won’t
set it off, but it will disarm
it. [laughter] [applause] Ok.
Second solution: Phone to clone
to pwn. So. Um. This is using an
AdaFruit GSM break up board. Um.
This is heavily based on, uh,
Samy Kamkar’s ding dong ditch or
digital ding dong ditch if
you’ve seen that. Um. Some
slight modifications. So
obviously it uses infrared
rather than RF. Um. It also
doesn’t use Interrupt. It just
uses a time loop and it deletes
text messages off the SIM card,
uh, once they’ve been read. So
the idea here is you would hide
this or pay someone to hide this
near an alarm, um, during the
day when it’s deactivated. Then
after hours when the system is
on, you can just send a text to
a number containing a certain
string, and it will then disarm
it. Ok. So as usual the first
thing I’ll do is arm the, uh,
main unit and then just test it.
[alarm beeps] Ok. And I’ll just
look quickly at the Arduino
sketch, um, which is just
checking for new messages every
five seconds on that SIM card.
So I’m now going to send a text
to the number that’s on that SIM
card. And in this case, the
string, uh, sketch you’re
looking for is “new phone who
dis.” [laughter] [alarm beeps]
[applause] And then just looking
at the sketch to just to make
sure it reads the, uh, text
message and sends a signal and
then deletes the message from
the SIM card. Now you could
combine both of those together
and do Phone to Drone to Clone
to PWN. Um. [laughter] But that
would just be absurd so I
haven’t done that. Ok. Um. The
next kind of motion detector is
this. So this is active infrared
motion detector. So the idea
here is you have two components:
a transmitter and receiver. And
the transmitter is constantly
sending a pulse of infrared
signals, uh, to the receiver.
And if the beam’s broken [alarm
beeps] then the alarm sounds.
And if you continually move the
transmitter, away [alarm beeps]
then the alarm would just
continually sound until you
clone the signal from the
transmitter and just put it
right next to the receiver.
[laughter] Ok. Uh. So in terms
of mitigation for these kinds of
attacks. So for laser
microphones, um, you can get
devices that vibrate the glass
on windows, um, to try and
disrupt laser mics. I’m not sure
how effective they are. But
things like wire screens and
coverings on windows. Um. As
you’ve seen with the, um,
infrared torchlight is you can
detect the infrared light if
you’re using an unfiltered
camera. So you can use that to
detect infrared lasers. Um.
Double-glazing or curved glass
can cause issues with laser
mics. Um. As can other
environmental conditions like,
uh, rain and snow and that kind
of a thing. Um. In terms of
alarms, ideally you want to try
and disarm the physical keypads.
Um. Not that that’s perfect, but
it’s better than remotes because
the signals could be sniffed.
Um. And if you do have to use
remotes, you want to go for ones
that use, like, tried and
tested, encrypted rolling code
algorithm. Um. And that are
paired uniquely to a device. You
wouldn’t think you’d have to say
that explicitly, um, but yeah.
Ok. So, uh, last part is bantz.
Um. So the first thing I want to
show you is speech jamming or
delayed auditory feedback. Um.
So this is a technique that’s
been around since the 50’s. It’s
actually, um, originally used to
help people who stutter. Um. The
idea is you introduce a latency
between someone, um, speaking
and them hearing themselves
speak. And when, uh, used with
people who stutter, it, um,
enables them to speak more
clearly. If you use it on people
who don’t have a stutter, it
dramatically inhibits their
capability to speak. Um. And it
causes, like, mental stress.
Safe to assume. Um. Researches
in 2012 who came up with, like,
a hardware version. Um. I built
a software version called
doubleSpeak. And I tested it out
some- on some colleagues because
I didn’t want to look stupid
myself. So. [laughter] So what
these guys are doing is they’re
reading a paragraph, uh, from a
website about delayed auditory
feedback, uh, while my tool is
running on the laptop and
they’re wearing a pair of
headphones. >>Delayed auditory
feed-feedback, also called
delayed side tone, is a type of
audi- auditory feedback -back
that consists of extending the
time between speech and auditory
s- perception. >>Delayed
auditory feedback, also called
delayed sidetone, is a type of
audi- aud- auditory fee-
feedback -back that consists of
extending the time between the
speech and the auditory per-
perception. [laughter] >>Delayed
aud itory feed. back, also
called delayed sidetone, is a
type of alted- alteuditory
feedback that consists of
extending the time between
speech and auditory percep
tion. [laughter] >>when hear
his.. voice in headphones a
fract- come of a sec ond later.
Some DAF devices are hardware.
DAF computer software is also
available. Most delays produce a
noticeable effect are between 50
to 200 milliseconds. DAF usage
with a 175 millisecond delay has
been shown to induce mental
stress. Surely this is
stressful. [laughter] So, um, on
the face of it, that doesn’t
seem to have much practical
application to security. Um. One
way that we came up with that
you might be able to use it is,
um, say you’re on a network and
your goal is to kind of sow
disruption and discord but in a
very subtle way. You could find
out when a very important
conference call is taking place
and use this. And kind of affect
the decision outcome of that
conference call, um, without
kind of having to do anything,
um, too blatant. Ok. Uh. Next
thing: demotivating malware
analysts. So, um, this is
inspired by Christopher Domas
who’s speaking, uh, tomorrow I
think. Um. And he came up with
this awesome thing in, uh, 2015,
um, which was he created fully
functioning malware which when
looked at in a disassembler in
the flow graph, represents an
image, um, under his control. So
he can basically choose the
image that a malware analyst has
to stare at all day long. Um.
Which is awesome. So I used my,
um, spectrogram tool to come up
with something, uh, similar,
albeit a lot cruder. So let’s
say you’ve got malware and when
you run it, it plays really
weird music like this.
[screeching computer noise] So
the first thing you do is
disassemble it. In this case
it’s dot net so it’s very easy.
And you look at what’s causing
that sound. So in this case,
it’s a wav file, um, that you
can then extract from the, um,
main binary. And you’re playing
that wav file and trying to
think what is this? Is this some
kind of encrypted communication?
Is it trying to exploit
something? What is it? And you
spend ages and ages looking at
it. Until eventually it occurs
to you to look at it as a
spectrogram. And then you see
something like that. [laughter]
[applause] Ok. Uh. Do we have
any Gilmore Girls fans in the
room? [Cheers] Ok. So, um, to
give you a bit of background on
this, my wife is a huge Gilmore
Girls fan. Uh. She watched it
all when it first came out. Um.
They streamed it like two years
ago and she’s watched- since
then, she’s watched season one
to season eight I- I’ve lost
count. In that time, I’ve gone
from passive indifference
thinking, you know, “this is ok
but I can’t really see the
appeal” to kind of active
loathing of this program.
[laughter] So I came up with,
um, Kill More Gilmore which I
think on reflection is probably
the best thing I’ve ever done.
Um. So Kill More Gilmore is, uh
It comes- it’s two parts. It’s a
Python script and an Arduino
device. Now the Python script
uses, uh, an open source music
recognition library called Deja
Vu, um, which is on GitHub.
Again, the- the link will be,
uh, at the end of the talk. Um.
And what Deja Vu does is it lets
you write mp3 files to a
database and it fingerprints
them, um, I believe using a fost
furat. And it then compares
audio coming into the microphone
to what’s in the database. So my
Python script here is comparing
audio coming into the
microphone, uh, to the database.
And if it gets a match for the
Gilmore Girls theme tune, it
sends a serial byte, um, it
sends a byt, sorry, over the
serial port to the connected
Arduino device, which clones the
power off signal for my TV.
[laughter] [applause] So, um, I
have a video of this.
Unfortunately because of
possible copyright issues, I’ve
had to mute it. Um. But after
the talk if you, um, look at my
Twitter feed, I’ll upload it
somewhere, um, with the full
audio so you can see it. Ok. So
this is like the pre-credit
sequence so there’s no music
yet. Um. So what the script’s
going to do, it just listens to
ten seconds and it will conclude
that the-the Gilmore Girls isn’t
playing at the moment.
[laughter] Ok. And then the
theme tune starts. [laughter]
[applause] Ok. And, uh, the last
thing I want to show you is
this. So this is AstroDrone. So
this is using, uh, echolocation
jamming against ultrasonic
altimeters in drones. Um. So
I’ve demonstrated it with a
Parrot, um, just ‘cause I had
one handy. Um. It’s not picking
on Parrots specifically. Other
drones with ultrasonic
altimeters will be vulnerable to
this as well. So the idea with
an ultrasonic sensor is it uses
echolocation. Alright? So you
have a transmitter that sends
out ultrasonic pulses at a
particular frequency, they hit
an obstacle, get reflected back
to the receiver. And based on
the width of the pulse that
comes back, um, the navigation
board can infer how far away it
is from the obstacle. So when
you do this with drones with
ultrasonic altimeters, ‘cause
it’s used on the bottom of the
drone to figure out how close it
is to the ground. Eight times
out of ten it launches it
upwards at quite a frightening
pace. Um. Two times out of ten
it tries to sink through the
floor because you’re making the
drone think it’s either at
maximum or minimum altitude. So,
um, there’s a talk last year at
Def Con by Liu and others
against, uh, about ultrasonic
attacks against autonomous cars,
against TESLRs. Um. So this is a
similar technique albeit, um, a
lot cruder. Um. So first thing I
used was this. So this is an
animal repellent alarm. So, um,
you put this in your garden. Um.
The idea is that you have a
passive infrared sensor. When it
goes high, it sends out an
ultrasonic tone to scare away
dogs and cats, that kind of
stuff. When you fly a drone over
it [drone noises] So you
noticed that the drone became
like completely unresponsive to
commands. It just refused to
land. And in that case, uh, with
a broken drone. [laughter] So,
um, that was kind of the first
part of this. And then I
thought, well, let’s try to
expand that. So rather than
having the drone fly directly
overhead, can we come up with
something that detects, um,
drones in multiple directions
and sends out a more powerful
signal. [laughter] So, um,
that’s a colander, um, ‘cause I-
I ran out of money. Um. And you
have, uh, four, passive infrared
sensors. There’s two Arduino
unos, um, underneath. Uh. And
eighteen ultrasonic transducers
connected to it. So, um,
infrared’s one option and then I
also used acoustic signatures
with the Deja Vu library again.
So I recorded the sound of a
drone flying, um, and then
compared the microphone to it.
Um. And that works just as well.
I just don’t have time to show
it. But, uh. Let me show you
this one. So. [drone noises] Ok.
Um. So. We are not doing further
research on that in the moment
and trying to, um, test it
against different drones,
different, um, kinds of, um,
environmental conditions,
different kinds of echolocation,
that kind of a thing. Um. So.
Um. You could use this as
essentially like as a drone
repellent. If you wanted to, uh,
you could use it as a personal
drone repellent as well.
[laughter] [applause] Ok. So I
think I have about five minutes
left so I’m just going to do a
really quick summary. Um. If I
don’t have time for questions,
um, then I’ll take them in the
hall afterwards. And you can
email me or whatever. So this is
an overview of the research I’ve
done on light and sound. Um. And
you can, um, interpret this in
two ways. You can either look at
it and think, uh, “Yes. He had a
really careful and comprehensive
research plan.” Uh. Or “it’s
something he coupled together
this morning to give his talk
the illusion of structure.” Um.
Either one of those is good with
me. Um. But they all kind of do
fit into each other. So as an
attacker, um, using light and
sound for attacks, um Pros are
they’re great for any, uh,
environment that uses physical
security devices. Particularly
infrared stuff. Uh. Any
environment where there’s
air-gap systems. They’re really
difficult to detect and to
defend against. Um. And they
leave very little trace. And you
can, uh, as you’ve seen, uh, do
this stuff on the cheap, um, a
lot of the time kind of at home.
And test it out. Cons are you
need proximity, um, to the
systems you’re attacking
obviously. Um. Subject to
environmental interference
particularly things like laser,
microphones. Um. And the range
and power of your solutions are
very much going to depend on the
resources that are available to
you. So in terms of mitigation,
um, definitely the first step is
knowing these techniques exist
and knowing they’re out there.
Um. And the inputs and outputs
can be manipulated. Um. So
ideally if it’s possible or
feasible, you looked up block
those inputs/outputs completely.
Um. If you can’t, you’d have
like a reliable failover. Um.
And lastly, yeah,
clone-and-replay attacks and,
you know, jamming, that kind of
thing are as much applicable to
light and sound as they are to,
um, any other kind of
technology. So ideas for future
research, um, exfiltration via
infrared, uh, is something I’ve
wanted to explore. Acoustic
keylogging which has been
empirically proven to work. Um.
But I’ve yet to see like an
automated practical solution for
it. Um. More work on LiFi and
some more work on drone
repellents as well. So
hopefully, in terms of how you
feel about this talk, uh, you’re
more on the left, uh, than on
the right. [laughter] Um. So,
um. Um. So just to wrap up. Um.
The music credits that were used
in this presentation were
Royalty free or creative commons
so thanks very much to those
people for putting that music
out there. Uh. References. Um.
I’ll let you guys go through
that on your own time. Uh. So
yeah. So that’s my email address
and my Sorry. That’s my email
address, my twitter handle. Um.
So please do get in touch if you
have any suggestions, comments,
um, feedback, generally
criticisms, anything like that.
If I’ve got anything wrong
during the talk or presentation,
you can just keep that to
yourself. Um. Um. [laughter]
Yup. So that’s it from me. Thank
you very much. [applause]