>> Uh, we're gonna be talking
about a post-exploitation tool,
but uh we just have an extra
little add on of this o day. So
when uh Jenna Magius and I were
working on the eternal blue, uh
we discovered that uh part of
the pool grooming process was
allocating uh memory uh and in a
contiguous way and by abusing
those memory allocations we were
able to come up with an attack
that we're calling SMBLoris. Its
similar to uh the slow Loris
attack that is for HP servers.
So with that, a single machine
is able to open, uh many
connections. Hold on. Just want
to show the flags here. So the
first uh four bytes of a
connection are this uh net bio
session setup header. And it has
a seventeen bit length field. So
what windows is gonna do is its
gonna see that length field and
its automatically gonna allocate
a buffer uh for whatever length
you say, for whatever length you
say and uh preemptively allocate
that much memory on the non
paged pool. Which is memory that
cannot be uh swapped out. Its
physical RAM that has to be
reserved. So two to the
seventeen gives you a hundred
twenty-eight kibibytes and if
you uh send many connections
that do that uh from a single IP
you can get to eight kibibytes
which is like eight and a half
gig- gigabytes. So we're gonna
demo the attack now. And all
we're doing is opening a lot of
connections and sending uh this
packet with the full length. And
as you're seeing now the uh non
page pool is filling up. Its
actually down here. Right now
we're at five. Five and a half
gigs. And eventually this ping
is gonna die. Because there is
not enough uh RAM and you'll
also notice that the CPU has
spiked to a hundred because now
the operating system is
searching through memory looking
for a free spot. And now we
actually have free uh- the
computer, so like Slow Loris if
we stop this attack, uh the
computer will restore unless you
sustain the attack. Eventually
you will get a hard freeze.
Which is worse than a blue
screen because then you need
physical access to uh restart
that machine. Uh you can't just
RDPN. Um, so. [applause] There
you go. Thank you. Oh and I just
wanna mention that we did report
that to uh Microsoft Security
about sixty days ago. Uh they
said they aren't gonna fix it
right away. So we had to uh go
to full disclosure. We already
told uh our DDoS partners and
stuff like that. So. Ha. And it
works on ipv4 and ipv6. Um so
here's just some of the
artifacts that we have that
happened. Um and then you can
crash programs and then right
here is Microsoft's response.
Uh, this is fine. Haha. Alright
so onto the main topic of the
day. Uh we're gonna talk about
the current open-source malware
options for red teams. So these
are teams uh that you can use on
your pen tests to you know own a
network and then we're gonna
release some new tool uh called
Koadic C3. It's an advanced
JScript VBScript RAT. Uh it's
based on a lot of work by
others. Um subTee, Enigmo, OX3.
Uh Tiraniddo. Um they were doing
a lot of work on research. A lot
of research on JScript uh past
year or two. Uh we're gonna talk
about some of the hell we went
through with Windows Scripting
host quirks. And then at the end
we're gonna have a demo of the
tool. So this uh a list of the
people who helped work on this
tool. Um, I'm zero sum. That's
Aleph Naught. We got Jenna
Magius in the audience and The
Naterz is watching on the live
screen. Um so we're the red team
at RiskSense, it's a spin off of
New Mexico Tech. Uh led by Dr.
Srinivas Mukkamala. He lets us
have time to do some research on
side projects, so we've done uh
extra bacon and eternal blue. We
reported both those exploits to
metasploit uh we're kinda the
first to uh look at those
exploits. Uh just a couple quick
notes before we get started. So
if you use this tool for illegal
activities we're not
responsible. Uh we're releasing
this with pen testers, there's
no like ransomware in it or
anything. Uh like I said,
there's a ton of overlapping
research uh from subTee, Enigmo,
OX3. Uh Tiraniddo. Um but we're
trying to consolidate all those
research techniques into a
single tool. And we've also
advanced the state of art a
little bit. Um so this is just
prototype. There are gonna be
bugs in it. So submit fixes, not
tixes. Ha. And uh just to be
very clear, this is a post
exploitation tools, so this
won't be like metasploit where
you get access to a box. This
assumes you already have access
and you want to do something
better with that shell. You want
to add pivot, uh dump passwords
and stuff like that. So the
current state of Windows post
exploitation, you have you know
Meterpreter, Cobalt Strike,
PowerShell Empire or you can
roll your own. Those are
basically your options right
now. For uh very- and they're
all very nice tools but, we're
gonna talk about some of the the
downsides of those tools and
we're just kind of a very niche
gap. Uh you're not gonna use
this tool a lot. But it will
fill uh uh a very niche gap. Um
so the downside to PE Malware.
This is stuff like Cobalt Strike
and Meterpreter. Um they're both
amazing software. Uh but most of
the time in the post
exploitation scenario you're
gonna be dropping a binary on
disc and that's what AV loves to
eat. And you're gonna, you're
gonna have to evade that payload
with either Veil Evasion or
Shellter or some type of Crypter
Packer. Um so that's one
downside. And one of the main
exploits we have eaten a lot is
uh PS Exec, which is probably
the most common one you use on a
pen test. Um, so the downsides
of PowerShell. Again, Empire is
amazing software. Officially it
requires PowerShell. Obviously.
Which is server 2008 service
pack two, you can install on
earlier versions but officially
that's what Microsoft supports.
And PowerShell Empire also uses
some features that are in modern
dot NET. So I've actually had uh
the case where I compromised a
box and had PowerShell on it,
tried uh doing an Empire Stager
and it failed. Uh with the
error. Another very bad downside
of PowerShell is that it is a
first class citizen in the logs
on Windows. So that's that's one
thing you need to realize when
you're using PowerShell is you
are uh filling up the logs. So
we fill, we made a tools made
out of JScript and VBScript. Um
it works on Windows 2000 service
pack zero, possibly easier. Uh
the main benefit of that is that
the Windows Script Host unlike
PowerShell is baked directly
into the Windows core. Unlike
PowerShell which was like bolted
on later. Uh so it's a little
bit harder to limit. And we
found some creative use of uh
the default EXEs that are in the
system folder. And we also found
some ways to execute completely
by memory so there's no dropping
to disk. And that's the main
benefit of PowerShell. Need some
water. So the down sides are is
that there is no access to
Windows API, uh the only thing
you get is COM objects, which
I'll talk about in a second.
There's also no real threading,
so when you have an agent
running you might want to run
multiple jobs at the same time
and have them report back. Uh
there's no threading in JScript.
It's also missing a lot of uh
standards functions like base
sixty-four, you can use certutil
and some other utilities that
are default installed but
they're not on all versions of
Windows. And then what's really
bad is uh all the strings are
UCS two wide unicode. So when
you insert uh structor shellcode
in memory, it's gonna fill it
with null bytes or even just
totally uh clobber all of your
strings and you're not gonna
have the same shell code that
you put in. That you thought you
had. So COM was kind of this big
idea from Microsoft that you
could write uh a class in one
ob- uh language. And then
instantiate an object in another
language. So what they did was
uh write a lot of COM objects in
C. And then now you can use them
in JScript and other uh
scripting languages. Um so it's
language neutral. Object
oriented. It has a very uh
spelled out binary interface.
And it's distributed so you can
actually instantiate objects on
another server. And then use
them on your local host. Uh uh
which actually leads to a lot of
pivot opportunities. Uh it's an
arguable precursor to dot NET.
It has slightly different goals
than dot NET did and dot NET has
a lot of tools that you help you
to interact with COM. And it's
also found everywhere in
Windows. It's in uh its its own
secur- or its own registry hive.
It's uh HC- or HK- uh current
classes or classes. So this uh
an example of instantiating in a
uh COM object in JScript. So
what we've done here is we've
instantiated this object called
html file. And like I said, we
don't get access to Windows API,
but we get access to all the
interfaces that this uh COM
object exposes. And from that
we're actually able to scape the
clipboard by uh going to the
parent window and getting the
text. So we uh- be- originally
started this project back in
October. Using VBScript.
VBScript and JScript are
basically the same thing at the
end of the day. They just have
slightly different syntax. And
uh couple other things. Uh one
thing that's really bad is that
uh it has VBScript has an insane
error handling thing, where you
have to do on error resume next
at every function scope. And
then for every uh instruction
that you run, you have to check
there's an error condition. So
there's no like uh try catch
logs that you hit in uh JScript.
The other thing that we ran into
was Shlemiel the Painter
problem. So this is a problem
with string indexing. Normally
for string indexing you want oh
one look up so you want to look
at the hundredth element in the
string. That's oh one. Uh with
JScript, it counts from the
beginning of er- with VBScript
it counts from the beginning of
the string. Uh so you actually
get oh of impactorial to
traverse the entire string
instead of oh of N. Uh so Jenna
Magius had a, he solved uh a
parse problem in computer
science when uh we just grouped
the bucket with a so every
thousand iterations. We moved
part of the string pointer up.
Um while working on this tool we
uh researched a good new
Readline. Which is a interactive
shell for um Linux and Unix
systems. So in Metasploit, what
happens is a as shells start to
rain in, your input is getting
overwritten by uh all those
shells raining in. So we were
able to uh redraw everytime a
shell came in and not mess up
your input and that's just the
pictures just an example of uh
kind of the bad input. Uh we
committed it in PR seventy-five
seventy to Metasploit uh they've
actually commented it out. They
have to support Windows and some
other systems. So, it wasn't,
there was a couple bugs there,
but we're only supporting Linux.
So I'll talk about some of the
uh terminology before I talk
about how we architected this.
So Zombie is a hooked target,
it's basically like uh a session
in Meterpreter or an agent in
PowerShell Empire. Uh Stager is
a web server that we used to
have the C2 C3 server and then
Implants uh just starts one or
more jobs on a Zombie. And then
a Job we figured out a way to
fork and so you can have a
simultaneous jobs running. And
then report back to the server.
So this done by a plugin class.
There's two types of major
plugins or uh stagers which
spawn web servers and implants
which starts jobs. Uh they all
have a load method which has uh
variables so these are like
things that you set Meterpreter
kind of. Uh all we do is a
simple string replace for tilde
and the variable name. Uh inside
of JS files and then they also
have a run method. Uh which like
I said starts an HP server or
starts a job. Uh uh the job
class is what you instantiate uh
from implants. And then have a
report handler, so when the job
reports back to you, you're able
to handle that. And then we also
implemented a standard lib dot
js file which uh kind of
abstracts a lot of that COM
stuff for you. Its so you can
run commands. Upload, download
files. And uh perform those HTTP
communications. Uh Uh we have
all the standard implant
categories you would expect. You
can pivot to move from machine
to machine, persistence so you
can uh if a machine reboots, it
will still call home. Manage and
Utils are kind of like, they'll
they'll let you enable RDP or
run commands, download, upload
files. Elevate is a whole class
of UAC bypasses. Lets the run as
administrator box on Windows. Um
Gather will scrape credentials
out of uh from the hives, like
NTM hashes. We actually wrote a
TCP scanner which I'll get into
in a little bit. We have a fun
category like PowerShell Empire
does uh they play AC/DC
Thunderstruck, they blast the
volume and do that. We do that
but we do uh the Cranberries
Zombie song. Um and then we also
have inject, which is a whole
category where we've figured out
how to break free of the COM
chains and uh get to the Windows
API. And from there we do
reflective dll and mimic hats
and stuff. We have a cool demo.
So stager architecture is uh
generally in a post exploitation
stetting you're gonna hook by a
manual command. That's what you
do with PowerShell Empire. Uh
you just run a command and then
it calls home. Um you can hook
from IE if someone, so you can
fish somebody. And if they click
Yes from this you know, huh all
these active X objects, it'll
work. Uh also off this macros,
you can do a Stager that way. Um
so all we're using is a simple
HTPS threaded server and Python
as the uh main C3 server. Uh so
you get enryption through TLS or
SSL. There is a caveat there, uh
couple caveats. So one is uh
older versions won't have TLS
enabled so you'll have to fall
back to SSL. And the other one
is you need a valid certificate,
so you'll have to call home to a
domain that you own a
certificate for. And how we do
the uh the call home is if you
do a long poll. So this is kind
of the old way of doing A checks
before web sockets is you call
home to the sever and then the
server hangs you for like a long
time until there's a job to be
done. And it tells you that job
and you run that job. So there's
a couple problems with that.
Haha. Uh there's no problem with
uh hanging forever 'cause once
you go into the uh COM object
and you run that, you're in COM
world. It's outside of your
script context, but there is uh
a limited amount of it
instructions you can run in
JScript. So it's actually
default five million I believe.
So if you run five million
instructions in JScript, which
is actually very easy to do. Uh
even for just a few
milliseconds, its gonna pop up
an error saying stop running
this script and it's gonna hang
the script until the user clicks
yes or no. So for that reason we
fork on a regular basis. So the
first time you call home to the
sever you're not gonna have a
session ID. Um it's gonna assign
you a session ID. And it's gonna
fork to a special job called
stage. That stage is gonna do
that long-poll process I was
talking about uh until it gets a
job ID. When it gets that job
ID, it's gonna fork uh that
special stage job again so we
don't use too many instructions
and it's gonna fork the job. And
then uh when that job calls
home, it's gonna have both the
session ID and the job ID. So
then it's gonna send the job
payload, which is gonna do some
work, it's gonna report back to
the server about that work and
then it's just gonna strictly
exit. Um so some of the stages
we have. Uh we do have the
traditional way of running
JScript and VBScript uh through
cscript or wscript uh these
require dropping a file on the
disk so um anti-virus can catch
that pretty easily. And you can
always disable the windows
script host. Uh an interesting
stager we have are MS uh- HTA
html applications. So these are
kind of like in a weird IE
security zone. Uh they'll let
you get access to the registry,
filesystem, the command shell.
Um and the payload for that is
really tiny, it's the tiniest
payload we have. All you do is
run HT- er MSHTA and then URL.
And then it's gonna home with
that session ID and get assigned
one and all that. Um so with
these html applications, they're
gonna pop up like a little
browser window. So we
experimented with many
techniques to try to hide this
window. Uh the best that I could
come up with and I really did a
lot of experimentation was I
moved the uh window two thousand
pixels off the screen, resized
it to one pixel and then I blur
it so it doesn't steal focus and
then also there's some uh xml
that we can do to hide it from
the taskbar. Uh I thought this
was really bad until I looked at
some malware samples that were
doing the same thing, so I
didn't feel as bad. Um, so run
dll thirty-two, uh this kind of
abuses the way that run dll
thirty-two uh parses. Uh the dll
it's supposed to run. So in this
example, its loading the MSHTML
dot dll and it's running run
HTML application on it. Uh which
is the same thing that MSHTA
does only this is a little bit
more hidden. Now when that
function gets called, it's gonna
parse the entire command line
and its gonna see it starts with
JavaScript colon, it's gonna
start. Uh executing JavaScript.
Such our MSHTA stager as soon as
we fork uh we go to this one
'cause it has less windows
visibility. Um another one that
uh another stager here that uh
subTee rediscovered is uh called
COM plus scriplets. Uh they
still get written to disk, but
it's uh this program called red
server thirty-two dot exe which
is supposed to assist you in uh
installing uh COM stuff uh you
can actually feed that URL and
it's gonna go fetch that
scriplet and then it's gonna run
some JScript. Um so this is
actually a stage of this
presently on Windows 2000 MSHTA
is not uh, maybe it is in a
service pack, but at the uh
beginning it's not. Um so
there's a couple of ways to run
commands. Uh the most common way
is through WScript dot Shell. It
has two ways to run commands,
either exec or run uh exec gives
you access to standard out and
standard error for all of uh
that processes output. Uh the
only problem is its gonna flash
a little command dot exe window.
So it's not good. Uh we had to
resort to dot run uh which does
not give access to standard out.
Um but we kind of piped to a new
UID in the temp folder. Temp
folder text file and we pipe uh
standard out and standard in to
that file then we read that
fine. So we were able to get the
output. Um another way to uh
start a process is is with wami.
Um win thirty-two process is
part of that and that's the
windows management
instrumentation, kind of for
managing boxes. Um so one of the
main things you wan to do with
post exploitation tool is upload
files and download them. Uh the
binary data is very hard to work
with in JScript. Um so writing,
if you want to write a file to
disk, writing byte by byte uh
you use all of your limited
instructions I was talking
about. Um so what we do what
what one way you can do that is
you can write the response body
screen directly to a an A D O D
B dot stream. Uh the only
problem is as you can see, uh
you get an error that says
safety settings on this computer
prohibit access. Accessing a
data source on another domain.
So this is part of that IE
security zone. Sandboxing I was
talking about. Um. So what we do
is we create a temporary uh A D
O D B object in memory. We write
that string to that object in
memory and then so now its on
our domain or whatever. And then
we're able to write that to
file. So this is just some
boilerplate co- code that just
lets you write directly to file
without using a lot of
instructions. Another problem we
encountered was with downloading
files. So this is when you want
to get a file um its on the
Zombie, you know you see x
arrays, you see something
interesting on the fa- uh
target, you want to download it
to your machine. You're gonna do
that by having it send an http
request sending a not text
string, which is gonna have uh
all that binary data. The only
problem is that Windows is going
to put uh double encode that
date uh so through some reverse
engineering we found out it was
encoding it with Windows twelve
five two encoding first. And
then you UTF eight uh so we saw
that the binary data did not
match up when we got it back. Uh
another thing is if you send a
null byte, it just ends the
response string right there, uh
the request string. Uh so we
added another layer of encoding
where we then code backslashes
and null bytes. So we have three
different decodings we have to
do once it gets back to the
server. Its really slow uh LF
Knot wrote a hard coded lookup
table. So it's about one second
per megabyte now. Down from ten
seconds per megabyte. Um so
these are all of our UAC
bypasses. These work um because
on Windows there's the current
user hive, which a user is able
to write to their current user
hive, no problem. Um and then
windows has these binaries in
the system thirty-two folder
that have a manifest that auto
elevates them, gives them UAC
bypass privileges and then
there's a couple binaries that
are gonna look in that current
user hive that you're allowed to
write to for a command to run. I
don't, I don't know why. But ha.
You're so we're just gonna put
the stager command at those
registry keys start that process
and its gonna call home and
we're gonna be elevated. Um
Microsoft is trying to fix some
of these, they've closed a
couple of them in red stone two
and three. Um but the UACME by
hFireFox uh some future work if
you know these methods get
closed down, there's thirty-five
plus methods we can use. Uh some
are applicable. So uh another
main thing you want to do in the
post-exploitation tool is dump
the NTLM patches off the server.
Uh so there's a reg dot exe. I
believe it was added in some
service pack in windows two
thousand, its at least present
in windows xp and and higher. Uh
but from there, if you're
elevated you can save the same
system security hives and run uh
CoreSecurityImpacket which will
uh decode decrypt those hives
and give you the hashes out of
them. Same thing for domain
controllers uh you can create a
volume shadow copy. Uh and then
the system hive you can get
that. And we get the ntds dot
dit, we can run the same tool uh
with some different arguments
and extract uh AV credentials
out of them. So there's several
different HTTP COM objects um
most of them are just like like
msxml two dot xmlhttp and then
there's the server xmlhttp. So
this dates back to uh the early
days of the internet. Um where
you first start with ajax and so
the ones that are not marked
server are going to have a bad
uh sandboxing policy it's gonna
have that cross origin ajax
policy you see in web browsers.
Where as the server versions are
gonna be what you would have ran
on a classic ASP server to one
of the server to fetch
something. So it's gonna be less
sandbox. Um so same interface,
but a little bit different
behavior. Um using these objects
uh checking out the error
messages they do when we try to
do an http connect- connection
to a uh an IP uh we're able to
tell which ports are open and so
we have two different methods.
Um of telling if a port is open
or not and uh based on the error
codes, so we're able to write a
TCP scanner using these methods.
Um another interesting COM
object is the uh wscript dot
network, this let's you
enumerate the printer
connections and the network
drives the that computer is
connected to. So that's useful
information. And now we're gonna
talk about uh the the pivoting
modules. So PS Exec uh was
originally written by Mark
Russinovich. Um for the sys
internals before he was hired by
Microsoft. Uh now it is in
Microsoft signed binary. And
this lets uh admins run commands
on different uh boxes remotely.
Um there's no reason for us to
have to upload this binary to
the server because Microsoft is
hosting it on a live share on
the internet. So we just use
that live share, um we do get a
dirty bit when we do that, but
the bypass I found was just
running it uh instead of WScript
dot run I ran it through the BMI
or something, I forget. But we
didn't get that dirty bit which
would have popped up a message
of an error. Um so that that
just lets you run commands on
another box and we do have a
working pivot with that. Another
way to uh pivot is with WMI. Uh
so this lets you spawn that WMI
uh win thirty-two process I was
talking about. On another
server. Uh as long as you have
uh cache, er, either your
credentials or uh you get
credentials out of memory. You
can perform a pass the hash uh
with JScript, we found. Um uh a
really bad problem with this is
when you start that new process,
its gonna run a session zero on
the sever, which is GUI-less
process so you won't be able to
elevate. Um but it it it does
let you get on those other boxes
and maybe there's a work around.
Another things that been uh
making the the the waves the
past couple uh weeks are uh DCOM
lateral movement type makes. So
MMC twenty dot application
enigma oh three, oh x oh three
uh found back in January, but it
has a you can spawn this object
on another server and it has an
interface called Execute Shell
Command let's you re-stage. Um
and then just this week we had
Excel dot Application and
Outlook dot Application by Ryan
Hanson four two four F, four two
four f and uh staaldraad. But
both of these have ways that you
can uh load uh commands on
another server. Um so that's
some future work, we don't
actually have plugins for this
yet, but if you know PSExec and
the BMI aren't good enough, the
we can write a plugin for DCOM.
Um so now we're gonna talk about
some of the ways we escaped that
um COM context into windows API.
So uh work they gave us some
office licenses and we did find
a good use for them. We gone, we
didn't actually write any
reports with them, but, um we
did create a GUI list except
object in memory and then from
that GUI list Excel object, we
also wrote some registry keys
that let us uh uh run macros
without a prompt and so we
actually eh and when you run
macros in that its Visual Basic
which is different than VScript.
That lets you get access to uh
the the entire windows API. So
whomever we were able to run
Shellcode or Reflective DLLs. So
that's one of the ways we
escaped. Uh another technique uh
was published a couple months
ago by Tiraniddo this guy from
Google Projects Zero. Um so when
you install dot NET on a server,
it gives you or a workstation
error thing. It gives you a
bunch of COM objects uh for that
dot NET installation and one of
the and a couple of those COM
objects that you write to memory
and then also deserialize a dot
NET object and when you can
deserialize dot NET object, you
get access to the Windows API
because dot NET has access to
Windows API. So uh we can do all
that from JScript. Um and then
the final way that we found in
our research was dynamic wrapper
X. This was a DLL written by
Yuri Popov and releases Freeware
in like the late nineties or the
late two thousands uh it does
have zero to sixty-one of virus
total. Uh people are using this
for legitimate reasons. Um but
basically this lets you install
a COM object on the server,
which gives you access to the
windows API. Um normally
installing a COM object you're
gonna have to write a lot of
registry keys and stuff like
that. Um, but subTee uh
rediscovered a thing called uh
registration-free COM so we
don't actually have to write all
those registry keys. We just
drop a manifest file also on the
disk and that DLL and then we're
able to load that COM object. At
least for our process. So now
that we have access to the
windows API, one of our design
goals was to use the powerkatz
dot DLL. So this is the uh
PowerShell Empire DLL, uh that
lets you get access to Mimikatz.
Uh there was a problem with this
and that was that all the DLL
mapping was performed in
PowerShell, so normally with
reflective DLL you're gonna
write some C code uh that will
load itself. And uh they did it
in PowerShell. Uh so we have
limited instructions, we can't
do all of that DLL mapping. So
what I did is I wrote a DLL
called mimishim and that's just
normal reflective DLL. So all
the uh loading code is in C,
it's part of the DLL and we just
say start a thread there and
it'll load itself. Uh so what
it's gonna do is it's gonna see
if we're an x sixty-four pro- or
an eighty-six process on an x
sixty-four system. Which if
you've ever uh dealed with
Mimikatz that can be an issue.
If that is an issue, we're gonn-
uh, we're just gonna fork uh um
a sys native notepad dot exe.
We're gonna process all of that
uh and inject the powerkatz dot
dll into it. And from there
we're gonna do a couple default
things. We're gonna do, we're
gonna get the debug privilege
which is kind of a God mode
privilege on windows and then
we're gonna elevate our token to
system and then we're gonna run
whatever custom mimikatz command
you want to run. Um which will
let you extract plain text
passwords out of memory. Uh
provided that credential guard
or some other defense aren't
enabled. And with that I'll let
Aleph-Naught uh run the demos.
>> Heard you guys like live
demos. [applause] Alright so
what we're gonna do is we're
gonna show our tool. At least we
have a screen, I heard we had a
screen problem, so we have it.
[inaudible] Ok, uh so the first
thing we're gonna do is uh we're
just gonna load it up and try to
get our stager first right. Uh I
know we were talking about this
in the beginning. So. So we lit
up, uh we were greeted with a
screen like this. Uh we have a
lot of options in here. So as
you can see its very similar
kind a structure to like
Metasploit or other tools of a
similar kind of nature. Uh we
run info and we set our LHOST.
This is uh a local hosting
eternal network for a domain
that we have here uh on a couple
of VNs right now. >> Yeah, the
only reason why he's setting his
LHOST manually is because we
have a weird network setups,
we're not on the main internet.
Uh normally it will try to go to
eight dot eight dot eight and uh
get your IP automa- your local
IP automatically. Spawned a
stager there. >> So and then
after that's run uh the stager
is done. You can close the
window and you see no windows
pop up and nothing seems out of
the ordinary. But we got a
stager coming back right here uh
and we'll see uh if you take a
good look here, it's not an
elevated prompt uh as you can
tell right here. It would come
back with a star if it was. Uh
and so from here we have our
zombie and we can kind of do
what we want. Uh so to
demonstrate the kind of
ridiculousness that we had to go
through, uh we can kind of
upload a file, get a shasum,
download the file and do a
shasum again. So we're gonna use
an implant. And we see
everything has a like a nice
little options file. So we can
also get into a command shell
from here. Um so if we look onto
our hook client right here and
we take a look at the directory.
Um where we should have uploaded
the putty. And we'll see it uh
and it's right here. Nice little
putty. Uh we'll open a local
window right here and we'll do a
shasum of the actual putty file.
See it is shasum right here.
Eight one and ends with five E.
And so now we will download the
file from the victim client, the
one that's hooked. Oops. And so
we go to our file right here.
And we'll see uh that the
integrity has been kept. Right?
So we got a nice upload of data.
Uh and the client doesn't notice
a thing, no windows are coming
up. Nothing at all. It's uh nice
and in the background. So uh
what we're gonna do next is
we're gonna try to elevate the
prompt, right? A little bit of a
UAC bypass and stuff like that,
right. So we're gonna use er uh
elevation. So if everything eh-
if everything goes right, we
should see uh a shell come back
with the little bit elevating
code. Looks like we're coming
back and here we are. And a nice
elevated prompt. Hmm. Ok, here
we are. Alright so uh from here
uh you could kind of um move
around and try to pivot across
the network. I know we were
trying to explain to everybody
that the ridiculousness that we
had to do for kind a TCP
scanning and everything along
that line. So what we could do
is we could try to find another
victim or we could scan them for
like an open port five and then
try to migrate and pivot right?
Er pivot, just pivot. So. So
we're gonna use another implant
for this. Doesn't really matter
what filename you use for this.
This font is ridiculous. We had
to make it large for everybody.
So as we see here a nice little
read out. Um a nice scanning
from one of the hosts to another
host upon a mate. And right now
uh we're gonna try to pivot ok?
So so we're going to use.
Actually uh we should probably
get the hash tags first from the
current machine that we got,
right? We're gonna use the uh
elevated zombie uh with the
elevated crypt tools to kind of
dump the hashes here. And here
we go. Uh we got hashes from the
hash machine. Uh and that's uh
mimikatz. Uh you can kind of run
any command from that uh from
mimikatz. So uh right now we're
going to uh kind of pivot from
the one machine that's
compromised and we're gonna
pivot and we're gonna get a
stager on the next machine uh
within the domain, right? We uh
as you see we got the
credentials from mimikatz and so
we assume we got plain text
password or something along that
lines. And we're gonna move onto
the next machine. So. And here
we go. Uh we pivoted uh
throughout the network and uh we
moved. And we can see a command
shell. Um if you take a look at,
take a look at who am I. We're
here on the machine pivoting
through the network, um nice and
small execute COM objects. So.
[applause] >> Yeah, so you can
see he has two different or
three different shells here. The
first one was his medium
integrity. Next one was one he
elevated and then this has a
different IP because he pivoted
uh to another machine. Just
gonna. Um so we're gonna talk
about some of the mitigations
we're gonna do against this. Um
there are some uh ransomware
samples that we saw that do all
of there uh operations in
JScript including their
cryptography. Um so people are
mainly focused on PowerShell
right now. We kind of want to
point out that uh JScript is
also an attack surface. So
there's a thing called the
anti-malware scanning interface.
I haven't actually played with
it. But it was designed to catch
PowerShell scripts before they
execute. It's also hooked with
anti-virus to get uh JScript and
VB Script uh files before they
execute. Even if they're uh
using the type of bin memory
stagers that we talked about. Um
another thing is device guard,
app locker, CI, it's all kind of
the same umbrella. Uh for a term
a common term called app white
listing. Um in your environments
you only want to run the
programs that you want to run
and this will actually prevent a
lot of extra malware that gets
on your system from running if
you only have a whitelist of
what can run. Um its kind of a
pain to setup right now, it
requires a lot of uh PowerShell
and registry editing uh I've
heard that there are good things
coming there. So just keep an
eye out, probably red stone
four. Uh next year. Um but if
you do get it working, you want
to block the windows script
host, you want to block HTA and
uh compost scriplets. Um you can
also delete uh the MSHTA dot exe
and red server uh some
components rely on that and
windows update will probably
reinstall them um but that's one
thing you can try. Another thing
is you can delete COM objects if
you're not using them. It's hard
to tell what you're actually
using. Uh including the script
parsers themselves, so like the
JScript and VBScript. Those are
all COM objects that are script
parsing. I haven't actually
tried deleting them, I think you
might break your system, but ha.
Uh we do have some uh intent to
add this to Metasploit at least
as target to PSExec uh so right
um it has a it drops a file or
it runs a PowerShell command. We
want to do a MSHTA command back
and then iterate it through all
those methods that we found a
fork to uh windows API. And try
to spawn a meterpreter binary
that way. Uh just iterate yeah,
just iterate all over those
methods. Um some more future uh
work is exploring COM uh seeing
what is exposed through the
interfaces. Uh its a large
attack surface on windows that's
kind of forgotten about or its
kind of a difficult concept to
to grasp. Um Tiraniddo has a
cool tool. I forget what it's
called. Like LOE Viewer or
something uh that lets you get
the interfaces for a lot of
these COM objects and you can
see what you can do with them.
Uh another thing is that with
this tool like I said, there's a
lot of bugs. Uh so we do plan to
clean up the code and uh do a
small plugin revamp. So uh right
now the plugins are kind of
reusing a lot of the same code
and uh we also want to implement
a JavaScript obfuscator so right
now all the payloads are pretty
generic. They're all the same um
but if we obfuscator its gonna
kind of uh add some uh bypasses
for very obvious lookups of
that. Um we've kind of neglected
persistence implants. Why we
didn't talk about them. There
are a few ways to get
persistence. That's when the
machine reboots, it will
restage. Uh WMi subscriptions is
one that we could do. And then
another things is we're using
the basic uh Python server uh
just very generic. Uh so we
actually do have the Slow Loris
attack, I believe it works on
this similar when we drop that
oh day. Uh SMBLoris, the- we
have Slow Loris attack on this.
Um so that's one thing we want
to close down by throttling the
amount of IPs. Some related
talks by Tiraniddo. He did COM
in Sixty Seconds. This is the
best primer on COM you can
watch. Um better than any book I
ever read. Um he does it, it's
not actually sixty seconds, it's
sixty minutes, but he did at
infiltrate uh this year. Another
one is Windows Archaeology which
uh subTee and enigma oh x three
did at BSides Nashville this
year. And then last year subTee
wrote a very basic uh JScript
RAT and presented that at
Derbycon, uh we're trying to
expand that concept and it, uh
you know, as close to empire as
we could. And so yeah this code
is available at Github. Uh zero
sum slash koadic. Uh we're also
doing a workshop today uh it was
a registration only though. But
we have also released that code
as well. Uh just check my
Github. Um more lower level
stuff. C and shell code. But so
cool stuff. So yeah. Yeah that's
zerosum and aleph naught. >>
Thank you guys very much. >>
Thank you. [applause]