>>Hi all, uh I’m Tim, or Vulc@n
more often uh d uring this
weekend of the year, anyway. And
uh, if you are here to see the,
the CFT, CTF [laughter] uh
talk, with uh, the last 20 years of,
of organizers, which incidenta
lly is- is all the years. So uh,
um we have from the beginning
all the way to the ones that are
currently organizing it on, here
on, on the panel. And, um I
believe the current organizers
are, this is the last one.
Right? So, so stepping down this
year. And every, uh few years,
the, the current organizers step
down and there’s um some,
process for passing the baton.
And uh one of the reasons that,
that this talk is on the on the
docket on this year is to um,
answer questions of people who
think they might want to step up
and take the baton and also to
have sort of an archival
reference for when this happens
in the future. Um, so uh again
I’m Tim, uh I’m going to um, do
my best to um, moderate, uh
these folks up here, when we get
to the panel time. But I’m also
going to uh, sort of lay a
foundation of, uh um, sort of
the basics of what uh CTF is.
I’m not going to try and make
too many assertions. Now, uh I
am sort of inherently biased
being one of the organizers for
uh few years. And also being a
participant for a few years. Um
but I’ll make uh every effort to
um, sort of remain neutral up
here and pass the questions off
to our panel of, of experts
here. Now the talk is geared
towards um organizing CTF. So,
I’ll do a little bit of
explaining about what CTF is,
but it’s from a organizer
perspective, right? And some of
us, even do CTFs from time to
time, uh professionally, uh but
in most cases these slides are,
are geared specifically to what,
uh what CTF means in the context
of Def Con. So, uh what is CTF?
Right? So, we’re not going to
cover uh, what is CTF, in depth.
But at, at the basics it’s a
cyber security based, uh capture
the flag contest, right? So,
it’s just like flags when you
play with hills and kids and
stuff. Except the, the flags are
digital, uh also called an
exercise or an event or a game.
Um, typically it’s all geared
towards the industry and some
minimum bar of proficiency or
ideally some bar of excellence
in fields of, of cybersecurity.
So, there’s different models
for, for organizing this. And
we’ll go over a couple then, uh
in a bit. But to sort of stress
different things and as an
organizer you get to decide how
you’re going to stress the, the
different uh sort of areas of
excellence. Um, CTF exercises
are becoming um much more
common. So, these days you can
almost play about every other
weekend. Uh, if you’re okay
playing in these remote
competitions that happen all
over the world. So, there’s uh,
uh circuit so to speak. And um,
there’s also uh, uh multitude of
contests that sort of just tack
on CTF at the end where it’s
very domain specific. Like the,
um social engineering CTF or uh,
um ICS CTF or something like
that. And some of those bear
more resemblance to the game
we’re going to talk about today
than others. Um but uh, in some
cases this really just means
contest, in other cases there
really are flags that uh can be
captured. So, going all the way
back to the basics for capturing
the flag we need to talk about
like what the flag is, right?
What’s the thing that needs to
be captured? But from an
organizer's perspective that
actually has uh, uh there’s,
there’s a lot to sort of suss
out there. Um, is it just random
text? Well if you just use
random text, then from a
participant perspective it’s
difficult to understand whether,
uh you’ve actually found the
flag or whether it’s just uh,
random text right? That’s uh,
encrypted or compressed or
something like that. It’s
somewhat difficult to know when
you’re done and when you’ve
found the flag. Um, from the, uh
uh, also from an organizer
perspective it might result in a
lot of guessing. Because the
participants end up with this
sort of um denial of service
sort of situation where people
are just guessing repeatedly
hoping that they’ve found the
flag but they’re not really
sure. Um, so then the, the next
thing you do is you try and add
some structure. Ya know, it’s a
certain size, it’s a certain
format, it has a particular
prefix. Um, all of these things
sort of limit that space of
brute forcing right so now you
can increase the likelihood of
guessing correctly for people
who do want to guess. Um, you
also open the door to all kinds
of, of difference defenses.
Like, consider writing a, a IDS
signature for uh, for the prefix
that you know is going to be
there because the flag has a
specification. Uh, so there’s
these, uh trade-offs that happen
when you, even define something
as basic as, what is a flag. Um,
so, uh even beyond defining sort
of the specification for what a
flag is, there’s uh, um, uh, a
lot of other mechanics that
happen around the flag. So,
flags are stolen and you sort of
have to prove that you’ve,
you’ve actually stolen it right?
So you have to go back and
assert to the organizers that
you’ve successfully stolen it
and over the years that has
really matured uh over time from
um, uh verbal or writing on
paper, to email, to uh now you
sort of have rich-ish web APIs.
Right? Solid services where
there’s structure and, and
protocols around how to, uh sort
of automatically or in automated
fashion submit flags to uh web
APIs or scoreboard servers. Um,
and then there’s all of these
sort of game decisions that have
to be made. Some of them made by
the participants where, flags
might be shared. Um, uh you have
collusion between teams for pot-
uh potential collusion. Um, do
flags have a preset, predefined
constant value or do, does it
change over the time? Maybe
being diluted as more people
have stolen flags from easier
services. Um, do flags expire?
If you steal one at the
beginning of a 48-hour period is
it worth the same amount at the
end of the 48 period. Is it
worth anything? Um all of these
things sort of go into the
mechanics of how that particular
game is going to operate. And uh
adjust the game strategies that
the participants are going to
adopt. So then what is Def Con
CTF specifically? Well there’s
no shortage of quotes. These are
just the top hits from when you
do a Google search but um, the
assertion that I think most of
the people up on this panel
would say is that Def Con is one
of the, the highest regarded
CTFs out there. Right? And uh,
it’s kind of grown over the
years from being one of the, the
oldest and uh sort of one of the
only to be the, the, the world
series or the best of the best.
Right? Um so typically the
phrase Def Con CTF, if you hear
somebody saying it they’re
referring to the on-premise
version of the game which starts
tomorrow morning, right? At 9am
and goes til Sunday, goes
throughout the weekend. Um, in
the beginning there were the
Goons. Or more specifically
there was Myles. Ok. And um, so
Def Con uh CTF was one of the
oldest and longest running. Uh
there are some others that have
been around for uh, for a while.
Like the UCSB’s ICTF comes to
mind. Um, but even ICTF is, is
fairly restricted until just
this year was sort of academic
only. Right? And they opened up
for you guys, right? So as a, as
a pre qualifier they, they
opened it up so it’s not
academic affiliated. But, but
Def Cons got a long history of
being very approachable and very
open and um, it’s one of the
longest running CTFs. It’s also
one of the oldest contests
that’s still running uh at Def
Con. Um, so back at Def Con 4,
uh was the first one. It was
just called capture the flag or
network capture the flag I think
a little bit later. And um,
certainly grown uh, over time.
So while this Dec Con 25, it’s
CTF uh 22. Uh, uh oh. There we
go. Um so if you look at uh, uh
quick a timeline, again in the
beginning there were Goons. Um,
sort of later on, uh teams more
formally organized and sort of
had a multi-year approach to
organizing. We may switch to
different computer yet. Around
the year 2000 it was clear that
organizing needed to be a team
sport. Let’s go back one and
see, less, less epilepsy.
[laughter] Um, now, now CTF, now
with less, less epilepsy. Um,
sort of around uh 2000 it was
clear that organizing needed to
be a team sport, right. Uh there
were other hacking competitions,
um HOPE for example had
something. But there was nothing
that really had, uh sort of the
network component, the defensive
component. Yeah, you got one
more, see if this will last, ya
know. Alright so in the way of a
road map, which might stay there
for a few seconds, nope. Um,
let’s go back and forth here.
Uh, quick, look at it, uh so in
the way of a road map there’s
sort of different milestones
that happened over the years. Uh
in the beginning. >>Hey Tim, can
I interrupt you for a second?
>>I’m sorry >>Just me, just me,
Uh I just wanted to say, he’s
had 2 problems here that are
totally classic what happens
every year when you come with
new technology. And that happens
every year with organizing these
contests. We don’t’ know
necessarily who’s going to be in
the audience. What words to use
to say to talk to make things
work right and we definitely
don’t know what cables to bring.
[laughter] >>Um but they do
provide testing harnesses in the
speaker room with do work fine.
It’s fixed. You had to go kick
the cable apparently. It’s
unfixed [laughter] [off mic
discussion]. There’s so much in
between here and there [off mic
discussion]. Yeah, we’ll just,
we’ll just skip over it. The uh,
there’s sort of different
milestones that happen
throughout the years right.
There’s, there’s the realization
that teams are going to be
competing, right even though it
wasn’t necessarily organized as,
as a team competition. There’s
the realization that teams are
required for organizing. Right.
It’s too much for 1 individual
or a couple of individuals to
handle. Um, fast forward to
there’s so many people that want
to play that there needs to be
some sort of qualifying round in
order to gate the people that
can actually make it to what’s
now known as the finals of the
Def Con CTF that’s on premise.
And then, uh the sort of
different things that happen
sort of along the way. Like the
inclusion of the game outside
the game, the the meta game and
the moving to IVP6 and badges
that have uh game code on the
badges. Uh, and then last year
was actually the first year and
perhaps the only year that the,
the architecture and the format
of the game were announced like
long ahead of time so you could
actually spend time
developing tools as a team and
come in with tools that you knew were going to
work. Right. >> We actually, we
actually announced last year
that we were having uh, a custom
architecture. It’s like a 9-bit
middle ending thing,
monstrosity. >>Middle ending is
not actually a thing by the way.
[laughter] >> No, No. [laughter]
>>Oh, it totally is now. It is
now. >>Yeah it is now. >> Um, so
yeah, now we actually have a
completely custom architecture
that the teams just got this
morning, they just got the
manuals this morning. >>So, so
preparation before 9am is
perhaps of limited futility,
right? Um, so getting back to,
to what is capture the flag if
we kind of grossly break them
down into 2 categories. This is
again been covered in other,
other presentations so we won’t
spend too much time on it but
the 2 broad categories are, are
attack defend and uh game board
or Jeopardy style. And the big
thing in attack defend is that
the participants are directly
connected to each other. So
defense actually becomes a big
component of the game. Uh also
service level availability or
SOA uh becomes part of the game,
the, the part that need to be
vulnerable and able to be
attacked have to be there and
running. Uh so everybody is
typically level-set. Uh think of
a VM that has custom software
and is distributed to all the
teams. There’s different ways to
do that but that’s a good
analogy and ultimately it's
composed of a set of challenges
and that’s another thing that’s
matured over time. The concept
of challenges or services and
these are sets of custom
software that uh typically run
with some amount of concurrency.
Um there’s debate on how many
challenges, uh concurrently make
a good CTF or not. So, uh
conversely the Jeopardy style is
much like the show, right you’ve
seen the show. It’s a grid of
questions, um participants are
not connected to each other so
defense is typically um not part
of these games and you solve a
series of challenges where the
order might be determined, there
might be say control by the
leader by the organizer, and the
categories might be completely
arbitrary or they might be
designed with uh certain ya know
learning objectives or goals,
such as gating for, for CTF,
demonstrating proficiency in, in
subjects that, that would uh
work well when you get here for
the weekend. There’s also
hybrids and things that don’t
quite fit but broadly these are
the 2. Uh, so Jeopardy style
world-wide or just
proportionally with the number
of CTFs that happen is by far
the most common. Um it's uh
possibly more diverse within a
single event because defining
what a question is, uh is very
broad. Uh whereas you can find
what a software service is in an
attack defend game is perhaps
relatively uh confining. Um,
it’s arguably easier to, to
organize for several reasons.
So, so today Def Con, when you
say Def Con CTF it means a thing
hear, uh there’s typically a
Jeopardy style one that gates
everybody as a qualifying round.
Um so this was introduced in uh
2004, Caezar, you did
qualifying, right? >> Uh, turns
out yeah, we were just debating
that, discussing that. >>No,
Caezar was like we didn’t do
quals. I was like, I remember
playing in your quals so I’m
pretty sure you did. >>Yeah so
the last, so on the, on the
chart it should show but you
can’t see it because it causes
epilepsy. Um, but I think the
last year that data hackers-
>>Yeah that was all DD back in
the day. Like that was
literally >>Although Myles
brought us a long, DD
implemented so much stuff it,
you really would have to
understand the guy that, how
amazing he could pump out a user
mobile and X router system with
double back. >>Right
>>Firewalling and stuff, like in
a night, in a night, in an
evening. >>They, they also had
some pretty crazy constraints in
their quals too like, I remember
specifically playing and, and
not being able to actually make
any kind of connection into that
box or out of that box, other
than the literally just terminal
IM. And so we had to write like
GU encoder and decoder routines
into like telnet so that we
could move binaries to the box.
>>There, there first qual was
just a race to finish 8, 8
levels of the challenge, that
was it, 8 questions. >>Yeah it
was totally linear. Yep, yeah
exactly. >>So, we’re having a
sad realization up here that
anything with pictures appears
to anger the projection system.
Uh which is unfortunate because
there’s a lot of pictures in
most of this, so. [laughter] Um,
so you’ve seen the board. This
is what the board looked like
when DDTEK [inaudible] had quals
in 2006 anyway. And uh there’s a
starter question, there’s a hand
that kind of points off
somewhere, gotta download a file
or go to some web service. And
uh, maybe I should try and
switch computers here. Uh but
unlike Jeopardy uh the leader
controls the next question but
unlike Jeopardy, uh other uh
teams can sort of catch up and
answer the, uh the previous
questions. I might just try and
switch briefly here. >>We could
probably fill the space. >>Yeah
go for it. >>We’re gonna talk
about stuff while he works.
That’s usually how organizing
CTF is. >>I was going to say
yeah it’s pretty, it’s pretty
AD-HOC to begin with. Basically
something, something goes awry
every time. This, this is on-
this is its own sort of like
micro example of how CTF
actually works in real life.
Because it turns out nothing
goes to plan. It’s the old like,
you know planning is useful or
plans are useful of some sort of
thing. >>And pulling out that
Tim was a part of DDTEK. And
DDTEK CTF’s were famously
broken. [laughter] >>Oh yeah.
There was one year I think you
completely erase the scores from
one day. And we were, we were
upset with this. >>Yeah. >>Yeah,
and I actually, uh, playing CTF
uh most of my CTF experience was
under DDTEK. My 2 black badges
was from when in their first and
final year. Um but a funny story
we actually were, playing quals
or organizing quals, uh I once
wrote a, a mock web server with
a CGI script underneath it. And,
uh there’s, the bug was in the
CGI script but all the, the web
script kitties were like, yay a
web challenge. [laughter]. And
then uh, so they started
uploading like PHP shells and
python shells and one team in
particular, uploaded a python
shell connect back with a
hard-coded IP address and port.
So like, kind of, let me play
with this. So, I killed it since
it wasn’t actually part of the
game. Or necessarily part of the
game and they did it again.
Alright, this is what’s going to
happen. Killed it, just
immediately started kicking back
to them and then uh, finally it
kicked back and they started
typing commands. And me trying
to L S uh slash. And then like,
you know, cat something, uh let
me type some other stuff.
Eventually realized they were
talking to somebody buy uh,
[laughter] but uh yeah
[inaudible] so much fun >>Yeah
it took an amazing amount of
self-control to not mess with
everybody else’s exploits
essentially like, people would
land stuff on boxes and like
watching it happen you could
like connect to it faster than
they could. And so like not
going in and grabbing everybody
else’s shells when you’re the
organizer just for fun was
actually like a massive, massive
self-control. >>The reason I did
though was because it wasn’t
necessary to, to land the
challenge. >>Right >>So, that
was actually the year, so I
don’t know if you guys know
Geohab he popped the servers by
figuring out that, dot bashRC
was writable by general users.
So, he wrote cat, uh flag in
the- slash temp slash something.
So he just waited until somebody
else exploited it cause they
were just going to run bash
because it wouldn’t run bash so,
whatever and so he just waited
and just saw a that file pop up
in temp and got the flag. It’s
the way to do it. >>We actually,
we actually had a whole, we had
a whole um, we had a whole like
sub like focus area that we,
that we called the dirty tricks
department. >>Yeah. >>Which was
basically like trying to figure
out all the, all the herent
conditions in everybody else’s
exploitation methodologies. So,
like I remember one year there
was a team that was doing really
really well but they were always
like, their payload would
actually cat the flag in a file
in temp and so we could just
like walk around behind them and
mop up all the flags that they
were getting too. >>Nice >>One
thing that I found, though is
uh, nevermind are you ready?
>>I’m ready >>Alright >>Want to
finish your thought? >>No, no go
ahead. >>Alright, too much of a
thought. >>Yeah, you’re in the
middle of your thing, go ahead.
>>Um, I will say that I walked
into the, the speaker room
earlier today with my uh, laptop
that’s running Linux and plugged
it in and everything worked and
then I didn’t tell anybody I was
like, oh linux and it finally
works, it understands how to do
it. >>It’s the year of Linux on
the desktop. >>So I went in
there later and I tried it again
[laughter] and it worked again
and I got up here. I’m like, oh
no, and now I have a mac plugged
into the projector and it’s
working fine. Um, so I guess
it’s still not. >>Go back and
show your timeline, I thought
that was uh, that was a good,
you should flip back to your
timeline. >>Yeah agreed. >>Oh
yeah. >>Nobody got to see that.
>>Yeah, I’m a few slides down
now. Um, great so now we have
timelines with no epilepsy. Um,
so uh I- I, kind of went over a
few of the um the parts and this
is by no means exhaustive it's
just sort of like the things
that stood out in, in, in my
memory and sort of uh worked
well for the slide desk right.
Um, but uh, it definitely has a
lot of the, the pieces that
matured over time with the, the
qualifier introduced in 2004 and
then the tradition that
continues now with returning
the, the return in champion. So
uh, so Kenshoto would be
inviting the returning champion
back for the first time in 2005
and there, there’s sort of these
uh, I don’t know, um dirty,
dirty tricks or, or twists or
things that sort of make it hard
to um, uh come in prepared
right. So, like one of the
things, this year makes it hard
to come in prepared is that it's
en- entirely custom architecture
that wasn’t announces until 9am
this morning right so that’s
like a way that preparation is,
is difficult. Um, some other
examples we’ve got going back in
2006- to submit keys over DTMF.
>>We, we were just talking too.
I remember, I remember basically
everybody, so we had, we had
deployed like a, an actual like
I think it was an asterisk
>>Asterisks >>Yeah, and so
basically all the tokens, all
the keys were just ya know,
really big entirely numeric
digits and so we were making
everyone like, they would pick
up a phone and it was like press
1 to submit a key, press 2 to
talk to a member of Kenshoto.
And so all the teams had to like
run out into Vegas trying to
like buy modems and like had to
like write their own DTMF like
scripts to submit tokens.
Because otherwise the first few
tokens that were being submitted
by people, they were first of
all, they were like 32 digit
numbers, like they were big. And
everybody’s like [beep beep
beep] [laughter] [beep beep]
s**t I f****d it up [beep beep
beep] [laughter] >>Specifically
Hangout >>Yeah exactly. And then
yeah, and you couldn’t submit
more than one token per call so
you had to actually, hang up the
phone and do it again.
[laughter] >>We, we had so many
tokens we exceeded the available
bandwidth to submit our tokens
we couldn’t submit them fast
enough. >>Yeah so everybody ran
out, everybody ran out to Fry’s
to try and buy, to try and find
modems and like. >>Which also
has ranging ramific- >>And
people are like how, how do I
connect something over serial to
my like modern laptop. >>Which
also has like interesting
ramifications because then next
year like teams would buy all
the modems like just to >>Yeah
and we didn’t use modems next
year. [laughter] >>Good, they
have good return policies.
[laughter} >>They do. >>Uh, but
there’s, there’s other things
that sort of, uh go through the
times. Uh, multiple hosts, uh
IPv6, a lot of people were um,
sad face when it was all IPv6
and they had a lot of IPv4 tools
and shell code and so forth. Um
so, cust-, so MSP430
architecture on the badges, sort
of midway through, uh legitbs
and, and, and again this year
with the custom architecture.
So, sort of the, some of the, um
milestones by no means
exhaustive, um but um as you
already said, the one that I
want to focus on now is the, the
qualifying round. Because that
gets into the, they style of
game that’s game board style.
>>Actually, before you jump off
that slide can I, can I like
mention one other thing? >>Yeah
>>I think there’s an interesting
pattern that’s shown uh as a
result of this slide. Which is
the like burnout cycle of
hosting CTF. If you notice,
almost all of those are the
same-ish like maybe off by 1
year here or there or whatever.
Because the, just herculean
level of effort that goes into
creating CTF in general
literally causes like internal
drama and burns out teams over
time. >>It’s, it’s a second job.
>>It’s, it’s literally, so like
our as an example during, during
Kenshoto CTF we had full time
jobs and actual really life
stuff to do besides you know CTF
and then had an 8-month
development cycle every year
for, for CTF. And by the end of
it we were just like nope, not
doing this again. >>How many
hours a week did you work? >>Oh
my God it was literally,
literally a second full time job
for almost the entire team.
>>Wow, we had DD so we went
[laughter] 4 hours a week. >>I
know, right? >>And he worked.
>>And you guys were like, DD go
do a bunch of stuff. [laughter]
>>What’d you do this week? >>So
um. >>What’s our contest like?
>>Uh Lightening who wrote the uh
architecture for this started in
2015. >>Yeah >>So >>Um, to be
fair it took Intel a lot longer.
[laughter] Um, so if you kind of
uh, uh fast forward, the the
previous slide showed a Kenshoto
board form ’06. Here’s another
one from ’08. I think maybe even
the same code or the same style
was used in 2007, it looks very
similar anyway. Um, but you can
see that the, the board is, is
sort of uh, um staying the same,
static, as Kenshoto evolved. Um
you, you do get to the fine,
sort of the areas of excellence
in the categories, um there,
there’s uh, uh an aspect of the
organizer side of how
approachable do you want the,
the, the open qualifier. Anybody
can sign up right. So how
approachable do you want it to
be for novice players? But
typically, that’s solved with
uh, sort of a trivia category
and uh, and also the, the lower
point value ones, uh where
they’re, they’re very
approachable to uh.
>>Approachable enough that, that
for all the years we hosted it
the trivia 100 had the same
answer. [laughter]. It was, well
it was >>Hack the planet!
>>There ya go! [laughter] It was
literally hack the blank. >>So
uh >>Blank the planet. >>The
last  >>Hack blank planet >>And,
and our last version was blank
blank blank blank [laughter]
>>Yeah. Yeah. They submitted a
version blank blank blank and
people just submitted hack the
planet. >>We actually have a, we
have a baby’s first category
now. >>Yep >>So it’s all like
baby’s first heap exploit.
>>Yep, yep. >>So through the
years, there’s uh, the next uh
set or organizers. DDTEK, um
obviously different uh look and
feel but, but very similar.
>>Really? >>Very [laughter] >>Uh
similar semantics. It’s still
Jeopardy, it’s still categories.
Um, you’re still choosing the
area of excellence so to speak.
So it, its, when you go around
the other clocks um, it’s it’s
sort of all the same things
right. Crypto, cross site
scripting, buffer overflow, heap
overflows, right. The, the, the
boxes open into to any of the
security related fields. Um, and
then the, the current organizer
right, um have a, a slightly
more Japanese game show right.
This is one of their, their
earlier ones from uh 2013. Um,
but the concept of qualifying
the teams through this gate has,
has persisted since it started.
And it really uh filters down to
the, the handful of teams that
are gonna be present here >>Do
you guys know >>Uh at Def Con
>>Do you guys know anybody,
anybody who’s been an organizer
and stuff, do you guys know like
off-hand the total number of
like, I actually clicked, I am
beginning to play. >>Yeah
>>Quals? Cause those numbers
>>If you guys will >>Are
impressive >>Stop interrupting
we’ll get them. >>Oh, okay. >>Um
I, I should have said at the
beginning that, that I made
these slides and they haven’t
actually see them, so there
might some >>True story
>>Disagreement and, but I’m, I’m
trying to be, uh to be honest
and, and faithful, I’ve uh, I’ve
kept everybody in the dark.
[laughter] So the basic
organization of the game is the
game, um has remained the same
and um. You know other CTFs
around the world sort of take a
similar approach so they modify
like how you get through the
board and so forth. So, one
thing you might’ve noticed, the
uh, the astute observer, through
the boards that we’ve looked at
some of the same teams keep
showing up. Like everybody up
here and anybody out there
that’s a team know that. But you
see the, the sort of regulars
the familiar faces that come
back. And um, teams have really
started persisting over time.
Uh, um back even when uh the
Ghetto Hackers, were, were
playing and then, and then uh
organizing. And uh these are
teams that, that sort of prepare
and, and practice and test tools
and, and things year round. So
it’s, >>Except for us >>It’s on
a cycle >>Not the ghetto.
>>What’s that? >>The ghetto did
not. [laughter] Sort of I mean a
few hours a week we, we, we
drank a lot. >>You had DD. >>I
said that teams existed Um, so
they develop and maintain tools
and teach processes and so forth
and you can sort of track them.
These, these are just points in
time so it doesn’t say anything
about their, their final placing
in quals. But you see these same
teams kind of over and over both
in quals and also in finals. Um,
so so much that, that it’s
actually tracked somewhat
formally now. So, this is uh, a
website called CTF Time. There’s
other ones but this one is sort
of emerged as the, the
predominant one and it’s, it’s
sort of mostly opt-in. So, it’s
you, you might not be as tracked
as you want to be, but um when
the results are posted publicly
the teams are known and, and
based on, ya know pattern
matching on the IDs they’re sort
of matched together. But um
individuals can sort of
affiliate with the team and, and
opt in. But uh, um but these are
tracked over time right so these
teams persisted since uh, um for
some it’s again a second job
kind of situation. Uh there,
there’s formulas, there’s
there’s APIs you could use to
extract the information and
verify that you’re, your
rankings are correct. Um, even
so, still subjective right.
Somebody’s still saying, oh that
CTF was harder than this one by
some metric right. And the, the
formulas still had to be plugged
in. Um there’s still interesting
opportunities for cooperation
and and collusion and what
happens when you switch teams
and all that sort of thing. Um,
so how many will participate?
Right. >>Woohoo! >>So we’ll go
back to the uh the, the
timeline. And uh, you can see
the, in the in the bar graph, I
don’t know if you can read the
numbers very well but the, the
largest bar is 414 and the
smallest bar is 162. I didn’t
have numbers from the, the early
Kenshoto days. Uh, I don’t know
how that worked. >>Yeah I don’t
think we do either. [laughter]
>>Uh hey I couldn’t, I didn’t
have them and then I couldn’t
find them so. But you can, you
can see there’s a, a bit of a
trend line right in the teams.
And um, it’s important to know,
which I think Visi was getting
at, is how many teams are
actually participating. Which is
vastly different than how many
teams registered. Right. So, I
think last year there were 1500
teams that registered I think
Vito said. So, 1500 teams
registered 276 actually
submitted something, right.
Which isn’t a perfect metric,
might, there might be some
people that tried to play and
just couldn’t figure out hack
the planet, right. And they
didn’t submit anything. >>Right
>>It’s possible so it’s not a
perfect metric. Um but these,
this is a, a good approximation
of how many teams are playing
right. Not how many people,
teams can have many people. Uh
they probably have at least 8 in
most cases but. >>Or like 50 if
you’re School of Root >>Uh
[laughter]. We don’t
discriminate. >>There’s no rules
in CTF >>Equal opportunity. Um
so you can see a trending up um
there’s, there’s sort of other
caveats in that uh registering
shadow teams might have some
advantage depending on how uh
the game is structured and how
flights have values so having
extra teams on your team might
be useful. Um and, and so forth
we can even in some cases dilute
flag values strategically. So
then, the, the other flip side
of how many will participate.
That’s how many play in open
qualifiers. But how many are
actually going to play when you
get, uh to Las Vegas right.
There’s logistics in setting up
the right amount of tables and
how many prizes and uh what kind
of uh orchestration you need to
run. So, um, when the ghetto
hacker started there were 8.
Right? And there was always 8.
And where did 8 come from? >>Um
I think we had, no it was
probably Myles. >>That’s how
many teams we could fit tables
in the room. >>Okay. Fire code
essentially. >>It was fire code
and like lines of network and so
we built some really nice PVC
structures to run the networking
cables, that’s where 8 came
from. >>Yep that, my >>Did you
guys >>My working theory was 8
port switch, or 8 port hub at
the time. [laughter] >>There was
never, th- you guys never had, I
think we were, I think we ended
up being the first ones to like
im- implement like a team table
limit. I don’t think you guys
had that right? Because we, we
also saw the instances of teams
8 or 10 or however many teams
were in the ballroom at the
time, we would see 1 table with
like 3 dudes and another table
with like literally people like
crowded around with laptops and
stuff. >>Yeah, yeah there were
all starting fire code
considerations there too. >>Like
MUXT >>So anyway you can see
that one of the things that
DDTEK wanted to do as organizers
is expand the competition
acrossed uh several dimensions
and one of them was size. So,
uh, it kinda ramped up a little
bit. Uh the first one should
probably have an asterisk in
that, there weren’t actually, 10
uh viable teams. There was one
sort of deceptive team, so
really, only 9 teams in the
first year. And then uh the, the
last year that DDTEK ran it
there were 20 and that was, they
were, we were sort of gently
pushed because it was Def Con 20
to have 20 teams. Um, and then
LegitBS maintained for a little
while has then settled on, on 15
in the most recent years. Um, so
how many teams will support is,
is another question that you’d
have to ask as uh, as an
organizer. Alright, so this
competition once you get to
Vegas and these 10 teams or 15
teams uh get here. Um, how are
you going to implement this
attack defend game, right?
So fundamentally uh you’re
gonna be concerned about
scoring. They’re, uh 4, uh I don’t know,
here there’s 4 basic components
but there’s going to be basic
building blocks right. There’s
offense, there’s defense, uh if
you have defense you probably
need some amount of SOA. And
then there’s this concept of
like other points. With like
bonus points granted to the
breakthroughs, or, or other
stuff. So offense is going to be
stealing flags or corrupting
flags right you can, you can
defeat and take one or you can
burn one or whatever. And these
have to be combined in some way
to come up with a score that you
can then use to declare a
champion, right. So, score might
be offense times defense times
SLA. That has pros and cons,
right. If, if any of those is
zero your total score is zero so
you could drive to zero real
quick. So, if you have no
offense do you get no points? If
you have no defense do you get
no points? Maybe that’s the kind
of game you wanna run. I don’t
know. Uh maybe you do, uh, uh
more of a summation, right? If
you add them all together now a
zero score in any one of them
doesn’t drag you to zero but it
also doesn’t have that big of an
effect so you can have um
slightly more complex formulas
where SLA maybe is the
multiplier. Meaning you have to
allow your opponents to play uh
in order to score any points,
right? If you have zero SLA it
means nobody can attack you,
nobody else can sort of play the
game. So, you don’t, you want to
encourage the game to be played.
Um, uh and then uh, these need
to work over time, right, we
have the concept of rounds,
you’re gonna to play all weekend
so now this has to added up over
these uh fixed, or variable
length, 5 minute, 15 minute
rounds, uh whatever. So now your
round score is the summation of
these. Uh, um uh the round score
is the formula and the game
score is the summation. And then
you might have multiple services
right, these concurrent
services, these, these 10
vulnerable things that are
running and your host that needs
to be added in there. So maybe
you end up with the formula,
that looks like this down at the
bottom. This is by no means the
right formula or even one that
will even work well but you kind
of get the idea. There there’s
some uh mechanics that go into
devising the formula that you
need to um have the score.
There’s value in, in having this
well-defined ahead of time. Many
other methods. Um, once you even
have these formulas figured out,
you need to measure it all.
Right? So you have uh, SLA, uh
so this might be a port scanner
but now they’re much more robust
pulling, right. And uh, that’s
very uh service specific,
testing different code paths.
Um, if a flag is corrupted for
offense the organizers need to
tell somehow. Um, there’s,
there’s a lot of sort of game
uh, uh strategies around uh sort
of permanently overriding other
people’s flags and things like
that. Um, some moderate CTF’s
employ custom kernels and, and
hypervisors and traps and all of
these things in order to detect
that a override has happened.
Similar protections for reads.
And defense is sort of the
absence of offense right? You
must be doing good because
nobody is successfully attacking
you. So, none of this is set in
stone, every year there’s a new
opportunity to revise and come
in with, with new scoring
methods. Um, there are more
questions here that, that uh um
will need to be answered, right.
Will there be bonus points? Uh
will the scores always increase?
How important is offense? So
forth. >>Some of the important
parts about what you’re saying,
um like uh, some of the formulas
he was just talking about, if I
turn off my computers and start
hacking, then the games over
right? It’s not fun. Uh it it’s
really difficult to convince
security people to do blue team
when they’re here for a red team
contest. Uh that, that figuring
out how to game things has been
the evolution of the game.
Really >>Absolutely >>Making it
fun >>Absolutely. That’s the
whole dirty tricks department. I
mean we had, we had dudes
basically going and like, so
when we were playing our dirty
tricks department was doing
stuff like, we had a guy that uh
did physical pen testing for a
living like his, he was the guy
that talked his way into data
centers and did all that kind of
thing. And so, he had like a
high and tight, he was you know
ex-military whatever. So he’d
like roll around in like camo
and like you know camo pants and
like a, you know Def Con like,
Def Con regulation black shirt
or whatever. And he would
actually, like never ever talk
to us. We would send someone
away from the table to like make
drops and like meet with him.
Who, he was rolling around doing
things like brushing a CD off
like, brushing burnt CDs off
someone else’s table and he had
like duct tape rolled in a loop
on the bottom of his shoe and he
would walk with a limp so that
he wouldn’t like stick it down. But
like camo guy walking with a
limp, like no big deal so he
would literally go by tables
brush CD-ROMS off, stick them to
the bottom of his shoes and walk
away with them. [laughter]
>>Yeah. Yeah. There’s, there’s
many colors to that.
>>Definitely >>Um, so these
services that are running
concurrently, you need to
define, you need to define how
much you’re going to define
them. Right. Is there a spec for
this? Like, how, what kind of a
box are they gonna fit in? The
more of a specification you have
for a service, the easier it is
to uh, to automate the test and
the deploy, and the redeploy,
and to rebuild and also to
outsource it turns out. Because
if you have a spec you can get,
tell somebody to write against
the spec if this’, if it’s an
open box you might come back
with something that’s really
hard to, to organize around. Um,
but lots of decisions about how
many you’re going to run, what’s
their point value and so forth.
Um, need to decide how teams are
going to interact with the
infrastructure, so they’re
connected, together, there’s
some way that they’re
interacting with each other. Um
but they’re also going to have
to, to interact with all the,
the, the pie- the, the bits and
pieces that you’ve assembled.
Um, so will they operate their
own defended host? Is it a VM?
Um will they route through the
table, right. Do they have an
uplink that’s on a table? Do
they get a tap? Is the tap
delayed? So forth. There’s lots
of uh, um decisions that have to
be made about how the, the game
is going to be represented and
how it’s going be interfaced
with. Um, one thing that I
think, I think everybody another
thing that’s continued over time
is having a, a, an immense um
desire to protect the integrity
of the game. Right. And there’s
lots of ways that you can, you
can take that to heart and, and
for, um for >>Specifically it
needs to be just hackable
enough. [laughable] >>Right,
right it’s apparently, I mean
it’s already a hostile network,
right it’s already hostile
people. Uh it’s designed to be
vulnerable right. Uh but you
wanna have a fair game, you want
to make sure that when you’re
crowning the champion you’re
sure that that’s the champion.
That it’s the right person,
you’re confident in your scoring
you’re confident in your
infrastructure. Um so there’s
there’s lots of different
pieces. This is another slide
that’s by no means exhaustive,
um but you wanna take, uh I
think that at least up until now
[audio cuts] taken to protect
the integrity of the game. Um
and the non-technical side,
there’s, there’s even things
about table positioning, right.
Is it unfair to put one table
sort of like with their backs to
the doors, when you’re opening
the room? Uh is it unfair to
give 1, 1 team a particular ID
that might result in nulls in
their shell code? Because of
their network subnet and things
like that, right. So, you really
want to ha- um strive to be
fair. >>Who did that exactly?
[laughter] >>When we, when we
designed the uh, uh that custom
badge he mentioned uh
unfortunately we, so we gave
index numbers to people who
placed in our qualifier. And PVP
got first so we gave them the
zero index. Uh, unfortunately
their index was not exploitable
on the RF network. >>So that’s
one, one instance. Like
everyone’s got their instance.
>>Oh for sure. >>Um, so plan for
failure, right. Like in this
case, bring a Mac that can also
do your presentation. Um but uh,
and this is the kind of thing
where I’m sure we can just go
down the table and everybody can
talk about the different
failures but uh one of the
failures that happened in, in
this picture, I’m pretty sure
this is the right picture was
uh, a sort of essential scoring
database had a hard disc just
totally tank, right, right in
the middle of the competition,
right. So, you have to have, uh,
uh ideally some resiliency um
some like fail over, some backup
plans right. Like uh the, sort
of the game must go on
mentality, right. Um, so what
will the rules be? So, I think
uh, typically historically the
rule is no physical attacks
right? And this is really, to
keep people from physically
being hurt. This is actually
there and I think there’s good
reasons >>Well and also >>To
have that there >>Don’t cut our
cables because we had to do
that, like that would cost us
money so don’t’ cut our stuff.
>>Yeah, so there’s, there’s
other things right, there’s,
there’s >>Those were not the
rules when we played. >>It sort
of expands into things
[laughter} like, don’t mess with
the infrastructure right, don’t
destroy personal property right,
don’t toss >>Messing, messing
with the infrastructure used to
be like part of the game. >>That
was the game >>Along time ago,
that was the game. >>That was
the game. >>Along time ago, we
hacked >>Well this is like >>We
hacked part of the scoring
system and basically like I
remember, I think it was DD that
came up to the table and he’s
like, that’s really cool, knock
it the f**k off. [laughter] Like
>>Did you get, did you receive
bonus points for your efforts?
>>Yeah, yeah definitely I mean
that was always the thing is you
kind of reward people for doing
something novel and new. I
remember uh, I remember the year
that um we had uh, again sort of
the de facto rule, don’t cut
cables. Right? Cause, obviously
you could walk around with a
razor blade on your shoe and
like cut cables all day long and
so one of the things that we had
said was you know basically
denial of service isn’t actually
that cool, right? So, like do
something cool. And if you’re
trying to do something cool and
you mess it up, like okay we’ll
have a little bit of forgiveness
and it will be alright. So, I
remember um I think it was
School of Roots captain John
Boss comes up to me, comes up to
me and he’s like so Visi we were
trying something really neat, I
was standing, kind of the tables
were like this and actually this
was a lessons learned but we had
uh, the sort of ring of tables
for the uh, for the people
running, you know for Kenshoto
in the middle. And the tables
had skirts sort of on both sides
you know like the hotel does.
And so, we’re standing there
next to the table, you remember
this story now. [laughter].
Right, so we’re standing there
and this was actually the DTMF
year. So, we’re standing there
and he’s like so, what if a
friend of mine theoretically was
trying to do something really
cool but kind of messed it up
and now maybe a team needs a new
cable? And I’m like, what’d you
do? So he’s like well you see,
and he lifts up the skirt of the
table and there’s a dude
underneath our table like right
next to me and he’s like, well
we haven’t been able to get him
out for like 2 hours because we
managed to get him under there
to try and, so they had gone and
bought a 900 megahertz phone and
were trying to wire it into one
of the other teams pots line to
literally broadcast whatever
tokens they were submitting over
like 900 megahertz analog. So,
they apparently messed up
splicing it in ya know and like,
like happens but then they also
couldn’t actually find a window
to get the guy out from under
our table covertly and so he had
been under there for like 2
hours. [laughter] And so like,
John, John Voss lifts up the
skirt. He’s like, so we’ve got
this dude under your table and
I’m like. That’s about it right?
Something like that. Oh, there
he is, yeah man. So, like, so,
basically, we were like, yeah
that’s, that’s actually really
cool like, and well played you
know, I’m getting people under
our table. So, we just ran a new
line and didn’t uh, didn’t cause
a problem but basically that
whole dirty tricks thing, like
messing with the infrastructure,
definitely was part of our, our
game. >>On, on totally unrelated
fact, when infrastructure moved
to dedicated rooms I may or may
not have been in balconies, the
rooms locked at some point.
>>But the balconies didn’t?
Yeah. [laughter] Yeah, uh who
was it that climbed across from
one of the balconies to the
other to get into the Kenshoto
skybox one year? I- >>Uh, I
don’t know >> I think that was
School of Root 2 >>Yeah, I don’t
remember. Um we’re talking about
cultural influence, actually
right before the talk there were
some, some bits of culture
slides so again this sort of an
incomplete slide but um,
culture is, is, is interesting
in that um there’s a lot of um,
of barriers right especially as
this becomes an increasingly
international right
there’s teams from, from all
around the planet that played,
not only in quals but also in
finals these days. And there’s,
there’s clearly the language
barrier, there’s clearly the
popular cultures. Like uh, uh,
um the hacker movies from the
80’s like some of them weren’t
as internationally popular as
others so like, those questions
don’t resonate as much. Time
zones and holidays right. Like
there’s, there’s, there’s
different things to try and keep
in mind. Um, they tend to show
up during uh, trivia and
question starters and things on,
on the right-hand side. Just
generally when interfacing with
the teams and when designing uh
services that have ASKI
protocols, right. The words
sometimes have meanings to, to
different cultures. Um, there’s
also the cu- culture that’s
influenced by CTF, where the
community uh sort of leaves it’s
mark uh in various ways. So
generals and producers and
actors and, and so forth uh
actually come through and visit
the CTF room and, and want to
have sort of their own
individual uh briefing and their
own sort of explanation and you
have no idea of the ramification
of those conversations are going
to be and how that sort of
spirals out right? Uh so here’s
uh, uh a team mentioned, uh
School of Root mentioned in a,
the HBO show. Um, another sort
of thing to broach by the
organizers is um how are you
going to engage everybody right?
Not only the participants but
also the, the folks that are
walking around and the average
human attendee. So should there
be ambiance, should there be a
distractions, should there be
attraction, like should there be
music at all? How loud should
the music be, should there be
videos, should there be
scoreboards, visual effects.
>>Really, really, loud.
[laughter] >>Uh there’s probably
contention here about that. Um,
but, but otherwise if you don’t
consider these things it just
ends up being a bunch of people
in a fairly dark room staring at
computers, right? And uh the
teams don’t really have any
physical interaction with each
other. The attendees don’t
really know what they’re looking
at, so handouts and so forth.
So, this gives way to
visualization. So, uh back in
uh, I- I- think this is about
2002, I don’t really know. I
think this is a ghetto created
scoreboard. >>Yeah, I think it
is. >>Um, but we had uh
scoreboards right, projected up
to the, the wall. Um, here’s
>>One of the, one of the
problems with showing scores is
uh, it can be really easy to get
away with a win in the first
day. And you c- you might have
teams start to lose interest.
This is part of you know, do
scores always go up? This was
part of uh, this is a zero-sum
game and you can see the teams
in the bottom have a little bit
of a red bar and the bigger
green bars are the, the top, top
games. Eh, eh at some point
you’re trying to keep people
interested even if in reality
you think there’s no point, they
can’t win anymore. >>I don’t
know if it was us who started it
but so the first day we showed
scores uh live scores, the
second day we only show relative
positions and finally the third
day we just played back the
previous >>I think there were,
there were sort of a refinement
process on that. We had
something where like, I think
for the last 4 hours we didn’t
show the scoreboard, something
like that too, yeah. >>Yeah,
yeah, I think everybody has
their own variation on that
theme, I think you’re, I think
you’re a little bit more extreme
than has been in the past. Um,
there’s some uh, some boards
kind of through time. Uh, here’s
uh, a Kenshoto board with the,
the ordering and uh the team
relative placement on a line
chart over, over time. Um, a
little bit later still a very
similar scoreboard. Uh, even
later in the Kenshoto time you
still have a similar scoreboard
but it’s also rotating with ones
that have um, uh I guess
innovative in some sense. Like
showing different types of
information. So, the one down in
the corner is, is kind of
showing what’s left on the
table. These are the points that
are, are still sort of up for
grabs. The services that need
some more attention. Um, if you
open your data you get
visualizations from others, so
here’s some quals data that was
taken by some uh, some uh sort
of non-organizer folks and
graphed over time and it’s sort
of easy in, and different types
of visualizations to see um, how
the scores progress. So here you
can see relatively quickly a lot
of teams spike up and one sort
of is, is in the lead for a long
time but then there’s still a
relatively dramatic come from
behind a few hours before the
competition, where the red line
cuts up. So, this uh it’s, it’s
quals so it’s a little bit
different but this is an example
of that come behind scoring that
you like to embody in the game.
Uh, if you want to encourage the
availability for a come behind.
>>Teams, there were also teams
that were like fairly heavy into
like using their lead
psychologically >>Oh yeah >>To
win the game, like team [audio
cuts] [laughter] that spent the
last 2 hours of, of CTF one year
uh, very, very publicly and very
sort of flagrantly having all
their people just play guitar
hero. Mostly just as like uh,
you know you don’t even need to
try anymore because we’ve got
this. >>Whenever we say a
certain team we mean Chris Eagle
and School of Root >>Yeah pretty
much >>Every time >>Just so it’s
clear >>A certain team is always
them. >>So there’s a new, uh new
organizer took over, right, the,
the scoreboard is uh, still um,
relatively basic, it’s
displaying the same sort of
information. This is sort of one
of the things that the game ends
up being more important for the
organizers so the visualizations
end up being sort of back
burnered and back burnered and
then like cobbled together at
the end, right? And, and that
code doesn’t persist uh,
generally from organizer to
organizer. So, um you see this,
this trend where like the new
organizer that takes over, takes
over and then it’s like sort of
back to square one and it kind
of builds back up, so uh, DDTEKs
early boards looked like that.
Um, then you know later on they
had much more, um, appealing
graphics, uh that uh displayed
some of the same information but
also like that’s a place holder
screen on the side. And then in
the end you, you sort of see
the, um the the more appeal
ing side. And some attempts at uh, trying
to display types of information
that are kind of hard to
consume. Like the bubble chart
where it shows team uh versus
team action. This one is
particular in the numbe- number
of writes per service. So, that
big blue circle is showing that
like one team is like massively
over writing on one particular
other team instead of evenly
distributing their attacks
across. Um, and then you know
like gadgets and stuff like
that. And then another new team
came, comes, takes over still
relatively basic. They’ve taken
a different approach where it’s
sort of a graph based um thing
where the, the edges display
types of information but it’s
still sort of basic blocks, not
particularly appealing that
advances over time, sort of
similar information but much
more appealing. >>Oh I’m saying
that, that the, the blocks going
across were live. That was our
first iteration. I just saw the
next one, it’s got much better
>>Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah, that’s,
that’s sort of the point. Right.
It sort of evolves over time.
And uh, and, and as an organizer
you have an opportunity to
decide how you’re going to try
and convey information and what
information you’re going to
convey right. Because you want
to engage the audience but uh,
in some respect it actually also
inform all the teams that are
sitting there present, right?
So, in some way this acts as a,
a, an intrusion detection
system. You can tell somebody’s
attacking you and, right so
that’s why you have the staged
thing where it’s like live and
then it’s like delayed and then
it’s like gone. Or however you
phase it out. But these are
considerations that you have to
have as a, as a organizer. Um so
then there’s the, I’m just gonna
rip through these pretty quick
so we can get the questions.
There’s the expansion into
physical space, we talked about
this a little bit already
alright with the, uh going into
the custom badges that are
actually codable. Uh the, the
meta game. Lock picking is super
common in lots of CTFs, like as
a physical aspect to get to your
passwords, your keys to start
the game or whatever. Um,
another physical uh thing that
was tried is a service that was
in the game actually controlled
physical things outside the
game. Um, so like uh, this is
the robotic chicken fight. Um
that was a, a service in 2011.
And uh, that was, it, it was
sor- sort of an ancillary to
slide, one of the teams actually
went out and got like game
controllers and, and pro- like,
had an adapter interface to the
service where they could
actually automatically activate
the service and then control it
with their PlayStation 4
controller or something. Um,
interesting thing, right? Um, so
tradition, uh so future
organizers, I, I think there’s a
lot of aspects of tradition. If
you’ve been a player or close to
the organizers you get some of
that, trying to like document
some of that here. Um but
there’s, there’s certainly a
desire to keep Def Con CTF the
best in the world. There’s
certainly a desire to keep it
fair, fun and innovative. Um
there’s, there’s always desire
to engage the audience. You
never know what the next
generation of players is going
to be or where they’re going to
come from. You really, really
want to have that open to
everybody. Um there’s logistics,
there’s game banners and team
banners. The winner typically
gets to bring the game banner
home as part of their spoils.
Um, there’s swag, there’s
t-shirts and stickers and so
forth. Typically, announcements
are happening on, on April 1st.
Right that’s just the, the
thing, you know when quals is
going to happen. Um, fortune
cookies started. I think, I
think uh Kenshoto started that
because they had a balcony and
there was a desire to throw
something off the balcony. So,
there was the, the Sunday
tossing of the cookies. >>That’s
why we >>Oh yeah, the >>We get
coins >>Fortune cookies
>>They’re much bigger and they
hurt worse. >>We had, we had the
an- like the annual Sunday
tossing of the cookies. >>Right
>>Yeah. >>And so just some of
those are here back in Def Con
15, some of these are DDTEK
ones. DDTEK incorporated some of
the challenges into some of the,
um, uh fortunes. So, there’s
stickers, right. Kind of a
hacker thing, there’s laptop
stickers and everybody’s got
their stickers. There’s coins as
uh, [inaudible] mentioned. Uh,
now, sort of one of the longest
lasting traditions. But there’s
one for, for every year going
back a few years. And then
there’s sort of >>Holy s**t
really? >>Other things,
[laughter] right. >>An actual
CTF tattoo. >>Uh, stress sheep
and so forth. Teams bring stuff,
you can’t stop them. They bring
stuff, they do stuff, um,
particularly like the sheep
>>This slide should have been
titled, will there be sheep?
>>Um, there was uh, they
modified the stress sheep to
have the LED eyes. Um, so teams
have to prepare, uh for a couple
people who already brought up
that, uh this is sort of a
second job. It’s a multi-month,
it might be an all-year round
thing, like when do you start
planning for next year? It’s a
soon as this year's over kind of
thing. Uh so there’s a lot of
preparation, there’s a setting
of the servers the
configurations, building all the
services, building the
infrastructure if you don’t
already have it. Um and then if
you do, like the meta games
stuff, you have to set up all
the meta game stuff, you have to
program the badges, you have to,
we did uh, um DDTEK interfaced
with all the human badges. So, I
think if you have a human badge
from DEFCON 18, you actually
have CTF code in the firmware.
So, that’s like a whole other
layer of, of uh of working with
other parts of DEFCON. >>Did you
guys end up having the thing
where like every year where you
swore off doing it again? Like
every year, we were like we are
never doing this again. And then
like a couple months later
you’re like, well maybe. >>Well
we have some like >>If
we do this year next year it
will be so much cooler.
>>There’s a couple, like even
now I think, eh maybe you could
do it next year. And no, it’s
written down, we’re done.
>>Yeah, it was like the year we
stopped, the year that we
stopped hosting was literally
the year that nobody stood up
and was like, yeah, we’re doing
this. Like everybody was just
like, eh. >>Yeah, we we
definitely got drunk at quals
and like, yeah, let’s, let’s do
this, we’ve got this. >>Yep
>>Next morning, no, no, no.
>>Not, no >>Just forget what we
said. [laughter] >>So we’re
talking about how much effort
there is like year-round. When
you get there on site, there’s
an amazing amount of things that
have to happen behind the
scenes, and I say proportionally
most of what you’re going to be
looking at as an organizer is
something like this. You’ll see
like the empty rooms with no
participants in it, you’ll be
watching some of your, your
buddies terminate network cables
across the room as you’re trying
to make sure all of your
services work. >>That’s
happening right now. >>And um,
and this, this is the view that
you get. Or you get a view in
the back room, your, your
infrastructure servers or
something like that. Right. Uh,
what the >>Also I think, I think
since you’re, since you’re on
the topic of preparation, it’s
also pretty important
to point out organizers of CTF, the
entirety of the infrastructure
and the code and the logistics
um has always been completely
something provided by the people
actually running CTF. Like our
actual, Kenshiro's logistics
bill every year out of pocket
for us was like 20 grand. >>Yeah
>>Like that’s why I say don’t
cut our cables, like seriously.
>>Cause >>They’re our >>Because
they’re our cables [laughter]
>>I don’t know >>So if we’re
talking >>How much it costs just
to ship all the stuff out here.
We had >>Yeah, yeah shipping
costs, shipping costs alone. The
pelican cases and all crazy
nonsense. >>If we’re talking
proportionally, partially what
the team [audio cuts] something
like this. Cause again, like
the, the table are meant for
fire code or due to prizes
there’s only 8 black badges. Um,
uh the teams are much larger
than that or some teams are. And
you see, uh you know extra hotel
rooms with wiring all over it
and you see the, um you’ll be
staring at IDA screens and
debugger screens and have your
persistent servers that have
UPSs strapped to the bottom of
them so you can wheel back and
forth as the game goes live.
[laughter] So, so why do people
play? Right? This is like, these
last couple slides sort of like,
make you wonder like, why? Like,
right? Um so why do people play?
Uh well there’s challenge, uh
the, there’s some prizes
especially around the world,
some of the CTFs are getting
dollar prizes, right? It’s not
quite like eGames. But um like
you, you can’t make a living at
it but you can make some money.
Uh what if you just couldn’t get
into talks at Def Con?
[laughter] Right? So, you’re
stuck there, right? >>I know
right? It’s ridiculous. >> I’m
convinced there’s some people,
have logical disorder >>Glory,
glory is the reason you play.
>>Glory, yeah. >>So the really
reason right? >>And that’s why
it started, capture the flag,
was to have a chance to go head
to head. >>And you get the flag
badge >>Glory >>It’s a black
badge and a jacket. That’s why
you play. >>Yep >>Yep >>Yep,
oldest, oldest [audio cuts]
like, around. >>So why, so why
do organizers organize? Right?
So this is actually the
question. >>Masechism >>yeah
this is the question, this is
the first question I wanna, to,
to hand off to the panel. Before
we do that, just very quickly
um, you, you roughly know who's
up here but uh, to, um to
introduce them sort of
officially. Uh, Visi, uh wave
your hand. Yeah. So Visi’s
sitting >>I crowd sourced my bio
because I’m s**t at writing
bios. So, this is all the
Twitter responses to what should
my bio be. >>Yep, so he crowd
sourced the bio, he was the
organizer, uh sort of uh, uh
main or chief organizer for
Kenshoto. Uh, Chris Eagle, yeah
down there on the end. Uh so he
was uh, uh um a player and then
a organizer and then a player
again. Uh lots of CTF experience
from, from both sides. Um,
literally wrote the book on uh
[laughter] on IDA Pro. >>Oh
nice, dude hook a brother up >>I
know, right? >>I got you. Don’t
you worry. >>Riley >>We’re,
we’re rebooting. Sorry. >>Caezar
>>One second our monitors are
not working. They’re giving
epilepsy out. >>So Caezar is
talking >>Momentary technical
difficulties >>Right now. So
he’s, he’s part of the Ghetto
Hackers who, who won 3 times and
then became the first formalized
organizer and really brought it,
brought it to the next level.
Also known for uh, for uh, C, uh
Caezar's challenge um, sort of
an annual thing at. >>21 years I
have thrown a party on Saturday
night because uh, behind a
masochist and doing CTF wasn’t
enough. [laughter] Uhm find me
at any time and I will hand you
a puzzle and if you can solve
it, which is not very hard this
year, uh if you can so, solve it
then I buy you drinks on
Saturday. >>Uh, Hashen. Um, uh,
uh also, excuse me, 2-time
champion. Uh unlike the other
champions, what 2 different
teams, right? >>2 different
teams >>2 different teams
>>First ones Meta Gods slash
Team Awesome the second one's
Samurai TA >>Yeah, there you go.
>>Um, and um one of the current
organizers, uh 2013 so we’re not
really sure when they are gonna
stop. >>This year, definitely.
>>Yeah we’re not sure when
they’re gonna stop. [laughter]
Uh, and uh and Myles. Right. Um,
Myles is, is uh responsible.
He’s like the reason that we’re
all here, right. Cause this
wouldn’t have happened if he
wouldn’t have started it so. Um,
>>I know that our presentations
not gonna do it but uh, I’m
gonna- it’s time for everybody
to give this guy a big round of
applause. >>Specifically
>>Capture the Flag >>Yeah.
[applause] >>It’s Myles’ fault
[applause] >>Hacking, hacking is
basically a modern watchable
sport. I mean there are Twitch
feeds now for this kind of
thing, right? And mostly it’s
all because of the, the bucket
that you started kicking. >>And
uh, and with that I’d like to um
kick it back off and I think the
first question will be, so why
do organizers, organizers
organize and let’s go uh, in
order, right? In chronological
order. And uh then this room
didn’t get set up uh well, we
don’t have mics so if you have
a question, uh you have to come
up here and you can either take
the mic or, or I can repeat it.
And also I’ll put up uh, um I’ll
try this thing where you can put
up a URL and you can like send
questions to the podium. We’ll
see how that works. >>I would
not trust a single person in
this room for that. >>Yeah
>>Alright, goes through Google
stuff. >>So Myles. >>So Myles,
yeah >>Why CTF? >> Why, why
organize? >>Because there wasn’t
a way to figure out who was best
and not practice out on the live
internet where the con would get
shut down. [laughter] Now you,
we forget that >>Who was, so
you’re saying it’s harm
reduction? [laughter] >>For the
public >>Totally, and you forget
that like at first, I- I- went
behind him because I was
seriously worried if my
employer's heard about Capture
the Flag I might be fired. And I
worked as a security guy. And
this last year I was in the
Smithsonian as a Black Badge
there, I mean this is really
different. So yeah, it was harm
reduction, it was head to head,
it was a chance also if you had
controlled the environment that
you could start throwing in some
stuff that explains it to the
general, about why would someone
stand in front of a screen for
so long. Well because it’s
really cool and there’s these
things, it’s a puzzle that
they’re solving. So, it’s clear
to me that we needed something
with a big more showmanship, and
also chance where attackers and
defenders could go head to head.
And that it didn’t break the
rest of the network and throw
out the con. >>Yeah, uh, for,
for us we came and um, we felt
like we knew enough about
security to not necessarily need
to see every single talk so we’d
catch [laughter] a couple of
talks and enjoy it and then we’d
kind of wander over and see
Myles’ game and say, ya know,
gee, so I just set down at a
table. Every person at that
table today is a dear friend of
mine today and like we go out
together all the time, we live
near each other we’ve all move
to, to live near each other. So,
my social life is Myles’ fault.
Uh the Ghetto Hackers was formed
because we didn’t have any
paper, cause we didn’t bring
pens or paper or notebooks or,
or hardly anything. Uh so we had
a napkin and uh mascara and uh
we wrote IP addresses that were
available on the network. That
was our, our group of friends
came out of us sitting around
each other. And, for us uh after
the first year, the first year
we just sort of tried and saw
how it was and, and then after
that there was kind of this fire
of, well you know, if we just
stored every exploit we know.
And that w-, that was the
contest back then, was like how
many exploits can you bring in a
searchable useable format. And
uh, and i- j-, i- b-, it just
became this, this passion to
actually just get better. So,
for, for us we didn’t
necessarily try to win as much
as we tried to be c-, get good.
Like get good scrub. That, we
were scrubs and, and we came and
you kind of made a crucible and
a bunch of hackers popped out.
>>And then why did you run it?
>>Why did we run it? Uh, we ran
the contest uh, after the third
year, uh somebody in one of the
teams said that they hated us
and we were cheating bastards
and that they didn’t wanna play.
>>Hackers, hello. >>We, we, we
took it as a great honor, and
pride? And but, but there was
something uh, a, spark in, in,
in, in our, among us that, um
made us jump up and volunteer to
take the game to a new level.
And so uh we got up on stage and
talked about coming back the
next year and making a new
contest. And Myles was part of
that contest as well. Uh and,
and that was how we kind of came
to the uh, scoreboard and, and,
and sort of all the th- some of
the the trappings that are the
beginnings of what these guys
who won the contests that we
threw and we handed the reigns
to them. >>That’s actually kind
of been a tradition. I know it
was kind of touched on earlier
but there is also a, you end up
feeling this sort of sense of,
of belonging and ownership to
the game. Um, when you’re al-
when you win it also. Um, and
you have your own designed on
how you want it to be or how you
think it should be so, like
transitioning to the reason that
like Kenshoto uh decided to run
CTF for a few years. I think
there’s, I mean there’s a number
of facets but for us watching,
watching the Ghetto Hackers and
watching the coalescents that it
caused in the hacker community
specifically. And the and the
crucible effect actually is
super huge, like I, we would
watch people literally have a
reason, have drive to learn all
these new exploit mechanisms,
and, and all of these like
details about- part and
whatever. So, for us actually I
think that the biggest thing
that, that caused us to actually
run CTF was uh, we were
concerned initially uh that it
would be taken over instead of
by someone that is about the
hacker community, that it would
be taken over by a university or
a corporation or whatever like
that and we were very concerned
about that initially. [laughter]
Turns out, ya know, off we go,
modern times and all that. But
um, but the other reason um, the
other reason that Kenshoto
stayed in the game, the reason
that, not, not the first year
but the reason for the years
after that um, was that we
really felt that it was sort of
an unmeasured uh like an
unmeasured resource, right? So
as an example, um in our game we
were sort of one of the first
people to be like, don’t bring
any of those exploits because
they’re not going to work
because it’s going to all be
entirely custom software with
challenges that you have to
reverse engineer and exploit and
land payloads against like, in
that weekend. And for us that
was um, it was really important
for us because we felt that,
that was a, that was something
where people hadn’t stretched
far enough yet. The, the bar
wasn’t high enough and we felt
like um we felt like we wanted
to continue to be able to push
that higher and higher. So, that
eventually not everyone was
making it. So as an example
actually there’s also, what,
what do they call it? I think
they rename amateur CTF but it’s
called something else now.
>>Open CTF >>There’s several now
>>Open CTF, right >>Yeah open,
project too >>So, but like that
>>Subtle >>As an example
>>Subtle humble brag there >>Oh,
yeah right but so, that is
essentially formed out of the
fact that we pushed, we tried to
push the game into actually
measuring the real redline of
what people were capable of in a
weekend. And that, that really
drove us for the years after the
first year that we hosted. The
first year was cause we were
super concerned that it was
gonna become this like corporate
sponsorship kind of thing. Um
and after that it was because we
thought that the, the, the
performance that we’d seen uh,
warranted further measurement.
Higher and higher so. >>And that
is a perfect transition to him
to Mr. >>Right >>Cause we, we
had a lot of the same reasons.
So, we played in Myles’ game, we
played in Caezar’s game, we
played in Visi’s game, and uh we
loved every iteration um I teach
and it turned out that the game
as it evolved was it, was a
great microcosm of the security
space. Uh in which to uh conduct
uh teaching an- and learning. Uh
my students got really excited
about it so w- w- we loved the
game as it was, loved uh, the,
the game uh the last year we
played. Uh with Kenshoto and
when they stepped down we were
also very worried that ya know,
some company would come in and
commercialize this thing. Uh,
and it, we looked around and
would say, well who's gonna to
run it. We could, we couldn’t
imagine who might run it.
>>That’s exactly >>I think there
was one other that might’ve run
it, we didn’t know what they
would pitch. Uh so we made our
pitch. I think another team made
their pitch um, and uh we
basica- [off-mic comment]
[laughter] >>But you lost. And
>>Our, our [laughter] out, our
pitch, our pitch was a lit- was
basically if you don’t’ give it
to us it’s gonna suck.
[laughter] >>Ours was if you
give it to them it will suck.
[laughter] Um, uh and we really
like the game and wanted to see
it continue as much the same
vein, of course it didn’t’ occur
to us that we wouldn’t get to
play for 4 years. Um, and then
>>Playing is way more fun then
run- >>Why we kept running it
was more or less, well, we
screwed that one up, maybe it’ll
be better next year. Um, I think
we might have got it, we got it
close to right the >>Your last
year >>Fourth time >>Was good
>>Yeah we got it close to right
the four- it actually started on
time. >>It did? You didn’t
delete all of our scores.
>>Yeah, so um >>Chr, Chr, Chris.
Before, before you, before you
stop Chris, uh, how did it
change your team’s experience,
your school’s experience to go
from playing, to running it, to
playing. What d- do you play
differently because you ra-,
because you ran it. >>No, uh,
playing to running is a really
tough thing so uh, to e- it’s an
entirely different mindset to
become an organizer. Right, so
yeah, if you’re, if it you’re
doing ya know different type
stuff and then now you’ve got to
turn around and write it. You’ve
got to write with an entirely
different mindset. Uh writing a
challenge is no easy task. I-
it’s easy to put one bug i- in
the challenge of a very specific
nature. It’s a little more
difficult not to put other bugs
in that you >>it’s really
>>Didn’t mean to >>Yeah, it’s
really hard to write secure
insecure code. [laughter] >>Yeah
>>Just, just exploitable enough
>>Yeah [laughter] and uh >>And,
and >>So >>How many of you have
found exploits in code you’re
adapting? Cause I know I was
finding exploits out there, it’s
like wow that’s been vulnerable
since the 90’s. >>We actually
>>I’m the first one >>Had 2
challenges that, that literally
just incorporated a library that
we knew had an o’day in it.
>>Yeah and we wrote challenges
like that too. You take things
from real world and you try to
bake it into this challenge, uh,
w- we didn’t want to drop
mountains of software, like ok
here’s a patch you find the
o’day. Uh [laughter] which was
easier, ya know, 10 years ago,
but uh, eh so yeah everything
was pretty stripped down and
you, you try to build the bug
you want people to hit and you
try not to have other bugs. Um
so, so from running to
organizing th- that mindset was
hard for some people to, to uh,
uh a- adapt to. So, we did lose
a lot of people actually from
the, from the playing side.
They, I- that’s what they want
to do. They want to keep on
playing. I don’t blame them. Um,
but yeah, we were a much smaller
group when we uh, during the
time we spent running it. >>That
tells into another question.
This things actually working so
we’re getting questions that are
coming in. Uh so, uh you wanna
answer HJ >>Oh sure >>And then
I’ll follow >>I think I think uh
>>Into the next question >>Short
and sweet anything he can do, I
can do better. [laughter] >>We
played um TEK’s game >>Uh and
you got 2 black badges out of
it, uh sorry. >>We played their
game, got 2 black badges and saw
what they did. And knew how we
were a**holes and how to beat
ourselves. And decided we could
make an interesting game.
>>Masochism >>What was that? >>I
was just gonna say it all boils
down to masochism. >>Yeah, yeah,
like you know what, yeah we, we
made people upset about how we
beat their defenses. Anyway, um
so yeah same, actually same
reason. Like we played their
game and thought we could do
better or do things differently
and take an it an interest,
interesting direction for the
community. So, >>And, and
they’ve done an amazing job and
I will say that one thing as an
organizer, the only thing I’ll
add is the only fun you can have
in organizers is trying to f**k
with the players. >>Totally
true, absolutely 100 percent
true. >>So whether it’s a
challenge you designed or some
new twist, the badge challenge,
the >>I really support >>Get a
kick out of >>Or challenges, or
challenges that were actually
purposely not actually
exploitable. There was a bug but
it, like couldn’t be landed.
>>No w- we, that’s why, our are
always exploitable. [laughter]
You thought there was a bug and
now you want to say you were
f**king the players. >>What’s
that? >>Yours are always
exploitable are zero. >>Oh that
was an accident. >>For one team,
yeah >>For one team, yeah that
was th- it was exploitable. >>So
the follow-on question which uh
perhaps I’ll ask uh Chris first
since you already started
answering it. Um, how big are
the organizing teams? And you
can sort of take that with, with
the transition from player to
organizer and everybody else can
answer it. >>Well we went from
about 900 players down to
[laughter] uh, you’d probably
accord it topped out around 10.
But you know, but there was you
know even a subset to that, that
was a little more active. But uh
for the 4 years we ran it. >>We
were around 10 as well, uh
>>Yeah, we, Kenshoto was around
8, we had a couple outside
contributors. >>Yeah but
composed is funny, like people
who write challenged people who
organize, the guy I knows
actually the head, uh he’s, he’s
more like having to deal with
uh, Def Con stuff. We’ve got one
guy who's just an amazing
network guy. No joke, he is the
person that Cisco calls when
they can’t answer a problem. Not
even j- not even joking. >>Yeah,
we were um, as many as 14 but we
did ya know we made movies, we
did all sorts of stuff but it
was really only I think um 6 or
8 people that were the core of
our team. >>You were 1. >>Yeah
>>Yeah >>My- Myles was >>Army of
1 >>At, at the end was it still
1 or you drawn in a couple
people at the last [inaudible]?
>>It was 1 >>Yeah >>And that was
why it was time to hand it on.
>>Yeah, you lasted, you lasted
longer, you’re a good many
Charlie Brown. Um, so it turns
out that this thing allows you
to vote, there’s actually like
most popular questions. Um, what
is the most unexpected way
someone solved a challenge? So,
there’s like an intended path
and then there’s like unintended
paths, so. >>Yeah there’s a lot
of those. >>I mentioned they
used free BSG jailbreak
[laughter] to get out of our
jails. But, the we, we watched
them do it and they were so
inept when they go out. >>Yeah,
people, people bringing o’days,
people bringing o’days and then
completely messing up using them
correctly, would be a, that’s a
good one. >>My favorite one was
I had managed to let’s see,
Quake was the hot game in Def
Con 4, 5 so I managed to talk
its software to donating Quake
licenses to the Capture the Flag
contest. Like Quake servers and
a couple station setups so that
people could play Quake and then
I got free video games out of
it. So, all good. Um and so
someone came up to me and said,
you know we’ve dialed servers
but it’s not on the network. We
can attack the quake server and
one of the people gets so p**sed
off he goes over and reboots the
machine and that causes it to
reboot so we can run our RC
script. I said, go for it. >>We
uh, we convinced a team to
surrender. [laughter] Give us
all their points by telling them
that we were about to win even
though they were ahead. And so
they joined and all became
Ghetto Hackers. >>Actually, I’m
gonna, I’m gonna relay uh
something we were talking about
earlier act- an anecdote that we
were talking about specifically
in the Ghetto Hackers playing.
So, it wouldn’t be an instance
of Caezar having seen this occur
as a novel way to score points
to win the game, um but having
executed a novel way to win the
game, uh they basically
convinced the CTF organizers at
the time that they needed, they
needed store a half rack of
equipment that they had, so they
had ya know, your little like uh
what would it be 20, 20-ish u
rack. Um, and they had a
completely built out entire
faceplates of real servers and
stuff and they like stuffed a
person into the half rack and
actually got them to store it in
the room with all the rest of
the CTF equipment and
infrastructure overnight.
Because, well we need a place to
put this, right? And so
obviously out creeps person
>>Single roots all the machines
>>Single roots all the boxes
>>Reboots them all >>Peace
>>Puts them in single user mode,
roots them all. We come back in
the morning and then not
prepared or worked or done
anything the night before. We
come in with like, I, we’re
pretty been drinking all night,
uh the contest is over so let’s
all go home. And we got a whole
bunch of points and it was, yeah
it was pretty good. The contest
was not over. >>Oh no I >>We did
not go home >>I already
mentioned the, the bashrc one
which was fantastic. When we
were playing, we once snuck the,
the root search for one of the
teams and got first blood on
every service. That was during
your, your game. >>Uh, this
worked pretty good I can just go
to the next most popular one.
Um, so how do you come up with
unique uh flags or challenges I
think, uh I think it means
challenges or services uh every
year, aside from following CVE’s
or meeting content from other
>>That was actually a serious
source of exhaustion. >>Is is
>>Like >>Actually >>Like mental
exhaustion of attempting to come
up with services. And we used to
even like, we would literally
scrap 2 or 3 services every year
because they wouldn’t’ get
deployed correctly or they
wouldn’t get done. But like
coming up with like unique idea
of like, uh here’s a web service
that helps you make a sandwich
like or whatever. >>Well and,
and now with 20 years of Def Con
history >>Exactly, now you wanna
like do something original like
>>And that’s just Def Con
history that’s not talking about
every other CTF >>All the other
CTFs yeah, for sure. >>100 plus
probably per year, how do you
actually be unique, you can’t
really be unique anymore. >>NO
definitely now >>That’s why >>We
would actually, we would
actually basically, the real
truth of the story how we
produced our services is mostly
about getting a bunch of people
in a room, getting a bunch of
whiskey in the room too, and
like just bulls**tting until
funny ideas came out. And then
like codifying that list into
services. And then, and then
going in and deciding what kind
of exploit goes into it, what
kind of whatever. But every one
of those services had a little
>>Oh and for us, what we’ve done
is we’ve really introduced
multiple architectu-
architectures. Uh, 3 years ago I
think we had 5 different
architectures uh, in 1 game and
it was just XX6 and, and NIFs
there was, we even had a Windows
IoT arm challenges running a
powerPC shell, or something like
that, I don-. And this year of
course I’ve mentioned we have
the, the custom architecture
that we built. But it really is,
we’ve had to push it >>Nobody’s
quite explained this. Custom
architecture means >>Oh right
>>A system for storing bits in
electronics [laughter] >>Right
>>So imagine >>Instruction
stacks >>They implemented a CPU
>>Processor >>Yeah we
implemented a CPU >>A processor
of VM all up on top of nothing.
It’s, it’s um whole cloth, it’s
fantastic. >>Lightening actually
did it, but seemed to handle it.
>>Epic >>Yeah it is pretty good,
um yeah, it’s pretty much, we’ve
had, and the caliber of people
who are playing are just
phenomenal, like it, they
frighten me. People like Load
Key and GeoHash, scary good. So
the, the challenges, the level
that we have to do for the
difficulty has astronomically
increased. Um the, the medium
challenges back in the day are
now easy challenges for
everybody. >>Yeah, tools, tools
have gotten so much better too
you don’t want to write a, a
challenge that’s gonna be auto
solved by a tool, under, ya know
under a minute. >>Auto solve you
just, yeah >>That’s a good
segway for >>You have to keep up
with the state of the tools and
uh try to find the weaknesses in
the tools so that the, you still
will get the human you just
gotta do the deep dive. >>That’s
a good segway into the next,
actually set of questions.
There’s uh several related to
uh, CGC and, and sort of
automation. Um lessons learned
from, from Cyber Grand
Challenge. It’s been a year, was
it a success. >>Hackers are
obsolete [laughter] >>Failure,
I’m looking for one, I sorted
these and now I can’t find one
that I saw earlier. There’s this
one, mostly for Visi, how many
years until a computer wins Def
Con CTF, right? >>Uh, that’s.
>>So the, the thing that the,
the thing the computers have
trouble with right, is the dirty
tricks department. Um, and so I
think it will be awhile unless a
game is designed specifically
for the computer system, I mean
that’s really, that’s really
kind of where we are at like
right now I think CGC was a
really good example of this just
massively forward in technology
but at the same time you have to
keep in mind that um it was a
reduced instruction set and a
reduced sys call set and all
these other things that add a
really sufficient level of
complexity that I think there’s
still a lot of room, a lot of
wiggle room for like the human
dirty tricks department kind of
mindset. So, I think it’ll be a
little while yet. But it depends
kind of on the structure of the
game, so if elements of the game
require creative th- require
creative thought and unique
approaches um, I think that’ll
continue to kind of be an arms
race. And, and >>I only think it
matters if they have arms. If
you have to actually go walk,
pick something that the computer
won’t do that well. >>Well and
actually that’s a really good
example, because, because you
guys were notorious specifically
for incorporating into the CTF a
whole bunch of side games, where
those side games were like,
every team gets issues this
ancient hard drive that was like
gigantic and, they’re gon- that
hard drive is painted your
team's color and it’s going to
be out at the Def Con shoot
which I think still happens,
right? >>Myles >>Yeah >>Myles
>>Yeah that, the incorporate Def
Con shoot was mine, >>Right
>>That turned out to be a really
bad idea [laughter] >>Right,
well so basically I think a team
got a, a team got some bonus
points for like having like
basically punched a hole with a
bullet like through the most
center point of the drive or
something like that. Um,
computers aren’t gonna do that
for a little while yet, so.
>>Th, the other aspect with
computers is you have to freeze
the game, right chess is,
doesn’t change. Chess is chess,
is been chess forever and a
computer knows how to play chess
and if you wanna >>How, how
would the computer, how would
the computer deal with this new
architecture, >>Yeah, so
>>Right? >>You know >>Read the
manual >> We wanna see something
different every year, we wanna
throw curve balls every year and
its, unless you advertise that
some amount of time in advance,
like the CGC version that you
guys did last year, uh it's, I
think in Def Con CTF in
particular I don’t think we’ll
ever see it because that’s not
the game we humans want to play.
>>All, all we’ll ever need is
64K of RAM right? [laughter]
>>So uh, it, it probably wasn’t
clear earlier but 4 people up
here were involved in, in the
CGC competition some way and
then for those that aren’t aware
Def Con CTF last year was mostly
more or less CGC compatible,
right and the winner of CGC the,
the machine was a player in the
CTF competition last year which
kind of ties all these questions
back into the panel. So, uh it’s
sort of a related question and
um I won’t direct at anybody in
particular. But, so it’s been a
year right, CGC was last year
and the CTF that had the
computer was um, was a year ago.
Um, was that a, a success, a
failure was it sort of um, a, a
>>I would say that >>History >>I
would say it was definitely a
f-, a success. I really am a fan
of the fact that uh anger was
really open sourced. Um, I think
>>Pushed tools >>Right getti-
th- getting these tools out to
th- the general community is
fantastic. The fact that anybody
can go and use these and learn
how to write software, write
tools, to automatically RE and
go towards uh exploitation is
fantastic. Um, when you can m-
lower the bar s- uh to entry it
really makes it that much
better. >>Learning uh, learning
how the teams did their job last
year is probably the best thing
that anyone in the audience, any
of us could imagine doing for
their career for the next year.
>>An, and to be honest even
>>State of the art >>Uh, th-
future of ARRI just in normal
careers is gonna be automated,
it’s go- software’s becoming so
incredibly difficult, some
amount of automation is going to
be required, just to get even
the low hanging fruit anymore.
So incor- we’re actually, we
have to incorporate this idea
into CTF so that we can still be
representative of the wider
security community. >>Yeah, I
think that’s, the mistake people
make when they look at the CGC
is to think that the goal was to
build a purely autonomous system
and that wasn’t the goal. The
goal was advance the state of
the art in software a- analysis,
and wh- what, ya know we’ll see
last, we saw last year, we’ll
see it this year, is that uh,
software automatons assisting
humans make it, ya know making
humans better at what they’re
doing, is is probably where
we’re going. The best chess
playing systems in this world
are hybrid systems that pair
computers with the best players.
>>Yep >>Not, not purely
computers. >>Yeah, I think, I
think we’ve seen that too in
like, the a, even other CTFs now
all with modern things like
anger being applied in an
automated way to catch some of
the low hanging fruit or point
out areas of the code that’s
like, this probably like, we
don’t, it can’t necessarily
automatically generate an
exploit for every condition yet.
>>So we’ve actually had
challenges that required um,
anger or some automation,
automated reverse engineering.
That was >>Absolutely >>Like I
think it was called a Thousand
Cuts by Vito. Where you do, you
were given a thousand binaries
really fast and you had to be
able to exploit them in computer
speed, not human speed. Um
there’s even a challenge on
pwnable dot KR, called AEG where
it requires you, you to download
it and it gives you a random
binary every time and you have
to, uh auto RE it and that,
write the exploit. >>So how
international has CTF become?
Um, when did international teams
start showing up and do
Americans still stand a chance?
>>One of the, one of the first
uh things that I remember
happening was uh, Dillon
Kanabraun from Hack in the Box.
Uh reached out and asked uh, if
he could take CTF obviously, do
it yourself I mean do whatever
you want but, uh that was uh
taking CTF to Kuala Lumpur,
Asia. Uh, in I think 2001. So
it’s, it’s been coming for a
long time, it’s been s-
diversifying and spreading
rapidly uh, it’s I think one of
the most true and honest ways
that hackers can really be
better than each other. Because
we’re not very good I think
otherwise at knowing like am I
good enough. And being able to
say, well I’m better than that
guy is a huge, huge uh
foundation to stand on >>Yeah,
we have uh, competitors from all
over. We’ve got Korean and
Taiwan, Taiwanese and Chinese
and m- most major areas of, of
the world are representative,
like are represented and um,
they actually, 2 years ago Def
Corp from was it Korea, actually
won our game, so it was a, one
of the first times that I can
remember, and outside one, they
were mostly Danish um that
they’ve won CTF. >>I remember
actually it kind of, it kind of
like goes back to some of the
slides you were talking about
earlier with the language
barrier stuff. I think the first
like fully like non-English
speaking team um was, was f- was
a couple of the Korean teams
that were fielded early on in
the Kenshoto CTF and like we
actually had to really
specifically sit down and think
like, what are we gonna do about
this? Because we don’t want to
create a game, because the game
isn’t about English, the game is
about bits, right? And so like
we actually tried to create like
e-, we actually went through
several iterations of attempting
to create like pictographic
representations of like stealing
a key, key submission and things
like that with like, like you
know stick figures and stuff
like that, because the language
barriers, is so significant
that, um, I remember actually
one of the um, the captain of
the Korean team at the time, um
they did amazingly well in
quals. They like whomped
everyone in quals that year.
They show up, uh at the actual
game and they had a lot of
trouble but it was mostly about
understanding what was going on,
and the and the actual mechanism
of the game. And the, the
captain of that team came up to
me and was like, I think this
next year we’re gonna work on
hacking English. >>Nice >>Uh
some of those stickers, I think
that might have become Ken’s
stickers later on. >>Yeah, no
they were totally stickers. >>So
at the top there you can see
>>Oh yeah, actually, no that’s,
that’s exactly some of what I’m
talking about. We were like,
yeah. >>So, I mean clearly you
didn’t make those right then but
like that became a thing for
later. Um so I guess speaking of
that uh, what’s with all the,
the Japanese or like sort of
Asian references, right? So,
like when Myles ran it, it had
like the big >>It’s his fault
>>The, the red uh >>Did ever
pick out uh, Myles >>Japanese
thing, right >>No I think that
was actually >>It was Caezar
>>Back that up, oh ok >>We did,
uh we decided that we wanted to
give away a championship belt.
So, we gave away the Root Fu
Championsh- it, it was like a
boxing belt, like >>Like a
literal like WWF like belt
>>Yeah, yeah, so we made up this
whole concept of Root Fu. And it
was gonna be, um ya know a
measure of how good you could
compete against other people.
And it basically turned into
hacking and and, and the whole
thing fell down but as a theme.
You know we had um, uh all the
cultural references, in, in, in
Blade Runner and hackers, and I
mean the connection to
>>CyberPunk >>Yeah CyberPunk, uh
yeah Chatsubo. Uh I think I was
just kind of the gestalt hacker
meme at the time. Um as were a
whole lot of bad ideas and
things that we’re growing past.
So, we don’t have to live in
that world forever but uh I
think it was just the way that
things uh, everything grew up
then. >>We kind of just followed
suit. I mean Kenshoto actually
the like the name is in Japanese
so. For us there was that tie in
but it was mostly out of the
influence of that same sort of
cyber punk picture that you guys
had created. >>And, and one of
our uh, founding members uh
Praisin’ Angel uh is Korean, uh
woman who uh fits in a half rack
it turns out. [laughter] Uh, and
she and uh Data Angel uh did all
of the what we call the Ghetto
News Network. We did um news
videos that were kind of in um
the Blade Runner if you remember
the movie the Blade Runner on
the screens there’s uh, some
kind of Asian commercials I
think over like a soda. Um
>>I’ve seen it yeah. >>We kind
of took that image and we just
blew it out and made a whole
fake news system. >>They had her
basically congratulating teams
on not f**king up the network as
I recall correctly. >>Uh, yeah
so I just, had some back up
slides to show some of that,
there’s the, I can’t remember
what it's’ called but it’s like
the Japanese for uh, um, uh
something religious the red
thing in the background there.
And uh, certainly the Japanese
stuff continues uh over time.
Um, so what’s the oh I wanted
to, this one. So how do you find
middle ground uh, in the
challenges between the ones that
are too easy and the ones that
are too hard? >>Everything is
too easy. >>Yep >>Hackers are so
much better when they’re under
pressure than we are when we’re
sitting around trying to be
cool. >>The way our, we had to
modify our scoring algorithm, w-
the way we do it, is uh so for
quals everything starts out at 5
points except for baby's first,
and the more people solve it the
less it becomes worth. So it
just kind of, they were
self-correcting. >>Yep >>Cause
we, we’re it’s funny if you
write a challenge it’s really
hard to judge how hard it is
when you write it yourself.
>>So, so wait it’s 5 points when
I get it but then if so many
people follow along, then I lose
my points? >>Right so its >>Yeah
that’s fantastic >>We also made
>>So much smarter >>We made
other people in Kenshoto g- um
actually do all the challenges
with no prior knowledge of them
and so >>Testing >>Yeah testing,
essentially >>Time is the
problem >>Because the problem is
it’s also really it's really
easy to implement a challenge
where there’s some like leap of
faith that you didn’t realize
you made and then other people
wouldn’t and aren’t part of the
logical analysis progression.
And so that being the case like
we, we had found challenges,
actually there were 1 or 2 in
your guys’ game too, and
there’ve been others and
specifically in, usually in
quals rounds. Where like there’s
some like leap of faith required
if you, actually I think the, I
think the best examples are
listen, listen to the crazy a**
explanations of the Def Con
badge challenges where they’re
like, I realize that these dots
were actually morse code of
GEOlocation things that were
airports that then if you
arrange the airports and then
reverse their letters and then
just all these things that
you’re like, why did you think
to do that in the first place?
And so, like we didn’t, we
didn’t want to have challenges
that were, that were, why did
you think to do that in the
first place. We wanted there to
be this sort of thread through
them and, and essentially the
way we imp, enforced that was
just entirely, here you go other
person on Kenshoto like go break
this and solve it. >>It’s also
really easy to make questions
that are easy for your top 1
percent. And so, it’s like no
one gets it and the top 1
percent gets it in 5 minutes and
then where’s the rest of the
contest? >>Well but that’s, so
for the, for the real game
that’s what we were shooting for
cause we were trying to we were
basically, if anyone was topping
out that R and solving all the
challenges they weren’t hard
enough, right? So, for us, we,
we considered it a failure in
any year if someone solved all
the challenges. And so, I think
that they like the pushing of
that scale to, to being higher.
We didn’t really concern
ourselves in the real game with
that approachability or, or
middle ground but in quals we
did because that’s the thing
that lie everybody gets to play
everybody gets to be inspired
and do something, right >>One of
the things that we did for quals
was we really, prior to us they
had things lie forensics, trivia
and because those weren’t really
necessary for the actual finals
game, um we only did, ya know
Puntables, we did like gorilla
programming, things that will,
you have to know in order to
play, uh succeed in finals. So,
forensics where you have to go
and take ya know the first bit
of every sector of the NTFS dri-
or section ah that was terrible.
That was also before you did
flag open brace cl- closed
brace. That’s when you were
guessing. >>Yeah, we left those
in because we wanted be, we
wanted quals to be accessible to
a large number of people. >>Yeah
it was a conscious decision for
us too >>That’s why we added
baby's first because we wanted
that same approachability
without it still be you know
directly uh, ac- or uh be
directly applicable to the game.
>>Playskool my first tp exploit
>>Yeah >>Um, you guys ever seen
evidence of collusion?
[laughter] >>So, uh >>We
literally >>I was going to say
>>Colluded with teams >>Teams
>>All the time >>Won via
collusion >>We only won by
collusion [laughter] >>Uh
where’s, where’s Zeon is he
here? >>So >>There he is
[laughter] >>So I think at, at
this stage in the game for us
most people have at least begin
treating it like a gentlemen’s
game. Like, we genuinely want to
see who is the best and other
teams feel the same way. For
example, uh a few years ago,
there was a team for some reason
who put a wiki up on the game
network and that wiki had their
passwords on this, and one of
the, the teams actually the
[inaudible] officers came up and
said hey guys, we saw these guys
had a wiki up you should
probably tell them. And that was
during finals, where they could
have gone just completely wiped
all their flags, and just ran
the board. But it’s really
become, uh, uh like I said a
gentlemen’s game. So, for the
most part >>Whereas like,
whereas like in our game like we
were owning other people’s
laptops and stuff too. Like if
it was connected to the network.
>>So that’s sort of breaking
outside of the intended path,
but that’s not really collusion.
Right? That’s >>No, so, but
there was, there was legitimate
team, there was legitimate team
collusion at least in the, in
the, in one of the ghetto hacker
wins and, and uh, I mentioned
Zeon and Evans, stuff like that
from back in the day. Because
it’s that’s actually really hard
thing from a game mechanic to
detect and so we actually had,
so I mentioned the idea of like,
ha, ha to mess with the teams we
had services that weren’t
exploitable but they were
actually canary services because
if someone submitted a token
from that, from another team
either the game mechanism was
broken and they managed to get
tokens they shouldn’t’ be able
to or they’re colluding. So, we
were very concerned about that
because it’s almost impossible
to totally prevent right. If
you’re just like slide a couple
of tokens by here and there
between 2 teams to that they can
like get, get way far ahead you
make it so it’s a race between 2
rather than 8 or 10 right.
>>Yeah for us the, the biggest
problem for collusion happens in
quals. So, you have less control
over quals than what’s going on
in the game itself because it’s
not on your own infrastructure,
they’re not in a room >>I
actually think uh the, our game
mechanic that we do where if you
submit more than eh, s- submit
the keys, uh that the score
drops for everybody. Um you’ll
see, so back when I, a- actively
played I had a team myself I
would go and test the keys and
see if it worked. And however,
that’s actually a bad move now.
Because if you were to do that,
you actually dropped the score
for everybody, including your
own team. So, if you start
colluding there’s a possibility
that somebody will actually pull
ahead of both of you. So,
>>Right >>Yeah because you end
up cutting those >>Strategy,
right? Because now the people
that are, you could delude flags
that are more important to other
teams. >>Yeah >>Right >>But if,
but if you >>HJ is that specific
to quals? >>This is specific to
quals >>Yeah >>But if you’re on
top then you’re on top, right?
>>Right >>So that’s not gonna
affect you much. >>I mean we, we
built collusion detection in the
quals because we had unique cha-
challenges were tweaked in a, in
a small way or everybody had
their ya know, their own
service, their own accounts.
>>Monitoring source IP addresses
of submissions and >>Yeah
>>People would say I can’t log
into my account, that’s because
you’re using someone else’s
creds and you’re not supposed to
see those creds unless you’ve
been sharing or the keys were
different per team. So, we, we
did set up some services wh-
that were specifically to detect
teams that were sharing answers.
>>It takes a massive amount of
work >>I th- I think the, the
conclusion is, that uh as an
organizer you’re increasingly
playing game theory. We’re
playing a game. Everybody else
is doing an activity. [laughter]
We make an activity and for us
it’s a game and maybe that’s why
we like to >>So that’s why you
organize because you want to
play the game. >>Kina yeah
>>Well we know the tricks for
the game, so we try to beat
them. >>Yeah, for sure >>Uh so
here’s a perhaps interesting
question so why is, uh the
finals uh attack defend style,
why don’t you just continue
Jeopardy style? >>Oh, because
that’s not hacking. >>Yeah so
>>Because, because reality.
>>Yep >>Cause that’s bulls**t.
>>If, If, if we wanted it to be
a puzzle game it would be a
puzzle game. We want it to be a
hacking game. >>It, there’s
almost zero pressure in
Jeopardy, right? >>Exactly >>You
sit back >>Exactly >>And you
answer questions and you’re in
your living room. >>Yeah
>>Attack defense, you, you
there’s a reactive nature to
that and that, that can cause
people to >>And, and, and we’ve
always wanted to make a contest
that everyone could start.
Everyone could start down the
road to winning Def Con CTF and
we needed something that’s hard
enough that it actually slows
people down who aren’t ready.
>>So, it adds another game
mechanic in terms of, nice, for
example defense-like patching. I
can patch my binary but there’s
a chance that it will now fail
poles. So. >>And the whole SOA
discussion from earlier. >>We’ve
also added uh a game mechanic in
our game where we have a
concurrency for patches, so if
you patch something and all you
do is add ya know 40 hex, 40 to
the st- side of the stack well
that’s published now so everyone
can see what you just patched.
>>If you take nothing else away
from this conversation that is
the piece of sheer genius that
we’ve been missing this whole
time since we started playing.
>>Agreed >>Is when you add
defense everyone else has an
opportunity to do the same. That
turns it >>Yep, I think really
into a game finally, for the
players because now do I accept
your patches blind? >>Oh PPP,
like they definitely back doored
patches, like they’ll, they’ll
patch something and then like,
yeah go ahead use our patches.
See what happens. >>Yeah and
like purposely deploying patches
that then cause other people to
try and analyze those to figure
out what was going on. Purposely
deploying a harmless patch that
doesn’t actually necessarily fix
anything but sufficiently
complicates something >>Or
>>That you use, that you use
resources of the other team
having to try and reverse
engineer, like what the hell
does that patch mean? >>I’ve
definitely heard of, uh patches
with Q&U bugs in them. >>Yep
>>Yeah y- y- you can create an
obfuscated code contest sub
contest as a player now while
you use the system. >>Which,
which really ultimately becomes
like team captain leadership
triage contest really because.
>>Who came up with this idea?
>>So it was actually uh the guys
who did CGC. >>Yeah >>It was
there idea. >>It came from CGC
>>Thought >>Just amazing, just
the most important thing that
happened. >>Um, how bout, what’s
the uh, uh I can’t find the
exact wording, what’s the
hardest question or service that
each of you have ever fielded in
your tenure? >>Man >>That’s hard
>>Super tough, yeah >>Yeah and,
that’s eh no preparation you
just have to come up with it but
like which one of your >>I would
say every new CTF is so much
harder than the old ones, that
listening to anybody but Hawaii
John is probably a waste of time
cause the new contests are just
so much harder. >>Well so I’ll
give you >>Uh, I, I invented a
CPU in order to write bugs on,
um uh, is such a high bar. >>One
of our guys uh, Solier it was-
was uh, J Dub, um he wrote a
MUD. H- a full featured MUD,
where you had to go in and
collect certain uh numbers of
items from each, like from b- uh
NPC’s and then that’s your shell
code. So th-, in the place,
then, then you actually cause,
you trigger the overflow and the
number of items you have of
different types becomes your um,
your code. [laughter] Yeah, it’d
be your shellcode direct. >>So
we had a MUD, we had a MUD but
you could hit A L a lot of times
and then hit enter and it would
crash. [laughter] >>Yeah no
>>See the game is not the same
thing >>I- well what was really
fun, he put, uh he made us all
God mode characters, um so we
get to walk around in it and, it
was really funny because if
somebody attacks you, you can’t
stop attaching back it just
happens automatically so
eventually you realize, alright
we don’t hit these guys. Because
if you hit them I just die >>We,
we had a, we had a MUD a couple
years but it was all just about
like uh the social aspect of
quals it was where everybody
would talk and, and hang out and
stuff during quals, um but
effectively we ended up like
killing all the players a couple
of times by accident, like some
monster that one of the other
Kenshoto people was creating
like got loose and we didn’t, I
don’t know. >>Oh it S-, it was
S-, so Seer Goon the guy that
wrote the MUD is also the guy
who uh developed the badge that
you saw up there. So that badge
he designed and we floated
ourselves on a hot plate. Like
not even joking, put it on
there, did all the solder and
LE, the components and floated
on a hot plate and, that was,
you had to exploit it over rf,
you can send them all text
messages back and forth.
[laughter] >>Yeah >>So it’s
like, it’s like a twist question
that came in from the audience.
Uh what about the most elaborate
challenge that you were able to
dream up but that couldn’t quite
pull off. >>Man >>It’s like
still on the to-do list >>Uh let
me make sure I can act- >>A
really good scoreboard
>>Actually >>Uh the >>Ours was
>>Scoreboard >>The uh, ou- ours
was the uh World Series of Poker
printer challenge. >>Oh yeah I
remember that one >>Oh yeah
that’s right >>That that’s when
we started to destroy that
thing. You’re like, no, no, no
it’s not our printer >>W- we
>>Yeah, I remember that one >>I-
one year at the Rio, we, we,
rolled in right after the world
series of poker had ended and in
the back rooms were all the
printers that they had used for
the World Series of Poker's and
we just wheeled one out and put
one on every table. Everyone had
an Ethernet [laughter] we ran
cable to every table. And uh,
yeah we wanted to work that into
the game but didn’t quite get
there. >>So [off mic comment]
>>Y- yeah some of them got fully
disassembled and never
reassembled and >>Yeah >>I think
>>There’s, there’s actually some
significant analysis on the
internet of some of those
printers >>Pay for a few
printers I think >>Uh Guynar you
here? No. I was trying to ask if
I could mention his challenge
but I guess I’ll go ahead it’s
in a text message. So, he came
up with an awesome idea, uh GDB
over phone. So, you dial in and
says, this is your prompts and
he actually got a decent way
into the challenge, like it, I
ya know press 1 for R aright.
These are you registers,
alright. Ya know, step. There
was a [laughter} But we
couldn’t, like the, the band-
bandwidth and throughput just
wasn’t enough for that one.
>>Operator, operator >>My God
that’s great, that’s great
>>Real person [off-mic comment]
>>Well >>And then, and then do
the teams have to implement
like, like audio lang- language
processing to sort of automate
the debugger? >>Hang, hang on,
hang on yeah at Goa at NolCon uh
I was a, I was really proud of
one of the kids there he made a
DTMF only attack for IVRs. He
found a sql injection attack in
the default template for IVRs
running asterisk asterisk. So he
had a compressed DTMF string
that he could play into an IVR
and get it to read out the
username and password of all of
the accounts allowed to edit the
system. >>Awesome >>And the
phone came out, it, h- h- he
used his own voice so it was
hard for me to understand, but
uh nothing to do with our game
but uh but you can make DTMF
attacks. >>Yeah >>Turns out it
takes only about I don’t know 50
milliseconds or something to get
a digit through. >>Um, when did
black badges start being
awarded, was it always 8? >>I
don’t know >>Uh >>Caezar >>We
got the first one, um I think
they were I don’t know actually
when they, black badges came out
[off-mic comment] >>I’m saying
they were, when the team was I
think the largest ever team was
like th- tw >>20 people >>20 odd
people and DT’s standing there
with like 1 black badge, like
[laughter] uh, yeah. >>Yeah so
he went and grabbed and he could
like spare 8 total so >>That’s
hilarious >>That became 8 of us
got black badges the rest of
them did not >>Cause yeah, we
pick 8 people for our team, we
picked 8 people for our team for
the first year because you guys
did and you probably picked it
because at some point he just
had 8 badges. That’s kind of
funny >>8 teams, 8 badges >>Well
alright >>8 players >>That was,
that was based on, that was also
based on the like table layout
at the time, like there were
like 8 approximate seats without
whatever and so we basically
decided that you couldn’t have
more than that at the table >>I
think that’s still the same we,
we, we limit the size of the
table just because uh, just
managing it all’s a pain.
>>Which I mean doesn’t really
prevent large teams but what it
does do is gives large teams the
same problem that large
organizations in real life have.
Which is left hand right hand
communication problems and
organizational problems because
like 20 people sitting at a
table can still kind of coalesce
and self-organize but 20 people
divided into 2 groups sitting in
2 different rooms can’t >>In the
real world you can buy a
fractional T3 or, or a you know
a private line and have it run
and have somebody put up some
VPNs and buy some keys and walk
them over there, all these
things, here you’ve got 48 hours
to end the contest from the time
you know where you’re gonna be
and getting a remote team
connected is >>Yeah limited the
effectiveness of a large team
was one of our driving ideas
>>Yep >>And the way we’ve done
that is that we actually don’t,
wh- when the game first started
like, during DDTEK they would
just give you all services
immediately except for maybe a
few handful excep- exceptions,
now we’ll drop one service so
sure you have 50 people, let all
50 people look at 1 service,
good luck, alright have fun.
>>Limiting parallel >>Limi- yeah
li- limiting parallelism is what
we do and then ya know maybe la-
maybe later we’ll do ya know 2,
2 more services or something
>>Yeah we never thought about
anything like that I wish,
honestly I wish we had because
limiting, limiting team size was
a huge motivator for us too.
>>For a certain team >>2
actually >>Uh it’s >>You, you
and Shellfish >>It’s sort of
interesting because it also
plays into the, sort of
distribution int- inside of a
team, right? How many rockstars
are there and how, how fast does
it drop off and like what is the
curve >>We also started
implementing what we do cal-, uh
we patch a service so like real
world we’ll implement the basic
functionality of a service and
then y- maybe mid-day on
Saturday, >>Change it >>A
completely new one and the
original bug is patched, so now
you have to pull the person who
was originally the, the facto
expert on that, that service and
they now have to do this new
thing because do you really
wanna ramp up somebody else on,
on the same service or, hold
them? So yeah we’ve, we’ve
really spent a lot of time
thinking about these game
mechanics and, and how to make
it um, more playable, useful for
the real world. >>Yep >>Uh so
how many women have
participated? >>I know that um,
um More Smoke Leak Chicken has
at least had female
participation. Um unfortunately
not enough. >>Yeah >>We had more
than 25 percent every year that
we’ve played. Uh we, we uh did
not try to make a conscious
inclusion of people, we picked
the best people we knew and in
Seattle that’s a mixed group.
>>We had women with us, uh not a
huge percentage but we had more
and more with us every year with
School of Root. >>Imagine they
just didn’t want to smell us. We
start stinking after a day.
>>Par- participation
participation-wise there’s been
a lot of mixed team, um but by
far it’s obviously uh been
lopsided. >>What about it as
organizers. >>Uh so, uh
Lightening, uh eh- her name is
Jewel, the person that wrote
this. >>Wow, again it’s just a
full stop. >>Phenomenal, yeah
like custom architecture
implemented by a woman for
absolutely, yeah. >>We’re not
looking for a winner, I’m just
c- [laughter] >>No, n- >>No, no,
no >>No, that’s >>We found one
>>That’s >>You weren’t looking
for it but we found it, yeah we
found the winner of CTF
>>Exactly >>And it’s up here
with Lightening >>Um, I feel
like just putting this up here
even though it’s clearly a troll
but Frank wants to know. He’s
hacked the Gibson and only got a
partial download of the garbage
file so can you help him look
through it? >>I think >>There’s
a person in the audience who
does not know what this means
and we just found this out right
before we walked to this room
[inaudible] >>Hack the Planet
>>Or something >>Blank, blank,
blank right? >>I kind of have to
do it >>Yeah >>It’s like
>>Blank, blank, blank >>It’s
like the only question that’s
been posted that wasn’t
anonymous so I felt like I had
to actually put it up there
[laughter] Um so here’s a
curious question at least to me,
uh did you do dry-runs and like
how many people would
participate in the dry-runs if
you did do >>We never had time
>>We can’t, w- time plus we
can’t do dry-one, runs. >>We did
cause we really only trust
ourselves. >>We did dry-runs of
individual services >>Okay yeah
>>Right. So, the, the the idea
of the dry-run thing of like
here other member of Kenshoto or
whatever like try to solve this
challenge but other than that
>>Internal >>No way >>Data
testing I guess you’d call it
>>Yeah, yeah unit, unit testing
and not integration or systems
testing. >>No >>Like systems go
online at the real game >>Test
them >>Yeah, exactly and we had
to make changes like, like last
second all the time, like every
year. >>M- yeah, we did it as
well, we did it for our, all of
our automated polling scoring
all of that stuff, I mean th-
the second part of the question
doesn’t make sense to me, right.
How did you stop any info
leaki-that’s an outside thing.
[inaudible] >>Some sort of beta
run or something, more people
have, it sounds like >>We didn’t
have >>No way >>It was only
team, right >>No way >>It wasn’t
like we opened it to public beta
or something like that >>No way
>>It, it was only our internal
dev team. >>Yeah >>It’s, it’s
probably one of the reasons his
code hasn’t even transacted from
hand to hand really. Is, is just
because we all feel like, at
least I think we felt like, we
wanted to play Myles’ game and
then once we kind of got on the
inside we didn’t want to be
tainted, we didn’t want to taint
anybody else we wanted all of
our friends to be able to enjoy
the game that they loved. >>Yep,
totally. >>Got 5. Oh, we’re
done? Okay. Program says another
9 minutes. But we can be done if
you want us to. [laughter] >>My
beers empty >>Mine too >>Alright
last, last >>No more beer >>Last
question then >>Let’s go >>Uh,
what qualities do you admire
most in the teams that compete?
>>Fury, like there are teams
that just like throw down and
they don’t do anything else.
They don’t sleep. They don’t
eat. >>Do you remember the mad
>>Passion >>Hackers >>Yeah >>I
was going to say like I admire
no whining [laughter] >>Yeah,
like as, as an organizer that,
that becomes a big problem. I
agree like that’s yeah, that’s a
big issue but just the fury the
passion of it. >>Like, the fact
that you can go and you spend ya
know 12 hour, 10 hours in front
of a PC and then you go and
spend all night in front of,
doing the same thing. It’s
pretty hard core like, like I
kind of admire all of it. Yeah
>>Yeah the endurance, the i- it
really is at some point an
endurance feat. >>You know
what’s funny is thinking about
that is you’re right now th- the
cost entry is, well they get
free entry now I don- it wasn’t
when you guys, was the case but
they get 8 badges per team but
before when you’d have to pay
>>We didn’t even get badges >>Oh
yeah. When you pay, you go and
you come here like especially
people coming here from far
away. Russia and Japan, and they
spend their entire weekend in
front of a computer, the exact
same thing they do at home and
they come in here and do it so
uh >>Th, the yeah. Aside from
that the thing that always
shocked me as an organize-, time
to solve, is the thing that I
always looked at right? Some,
something drops like radically
faster than you expected it,
>>Oh yeah >>That that’s like an
instant >>That’s frightening
>>Wow >>Sometimes >>Yeah,
agreed, agreed. >>Yeah th- and
the level it’s not just the
stamina, like yeah I can drink a
bunch of Mt Dew and see, I put
in the 10 months getting to this
>>That’s true a lot of people
bring, now you have to bring
custom stuff, for >>Right
>>Example when h- he was
mentioning that if you pull a
flag and you don’t encrypt it,
it’s gonna get caught, cause oh,
that’s one thing we mention too
is that pe- all the teams have
access to the packet captures,
so they see all the data coming
across the network and they
control what’s uh, coming in and
out of the box, so, um if you
don’t encrypt your, your data
back and forth in your shell
code, your shellcode has to
implement the encryption, then
you’re gonna fail. >>Alright, do
you have something? >>Uh, uh
just, just one of the things in
time, time to crack uh, I don’t
know if it was you guys uh, 1 of
our routers leaked 1 bit of
information and the scoreboard
had a different TTL, off by 1
from th- >>I remember, no that
was, that was, I remember >>Was
that you? >>That was us, yeah
>>Was that you guys? Aight
>>Yeah >>The TTL on the
>>Basically we could tell, we
could tell apart the packets
that were your engine testing
that the service was online from
everyone else. >>So they
firewalled only the players
>>Nobody else can get >>Percent
SLA, zero percent defense >>Yeah
>>An- and they did this in maybe
I don’t know, maybe 7 minutes.
From the time, we handed them
their discs, they were. It was
amazing >>We profiled TTL and
your agents on your >>Yeah >>We
missed that one we didn’t, yeah
>>Alright, we’ve got the, the
cutoff so um the, the slides
will be posted and uh, th- the
video will be posted so it's, uh
thank the panelists and uh I
suppose we’ll be around for a
little bit. >>Thanks for coming
>>Yeah thanks for coming
[applause]