>>I am not Jeff Moss [inaudible
talking] Just FYI. I am not the
dark tangent uh it’s like we get
confused all the time. Um, I’m
Jayson E. Street but uh, Jeff
couldn’t be here because there
was way more important things
uh, to do, obviously. Uh,
[laughter] which is okay
[chuckle]. It’s like, we’re cool
with that. Um, I’d also like to
introduce uh Waz. Uh, The DG uh,
[cough] DCG coordinator. Thank
you. [applause] Yep. [applause]
He’s the supervising adult that
makes this uh, work. Um, and
then I’m uh, Jayson E. Street.
I’m the DCG ambassador. Uh,
because I travel all over
everywhere uh, so they just
thought hey and I like Def Con
anyway and I talk about it
everywhere so they put me in
there as the ambassador. We got
Brent White, uh B1TKILL3R. The
uh, part of The DCG and also DC
615. >>Yay. [whoops] [applause]
>>And we’ve got Grifter from uh,
DC 801. >>Wooh! [applause] >>And
we got uh, Jun Li from uh, DC
010 from all the way from
Beijing China. [applause]
Amazing. [applause] And we’ve
got Soups uh, he’s uh, an
intrical part of a DCG, and he’s
also the head of the DC 225 in
Baton Rouge uh, Louisiana.
[applause] And we have the myth,
the legend, Major Malfunction,
from [applause] all the way from
London England, [applause] DCC
uh DC uh 4420. [applause] So, uh
so I guess I’m gonna now go
look. I’m no longer Jeff over
here. I’m now me again. >>Come
sit. >> There we go. >>Oh. Hey
Jayson. >>So. Hi! >>Nice of you
to join us. >>[audible talking]
>>So a little bit about uh,
things that I do is uh, this is
a actual uh picture uh from a
Def Con Group meeting. I, last
year uh trying to make uh Def
Con Groups a little bit more
Global. Uh, I took it apon
myself to travel uh, even more.
Uh, and I went through Asia
because there was not that many
Def Con Groups in Asia so, I
literally started out in
Beijing. Uh went to Hong Kong,
Shin Jin, Singapore, and
Thailand. Uh, talking to uh
hackerspaces and makerspaces uh
in all those cities trying to
get them to start up. Uh, I am
happy to say that uh things are
actually, Jun Li’s here. It's
like we’ve got a Def Con Group
now in Beijing uh, Hong Kong,
Shin Jin and Singapore. So uh
that's really cool. They,
they’ve already had meetings,
they’re uh doing really good
work. Um, and uh so this is the
one from Hong Kong. Got started
off there and we've also working
on getting some Def Con Groups.
WE’ve got one started in Garden
Route and Johannesburg and South
Africa. We’re working on another
one in uh Close Napoca Romania
and uh we’re trying to make it
way more global. And, oh ya.
There’s some other pictures of
me as I’m traveling. It’s like
uh, that's from Singapore. >>The
robot Def Con Group right? >>Ya,
uh I was trying to uh hey, I do
not discriminate. It's like it’s
it’s a global inclusive
community, robots as well. Cause
they're our new overlords. Uh,
not everybody appreciated how I
did ambassadorship, uh some uh
were a little bit more uh uh
handsy or less handsy than than
I like so but they worked out.
Uh, this was a great meeting in
Singapore with uh Jeff Moss.
That’s actually Jeff Moss, the
one in the middle. Uh, and then
Deno Desavi uh, at the news
hacker space uh, the news uh
hacker meeting, which was really
cool. And uh, then this is uh
Adrian from uh the Garden Route.
He started the Garden Route uh
Def Con group. So, um I think
this um the the State of the
Union is really good. We’re
getting a lot more global uh
[cough] and I mean we got, we’re
getting uh, Def Con Group
inquiries from uh Columbia, from
uh Turkey, it’s uh from Europe,
it’s like we’re getting a lot of
great um initiatives. It’s like
for Def Con Groups coming out
and we’re expanding that which I
think is very important. Uh, Def
Con Groups is not a uh, Western
centric or US centric uh
organization. It should be you
know, everybody. Um, and what
we’re doing now and with the new
initiative that we’re working on
um that I, I literally just said
you know, yolo, let’s try to
make this happen. So, it’s gonna
either be spectacular or fail
spectacularly but either way,
spectacular. >>Jayson, >>Um,
>>can I interrupt you for a
second? >>Yes. >>You’re killing
the captioner. >>Killing the
caption? >>You, you’ve got to
slow down. Look at that thing
over there. >>Oh. [laughter] I’m
talking to fast. [Laughter] Wow.
[Laughter] I didn’t know that’s
going on. [Laughter] Alright
[Laughter] OMG. [Laughter]
>>Laughter! [laughter] You guys
got in there, you’re on the
board! Wooh! [whoops] [yelling]
[applause] >>Oh, that’s so cool.
[Laughter] >>Okay >>They gotta
say everything? Oh sorry. I’m
sorry, I’m getting distracted.
Okay, >>Squirrel! >>My, [laughs]
>>Squirrel! >>Alright. >>I love
pizza. Okay um. Okay sorry.
Okay. >>Bring it back. >>Okay
sorry, socially initiative that
we’re going to do is um I was at
a uh uh crime conference thing
for small businesses that were
thrown by um, that was thrown
together by Homeland Security in
Tennessee. Uh, Memphis. Which is
of course where you think of
when you think of Homeland
Security uh and one of the guys
there, one of the feds whose
name he does for some reason he
doesn’t want me to say what his
name is uh here. It’s like uh
though everybody would be able
to get a free t-shirt. Um, he
was very >>It was Jayson Street.
>>Ya. He was very interested in
uh the initiative that I talked
to him about, about having Def
Con groups all over the world
connect with law enforcement.
Cause that seems natural and
like, just totally cool right?
You know, like chocolate and
peanut butter. Um, but the
reason why is I want to see the
Def Con Groups to connect and
get involved with uh uh this
initiate contact with law
enforcement so the law
enforcement can introduce the
Def Con Groups to schools. We’re
going to create a script that
were going to put up on our
website, and we're going to put
reading materials and
documentation for schools on our
website for online safety, and
what hacking is and what and how
to protect yourself online and
instead of having police
officers and law enforcement
people who come over and to talk
about the evil hackers that are
breaking into your Facebook and
your Instagrams, were going to
have vetted Def Con Group
members come to schools and tell
children and students what
hacking is, what it’s about, and
how to protect themselves.
[Coughing] Going to a school, an
elementary school, as a hacker
in your hoodie going hey I want
to talk to your kids about
online safety. [Laughter] That’s
not gonna work out so well. But
if we can actually get law
enforcement to actually to you
know, serve us a little bit
here, it’s like then we can
actually use the system to help
us further the message and the
positivity of what hacking
really is. And I want that to be
a global thing not just um uh
just a US thing. So it’s like
we're already talking about it
to other uh countries, to other
groups, uh to talk to the law
enforcements in their country
and get an engagement and engage
with them. Uh, so you pick like
2 Def Con Group members that uh
you know will pass a background
check, that or one, if you and
if you know the certain groups
it’s like you can get one. It’s
like you know. >>You can only
get one. [laughter] >>Exactly.
It’s like so if you can get one,
it’s like have them be the the
point man and then have that
going. So we’re going to start
working on that uh, Brent is
going to be working with the Fed
because he’s in Nashville. um,
that’s where he’s stationed out
of. And they’re the DC615 in
Nashville. So that’s going to be
our pilot project but once that
gets hammered down, I want this
everywhere by the end of the
year. It’s like we're hackers
are going to schools and telling
kids what it’s like and how to
protect themselves, and what
hacking is. Let’s change the
narrative there and then go
outward. So, that’s what I’d
like to hope we can start.
[applause] >>So uh, something I
want to add on to that Jayson,
so um, my daughters in
elementary school. My wife and I
went and spoke uh for career day
and uh so I talked you know,
spoke about hacking and you know
what hacking is and then all
this stuff and so uh, it I
thought it went really well but
as we were leaving, the kids
were at lunch and I think this,
I think this kid was in second
or third grade and he goes oh uh
you're the one that spoke about
hacking? And I was like ya, and
he’s like so can you like, teach
me how to break into banks where
cops don’t see me? And I was
like no, wait wait you’ve got
this all wrong. [laughter] It’s
uh So uh we’ve gotta make sure
that those conversations don't
come up in this initiative or.
>>See, it’s not technically
wrong, I mean >>Ya >>it’s what
Jayson does. >>Well but, he
would no but but but he was like
you know where the cops can’t
see me and stuff. >>Oh. >>And I
was like you need to stop
watching so much TV there kid
so. >>Right. >>So anyway, >>As
long as you have the paperwork
you’re good right? >>Ya >>Ya
[laughter] >>Alright [laughter]
you’re up. >>Hi. Uh, so I’m
gonna talk about what Def Con
groups are or more like where
they came from as well. So, uh,
I’m Grifter from DC801. Uh, DC
801 and DC 719 are are or were
are the original Def Con groups.
Um so, [noise] [laughter] hold
on. I want to see if it says
like Jayson opening diet Pepsi
on the captioner. [Laughter]
>>It does now. [laughter]
>>what? [laughter] >>It does
now. >>Sound of carbonation
escaping the bottle. >>Pssssh
[laughter] >>Jaysons spewing on
the floor. [laughter]
>>psssssssss >>We broke him.
[laughter] um. Okay, so, so
basically they came about cause
we um we had a pretty good group
of folks out in Salt Lake City
which is where DC801 is from. Uh
and we were running 2600 SLC. We
had I think at the time that we
flipped from a 2600 meeting over
to the concept of a Def Con
group was um about 50 people
would show up every month in a
food court and kinda descend on
it and have a mini con which was
really cool. Um, but it
basically came about because at
the time, 2600 magazine was uh
by a lot of people in the group,
getting political. LIke it was
actually telling people like oh
you should vote like this if you
want to support these things and
if you’re a hacker you should be
voting this way instead of more
like uh regardless of what their
political views are that’s just
not cool. So, um, we said well
what can we do where we can
still have a good name around it
and then have this group thing
and so um I talked to DT and
said hey, what do you think if
we did this? And he was like
that sounds awesome, talk to
Russ. And Russ is, he was in
DC719 um, so I called up Russ
and we kind of worked things out
over the course of a about a
month or two and then we
launched our meetings and we had
them. We started them in
February and then we announced
them in the summer. The next
summer at Def Con. So they had
been going on for about 6
months. Uh, they’re awesome. I
mean like. >>It was Def Con 12
right? >>Uh, >>Or Def Con 13?
>>Ya it was, it was early on.
>>It was Def Con 12 or 13. I
don’t remember which but it
started there. >>For sure. Wait,
yes. Because we were still at
the AP. >>Yup. >>Ya. Alright.
Um, so now Def Con groups are
everywhere. They’re all over the
world. So, um, if you’re looking
to join a group you know check
the website, see if you can find
one that’s already established
and if you don’t see something,
please start one. Um, so, how do
you start one? >>Wait, wait.
>>What? >> Hey Grifter, what’s
the website? >>What, what is the
website? [Laughter] Isn’t hasn’t
it been on every slide? >>Ya.
>>Oh alright. [laughter] Dear
captioner, please type Def Con
groups dot org. [Laughter] >>No.
>>D****t [laughter] >>Close
enough >>Oh [laughter] >>Close
enough >>I’m outta here now.
>>OH, that’ll work. >>Look what
you did. [Laughter] Look what
you did. [laughter] >>WWW dot
DEFC [laughs] Oh no. That’s
messed up. [Laughter] Now they
got it. >>Alright. >>Alright.
We’ve gotta stop messing with
the caption person. Um,
[laughter] So ya so go to the
Def Con groups website. Look for
um, uh, a group that’s around
you, and if there isn’t one
start one. And when I say if
there isn’t one, that doesn’t
mean if there’s one that’s 30
minutes away and that’s too far
so you should start another one
like, get in the car or on a bus
and and head over there. I think
that was something uh that
started to happen with 2600
meetings as well. Where it was
like there was one here and then
there was one like 5 blocks over
because people didn’t wanna
commute so. >>Alright so the
next things like um how do you
get people to attend? It’s like
that I’m given a lot of the
questions when people are uh
approaching me and I’m talking
to them in different areas and
uh and in different places and
they’re saying like well uh how
do I get people to attend? Well
well what's really going to be
drawn what do I do with it. And
the first thing I tell people
it’s like you start if you get 2
people at your first Def Con
group meeting, awesome. [claps]
>>Yes [applause] >>That’s great.
That’s a good start. It’s like
You know and you just work from
there. It doesn’t have to be oh,
we didn’t get 20 people showing
up. IT’s like uh it’s gotta
start organically so it’s like
you got people by word of mouth,
it’s like you’ve got social
media. I know people that are
starting uh starting with just
facebook pages because they
don’t have website yet. Um, so
start off by that. Start uh by
broadcasting that on Twitter. Um
um CC the Def Con groups uh
Twitter handle and we will
amplify that for you or you know
James will amplify that for you
and uh it’ll get that word out.
So, you can start doing it that
way. Just start finding a good
location that’s uh central for a
lot of people to get to in a
nice area where they uh usually
have alcohol some for some
reason helps. Uh, it’s like it
maybe a projector screen you
know even better. Um and start
if off there. It’s like start
getting people to show up by
like giving them something to
show up too. You can’t just say
hey you wanna sit around, get
drunk and talk hacking? It’s
like Which actually works for a
lot of people but you know, uh
but you gotta do something like
have a talk start a talk
somewhere. Uh Get involved. Defc
and another thing key thing I
want to make sure we understand,
Def Con groups does not replace
or surplant any other
organization that’s going on in
that city. IT’s like if you
can’t say well I wanna start a
Def Con group but you know uh uh
there’s also 2600 or a city sec
or you know, some other hacking
or security related uh group
going on too so no I can’t do
there. That’s not what it’s
about. IT’s like there’s got
there’s always room for more
people connecting and being
together and working to make
things happens so uh don’t let
that be an excuse, don't’ let
that be a reason you’re not
starting a Def Con group in your
area. >>Ya so >>That was the
longest sentence I’ve ever
heard. >>You’re welcome >>Ya
[Laughs] So one of the >>I I’m
going to inter interrupt you
know. Some practical advice on
finding uh a location. Um, what
we found in London there’s a lot
of really uh good setups like um
nightclubs, and bars, so on that
don’t actually open until quite
late. So our one of our first
locations was um a night club
that gets going at midnight and
we don't want to to be having uh
uh a group meeting starting at
midnight so they’ve got space
that's all set up with
projectors in the bar and lights
and space and so on and it’s
standing empty um and it’s in
cent the center of London so uh
we’ve found we could actually
get into that space really cheap
uh, well free in fact because
um, generally you don't get
charged to use a bar or a
somewhere there that serves
food, if you bring enough people
in that they actually start you
know paying um giving money over
the bar or buying food and and
and so on, so they didn’t charge
you for use of the room and
we’re done by 11, 12 so that’s
the point where they’re gearing
up for their main business. So
we’re giving them a use for
their empty space uh and and
actually we um, that’s how we
got started so ya. We we ended
up moving to a pub because they
were charging us night club
prices for drinks even though we
weren’t in a nightclub. Well we
were in a nightclub but we’re
not in a nightclub environment
if you know what I mean so. >>It
so, some of the things that we
did for uh DC615, uh you had
mentioned you know, how do you
get people to attend? So, one of
the things that we did uh we had
a really good B sides um
conference that goes on uh with
Little Loss and then uh we have
uh Jeff and some other people
that were kind enough to let us
you know, do a quick little
blurb doing the opening ceremony
and they were able to carve out
a little room for us to talk to
go um people and and tell them
about the group. Uh you know
websites, social media obviously
uh and then you know college
campuses if they let you hang up
fliers, um, and you know and the
and the technology room and
areas like that to kind of get
the word out. Um, and I’m glad
that you mentioned that to about
how we're not trying to compete
with other meet ups and that’s
one of the things uh you know
Nashville we have, there’s quite
a few uh other meet ups that go
on and so before we even started
the group we did some research
and made sure that we weren’t
stepping on anyone's toes, cause
that’s the last thing we want is
to get you know politics and and
um any drama involved in that so
uh so we were pretty careful
about that. >>I didn't know we
weren’t supposed to compete with
the other meetings like we have
gangland style fights with them.
>>Well [Laughter] if that it
that’s cool. >>Ya a dance off.
>>We want a dance off. >>Well ya
ya well dance off. >>Oh ya.
>>Break dance fighting. Um, no
we do um some similar things you
know we have uh a couple of
local conferences that take
place um in Utah, Saint Con, and
Eastside Salt Lake City, and
Hack West and so we work with
those guys to get the word out
at those events. Um to your
point, college campuses thats,
thats a big one. Um we go and
put flyers you know around the
CS department you know or up on
any boards and stuff that were
there as well as um if there are
still are any existing book
stores in you area [laughter] um
we would put flyers like in you
know Linux journal or you like,
like minded magazines uh and
we’d get people from that as
well. >>Know what? Let, the
frequency of meetings. We forgot
to mention the frequencies of
meetings. Some people have em
for um every month, it’s like
once a month. It’s like uh I’ve
heard some that's had it like
every 2 weeks which is like, I
don't know anybody that would
want to sit here 2 weeks. Um,
but they have those and so some
have em like every quarter. So,
it depends on what kind of
frequency you want to have it,
It’s not, there’s no set
frequency. [coughing] >>Cuh uz
it’s my turn? >>Ya you can go
ahead. >>Okay, okay, okay so,
I'm going to mil- milk that
captioner. I hope everybody here
can survive. Uh I’m I”m I come
from China I’m un I’m let me sit
down kay, I come from china, I
started Def Con group Beijing,
the Def Con group 0100 and uh we
have like a frequently we we
meet very frequently we have
like over uh 200 people every
meeting and uh regarding the
frequency of meetings I think uh
all all the regarding the
competition, I don’t think that
you should compete with other
conference because we are
different, we are unique. Uh,
for example I think the Def Con
group because uh we are so we
are meeting so quite frequently
I don’t think this is contest to
be enough so ver too advanced
too like too complicated to uh
to to uh like new to so ya uh I
think we were are now having
meeting like uh every 3 months
and uh uh a small meetings a uh
uh maybe per month I think
maybe, it just just a few people
and also I have the uh chat
group to discuss some certain
stuff so ya. And uh the
different group I think you the
countenance need to be busy and
the the tech in the audience is
different. The tech in the
audience for our group I think
is more like the college
students anduh like the uh
amateur practitioners. And uh so
it’s different you don't don’t
have to compete with uh other
conferences and uh regarding the
how to get people to come and
the I think that as you are
organizing this event you have
to make this event uh uh
meaningful thing with stuff to
do. So I found it frustrating
when i when uh the attendees is
very interesting the lockpicking
village because uh we have
another version of village so
peoples can discuss uh different
areas like the cryptography, uh
straight printing and other
stuff but uh peoples tend to uh
go to the uh the uh lock picking
village. So I found that's quite
quite frustrating because as a
hacker you need to know the
cryptography, reverse
engineering and the environments
it creates and that stuff. So I
talked is Jayson your uh on the
taxi and uh I found out the
reason that I felt this is
because it’s more like you can
touch it you can feel and touch
it and see the results instantly
so I start to think So I, now
the the next meeting I’m
planning to do uh uh this. I I
build a robot which you can
control via a web interface and
the it’s a robot is connected to
a cloud using uh wifi so you can
do wireless, you can do you can
do web penetration tests at
penetration to control the robot
and finally you can play with my
cat so [laughter]that this turns
the information like uh uh
expertise in ex so you can use
our expertise to get some like
physic feed back so that's how I
can get people’s attention and
then we made all those swags.
Very cool, so they can uh like
when you publicize this kind of
stuff, they can they want it
well they will come so that's
the first time to uh shock them
and see this. >>To the um the
the point about not competing
competing with other entities
uh, us and uh in the bayou down
down in Baton Rouge, we actually
work really close with uh the
local Maker Group and uh we
found that our our disciplines
while different like they’re
more hands on with electronics
and everything, we’re more about
the technical software side of
things. They mesh well so, we
actually share makerspace, we do
presentations there with them,
um there they bring unique um
viewpoints to a lot of the
products that we work on and we
we bring viewpoints, our unique
view points to what they what
they’re working on too. So um,
and it works out well for us so
far. >>So um then I guess uh
next for we’ll kind of go down
the line and quickly talk about
some products that we do I know
Jun Li you already kinda
mentioned a few which sound very
interesting. So I know um just a
few that we’ve done in
Nashville, um you know as Jun Li
mentioned as well, we try to
keep things uh you know
different levels. People that
are just wanting to learn very
basic things, all the way to
having things more advanced for
those who are interested uh, so
we try to consider that. So uh
something fun that we did, uh we
got we all got raspberry pi’s,
built a retro pi. Um, and so you
can see we kinda took it a few
steps further with the wireless
controllers and the uh wireless
keyboard and things like that.
>>That’s hot. >>Ya it’s pretty
cool. It’s pretty sexy, huh?
[Laughter]Ya, you know. So um so
and then, we >>I’m gonna need
the plans for that. [Laughter]
>>Ya, okay. So, those are
actually on our website at DC615
dot org so if you’re interested
in that. Um, >>So that’s how you
join DC 615. [Laughter] or 201.
>>Ya or 201, there ya go. So um
and another thing that we, I
don’t I don’t have a picture of
it but another thing that we did
too with the raspberry pi’s, we
uh implemented the touch screens
and uh taught people how to
install the kali linux distro
and then uh changed the kernel
weren’t where you know where the
touch screen would work with
that. So that was a little bit
more advanced for for uh for
them so that was that was fun.
Uh heres a, this was one of our
very first meetings. Um we also,
this is Ski Boy. Uh Ski Boy’s
awesome if you ever get a chance
to hangout with him, um smart
dude. But, this is and so we
actually uh in Nashville it’s
it’s kinda hard to find places
that are, that are open and you
don’t have to pay a whole lot of
money for so um this I think was
at Chris Scott Cyber Assassin.
He’s a member of our group. Um
he, this was at the clubhouse of
the apartments that he was
staying at downtown and then uh
currently we have uh Dan
Augustine who is at another uh
very nice place downtown and
we’re able to use his clubhouse
and uh it’s furnished and you
know have they have pool tables
and everything too so that’s
that works out. Uh One of the
things we like to focus on too,
if you’re if you’ve never
presented before or you have a
topic that you are that you are
presenting and you want to do a
dry run you know we’ll we’ll
we’ll go through those things as
well. Um our DC615 badge uh, my
batteries actually fell out on
the way over here so. Uh But
yeah the L they LEDS and then we
also have it where you can
program the Arduino and scroll
whatever message you want or you
can make them super bright and
troll people at parties where
they can’t see anymore. >>Not
very cool [laughter] >>Jayson
>>So ya there’s a picture of
that um and then here’s a
picture of of a lot of us
actually spending time soldering
and teaching people how to
solder basic electronics and so
on, so um. Soups, you up? >>Ya
um so this, back to the point
about reaching out to kids, we
uh we go to the uh maker fair
and so this is at the library
every year. Um There’s a bunch
of different groups from around
the area, um and we have a
little booth to kind of display
our projects that we’ve worked
on throughout the year as well
as uh just kind of spread the
word about what, what we do. Um
We do [laughs] we do lockpicking
uh a lot and like you were
saying it’s ikt kind of helps
the whole tactile um aspect of
it. Getting people kind of into
the scene uh helps out alot. You
can go to the next one. Uh ya
this contraption. Um, it’s
actually a remote controlled
Roomba. He hacked it and uses a
controller to actually move it
around, I think he added a
little horn to it as well,. It’s
rather cute. Um I’m not entirely
sure what he’s doing with the
neck and the screen as of yet.
He’s still working on it. Uh, he
actually had an AK47 attached to
it for a little while which is
kind of scary. >>It looks like a
telepresent. >>Ya. He wanted to
put like a a microphone on it so
it’s talk out. I don’t know if
he’s gonna use a megaphone or
what but it’s getting kind of
top heavy right now. [Laughs]
>>Next, next one? >>Yeah, go
ahead. Um We have a really smart
kid, his name uh he he goes by
he goes by Cryo uh and this was
a gameboy that he hacked. He
actually, he actually just found
a couple of vulnerabilities in
some the original Pokemon games
uh that he’s utilized to kind of
do speedy runs but he at one
point hacked a uh little logo on
there for us so. Uh were
actually als also working on, a
couple of years ago we worked
with the Cyberpatriot program
which is an Air Force initiative
to go out to schools and train
um high school students for a
competition that they end up com
competing out throughout the
year and um it works. It works
really well with with the new
initiative that were going on
with Def Con groups is. It
basically gives us an an avenue
to kind of communicate what what
security is and and that hackers
aren’t all bad so. >>Just mostly
>>Most of us. [Inaudible words]
Jayson’s kind of shady
sometimes. >>Um sorry I don't
have pretty pictures cause I'm
I’m a busy person and I don’t
respond to email. Um, [laughter]
the >>That’s true! >>True story.
>>IT is true. It’s fair. You
gotta, you gotta text me, here’s
my number. Um, no. That’s not a
that’s not a thing. uh so ya, so
projects that we work on um DC
801 um do we do a lot of things.
ONe of them probably the
flagship project for us is the
hackerspace in Salt Lake City
which um is called 801 labs. Um
WE uh basically do all of our
projects out of there. That’s
where we have our meetings, so
when we have a meeting it’s it’s
at a hackerspace, Jayson has has
been out there before. Um WE
have a lockpick village, and
tamper evident room, a hardware
hacking room and like all other
kinds of dedicated classroom
where teach each other different
things and were when we do the
DC 801 meetings we have like a
webcam that we stream everything
um to Youtube so when the talks
are done for that month they’re
immediately available online.
>>Did you take that webcam out
of the bathroom finally? >>Uh
no, that one’s still there. The
bathroom webcam will be there
forever. [Laughs] That’s, would
be silly to remove it.
[Laughter] What, what are you
saying down there? Just tell us.
>>Start the Q and A in 3
minutes. >>Start the Q and A in
3 months. Thanks. >>Uh, it’s my
turn? >>Yes. >>Yes it’s your
turn. >>Okay uh I’d like to uh
share with you my how so what’s
we're going to talk about now,
should we talk about now. >>What
are those nanoparts? >>Uh this
this is nano village is way way
waY what they did so because uh
people's interest are different
so I started to like mimic the
Def Cons to like to the nano
version villages so. I put
actually thanks to the support
of my team, these are all my
team’s gadget. This equipment
all come from my team. So the
you as you can see later I let
all the the this. Yes yes.
Actually I I did a talk at uh at
a presentation back at our
hacking car king because I we
have many members in on my team
and their are many differences.
So those those are the speakers
on the the supporters of Um so
yo ucan see ma ma many of them
come from my team and uh the the
places we we meet is in the comp
my companies meeting room so
thanks for the support of my my
supervisor my my- leaders. The
the also, the money come from my
company. Yes Yes so if you want
to find a place you don’t have
to lad clap a because the
conference room or meeting room
in your company most likely is
empty so you can use that as
well. Uh You can see how many
people we have and yes so there
more villages and uh we also
post a video of the the meetings
online so were were we
cooperated with this is online
education uh website. They were
like doing free for us, to
record it and publish it for
free. It’s Integrity a Tech from
from China and uh yes, next one?
Malfunction. [inaudible talking]
>>Yeah. >>Okay hey um so one of
the things we did in the London
group uh is try to make sure
that it’s not um cliquey and
it’s very inclusive to everyone
who comes along. So one of the
first things we do at every
meeting that we’ve done right
from the very beginning is
everybody in in the room
introduces themselves and we get
to know each other um obviously
if you don’t wanna introduce
yourself as your real name or
you work for the man or
something than you make
something up. Um, but that way
you know we get people talking
and we reintegrate the the black
shirt wearing um hackers from
the basements through alcohol
and cuddles and talking so. Um
we concentrate on content so we
don’t do projects together, we
don’t do building um because
we’re in uh [coughing] London
and there aren’t any other
groups in the UK at the moment
uh a lot of people travel from
quite far to come to the meeting
so we have a couple of talks uh
and then you know uh uh
basically we have like an hour
long serious talk where people
are expected to concentrate, and
by the time we get to the second
talk because we’re in a pub um
probably not quite so
concentrated and focused so we
have like a funny wacky talk
usually. something that’s not
necessarily specifically
technically hacking but
something we as a hacking
community would find
interesting. So we’ve had talks
about um you know home home made
torches, how to make a really
bright torch or how to make uh
thermic lance or fireworks or
crap like that so things we
we’ll find quite fun. Um I think
we’re quite keen to get to Q and
A so I won’t take up anymore of
your time. >>[inaudible talking]
>>Waz? Waz is doing something
else man he doesn’t care.
>>Actually you have a lot more
time. >>Oh [laughs] >>Eff
[laughter] >>I would like >>NOw
he tells us >>I would like, I
would like to add one more
thing. Uh uh regard uh as Jayson
has said that we should go to
the remote areas to teach the
kids to start uh in the the to
know what they they can do, so
I’m planning to like bring my
Def Con group to the remote
areas to teach the kids the
basic stuff. How to [inaudible]
electronics, how a computer
works, [inaudible] I think that
would be meaningful if you guys
want to do it with me I thinks
it will be better so ya. Oh, I
named this Def Con hacker tour
but Jays, Jeff said that you
should add it geroup so I I name
it like Def Con group hacker
tour. So wha uh actually uh to
deal with the government it’s
very hard so I got to kind of
support of my company’s my
colleagues, they are deal they
usually they are very good at
dealing with them so they uh all
uh actually there alrady
projects that uh where the
anyways for the schools to teach
the kids so I would a corporate
them to go to the uh remote
areas so that was to dealing
with the government or the
police won’t be a problem for
me. >>Very good. Any questions?
>>Ask them to come upfront.
>>What? Huh? >>Ask [inaudible
words] >>Ya. If you, if you have
some questions for us, if you
could if you could come up here
when you ask the question.
There’s a purpose for that I I
promise it’s not >>Cause we want
to put you on the spot so come
on up. >>No pies in the face,
promise. >>But I wanna I wanna
ask a question first. Can you
please raise your hand if you’re
already currently in a Def Con
group? That’s awesome, very
cool. >>That’s not enough
though. >>How many people want
to get into a Def Con group now
that they’ve been to this panel?
EVen better! Awesome. [coughing]
okay Yes. >>So uh I’ve tried to
start a Def Con group locally
and I’m just waiting, I haven't
gotten any response from like my
submission and so I’m like
scared to move forward with like
buying swag and advertising and
stuff like that cause I need to
ensure I’m not going to like,
>>When, when >>You don’t need
permission hack the system just
do it. >>Exactly. When did you
send it out? >>Mid May. >>Oh.
[Laughter] Then you should've
gotten a response. [Laughter]
>>Okay >>You’re in the right
spot for an answer for that
though now. >>That’s why I’m
here. >>There you go. Awesome.
>>It went in the black hole.
>>Yup. The the man right there
next to you, is the guy who to
talk to about getting that uh
taken care of immediately.
>>Thanks. >>Awesome. Yes? >>Hey
guys, >>Hey. >>um what do you
guys do about uh finances? Do
you collect fees or do you take
donations >>Oh that’s a great
question. >>for that or? >>Um
>>I’m not gonna answer it. >>Ya
I I can take that one off so um
there’s a uh when we first
started we had a a company um
that was owned by a friend of
mine and he actually uh I guess
sponsored to some extent and so
uh for some groups he would send
money and basically buy food
like pizza and then beer if we
wanted it and then uh when we
sort of moved it into a more
technical direction, you know
for like raspberry pi’s and
things so that’s that’s always
an option. >>Um, we actually do
the opposite. We try and not to
get money. We have to refuse it
from the the venue um so we’re
in the basement of a pub and
Tuesday nights were a dead night
for them and now we bring over
100 people in once a month and
those people drink and eat and
the normal um marvel if you’re
like a comedy club or something
and you're in those venues, you
either charge at the door or you
take a a percentage of the take
at the bar and so when we
started bringing in money on the
Tuesday night, the the the pub
came to us and said okay so um
now you’ve reached the level we
should give you a percentage and
we decided um that it would just
complicate things. we would then
have this pool of cash that we
then have something to do with
so unless it was a very clear
what do we do with this money, I
didn’t want to pollute the the
ethic of it being just a
free open thing uh with money so
we just say no thanks but.
>>Thank you. >>Yes >>Actually
the the the the money from my
Def Con group has come from my
company and uh the the the
resources I use for example the
[inaudible] I use, come from my
team. So I convinced my [laughs]
leaders to to support me. I
don’t think that the uh by like
taking money from company can
like uh pollute the the the the
free environment because uh
aztec and steel like corporates
other with other companies. I
invite them to to join us but uh
as long as you can get this down
and uh I think it’s it’s it’s
good because uh the attendees
will if you want to come way
there's like no obstacles for
them for them to come. I think
that’s a good thing. And the
company that does till now they
didn’t they didn’t require
anything from me ha atleast.
Yes. >>We did bake sales. >>Oh.
[Laughter] >>Alligator muffins.
>>Woooh! [Laughter] >>Uh so for
meeting twice a month how much
work do you think would
typically be involved for
meeting twice a month for a Def
Con group? >>Um I think it
depends on how uh for so if I
were to meet twice a month uh I
would look at all different
options. So we have uh we
regularly have now that we built
the um the retro pi’s we always
have like vintage games or
lockpicking for people that just
want to come and hangout, of
we’ll just throw together
something uh like an older um
older system and some wifi and
do some wifi hacking basics or
just put planning if you want to
do a bigger project I think it
just depends on the maybe the
technical maturity of the group
or the ones that be would be
attending on a regular basis so
I think that sort of depends on
just the the atmosphere and
those who attend. >>Uh I did a
um uh uh 2 meeting uh 2 month
meeting, uh 2 meetings a month
uh group and what we did was we
had the first meeting of the
month was a social meeting.
There were no talks on hacking
or anything like that it was
just people showing up and
actually interacting with each
other and having to talk and get
to know what's going on and just
you know shoot the breeze and
actually in a nice social
setting uh usually at a
restaurant or something.
Everybody would just get
together and socialize and then
the second meeting of the month
would be the technical meeting
where we would actually have
projects, we would have someone
giving a talk, or it’s like we
would all do like a capture the
flag. it would be an actual
technical meeting so it’s like
you have one social and then one
technical uh to sort of balance
it out. >>Ya. >>So those are two
good options. >>I would I would
also give the advice that if you
are going to do 2 meetings a
month that and actually this
goes for even if you’re just
going to have 1 meeting a month,
like uh you can’t rely on just
one person to run everything
like if you have like 1 person
that is the point of contact for
the meeting or the group or
whatever and and like they have
to go on vacation or go on an
engagement for work or something
like that and it falls apart
every time they’re not available
um that’s not good for the
group. So you have to have at
like at least 2 if not more
members who are willing to say
like yeah we should get some
talks together, I’ll talk to so
and so, that kind of thing. >>Ya
uh something that we to sort of
prevent that too is we make sure
to let everyone in the group
know like hey there’s no like
you know one you know single
power in this group, like this
is a group. So if you have an
idea or a project you wanna do
just get it ready let us know if
we need to get supplies and just
bring your idea or if you have a
talk just let us know and just
bring it. Uh that way it’s not
like Grifter said it’s not
dependant on one person. >>Uh
would it be too hokey to do a
quick 30, 45 second picture of
our group? >>What, what >>What?
>>Def Con 201. >>Where, where is
201? >>North Jersey. >>North
Jersey? >>So do it? Okay. Uh ya
were Def Con 201 uh in NOrth
Jersey about a 7 minute train
ride outside of New York City,
um sorta similar to some to what
some of these guys were saying
we are a lucky hybrid mashup of
an already existing hacker
space, and also the strong
infosec community in New York
city so we have a hole range of
people from Nubes to people who
are Def Con OG’s and have spoken
several times. We do a lot of 3D
printing and ticker typical
hackerspace stuff. But we're
also trying to set up some CTF
servers and we always have uh
infosec talks. Um we meet every
third Friday and we have pretty
consistently for the past 6
months and we just had our first
month with a second meeting and
it was like you said, uh we
redesigned the website. I’m
actually trying to get the IT
guy, this is admin guy to uh
deploy that while uh I’m here
now um but if anyone is in the
New York City oh we we we get
members coming in from very far
too even though there’s a robust
community there uh all the way
from Long Island some people we
have one dude who actually comes
in from Philly uh if anybody’s
in that area, in the New York
city or North Jersey area raise
your hand or let me know I”ll
give you the info. >>Um
[inaudible words] >>Now you’re a
Def Con speaker. [Laughter]
[Applause] >>Congratulations.
[Applause] Um, [inaudible word]
>>Do you guys have any um tips
and suggestions for when you’re
in more of a rural area uh we
have a very small 2600 group and
you’ve mentioned that you kinda
split off from 2600 groups but
do you also kind of encourage
collaboration with or maybe even
overlapping with? >>Ya
definitely incorp collaboration
there like I said there’s no
competition and and also the
other thing is like one of the
things you can do uh if you got
uh uh a rural Def Con group is
making sure that you're doing uh
a chat system. It’s like uh
doing a Slack Channel or uh
having some kind of interaction
on the forums or like facebook
profile where you can like take
pictures and share message and
actually maybe invite speakers
to skype in from other
locations. It’s like reach out
to different speakers and
different people and say hey can
you skype in and and do a
meeting for us? >>Ya and I think
also um so if something for for
Utah, one of the things that we
do because there are so many
other organizations, we have
like this umbrella organization,
we call it Utah Sec so like I am
the point of contact through
DC801 for Utah Sec and then
there’s like infragard and the
snort user group and like so
every meeting like saint con
they all have someone who
represents them um and get
together and kind of talk about
like oh hey you were gonna do a
talk this month, this way like
the content that gets shared at
those meetings normally only
once can get spread among a
larger group and usually that
means some cross pollination as
well so if you wanna get
additional members I’d encourage
like going to some of the other
meetings like I Sock or ISSA
meetings and things like that
that are in the area and then
being like we wanna do a Def Con
group. >>Well the thing is is
our our area is so rural that we
don’t have much of a tech field
but we we know they’re hiding in
the woodworks and we’re trying
to drag them out through having
a 2600 and or a Def Con group.
>>Mmm >>Smoke em out. >>That’s
what we’re trying to do. So, ya
if you have any tips on on
bringing those people out of the
woodwork in such a rural area
that doesn’t normally have
technology in the forefront,
that’s very helpful. >>And you
don’t always have to do like
high like technical things at
the gr at the meet up too it
could just be like Jayson said
the one that they did it it was
just hanging out getting to know
you know like minded people or
even uh you know teaching
lockpicking or you know vintage
video games or something just to
start building that community,
and then from there somebody
might have an idea or something
for a project so. >>That’s
great. Thank you very much.
>>Sure Thank you. >>And just one
quick second I want to remind
everybody about the DCG mixer.
Come meet the Def Con Groups
organizers after their talk on
Friday this Def Con groups mixer
is for all who were or who want
to members of local Def Con
groups. Come to get info, meet
peers and get some DCG swag
they’ll be a limited amount of
free beer via kegs courtesy of
The Dark Tangent. So that’s what
he was doing, he was getting the
kegs ready so thank you for
that. Where? the Chill Out
Lounge Promenade Level. When?
1800 to 20, 100. Friday which is
today so. >>Get it while you
can. >>Hope to see you there.
>>Ya it it’s I think it’s starts
like right at 6 o'clock but so
>>Don’t tell em that because
there’s free beer they’ll leave.
>>Ya so from here so come come
hangout with us and uh have some
free drinks and whatever. >>So
yes >>uh Okie dokie so uh mocal
Def Con chapter has been around
for quite a while but
unfortunately activity oin us
has been kinda slow because uh
our past uh let’s say let’s say
uh council has had to take off
due to family and other
professional or or uh
obligations decided to leave and
we’re trying to jump start it
back up at the moment but I was
just kinda curious as to how you
would if you got if you all had
any uh no not just a panel but
anyone else has also had like uh
scheduling conflict issues, when
you’re trying to get the group
but not but not everyone’s able
to participate due to like needs
being needs that go beyond it.
>>JUst you gotta, oh man
microphone You just gotta you
gotta >>It’s truly important to
have a regular um date, you just
have to pick one and stick with
it. I mean we meet the last
Tuesday of the month >>Ya you
gotta pick something >>and
that’s not right for everyone
but nothing’s going to be right
for everyone so. >>Exactly. As
as long as it’s consistent. If
you move it around then you’ll
just lose people all the time
and then the numbers dwindle.
Like just say like okay it’s
going to be this day every month
and leave it there. >>CAuse
people will start planning for
it then. So the other thing is
make sure you announce. We find
um we we like everyone we’re
busy, lazy, useless and uh
[laughter] if the the months
where we announce at least a
week in advance, we get a much
bigger attendance and there’s
even regulars just forget okay
always oh it’s that Tuesday
again d****t. I would’ve come
but I arranged this other thing
and did things so um if we had
announced a week earlier and
reminded them they would've kept
the time free um so you know
give good information and be
consistent. >>Heck yeah thank
you very much. [coughing] >>Yes?
>>Hi just to comment back on
your internet safety uh IAC
Squared has a safe and secure
online. Uh There’s like 2 tracks
for like elementary middle
school, there’s also another one
for seniors. Vetting you know
work with the teachers, and I
mean they’ve got a format made
where you can take advantage of
[inaudible words] >>We wouldn’t
mind taking a look at it ya it’s
like we don’t want it to be
corporate you know because IAC
squared but uh we we’d want to
do that little hacker edge to it
but ya that’s actually a good
resource to we’ll steal from I
mean borrow I mean uh uh look
at. [Laughs] >>We’re not
competing. >>Cool. >>Thank you.
>>Thank you. >>Thank you. >>So I
was wondering when setting woah,
when I’m setting up a space for
this and working it out, when
you get the especially the
teenage kids, maybe younger
kids, how do you even you know
cover yourself if they go do
something nefarious? >>Um
>>Unfortunately you know I don’t
think you can control everybody
so >>Just >>No I mean we we
don’t >>Just don’t attack any of
them and then it’s pretty solid.
>>You just always remind em it’s
like Law enforcement as is is
invited and welcomed to these
meetings as anybody else so uh
don’t do shady stuff at the
meetings. [Laughs] It’s like.
>>[inaudible talking] >>But you
know if like myself or a few
others you know if I’m in charge
of it they have a tendency to
come after those people if they
do something bad so. >>don't
have one person in charge.
>>Okay >>Yeah >>Okay. >>Yeah
>>Thank you >>Hi um I’m pow from
uh DC 170 from >>HI Pow! >>Hi!
[Laughter] >>We are the I think
are the first Def Con group in
Spain we are based in Barcelona
and one thing we do there's uh
every year we host a security
conference uh we made it the
people uh for our Def Con group
and uh I want to officially
invite the all all of the other
Def Con groups to attend to this
conference cause I think it will
be a it will be cool like to
meet everybody from other Def
Con groups and make a community
there in Spain. In Spain uh
computer security community is
just starting so that’s it I I
just want to invite you. Uh
WE’ll we’l hose a conference in
September but we do it every
year >>Nice >>and Grifter is
coming to speak >>Very cool
>>and if you want more
information want to join us uh
reach me, I will be around uh
and just for sake uh we can help
the speakers and attendees uh
for hosting them and everything.
>>Uh I’ve been to Barcelona,
it’s beautiful city yeah Good
place to go. >>Thank you >>Thank
you >>Thank you >>That was it
guys uh thank you for sticking
out uh hopefully [applause] you
go to the mixer and we’ll wait
for one per question right here.
Yes? [applause] Oops. [laughs]
>>Okay >>You snuck up on me.
>>Um uh just one question um uh
I intend to create a group for a
region rather than one country,
>>Right. >>So um apparently you
use the area code or my country
code for this >>Right. >>So how
would I do that? >>Uh what’s the
region? Uh oh you uh the
question was he wants to start a
Def Con group for a region so
like several countries not just
one country. Uh What region is
it? >>Uh I was gonna suggest Def
Con GCC. Which is Gulf
Cooperation Council. >>Okay um
that is interesting um the we
will have to take that one
>>That’s a thinker >>offline and
look at it >>That’s a thinker
>>because uh I don’t have an
answer uh and I’m just gonna
hymn and hall a little bit until
ya >>Give you a little bit of
background um I don't I don’t
remember when I started
attending this Def Con whether
it was the second one or third
one, um I stopped in 2011 then I
came back now um it’s much
better than what uh I was uh
expecting. >>Oh very cool. >>Uh
uh I’m the ex german of coit IT
Society my back on this can be
dealt uh so I’ve done a lot but
uh why I’m doing for the region
because I believe that um not
having one group uh is much
better than having uh multiple
groups. >>Well it it depends
it’s like we’ll definitely go
offline like cause it’s like it
all depends. it’s like i would
suggest like having it like mult
having each one for each country
it’s like re and then just
having a group meeting in the
different regions but we’ll talk
about that offline. >>Eventually
the entire region will be one.
>>Ya okay. Well thank you very
much. It's like uh once again
guys thanks for sticking it out,
really appreciate it [applause]
and [applause].