>>Alright, so um, before we get
started I just want a quick show
of hands. So, how many of you
out there [laughter], yeah there
we go see so quick show of hands
how many of you out there have
done any kind of ethical or you
know wink wink unethical hacking
of financial applications? Any
kind at all. Alright, okay good
yeah. So yeah, I- I've been
focused on these things for like
13 years and um I've seen some
really crazy stuff. Um so now
out of you guys who've done that
how many of you have thought
that the code was so beautiful,
so flawless [laughter] that it
didn't need even the slightest
bit of human intervention you
know once it rolled out of the
dones list right everyone right
yeah sure yeah. So, now imagine
for a moment that that financial
code couldn't be changed, you
know once you put it out there,
it's just, it's out there. So if
it has any huge gaping flaws or
anything that's the way it's
gonna stay for eternity ha. So,
that's sort of what goes on in
the world of smart contracts,
okay. Uh, there's no updates,
there's no patches, there's no
revisions, there's ways to point
to other programs but once you
put it on the block chain by
it's nature the block chain is
this immutable thing right. So,
if this codes expected to move
money around forever on it's
own, it probably needs a little
more attention than the usual
financial apps you might have
looked at in the past, so that's
why this is an important field.
And uh, we're sorta getting in
on the ground floor still here.
Um, think about if you had gone
to a web app hacking talk around
the year 2000, you know, that's
the idea here, this is very new
to a lot of folks. So I'm gonna
try and you know, ease everyone
into it. So, I want everyone to
be able to get something out of
this talk, so no I'm not going
to just explain how bitcoin
works, that, that, that's silly
but [laughs] I assume you guys
know that. But, but, I'm just
going to explain some of the
quick differences and what makes
ethereum, different, better, um
and a lot more useable in terms
of uh things like smart
contracts. So everyone's aware
of bitcoin, yeah we know that,
so, sit osha met his goals
right, he wanted to have the
whole uh distributed ledger to
avoid double spend, you know
have have the computational
proof of work to make this thing
actually be of some value. And,
and some ultraistic goals cause
half the world doesn't have a
bank or access to a bank so now
thanks to bitcoin they do. But
with ethereum we've got
something different going on,
you know, uh it takes the idea a
little further. Creates this,
this idea about turning a
complete system. Uh, the ebn the
few virtual machines runs over
the entire globe, this one big
mega computer that you can
access and do things with. So,
it can save state, um it can
detect changes to info, it can
remember them um it can
intelligently handle
interactions between users, uh
control flow programming. Uh, so
it can run smart contracts,
which is why we're talking about
it. You know, there are some
companies building smart
contract like features over the
bitcoin, uh network, but it's
not quite the same thing. So,
what's a smart contract? You
know real simply? So, it's a
program right it consists of uh
business, business logic, it
runs on the black chain, uh it's
semi-autonomous, you know you
can think of it as this thing
that just runs on it's own,
which sometimes doesn't really
bring comfort to anyone
[laughs]. Um, so it can move
out, we can enforce agreements,
uh it can remove repetitive
labor which everyone's all for,
but again it cannot be patched,
I can't stress this enough. But
it is important to really take a
look at this code before you put
it live. An-And reality you're
limited by creativity you know
you can make escrow systems that
hold money in place when it
checks returns, uh you can
create new tokens. Uh people
think about tokens as like just
extra coins, but, you've been
using tokens all your lives,
i-if you have frequent flyer
miles, for example, that's kinda
like a token, like unlimited set
usage, so smart contracts lets
you create ones that have
purpose like that. Um, it can
handle real estate records, uh
you know if a country has an
unstable government, a smart
contract will prove you own
something, uh, enforcing its
another matter but you can at
least prove intentionally
[laughs]. Uh, it can do things
like pay people when work is
done, um trust funds, wills. You
can even imagine something like
airbnb or uber without the
company behind it. You know you
can have these smart contracts
negotiating for people, uh so no
one takes a cut when you take a
drive or when you stay in
someone's room, it's kind of a
neat idea. So, why should we
look at smart contract security?
Well I could literally think of
a billion reasons [laughs]. Uh,
if everyone remembers the DAO
which was a little over a year
ago, uh basically, um it was an
essential as the time as
operation and organization. It
was designed to operate like a
venture capital fund letting you
move money in and out. Um, a
flow was found in May 2016, and
no one really did anything about
it and June 17, a hacker used
the recursive law which were
going to look at in detail. To
make splits inside of splits,
and keep syphoning money out and
array-erase condition without
checking the balance. So 3.6
million ether was stolen but at
the time they were reporting
accurately that it was you know
a decent amount of money. But,
if you look at how ether has
gone as high as 400, or 3
something at times, uh you know
it's pretty much if it happened
today it would be close to a
billion dollar hack. So, that
would definitely make even
bigger news than it did a year
ago. Smart contract security is
not going away, it's not a
problem that's you know last
summer [laughs]. It's something
that's very much going to affect
the future. And what's funny is
I'll show you how you can
prevent similar left like that
with just switching two lines of
code as as we'll get to. So uh
more recently we had another
smart contract attack, so 30
million reasons are good to. Um,
basically, parity was hit, and
uh there was a multi sig wallet
that allowed people to swipe 32
million dollars from a few
ICO's. Um, it's another
ridiculously simple flaw that
we're gonna look at in this
talk. But, the idea is there,
you know people inves- put so
much money into these things,
and they have them be
responsible for so many critical
assets, that to code them poorly
is just not acceptable in this
day and age. So, um quick
caveat, there's no zero days
here, you know uh you can't
always easily identify where the
first time something was
discovered, we're gonna be
talking about like I said,
imagine you go into web net
hacking talk like around the
year 2000, I'm going to try to
introduce as much as I can in
this time about what you should
be looking for. Uh, there's no
customer code that's going to be
shared, I haven't shared
customer code you know
accidentally in 13 years, I'm
not starting today. So, you're
not gonna see anything from like
real engagements, I'm gonna use
like sanitized examples and
things like that. Uh, but this
about generating methodology,
you know I-I want you guys to be
able to go out there and try and
get involved in this uh
especially if you take a little
time learning the solidity which
we'll get to in a sec. And uh
no, I don't think smart
contracts are that smart, I
don't think they're going to
like take over the world or
anything, so you know, there's
always that fear like I-I'm sure
it must've come up in the talk I
just missed, ha. Um yeah,
they're smart but not really
that smart. No mega fears here.
Okay, so solidity. Uh, this is
the programming language, ominus
ethereum like looking uh symbol
there for solidity uh so it's
the one that won out, okay um
you don't need to program
solidity to do smart contracts,
but this is the one that
everyone settled on. Uh it beat
out serpin, uh which is a little
bit like python, uh list black
language, bluetongue, uh it's
high level, human readable, it's
kinda pretty in it's own way I
guess. It has some syntax
similarities to uh javascript
and c so if you have any of that
in your background you know,
maybe you'll take to solidity
quite well. Um and when you
write this code, it compiles to
uh ebm bycode. So, it's
statically typed, uh it supports
libraries, inheritance, complex
user fine types. Uh, it's it's
pretty fancy. Uh, honestly, I
can't teach you how to code in
solidity, in this 45 minute
talk, that, that would be kinda
crazy. Uh, so we're gonna focus
on the general types of
vulnerabilities you should be
looking for, and uh maybe you
can rewatch this video if you
don't know solidity after you
learn it, that's a possibility
too. Um, so it's in high demand
right now, uh I think it's worth
taking the time to learn.
There's a book coming out next
week, Ethereum Programming, that
actually looks pretty good to
me, so, I think, I think some
folks might find it useful. Uh,
if you learn solidity, you'll be
like the tenth person to do so,
so congratulations to you
[laughter] [laughs] yeah, we
definitely need more. Um, so
ethical hacking of solidity is
is usually part of the dev
process. Alright, think of it as
a typical code review, um, so
sol files, dot sol files of
solidity, they get compiled and
they run on test block chains,
uh then on private or public
ones depending um so the
customer other environment could
differ greatly. So, you're gonna
have to definitely talk to the
devs about what's going on if
you're working with this. So,
Matt Squeeze yesterday, uh I
don't know if he's here but, he
gave a great talk on his tool
porosity, and uh that tools kind
of interesting cause it lets you
pull from the blockchain and get
back solidity code. Uh, that's
not what we're going to be
looking at here, uh here we're
going to be having the solidity
files handed to us up front,
just like you would have any
other code review. So, that's
the sort of approach we're
taking here. So, the first step
is definitely a look at the
solidity files before they go
down that process. Um, a good
way to do that is to have an
IDE, uh there's a lot of options
available, um my favorites atom,
you can actually get little
plugins for that. And using it
you can actually have
highlighting and um it can even
test compiling which is pretty
cool using etheratom. Uh realmix
ID, uh ID is kinda neat, it's
browser based, let's you try and
compile code and see if it
errors out. So that's, that's
useful too. Okay, and yeah emax
can have plugins too, I don't
want to start like a religious
war, but it they do [laughter].
[laughs], alright, So, while
you're still learning solidity,
uh I find it useful to run a
parser like solgraph, um, it's
not a bad way to look at code
even when you know solidity too.
It takes a sol file and it
outputs a dot graph, that
actually let's you visualize the
function, the flow, so it sorta
like walks you through how the
code works, just so you can get
that big picture view before you
even get started looking for the
little nit picky things. Um, so
there's another one called
solidity parser coming that
looks promising too. Uh, so
these kinds of things are just
aids, visual aids, cause,
sometimes code just becomes you
know mind numbing after a while.
Um, so a real awesome tool that
came out awhile ago was oyente
and it got both better and like
sort of worse, I-I'll explain
that. Uh so it's a symbolic
execution tool, um it's designed
to analyze your smart contracts
um, it follows the execution of
contracts and what's cool is it
can actually reach out and
analyze contracts that are on
the blockchain. You know, you
don't have to just work with
solidity files. Uh, no, it
doesn't give you back a solidity
document like um veracity would,
but it actually could still step
through the ones that are out on
the blockchain. But uh in this
case we'll be talking about
pointing it to locally uh stored
files. So, it detects three
valid issues, and um one sort of
invalid one. So call stack
basically, the call stack attack
which we'll talk about later, um
it hasn't really been valid
since eip 150. Um, but it also
detects concurrency bug or
transaction order dependence, um
time dependency attacks and
reentrancy which is the big DAO
attack so that, that's an
important one and it's pretty
accurate, I mean it looks like
it has less than 10 percent
false positives based on other
people's data and my testing
too. Uh it's just a little
tricky to set up so I'm warning
you in advance. It complains
about versions, it wants you to
use old versions of things, and
then you have to do all that
crazy stuff, specially linux
forcing of origin. But if, if
you want my honest opinion, you
can just use the latest version
get a few error messages and
most of the time it just works
anyways, so don't worry about it
[laughs], so just use the newest
versions of everything. Um, so
to that end, we're looking at
hopefully getting a basic
methodology in place. So, so
whenever you start one of these,
the best thing to do is to talk
to the devs you know, uh, if you
come from an app testing
background, uh, like, like I do,
you know, um, you'll find that
kick off calls you know who
really likes kickoff calls right
there like the worst. And and
most of the times it's people
explaining something to you as
if you haven't seen it 100 times
before. Uh when it comes to uh,
smart contracts, take the
kickoff call, because sometimes
there's a really unique or novel
thing they're trying to do.
Again, we're in the infancy
here. So, you definitely want to
talk to the devs in these type
of uh hacks. Uh, they can share
a lot of you, useful info uh,
what does the contract do, you
know, what environment is
required for testing, these are
all important things, especially
if there's any kind of like
private or permission blotching
it has to talk to. Um, so think
along the lines of threat
modeling at first, you have to
kind of understand the
application a little bit. Um,
then after that you're going to
want to plug it into something
like atom, remix ID, take a look
at it with highlighting, really
understand if, if everything's
okay, compiling it, making sure
it doesn't error out, maybe the
wrong version, you know. Get
that silly kind of housekeeping
out of the way first. Uh, but
then after that you're gonna
wanna start to dissect the code
flow, you're gonna want to read
any comments under there, um use
something like solgraph to
understand it. You're gonna want
to run oyente, and cross your
fingers that it doesn't error
out and it might, it often does.
Um, and then you're gonna want
to verify that the three that
are real are there or not if you
find them, but of course you're
gonna want to look at in
manually too. And then uh you're
gonna want to check for the
types of things that we're gonna
talk about now, in the meat of
the presentation hmm. Alright,
so, because of how popular the
DAO hack is, uh we're gonna,
we're gonna start with this. Um,
so I'm not gonna be dumping all
the DAO code here because I-I
don't even think these screens
are big enough uh and you sure
wouldn't be able to read it, so
what I'm gonna do is show how
reentrancy works with a really
simplified sample that I coded
here um and I call it reentrancy
what an original name for a
contract and I'm just gonna show
the basic idea. So, solidity is
read sequentially by the evn
okay, so reentrancy can happen
if the amount transferred on a
contract depends on a balance or
state that's updated after the
transfers made. So, because it's
done sequentially, where you do
your accounting is very
important. Where you tell the
program what all the values are.
So, in our vulnerable code
snippet you can see the
expendable tokens balance, it's
set to zero at the very end, so,
so the line I highlighted there
with the little explosion.
That's where the dangerous send
or, or of money can go out and
after that, it's set to zero.
So, if you could somehow
repeatedly invoke this function,
oops, sorry about that, slipped
there. Um, if you could somehow
repeatedly invoke this function,
you'll end up pulling the money
out before it's set to zero,
over and over and over and over
again. And something like that
is what happened in the DAO. So,
let's see if we can't take some
of this uh re out of entrancy,
you know. If you were to
instead, switch lines 7 and 8,
so now the exploding line does
the accounting first, then if
any other contract or whatever
was try, tried to pull from the
if scape right there, the
money's already zeroed out. You
know, it's setup it's a one time
thing, and it's not gonna go
anywhere. This accounting move
means token balances are taken
care of early. So, even though
this is tremendously simplified,
uh the idea is that such a small
little change can prevent a
billion dollars from being
stolen in a race condition. It's
it's all comical right? You just
don't see stuff like this in any
other kind of programming. But
it really is that simple. So,
understanding that, we'll just
jump out of here for a second,
we'll do a quick, quick demo,
see if the demo gods are smiling
on us today, alright, okay. So,
this is on extended display so
it might be hard to control here
but uh if you can see that. So,
basically, uh, sorry about that,
I can't see if it moved, okay,
alright, so, we have a simple
program like the one I just
talked about where there is a
reentrancy condition present.
Okay, so if you can see it
there, the balance is being
zeroed out in the last line, if
you can make that out. So, if I
were to run oyente against this,
I should be able to get it to
flag the reentrancy file. So,
I'll just do that real quick.
I'll set it up and I'll execute
it, alright, okay, so once we
hit enter, it should run, did
it? [laughs] awe come on man
[laughs], alright hang on a sec.
[laughter]. [laughs], I'm a bit
of a comedian because of course
it doesn't show the password.
Alright, so, so, it's running,
and it shows the uh, the true
condition to the reentrancy
button. So, it could run pretty
simply uh because of this
extended situation, I'm not
gonna run the next part but, I
was gonna show you how
ironically a bit of code that
the developers wrote now errors
out in oyente which is kind of
comical because it's their
sample code. But this one
actually successfully ran and
showed you so you'd be able to
go in and say why is it there
and then you can make a tweak if
need be. Alright, so I'll just
get that out of the way. Okay
and we're back, okay so after
seeing that, you should be able
to spot it pretty simply in a
snippet of actual DAO code
right? So if you look here, it
should be pretty obvious,
because they're doing the
withdrawal function first,
without doing all the accounting
that follows afterwards, it's
possible for a reentrance for a
race condition to occur. And
it's possible to keep hitting
that red line over and over and
over again and draining the
balances down to zero. So,
that's the basic idea of
reentrancy, you just have to
watch the careful ordering of
the outpatient. So, what just
happened last week with parity
wallet, um is interesting cause
Gavin Wood, the guy that wrote
parity wallet is one of the four
developers of solidity, so for
him to make this kind of mistake
was kind of embarrassing on an
epic level ha, you know, ha so
uh you know uh sorry about that
Gavin, but it but it really was.
So, the company basically tries
to do browser based access to
ethereum to try and bring it
more into use- usability. Um, he
wrote a multi sig wallet and it
in theory multi sig sounds
great, right? Multi signature,
extra security, the only problem
is solidity, there's something
called uh visibilities. So
functions have visibilities, uh,
in the case of functions the
visibilities could be public,
internal, external, or private.
The problem is if you don't
declare them specifically,
they're by default gonna be
public. So, if they're public
that means it could be called
internally or externally, by
anyone via message. So, that's
not what you want ideally in
code, um so you could see in
pink how in the original version
of the code, there was no
declaration made. Uh, in green
you can see how they were
changed to internal, of course
that happened after a whole lot
of money was stolen. So.
alright, so the attackers could
send a message calling the uh,
it might be a little hard to see
this, but the attackers could
send a message calling the
public init wallet, and that
function will override the
original owner addresses with
their own. Um, so the attacker
is then able to wrap that
function call and pass in his
own, or her own eth address as
the new owner. So, in that first
step you say hey, this wallets
mine, and then with just another
simple request, um, you can use
the execute function, and when
that happens, your private key
is used to sign an outgoing
transfer for the balance of the
account. Uh, if you do this,
rinse and repeat for 3 major
ICO's, you get 30 million
dollars for your effort, not bad
for a day's work, right? Not too
bad at all ha. So, interestingly
enough we used the term race
condition before, uh, here this
became a human race condition,
because a group called the white
hat hacker group, uh they
noticed this too, and noticed it
was going on, so they quickly
went in and started stealing the
money from um people who hadn't
been attacked yet, from accounts
and things that hadn't been
attacked yet and they syphoned
off if you add everything up
about 200 million dollars and
moved it to a wallet to protect
it from this attack until it's
code was patched. Uh, but only a
few people have gotten the money
back so far [laughter], soooo,
you know, they, they promised by
the 31st but uh the white hat
hacker group if they don't come
through, that, that name is just
gonna suck [laughter]. You know
they're gonna, they're gonna
have to come up with a different
one [laughs] so. So, another,
another popular attack was
uncheck send. Um, it, it was
first discovered in kind of a
goofy game, uh but it's still
worth talking about, now, you'll
find this kind of thing in
ethereum a lot, uh in the early
days of solidity, people would
make these silly games, almost
like ponzi schemes uh or, or a
digital chain letter, in the
blockchain if you will. You know
that's what they went for. So,
the idea was to uh claim a
prize, so, you would submit
let's say one ethe to a game
like this, and that would make
you King of the ether. Now, back
then, one ethe was worth like
nothing, now it would be like
handing over 200 bucks but uh so
you hand over this ethe and
you're now king of the ether, so
for someone to dispose you,
they'd have to pay 1 point 5
ethe, the contract creator gets
a little dig off of that, and
then, you get the rest of the
money, so you get paid, kind of
like a chain letter to be bumped
out of the process then the next
person pays more, and the next
person pays more. So, if it's
all fair, it's a way to just
keep throwing money for, I have
no idea why, [laughs] but they,
that's that's the way the game
works. So, games like this, um
you're sending using the keyword
send, and it acts like a method
that's uh defined for every
address object, but send can
fail, it's not foolproof. So
ether stored in uh either
externally on contracts, uh, uh
accounts, controlled by human or
in contract accounts, um and
these are controlled by a
contract, like that's why
they're called contract
accounts. Um, metropolis version
of ethereum is gonna kind of
abstract this, but anyway. So,
in a contract account you can
have a generalized error that um
would cause it to fail. That's
basically what happened. Uh,
because anytime a contract like
that was called, an error would
occur, a new person would become
monarch but the old person would
not get their money. So, if you
had been expecting to get 2.5
ethe or whatever at that point,
you got zip and now the new
person was king and you were out
2.5 ethe. So again, it's a goofy
game, it's not really serious
but this kind of ability for
send to fail is dangerous if
you're talking about you know
millions of dollars or something
like that. So, it's important to
look for. So, rather than go
into the whole long remediation
code and the king of ether, I
just whipped up something a
little easier to hopefully to
understand. Um, so over here you
can see uh the top code snippet
it's called king of losing cause
ultimately like what's the point
of this game right? Ha,but uh so
if send fails,over here the
winner doesn't get the money.
Uh, the compensation sent will
be set to true, again, it's the
order that got you in solidity,
the order of operations here.
So, if there's a fail, it says
that that person got paid, but
they actually never did,that's
why at the top there it says
compensation sent is true. Now,
again, it can fail if it's a
contract that generates some
kind of error, or some other
kind of condition occurs. So to
protect the price from being
sent into the you know ether, um
you can have it do a check, like
on the bottom, um you can have
it do an if check where, if it's
not actually sent, there'll be
some kind of thrown error. Now
uh, uh a thing about throw as
we'll see in a moment, it's
being deprecated uh there's
other forms of validation that
I'll, I'll talk about in a
moment, but uh throw is just
easiest to show in a slide like
this. Alright, so back to um
what was going on with king of
ether, those contracts were
failing because they uh ran out
of gas, you know. Uh, it, it,
it's a funny thing about um gas,
so miners are incentivised
they're paid to run the ethereum
virtual machine in gas, it it
it's like a unit it's a small
unit of ether um and it
fluctuates of course. So, you
get these little payments, but
just like a block shaped Jeep, a
block can only hold so much gas,
and if you try to overfill it,
well you know, you have an
exploding station, or, or
something like that. Um, to find
out how much gas you can ever
have inside of blackhat at any
given time you can go to estats
dot net, and it shows you a
whole lot of pretty you know
Hollywood hackery looking tables
and things, uh but in there is
also an important number.
Currently, a little under 7
million, so that's how much gas
can be in a block. So, if you
disobey that, you're gonna have
a problem. Something like an
externally contrac, sent
contract and fail and introduce
errors like we said earlier.
Alright, so auditing contracts
uh requires looking for uh
places where errors lead to
unintended uh possibly costly
outcomes. It's not so different
from other types of uh hacking
you know. So, you have to look
for the order of operations like
I've said, uh if something fails
due to an error, nothing that
comes after might run. Um, so
this could be sort of like
unintentional denial of service.
There's a lot of problems in
ethereum where something will
error out and then everything
that comes after is just
ignored. Which could be pretty
dangerous. So, in this case line
11 is trouble, um it's it's fru
this is uh, an example taken
from the solidity docs um an
attacker could trap the contract
into an unusable uh state by
causing the richest to be the
address of a contract that has a
fallback function which fails,
so uh I think Matt talked about
fa fa fallback functions a bit
yesterday to. Um, so it or even
if it just consumes more than
the amount of gas that that's
needed, so that way, a transfer
like that failing, will cause
the rest to not work. So, to
avoid this kind of problem,
you're gonna actually set up
withdraw functions. Uh, patterns
in the application, that allow
withdrawals to happen instead of
forcing things to happen. So, if
you're overthrown some wrenches
for example, you'll still get it
because no errors can happen. In
this case the worst you can do
is cause your own withdrawal to
fail, which, I don't know why
you'd want to do that uh but,
but that's the safety of using
withdrawal. Sometimes, this is
also called push pull instead of
withdraw and send, but the idea
is the same, that you can
intelligently withdraw from a
contract. Now uh before we talk
about the next vuln I just want
to make a note about the
blockchain. There's all sorts of
crypto involved in the
blockchain in general, but what
you'll find is most of the data
that's actually put on a public
blockchain ethereum is, it's
readable you know you can
explore it, you can analyze it.
Um, so, yeah, encryption
protects wallets uh it protects
things like that, it doesn't
protect necessarily the data
that's going up on a blockchain
so games and other contracts
that rely on any kind of like um
secret knowledge or winning
knowledge can sometimes be
fooled. So, if, if you see that
people are making guesses on a
chain, you're gonna make on a
game of chance, you obviously
wouldn't make those guesses if
you saw they never won right?
You would kind of observe what
other people did and then you
would figure out and narrow your
chances and make your own guess.
So, that that's not really a
great thing, um the new
metropolis hard fork is going to
try to do something about um
having some kind of
transactional privacy. Uh so
i'll talk about that in a sec.
Alright, so, we've seen examples
of how the order is so
important. Um so this was
discovered by the guys that made
the Doante tool um, transaction
ordering dependence. So, the
idea is that transactions can
hit the blockchain in unexpected
timing right you're not
necessarily sure when they're
gonna go somewhere. So, if you
have like a simple puzzle like
this, um on the left there
you'll see that the contracts
private storage is allocated,
initialized in line 8. Um and
then on the right you have the
exec, executable code start and
that's line 15 over there in the
giant margin. So, transactions
invoke puzzle will execute that
part and it's anonymous by
default. So, sender info, send
ether data, it'll all be invoked
and uh sent out. Now, the
contract owner can update the
reward variable, okay, that's
kinda like dangerous, uh you can
literally say how much the
reward is gonna be in in 19 and
then it loops back to 18, if you
look I tried to makeup a little
symbol. So, then after that you
have that arrow going down which
shows the actual pay out of the
contract. Now what happens if a
couple of blocks appear at the
same time, to a miner and
someone is able to influence
that and say oh well someone's
about to win all of a sudden the
rewards gonna be 1 ether instead
kind of a dangerous situation
you have someone being very,
very dishonest in that case.
They can present this seemingly
fair game and mess around with
it. So, oyente is actually
pretty good at discovering this
kind of like forking possibility
and detecting the transaction
order dependence bug. Uh the
other function I mentioned that
they'd find, the other error uh
call stack depth limit, this is
no longer really a problem and
most people don't know this, but
um , the vip 150, it's now
become exponentially difficult
to exhaust gas uh in this kind
of attack. So, what use to
happen was you'd have let's say
um because of the one thousand
twenty four limit on call stack,
someone can create a contract
that brings it all the way up
one thousand twenty three and
then make a request which would
be one thousand twenty four and
cause an error. But because of
the IP 150 changes, now what
happens is it just becomes like
I said exponentially more
expensive to do an attack like
this so in the real world, I
don't anticipate call stack to
really be a problem anymore. So,
it's sort of just like a
historical footnote, unless,
something drastically changes.
Um so we saw that there's a lot
of ponzi games and things going
on in ethereum for some reason.
Uh and one of the reasons
the-there so popular is you
could publish the source code.
Right? You can say to people hey
look this game is fair, read it,
read the source code, find
something wrong with it. Uh, of
course no one really does but
[laughs] it's out there for
anyone to analyze. So, it's
possible to make a mistake, you
know, if you use highlighting,
it-it makes it easier sometimes
to see when you are doing
something wrong, but uh it's
possible to make mistakes,
mistakes can happen. But, it's
also possible to trick people
into the code they're reading at
a quick glance is actually doing
something different than what it
does. So, in this case we have
two separate variables, a payout
cursor id with an underscore at
the end, and you've got payout
cursor id with no underscore at
the end. Talk about something
that's incredibly easy to miss
if you're just scanning through,
it's like oh yeah yeah you just
talk about having cursor id. Um,
so what happens is the first
variable is getting incremented,
but the line of code that
actually draws the money out, is
taking it from the other one, so
the person who's involved in in
a game like this, thinks that
they're contributing to a fair
game, when in reality their
variable is ultimately being
ignored and it's the other one
that just looks kind of similar
and you might miss is actually
getting all the money. Now
again, this could happen
accidentally, but in, in
reality, this is where the
ethical and unethical hacking
comes in right? This is where
you'd have to notice something
like this is going on and be the
one to you know raise the hand.
So, as I said before, throws
being deprecated, uh but input
validation is a theme that
should never leave uh any kind
of app testing behind. Uh, you
always have to do proper input
validation. So, now we've got
these new um, we've got require,
which is meant to be used for
input validation, um it should
be done at any user input. So if
the user sends something that's
not expected, it throws if a
condition is false. So, that,
that's a good thing you know
you're getting what you expect.
Uh, there's also assert which is
neat because it can also check
for internal errors, uh or if a
contract as reached any kind of
like invalid state. So, uh this
is far more superior than just
simple throw although I didn't
want to make examples with these
two cause that just gets too
long so I used the deprecated
throw, sorry, it's easier to
show. But, this, this is the
kind of thing to look for,
everywhere that there could be
validation of contract there
should be. Again, to prevent any
kind of like denial of service
or anything like that that we
talked about. So, a couple odds
and ends here, um timestamp
dependence um it's a little
different than transaction order
dependence, um the timestamp of
a block can be manipulated , so
watch out for any contracts that
actually rely on a timestamp, uh
it could be manipulated, it
could be changed, it could be
read within 900 seconds um to
have uh a different one be
valid. So, because of
reva-reasons like that, you want
to make sure that silly things
like that aren't being done,
cause it's too easy to trick
something that relies heavily on
time. Um, business logic flaws
in solidity, I-I expect this to
be the next like big thing. Uh,
people are focused on those
little line to line errors but
sometimes you have to take a
step back and say hey what is
this thing supposed to do? And
see that maybe it's not really
doing what the developer thinks
it's doing. So, so that becomes
something worth looking at. Um,
separating public and private,
this is real interesting, and
ethereum has taken off quite a
bit in the last few months, um
enterprise ethereum alliance
forum. Uh, the idea there is a
lot of companies are starting to
have private permission block
chains internally that are then
communicating with the bigger
public block chains, and how you
handle that public-private hand
off is huge and I think could be
a potential attack vector. So,
something that'll be worth
looking at in the future. Um,
I'm not sure if the JPC quorum
guys are here but, but basically
in quorum they handle this
pretty well, they have
transaction senders that can use
something called private core,
and you can basically say hey,
this transactions private for
these people, and then after
that it uses a hash of encrypted
data only, and then it points to
the actual encrypted data, so
that way um, no one actually
get's access to po- to any
information that they're not
supposed to have even though
it's all in the blockchain world
right? So, it, it's a pretty
ingenious way to handle it, so
good on them. But, basically
when you're going in and doing
any kind of like test of
something that's new, some new
interaction, you've got to look
at those boundaries, which again
kinda goes back to the whole
idea of um threat modeling. You
know like, like how, how is data
handled, how does it um move
through? Uh, okay, so um, I
think it's time for a lot more
people to get involved, I'm
lonely, no [laughs], a lot of
people have to be looking at
this stuff. So, I, I've been
coming to Def Con since the
Alexis Park days, you know, and
I know there's a lot of talent
out there, uh so it shouldn't
take very long for uh some of
you guys to get spun up and gals
to uh, you know, join the fight
here [laughs]. You know, you can
get involved in making smart
contracts more secure. Um,
despite it's hiccups I still
believe in ethereum. I-I think
it's pretty incredible
technology. Uh, they've never
missed a dev milestone which I
don't know if there's any other
project in the history of IT
that's never missed a dev
milestone and, and somehow this
young kid, metallic made that
happen, so uh good on him for
that. Um, so now we're entering
what's called metropolis and
yeah that's actually the, the 20
silent movie, um, you know
[laughs] not not ethereum art
but, uh it's gonna, it's gonna
be even more touring complete if
you will. Um it's gonna have a
new revert and a new return
data, it's gonna improve
exception handling, so, that'll
be cool for security. Um, some
account abstractions coming,
which will have to check
wallets, um it might even help
protect them against quantum
computing attacks in the future.
Which, uh is a whole other topic
that uh if you want me to bore
you to death, stop me in the
hall and um, I'll talk about
that [laughs]. It's also
introducing zk snarks which is
the cool crypto primitives. Um,
even though they're again
primitives for now, it should in
theory allow um enhanced privacy
and transactions going forward,
so even though it's the public
ethereum blockchain, you could
be able to actually have some
privacy for the first time in
the transactions you make. So
that's a pretty cool thing. Uh,
and finally with what's coming
there's swarm. I mean if, if you
haven't heard about swarm,
please go forth and google. Uh,
it's quite possibly you know the
next amazing thing that you've
never heard of. Uh, if anyone's
watched Silicon Valley uh this
summer on HBO uh they did their
whole 'trying to have a
serverless internet' you know by
taking up little bits of data on
a phone uh storing and
compressing it. Well, swarm is
sort of like that, where it's
gonna be using the EVN to have
sharding and, and files located
all around the world with um the
address translation and
everything so you could pull it
back and get it. Uh, it's pretty
amazing technology and once it's
rolling full swing I mean it's
gonna change a lot. So,
definitely try and get involved
and uh join me in this uh good
new fight. And uh, if you guys
want to keep in touch, uh please
do reach out um, if, if you have
questions, like some little bit
of code you're working on, maybe
I could take a quick look or
something, uh or if you just
wanna you know yell at me or
whatever. Uh, so [laughs]
definitely reach out and uh
thanks for coming. [applause]