>>Aloha and welcome to my talk
on offensive malware analysis.
My name is Patrick, I am the
chief security researcher at
Synack. Briefly, Synack does
crowdsourced vulnerability
discovery with vetted security
researchers. So, if you're
interested in getting paid to
find bugs in our customers apps
and websites uh, check out
Synack dot com, or come chat
with me. So, today we're going
to start by looking at an
interesting piece of malware
called fruitfly, and we're then
going to talk about some
monitoring tools and
capabilities I wrote for Mac OS,
then how I built a custom
command and control server,
following this how then I used
that server to task the malware,
in order for it to reveal its
capabilities to me. And then
Finally, what happened when I
put this command and control
server on the internet. So, our
goal here is to analyze
fruitfly, comprehensively, but
do so in a rather efficient way.
So, traditionally, when you
analyze malware you use
disassemblers and debuggers. And
with stress these methods
definitely work, but they're
kind of slow. Now, I didn't have
access to a command and control
server but, I figured if I'd
write my own, then be able to
task the malware and observe how
it responded, I would be able to
basically coerce the malware
into revealing its capabilities
to me, just by asking it the
right questions. I thought this
would be a lot faster of a
technique than spending many
hours reverse engineering. So, I
mentioned the target is going to
be a mac malware specimen named
fruitfly. But, before we can
build this custom command and
control server to task it, we
need two things. We first need
to figure out the address that
the malware is trying to connect
to, where it's looking to
connect to for a command and
control server. And then, what
protocol does it speak? Because
this will allow us to create a
compatible command and control
server, which will then allow us
to task the malware. So,
fruitfly was discovered in
January, uh initially it was
undetected by antivirus engines
on virus portal. Uh, my good
friend Thomas Reed who is here
in attendance, an incredible Mac
security researcher, did the
initial analysis, wrote a great
blog, articulating the
components of the malware, it's
perses, it's persistence
techniques, and also, some of
it's capabilities. It's fairly
standard, but fully featured Mac
backdoor, but it has some
interesting interactive
capabilities, also the ability
to turn on the webcam. Now, we
don't know the infection vector,
we never found an installer
which is interesting, but
perhaps it was via an email
attachment or pirated or
trojaned application. Today
we're going to be looking at
variant b, a friend send me,
sent me a hash of this sometime
in late January, at the time,
variant a was already being
detected, but variant b was
still undetected. It was
submitted to virustotal with the
name of fpsaud, which is
designed to mimic a common flash
player, and like variant a, it's
main component was an obfuscated
perl script. That's kind of odd.
As I mentioned, we want to build
a custom command and control
server. We need the address that
the malware tries to connect to
and we also need to understand
its protocol. So, let's briefly
triage this malicious script, to
get this information. So, the
first thing we do is we beautify
the script, which allows us to
read it easier, because it's now
formatted better. We can see it
starts with some imports,
followed by some subroutines and
finally is the main logic of the
malware. Briefly, if we look at
these subroutines we can see
there names and descriptions in
the table on the slide. Now,
these aren't the core of the
malware per say, they're rather
helper functions. But, what we
can do is provide insight
especially into the protocol of
malware which is essential for
us to understand. So, for
example, the g subroutine sends
data back to the command and
control server. So, we see a
command invoking the g method,
we can determine how many bytes
it's going to send, so then our
custom command and control
server can handle that response.
Similarly, the j subroutine
receives some number of bytes
from the command and control
server. So if we see a command
say invoking j, 9, we know it
expects 9 additional bytes that
we must send form our command
and control server. Now after
the subroutines the malware
decodes some strings which turn
out to be the uh addresses of
both the primary and the backup
command and control server. The
easiest way to analyze these and
decode these is to step over
them in a debugger. Don't want
to spend a ton of time
debugging, but again, once I
stepped over this and printed
out the strings I could see they
were URLs and IP addresses,
albeit reversed, of both the
primary and backup command and
control servers. Now, before the
malware connects to the command
and control server in that main
processing block, it does a few
other things. It processes some
command line arguments which we
can see is looking for an IP
address or an IP address and
port of the command and control
server. This is awesome, because
it means we can specify our own,
for example when we execute the
malware in a vm and have it
connect to our custom com,
command and control server. So
this greatly facilitates
analysis. It also hides its
process by just changing arcs of
zero, this will fool tools like
ps, and then finally decodes
some binary data which turns out
to be an embedded mach o binary.
Finally we get to the main
processing loop and this does
two things, it checks in with
the custom command and control
server, or the command and
control server sending some
information like the host and
user name and then it invokes
the j subroutine to receive one
byte from the command and
control server which it then
processes in a massive else if
else loop. What this is doing is
basically just receiving a
numeric command from the command
and control server, processing
that and then returning the
response to the server. Ok, so
now we know the address of the
command and control servers and
actually we determined that the
malware will connect out to
whatever you specify on the
command line. And also we
understand the basic protocol.
Now, before we start building
our custom command and control
server though, let's talk about
how we can passively monitor
malware. This is important
because if we task the malware
but we can't observe what it
does if it just sends us back a
zero or one, we really have
gained to insight in which, into
which that command actually did.
So, what do we want to monitor?
Well, pretty much everything.
Uh, a given command might you
know create files, write files,
it might spawn off processes,
execute shell commands, might
interact with the mouse and
keyboard, or send interesting
data back, via the network. We
should monitor for all of the
events so that when we task for
malware, we can determine what
its doing via this simple
tasking. So let's take a closer
look at each of these now. Uh,
we'll start with network
monitoring, back os this is
pretty easy to do you can use
tcpdump or wireshark uh, we'll
talk about tasking a little bit
in um shortly, but at the bottom
of the slide you can see the
wireshark capture when the, the
malware is responding to command
number 13. Now originally, I had
no idea what command number 13
was, but we'll see when we task
the malware if we look at the
network capture, we can see this
command returns the location
where the malware is installed.
So, this is basically how we
revealed the capability via this
network monitor. Next up, we
have file monitoring, we can use
the built in fs usage utility,
uh this is a mac os utility that
allows you to monitor file io
events. We'll see that various
commands when you task the
malware will cause it to drop or
save the embedded mach o binary,
you can see from the file
monitor its saved to slash tmp
slash client. Now we can grab
that binary and do some
analysis. But, we'll see we
don't have to actually fully
reverse engineer this because
we'll reveal it's capabilities
just via tasking. Next up is
process monitoring, again this
is important because I assume
the malware probably spawned off
of other processes or executed
other shell commands. Uh, since
detritus is neutered on recent
versions of mac, there's no easy
good way to do process
monitoring user mode, so I wrote
an open source free process
monitoring library that allows
us to see what the malware is
doing. For example, here when
can see that when we task
malware with command number 11
it executes the pwd command to
get the current working
directory. I also wanted to
sniff the mouse and keyboard to
look for simulated mouse and
keyboard events. I found some
old proof of concept code that
would intercept and modify mouse
and keyboard events, so I
updated this, this will be
online available for free as
well, open source and it allows
us now to capture mouse and
keyboard events. So, on the
slide you can see when I type
and move the mouse our sniffer
will now detect and log those
events. Okay, onto building our
custom command and control
server. Recall, we can specify
the address of the custom
command and control server via
the command line, and we also
understand the protocol of the
malware. We know it connects
out, sends some client
information of the infected
host, and then expects a single
byte which is the command it
will then act upon. So we start
by just creating some basic
python code, uh we then listen
on a port, we then execute the
malware in a vm, give it the
address of this python custom
command and control server, and,
we see that the malware
connects. Now, nothing too
exciting here but, baby steps.
So, yeah when does the malware
send when it originally checks
in? Well, we can triage the
malicious perl script, we can
see it sending things like
version string, the host name
and the user name. So now we can
extend our custom command and
control server to basically
parse the format of this data,
so when the malware connects, we
can dump this client
information. Now the meat of the
custom command and control
server is obviously tasking and
handling commands. Turns out
there is about 25 commands and a
variety of these had
subcommands, bringing the total
to about 50. So, I built the
custom command and control
server to support all of these.
Now again, it's important to
understand that originally I did
not know what these commands
actually did, like command
number 2, no idea. So, what I
did for each command is I would
basically triage the command
with the goal of understanding
its protocol. Did it receive
additional bytes from the
command and control server, and
then what is the format of the
response? So here's a simple
example, command number eleven,
we can see it res, expects no
additional, uh address or bytes
from the command and control
server. But then responds with a
byte and a variable length
string. So we can extend our
custom command and control
server to parse this response
and then we can see this is the
malware setting back its custom,
current working directory.
Alright, now we task. So again,
we have our monitoring
capabilities, and this custom
command and control server. Now
unfortunately, I don't have time
to go through all the commands
but we'll look at some of the
more interesting ones. Again,
when I began tasking the
malware, I really had no idea
what these commands actually
did. So, the first command is
command number 2. If we look at
a malicious perl script, we can
see this command via the j
subroutine expects an additional
byte from the command and
control server, it then invokes
the v subroutine, to execute the
embedded mach o binary, and then
invokes the g subroutine to send
the response some information
back to the server. So now we
know, understand the protocol,
we, we know it's requires an
additional byte and then it's
going to send us back some
variable length data. But again,
we have no idea what this
command actually does. So we
send the, the malware command
number 2 and for the second byte
we just send it as zero, and via
the file mon we can see it
dropping that embedded mach o
binary and then via the process
monitor, we can see it executing
that embedded binary as well.
Now, via the network capture, we
can then send it, we can then
see it sending back about a meg
of data. So, we extend our
custom command and control
server to receive this data and
drop it or save it to the file
system. We can then dump it in a
hex editor or run the file
command and it turns out then
its an image a png file, and
when we open it, we can see it's
a screen capture of the infected
host. So now we know that
command number 2 is a screenshot
utility, screen capture, and
again just via tasking. Now
remember though, this command
takes a second byte and at the
time again I had no idea what
this was I had sent it as zero
and it sent me this nice color
png. But we have the ability to
task the malware, so, instead of
having to spend time to reverse
engineer, let's just keep
tasking command number 2, and
change the values of that second
parameter. We can see the table
contains the results, basically
that second byte influences the
type and quality of the capture.
So, for example, if we send a 1
for that second byte, it gives
us back a low res black and
white png, while a 10 gives us a
low res color jpg image.
Alright, onto command number 8,
again we triage the command we
see it expects an additional 9
bytes, and again drops and execs
that embedded mach o binary. In
terms of its response though it
just sends us back a zero or a
one, so unlike the screen
capture command we have no
insight into what this command
does by looking at its response.
But, if we task this, send the
command number eight and then
for the additional 9 bytes just
send 0,1,2,3,4,5,6, we can see
the mouse sniffer registers
event it moves to the x,y
coordinate. So, watch closely,
we're going to task the malware
with this command and what it's
going to do, it's going to move
the mouse, amazing right?
[chuckles] Gets a little more
exciting, okay, what about that
second byte? Again, we didn't
know what it was but we now know
the 8 bytes after that are x,y
coordinates. So again, we can
just task the malware, varying
this second byte, we can see as
it shows on the table in the
slide, this is a subcommand, it
basically tells the malware what
type of mouse command to do,
left click, double click, right
click, drag. This is a really
neat capability because it
allows the attacker to actually
interact with UI elements of the
host. For example, security
pop-ups, again watch closely,
we're going to task the malware
and via the malware dismiss a
security prompt. Kind of a neat
feature. The final commands
we're going to talk about are 16
and 17. Again, we triage the
command, we see that in, it
invokes j to get one extra byte
from our command and control
server. So we know okay, our
custom command and control
server should send one
additional byte. It then
executes again the v subroutine
which drops and executes the
embedded mach o binary, the file
mon and process monitor show
this happened, uh but most
interestingly then, the keyboard
sniffer lights up. So for
example if we send command
number 16, with a value of 65
for the second byte, the
keyboard sniffer shows a keydown
event for the letter a. If we
then execute command number 17,
passing in a 65 as well for the
second byte we can see it
generates a key alphabet. So
this allows the hacker to
remotely type on the infected
host. So again on the slide
we're going to send it a command
to type in H and then an I.
Okay, so what I did was I
repeated this process for all
the commands. So this allowed me
to understand comprehensively
the capabilities of the malware.
Right? They say communication is
key, apparently, people say this
applies to humans, but in this
case it also applies to malware
as well. So we talked about some
of the more interesting
commands, but of course the
malware supports other
interesting commands as well, it
allows you to execute system
commands, shell commands,
process listing, upload files,
etcetera. The most interesting
one though is the malware
actually has the capability to
alert the attacker when the user
is using the computer. This is a
very interesting capability,
obviously this malware was
designed for interactive
operations, and when you're
doing interactive operations,
for example moving the mouse,
maybe typing, perhaps turning on
the webcam, you obviously don't
want the user to be there
because they will observe these
very observable actions and this
will be a dead give away for
what that the system is
infected. Alright, so we now
have a fully compatible custom
command and control server,
let's go hunt some flies. So if
you ping the primary command and
control servers, they are all
offline. But, recall we
encrypted some backup command
and control servers, and guess
what, they were available for
registration. So, I hopped on
line, registered the URLs of
these backup command and control
servers, pointed them to my
custom command and control
server, and immediately hunder,
hundreds of infected victims
started to connect. And again,
recall for each victim the
malware when it checks in sends
the username and the computer
name which when coupled with an
IP address gives us a very good,
pretty accurate way to identify
victims. For example, if I was
infected, you would see an IP
address in Hawaii, you would see
username Patrick and host name
be Patrick Wardle's Macbook
cause by default mac uses first
and last names for the
hostnames. So, I looked into who
these victims were, geolocation
and there names, and it turned
out a vast majority of them were
in the U.S. and also, they
appear to be just normal
everyday people. So, this was
interesting, again we have a
piece of malware that looks like
it has surveillance type of
capabilities, uh for example
webcam capture etcetera, but its
targeting everyday people. Now,
everyday people are normally
targeted by financially
motivated cyber crime malware.
And malware that has this more
spying capability is usually
associated with nation states
which are not going to be
targeting those kinds of people,
it's going to be targeting like
defense contractors and military
organizations.So unfortunately,
what this means is that this
malware was designed to
basically spy on everyday people
and, and families and that's
kind of what I saw by looking at
the data. Uh, so I contacted law
enforcement and it's
progressing. Alright, so let's
wrap this up.So, today again we
illustrated how to fully analyze
a fairly complex piece of
malware, just by asking the
right questions. Again, in three
steps, we built a custom command
and control server, then tasked
the malware, and we reserved the
malware's response to fully
reveal its capabilities. Along
the way we wrote some cool, uh
monitoring tools for mac OS that
again will be open source and
posted online, and the end
result is we had a full analysis
of fruitfly variant B. Also
then, since we were able to
register these custom command
and control servers, we were
able to uncover a large number
of victims and get insight into
who these individuals were.
Again, worked closely with law
enforcement because
unfortunately it looks like this
malware was designed with a very
kind of creepy perverse uh angle
which you know is rather s***y.
Um we could've also though
hijacked all of those victims. I
always joke, and I probably
shouldn't say this, but you know
if all those connections were
you know computers in Russia or
China, I might have contacted
somebody else. Again, this is
the power you have with a custom
command and control server in
that if you can then take over
the address of the domain it's
talking to, you can task these
computers. I was tempted to, but
I did not. Now, people always
ask me you know how can you
protect against something like
this threat. Uh, forensic
analysis and also some
information we have that I can't
talk about publicly just yet,
indicates that this malware has
been around for 5, if not 10
years. Really just flying under
the radar again targeting
families to basically spy on
them perhaps via the webcam. So,
my response is always you know
use best security practices, uh,
install the latest patches, run
the latest version of Mac OS,
also look into perhaps third
party security tools. So in my
free time I write some free a
lot of open source mac security
tools, uh one for example is
called blockblock, monitors
persistence locations will
likely detect the malware when
it persists. Another one is
called oversight that monitors
for the webcam and mic, so if
this malware had got on the
computer, if the hacker and then
turned on the malware to turn on
the webcam to spy on the user
perhaps when they were walking
around in their bedroom in their
underwear or less, when the user
came back to the computer even
if the hacker turned off the
webcam, a website would have
alerted the user saying hey just
to let you know some process was
using the webcam basically
spying on you. And then I'm just
releasing a free open source mac
os firewall think little snitch
but free and open source, uh
this should be out in a few
weeks and this would have
detected when the malware
connected out to the internet.
So again, I think creating these
free third party security
utilities that trigger or alert
on these more generic actions is
a great way to target these
threats. Alright, so that's a
wrap uh thanks again for
attending my talk, and if you're
interested in being you know
basically a paid security
researcher to find
vulnerabilities in you know
Synacks customers checkout
Synack dot com. I think we have
a minute or two for questions,
if not I'll be around here and
again thank you so much for
attending my talk, I really
appreciate it [applause].