>>Good morning. Thanks for
coming out on the first talk of
Sunday. I am Josh. This is
Chris. Somewhere in the audience
is Krill, he's our plant. So,
um, just be careful about that
guy. Alright. We're talking
about breaking bitcoin hardware
wallets. All the links will be
up on our website basically
slash breaking bitcoin, the
Github links, support files.
Everything... not everything is
up there now, but, after the
presentation we'll have most of
the stuff. Okay, so, we're
talking about bitcoin hardware
wallets. Well what is a bitcoin
hardware wallet? So, what you
need to know for this talk is
that bitcoin is a
cryptocurrency. And I am going
to start my timer. So bitcoin is
a cryptocurrency. The security
of bitcoin base and all other
cryptocurrencies comes down to
the security of your private
key. So it uses a asymmetric,
um, public private key pair
system. If I know your private
key i can send transactions, um,
so transactions just like a
block in the, in the bitcoin
system. Basically i can send
money, is what you need to know
about that. And since we all
know that software is insecure,
the best way to store your
bitcoin private key is with a
hardware wallet. And so a
hardware wallet is uh, so
wallet's just the name in
bitcoin for the thing that
stores your private keys. A
hardware wallet is a dedicated
embedded device. Um, there is a
few manufacturers of them. The
two kind of big ones are the
Trezor hardware wallet, which is
what you see on the slide. The
other one is a Ledger. They're
essentially dedicated embedded
devices that connect to your
computer over USB and when you
want to send money, uh, so when
you want to sign a transaction,
you plug in the hardware wallet
and it goes... and your computer
will talk to the hardware wallet
and say "Please sign this for
me," and your private key never
gets onto your computer which
maybe you use for other things,
um, that you may not want to
keep lots of money on. Okay, so,
the other thing that we're gonna
be talking about today is Fault
Attacks. So, what is a fault
attack? Well, a fault attack is
an attack which applies an
external stress on an electronic
system. And the "attack" part
here means that it generates a
security failure. There's two
parts to a fault attack: there's
the fault injection and the
fault exploitation. Just like,
if you have a, um, stack
overflow vulnerability, you
know, there is, a stack, um,
overflow is the vulnerability
but getting the shell code in
there, that's the exploit. Same
idea with a fault attack, two
parts. We looked at two
different ways of injecting
faults. We looked at, uh,
voltage glitching, or Vcc
glitching. Essentially this is
just dropping the voltage of the
running micro controller to get
it to do things that it
shouldn't. So, specifically what
it seems to do is that when you
read and write from memory that
doesn't seem to work like it
should when you just kind of
drop the voltage at very
specific times. The other attack
we looked at, or the other
injection rather, is Clock
glitching. Clock glitching is
getting the clock signals, so
it's a very digital clock kind
of pulse and you drop the
voltage at very specific times.
The end effect is that you end
up skipping instructions. Uh,
how that happens, is there's
some instruction pipelining
going on that we won't have time
to get into the theory, but
that, that is the end effect.
And then the exploitation is
just you get the fault, um, you
know that it makes the effect
and then you time it at the
right spot and that's what leads
to the exploit. Okay, the last
kind of background is, what is
the ChipWhisperer? So we use the
ChipWhisperer to do this, uh,
talk. Uh, so this is what a
ChipWhisperer looks like. It's
essentially an FPGA, um, with
some other hardware on there
meant to do these Fault Attacks.
It also does side channel
analysis. This is like power
analysis, differential power
analysis. We didn't do that. We
focused on Fault Attacks, um,
so, you don't have to know too
much about it for now. Um,
there's a lot of information on
the wiki, on the ChipWhisperer
wiki. All you need to know is
that that's the tool that we
used to insert the Faults onto
the hardware wallets. Okay, and
so, this talk is basically the
combination of those 3 things.
So we wanted to look at, uh, 3
questions specifically. You
know, um, we looked at the
Trezor hardware wallet which is
based on the micro controller,
Trezor and all clones I should
say. The STM part, um, the F205.
Is this vulnerable to fault
injection? Can we exploit it via
a fault? And how do we raise
awareness for these kind of
attacks? So the first thing we
did is, uh, you know, I get the,
I get a KeepKey. First thing I
do, like any normal person, is
take it apart. Start looking at
things. I look up on GitHub and
there's this 2 year old bug
sitting on GitHub when they
forked it from Trezor, um, that
they didn't, uh, hadn't fixed
yet. So, um, string compare, all
you need to know about this is
that string compare, uh, is, was
being used to check the pin. The
pin is what is the primary
authentication mechanism to
allow you to send funds on the
device. And the string compare
also has this problem that it
fails on the first wrong
character. So if you measure it
with an oscilloscope, the first,
if the first character is wrong,
uh, that'll fail in about 1
hundred nanoseconds on the
device. If the 4th character was
wrong that's 11 hundred
nanoseconds. And so if you just
measure the time and can guess
the pin, you can basically see
if your guesses are working. It
really doesn't work in practice
because there's this back-off
timer that they implement that
makes you wait to enter the next
pin. The first time it's wrong
you have to wait a couple
seconds but by the time, like,
the eighth time it's wrong, you
have to wait, like, a day. So we
clearly needed another way to
get around this pin. >>Alright,
so how hard could it be? You
know, you dig out your
ChipWhisperer from the box. Kick
starter items that you haven't
played with. Uh, and you set it
up, you get your environment
going and you start running
through the tutorials. Within
the first few tutorials you're
actually, uh, scripting the
ChipWhisperer to drop out the
password from an XMEGA Target
that it comes with. Um, and
if... that's perfect because
that's exactly what we want to
do with the pin, right? On the
KeepKey? So you run through some
more tutorials and you start
doing glitches on the XMEGA and
you're glitching over while
loops which is exactly what we
wanna do with the back-off
timer. So, you know, plug in the
KeepKey, press the glitch
button, receive bitcoin, right?
Well it's not that easy. Um, so
as you can see my setup here at
the, towards the end, kind of
looks like surgery. And a lot
like surgery, we only had one
mistake to make. We had one
KeepKey to work with. Our timing
was really bad. Uh, bitcoin was
doing, uh, new highs every day.
It was over $2600. We saw
somebody pay $500 for a Trezor
wallet, uh, somewhere online
which is crazy. So, uh, you
couldn't even find the STM32F205
part, um, on DigiKey and other
websites so, it was really, we
had, uh, very small margin for
error here. Um, so, you know,
once you start attacking real
hardware you get into a lot of
technical hurdles. Um... Like,
Josh said you talk to the Trezor
and the KeepKey over USB. Uh, so
you're sending your pin, you're
uploading firmware, everything
that you're doing to communicate
with those devices is over USB.
Well when you glitch, uh, the
device it's going to effect the
USB very, uh, very strongly.
And, uh, your host machine is
not going to like it very well.
Um, so, some of these are
intended but some of them are
unintended. One of the intended,
um, hurdles is this, uh, sign
firmware check. So if you upload
your own firmware to make it
easier to attack the device,
they still check to see if it's
signed by KeepKey and they make
you press a button. So you've
got all these flywires in your
way, you're trying to press the
button. It's really complicated
and annoying. And, um, I don't
know if you've ever worked with
an arduino at different voltages
as well. The KeepKey is running
at 2.8 volts. The ChipWhisperer
is running at 3.3. You can't
just plug them in and get the,
get them to talk together. So,
um, and I don't really have a
slide to show you of just how
tedious it is to, um, fault
attack with a ChipWhisperer.
It's a lot of trial and error.
You're constantly resetting the
device because it's not always
working. You're trying to find
the variables to actually
exploit the device. So, it was a
big pain in the butt. >>Okay, so
we clearly needed something
simpler. Um, tried to go right
for the main device, that wasn't
working. We needed to just start
small and build up from there.
We wanted a simple proof of
concept, um, so we can just have
confidence that we can do the
glitch attack. And what we made
is a, a Trezor clone. And we are
releasing this clone. We have,
uh, some of the boards with us
that we're gonna hand out. Um,
all the design files are gonna
be up on the website. Completely
open source hardware or open
source firmware. Uh, you can
make your own Trezor. You can,
it's in this weird rectangle
format because it meants, it
sits on top of the
ChipWhisperer. Uh, so that's why
it looks like that, with all the
pins. Um, it's a full Trezor
clone so it'll both run
legitimate firmware, if you
want, but if you don't set the
fuses and you don't, uh, put the
Trezor keys in there it'll run
illegitimate firmware, uh, which
is more fun. Um, so that screen
is actually the screen where we
hacked our own bootloader. Um,
so if you own the bootloader,
you kinda own the device. So,
that's more fun. Uh, and then we
have dedicated on, um, kind of
the, a special glitch hardware
on the board so you can glitch
without the ChipWhisperer. So
this is an example you see in
the middle of an arduino uno.
You don't need a ChipWhisperer
to do this attack, you can do it
with other hardware. Though a
little bit tricky to get the
voltage and the timing just
right, but you definitely don't
need a ChipWhisperer to insert
glitches. >>Alright, so thanks
to Krill and, uh, his hard work
we got our breaking bitcoin
boards pretty quickly. I was
able to get a much cleaner setup
as you can see here. Um, I've
got the ChipWhisperer, the UFO
board in the red, and our
breaking bitcoin board. Um, No
flywires or any of that stuff. I
also didn't have to be as
careful, uh, so you know, I
could, uh, turn the glitching up
to 11, as you say. And in fact I
did. I burned, burned up one of
our boards and actually damaged
one of our ChipWhisperers. So,
you can actually do some damage
with that thing. Alright, so, if
attacking, you know, starting
out attacking the KeepKey or the
Trezor is kind of like attacking
a final boss on level 1 in a
video game, right? Um, so we
made our own hardware to give
ourselves a better platform for
these attacks. Well now we're
gonna, I'm gonna show you the
proof of concept or "get the
f**k out" examples of glitching
on our breaking bitcoin board.
So this first one here is
basically the "Hello World." You
should print out A, you should
wait at line 8 and you should
never see 1, 2, 3, 4 print out
on the uart. And so, um, I'll
just run through real quick what
you're seeing here. Uh, this is
the chipwhisperer analyzer
software. Uh, top right, the red
line that looks fuzzy, is your
voltage. Um, It's kind of like
an oscilloscope. You've got your
glitch settings in the top left
and now we have a serial output
in the bottom right here. As you
can see at the very bottom,
where I've highlighted the text,
it printed out Hello, new line A
and then 1,2,3,4. So we were
able to get out of that loop and
actually, um, print out 1,2,3,4.
Alright so this next example is
like level 2. And this one's
interesting because this is, um,
structured similar to the
back-off timer in the Trezor
KeepKey. It's in nested loops.
This one doesn't do anything but
print out your variables for
sanity checking. But as you can
see, um, this is a good example
in the top right of the glitch.
So you see the voltage drops all
the way to the ground for a very
small amount of time and comes
back up. If you see in the
serial output, uh, we've got a,
you know, the first variable is
actually lower so I don't know
if we, did we actually go
through the loop faster? Or did
we just modify memory on the
running device? Um, modify the
stack variable? The, the point
is that we caused behavior that
was unintended in a security
device. Uh, some more examples
here, you can really start to
get some garbage to print out.
And this thing is still running
at this point. But, uh, yea
you're really, uh,
"Cronenberging" it up here.
>>Yeah, so just, the reason
that's significant is 'cause
we're modifying how a security
device is, is running by an
external event. So, um, even
that example... where we're just
seeing the stack variable
change, this is the security
device. We're not using
anything, um, on the device to
change it except for changing
the voltage. So, um, our board
is basically, it is the same
microcontroller as the Trezor.
Um, so that's what we're kind of
using to do this example. So
then this last level is
basically "Can we skip over a
pin?" So if I can skip the pin
on your Trezor and you don't set
a passphrase then I'd be able
to, uh, do a transaction so...
How did this one go? So
basically you see there, um, the
password here is "touch" in line
2. It gets the password in as
input. If it's denied...
"imprint denied" goes to a while
loop. If it succeeds, "Welcome"
and there's just code at the
bottom to show that the LED
turns green if you get past
that. And we insert the glitch.
And you can kinda see in that
uart screen if you look at the
bottom we typed in the wrong
password so it was a J instead
of an H. And in that picture
you're seeing the LED, uh, a
green LED, which means we
entered the wrong password,
glitched and then jumped out of
the failed password and
essentially skipped over. So we
don't know the password but
we... doesn't matter 'cause we
just skipped over it. Okay, so,
we were only able to do this on
our board. Which is essentially
a Trezor clone. So we are
confident in saying that the
F205 definitely is vulnerable to
fault injections. We showed here
voltage glitching, uh, which
does affect the microcontroller.
We also had success with clock
glitching. Um, so i'll talk
about that vulnerability on the
next slide. Is the Trezor
firmware exploitable via a
fault? Inconclusive, right? So
this is where we came up a
little short. Um, we couldn't,
we could not glitch an
unmodified device. But, um, part
of the thing and raising
awareness for this talk is
releasing the board, giving this
talk, releasing our tools. Uh,
there's probably smarter people
than us who can get the glitch
parameters exactly right, um, to
do this, to do the talk on the
live device. And the
significance here is that once
you kind of do this once, it
becomes this break once run
everywhere attack, right? So if
you can learn how to do the
glitch parameters you don't need
a ChipWhisperer anymore. You
make a custom device and you
could maybe like put that over a
Trezor or something kind of like
a pay TV on Looper. Okay so the
summary of the vulnerabilities
we found and these were all
disclosed to treasure... Trezor
in KeepKey. Uh, the F205 is
definitely susceptible. Uh,
KeepKey had that timing analysis
bug on PIN verification. Uh,
Trezor and all clones had, they
did not turn on this feature
called "clock system security"
which basically would tell when
the external clock failed while
it was being glitched. Uh, they
would get an interrupt and they
could do something like erase
the PIN or take self defense
mechanisms. Um, they did not do
that. And so that was actually
one of our biggest
recommendations is that, uh,
with either the clock glitching
or, uh, through voltage
glitching they would be getting
these hard faults. It would
trigger the interrupt service
routine, they could detect that
and then, you know, shut down
the Trezor wipe the... wipe the
PIN and prevent people from
experimenting with the glitch
attack on it. So as far as I
know that's the change that they
are making. If you are a wallet
user, like, just like normal
don't lose physical control of
your wallet. But you really want
to set a PIN plus passphrase
because even though we couldn't
glitch over the PIN on the
device, if you set the
passphrase it also encrypts your
private key in two sectors so
that is the strongest way to use
it, um, and we recommend you do
that. If you are a hardware
designer, either have wallets
or, um, any other IOT device
you're going to be glitched. So
take that into consideration.
Um, defenses from faults we're
not going to have time to go
into this but there's some
really good papers on our
website that we linked to of how
to write functions that are
resilient to these kind of
attacks. And we want to now show
you a live demo, if I can switch
the video. Okay, I pressed the
magic button over here. Okay,
sweet. Okay. So, Chris has got
the ChipWhisperer up on stage.
We've got our board, which again
is a Trezor clone. Uh, he is
loading up the ChipWhisperer
software which is in the top
left. Uh, the top right you'll
see a display of the scrolling
output once he turns on the
target. And we, we did all the
hard work. We know what the
glitch parameters are so we're
just gonna press the magic
button. And, okay! So there was
the glitch. And if we stop it,
he'll highlight that loop there,
he'll highlight where the glitch
happened. And the code in the
bottom left is this nested while
loop. We inserted the glitch and
we, well what we think happened
is we busted out of that one
while loop, got back to that
other while loop and then it
kept going. And Chris can modify
some parameters and make it not
work. Make it do different
things. We'll do some live
glitching here. Um, okay, so
then it resets when you see
"Hello". Okay that one just
reset the board, right, so
resets aren't necessarily that
interesting. Um, they can be.
There are reset attacks like on
the XBox. Um, he'll change some
parameters... sometimes it
doesn't work. So this is the
trial and error part that we
were talking about that's really
painful. But, uh, yea. Voltage
glitching does work on this
microcontroller. [applause]
Thank you! [applause continues]
And I think that's gonna wrap it
up for us. We did also do some
other stuff which will be on the
slides. We made an OpenCV PIN
descrambler so if you, there's a
little thing, you can now bypass
that with OpenCV. And we
decapped, uh, the STM32 and
we'll post the silicon slides,
um, pictures of the MC up there,
but, thank you! >>Thank you!
[applause]