>>Um right, so my talk is Are
all BSDs Created Equally? A
survey of BSD kernel
vulnerabilities. Um so who am I?
My name is Ilja van Sprundel um
I uh work at IOActive I’m the
director of penetration testing,
uh I do pen test, code review
and I break stuff for fun and
profit, basically, and then it’s
somebody else’s job to fix it.
[laughter] Um so my outline is
sort of really easy, I have a
one slide introduction that sort
of puts something out there and
then I tried to collect some
data uh which is essentially
vulnerabilities over the years
in uh BSD or BSD- BSD kernels
and then sort of lacking more
than what I want um I sort of do
this sort of test by audit and
then basically um I sort of rung
through some common attack
surface and some issues I found
uh and then I sort of of uh lay
out some results and draw a
couple conclusions. Um so what’s
this talk about? About BSD
kernel vulnerabilities, a
comparison between different BSD
flavors uh the audience I think
should be- pretty self
explanatory, right? If you’re a
low level security guy, or
you’re UNIX or BSD geek, or if
you’re a Linux guy you might
enjoy it too. Um or people
generally curious about you know
low level OS internals, I think
they might enjoy this um as far
as knowledge goes um I mean I do
expect that you have some basic
understanding of the BSD kernel
um it doesn’t have to be too
deep but just a general concept
would be nice. Um yeah before I
wanna continue um this is not
just- I didn’t just create this
out of thin air, um there was
work by others that I’ve uh sort
of relied upon and sort of- that
came before me um and I’m sure
I’ve forgot some because you
always do uh if you feel like
you should be on the list and
you’re not I’m- I’m the only guy
at fault here, um but most all
of these guys had basically had
contributions at some level at-
in sort of the uh- offensive BSD
kernel stuff. So this is my
entire intro it’s basically a
small rant by Theo De Raadt um
from about 12 years ago um where
he gave some Forbes magazine
review about the Linux guys and
how they suck um and he follows
up with some uh- some uh- um
some posts online and he goes uh
‘well you know if the Linux
people actually cared about code
Quality as we do, they wouldn’t
have had as many you know local
kernel holes in the last year’
and he goes like ‘how many has
it been, like 20 so far?’ right?
That’s the entire slide um and
now that thing is 12 years old
but somehow that’s been stuck in
my head I’ve never gotten it out
and I’ve been like ‘well you
know is that- is that really
true? Like, can you back that
up?’ um and so I went to look-
looking for some data and sure
enough most of these things have
CVEs um and there’s a website
that collects them all and you
basically go there and say,
‘please show me all Linux
vulnerabilities’ and it gives
you this beautiful grid and
says, ‘these are all the bugs
per year, types of bugs’ all
that type of stuff. Um and so if
you look at this thing you- you
sort of see from 99 til 2007 um
and this- this- this- this
grid’s actually slightly older
this is from uh about three
weeks ago the numbers from two
thousand and s- 2017 aren’t
quite right, it says 346 there,
but it’s really today it’s 353,
that’s the number of Linux
kernel vulnerabilities this
year, right? Um but if you start
looking at the- at the- at sort
of the bo- the- the top, 99 til
about 2003 you know the numbers
were pretty mild right it was
like oh you know 5 anywhere
between 5 and 20ish right? So
that- and then- and then sort of
as of uh 2004 it kind of sort
of- you know it sort of hockey
sticked that goes on right? Um
so the numbers basically get
worse and worse and worse, more
and more security vulnerability
is discovered and disclosed
every year in Linux kernel,
essentially, right? So now what
do those numbers look like for
the BSDs? Well, I went to the
CVedetails dot come and said uh
you know what were BSD kernel
vulnerabilities and sort of
[mouth noise] zilch and it says
net BSD kernel vulnerabilities
nothing, CVe kernel
vulnerabilities, zero, well I
know that’s not true um [laughs]
I had some before, they should
have at least shown up um but I
do know they publish their own
advisories um and I guess to get
it so BSD it’s neurota um and
it’s it’s essentially the same
thing except it’s uh much
s**ttier to pa- to get data out
of um so I spent like an evening
writing some uh web crawl and
some s**ty protocol that parses
HTML and then like f***k around
in Excel to get the numbers
lined up. Um but I did that and
so you sort of you know build a
similar ish table um and you’ll
see that the- the numbers from
1999 to about 2003 more or less
are in the same ballpark as
Linux uh and then Linux after
2003 kind of you know goes like
this but then all the BSDs kind
of sort of stay the same, I mean
it’s- it more or less line up,
goes up, goes down a bit, it’s
usually anywhere between zero
and like 20 or something um and
that- that hasn’t changed so if
you look at numbers even for
this year, they’re more or less
in line. Um so looking at these
numbers um Theo was right, you
know, the Linux guys are doing a
lot worse than the BSD guys
right? A very astute observation
um and when he said 20 in 2005
um that was you know a very
conservative view if you look at
the table here, it’s 133 not 20
[laughs] so you know he was uh-
he was off but uh the- his- his
sort of uh the impression he
wanted to give seems to sound
right um. But then I wonder
well, you know if we see this
kind of hockey stick um in the
Linux numbers why don’t we see
it in the BSD numbers, right? Is
it really true? Is it- is it- is
it code quality, is that what it
is? And so I wanna sort of- in
my presentation I want to I
wanted to basically figure out
okay are these numbers equal
footing, are the Linux guys
doing something different, or is
everything else the same, and
it’s all about code quality. Um
and so when I was tal- thinking
about this I said well you know
there- there’s you know this uh-
this many eyeballs thing right?
And and and I know I know cause
the many eyeballs thing is
mostly like you know this sort
of it’s not really true and of
course not all bugs are shallow
no matter how many people you
have looking at code, some bugs
are just ridiculously hard to
find. Um but the general idea
behind the many eyeballs thing I
do like and so I’m- I’m thinking
is there some truth to it? Um
cause surely there are more eyes
looking at the Linux kernel code
than there are at OpenBSD just
by sheer number right? Um and so
I wanted to figure out if
that’s- if that has- if that has
remotely anything to do with
this. Okay so um first of all I-
I sort of looked around and sort
of has anybody else done this
before right? Cause the way you
would do this is you go and look
for vulnerabilities in these
things and see what the numbers
are. Um and it turns out
somebody did that um 15 years
ago, Um so- uh uh uh a very very
nice Australian guy named um
Silvio and he did uh um he did a
Black Hat presentation about
this um and I and I vaguely
remembered this and I looked
over the slides and I’m like
this- you know you get so
nostalgic looking at it again
and you’re like all these slides
are so f***king awesome um and
then you start looking at them
and then- and then it sort of
get to the last three or four
conclusion slides and and um
Silvio basically goes well you
know there’s really not much of
a quality difference between the
BSDs and the Linux in terms of
security. Um now that was over a
decade ago, it was 15 years ago,
so have things changed, right?
The- the history conclusions are
3 years before oh Theo’s rant so
things may have changed in those
15 years, right? Um the time
spent um in the slides compared
between BSD and Linux is like he
spent like a week on all the
BSDs combined and then like 3
months on Linux right? So the-
even- even- like there that’s
apples and oranges right? And
then the last one sort of the um
uh Silvio basically put out this
okay I’m going to go look for
trivial integer overflows and
some info leaks and and so
that’s kind of it, right? And so
what I wanted to do is I was
like I don’t want to limit
myself to just those two I wanna
be a little bit wider and then
see if I can find some other
stuff as well and how easy those
things are to find. Um so I sort
of set- set out and said, okay
I’ll do the same thing Silvio
did, just 15 years later um so I
spend a April, May, June, and a
little bit of July um auditing
BSD source code. Um and when I
set out to do this I was like
okay well um where where do I
think the bugs are? Where would
they be, right? Whats- what’s
the interesting attack surface
right? And so you come up with
this sort of short list of you
know where I think they are,
right. Number one eh- I mean
it’s stuff we’re- a user can
talk to it essentially, right?
So number one is system calls,
right? Users are gonna have to
talk to the kernel and they’re
gonna have to do it through
system calls, right? Uh number
two is obviously TCP/IP Stack,
right? If you’re network
connected [cough] someone's
going to be sending you packets
at some point so that’s attack
surface and so that’s sort of
the super common that’s the one
that you know my- my mom could
come up with those and then sort
of a little list of like
slightly less common to like you
know sort of rare-ish or exotic
or something, right? Um and so
at the top of the list is sort
of the drivers and specifically
you know ioctls um cause you
know most devices need just
someone to talk to it and
configure it, and get data out
of it Um [coughs] and that’s
sort of uh- I started thinking a
bit more and I was like oh well
these bs- BSDs um most of em you
know it comes with these compat
layers um that’s probably
interesting to go and find- look
for bugs um and then um I was
doing something else where I had
this idea that I’ll- I’ll talk
about in a second and based upon
that I was like oh you know the
uh the trap handlers are
probably interesting too and
this is where it gets sort of
get a little bit more and more
esoteric and then I sort of did
okay well what about filesystems
and it turns out there’s some
attack surfaces in filesystems
as well and then I’m like okay
well, there’s also networking
that isn’t um TCP/IP stack like
you know wifi, I mean it kind of
ties into it but it’s really I
mean it’s not, you know you open
up TCP to illustrate it it
doesn’t talk about you know- uh
a wifi frames right? Um and
there’s other things like
bluetooth and IrDA and I wanted
to cover those too, but I ran
out of time so I’ll just in that
section I’ll only talk about the
wifi stack. Um and then I was
like, okay let’s just dive right
in, and what I’m gonna do is
I’ll sort of um have a little
slide that sort of introduces
the thing and then I’ll show you
a little bit of code of a- of a
bug and I’ll describe the bug
and for 4 or 5 of them I’ll
basically run through a little
bit of a demo [coughs] So let’s
uh [clears throat] start off
with syscalls. Obvious attack
surface, right? Um it has
exactly how the user talks uh to
the kernel um without system
calls your OS would be
essentially useless. Um it says
the BSDs have you know evolved
since the 70s um they no longer
have 4 different system calls uh
they- their- they number in the
hundreds uh and they do all
sorts of funky stuff and
performance improvements. Um and
these, I mean, th- uh-
essentially these are things
like you know, open a file, read
a file, you know, create a
network connection, send- read
something from a network
connection, close a file, you
know, send a message, get my
UID, that- that’s the kind of
stuff it does, right? Um and so
FreeBSD at the top of the list,
they have like 550 ish and then
um NetBSD is slightly below it
with 480 and then at the bottom
is like OpenBSD they only have
330 system calls um and
functionality wise you might say
okay well you wanna have more,
wanna know less because that you
know have more functionality and
while that may be true, from a
security perspective, the less
system calls the better, right?
Um cause no- less system calls
means less attack surface, means
more security, right? Um so just
looking at these numbers you go
like oh go OpenBSD, right? Um
and then I- one of my
assumptions basically that well
given that their such obvious
attack surface and they’re so
well tested and they’re
constantly used by apps this is
probably you know less likely to
contain security bugs, right?
[laughs] and so let me show some
code, so that’s a system call,
this one basically you know
drops a sys- a sys log message
right? And it takes a buffer and
it takes a length and it takes
your buffer and your length and
it passes on through this
function called dosens uh-
dosendsyslog and dosendsyslog
basically takes the length field
and then basically puts it in uh
um in on uh uh IO structure and
then from there sort of takes
out a link- the length field
again and then passes that along
to uh the kernel malloc
function. Um now the kernel
malloc function is sort of um
historically in BSDs it was very
special um the free [inaudible]
BSDs have sort of evolved away
from that um but OpenBSD still
has the original model where um
malloc basically goes and says
if your length is too big um
you’re doing something really
horrible and instead of just
hanging your system, I’m going
to c**p out um and basically
panic and then it looks like
this, your system essentially
dead after you do this. Um and
so essentially this is the uh
it’s a- it’s an unbound malloc
in OpenBSD um that triggers a
kernel panic um and it’s- it’s
easily triggerable through
dosendsyslog system call. And
let me see if I can- man I ca- I
really can’t see that [mumbles
under breath] is that it? What?
One more? Uh this guy, there we
go okay, so that’s a [laughs] I-
I- I seriously can’t see it
cause my screen’s different than
what’s there uh anyway so that
should tell you the U name that
is NetBSD uh- OpenBSD sorry,
right? Yes, yes! And I- I
precompiled the syslog binary um
and I will be throwing the
physical thread out after my
talk uh I just don’t know where
yet um but if you- if you wanna
figure out where it is um shoot
me an email and I’ll tell you.
So if we run this thing, boom
there you go. RIght there that’s
a kernel panic, the box is dead.
>>Woo! >>Awesome, thank you!
[applause] [laughs] there we go,
oh yeah hold on. Yeah that looks
about right. Okay so that
definitely triggers a kernel
panic, right? Okay let’s uh do
an- let’s look at a non system
call cause we don’t have just
wanna look at OpenBSD right? So
there’s this system code called
kldstat which is um uh in uh uh
FreeBSD basically it basically
you call system call and you say
hey give me a um a list of
loaded drivers or for that
particular driver, tell me
everything you know about it and
sort of this- syscall goes back
and says, here’s what I got. And
the way that works is um it
calls this thing called copyin
which takes the data from the
user and then it calls kern
kldstat and it basically
collects a bunch of data and
puts it in this structure called
the stat structure um and I
don’t have the function for um
kldstat in here cause I didn’t
want to spoil- I didn’t want to
like pollute um the slide but
essentially what this function
does is it fills out two strings
uh that can be about 1000 bytes
long um and it sort of um copies
an alternate string into it uh
but then everything else after
the no byte is never initialized
so you basically end up with
about a half a page for the info
leak stuff just data that’s on
the stack never initialized,
right? Um [clears throat] this
is in uh FreeBSD 11 is when I-
when I looked at it went back
and saw that this book has been
around for ehhh more or less
about a decade um so [clears
throat] let me see if I can demo
that too. [mumbles under breath]
okay this works better. Uh I
think that one’s right, yes So
this basically um triggers the
bug over and over and over and
what you’re going to see is like
a long stream of like random
kernel bytes um [indiscernible]
boom there you go! All that
stuff is that’s all you’re
leaking, you’re leaking, you’re
leaking. Yeah, there’s some
weird bug where sometimes it
hangs but it basically just
keeps leaking and leaking and
leaking, and leaking, that’s
endless amounts of
[indiscernible] um I was
thinking of doing a demo where I
grabbed some stuff out of it um
but I didn’t um ran out of time.
Um. Oh yeah um d**n it. There we
go, okay. Oh yeah. Um [clears
throat] so now that I’ve seen
two of these bugs um and I have
several several more uh syscall
bugs uh I didn't want to spend
all my time just demoing those
those things um but essentially
you know the previous assumption
where we go ‘oh well you know
these things are well tested,
they’ve been around forever,
it’s highly unlikely to get
bugs’ well that’s not really
true, turns out bugs do occur in
system calls with some
regularity um and particularly
newly added system calls, right?
Um that do senses locking has
only been around for one version
um the KLD one happened to be
happens to have been around for
a decade um there’s a bunch of
others like um I have- I have a
bunch of other like FreeBSD ones
um like you know that show up um
so you know that the assumption
is isn’t really true like if you
just assume syscalls won’t have
bugs well that just isn’t true.
Okay so let’s move on to the
TCP/IP Stack right, hopefully
presumably everybody knows um uh
what that is and what that means
um it you know it handles
networks you know [clears
throat] the low level stuff IPV4
and 6, Udp and tcp and the
sequence numbers and you know,
Ipsec and how it all ties
together and then how you route
it back and forth to userland
app and those kind of things. Um
this is obviously very well
known attack surface [clears
throat] it’s been around
forever, again the same
assumption here is that this is
very well tested code, it’s been
around since the early 80s uh
very unlikely to find security
bugs in there. Right So here’s
another piece of uh OpenBSD code
this basically takes uh P- pppoe
vert net packets and sort of
passes them all to to this
handler and it sort of loops
over the the packet data and it
looks for a tag in the length
when it finds a tag in the
length it goes into the switch
and the switch goes ‘oh hey,
this tag, this tag, this tag’ in
this particular case, there’s a
um an error [clears throat] some
error tag in this case I guess
SName error and it basically
goes there and says ‘okay let’s
me- set the error message to
this’ and then send a flag which
is error tag and then end of the
uh switch case you kind of
there’s this code that kind of
goes ‘oh hey, if we got this
particular error message go and
and and go do this’ and then um
they obviously pull out the
thing out of the packet um
before they can actually touch
the bytes and this is- this is
like a bizarre um uh uh they
have these things called Mbufs
which are basically very pa-
specific buffer structures that
are designed to hold network
data, right? And there’s all
sorts of APIs around them to
work with them and so they’re,
they’re made in a way so you can
chain it together so that if you
wanna like append or prepend or
like ch- swatch- uh switch stuff
out as you’re building a packet
that- that they work, right. And
as part of that um before you
ever touch any of these things
um you- you you’re not going to
need to have a continuous
buffer, right? Um and so there’s
a function called Pulldown and
basically what what Pulldown
does is it says ‘okay what I’m
gonna do is I’m gonna look at
all of these things chained
together, um, and when I
successfully when I- when I-
when I complete and it’s
successful, I’m going to hand
you back a you know a buffer
that is completely continuous
and you can start using that’,
right, and so it does that um
and if that works it goes on and
does what it’s supposed to do.
Now if that fails, it bails out
um and it basically goes to this
thing called Done and then Done
basically goes, says, ‘Oh yeah
this is your original uh Mbuf
let’s go and free that thing’
right? Um and so that code looks
fine except if you look at the
main page for Pulldown um it
says in uh the fine print it
goes ‘well if Pulldown fails it
frees the Mbuf and then it tells
you it failed’ um so what’s
happening here basically is if
the Pulldown fails, the Mbuf is
freed, and then it goes and
frees the Mbuf again, right? So
s- uh uh sorry. Um so uh uh a
pretty trivial case of um you
know double free um this isn’t
o- I found it in OpenBSD 6 point
1 and it turns out it’s been
there for a decade and change um
and then um one of the things I
did is I tried to cross
reference, because they do have
a fair amount of shared code, so
I tried to cross reference um
and I looked at the NetBSD code
base and then I saw that in
February of this year they
discovered this bug
independently, and they fixed
it, but uh there was never an
announcement made, it was
silently fixed Um [laughs]
[applause] and so again the- the
previous assumption that this is
well tested code, and it’s
highly unlikely there’s a bug in
there, well that isn’t really
true, it’s- I mean it was well
tested code, it’ll still have
bugs uh and the other thing I
discovered is that um so these
mbufs are incredibly complicated
and it’s very error prone,
right? To- uh to do it right and
never make a mistake, it’s kinda
hard and one of the things is
that um a lot of APIs have sort
of handled these things um it
depends on their failure cases,
so about half of them basically
go and say ‘okay if I fail I
don’t free this buffer’ and the
other half go, ‘if I fail I’m
going to free these buffers’
right? And so that creates an
inconsistency where if you’re a
developer, right and you’re
you’re- assume the API uh uh um
frees on failure um and so uh
you basically say ‘okay I’m not
gonna free this thing because it
frees on failure’ but if the API
really doesn’t free on failure,
then you’re leaking memory and
the opposite oc- occurs too,
right? Where if you go and say
‘okay I’m pretty sure it’s API
on the return- on the failure
doesn’t free- all the- will free
it, you know it’s double free so
this- it sort of you know
inconsistency among API behavior
um uh combined with the
complexity of of the mbuf
structure sort of creates this
um situation where like it’s
pretty d***n hard to get things
right every time. Right. [clears
throat] so let’s move on to
drivers right. Ioctls you know
everybody's favorite hack
surface um you know lots and
lots of drivers are out there um
B- BSDs they’re no different,
they have piles and piles of
drivers for all sorts of stuff
um and you know eh- obviously
BSDs UNIX and in UNIX you know
everything’s a file so the way
you expose a device to userland
is you put it in slash dev
right? And you give it some name
and obviously these things
basically expose file operations
to userland right? Like file and
open and read and write and
ioctl and things like that. And
I guess you can mmap some of
them too, things like that. Um
[clears throat] so you know
ioctl obviously is where you
have an attack surface okay so
uh let’s take a look at an
ioctl, right? So um that BSD has
this device called crypto um and
basically what crypto does is um
it takes uh uh uh an ioctl input
and I actually- um anyway- it
takes uh an ioctl input and it
basically goes and says ‘okay
well here’s uh here’s some
structure that comes from
userland and it contains this uh
this account field’, and what
we're gonna do is we’re going to
create an array of number of
account fields um and then we’re
going to start running data into
it, right? And then we’re going
to start using it, and then
we’re going to start like,
manipulating stuff. Um and as as
you can see there’s a count time
size of the structure um and
anybody who knows anything about
writing code and security knows
that that is a very class
integer overflow. Um [clears
throat] right that’s integer
overflow right there, and that’s
your memory corruption block,
right there. The- I didn’t-
again I didn’t want to put more
code on the slide cause it would
just pollute things but that
crypto dev mkey stuff is
basically you know starts uh uh
uh writing stuff to to that
buffer that was previously
allocated. Um so yeah that’s uh
uh uh uh classic integer
overflow leaks memory corruption
um it’s in NetBSD it has been
there uh s- about 9 ish years um
and then hold on let me see Yeah
let’s uh There. So this is
basically hopefully fingers
crossed gonna trigger the um
integer overflow and then cause
memory corruption and it’ll
basically trap into the
debugger. There you go. Boom,
it’s on- it’s gone, memory
corrupted, rebooted [applause]
[clears throat] so here’s
another one this is uh uh this
is uh um this is a device on
FreeBSD called ksyms which
basically gives you the ability
to expose kernel symbols to
userland, right? Um and it
basically as I mentioned
earlier, most of these drivers
have an open callback, and this
one’s no different. And when you
uh when you call the open system
call it goes to this callback
and this callback basically sets
up a few things so you can later
do operations on it, and then it
returns successfully. Uh one of
the things it does in this case
is basically um so it creates um
a file descriptor storage
specific private data which
means there’s kernel private
data associated with the final
descriptor you’re going to use
in userland. Um in this
particular case what they do is
um they uh uh look at the
pointer to your uh um that’s
basically contains all the data
needed to describe your virtual
address space for your- for your
process and stores it in that
pointer or or yeah inside that
uh uh driver specific um uh uh
uh storage um and then basically
returns successfully. And then
um later on there’s another
system call that basically gets
called if you do an mmap in that
particular file descriptor um
and as you can see it references
um that particular pointer that
was previously saved, right that
uh sc pmap is saved here and
it’s referenced here, right?
Okay so the bug here is that uh
um uh that pointer using mmap
doesn’t necessarily still have
to be valid then the one using
open right and so the way that
works is um- ‘cause usually you
say okay well the file
descriptor associated with the
process and so as long as the
process is around the file
descriptor will be around and so
that virtual address space map
will still be around except you
know OpenBSD er- er- at least
the BSDs in UNIX in general is
smarter than that and it gives
you the option to basically not
just hold on to a file
descriptor but instead go to a
different process and say, ‘hey
you can now have this file
descriptor too’ and then once
that guy has the file
descriptor, you can say to the
other process, ‘okay well you go
and die’ and so the other
process is gone and so all data
associated with it is entirely
gone and expired and now you
have that second process, and
the second process is still
holding onto the file descriptor
and all of a sudden it says ‘oh
well now sounds like a good time
to call mmap on this thing’ and
mmap goes around and says ‘oh
look I have this- I have all
these pointers to uh this
particular process, this virtual
memory uh space’ um and it goes
and references that, does all
sort of things with that, except
the original process is gone,
it’s dead, it’s entirely
expired, um and so this guy um
ends up- if you do that, you
know it ends up doing really
really horrible things. Um and I
would love to demo this but um
well I have a pock ‘cause it’s a
s**tty race to hit uh this one
took me a couple days to hit um
I don’t have that- I don’t have
that long um to show you um I
will be releasing code um so if
you wanna play a- play around
with this uh you can just for
now you you’ll have to do with a
screenshot of a kernel panic
[clears throat] okay so that’s
it for this sort of super common
attack surface. Uh so the compat
code is another one where it’s
like okay this is an interesting
uh attack surface um and so uh
the one there is basically so
most BSDs have this thing where
they tr- um offer additional
binary support uh so for example
uh uh FreeBSD NetBSD and up
until a couple of years ago
OpenBSD had support for Linux
and what that means is you can
have a Linux compiled binary,
you would run it on FreeBSD, and
it would just run. Not just
‘cause you have to set up like
an environment but by and large
the binary would work. Um and it
could do other things like uh
you know emulate [indiscernible]
environment of the 64 bit
version of of of of that BSD you
have um a- a- and it could do um
like old versions of the OS,
things like that. Um and the way
that works is basically what
they do is they emulate a whole
bunch of system calls, they fake
a- the system call that you
expect it to be and then they
sort of funnel it to the real
system call and then sort of you
know parse the stuff back and
forth um they uh now s- uh um
compat layers are a great idea
from uh a user functionality
perspective, they are an
absolutely terrible idea from a
security perspective um and uh
Theo De Raadt who’s the you know
the leader of of OpenBSD and and
you know a pretty go- d***n good
developer um you know had some
really interesting insight of
the compat layers and if anybody
would know, it would be him, he
goes, ‘well you know, people who
rely on this stuff don’t care
enough to maintain it and the
people who work on the actual
kernel uh don’t give a d***n
about compat layers ‘cause they
don’t use ‘em’ um and he says
‘cultures aren’t aligned in the
same direction’ and then he
says, ‘compat layers, rot very
quickly’ which means you write
one today and tomorrow it’s
gonna be just useless and just
have nothing but security bugs
in it. Um so here’s the uh uh um
here’s the NetBSD um this is
it’s this like svr4 which is
like fairly ancient
[indescribable] thing um and
they basically emulate that on
NetBSD so if you have original
binary compiled for that and you
move to binary NetBSD it’ll
still work and it has this thing
called streams which is sort of
a predecessor to sockets ish um
and so what they do is, NetBSD
doesn’t support stream so what
they do is they fake it and they
sort of put a socket underneath.
Um and so the- the original svr4
binaries will think they have a
stream even though it’s a socket
um and so this thing basically
it’s it’s essentially uh um it’s
essentially an an ioctl that’s
supposed to do a socket
operation um and it copies in
the data structure and they put
it in the BSD structure, and it
passed on to this netaddr the
sockaddr in and netaddr sockaddr
in basically looks at this uh
structure and it says ‘oh this
thing contains uh uh you know a
32 bit offset inside it’s
structure I’m gonna use this
offset and I’m gonna add it to
my pointer and I’m gonna give
you back a pointer to where you
can start reading from’ uh
problem there being is there’s
absolutely- uh no validation
being performed um and so
basically you can end up with a
wild pointer that points
anywhere um which you can either
use to trigger uh kernel panic
you know your box goes down or
you can if- if you know what
you’re doing you can very
selectively pick pieces of
memory and start leeking you
know very selective pieces of of
kernel memory. Um and then
what’s really beautiful is that
at the top of this file someone
said ‘well we’re going to
pretend to have streams, we
don’t really, oh yeah by the way
this code is really gross’
[laughs] Um so yeah this was
found in uh uh NetBSD 7 point 1
but this things been around for
uh uh 21 years uh it’s been
there since NetBSD 1 point 2,
it’s been around for a very very
long time um and it- it gives
you the ability to read
arbitrary ish kernel memory or
cause kernel panic. And so I
submitted this bug to the uh
NetBSD guys uh and they go ‘oh
s**t yeah this thing- this thing
is tot- total piece of s***t’
and they go uh ‘we fix- we fixed
a gazillion bugs in this svr4
thing uh we should have never
enabled this by default it is an
absolute minefield’ um and so
when I submitted the bugs and
they fixed them they also
changed uh their OS config file
to be like- and and basically
turn off svr4 support um if you
want it now you’re gonna have to
recompile your kernel. [laughs]
[applause] Okay so another thing
I was thinking, I was like okay,
well, okay we have these things
called trap handlers and um this
is where things get a little bit
exotic um so trap handlers were
these sort of callback that you
reg- that like very low level OS
code registers sort of when it
boots up and it’s goes eh-
basically goes to the os- or the
OS basically sets things up and
so when some kind of a hardware
thing happens these things get
called, right? Some kind of
exceptional fault happens and
these are things like division
by zero, a system call, a
breakpoint, invalid memory
access, um when it- when the
hardware sees any of these
things it sort of goes ‘oh I
don’t know what this is but I’m
gonna call this function pointer
and we’ll have that deal with
it’, right? Um some of them can
be triggered by userland and
some of them can be triggered by
kernel um and the kernel has to
trigger them correctly um the
thing though with trap handlers
is that they are unbelievably
nasty pieces of code um and
exceptionally architecture
specific. Every architecture and
like every little miniscule like
little dif will have between
architectures things are very
different and then every little
dif within the architecture
might still have like tiny
little changes between them um
it’s an absolute pain to try and
understand these things um and
it is- it’s a ridiculous pain to
look at this code so I didn’t
look at it. Um so I said okay
but I’d still like to play with
this a little bit, where do I go
from here? And I was like ‘Okay
well what can I do to trigger um
uh uh eh- exceptions an- and
faults’ well what if I just
start executing random
instructions, what happens? Um
surely they’ll trigger a bunch
of uh uh uh uh uh uh uh e-
exceptions and traps and then
the OS has to handle it and then
I have a slightly more um bigger
fuzzer, this is essentially it
this is uh sort of a one slide
um sort of uh uh trap handler
fuzzer where essentially what
you do is you map a piece of
code read and write in
executable you sort of start a
loop and every time you get into
loop you basically you know read
out op dev urandom- uh a page of
random garbage, you fork off a
process, you hand that phd
process and the process
basically goes, function pointer
call’ and then surely crashes
and it does this over and over
and over and over and over again
um [laughs] and essentially I
did this on the previous Z and
you know there’s a uh a Xen trap
that kinda blows up my face and
then [applause] [laughs] and
there’s some other signal stuff
that uh um sorta blows up and I
have a demo of this, I’m not
sure if it’s gonna work ‘cause
this thing sometimes blows up
fast and sometimes it takes
awhile but I could at least um I
could at least try and and show
this thing. Uh Oh man this is
so horrible ehh. Tu- uh god
d***n it! [laughter] I got em!
Okay there we go, awesome!
[applause] Wow look at that,
this is I- this is a horrible
set up I got here [chuckles] And
plus my eyesight sucks um so
this page functions for the
[indiscernible] processes I
don’t know if it’ll uh I may
have to come back to it later
‘cause um give it a few minutes
it might die um >>So these are
all crashes of that second
thread but like how many can-
>>Yeah this has- doesn’t crash
the kernel yet but eventually
it’ll- it’ll crash the kernel um
if we’re lucky, fingers crossed
um I got a hit earlier this
morning and- and usually it only
takes a couple minutes but it’s
like random garbage so it’s like
>>And how are you recording
which [inaudible] [speaker
inhales] >>Uh so not in this
version but I have a version
that basically uh has utp socket
and sends it to a server and so
the server basically goes and
says ‘okay this is- this is the
garbage it generated- this
garbage it generated’ and so
when it crashes I look at the
last packet and I go like ‘okay
let’s decode what this- set of
it- set of bites are like you
can feed it to like Ida or
something and it’ll tell you,
this is what it means. Um anyway
I’ll- I’ll get back to this
later, I hope it dies [laughs]
Uh um but essentially so yeah
there’s uh uh uh uh uh uh a Xen
trap I hit and then there was
another sendsignal trap I hit
which is this one um and so
hopefully I ca- I can show this
uh uh in a little while um
[clears throat] so let’s mo-
move on to file systems um so
obviously when you think file
systems you say okay well you
have a file system image and you
can mount it and obviously if
you or or you know have USB
stick and plug it in and have
that mounted and if somebody
doesn’t parse the file system
correctly then you know bugs
show up right? That is number
one that is an easy attack
surface. [sniffles] Um there’s
another one that I sort of- I
was playing with and I was like,
okay that could be interesting,
so in the last couple years all
three of the BSDs have built in
support for fuse, um and I don’t
know if you guys know what fuse
is but fuse essentially just a
mechanism that allows you to
have userland file systems, and
the idea being there is that you
know, writing file system sin
kernel is really, really hard,
um and so if you ofed userland
it’s okay if your file system
does something bad or crashes,
the OS won’t go down. Um and so
what that requires is, um, your
normal BSD uh VFS layer now has
to support a file system that’s
in user as opposed to one in
kernel um if you’re talking, if
kernel- the kernel is talking
everyone’s trusted, if kernel’s
user’s talking, they’re not
trusted. So you’re now taking
this layer that is always
talking to someone that it
trusted and you’re basically now
feeding it a bunch of data from
userland that’s no longer
trusted um so the VFS layer-
layer- layers in theory should
have been hardened um for fuse.
Um so I looked at fuse for all
three BSDs and basically sort of
my impression was the NetBSD-
fuse-they’re- they’re- this is
funny right, so all the B-
they’re family right? They all
fork from each other except when
fuse came around they all said
‘nope we’re all gonna sort of
make our own little thing’ and
so you have three distinct uh
fuse implementations for the
three different uh BSDs um and
so NetBSD sort of um in my view
made the most complete
implementation which allows for-
for the most options and
flexibility. Um FreeBSD I think
has the most controlled one in
terms of uh the amount of stuff
they’ll take from userland in
terms of file system is highly
controlled um and so what that
means is there’s relatively
little opportunity uh for
consumers to make mistakes but
there’s more opportunity for the
parsing inside the fuse code
itself to make mistakes. Um and
then um OpenBSD sort of um uh
has sort of just minimal
implementation I mean they all
uh um none of em on ioctl but
they implement all of the other
uh file operations. Um D***n I’m
gonna have to skip through this
‘cause I’ve got only a few more
minutes left I think and there’s
conclusions I want to get to um
but anyway this is the getcwd
system call um for um uh for the
BSDs [clears throat] uh for
OpenBSD and that- you can hit
that from- from fuse um anyway
let’s- let- let’s skip over the
file system stuff. Yeah the
network is interesting you know
there’s some bugs in the
networks- in the network stack
where if you send a packet the
box goes down. Um [mouse
clicking] blah blah blah oh and
this is one of these things
where there’s all- all these uh
wireless drivers that have like
these straight straight out heap
smashes where they’re not
expecting a malicious radio even
though they’re taking data over
over USB and so if you have
malicio- k- k- a malicious radio
all of a sudden the OS has all
sorts of heap overflows. But
let’s skip through that through
right there’s some miscellaneous
stuff I want to talk about but I
don’t have time [laughs] um what
oh yeah um so yeah results. Um I
looked at this stuff for about
uh 3 months um uh I found about
30 or so bugs in FreeBSD, uh 25
or so in OpenBSD, 60 ish in
NetBSD, and it’s- thing is it’s
hard to sa- ‘cause I sa-, I give
approximate numbers because some
of these things are like, it’s a
single function and it contains
5 buffer overflows, okay is that
1 bug or 5, right? It’s- so I
try to sort of be like ‘err it’s
this many’ um depends how you
make- or how you sort of look at
these things but I think these
numbers more or less make sense.
Um in terms of bugs I’ve seen
it’s like a very long list of, I
mean there’s the straight heap
and and stack smash like in
those wireless drivers uh a
couple of race conditions,
expired pointers, double frees,
recursion bugs [chuckles]
integer issues, um very very
interesting refcount issues um
obviously overflows but also
there was one uh NetBSD bug
where they’re like ‘okay we’ll
take a refcount on this v-note’
and then ‘okay we’re gonna take
the mount point out and then
we’re gonna drop refcount and
now we’re gonna play with the
mount point’ well there’s
nothing tying them together so
the mount point goes away,
you're- your’re meaning well,
pointers. Anyway, other things
that I found were info leaks,
out of bound reads, NULL derefs,
logic bugs, um a typo where they
literally called their own
instructor, it was something
something TX and it called
something something RX um
division by zero bugs, uh kernel
panics and memory leaks. So um
[clears throat] found bugs in
all 3 um and basically you know,
in the attack surfaces I
discovered uh I mentioned
earlier uh and sort of among the
range of the bugs that I- that I
just listed. Um winner loser is
is in my impression fairly easy,
when I started looking at this
stuff OpenBSD came out as a
clear winner um for a number of
reasons, um they have massively,
massively uh reduced their
attack surface, um they got rid
of loadable module support, they
uh um have relatively few
devices, um [chuckles] got rid
of all of their compat code,
including Linux, [chuckles] they
deleted their bluetooth stack
‘cause it sucks [chuckles] um
they have- more- they have more
than 200 system- 200 less system
calls than FreeBSD um and they
cut support for a bunch of
really s***tty architectures. Um
on top of that um when Theo said
they care about code quality,
they do. Um they have virtually
no integer overflows or
signedness bugs they’re as good
as gone in most places, except
the ones where they didn’t know
about the attack surface, like
the wireless drivers. Um oh-
yeah- um and then also very few
info leaks, so the bugs they
know about and the patterns that
they know um they look for them
you know like a madman and- and-
they eradicate them. Um NetBSDs
one of these where it’s like
okay, comparatively they’re the
clear loser, um tons of lazy
code and compat code so that’s-
you got an attack surface right
there um [clears throat] they
seem to be less consistent um
when it comes to uh um code
quality and too many signedness
bugs. And I know how this sounds
but- and I’m not trying to dis
them because I know it’s
incredibly hard to write an OS,
right? If you think it’s easy to
build, maintain, improve an
operating system, you should try
it, it’s really hard, like you
will cry yourself to sleep. And
then somewhere in the middle is
FreeBSD um now when I started
reporting these bugs um sort of-
here’s the response that I got,
right? When I emailed the
OpenBSD guys uh it took about a
week or so to get an email back
from Theo and fir- he fir- he’s
like ‘oh you know I’m so sorry I
took a week, I was out on
vacation’ and then within- you
know after that week like bugs
started rolling out, bug fixes
started rolling out, you know uh
the next couple of days,
everything got fixed within a 2
week period. Uh FreeBSD guys
responded as well um in uh uh
about a week or so and then
filed all the bugs, I don’t know
the exact status of the bugs.
NetBSD and this is where they
really shine though, so I was
kind of a lazy b*****d um and I
was sort of uh uh [chuckles] uh
procrastinating and I was like
‘oh I don't want to write up all
these 60 bugs’ so I did only got
them wrote up right before I got
to Vegas and so then I sent them
these bugs a couple days ago
[chuckles] which is really
unfair of me and I was thinking
like ‘oh how am I going to deal
with this, I don’t want to like
make them look bad’ um and then
something happened that was like
ridiculous um they fixed all 60
bugs overnight. [laughter]
[applause] Which is unbelievably
impressive, and I told them
that, and I told them like if
you wanna call me out on being
an a*****e you can, but I am in
awe of you guys ‘cause that is
insane. Um additionally they
also turned off SVR4 which I
think is a great deal and when
they emailed me back they said
‘we have disabled this thing,
something we should have done a
very very long time ago’ Um so
yeah pretty much and and my
insights, more conclusions. Bugs
are still easy to find. Uh very-
various levels of quality. Um
most consistent uh was OpenBSD
um yeah one more point I wanna
make is uh maintainers of these
BSDs should talk to each other
‘cause I had several bugs where
one guy had the bug, and then
the other guy fixed it like 6
months ago, right? And it goes
both ways, right, it’s OpenBSD
and NetBSD and it’s FreeBSD um
and uh I got another funny story
where- funny story about that
about a guy I met at a bar
yesterday, [inaudible] he’s a
developer, but I don’t have time
to get into it. Um yeah code
base is is OpenBSD is small,
FreeBSD’s the biggest and so
it’s interesting to look at
these things uh it’s clear
OpenBSD has the least amount of
attack surfaces, FreeBSD likely
has the biggest one. Um this
obviously plays a part you know
if you- if you don’t have code
for something then you can’t
have bugs in it, right? [laughs]
and there’s a thing between
accidental versus planned,
right? Uh some things didn’t get
ac- get- get implemented, just
didn’t get to it and other
things you made a conscious
choice to sort of get rid of it.
Um so yeah the many eyeballs
thing, I think it’s a factor. Um
based on my results I I think it
matters, I think code quality
alone doesn’t account for
discrepancy, I think code
quality has something to do- uh
I think the the many eyeballs
thing has something to do with
it uh my my view is that you
know say what you will about the
guys looking at the Linux
kernel, and you could say a lot
about them, um there are just
simply so many more of them and
it shows in the numbers. Um yeah
and then this thing leak- this
thing sort of presentation got
out before I did this thing, and
so the internet saw this and
they you know had some questions
and and and I don’t I’m pretty
much out of time but I wanna
‘cause somebody asked about uh
um DragonFly BSD and I did not
look at DragonFly BSD, I
considered it uh maybe I
should've, I just didn’t, I ran
out of time. Um and then some
links, and then that’s pretty
much it, I think i’m out of time
right? [applause] Awesome.