>>So as he said, I'm Sarah Zatko
and, uh, I'm going to be talking
about just the interesting
tidbits from our last year's
worth of research. And then
introducing everyone to the work
we've been doing with Consumer
Reports and talking about how
you can help on that or how you
can get involved. So for those
who don't know what is CITL,
it's a nonprofit research
organization focused on being
sort of like Consumer Reports
but focused specifically on
software risks and safety. So
some people get confused. They
think we're just evaluating
security software. We're
evaluating all software. Um. And
that includes desktop, binaries,
or things off of IoT devices
that's sort of what we're
getting into now. There will be
a little bit about that later.
But, uh, so well anything that's
a binary. And, uh, the goal is
that we test things and then
publish results just like
Consumer Reports does. Right now
where we are in that process is
we've got the testing part
pretty solid, but, uh, we're
working now on coming up with
nice looking, readable reports.
Uh. Scaling everything up so
that we test everything rather
than, you know, just a, you
know, a product here or there
when you want to do, uh, entire
industry like this, uh, requires
more scale than what you
initially set up for an approved
concept. And then, uh, we're
building up our partnerships for
publishing 'cause, again, we're
not publishers. We'd rather give
data to people like Consumer
Reports and other organizations
and let them disseminate the
information to their audiences.
So that's the sort of stuff
we're working on right now. And
the end goal is, of course, to
make the software industry safer
and easier for people to
navigate. You know. The people
who care to make the right
decisions about minimizing their
risk have no clue how to do it
'cause, not any fault of theirs,
but just an entire lack of
usable information. So that's
the, uh, problem we're looking
to solve in the long term. The,
uh- our software testing right
now... we do static analysis
which is different than most
people's. Our static analysis is
that we look at what application
armoring features are there and
how well are they implemented.
What functions were called and
which of those are historically
really risky or just straight
up, bad. And, uh, um, what
libraries are people linking to
and what are the features of
those libraries. And then, you
know, complexity of the code.
And we can measure all that to
our satisfaction, but there's a
problem when you want to take
the hundred or two hundred
features you extracted about a
binary and you want to turn it
into a single score. Like this
got a 75 out of 100. Because
it's hard to tell what thing is
worth how many points. You know,
are, like, stack guards worth 15
points or 10 or 20? I don't
know. Because there haven't been
a lot of studies that look at
how effective are the safety
measures that we use and trust.
The, um... In most other
industries, that sort of data
would be pretty fundamental.
Something you could take for
granted that it existed because
the first step is that somebody
comes up with their bright, new
idea and publishes how and why
it works and we hope, one day,
everybody will be using it. But
before you get to that universal
adoption, there's clinical
trials or there's small scale
deployment and then they're
studies to see did it do what we
thought it would do and how well
did it do that thing. The
security industry doesn't do
that. I hadn't realized what a
weird blind spot that was until
I needed that data for this
effort and then I was, like,
"Wait! We don't do this at all?"
That's, I mean, it's just sort
of mind-blowing when you realize
that this is an entire gap. But
it makes sense 'cause that
stuff's not as sexy. It's not as
exciting. So people- and there's
enough other problems that
people don't do it. So that's
what we're focusing on in the
immediate future, is that we
have a lot of static analysis
data. We're putting together a
lot of dynamic analysis and
fuzzing data to go with it so
that we can do those studies
about how impactful are
different elements we're looking
for and how much do they affect
a final score. Uh, that way when
we do finally publish results,
they'll be numbers we're ready
to get in a fight over. You
know. Things that are really
solid and that we really stand
by. And this'll... when we
publish that corpus of data, the
fuzzing data and the static
analysis data, that'll be a big
deal for a lot of other people
too, because we're not the only
ones who are frustrated by that
lack of quantification for
impact for the things that we
hope to be industry standards.
You know, if somebody is looking
to push for universal adoption
of a particular safety feature,
say, you know, the FTC or
someone like that, it's very
hard to make the argument
without the studies saying,
"This is why you need this."
And, uh, you know, it's also...
I believe that this gap in the
body of existing research is at
least partially responsible for
the success of snake oil
salesmen in our industry because
for the stuff that really has
suts-substance and does
something, and the snake oil,
the same argument is being made.
I'm an expert and this works.
Trust me. You know, the
non-expert doesn't have the sort
of data that they'd have for any
other sort of decision making
process. And it looks the same
to them. So whichever one better
marketed and prettier-looking is
the one they're going to go for.
Also snake oil people usually
make more broad promises. So,
you know, they'll go for the one
that says, "This will make you
totally secure." Not the one
where they're like, "Yeah! I
think this'll help." You know.
So I'm very excited about the
research we're doing right now
to build up that corpus of data
and that's what we're hoping to
have as our next big thing, is
releasing that. But for now, on
to our talk and what do we have,
uh, to show you today. So, uh,
as I said, we're ramping up our
fuzzing capabilities so that we
can build up the second half of
the data we need for our big
longitudinal studies. And, uh,
so we're going to look at the
really early stuff coming out of
there and talk a little bit
about the fuzzing framework that
we're building up. And then
we're going to get into the
interesting tidbits from our
static analysis so far. So we're
going to look at comparisons of
major OS's, a couple Smart TV's,
a couple Amazon AMI's. And then
for applications, we're going to
look at browsers on all those
major OS's. And then, uh,
revisit Microsoft Office for
OSX, 'cause, uh, there's an
interesting case study there.
And, um, finally we're going to
talk about our work with
Consumer Reports on the digital
standard which, again, I'm very
excited about. It's nice to have
so much work to do that you're
really, uh, feel like it's going
to make a difference sometime.
You know. Uh. Ok. So fuzzing.
We've fuzzed about 300 binaries
so far which might sound like a
lot in some context, but, uh,
given that we've done static
not where it needs to be yet.
Um. And what we're building is a
system that can do fuzzing in a
fully automated fashion. So set
up a VM, install the software to
be tested, take a bunch of
existing test harnesses and try
them out on the binaries. If
something fits, then you fuzz it
and then do the crash triage to
identify primitives all in an
automated fashion. When most
people are doing fuzzing, their
goal is to hit a particular
target. But what we want is just
breath- we want as many
different kinds of binaries as
possible. So if something
doesn't work, we ditch it and
just move on to the next thing.
And, you know, so that means we
can build up a larger set of
data, although probably a little
idiosyn-syncratic looking to
somebody who had a different
goal in mind. And, uh, to do
this, we're customizing AFL and
Triforce QMU and also borrowing
some stuff out of the cyber
grand challenge. And, uh, that
put together is called
CITL-Fuzz, very creatively.
Maybe we'll have a better name
for it somewhere down the road.
Uh. Names aren't totally my
specialty if you saw the talk
title. But, uh. So we've fuzzed
about 200 binaries with AFL and
about 100 with CITL-Fuzz so far.
So for the CITL-Fuzz results,
those are- it's not a terribly
rich data set at the moment, but
one interesting thing you d- can
do is look at the packages where
we fuzz multiple binaries and
see how well did those packages
do as a whole. So, um, what we
have here is package name,
number of binaries, how many of
those crashed that as a percent.
And then total number of unique
crashes for that package. And,
uh, you can see the winners here
are Libc-bin and Cook with five
and four binaries respectively
and zero crashes. Those were the
biggest sets of binaries to not
have any crashes found. Uh, the
runner up would be Canna which
had a handful of crashes for its
six binaries. That's still
better than anything else in its
range of, uh, binary counts. The
losers were, uh, Biosquid,
Elfutils, and then Cdftools. The
first two of those had 100
percent crash rate for their
eight binaries tested. And
Biosquid had several hundred
crashes per binary so that was
definitely the, uh, biggest
loser out of our tests so far.
For, uh, the AFL data, we had
static analysis to go with it so
then we can start doing some
really preliminary data science
of the type we're going to be
doing more and more of as our
data set gets to be bigger.
Right now, uh, we're only
getting numbers of unique
crashes and the signals. But
later on we'll have primitives
identified and then we'll be
able to do more complex, uh,
math magic. But, uh, for now, we
have the numbers of unique
crashes. And then we tried
correlating those with risky and
bad functions. You know, so
risky and bad functions mean
what you think. They're the
functions that somebody looks
for when they're bug hunting
because they know that people
screw them up a lot. Uh a- bad
is worse than risky. You know.
Um. So, uh, the highest
correlations that we found were
for execlp and execv which, you
know, had a pretty high
correlation rate with numbers of
crashes. Uh. And, you know, it-
this is, again, really early
days and a pretty small data
set. So it's an exciting, early
tidbit and tells us there's
going to be some really cool
stuff when we, uh, get this
fully op- up and running. So,
uh, onto our static analysis
data where we've got a lot more
to work with. Uh. So first up,
operating systems. Um. You know,
an operating system has
thousands, maybe tens of
thousands of binaries. Each
binary has a score. So the way
we show an entire environment
and its stances that we do a
histogram of all the scores in
that operating system. And, uh,
you can't see the numbers here
because I didn't want to get too
much on one slide, but you don't
really have to. You just need to
see the shape of the
distribution. Uh. So the X-axis
here are all the same. They go
from negative ten to 110. And,
uh, low numbers are bad, they
mean softer targets. Higher
numbers are good. So the further
to the right your distribution
gets, the better off you are.
And, uh, the Y-axis is not the
same on all of these because it
made things sort of unreadable.
Uh. But it's not really
important for this story here,
uh, 'cause, you know, uh, what
we're looking for again is the
shape. So what we've called out
is the fifth, fiftieth, and
ninety-fifth percentile marks
'cause this allows you to see
how long the tails are in either
direction. We particularly care
about the left tail 'cause
that's the s- the low hanging
fruit in your environment. The
longer that tail gets, the more
soft targets you have lying
around and the less you've done
to clean up that low hanging
fruit. So, um, Windows 10 does
actually very well. Uh, which,
you know, you might know from
seeing the new safety features
and improvements that they had
in that release. The fifth
percentile mark is pretty close
to the fiftieth. And, uh,
they're really very consistent
in the application armoring
features that they're including
which is why the distribution
looks so different than all the
other ones. It's a lot more
uniform in the safety practices.
So then you end up with a lot
more things in the same bin. So
for example, that biggest bin
there is the sixtyfive to
seventy and there's 5,500
binaries in there. So that's the
most consistent off-the-shelf,
uh, use of safety features that
we've found so far. Uh. OSX El
Capitan has scores in generally
the same region on, like, the
chart as OSX- I mean, as
Windows. But it's, uh- the fifth
percentile mark has moved a lot
further down. So it's, uh, got a
lot of the same safety features
but they're not being as
consistently applied. And, uh,
there's just a lot more low
hanging fruit hanging around. So
the percentiles all move down a
bit. The fiftieth is almost the
same, but the thing we care
about most is that that, uh,
fifth percentile mark went down
by almost fourteen points. And
then on Linux, again, the fifth
percentile mark moves noticeably
further, uh, down the scale.
And, uh, the distribution gets a
little lower as a whole. So, you
know, this isn't any sort of
surprise to most bug hunters
because this correlates exactly
with the prices for exploits in
these environments. And that
makes sense 'cause we're trying
to assess the cost to newly
exploit software. And, uh, so,
you know, the, uh- you get paid
for your work. The thing that's
harder to exploit, you get more
money. And- But it's nice to
know that the Pwn2own values for
these exploits correlated so
closely with our results. It's
good confirmation that we are
measuring what we want to
measure correctly. And the last
bit of data that we have for
standard OS's is that more
recently we got, uh, some data
on Sierra so then we can do a
comparison between Sierra and El
Cap to see what improvements
have been made. And, uh, so, uh
Sierra got a bit bigger. No
surprise there. Everything
always gets bigger. And then,
uh, ASLR's application rate on
El Capitan was already pretty
high, but it inched a little
close to 100 percent. Um. The
Heap DEP was the only safety
feature to have a decrease in
use. Uh. Heap DEP data execution
prevention, you know, one of the
exploit mitigation features we
look for. And this is explained
by the fact that most modern OSX
compilers, if you compile
something as 64 bit, then the
flag for Heap data execution
prevention is off. So the
increase in 64 bit matches
pretty closely with the decrease
in Heap DEP. Uh. This is a
worrisome trend in that any time
you have a flag that's off, uh,
there's the chance that that
safety feature will not be used.
Some people argue it doesn't
matter. That most modern OSX
environments enable Heap data
execution prevention by default,
but that's not always true. In
some cases, it'll see you don't
have this flag and it'll say,
"Oh. You're not compatible. I'll
turn it off." And, uh, you know,
there's nothing that will go bad
if you have the flag on so have
the flag on if you can do it.
You know. Uh. So I'm not clear
on why that's a trend, but it
is. And, uh, it'd be nice if
that got turned around sometime
soon. Uh. We also look at source
fortification. And, uh, the
numb- percent of binaries that
were fortified was about the
same. Although the number that
were unfortified went down. So
good. Uh. You might notice that
these numbers don't add up to
100 percent. That's because the
way that we tell if there was
source fortification is that we
look for the unfortified
versions of these functions and
we look for the fortified
versions, and, you know, if you
don't have either in your
binary, we don't know what flags
you had. And it doesn't really
matter, you know, 'cause it's
irrelevant. It didn't make any
change. And then, uh, the last
bit is looking at what percent
of the binaries had functions
from our different categories.
So good, bad, risky, and ick all
mean exactly what you think. Uh.
Ick is just the couple functions
that no one should ever use in
commercial code. Uh, there's
not... really it is just two or
three functions. So, you know,
it's, uh... you have to be
special to get in there. And,
uh, here again the story was
pretty positive. Bad and risky
both went down by about ten
points. I mean, ten percent. And
then, uh, good was actually the
biggest increase we saw across
the board. Uh. Going from eight
percent to twentyfive percent of
binaries with good functions in
them was, you know, a really
pleasant surprise. And, uh, so
next, I'm going to look at a
chart that shows the impact of
corporate policies for software
installation. Uh, so, I'll do
some explaining on this one.
Just bear with me. The, uh, blue
bars- the ones that are in the
middle row- are the base
installation for a large
enterprise organizations- well,
employees. Uh. Their base OSX
install for new employees. So
this is the clean installation-
everything that's on it when
they give it to the employee.
The little gray bars that you
can hardly see in front of the
blue bars are what executables
from that clean installation
their employees actually use. So
which ones got executed. And
then the giant orange bars are
what ex-executables get run by
employees when the company gives
them the right to install
whatever software they want. So,
the- if you're looking at the
live attack surface being
presented by your organization,
those gray bars versus those
orange bars are the comparison.
They, uh, um, and obviously, you
can't have just those tiny bars.
You have to allow them to
install some things, but being
judicious in what you allow is
important, because if you
aren't, you're increasing your
attack surface by a sizable
amount. And the... in
particular, the low hanging
fruit increases a great deal.
The negative scores for the
clean installs stop at negative
ten, but on the dirty install,
they go down to negative
thirtyfive. So you're increasing
your lower tail by a lot. And
again that's not something
that's a surprise to anyone, but
nobody's quantified it and
showed somebody a chart of, you
know, "Here's what you're
do-doing with this policy." Um.
Ok. And next we're going to look
at a few different linux
distributions. The first one is
the same linux that you saw
earlier. This is what you get as
the off-the-shelf linux sixteen-
Ubuntu 16. And then, uh, the one
below it is an example of what
you get when you take a
off-the-shelf linux install and
do a modest hardening effort. So
no co- no code modification, but
you take out the stuff you
obviously don't need and you
recompile it with all the modern
safety features enabled that
won't get in the way of normal
operations. You know, this is a
very reasonable thing to expect
from any major vendor when
they're putting something out
with a linux environment.
Obviously that's not what they
do right now, 'cause nobody
makes that modest, uh, effort if
no one's going to notice. Uh. So
what you see if you take apart a
Smart TV and get the binaries
is, uh, the two things we have
on the bottom here. A Samsung
Smart TV and then a LG Smart TV.
And, uh, these are worse than
the off-the-shelf linux. They're
lower distribution, uh, they
have lower points overall 'cause
they're missing a lot of
fundamental safety features. Uh,
you know, they have- they're
binaries respectively. But
they're clearly not, uh, doing
all the things a modern linux
environment does from a safety
perspective. And, uh, for a
comparison, if you look at
Amazon's AMIs for linux
environments, they're the same
binaries so, you know, very
comparable footprint. But this
is what happens when you care
about the security of your linux
environment. The distributions
are much higher and they've
taken out all the low-hanging
fruit. The scores on the other
ones went well into the negative
numbers, but here the minimum
scores are forty and thirty
respectively. So that's a nice
accomplishment and it shows that
it's entirely possible to have a
full linux distribution in the
footprint that they- these IOT
devices have while doing
everything more correctly. So to
see why those Smart TVs' scores
were as low as they are here's,
uh, some data similar to what we
saw for the OSX stuff, uh, just
showing all the safety features
that the Smart TVs don't have.
Uh. I've highlighted in light
orange and light red the, uh,
bad and really bad numbers
respectively. Uh. You know...
math terms. And, uh, I'm
comparing it to the harden linux
because they should have made
some effort to harden. That's
the bar they should be compared
to. So, uh, ASLR's lower than
the standard. Because the
standard is that we're getting
really close to 100 percent and
then, uh, RELRO is not existent.
That's a- a linux-specific
application armoring feature
that's really pretty common
these days. And, uh, stack
guards and fortification were
basically nonexistent on LG.
They were there on Samsung but
much lower than industry
standard. And, you know, that's
all reflected in their scores.
So that's it for, uh, full
environment views of operating
systems. Now we're going to use
those histograms as the context
for scores for individual
applications. And so you see the
same histogram that we had for
OSX earlier. Only now it's
showing you where the different
applications' scores fall. And
below it we've got our hardening
line, softer targets to the
left, harder targets to the
right. And, uh, we're calling
out where specific applications
of note fell on them. So for OSX
browsers, uh, the Firefox score
was not great. Uh. Safari was
middle of the pack. And then
Chrome did decently. Not
amazing, but decently. And, uh,
you know, this is a... I don't
know. Not maybe a earth
shattering result to some
people, but again it's nice to
quantify things. For linux, just
to have a third one to throw in
we did Opera. They're clearly a
little bit further behind the
times in terms of some of the
safety features. Um. And, uh,
for Chrome and Firefox- they
presented an interesting case.
So here, first I'm showing the
scores that they got just for
the executable- the main
executable alone. Not taking
into account the libraries
they're calling. I'm doing this
because viewed that way, they
got the same score. Granted, uh,
the one bit of static analysis
we're still working on is our
evaluation of sandboxing. If one
that gets finished, Chrome will
probably gain a few points so
they'll probably, uh, get a
little further ahead of Firefox
there. But right now, they're
neck and neck. Except when you
bring libraries into account
where Firefox falls fifteen
points behind Chrome. And, you
know, this is important to point
out because this was Firefox's
home turf. This was their chance
to shine, but, you know, if you
bring in libraries that are
scoring negative tens, then
that's going to, you know, be
reflected in your permanent
record. And, uh, you know, they,
uh... A lot of times when people
are figuring out what libraries
to use, they think first about
functionality because that is
admittedly very important. As is
what license its using. But
third place should be its
security stance. Uh. People fall
into the trap of not my code,
not my problem, but it's code
you're linking to from your
product and choosing to execute
when your customer runs your
product. So you should care
about it. Uh, that mini rant
over. Onto Windows browsers. So,
uh, here we looked at Firefox,
Chrome, and Edge. And, uh,
again, Chrome will probably gain
a few points when we get the
fir- uh, sandboxing thing in
place. But for now, Edge being
on its home turf... It got a
near-perfect score. Uh, slightly
better than perfect 'cause, uh,
they did- they got bonus points
for a couple things that very
few people do. And, uh, um... So
the- not a huge surprise there.
Firefox, uh, is again away from
their home turf so they fell
down a bit. And, uh, if we were
going to pick one of these
Firefox binaries to count as the
Firefox binary, uh, we would
pick the 32 bit because that was
the one that we got when we went
to their main website to
download. You know, I mean, it
didn't have explicitly labeled
as 32 bit but when we checked,
that's what it was and, you
know, it took a little bit of
hunting to find the 64 bit one
so your average consumer is not
going to do that. So, uh, you
know, you get credit for what
you make available. And, uh,
again, uh, the pwn2own values
for exploits match up pretty
closely with the, uh, rankings
that we'd give these, uh,
applications. You know,
Microsoft Edge and Google Chrome
are at the top. Safari's in the
middle. And then Firefox is
relatively cheap. Um. And then
our last bit of static analysis
data that we're looking at is
Microsoft Office for OSX. Last
year we beat up a bit on them
for Office 2011. People rightly
asked, "Ok. What about 2016?" So
we bought that and tested it.
And, uh, presents an interesting
story. Uh. So here's those bad,
uh, 2011 scores that we had last
year. Uh. In particular, their
auto update scoring of seven was
pretty embarrassing. And their
average for all binaries in that
package was around a sixteen so,
uh, you know, just, uh, not a
good going all around. But when
you look at Office 2016, uh,
they really did much better. The
average binary score increased
by sixty points. And the auto
update went from a seven to a
sixty-four. And, uh, you know
when a new Office Suite comes
out, I'm not in a big rush to
get it because all the features
that I need, I already have and
am using in the current one and
I know that all i- all is going
to happen is they'll have moved
a bunch of buttons on me. It's
going to take me a week to be
productive in it again. And so,
you know, it's not one of my
priorities. But sometimes
there's more hidden features and
this is an example of that. So
if somebody who's responsible
for purchasing decisions for a
large organization, had this
sort of data available, then
they'd be like, "Ok guys. Sorry.
You have to find out new
locations for buttons." Like,
you know, the- we're upgrading.
So, uh, done with our data that
we've collected. Now onto the
work we've been doing with
Consumer Reports. Uh. In
particular, uh, the digital
standard which launched earlier
this year. And, uh, you can go
to this website to see the first
draft we put together. And what
this is is that Consumer Reports
recognizing the need for
software evaluation for their
own product reviews, uh, asked
us to be part of a group they're
forming. Uh, the other groups
are all focused on digital
rights. Uh, privacy, one of them
is focused more on governance
side, there's data sharing...
You know, they're, uh, trying to
be a pretty broad view of a
consumer digital rights. And,
uh, together we put together
this, uh, uh, first draft of the
digital standard which is our
first step at a testing standard
for how you would evaluate
software or IOT products from a
digital rights perspective. And,
uh, we've done a couple of
initial rounds of testing based
on the standard we put together,
uh, including the browsers and
Smart TVs that you saw earlier
in the talk. And all those other
organizations tested the same
devices but since the full
report hasn't been published
yet, I'm sharing our, uh, side
of that 'cause that's the part
we're allowed to share. Um.
Right. So if you go to the
website and look at the digital
standard. This is what you'll
see. Uh. Everything gets more
technical the further to the
right you go. So the leftmost
column is the name for a
particular criteria like
vulnerability disclosure
program. After that is, uh,
lay-person readable material on
what that criteria means. After
that is a slightly more
technical description of what
indicators we're checking for
when we're evaluating that
criteria. And then after that is
a brief description of the test
procedure. So if something has a
little green check mark by it
like this one does, that means
we're pretty happy with this
one. It's pretty fully baked and
we feel like we have a test
procedure in place that scales
well enough for Consumer
Reports' needs or some other
similar kind of effort. If
something has a little flask
like the next one does, uh, that
yellow flask means usually that
we can test this for a single
product, but we don't think it
scales well enough for testing
an entire product vertical. Uh.
So, you know, there will be a
test procedure there but it's
something that needs work in
order to figure out how to make
it, uh, be more automated. And
then if something has a little
red exclamation point, that
means that none of the groups
that are part of this coalition
right now have an in-house
capability to test this thing.
And, uh, that's why that
column's blank. And, uh... So if
you go to this site, all of this
is linked to the GitHub page so,
you know, if you read a criteria
or description of something and
you think we didn't word it
right or we're barking up the
wrong tree, you can click and go
to GitHub and comment and
propose a change. If you have
some way of turning one of our
orange or red icons into a
little green check mark, then
you can let us know that and
we'd love to get input on how to
make our overall procedure more
complete. The- there was some
question as to if we don't have
the ability to test something
why are we including it? It's
because we think those things
are important and that an
evaluation of a product would be
incomplete if it wasn't there.
But, uh, you know, and us not
having the in-house capability
to test it right now doesn't
change that. And in this case
what I mean by "us" is the
total, uh- all the groups that
are part of the digital
standard. Not CITL. We're just a
little... We're only responsible
for a couple of these criteria,
thankfully. So, um, if you are
interested in the digital
standard and want to be a part
of that, I, uh, encourage people
to go to the website and, uh,
get on GitHub and or look at our
bits where we are missing
something and think about
whether that could be a new
research project. Um. And then,
uh, if you have anything follow
up for Cons- for CITL, our
contact info is at the top here.
So thank you very much.
[Applause] Um and, uh, are we
doing questions? I don't know.
[off mic response] Uh. Yeah, I
can do ten minutes of questions.
[off mic question] Oh. We're a
nonprofit so, uh, we're figuring
out a way to support the
organization while sharing as
much data as we can. Uh. But
public service is the main goal.
Uh. Sorry, I forgot to repeat
that question. Um, but he just
wanted to know whether, uh, what
the business model was. Yes?
[off mic question] Uh, so he
wanted to know if we're looking
at historically impactful
vuln-vulnerabilities and those
binaries. And we're not looking
at historic data right now
'cause we've got more than
enough present day data and
we're, uh, using the fuzzing
data to compare against. When we
publish our corpus of all the
static analysis data and fuzzing
data, then somebody else would
be welcome to do that study.
It's just the, you know,
so-many-hours-in-a-day kind of
deal. Anyone else? It's a little
hard to see the audience. You.
[off mic question] Uh. Could
you- could you say that louder?
[repeated off mic question] Uh.
So are we looking at
dependencies for software? Uh,
if it's a library that it links
to then we look at that. Then we
look at the libraries it links
to. We go down that whole tree.
If it's some sort of more
indirect, uh, dependency that we
can't see through library
linkage, I don't know what that
would be but, then we wouldn't
find it. But yeah, we look at
the whole tree of library
dependencies. Anyone else? We're
all good? No- there? Oh, okay.
We're all good. Ok. Great! An-
oh, wait. You have a question?
[off mic question] I'm not
currently on Twitter. [off mic
statement] What? [off mic
statement] Um. Yeah, we're in
between DARPA officers. Ok. So
everyone's good? Uh, then have a
great Def Con. [applause]