please a former colleague it sounds so
terrible
alright alright thank you all I like
that it's still going I like that
alright everyone thank you all for
coming I know Travis Goodspeed is a much
better talker than I am
I'm much better presenter he definitely
earns it however but I'm I'm here to
give kind of the other side of Car Talk
if you guys have and this is kind of a
an introduction but kind of a different
side of that introduction the talk this
morning especially at 8 o'clock or no 9
o'clock this morning was kind of like
hey here's how you hack some stuff I'll
be talking about that but this is more
so at a higher level so it's in my mind
an actual introduction or baby's first
introduction to vehicle security so Who
am I few of you know me hi my name is
Christopher Craig that is me at the San
Diego San Diego Zoo mounting a North
American Siberian tiger or at least a
replica of it with my friend with a
captain hat I've been working five years
at Cisco Systems and I've been working
for about seven actually about eight
months now so point seven years or so of
a year at Oak Ridge National Labs I'm
really into multirotors and as you can
tell from the center of this image is a
my first 30 minutes of drone ownership
careen headfirst into a tree and then I
patiently waited for it to fall down for
the rest the afternoon I still have it
it's Smyrna and it's a pretty good multi
rotor if I didn't crash it now I'm a lot
better of a pilot and I hope to get into
drone racing and hopefully some some
drone plus pineap-- and stuff a little
later so we'll see that for hopefully
for the next besides I'm in a
motorcycles so it's surprising the cars
that listen here
do I need to I need to speak in line
all right wow thank you a little bit
there we go
bringing the bass sultry tones so I made
a motorcycles as you can see that's my
Twitter and as you can see that's my
absolutely terrible does like problem
written like suzuki katana but i love
that thing and it's mine so only i can
on oh sorry poop on it
are we PC or PC here right okay who
cares and what for reserved it's a it's
a it's a great great whiskey and or
bourbon I'm not entirely sure which but
it's delicious of course in moderation
so why talk about vehicle security why
care it's an attractive topic
I'll get the elephant out of the room
ever since Chris valasek and Charlie
Miller committed their first kind of
demonstration on wired with Andy
Greenberg of hey we can hack cars now
this isn't hackers this is reality that
exists people have been very interested
in it and I've had the fortunate
opportunity to kind of worked in gently
related to it as you'll find later in
the presentation
my work is specifically related not
necessarily to ec2 hacking even though I
do have one for show-and-tell
that is an engine control unit there's a
lot of acronyms related to vehicles but
it's an attractive topic and yeah also
it's really easy for things to get blown
out of proportion that is from this week
tonight with John Oliver saying
scientists say smelling parts can
prevent cancer which is not true like
like if you actually dig into the
article they don't say that at all and I
feel especially with vehicle security
and people saying oh my god we can have
cars that it's something that like is as
ubiquitous as getting kind of data dumps
from not necessarily like Dropbox but as
often as information disclosures
actually do occur hacking a car is not
as common as you would think and it's
not as easy as you would
think in fact a lot of things have to go
right in the wrong way in order for you
to successfully compromise a car and
actually speak directly to the can bus
through an external entity as in the
talk this morning they had just so
serendipitously happened to have the ECU
direct or sorry the engine control unit
directly linked to the the automotive
dashboard essentially like the display
board they were able to get compromised
on those on the dash but it's kind of
hard to speak to the can unless they
kind of mess up in a particular way and
that was a happy accident for them and
Charlie Miller and Chris valasek
actually did find another happy accident
in their scenario but I'll continue to
talk about that a little bit later but
yeah it's easy for things to get kind of
blown out of proportion it's easy for
people to over speak and kind of not
talk about how hard this is but just
talk about the result and it's not all
doom and gloom
this is nihilist Arby's Twitter which
I'm a big fan of and I have a dark
twisted sense of humor but it's not all
doom and gloom a lot of people like to
think oh my god they're hacking cars oh
my god this is so no if anything it's
actually a great it's a great venture
that we're starting to actually explore
vehicle security because more so than
any other embedded or embedded device or
cluster of computers we trust our cars
probably a lot more than we should and
we put our lives in their hands and it's
good that we are pen testing this it's
good that we are trying to figure out
where weaknesses or vulnerabilities and
these vehicles exist so this is not a
bad thing this it's not a doom and gloom
talk I am gonna bring up some kind of
faulty areas security within these
specific vehicles but it's it's far from
and I don't want you to kind of leave
this thinking oh my god we can hack
vehicles this is terrible this is what's
gonna happen oh my god it's all no it's
not a doom and gloom thing security is
supposed to make a system more robust
and you're trying to make cars more
robust so Oh MB all we are setting a
precedent so nothing more than the
kind of current Apple versus the US the
FBI issue coming up we are setting a
legal precedent so what the states is
it's kind of hard to see from back here
but Michigan politicians want to want
people who have cars to spend the rest
of their lives in prison and that is in
my opinion absolutely ridiculous if you
kill someone with a vehicle you have
committed manslaughter we already have
laws on the books for that if you have
your car didn't do it what are you
accomplishing it's not necessarily
getting the same goal across trying to
set legal precedent in a negative way
yes true it's also how we had what is it
the there was supposed to be a backdoor
chip that was supposed to be implemented
in all you know that was in 1990s or so
there's suppose to be a backdoor chip
implemented in all security devices and
it failed immediately because that's not
how this works that's not how good
photography there works that's not how
computing systems work so we're sending
a legal precedent and we need people to
be informed on vehicle security to kind
of write the knee-jerk reactions of our
fellow politicians and our
representatives so this is this is on us
this is as a security group this is this
is our responsibility as well also you
might see some stuff from a mobile like
Leesburg Virginia that is another place
where you might see a lot of knee-jerk
reactions happening quickly and I do
have evidence to kind of go along with
that so we'll continue but what I want
you to leave with from this talk is that
Hagin cars is scary oh my god I'm not
trying to understate that in any
capacity hacking cars is terrifying we
can do something about we're not
helpless
we're not a helpless community
especially you know a group of a roomful
of hackers like we are not helpless in
any way so first comes to defining it
what does vehicle security duh it's in
in a layman's kind of stupid way
I've kind of described it as doing
everything possible to keep your car
performing as intended and keeping you
alive as one of those intentions like
not just necessarily like the vehicle
performing well or even optimally but
just like not knee-jerk reaction
careening into a ditch or things of that
nature and a car is kind of stupid it go
well it's smart in a lot of ways but its
intention is just to go fast in a
direction park eventually that's pretty
much it but I like to actually because a
computer is or sorry a car is an
amalgamation of several different
embedded systems
it's probably an embedded system problem
so vehicle security really should be
defined us in this standard for computer
security which they set measures that
computer security is the measures and
controls that ensure confidentiality
integrity and CIA of information systems
assets including hardware software
firmware and information being processed
stored and communicated basically that
it's not messed with and and there are
no surprises that's in a nutshell what
you would really like a vehicle to do
you would like it if you turn on the
radio to a certain if you like we'd like
it if the brakes when you press the
brakes down the brakes work they
effectively work and there's no
malformed canned messages being sent
saying no I don't don't don't close the
brakes you don't want that so that's in
a nutshell kind of what I'm kind of
describing so what's the attack service
of a vehicle
sorry vehicle how does the information
flow throughout the system
when inputs the car receive how does one
obtain access to those inputs so as
you'll see there's a variety of several
inputs that are actually in a modern
vehicle I'm trying to keep this light
but yeah we're getting in the
nitty-gritty but like there's cellular
Wi-Fi Bluetooth specifically TPMS is the
tire pressure monitor sensitive so
that's kind of like how and they're
actually been several attacks kind of
taking advantage of that so that's why
they the car hackers Handbook which is I
believe up for auction or up for I don't
mean external to the car
I mean these are the specific inputs
that the car can potentially receive not
necessarily through steering to go in a
specific direction which of course is a
type of input but what type of potential
inputs could come into the ECU or the
automotive CPU so the a or the osep via
a CPU which is controlling with the
dashboard and all the other fancy
features that we like to have in our
modern vehicles this is kind of a better
example if you want to think about it
this is all the stuff that could pretty
much interact with your car we have a
smart phone mote link type app airbag
ECU which the TP what is it I don't
think I show the tire yeah there is TPMS
in the bottom right corner which is
surprisingly noisy like you can listen
to that externally and it screams a lot
of information about a specific vehicle
passive keyless entry of which I
actually am a smart key owner I was
gonna whip it out but my microphone
there but I do want a smart key and I
will talk about smart keys actually in
this in this talk lighting system
there's a whole bunch of things that are
just shattering to and fro back and
forth not necessarily explicitly within
the can bus but also throughout the
vehicle itself so there's a lot of
inputs that your car is both screaming
and listening to so as I mentioned in my
abstract I'm gonna talk about these four
frontiers of vehicle security so as
things are changing as things are
getting kind of terrifyingly different
the landscape is definitely changing I'm
gonna talk about these kind of four
frontiers for vehicle security where
things are changing and what currently
has been presented and kind of existing
vulnerabilities and kind of things to
think about because what I would really
love is for you guys to leave with a
sense of just certain urgency but also
like an understanding of where we are
and where we can go so yeah oh by the
way that is a Nissan Frontier that is
another stupid stupid car joke that is
kind of service ly embedded in this
let's talk you may find other dumb ones
but hopefully they'll be less
stupid it should have four frontiers
yeah you're right
boo
all right so physical access I know I
know so those of you that know me know
that I am an amateur lock-picker
that is within the state of Tennessee
and I do actually do not pick lops I do
not own a lockpick set which is legal
and felony in state of Tennessee is no
longer as I'm not affiliated to a
specific locks locksmiths cool so I'm a
locksmith apprentice yes that is the
best appeal catch-all but physical
access so this has been so international
this has been the historical view of
security just people not getting into
your car not hijacking you having a
physical lock there maybe have that
weird claw that was invented the 1990s
to stop the wheel from turning so you
know the carjackers don't leave even
though they've already drilled through
that and drilled through your ignition
to take control of your car but physical
intrusion is kind of how people have
classically viewed vehicle security and
it's not wrong it's not wrong it's just
not good um and there are three specific
ad there's three specific features that
have been recently in that not recently
but like past 20 years or so that have
helped in this effort but there are
significant ways around them laser cut
keys kind of being the first so as you
can see a laser so well a key ignition
specifically the tumbler within a key
operates in the same way at what a
padlock in the sense that pins go up if
you visit a block picking village you
kind of even recently aware of this bins
go up in the thing turns laser cut keys
actually make this a far more precise
problem and it also works in both
directions as sometimes some keys to
implement and the tolerances are much
higher on a laser cut key making picking
it a timely process and that's kind of
what you want in a weird way the same
way your passwords are never necessarily
bulletproof they're just time sensitive
it just takes a long time
for someone to actually brute-force the
specific passwords some until the you
know heat death of the universe but
still it increases the number of
increase in the amount of time it would
take in order for you as a lock picker
in order to file a specific final
specific pins necessary to actually pick
the lock it's not necessarily foolproof
and it does have another mechanism
within it called a transponder the
transponders are obviously a combination
between transmitter responder and it's
in this weird kind of collaboration with
the key to let you know that the right
key is in the ignition in order for you
to turn the key and start the car so I
says the key is good the ECU which I
actually have below and I should just
kinda bring it out now which is the
engine control unit and I brought one
for my job but in a nutshell this is it
it's appraised your car this runs
Windows 10 in that weird window stands
in your car you don't want it to but
here it is oh you'll notice that it
actually has if I kind of covered
specific port it looks awfully familiar
as many of you computer nuts will know
but it does have WLAN support and two
sim cards which Charlie Miller and Chris
valasek took advantage of in their kind
of infamous attack to attack car
remotely via cellular exploit so I was
kind of in the mood to pass this around
just it rattles but like don't break it
so it is already broken but it is not
quite like - well in a way there is a
physical aspect and as I'll turn so I'll
finish the statement and then I'll
actually get back to that question or
I'll finish the slide and get back to
the question so the ECU sends a message
to the key the car starts it the ECU has
a correct response basically there's an
encrypted code within the transponder of
the key to actually communicate to the
immobilizer within the actual car if it
has bad key the immobilizer which
actually stops the direct fuel injection
into the car so i'm sure your car will
turn a crank but it won't actually spend
it won't spit new gas into the english
and so your car won't start kind of like
a weird abstract way of kind of viewing
it the emission actually has an
encrypted code within it the transponder
a views so you might see a little black
ring around your admission that's a key
an antenna that's supposed to
communicate that's receiving the
information from the transponder to send
that data to the internal ECU which is
going to take that speak to the
immobilizer the immobilise was like oh I
recognize that code okay totally fine I
will begin to send ignition oh we begin
to start the fuel injection process
which I think after 1980 most cars are
actually fuel-injected now or at least
some form of it you don't have a
carburetor in your car in the classic
car which is quite old it is within a
few inches however I will get to relay
attacks which are ways some ways that's
representing that absolutely not it is a
terrible POS which is why and made in
2007 but it is still carbureted so yeah
if you're all paranoid just buy a
motorcycle and risk your life as I do
trying to sell my bike that so but yeah
essentially this is kind of how it works
and if everything's going well the CPU
will actually speak to the ignition in
the injection parts and then your car
will start however if everything's not
present it shouldn't start that being as
it may there are ways around it
specifically relay attacks and hey just
drilling through the ring through the
ignition actually physically turning the
crank sometimes can can actually bypass
this however smart keys are a recent
invention so as recent as and I don't
actually have the dual screen that I was
supposed to my notes are not up so let's
wing it
I think it's recent as 1995 I think it
was in a Mercedes Benz I actually have
notes specifically on this but smart
keys meaning hey I'm actually gonna
reach into here and try to dig these
don't help me okay so I specifically
have I'm covering the rest of my house
keys here because this is being recorded
smokey I'm not done so it's a smart key
which allows you to unlock your car
unlock your trunk within a specific
limited range and actually I found out
that and even start your car but I found
that the internal Ella field
specifically related to the ignition is
actually so only supposed to have a
tolerance of 10 centimeters meaning
people with your key can't just yank
your key out of the car interest started
kidney you need to be physically in the
car in order to actually start that
however that can be circumvented with
some pretty some pretty neat relay
attacks and some clever ingenuity but
I'll get on that but yeah so keyless
cars are a recent invention but they're
also another mechanism that's supposed
to add another layer of physical
security to the device and so these are
the kind of ways you can kind of
circumvent that really attacks
essentially meaning hey if I let's say
I'm in a contract in an airport bathroom
and someone is aware of that I have
someone hanging out in the stall next to
me and then there is a recipient next to
my physical car they know that I have
some top-secret documents I'm a
government shield working in or a noun
so why not and they need access to my
trunk so they would actually have a
relay within listening to my key which
is very noisy and loud because it's a
smart key screaming out and trying to
send those same messages basically
they're relayed to the trunk which now
has the other agent to kind of like next
to my trunk relaying the other device
and opening the trunk so that's a very
simple attack but you can also so these
keys are the specific keys are actually
supposed to roll over well you can jam a
specific signal in or actually prevent
key relevant because it doesn't
recognize the other side of the key so
it keeps us retrying the same key and
you can use that to your advantage you
can perform forward prediction attacks
dictionary attacks which is a form of
brute force you can drill to the crank
to actually start a mission which is
another actual type of brute force
this is a surprising way cars are kind
of currently being broken into Memphis
is actually the still number one as far
as car thefts or grand theft auto and
all the things if you have a lot of
intimate time with the car you can
actually pull code from the immobilizers
memory and just directly respond to to
the the request the immobilizers
requirement no the immobilizer so some
people have are so depending on the
specific type of car there are two types
are immobilizers and others one sorry
only present this one type immobilizer
which stops the fuel injection can
happen well there's another where it
will actually kind of prevent the crank
from turning what people do often I
think in 2005 or later there's like a
little pin that stops the crank from
moving to actually physically start the
car they will drill through the actual
like like they'll actually bring up huge
big drill and drill through the ignition
to knock out that pin and then they
physically turn the crank with a
screwdriver in order to get the car
crank and go and they just throw a fake
key in and pretend like everything's
fine for vehicle stop points but it is a
problem so moving on to the infamous ODB
two-port as you guys a little where this
is your kind of direct link into the
heart of your car which I will kind of
just the canvas is kind of how you speak
it's how you speak car to your car it's
it controls things such as not just
Diagnostics but also your brakes
steering in some ways depending on the
features enabled by your car there's a
variety of messages that you can send me
a can that can be compromised if you
have direct access to this Odin going to
point and the ECU which I've recently
passed malware is that by the way I do
need to keep track of it hey okay
just making sure how you're booting it
you you loading up windows down maybe
you're really excited about it so and
the ECU is the invented device that
cannon uses can to speak to various
parts of the car to make your brakes
break and things of that nature so would
it be - speaks can and this is the camp
protocol it was alluded to in the
previous talk but I'll kind of walk
through the individual parts of it
there's an arbitration field which is
basically the ID of the advice trying to
communicate and IDE or the identifier
extension which is just a kind of
standard bit the same way kind of the I
am comparing this to TCP a bit later but
just kind of a standard there's the data
length which is the size of the data
being sent and of course the data now if
we compare this to TCP your kind of
notice that there's some things missing
I won't necessarily call TCP a robust
protocol but it works you know for the
internet and there are some things
missing for example sequence numbers to
prevent replay attacks right like you
know that a sequence number specifically
corresponds to a specific conversation
and compromising a sequence number is
difficult almost impossible but
difficult there are offsets their
specific flags sent you know there are
some improvements on it such as a window
size no this is really present in the
canvas it's an embedded device designed
to speak to all of the other embedded
devices within it as such it's typically
broadcasted there's no authentication
and it's kind of fragile to das attacks
there's in a paper I will lead to
earlier from 2010 by the University of
Berlin the University of Washington
let's say that it's really vulnerable to
fuzzing like you don't want to scream a
lot cuz it will break and you'll break
your car and you can't turn your car on
again oh my god so so eat and and some
ECU's employ a challenge and response
mechanism which these researchers found
that can kind of make it difficult but
not necessarily undefeatable so all this
is basically to say that as far as the
physical access from to you getting in
your cars
the symbol this is an infamous xkcd kind
of basically describing that your
specific view of security may not
actually be in line with realities view
of security as I mentioned there's a lot
of reasons people are still bringing the
drill to a grand theft auto like it
works and there are ways to get in so
this is actually interesting unless you
implement something as complicated as
the south of Africa was the South Africa
implemented blaster which is two
flamethrowers on the side of your car
has kept attorney there's a whole video
correlated to this but I kind of didn't
want to bring that up but yeah it's
surprisingly effective and also illegal
in America for all the right reasons for
a time yes yeah for a time yes so yeah
gosh I mean yeah yeah it doesn't so so
these are the common tools like when you
think of vehicle secured specifically
physical access like this is bringing a
transponder and a relay it's not what's
done it's a set of like slim jims like
actually picking into the passenger side
door it's a clothes hanger or worse a
piece of string which is kind of a
popular YouTube clip of people throwing
a piece of string into the door and just
lifting the lock or as I demonstrate or
not demonstrate because I love to but
show off in this YouTube video the
porcelain of a spark plug so it's gonna
buzz a bit but hopefully this award
fine got in Mike's dad yeah it's pretty
simple so good so if you want to get
into a car it ain't hard it's not
exactly it's kind of trivial as long as
you're willing to deal with you know a
few consequences like a busted
windshield getting in the car is not a
problem
he took the hard ionized part of the
porcelain of a spark plug through it at
medium strength and this is actually as
specific part of it through a medium
strength at the tempered glass of a
window if you remember tempered glass is
he's cool in such a way that it is
resistant to a lot of a lot of kind of
just not attacks and try think in
pentesting way basically it keeps her
from sharding and when breaking in like
a dangerous way so it breaks in little
tiny pebbles when it does however it
only requires a very small point of
impact and because the porcelain is so
hard
yeah getting your bars so I've seen
Andrews bounce off
yes Parminder but not not sparkly yeah
no no video yeah a piece of normal force
on all the toilet and both of them
bounce off whatever class No so
basically I'm just like well make sense
like that's physical texts are where
this would give you slack severe car
those probably kind of even-tempered
there's a lot of matters being developed
but at the same time
very very important force ways of
getting into your car beeping so how to
prevent malicious attacks those nation
states you know malicious people so I'm
going to get into remote attacks let's
talk about Charlie let's talk about
those two guys because they need hands
now changed
my red ball which I should be
considering was said by Marcus so this
is dr. trebla night without a second
papers they're all the love and they
kind of go through many pages of how we
did it's an extensive paper incredible
read personally this is initially they
found that they were kind of mechanics
to annex which is Lexus with the Jeep
they proved that I don't week the gates
backwards
but actually just said there are only so
few passwords so it was a remote
compromise of key driver functions was
essentially what they were able to
accomplish and this is unprecedented and
I think it's because of the means that
they used to get there oh and they put
Andy Greenberg in a ditch which is that
an actual videos they really sent him
careening in there kind of reckless
honestly his pen testers kind of
questioning the ethical part of their
whole hacking but you know he asked for
it he did ask them to show him something
interesting so what did they do what
they did essentially and this is a giant
paraphrasing of their 90 page paper
please read it it is worth it but I'm
gonna paraphrase it in five bullets
which grossly under state the amount of
work that they spent but basically they
scanned the vehicle for through the
Sprint network in order to get specific
IP and they actually for ipv4 of the
sprint vehicle on Sprint or of the Jeep
on the Sprint network after that they
were able to tether via cell phone to
the car and exploit specifically the ODB
chip so basically think of the ODB chip
within the jeep is kind of like the
display it's kind of like the dash and
the initial kind of media center for the
car they were not able to it also had
Wi-Fi which they actually found it was
useful but not nearly as kind of like
wow as the as the cellular network which
actually did expose I think port six six
six seven which is a well-known IRC port
I do know that they did expose port six
six six seven which is what they were
able to use to specifically send
messages to the ODB chip but after that
so they were able to get on the ODB chip
but they weren't able to speak directly
to can so unlike the previous talk given
earlier this morning where the ECU and
the kind of dashboard the ODB was
directly connected they weren't they
were air gap in Andy Greenberg's G so
they had to and and they speak over SV
our spy so they had to specifically
within three months of some hardcore Ida
and a lot of time reverse engineer the
spy bus in order to actually send direct
messages to can so this is the hand
waving oh it took so long part of it and
it's non-trivial it's it's it's a fair
amount of work but after which they were
actually able to get through my car's
firmware to install to install an
exploit via USB or X sorry B USB but
specifically the spy port
I think that's mislabeled party but the
end result was basically sending canned
messages to the vehicle via a cellular
signal and I think if you're on Sprint
now you'll realize port six six six
seven is blocked
can't send it over spray which is
interesting but what they were looking
for initially was they'd start targeting
cars with auto parking features and you
might think why Auto parking well it's a
weird specific thing to target it's
because your car is parking which means
it has control over over acceleration
and theory even more so than cruise
control steering it actually can control
where your cars going so if they can
actually compromise auto targeting they
both have acceleration and steering but
here's what not a lot of people talk
about they weren't alone in 2010 there's
a paper experimental security analysis
of modern automobiles written by a
researchers at the University of
Washington University San Diego that did
a physical cyber physical threat model
of a modern automobile and they
identified and exploited a lot of issues
that were exercised by Charlie Miller
and Chris valasek yeah about five years
earlier Charlie Miller is once again
about five years earlier like and had no
response from the community no one was
screaming oh my god these researchers
had totally broken into cars and I think
it's because they were specifically
accessing the ODB two-port in order to
get a lot of these firmwares accomplices
kind of into the system and then they
were able to compromise them
so they were like alright cool let's do
it again in 2011 they decided to go
through a variety of wireless attacks in
order to compromise the machine and the
same researchers or at least a large
majority of them and they investigated
both cellular Bluetooth and FM RDS which
is like your CD player and one of the
coolest things and I mean coolest they
were able to hack the car and install a
malevolent or a malicious firmware
through a CD they hacked the car by mix
tape and that's so cool
basically the at the time I mean this is
2011 so cars were actually updating some
of the more impressive features of the
dashboard and their CD players by CD so
they were able to actually eject a
firmware update into the CD and broke a
lot of surprisingly broke a lot of CD
players in the process and I thought
that that line listed in the paper was
hilarious because you can see on top of
their like whole research deck is like
just a sack the second wall and it's
just dead from all their exploits but I
was just gonna say my brother's a he's a
mechanic over at Lexus of Knoxville you
know and I we often talk about attack
surface of cars because he really knows
the car but he doesn't think about it
that way and that totally makes sense to
the CD because they use DVDs to update
the maps for the nav system you know
it's not just for playing audio yeah
that's how they actually ship updates
for the recording yeah being able to
update maps and accessories for the CD
players is it is an attack service and
not a lot of people are keenly aware of
and kind of take for granted but
definitely can be optimized or can be
leveraged by a sophisticated attacker
even DARPA was involved and DARPA Dan
Daniel Kaufman remotely demonstrated all
of the attacks listed in the paper once
again around 2010 2011 and in it he
showed that you can you know have remote
acceleration you can cut the brakes you
could turn on windshield wipers like
just kind of arbitrarily control the
system via exploits on the can bus and
yeah he too
a reporter by the way he works at Google
and Charlie Miller Chris valasek now
work at uber so goes to show like their
vested interests in trying to prevent
this sort of stuff so but what I want to
kind of leave you with especially for
remote attacks is the influence of
software and they're all kind of feature
driven ABS allows software to control
brakes cruise control allows software to
control acceleration specifically
stagnant or increasing because you have
a little button that says go faster on
your cruise control you never touch the
pedal so auto parking control steering
and in the near future and I do mean
near they're trying to implement apps
for your car so you can download last.fm
app a SiriusXM map things of that nature
are trying to be designed I know you're
grimacing I know I know but this is the
future this is the unavoidable future we
are walking into and self-driving I mean
is it Christmas like seriously are you
going to completely give away all of the
driving ability to your car and the
answer unanimously from the consumer is
oh my god yes like but like we want to
give ourselves to these cars we don't
want to necessarily drive them all the
time and they might make smarter
decisions than we do so if that's going
to be the case if this is our inevitable
future how can we best protect it wait
until cars can talk to each other oh
it's gonna be mine I actually had a lot
of salmon oh this is the okay so you
kind of cheated but here's the trivia
thing okay how many so I'm going to talk
about electric vehicles and this is kind
of one of the third frontier that were
talk about but how many electric
vehicles I got to keep track of time how
many electric vehicles are currently and
I'm I'm willing to
I don't know prices right prices what
closest without going over
how many electric charging stations are
present in knoxville currently 47
I'm gonna say one per my oh they can
drive 147 ok Hertz 75 75 right there are
80 80 charging station so I don't know
what I give you so simple with a
Knoxville work I will say the greater
Knoxville area because yes I include Oak
Ridge all the LA and Farragut s which is
a different city yeah whatever they're
80 they're about 80 charging stations
with a Knoxville so even us we are we
are getting into this field like we
thought we were comes or you think that
we're small we're not necessarily kind
of involved no we are we're keenly
involved the more charging stations kind
of popping up everyday and it look rich
alone accounts for 10 of them so about 9
of 10 so like we're getting intimately
involved and and electronic vehicles
actually are going to kind of control a
large majority of the market share this
is a Bloomberg report saying that in
2012 let your vehicle's will cost the
same as about their internal combustion
counterparts basically yes this is Tesla
I will just go ahead and say that that's
Tesla $35,000 is an attractive offer for
a completely automated vehicle and it's
only going to get like not necessarily
worse but electronic vehicles are going
or specifically electric vehicles are
gonna be a large majority of the market
share in the near future so it's kind of
an unavoidable certainty that they will
be an issue that we can ignore aside
from an impending real Isis an electric
vehicles will have additional
Diagnostics more software influence than
what I just listed before because not
only is it just monitoring that it's
also monitoring the battery maybe it
might be smart enough to know GPS and
telemetry to find nearest charging
stations because that's keenly important
to an electronic vehicle
or to someone that owns an electronic
vehicle and good software is not perfect
software right like we know that there
are buds in this code and so more
features tends to play to more problems
and I didn't know about this today one
thing I didn't really think about as far
as electric vehicles ransomware there is
actually tests little ransomware that as
of today finally got the master key
like revealed because they just decided
that we're not gonna do it yeah people
can ransomware your car like that
medicine that is that is an inevitable
future that did not really realize until
this morning I was kind of like reading
through my newsfeed today and yeah like
people are doing this as a February 2015
people were ransom wearing cars so like
that's a serious problem of someone kind
of compromising the car in a very
different way than we were originally
anticipated and finally in connected
vehicles so unlike everything I've kind
of babbled about this is kind of the
thing I actually know the most / least
about as in I am now into the field and
you know when you begin when you begin
to understand a specific subject you
realize how little you actually know but
our cars talking to each other and this
is a personal opinion I will completely
recognize that is an unavoidable future
but kind of one that we don't
necessarily need to be reluctant to
embrace so I'm gonna kind of throw up
some some terminology I hate doing that
because I don't like acronyms but it's
kind of important so there's V to V
which is vehicle to vehicle video i've
you know infrastructure which is kind of
like this basically all the vehicles in
your specific system kind of talking to
you're very very very busy intersection
there's B to X which is talking about
anything which is kind of something I'm
not actually as much of a fan of as much
as I am the V - V and V - i aspects and
there's the intelligent transport system
which is basically the giant network
graph that you would draw between all of
the individual nodes in this network and
I say sorry so our cars will be able to
speak to one another through a
department of transportation
or each other vehicle and it's not like
a cellphone cuz a lot of people are like
whoa oh my gosh you could you know track
anywhere yeah the government knows well
yes and kind of no it's not like a cell
phone in the sense that it's in your car
by law like that is it currently reached
a notice of proposed law our rulemaking
meaning it's on the books to be voted on
as far as becoming a potential law
people are writing protocols for it it's
it's impending the sensor is far more
accurate actually than GPS I did have on
my notes here kind of the specific type
of sensor but it is at least at the very
least as accurate as modern commercial
GPS systems it has a higher sampling
rate meaning even though your phone what
kind of sample between specific moments
the sampling rate for your car is much
more frequent as active measuring time
and the Vita I components facilitated by
do T meaning unlike Verizon which has to
get a subpoena before they released
certain aspects of like your SMS or
whether or not you were listening to
Spotify as you enter the crash these are
kind of owned by d-o-t and it's not
sending out arbitrary data in that
nature it's not a cell phone it's
screaming out stuff like I am the size I
am going this fast things that are kind
of done generic and should be adequately
anonymized for your specific vehicle and
I kind of want to accurately portray the
promise of v2v because it's hands down
one of the most unattractive listed so
far but the Department of Transportation
believes that this can actually improve
safety it can enable more robust crash
prevention and if fully implemented in a
robust system it can prevent 80% of like
stupid crashes as in I'm looking at my
phone and I don't recognize it so that's
happening it turns out that's a traffic
accident up ahead but I'm agitated so
I'm feeling off into the the far right
lane even though I shouldn't things of
that nature it can also improve
congestion because everyone's keenly
aware of when they should
shouldn't he can send sort of they can
relay information of a potential crash
kind of further up and daisy-chain its
way up to or up a specific highway to
kind of inform all users that there's a
crash ahead and I believe lessen this
but hopefully by more efficient travel
we can also reduce the kind of harm on
the environment from a specific impact
per commute because not everyone's gonna
be merging in our lanes hopefully and by
having a more efficient traffic system
we'll hopefully have a better one that
can impact the environment this is an
example of kind what I was talking about
earlier this is but basically this is
kind of a demonstration of an oncoming
vehicle so let's say that someone
stopped ahead
there's someone stopped in the middle of
the highway instead of everyone kind of
creating around that person potentially
causing more incidences the emergency
response vehicle will have sent a huge
alert to the rest of the corresponding
vehicles which will then kind of pick up
on that and they'll kind of
automatically being or they'll
automatically inform the driver hey you
need to get into the far left lane you
need to get out of the way there's an
incident up ahead and just kind of a
warning without having to patiently wait
for NPR to get to the new section for
you to be aware of a potential traffic
incident it's kind of important like you
can just be aware of that without having
to check your phone and did travel which
most of us do and it can it can really
help congestion so that's one of the
promising aspects of it and this is the
new new new new new this is where I
believe as researchers or security
researchers or even it's just people
keenly aware of security and kind of
where things are going we can make the
biggest impact and of course it's
inevitable so this is the official
notice of proposed rulemaking to begin
implementation of vehicle-to-vehicle
communications technology so it is
coming so we should
right it's kind of my caveat I can't be
admire so where do I as a dude that's
standing before you kind of fit into all
this
well I work out a bridge and oak ridge
is actually working on the specific
front so what you'll see is this is
actually research done at the lab not
specifically within my group I will get
into that but this is us capturing
multimodal sensor data so in a nutshell
I'm going to completely butcher their
research but basically they take a
variety of bits of information from a
specific vehicle and they basically make
it a signature uniquely identifying that
vehicle and the range finders detect
vehicle information measure distance
speed and the alarm triggers opposed to
camera snapshots and so what I really
like to kind of correlate that into is
sure being able to give each individual
of a device or each individual car kind
of a signature or some sort of like
unique fingerprint for that specific
vehicle is nice but where it really
lines up to is like Amber Alerts what if
you tie this in to the video I and you
notice that there and I asked the
question and I know was a Casey Trent
was recently found but how many other
white vans were stopped how many white
Dodge vans were stopped to actually find
her like like they liked her specific
car was not the only one on the road and
if we actually had better telemetry and
better metrics in order to and what if
other cars were not just participating
what if other car participating they
knew that the specific vehicle
information from this car was requested
and they all started itching but this
actually telling each other that hey
these cars are around me and they have
this specific signature and I noticed
that they received that from me we may
have been able to find let's find out a
lot sooner so this is definitely a case
that kind of needs to be investigated
but definite has potential right this is
something more abused yeah what was that
movie there was some movie where they
you know tapped and it might have been a
Marvel movie were they tapped into the
cell network like all over the world to
find stuff that is that into a knowing
verse but I think you're giving it way
too much credit it's it's much dumber
than you think
yeah like what it's actually the same
concept lifespan crowdsourcing like
essentially you're crowdsourcing or
yours crowdsourcing but also there's an
aspects of what specific Kennedys and
these signatures are unique but there's
a lot of noise in the natural world in
this cases this is specifically just
research to see if it's even possible to
a specific very honest
let's look at it from the standpoint if
if I'm because I know of a particular
case in this situation this is why the
guy gave up on the car you've been
waiting on for three years if you're an
attorney and you're going to you're
going to interview somebody for your
case and you don't want the other side
to know about it and now you've got
something that's tracking your system in
your car who manages that who's watching
The Watcher because now you're in a
situation now where that information if
you're going to retain that for a longer
period of time we already know we got
IRS agents who can't be watched you know
how does this go you're now at a point
where if you're in those type of secure
situations in you're one of those people
that does not need to be watched at that
point I mean it gives it makes me want
to go back and refinish restoring my 73
Cutlass and start driving that around
town because you know there's my answer
at that point cuz I've still got the
first car I ever bought so I take that
sucker to start driving it and I don't
worry about it but you know there's a
side to this from the investigative what
about the side with the investigation
needs to be kept quiet of course I
obviously have no idea as far as other
objections for of course it says
potential abuse I'm not going to ignore
that regardless of my government show
however I don't know
to be completely honest with you I think
we shut like what my I believe you saw
me is that all this stuff is strictly
research just to see how things work and
how it can all be done I don't think
it's being I don't think did you dicier
is going to be doing anything with this
data no no no this is being exercised in
any capacity oh yeah I think I think
your fears for the future are well a
well-worn however I have no idea as far
as where this could be a blood at this
point I mean sensors have to broadcast
out there you know serial number all the
time
why are they so chatty and why is what I
interrogated I don't know I don't I do
not necessarily exactly why they are so
many ways you correctly I know easy and
they do have documented and published
exploits against the way the other thing
it was other that's basically push
approach rather than a poll of yes it is
a Dacian purse
other than the fact that you would like
to know when you're kind of pressures
low inside the tire right so you can't
physically I'm glad you guys just from
my point of view very Maya haven't
exactly done research on but I do
believe that it has to it does hats
spew out like several information just
that way it actually sends it to the
right car and whatnot like you don't
want to pick up tire pressure
information of another car and also I
think the tire pressure monitors much
like other other technologies and
protocols idns they were they were made
and they work very well however I don't
think they were made with security and
mine at the time better which is
come on vehicle to vehicle communication
vehicle to infrastructure communication
you're saying it's gonna be anonymized
I'm thinking they're gonna anonymize it
but still send the VIN number out okay
so a PK is actually a way so one of the
biggest questions in this is how do
camera company trust a message sent from
a specific vehicle how can you even
guarantee that it's going to be
trustworthy and this is actually
something I'm closer to go subscribe to
Jason Carter and she led this project
which was developed a protocol or at
least one of the close measures in order
to guarantee vehicle to vehicle
communication actually determine what is
or is not trustworthy essentially they
developed an algorithm to ensure driver
entities and movements remain anonymous
and kind of non amaizing this
information is critical it's okay that
you know because we are kind of in a
habit of sending out our information but
anonymizing as much of this as possible
is pivotal so in a nutshell and I'm
grossly overstating his research but
essentially the vehicle itself would
kind of be an intermarried into WACA
it would kind of produce and sign its
own certificates you cannot hold it hold
on your phone it can produce and sign
and verify specific key pairs those are
sent of course to other vehicles which
then have a banks of specific key pairs
and they're kind of trusted through
group signatures as kind of the name
before so this is kind of how specific
message is sent from one to another or
this is a proposed measure I mean to say
how specific messages from one vehicle
to another are trusted it also adds a
bit of privacy because these pseudonyms
will actually change far more frequently
than a standard certificate from I guess
the web or through TLS or SSL and are
private to each individual vehicle as an
intermediary so yeah and the group
signatures
kind of preserve their privacy through
cryptographic pains
so people are sense of about the travel
data but I would like to reiterate kind
of that we've all kind of adopted a fair
amount of we've all adopted heaven or
not necessarily relaxed approach but we
all share more information I think than
we intend to and especially our tongue
kind of being the main culprit for that
these slides are not mine
these are slightly stolen by Jason but
it kind of brings up an interesting
point in that we are sharing a lot of
information kind of already and we kind
of on the forefront of oil the fact that
we're setting a precedent is that we're
going to share what is it this is
Florida's Department of Transportation
one of the spokesman said we're going to
share information our camera images all
our information that comes from the
sensors on the road right and Waze is
going to share its data with us like
like that's very interesting and I'm
glad that maybe the Department of
Transportation of Florida is all adamant
about trying to share as much of its
roadway data but I mean to what end and
especially the consider these locations
private we need to be more teaming aware
of kind of where this is going so I
don't so I'm kind of welcoming your your
paranoia but I kind of also would like
to bring up that we kind of self Jack
ourselves I personally know to Fitbit I
know exactly what I can or cannot relay
because I have seen my own traffic and I
am surprisingly lazy I pretty much work
out like one day a week and that read
the rest of that bar is pretty steady oh
but we do track ourselves through a
variety of applications it's not
necessarily our phone screaming out but
we voluntarily partake in it two other
corporate entities so the d-o-t try to
get it to save your life
necessarily isn't another one that's
that it's completely disinterested
because they want people to stay alive
that's a good report for them so
you know there is cynicism but let's
make sure it's well metered so I put the
slide in specifically to show you that
this information is public this is where
you can get it but this is the
de-identified leesburg data it can kind
of show you infrequent visitations and
this is time just to demonstrate if you
do have adequate video I like vehicle to
infrastructure information and it's
being pulled kind of through either
frequent or infrequent visitations you
can kind of learn an awful lot about a
particular not even necessarily a
particular user this is not necessarily
one specific instance but kind of a
group of them kind of what's travelled
what's not looking much like a sim city
graph if you're a fan of that video game
which I definitely am and had to stop
for all the right reasons
but it asked it it really asks a lot of
really interesting we had identified Rio
Dental ignition identification questions
which is like what if there's a large
cluster of Geo points how do we indicate
denser so traffic if they're all kind of
moving in a herd
what about customers of small geo points
can we estimate velocity things of that
nature so I'm kind of camera through
this because I'm running out of time but
yeah you can custom for patterns and try
to see individual patterns and kind of
where that lines in and where that goes
and the breadcrumbs of our data provide
a rich identifying data source so yeah I
think that's kind of kind of reiterating
yes so so then in that show cars are
down on the Iowa yeah it's pretty much
fun especially with the connected
vehicle technology that's something we
really can't avoid security is a moving
target and interested parties want to
keep you safe also interested parties
want to keep what to cause you harm I'm
I'm not buttering this up in some sort
of fantasy land like this is the reality
that we live in
some like the d-o-t and other enemies
especially government innings are kind
of interested in just keeping people
alive it's kind of bad for people to
just die
there are it's not all super conspiracy
bad stuff however yeah there there's
also malicious energies that work and
the laws are in their infancy like
people are reacting more so than just
being proactive about the laws currently
being written on these sort of things so
keep that in mind the next time you vote
or the next time you write your
Congressman so any talk I want it so
hood if you actually want to be a part
of this what if you actually want to you
know brandish a flag and march forward
well I have a good news for you so
there's a vehicle security center
actually located up the hill at Oak
Ridge National Labs that we're trying to
develop and this is the national
research transportation center this is
actually an image of it in there we got
a fold I know I've got a huge giant
toolkit we have car shark we have a
giant big ol monitor that you can view
and a bunch of other stuff that's
currently being developed to like assist
people that are trying to do vehicle
security within Knoxville yeah I know
the guys in I know there was a talk
earlier supposed to give out vehicle
security but unless you want to fly to
Israel I don't think you can exercise a
lot of their tools up there but we have
one locally and currently seeking
proposals so if you do have an interest
the pricing has not yet been solidified
but talk to oh I have them up ahead
president yeah been solidified and the V
sees that but I want to kind of
reiterate that the VCS is not exclusive
to or an out like talk to us let us know
and hacking the car the kind of leaving
thought I want to give you guys this
hacking of cars terrifying but we can do
something you're not as completely
crippled to the impending kind of future
that we have ahead of us you can take
part in it we can be a part of it so
that's so that's what I want to really
leave with not necessarily that it's all
doom and gloom oh my god they're
tracking this but like hey like let's
make sure that this is done proper let's
make sure that this is done well let's
make sure that if people are interested
the picture that they have proper acts
this sort of stuff so that's what I
really want to make you guys aware these
are the guys who took contact about the
lab Jason Carter specifically asked to
be photograph from the Iron Throne he's
also the guy heading the
the VP ki kind of infrastructure and
Stacey is heading the specific lab and
that's me