ameritech links he's going to be talking
about for Joe Marler how's everyone
doing this morning so I got I got asked
to speak last minute about crypto
malware I guess mr. gamblin couldn't
make it today so hence my somewhat
humorous but informative slide with the
line through letting folks know that
there's been a little bit of a change in
the schedule even as of this morning so
I hope you guys are all doing well did
do we finally get the the talk across
the street the hacking automotive
security going over there did was
anybody over there this morning okay
good was it was it good I'm going to
have to watch it later because I didn't
get a chance to get over there so well
hey guys I want to keep this a little
bit interactive this morning so please
you know as I'm going through this if
you guys have questions or comments or
heckling remarks as Kevin Thomas tends
to have you know just go ahead and shout
those out and there might even be
something in it for you so a little bit
about myself I'm the info SEC team lead
at tech links a little company here in
town do managed services and value-added
reseller I have around 15 years and
information security experience
co-founded the East Tennessee Issa
chapter here in Knoxville to help try to
bring the information security community
together increase knowledge sharing and
to help improve the the market here in
Knoxville for information security
professionals as well as raise security
practices here so at tech links
I assess and advise companies of
security best practices and I had in my
slides yesterday best in quotation marks
because a friend of mine Slade Griffin
shoutout to Slade says that you know
best is up for discussion it's really
more like common practice and so you
know the the best practice that we all
say you know best practices we hear that
industry Mont mantra is is really
debatable right what is best for us so
some of wort what we're here to talk
about today is the practices that we see
and and so I've started using the term
common practice because I think there's
always room for growth and it's a
continual improvement process you know
that that we have to continually get can
continually keep getting better at what
we do so that being said I've done work
here locally and nationally for
companies like Oak Ridge National Lab US
Army a company up in ohio called
reynolds and reynolds a software
development company for automotive
dealer management systems also you know
my free time I'm a worship leader I like
to keep an eye on the the threat trends
and I'm married celebrating ten years
this year to my wife Kristen and we we
have three daughters that we love dearly
so you know some of that threat trend
analysis is really what precipitated
this talk and so happy to share with you
guys today a collection of knowledge
from a lot of resources that are
smattered across the internet as well as
some of my own analysis that i've done
so without further ado let's move on I
want to just make mention I made mention
here
a minute ago about is a SI East
Tennessee chapter here's some
information for you guys if you're
wanting more info on that check us out
on Twitter or at our website etn Issa
org and the reason that i have this up
here is because one of the great
benefits of the information systems
security association is this little
publication that's put on by members
called the ISS a journal and it's a
monthly publication and in april
actually the feature article was on
cryptolocker and so one of the things
that you guys can do is scan this
completely benign and totally honest a
QR barcode right here if you like and
read this article for free I promise
that it's not a malicious QR code you
can come find me later and beat me up if
it is so these slides will be available
you know on SlideShare with the links as
well as I have a resource page I
published on my blog that go along with
these slides so I really encourage you
guys to check out the ISS a journal and
this article is really really good
pretty much he pretty much stole my
entire talk so I'm put in a journal
article so before we have a chance to
read that I'm going to go ahead and
finish the talk up so last June you know
the FBI put out an advisory through ic3
about crypto wall and just stating that
you know crypto wall and its variants
have been used actively to target us
victims since april 2014 and the
financial impact of victims goes well
beyond the ransom fee itself which is
you know typically 202 $10,000 I've
heard numbers as high as twenty
twenty-five thousand dollars depending
on the organization and what the
the malware developers are able to
determine from the infection who they're
dealing with and then then you know
inflate those fees and so you know as
we're considering the reasons for this
particular type of malware I think it's
really this is a really insightful
advisory to kind of keep in mind so how
many folks here have this is maybe your
first time here and about cryptolocker I
really hope that's not the case anybody
okay does anybody care to maybe tell us
a little bit about things that they know
about cryptolocker share a few things
anybody know you're gonna let me you
know let me fly solo today all right so
you know cryptolocker is a crypto
malware it's ransomware and encrypts
your files holds them for ransom you
know which is by nature extortion that
an act of extortion initially released
September 2013 targets all versions of
Windows encrypts files by file type
we'll get into a list a little bit later
but it's it's essentially everything
useful when the encryption action is
complete you're presented with a ransom
note that that may include heckling of
various forms in the the most recent
versions and demands of payments you
from you know in older versions two
hundred dollars now on average is more
around five to nine hundred dollars
depending on the value of Bitcoin or
whatever currency that is being demanded
and then that can range up quite high as
as I had mentioned previously you're
given a timed period you know a time
window where we're in you need to pay
that ransom in order to be giving your
data back if you don't pay the ransom
the malware threatens to delete your
data for good and most of these you know
different various versions of crypto
malware are demanding payment by money
pack or Bitcoin I've pretty even heard
of some recent versions now asking for
amazon gift cards or iTunes gift cards
and some of these things you know they
seem so bizarre and off the wall but
it's basically anything that you know
these developers malware developers can
use anonymously to make money right
we're going to get into a little bit
more of the the making money in a minute
cryptolocker encrypts everything useful
essentially even now going after a
company intellectual property in most
recent versions AutoCAD drawings as well
as other types of you know business
specific documents have been included in
this and here's a little bit of a you
know a consultant statement on and I'll
just read it to you hear this thing hit
pretty much all the file extensions that
are usable for
mp3s to Microsoft Word documents about
the only thing it didn't touch were
system files and exe s encrypting almost
everything else with twenty forty forty
eight bit RSA keys that would take like
a quadrillion years to decrypt once the
infection happens it can even spread
from someone on a home pc using a VPN to
access their work network and for me
that's the most scary part and
interestingly enough crypto wall for and
other more recent variants are now used
have now even increase their key length
to a 4000 bit key length so these
developers are continually making
improvements continually getting smarter
they know that we're trying to defend
against these kinds of threats and so
the advances are are continuing and so
one of the things that one of the
takeaways I'd like to have for you guys
you know during this presentation is
what are some of the more recent
developments and how do we protect
against some of those so looking at the
numbers for some of these you know in
2014 cryptolocker was infecting over
50,000 computers a month peak the u.s.
is the number one targeted country
statistically and in the US over 3,300
36,000 computers have been recorded as
being infected and you know one of the
things that's really interesting is you
know how metadata can be used to
determine what what's happening with
infections like this and one of the
things that is is out there is google
search numbers right so search results
for cryptolocker alone are over 210,000
per month and
it's on the rise and you know that's a
really good indicator of how how big of
an issue this is for people you don't
just go out and you know and I've were
many people just go out and search for
cryptolocker on Google unless they're
looking for an answer to some kind of
problem so which brings us to another
related issue and that's Mel vertising
how many folks the term malvert izing is
new to you it's okay you know if you're
not vulnerable enough to stick your hand
up for some of these questions let me
just tell you that yesterday I made a
bunch of changes to my presentation and
then I'd closed it without saving so so
there now that we're all sharing openly
so Mel vertising is a malicious al
advertisement that's injected through
through an advertisement stream and you
know one of the things that you may be
aware of but may not have a you know
occurred to you in light of how these
threats are propagated is that many
websites today don't control their
advertising stream those ads are served
rendered through a third party service
through an external service and then
displayed through an iframe or a script
of some sort on their website and they
really have next to no control over what
is being displayed there that has become
an excellent vector for infection an
excellent way to serve up our our
malicious software the developers have
identified that and are using that and
so this has really become somewhat of an
Internet pandemic I put on this slide
you know before I forgot to save my
changes
the real cyber pandemic because one of
the other things I've been following
recently is the FBI vs apple case so
who's also watching FBI vs apple and the
things that are you know coming in the
wake of that and I just found it kind of
comical that you know one of the things
that we we had had heard was we need to
unlock the iPhone because it may it may
contain a cyber pathogen so so I had put
on here you know the real cyber pathogen
because it was found later that you know
even that that the the iphone didn't
really in question didn't really contain
a cyber pathogen you know so these types
of things are you know the severity of
this threat is has led to FBI advisory
has led to other things like you know
fortune 500 companies investing highly
in protection against cryptolocker I
find it interesting that sixty-nine
percent of Fortune 500 websites use
external javascript to render portions
of their websites you know we talked
about malvert izing and how JavaScript
can play into that sixty-four percent of
them of those sites running outdated web
apps I think you know one of the apps
that comes to mind you know is WordPress
there's there's a there's a cold fusion
there's a there's a long list you know
of those types of things but I feel like
you know we we've got some so big issues
to handle in advising companies with
this type of capital of how to implement
just common practices keeping those
applications up to date
and and filtering external content so
we've done some case studies through
through you know of our customers at
tech links one of the things that we've
seen is that we're still seeing among
our customers one infection per month
and on average over the past year or
more over five cases in 2015 alone and
healthcare comprised forty forty six
percent of those which may look as you
know a disproportionately high number of
infections but of the customers that we
serve that's actually a representative
number of even across every vertical so
it's not one particular vertical that's
being affected most by this it's every
vertical every industry is being
affected equally it just so happens that
it tech links we have more health care
customers than other customers so if
you're in health care you're just as
likely as any other industry and vice
versa to to be targeted for cryptolocker
alright so you know we talked about the
motivation earlier it's mainly financial
these these developers are looking for
money through Bitcoin moneypak a single
instance could make over 250 thousand
dollars in a month within a corporation
and crypto wall has resulted in over a
million dollars paid out and ransoms and
you know they're after the information
they're after the money but most of all
it's it's just been easy
for these developers to continue doing
this despite law enforcement action
against these developers so here's a
little history about cryptolocker you
know it's gone by many names so we kind
of started with just plain cryptolocker
moved on to the F family in 2014 we saw
the crit Ronnie variants the revit on
variants crowd II otherwise referred to
as crypto wall three last fall saw we
saw crypto wall for come with a major
major change in the splash screen change
in functionality and then last fall we
also saw the first Linux variant come
with Linux encoder one so you know the
the linux unix platforms are no longer
safe from this some more recent trends
that we've seen is ransomware using rdp
to spread android ransomware
communicating over XMPP tour switchers
to help decentralize traffic in you know
obfuscate the origin of the attack and
anonymize protect the developer and the
command and control network from
discovery and isolation we've seen
browser mobile and eunuch linux variants
and i think you know the biggest thing
is i have extortion on this slide but i
had to come up with a little bit more of
a specific terminology to discuss this
because you know ransom you know
demanding a ransom is extortion and so
that's not really very very specific and
so
one of the trends that I expect us to
see is what i'm calling leak where and
and what i'm expecting for us to see in
this in leak where is that if you choose
if you're infected and you choose not to
pay the ransom that your data will be
leaked in a WikiLeaks kind of fashion or
similar to you know the threats that
we've seen through big breaches like the
sony breach you know we're going to
splatter you all over pay spin if you
don't pay whatever we demand from you
and a couple of my peers have pointed
out that X filtration is an issue so you
know well what about X filtration and
and I think that that's a valid point
however if you were not able to protect
defend against this threat and you
weren't able to remediate it before the
encryption action was complete I
question highly your ability to limit
port 80 or 443 exfiltration of this data
so does anybody have a comment on that I
will give you a teacher if you say
something so that I can take a drink of
water nothing okay
so crypto wall three you know encrypts
files displays ransom or a lock screen
and here are some of as a long list of
signatures by various vendors talking
about their particular signature for
that for the for crypto wall three as
you can see you know most vendors are
doing something in this area some are
doing more and we're going to talk about
that a little bit more later in the
presentation but there are some really
more advanced than just an anti virus
signature ways that some vendors are
developing to try to combat this which i
think is great because we have to do
something as a matter of fact several
big firewall vendors teamed up last year
to do a great deal of threat research
around crypto wall and they came out
with a report in q4 called the the
crypto wall report threat report and of
that they came out with some pretty
staggering statistics maybe even more
staggering than what we've talked about
so far and among those are an estimated
325 million dollar dollars in damages
839 or more command and control URLs
five second-tier IP addresses used for
command and control 49 campaign code
identifies unique campaigns or run four
hundred and six thousand or more
attempted infections of version 3 alone
and over four thousand unique samples
and then after all that research we saw
version 4 come come into the wild and
with that we saw some some interesting
changes encrypting file names and the
type which was new because previously
one of the remediation techniques was to
identify the types of the files that you
that had been encrypted to to kind of
tabulate what damage had been done now
even the extensions had been encrypted
which made it much more difficult to
remediate the threat and an HTML ransom
note re couching the the way that the
threat had encrypted that information in
a you need to help your files o kind of
message and it also included generally
taunting and arrogant kind of message so
congratulations you've been you become
part of a large community crypto wall so
not the kind of congratulations that I
really want to receive on a friday
afternoon at 4pm Linux encoder one we
know to be written in C using the polar
SSI library you know requires admin
privileges runs as a daemon and deletes
itself starts by encrypting the home
directory then traverses the filesystem
recursively and is only looking at
directory starting with these extensions
obviously going after people's hosted
content their server infrastructure and
only included a limited file extension
list which was you know I kind of look
at this as like a beta roll out
no the developers is very early on there
they're going after low-hanging fruit
and trying to hit people where it's
going to hurt them the most so I just
want to make a quick pitch for my buddy
Russ he's talking this afternoon on
power cell for cyber warriors who's
planning on attending Power Cell for
cyber warriors no it's got actually got
to be on your sched like to raise your
hand ok ok ok good good okay and one of
the things that r us is going to talk
about is a module that can be used in
powershell to test distribution of
crypto malware and so you guys will want
to check that out I was talking with
them a little bit earlier in the back
and I said well you know Russ you might
want to you know say a couple more words
so if you're at this talk and you show
up there Russ might have some some
goodies for you something delicious
information or something maybe even more
so how can you get this you know the
cyber threat Alliance report revealed
that sixty-seven percent of infections
were the result of phishing attacks and
thirty percent were the result of
exploit kits so obviously we've got a
lot more work to be done in the area of
what user education you should have got
a shirt earlier because you raised your
hand earlier so there you go user
education basics right I mean we come
back to the very first weakness that you
know
we've identified over and over again you
can't fix stupid right so we've got a
lot more work to do in user education
and fishing awareness and and you know
I'll i recant my statement a little bit
by saying that these fishing campaigns
are incredibly incredibly smart almost
indistinguishable from the genuine
article and it takes a keen keen eye to
identify you know when this is being
used and so if you maybe you've been the
root you know the victim of a fishing
campaign the resulted in cryptolocker
it's okay come see me later I'll give
you a hug so here's a little kind of
chart showing what the phishing email
you know kind of process or chain would
look like I'm sorry for you folks in the
back that this is you know that's
probably hard for you to see I tried to
make it bigger but I couldn't you know
the victim you know through vulnerable
browser and redirection is you know is
presented with a malicious server then
redirected again to an angler or other
compromised server they're going to get
the exploit kit page which is going to
then check for virtual machine and
security products so you know in the
most recent versions these the software
is sandbox aware right so anybody go
into bypassing sandboxing later this
afternoon okay so also related and then
if the sandbox is detected we're exiting
to a JavaScript exception exception
error if not then serving the ex
lloyds of malicious payloads leading to
the compromise of the system which is
which is pretty smart so these you know
the developers are finding ways to keep
their code from even being examined in a
sandbox environment exploit kits here's
kind of a list of of some of the
identified campaigns their corresponding
exploit kits additional you know in
addition to angler magnitude neutrino
and rig we've seen VIP and fiesta as
well so earlier I talked a little bit
about malvert Iseman and how that kind
of tides in here and that is really you
know what is feeding the drive-by
download mechanism and here's a little
bit of a chart from Microsoft talking
about drive-by downloads in detail and
you know this is where the iframe or
JavaScript that's hosting that that
malvert Iseman would become the
mechanism within the drive-by download
for that software to be served up or
that script to be run so this relates
you know to the previous page where as
kind of an additional layer of serving
up this and then directing the user's
browser toward that command and control
Network
I put this at slide in because a lot of
times when we r you know online the best
of us you know we can get in this in
this mode of clicking through material
and that can very quickly lead to this
drive-by download situation you end up
you know oh that article looks
interesting but it's served up by a
third party that is not completely
trustworthy and doesn't really screen
their content very well and then all of
a sudden you end up on a website you
shouldn't end up on and there's there's
kind of a little bit of an additional
piece of information in this meme that
I'm going to get back to in a little bit
but here's the iframe teardown j aj
company inc com may be hacked let's
check it out so we go and look at that
and we can see here the iframe to the
angler exploit kit that you know shows
us that the site's still hacked just
like google told us you know because of
this malvert izing is a silent killer
doesn't really require any type of user
interaction to propagate the the malware
just browsing to that website viewing
the ads having you know JavaScript
enabled on your critical domain
controller that you don't have another
one of causes it to become infected and
you're running as admin domain admin not
using enhanced security controls nobody
does that so you know essentially web
browsing it is now
you know a big big issue as it relates
to this and one of the problems it's led
to this is just our advertising economy
right so it's a complex economy buying
selling of advertisements many websites
are sponsored you know by wet by
advertisement you know we've known for a
long time that Google's main business is
advertisement not search you know and so
anybody here from google I heard there's
someone here from Google today but yeah
we wish we were all raising our hands
right and then you know this but one of
the things that Google does do a good
job of is screening advertisements
whereas other websites may not do that
type of diligence you know so what we
really need is industry partners that
work closely together to detect these
kinds of threats and keep them out of
our you know Internet economy keep them
out of our web browsers and so hopefully
we can see some of that come as time
goes on but probably not yes okay
we do have a lot of third-party
advertising and this is a big concern
for us do you have any recommendations
that we could all use to do a better job
keeping bad mal were tossing off um I
don't happy to get back to you on that
that's talking more about that yeah so
thank you for your comment yes sir so if
I understand what you're saying
correctly the mal vertising is actually
being hosted through legitimate
advertising companies it's not like
somebody's hacking the site and sending
it off into someplace we already it's
just they place an ad they happen to
stick the link in there to the X plate
know if you go right wow so of the you
know 336,000 I made on my last campaign
I reinvest 20,000 in an advertising
campaign that's malicious and now all of
a sudden I've served up you know an
additional you know 1.5 million
malicious ads that's not I mean that's
money well that's money well spent right
for the developer so this is you know as
as Robin pointed out is something that
we'd all like to do something about its
question of how we do that and so it
requires you know an industry coming
together and talking about that so and I
will get back to you Robin on so yeah
file system mods cryptolocker is saving
itself with a random file name which
makes it hard to detect creating
autostart entries in the system
configuration these work even in safe
mode hijacking exe extensions to delete
shadow volume copies and the linchpin of
the shadow valium copies is on your desk
tops this is what allows you to do a
system restore so if you don't have your
shadow volume copies available you're
basically going to get a message that
says oh can't do a system restore and
how many people are backing up desktops
with a third-party backup system backup
system where you can restore
very few very few probably a good idea
for your critical desktops if you have a
desktop that's like the gonna end
business as you know it then maybe a
good idea your computer all right so for
us techies how it works we download the
encryption keys encrypt the files and
then demand the ransom here's a pink cap
of of that action
you can see the proxies in work as well
as the the tour switchers being used to
to kind of redirect that traffic we get
our encryption keys and establish
connection through a domain generation
algorithm this is what one of the things
that's making it very difficult to block
cryptolocker through that that most
relied upon NSA top 15 information
assurance mechanism domain whitelisting
were reputation filtering like Open DNS
you know maybe a checkpoint or other
services that are out there it's now not
effective where as effective because of
the domain generation algorithm
component the malware connects and
downloads a public key to the windows
system configuration and then the
private key is saved to the command and
control server and this is of course the
reason why we can't find the key we need
to decrypt from the local system it's
just not there here's a list of file
extensions that cryptolocker is looking
for I know this is really hard to read
so you can check it out later when it's
done encrypting these files is when
you're presented with the the ransom
note so you may not even know the
encryption is going on aside from
indicators like high cpu load high
memory utilization exactly yeah so
resource monitoring it then becomes an
early indicator as well as
your network ID s so as mentioned
earlier draw files are now target and
interestingly enough even as of this
week cryptolocker is now going after map
drives first so there may not even be an
indicator on the desktop of this
happening it's it's really those map
drives which which says to me we're
going after corporate information even
more aggressively than in previous
versions so detecting preventing and
remediation quickly i'm going to move
through these because i'm running out of
time most people the first time they
they find out about this is when they
get the screen some people are
discovering this through their sim
products are out there with signatures
talking that that will help you detect
the traffic initially and then they're
finding that their local files are
inaccessible or their server files are
inaccessible and you know in the case of
that map drive information being
targeted first that's really our first
indication is oh there's all these weird
file extensions on my my map drive on
the server and now i can't access any of
that information so staying map to
network drives all the time is an
additional vector that we open up for
for cryptolocker to propagate through
the enterprise here's some external
threat policies that are helpful in
discussing or and detecting the the
check in via sim you can see the IP dash
address es check in as well as the HTTP
requests on the unusual port and then a
signature that's been tailored to the
crypto wall which
calling you know a trojan here's the
screen nothing new here not not much new
information on this slide just to say
you know here's the ransom in an average
amount it's timed the private key will
be destroyed and again this is really
the first indication a lot of people
have that they've they've got an issue
log management can be used to detect
this monitoring correlation services are
useful as far as you know things like
high disk utilization your memory and
CPU load and and other things so phone
home is kind of hit or miss because
again we're routing these things through
a number of different mechanisms that
make it much more difficult to detect
local ransom note files are also an
indicator here are some frequently left
behind extensions and file names these
can be searched using scripts to alert
detect an alert and even shut down the
system but the developers have you know
identified that this is how one of the
ways that we're detecting this and so
they're dropping these files at the end
which then decreases our time to react
talked about the scanning using
PowerShell script file screen management
with audit rules can be useful and it's
important to note that all these things
work in combination to bring your
detection time down you know some
detection have gone over five days you
know or more so how many people do
backups more
fine days yeah most people are doing
backups more often than five days so
that means that if you do a backup every
20 every two days you would have rolled
encrypted files to your backups twice
during that time period at least right
yeah in our Chi 1 per month for a year
exactly on you stop exactly yeah so but
rolling to backup is no bueno so here we
you know come back to this user
awareness training is key not running as
local admin does provide some protection
user account controls doesn't really
apply your path app data so you know
this is where a software restriction
policy is really important who who's
using software restriction policies in
their in their business today highly
recommend software restriction policy or
app Locker in you know it's newer newer
form so you know check that out it's
worth your time especially on terminal
servers and citrix servers yeah those
things we are really easy to run you
brought him every day
sealy recent domain have been registered
that maybe somewhere years cool whatever
civil j yeah awesome lee Baird's
discover scripts awesome thanks Kevin
alright so you know Microsoft is not
recommending you pay the ransom the FBI
has kind of flip flopped on this pay the
ransom don't pay the ransom pay the
ransom don't pay the ransom paying the
ransom is always a way to continue you
know this this industry to feed this
industry so I'll leave it at that
running antivirus and malware protection
with with a full scan not just your
quick scan mechanism preventing spam you
know additional things to do can't you
know what we were saying common security
practices run up to date software latest
software updates understanding how these
how this malware works turning on your
firewall limiting user privileges
obviously you know attending a talk like
this helps raise all of our
understanding of how this works and so
hopefully it's been helpful for you yeah
yeah ad blockers or pop-up blockers are
also a really great way you know to
mitigate against the mal vertising drive
drive-by download malicious iframe
component as a matter of fact on here
there are some some tools that you can
use these are all in my my my resources
page which I'm going to show for you
guys in just a minute and you know one
of those that I just want to kind of
come back to is is twofold well really
two things opendns or another web
reputation filtering mechanism is key
and two products that use application
control as a part of antivirus are a big
win because companies like kaspersky and
others are researching these threats
keeping a pulse on them and then
updating the through a behavior
signature system a behavior signature
stream malicious application signatures
so at runtime watching the system
detecting these and then also even in it
even providing a rollback feature for
application actions in some some cases
you know obviously a professional
remediation is key here restoring from
incremental backup we talked a little
bit about that using utilities and
regaining access to your files I have a
list of utilities I'm going to provide
you guys with as part of my resources
that I've talked about retrieving keys
online these you know these networks are
being taken down by law enforcement all
the time keys are constantly being
published and so there is hope even you
know down the road of recovering from an
infection like this even if there
weren't incremental backups available
even if you didn't pay the ransom for
those desktops that aren't built aren't
backed up rebuilding from gold image
wipe the machine it's not just
cryptolocker that we're talking about
cryptolocker comes with other things
like Blackshades remote access tool and
other trojan downloaders that can be
very very difficult to identify and
remove and you know because of that
early reaction is really essential in
earlier versions disconnecting from the
net
work was shown to stop the encryption
algorithm process it's no longer the
case really a hard shutdown is what's
needed pull that drive and mounted
externally and then attempt to decrypt
and salvage what is possible in an
isolated environment reimage a restore
our files is is the way to go here so as
I mentioned earlier save that what can't
be decrypted to offline storage in case
the keys are you know later published
out and I mentioned how law enforcement
is taken down these networks on an
ongoing basis so with that questions you
know how smart the algorithm for
cryptolocker is for example could I do
something like make a samba share and do
like a link to itself and then it'll go
after the samba share sort of a honey
pot black hole yeah and it'll just
recurse itself to death in his trap it
yeah so that has been shown to be an
effective mechanism in slowing down the
process and you know at freaknic last
fall I heard a really interesting talk
called analog security there's a book
out about it and the whole premise is
security is time-based and an
increasingly complex virtualized high
performance environment we have now
become so fast that we exceed our
ability to react to that and so what
you're talking about is a way of slowing
down the infection long enough maybe
long enough to give yourself by yourself
some more time it dislike to notice yeah
yeah it's not yet smart enough to know
that it's been given a honey directory
or whatever you
want to call it so a micro honey pot of
some sort to the best of my knowledge
okay cool thank you here's my resources
again clean QR codes so you guys I'm
serious about that the slides will be up
on SlideShare yes one of my buddies ran
across one of their sites and one of
their clients ended up with one that it
actually was already seeing the shares
even though they weren't mapped so it
actually was running through picking up
the shares live on the network and
hunting for them and this client had
made a mistake and the person who God
had had more privileges than he should
have so it ate up a whole bunch of stuff
but she didn't have a map map shares to
it so the mappings becoming less of a
problem it's learning how to go find its
own okay great thanks for sharing that
I'm going to be updating this so you
guys want to check back every once in a
while here's my contact information and
again encourage you to link up with us
at East Tennessee Issa and share the
wealth of information that's out there
so i'll leave this slide up for you guys
that want to connect with the
organization so thanks for coming I
appreciate your attention guys