so is everyone doing this afternoon and
we're good y'all having a good time all
right you like to bug my voice a little
bit I've got a little bit of a cough so
you know if you see over here died and
I'm okay I promise
let's give a big round of applause to
Adrian and all the guys that kind of put
this together for us can we can we do
that man that you know two years ago we
didn't have a b-sides Nashville and now
we've grown to I think he said 150
people like that's insane guys you know
Nashville is firmly on the map so it's
great so the name is talk is hack
yourself building a pen testing lab for
fun and profit floor score and seven
years ago Abraham Lincoln rode into
battle on a bear with an assault rifle
and he said these words as he rode in a
battle give me six hours to chop down a
tree and I will spend the first four
sharpening the axe I don't know if any
that's true Albert Einstein also had a
great quote that's related to this talk
he said any fool can know the point is
to understand so keep those in the back
your mind as I go through this so who's
this guy stay in for Nia my name is
David Boyd I'm a security analyst for
contextual security solutions I spent a
few years in the Army and then when I
got out I worked in every sector from
retail IT government finance media
energy sector then I got tired of
sitting in hot crowded cubicles and I
decided to do consulting I'm a Christian
which I'm just a forgiving sinner I am a
new husband a new father of that little
five month old right there
rumor has it he's unleashed a new
vulnerability out in the wild it's
called that diaper shock or maybe that's
me that's the shock I get from seeing
his diapers I'm also a geek and a huge
gamer as a matter of fact I'll be
putting together a D&D group after this
so if anybody's interested come see me
so on the agenda today we're going to
talk about setting up a lab the
different pen testing distributions
we're going to talk about the various
intentionally vulnerable virtual
machines that are out there I'm going to
talk about touchdown a little bit of the
recommended tools that I think anybody
should just kind of install and kind of
play with if all goes well I'm gonna do
a live demo for you guys
of kind of what you know lab would look
like and then I'm going to go on a
little bit of a rant and then we're
gonna go eat does it sound good all
right so let's take a poll show hands
who learns a little better by reading
about something God raised about okay I
thought who learns better by actually
trying something hands-on okay a little
more there so in our industry in the
security industry and in technology in
general reading is great I mean I've got
a library full of books and I highly
suggest you do that but there is just no
better way to learn than by actually
doing it and the whole point of building
a lab is to help teach yourself and to
help improve your skills so that's why
some in here why build a lab skill set
improvement if there's something you're
a little weak on build a lab get strong
in it right I'm not great at web app
testing I'm really not so in my lab let
me get the time I try to practice with
Mattila day and a couple other things
you get to try out something new you
know we get you know a little focused on
well a B and C work but you get into
different customer environments and none
of those things work right so it's easy
for us to kind of get you know that
single focus this gives you a chance to
try out some new things kind of break
the barrier without breaking your
customers Network you get to brush up on
some tactics both old and new I can't
tell you how many old tricks still work
like Cain you know back in 95 Cain still
works it's a proof of concept for
customers if you've got you know we love
our customers and we try to take care of
them but if you've got a customer that's
you know a little bit picky and you find
a vulnerability on their website on
their site or you know you know within
their network and they're like man I
really don't want you to to exploit that
you know you can go ahead and build it
out in your lab show a video show
screenshot do a WebEx you know just kind
of show them a good proof of concept hey
man this is really something serious you
guys really need to look at that
and remember scanners don't find
everything beginning of your career
and I'm just as guilty of it - it's easy
to go the automated scanners look for
abilities go from there you know and
that's great
you know that's we definitely need that
that's all part of it but scanners don't
find everything sometimes you got to be
able to just kind of go in there look at
different things and most of all don't
be a script kitty
right alright so you should build a lab
pentesters obviously if you're a pen
tester and you don't have a lab you're
failing yourself any kind of security
personnel red team and blue team both
you could actually build a blue team lab
with snort and things like that you can
build a red team lab you can have the to
fight against each other it's pretty
cool any IT personnel c-level xx my high
level guys go ahead and build the lab in
your spare time see what all that money
that you're spending on your security
team is going towards learn some of the
tools that they're using you know that
way you're better equipped when you go
and sit down and you talk to these guys
you say hey how are we looking
you better understand what they're
actually talking about and then anybody
want learning skill like mr. Deadpool
here so here's what you need to build a
lab a hallway full of servers and a half
a million dollars right no really and
truly you just need a laptop okay you
can do it on desktop you can even find
an old server somewhere you know
Craigslist got a bunch of them for like
a hundred bucks if you wanted to but
really my lap is right here on this
laptop you need a virtualization
software of your choice I'll go over
those here in a second you need a couple
of vulnerable VMs to practice on and
then you get money flowing out of your
laptop it's great so here's some of the
virtualization software that's out there
you've got VM Player it's free it's easy
to use me personally that's what I
prefer I've had a little more success
with a little more luck with it
there's also VirtualBox which is equally
as good it's kind of based on what you
want what you want to do there's also
paid software so unfortunately for Mac
users we have to pay for VMware fusion
it gives you a 30 day free trial - 80
bucks after that and then for a PC
there's a VMware Workstation again
another 30 day free trial it's 150 after
that the only difference between the
and the free ones is snapshots that's
like the biggest difference so if you're
messing around and you've got all these
machines running and an opposing one
your machines you can go revert back to
one of your snapshots bring it back up
no problem right let's go over some
pentesting platforms here we've got you
know kali linux that's obviously the
most popular one everyone knows that
everyone uses it that's the one i've
suggest you use and work on pen to back
box linux you've got samurai WTF that
actually stands for web testing
framework that's great for web app
testing samurai STFU which is utility
hacking and it's actually there's no
icon there because justin cyril will be
unleashing a new version under a new
name called the control things platform
he'll be unleashing at a blackhat this
this summer so go and check him out and
there's also def linux if forensics is
your thing you want to kind of practice
with that download that here's a list of
some vulnerable VMS you've got
Metasploit able to that's great for
Metasploit that's great for web app
testing it's an intentionally vulnerable
version of Ubuntu Linux that's designed
for testing all kinds of security tools
common vulnerabilities it's got remote
logins backdoors vulnerable web services
default passwords it's got all kinds of
cool stuff man you've got I put Windows
XP on there and Windows Server so XP is
still out there okay it's still out in
the wild there's still customers using
it still sitting on network sites you're
fooling yourself if you're thinking
otherwise I just saw one two weeks ago
and a customer site XP just sitting out
there man's golly it's still practice on
me
server you can download for free for 180
days so bill at our domain controller
while you're doing this you know
practice popping in domain controller I
said look at the bottom of an old laptop
when you go to install XP it asks for a
key so you got those little laptop still
lying around flip those over there's
your key morning catch is a good fishing
it's a good vulnerable fishing VM that's
built out specifically to practice
fishing
against an arm a wasp for and webgoat
both for web application so it's great
for web app testing and then volt hub
coms a website that's got a whole bunch
of vulnerable VMs kind of made by the
community and a couple good ones there
where captrick sin pono s with one
web.com you gotta kind of you know use
your discretion as you download the
stuff make sure it's something you can
actually use and it's safe some of its
not supported so it's kind of to you
here's some recommend tools I think you
should play with and map or masscan
right if you're great with then map
right to some mask and if you've never
practiced on masking or you've never
practice on a map going use that this is
great vulnerability scanner the neces
home is free for up to 20 IPS so your
labs not gonna get any bigger than that
I don't think so that's that's great to
practice you know vulnerability scanning
kind of seen things cane again it's an
old tool it still gets me credentials it
still works to this day it still works
some one to seven I haven't turned it on
eight or ten yet and it's great I would
definitely recommend you practice with
that responder is also fantastic for
grabbing hashes out in the wild fire
responder let it run for a while you'd
be surprised what you get once you get
all those yummy hashes with responder
you need to crack them with John or hash
cat if you never practice with other one
of those highly suggest you do so hash
pad is more geared towards GUI cracking
so using your graphics cards to try to
correct the hashes John is more CPU
intensive I I've had more luck with John
myself but we're actually spitting up a
hash cat box so we'll see how that works
Metasploit principally it's free - play
community definitely definitely to use
that it's mostly for exploits running
exploits which hopefully I'll show you
here social engineering to pit go fish
and SPF which Adam who just spoke Adam
Compton is the creator of SPF there
those are great
fishing tools to use again they're all
free so go ahead and you know reach out
and grab those and practice with them
discover scripts is great for open
source intelligence and PowerShell
empire if you're if you're a little weak
on PowerShell go and download PowerShell
Empire
kind of playing around with that any
questions so far all right let's uh see
if the live demo works here give me a
second let me set this up so this is my
lab here excuse me man
all right so as a Mac user I have VMware
fusion so this is my lab right here
welcome to Wayne Enterprises right I've
got my Kali Linux machine which is an
attacker machine I've got municipal able
an XP service pack 3 machine Alford's
machine another Windows 7 machine that's
another attacker so you know remember I
was talking about Kane Kane doesn't work
on Linux that only works on Windows so
it's good to have kind of both there's a
domain controller Windows Server 2012
and then the phishing server morning
catch so let's see here
let's try the first attack here let's do
a you'll remember MSO eight oh six seven
right call it out here and you get a
free thing well what was the biggest
thing for it anybody remote access
remote code execution there you go
alright so we're gonna go ahead and fire
up our let's let's let's play pretend
right that we're doing a pen test for
Wayne Enterprises we're gonna go ahead
and fire up our Kali Linux box here do
y'all hear me okay okay here all right
make that big there you go you see a
little better okay so for the sake of
time we've gone ahead and made a host
list so we're gonna go ahead and move to
our clients directory and let's go ahead
and just scan our hosts lists see what
happens show - IL h oh that's text see
what happens see what pulls through here
hopefully everything's open and live I
think it is that's up okay
all right so it looks like it found
well said freeze upon here
there we go okay so it looks like you
found a couple servers here right we've
got a whole Wow hole punch open points
on that one there I'll at 128 looks like
a good target you know we got some
remote stuff there we got FTP ssh telnet
man that might be a good one
looks like it's a linux box so nmap you
know it takes a pretty good guess it
does pretty good job of telling you what
OS is on there let's see what else we
got here oh we got a Windows XP box out
in the wild oh man I can't believe
people still have those didn't they stop
you know supporting them like 100 years
ago man and it looks like it's sp2 or
service pack 3 so that might be
interesting my vehicle little target
there windows 7 box ok and oh wow an XP
2 professional man I'm gonna have to
target that one I'll bet you that one
there's probably got some good stuff so
let's go ahead and open up Metasploit
here No I can make this go big for you
all right there's miss flick console
with a nice little moo-cow there all
right so like I said Windows XP great
for MSO eight oh six seven so after you
fire it up Metasploit here you'd go
ahead and do a search for MS o 8 - O's
67 it's going to go ahead and do a
search
we should feel bad for the boiling water
it's gonna be missed
okay now so you do a search in
Metasploit for any kind of module and
it'll pop back and tell you okay hey
we've got a list of modules here this
here is the most popular exploit that I
know of it's the easiest thing to
exploit its most popular one to know of
everyone talked about it for years it's
still out there so we're gonna go ahead
and say use and then paste it use
exploit windows SMB em so dos six seven
all right we're gonna go ahead and set
our aura host here well let me back up
we're gonna go into show options right
you wanted to do that for any minnesota
module that you open right so it's got
you know you have a center our post in
our host and our for SMB pipe so we're
gonna go ahead and set our host to that
lovely little XP box so we found out in
the wild there this one here
hit paste and then you just type in one
simple little command here exploits and
if all goes well
it didn't work that's okay ah let's see
here I can fix that though me third
seconds here well okay if it first don't
succeed try and try again I just guess
it doesn't work a long time doesn't mean
it won't work again right there we go so
now we have a meterpreter session
alright so who knows what you can do
with an interpreter session right that's
basically complete access to the machine
no password required right so we go
ahead to our handy-dandy little notebook
here fold notes let's sit here
okay by the way it's always good to take
notes on pen tests make a methodology
document full of commands it's hard to
keep up this stuff in your head I'm not
you know I'm not great at memory so it's
good to kind of have this stuff so back
on here we've got our interpreter
command full access to the Machine we're
going to dump all the hashes here see
what happens so there's all the hashes
there a little machine again no password
required right you can go ahead and run
this through John we've got Alfred we've
got Bruce Wayne what's he doing logging
into Alfred's machine there
James Smith a couple other people oh
I'll see here we can do terrible
commands can list a couple thing I like
to do for customers is webcam underscore
list that lists any video devices that
they have on there you can do webcam
underscore snap so if everyone will
smile for the camera here there you go
so that's always kind of cool to do for
customers that tends to kind of freak
him out a little bit so we've got all
the hashes off the machine we've got the
webcam let's go ahead and get a shell
now we have full access to the machine
there and from there we can just do
whatever we want right so let's say we
wanted to go ahead and go a little bit
further here we see that Bruce Wayne
logged into his machine
we've got his hash there let's go ahead
and load that into John and see what we
get
I'm not gonna run John for times sake
I'm gonna go ahead and just say that we
got his password but you go ahead and
copy that over over a new screen here
paste it into John
based it into a document here and save
it as I you know whatever you want
hashes dot text or whatever and then
you'd run John on that on the file there
as soon as you get that you'd have this
password so for times sake let's say we
got his password we're running John oh
man we got his password oh that's cool
okay let's see I wonder if he's got
domain admin let me try this here let's
see if he's got domain admin you know he
was logging in now for the machine he's
kind of a high level guy you know we did
her we did her pass over constants to
the company and we looked and saw the
the guys at work there it's good see we
got here so a lot up another tool here
called crack map this thing is great
right and looking back at our and our in
Maps cams from before we saw that one of
the machines was named DC so I wonder if
that's a domain controller right so
let's go ahead and just run this with
the captured Bruce Wayne password we've
got well let me make it big here sorry
we've got our tag loaded up here we've
got crack ma'am
that's the Python script there's the
domain controller that we're targeting
there's his user name and there's this
password so let's run it mmm let's see
what happens I didn't work
no it's is it make strollers not
turned on let's see
again all this is for free right I've
been able to do all of this for free
it's all on my own thing here it's all
on my own Network it's all
self-contained all right so that's
working now so we're gonna do - - NTDs
because we all love her in 2d s files
right see you API and there is the
entire domains worth of password hashes
right there on their domain controller
right yeah so so yeah I mean this little
stuff you could practice right just by
building your lab from home and I mean
you know if stuffs not working if you're
on a customer sign your site man you
know this is this is just killing me I
don't know I don't know what's going on
try to see if you can recreate at least
that section of it in your lab here you
know let's see I'm gonna trade you one
more thing here another cool thing now
remember I said you should definitely
try to try out trained Kane right it's
old but it still works here's a cool
thing you do with it right turn on your
sniffer see what you see right there
right-click resolve the host names and
it'll tell you sometimes you know this
admins aren't aren't great about naming
their systems we see right there you
know if you didn't already know 101 is
the domain controller so that might be a
target for later right come on the other
thing too about Kane it's a little wonky
so sometimes it might crash on you you
know I'm just kind of gonna go with it
another cool thing you kind of look at
the network here see if you can get some
more information you can see oh okay
that's a test lab domain let me see what
the con on there so you go and look at
all the computers on it kind of look at
the quick list there look at the users
oops Oh back computer got an XP machine
on there okay cool
so it kind of gives you you know
numerate some information for it kind of
gives you some more information there's
other ways of doing it this is just kind
of a
cool little graphical way to kind of
look see what you're looking at and any
potential targets that you might want to
look at and so it's no tool still works
ready for me man
with that I think that's the end of my
demo so be back my slide deck now and
all that was to say that and several bad
puns later you should build a lab right
you practice this stuff in our in our
industry right
like I said reading this great you got
to read your books in fact I've got a
reading list you know couple slides over
blogs or grace go out and write them and
read them but the guy that all he does
is read blogs or all he does is read
books isn't gonna be able to figure out
crack Matt probably I mean maybe he
might be smarter than me but he's not
gonna be able to figure out hey you know
if I dump the hashes off this computer
maybe I could try to use it and then
escalate my privileges on this computer
over here you know you can get some of
that from books but you can't get it as
well as you could from reading right so
let me tell y'all story I
raspy as all get-out good grief
I like you said I've worked in every
industry and I've worked for private
sector over for everything man and
there's just been no better way for me
to learn them I having a mentor right I
was giving a chance I was a young guy
you know I knew some things from reading
some books trying some things my own or
whatever but I didn't really have a
whole lot of experience and so I had a
guy come up he gave me a chance and then
he turned me over to another guy he
decided to mentor me and it has been
fantastic I can I tell you guys how much
I've learned from having a mentor right
if you have knowledge if you have if
you're really really great some say like
web app testing is your thing man and
you were just the bomb and it don't keep
that to yourself man pass that along
write up a blog do a video you know come
do a talk you know teach people
share your knowledge if you're really
weak it's something you won't learn
about it build it out in the lab break
it try it fail it you know you you you
can't fail yourself you know this this
this industry moves way too fast man and
you are letting yourself down you're
letting your company down you're letting
your customers down right by not trying
to learn but not trying to improve and
you higher level guys you experts you're
failing the people underneath you you're
failing your peers and you feel yourself
if you're not mentoring if you're not
teaching if you're not passing on that
knowledge all right back in the day this
movie here is what got me into this
right I loved that movie I thought man I
wanted to be those guys right somebody
gave me a chance
and I got to be those guys and I loved
it it has been the most fun I've had
doing any job I've ever had it is
fantastic pass on your knowledge take
some time to learn take some time to
teach some folks it's gonna build lab
now here's some books I'd recommend
reading these are all great love them
all I didn't put three mimic books on
here but that's all for social
engineering if you learn social
engineering go back in history read you
do your history reads books black hat
pythons are great if you need to learn
some scripting Metasploit was written by
Dave Kennedy so that's great all these
are good the hackers playbook fantastic
I've used that probably the most on all
my engagements it's got a bunch of cool
tools bunch of cool scripts highly
recommend picking that one up so any
questions no no okay
I'm David Boyd there's my Twitter info
my email were for contextual security
and there's the dog tax thank you guys
appreciate it