is
oh hi uh
hi
it's going to be back to the stage of
cobra
thank you all for being here
yeah and this
will report a series of vulnerabilities
on exchange server to microsoft
and then it is proxy logan
if you are paying attention to the
industry news you must have heard this
name
proceed lockdown may be the most severe
vulnerability in the exchange history
ever
however as we went into deep dive on
proxy logang
it came to us that it is not just a
single bug but a whole new attack
service to help researchers to uncover
more vulnerabilities
so to unveil the beauty of this attack
surface
we will start from explaining the
architecture
analyzing the loot course
and ending up with naive abilities we
find
by understanding the basics of this new
attack service you won't be surprised
why we can pop out your desk easily
okay so let me introduce myself first
an orange and now the principal security
researcher at deathcore
i'm a zero day researcher and focusing
on web and application security
my job is to find out the most severe
vulnerabilities
that can impact the world ahead of the
bad guys
and reporting to the vendors directly
apart from that and also a speaker ctf
player and bhagavanti hunter
i got several awards from my researchers
such as the pony awards and the champion
of pancho own
if you are interested welcome to follow
my twitter and blog
so however we targeting exchange server
in terms of enterprise security mail
servers are high value assets since they
are the place to keep corporate
copyright confidentials
exchange server is the most well-known
and important male solution in the world
with this in mind exchange has also been
the top target for nation state haters
for a long time
so based on our research there are more
than 400 thousands exchange servers
exposed on the internet
every server replace every server
represents a company
so you can imagine how severe it could
be when there is a critical
vulnerabilities on exchange server
so what have we done
we have reviewed the exchange security
from the architectural levels and find a
new attack service
through this new attack service we
uncover 911 abilities and chat this box
into four attacking exploits
the first and the most famous one is
proxy logang
it's a pre-os rce
and the second one is proxy oracle x and
exploit that can recover any user's
password in plain text format
the last one is proxy shell
is the exploit with damage chat at pong2
own 2021
is also a pre-owned rce
i would like to highlight that all the
abilities we uncovered here are logic
box
which means they could be reproduced and
exploited easily than any memory
corruption box
the new attack service i proposed also
launched a new edge for hackers to
research exchange server
there are lots of vulnerabilities
related to my research
such as the proxima file
report by nsa and the proxy token by
vmptisc team
it should be note that there will be one
more attack from me in the near future
however it's still under the patreon
process and we are not able to to
disclose today
as you can see all of their men have the
proxy prefix
that's also because of my new attack
service and we will explain that later
exchange is a very sophisticat
application
before we cut to the chest let me
introduce the architecture first
since 2000 exchange has released a new
version every three years
whenever exchange released a new version
the architecture changed a lot and
becomes different
the changes of architecture and
iterations make it difficult to upgrade
an exchange server
in order to ensure the compatibility
between the new architecture and old
ones
several design depths were incurred and
led to the new attack service we find
so where do we focus
we focus on the client access service cs
cs is a fundamental component in
exchange
the official document indicates cs is a
front-end that accept client connections
for all protocols
and responsible for routing and proxy in
connections
cs was further we paid attention to
and further attack service x60
because the cls is located at a very
early stage of exchange request
processing
all blocks here are authentication free
so you can imagine how dangerous it is
when this fundamental service is
vulnerable
so here is the cs architecture copied
from the document
as you can see the left side is the
client
no matter where the connections come
from
either http pop3 imf or snpp
cis in the middle part processes all
connections
and practices to the back-end service on
the right side
the back-end service will continue to
handle further business logix
and because
and because i'm specialized in web
security so it works on the web
the cs web is built on microsoft iis
as you can see there are two websites
inside the iis
the default website is the front ad we
mentioned before
and the exchange backhand is where the
business logic is
if you look at the configuration
carefully you will notice the front end
is listening on post 80 and 443
and the backend is listening on the port
81 and vote 44
it should be note that the posts are
exposed on all interfaces
so you may sense something wrong here
all the posts are open to all interfaces
which means you can access the backend
directly
wouldn't it be dangerous
yes please keep this question in mind
and we will answer that later
the cs is composed of several iis
modules
applications in front-end include the
proxy module
which is responsible for passing all
incoming requests
applying protocol specific settings
and forwarding them to the back cam
as for the backhand applications include
a rehydration module
which is taking charge of passing
front-end requests
populating the client information back
and continuing the business logic
so here is a question for you
how did the front end and backhand
exchange the information
they synchronize the information and
internal status by http haters
for a client request it will first be
handled by the front end
and the request will be passed through
several is modules
such as the filter
validation
logging
at the last proxy module
the proxy module then picks up a handler
based on the current application path
such as the slash owa or slash ecp
the handler will do the proxy work and
forward the request to the backend
when the backhand receives the request
it passes the request to the rehydration
module
to restore the original client state
and continue the business logics
so our idea is simple could we access
the backend intentionally
since the exchange synchronized
information by http haters
it seems like most of the essa's control
is done by the front end
if we can access the
if we can access to the backend we saw
restrictions
maybe there are several internal apis we
can abuse
we all know implementing implementing a
proxy is hard
and the front end seems like a well
implemented http client
so if there are some magic tricks to
manipulate the contacts between the
front end and backhand
it must be fine
so in order to abuse the context we have
to know how the proxy module works first
the proxy request handler is the most
important part of the front end
all handlers should inherit this class
to implement their message such as how
to handle the client cookies or haters
and how to proxy the client request to
the
bacon
we separate the messes into three
section
the first is request
which will pass and modify the client
request
and next is proxy section
which will proxy and send the http
request to the backend
and the last section is response
this section will receive the response
from the backend and decide which hater
our cookies should be sent back to the
client
because this handler is important we
will explain the messages one by one
the first method of request section is
copy headers to server request
it will decide which http haters from
the client can be sent to the backend
as we said the front end and backhand
synchronize information and internal
status by http haters
so maybe you are thinking i could force
the haters to conceal something
this is a nice try
but unfortunately you can see here is a
blacklist in the mazer
the front end blocks several http haters
which are used internally
please keep it please keep in mind that
the hater x common as this token
is an important one
you will learn this later
the second is copy cookies to server
request
the functionality is the send as
previous one
but it copies cookies instead
the last method of request section is
add protocol specific headers to server
request
this method allows a handler to apply
customized protocol settings
for example if the front-end owa would
like to pass information to the backend
here is the place it can insert
information to haters
besides the customized protocol settings
this means that also clones the user
identity to a new http hater
the identity is the client
authentication result in iis
also consisting of your security
identifier
the message theorized it to a string
and press it into the haters
which will be forward to the back end
later
so as of now you know how the front end
and back can synchronize your identity
then do it by the hater as common access
token
once the request passing is done
it will lead to the proxy section
the proxy first uses the get target that
can server url
to calculate the url where the front end
shoes sent to
this method is also a body plus
and full of vulnerabilities
we will discuss this
later the second step of proxy is create
server request
which first in
which first initialize an http client
sets up the http message and haters
and forwards it to the backend
we mentioned that posts in is are open
to anyone
and this is dangerous
that's why exchange has a mechanism to
avoid the situation
while the front end is creating a
request
it will generate a kerberos tikki and
put it in the authorization header
this hater will be sent to the backend
along with the request
so how the spec can mode which
connection is from a valid front end
by verifying this clever sticky
we look into the general kerose of
header
and note that the header is generated
with the http spn of the exchange
machine account
if you observe the traffic between the
front end and backhand
you will see
two headers shown in the request
one is the authorization header which is
the kerberos tiki used to indicate you
are a valid front-end
the other is the hater x common access
token
it's a sterilized token indicates your
identity
for example if you log in with the nand
orange the hater is the serialized
result of your security identifier
after sending the request to the backcam
the front end receive the response and
enter the last section
the response section is similar to
request
it checks the response from the backend
and decide which haters or cookies are
allowed to be sent back to the client
so now you understand how the front end
works
let's move on
to see how the back-end process and
populate the request from front end
the backhand rehydration module first
uses the mesa to check whether the
incoming request is authenticated or not
it is the time to leverage the capacity
the front end generate
by handing over the ticket the backhand
knows you are from you are valid from
and now
the back-end then codemaster try get
common access token to restore the
user's identity from front-end
the mesa retrieves the header this will
exterize it back to the original access
token
and put it in the http contacts object
for later use
so far you learned how the front end and
back can synchronize the user's identity
and how the header x common access token
plays an important role in the cs
architecture
since the nasa just checks if the user
are looking or not it doesn't check the
identity
here comes a question
could we all send cash as a normal user
in the backend
if we access the backend directly
and on sandycat with a normal user
we can specify whatever values in the
header x common access token
and impersonal as any users
the idea is good and actually you can
pass the is authentication of the back
can
but there is one more checkpoint
the method is token serialization laws
manifest the current log user
and there is a rehydration exception if
the checkpoint is fail
it checks if you have a token
sterilization right
by default only the exchange machine
account has this right
so that's why the kerberos ticket
generated by front end can pass this
checkpoint
but you will fail even you are using the
correct credential
so here is a quick summary
when there's a client request the
front-end is first tries to ascend
category cost
if succeed the front end series the user
identity and adds it into the hater x
common access token
the front end then generates a kerberos
ticket by xhttp spn and press it into
the authorization header
it will forward these headers along with
the client request to the backend
the backend also tries to authenticate
the request at the beginning
the rehydration module will verify
whether the user have the right of token
sterilization or not
since we are using a kubrow sticky
generated by the front end
we passed
lastly the rehydration restores the user
identity from the header x command
access token
and continue the backend business logic
so far we briefly explained the
communication between the front end and
backhand
let's start the hack
okay the first exploit is proxy logong
as introduced before this may be the
most severe vulnerability in the
exchange history
proxy lock gun is checked with two bugs
to get rce
one is an ssrf on the front end
and the other is an arbitrary file right
on the control panel of the backend
here is proxy logon
the bug is mainly looked at at the proxy
section in the front end
we mentioned that the front end handlers
calculates the back-end url
and forwards the request to that url
one of the handler is in charge of
processing the static resources
it will assign the backend target from
the cookie
so you will figure out how simple this
box is after learning the architecture
the front end change the user's supplied
cookie as the domain name and the domain
name will be concatenate as the backend
url
we use a bit of passing checks to
enclose the url and force the exchange
to fetch example.com
the exchange will then return the whole
response back to us
so what is the loot code of this archery
back-end assignment
as we mentioned that the exchange server
changed its
while releasing new versions
this cookie is a quick solution for
exchange to map the front end in new
architecture
to identify where the old backhand is
so it looks like a design step to that
backward compatibility
so with
the backhand this with this abstract
back-end assignment
we have a super ssrf and that can
control almost all the requests
and get all the responses
and the most important and the most
impressive is that
it will generate a coverage ticket for
us
which means even when we are taking a
protected and domain joint http service
we can still hack with the
authentication of exchange machine
account
so thank you thanks to the super ssrf we
can leverage the internal api
flash proxy logong.ecp to get a
validation to access the control panel
the api is also the reason why we called
it praxilogan
as for the rest of the exploitation i
believe there are already lots of
technical analysis out there
we will skip it today further
consideration of time
we will not do the demonstration today
but if you are interested welcome to
check the demo on our website
next i will be sharing details about
proxy oracle
compared to proxy log gun proxy autocar
is an interesting exploit with a
different approach
proxy oracle would allow the attacker to
recover the victim's plan tax password
simply by leading them to a malicious
link
we use a cross-site scripting and
padding oracle to complete the exporting
first we would like to explain how the
owa or ecp or centicad uses
if the negative is authentication is
used
an ugly prompt will
pop out and asking you to enter the
password instead of this fancy interface
which means exchange is using a certain
mechanism to ask you the transformation
between credentials and cookies
so let's take a look at how this fancy
interface is working with the original
architecture
let's get back to the cls architecture
all the ota and ecp looking mechanism is
done by the phone-based authentication
module
the fba module
is an authentication module prior to the
exchange front end
and responsible for converting the
username and password into cookies
or translating cool kicks back to the
original credential pairs
the implementation stores your username
and password in cookies directly
of course the cookie is encrypted to
avoid bad guys catching your password in
plain text on the phone
if you read the login traffic carefully
you will see several cookies which stand
for your identity
for the later mail operation you have to
attach cookies to identify who you are
among all cookies there are five
important ones with the prefix ca data
you can see from the screen
the ci data contains your encrypted
username and password
here is the pseudo code for the
encryption logic extract generates to
render string as the iv and key for
every session
the ibm key will be sent and stored on
the client side
however to avoid someone stealing the
cookies and decrypting it with the iv
and key
exchange uses rsa to encrypt with its
private key again before sending
the extract then use this aes
to encrypt your encoded credential with
the iv and key
and put the result into the cookies
and yes you can find painting oracle
here
exchange text the cbc as its painting
mode
if you are familiar with cryptography
you must know that cbc is vulnerable to
the painting or local attack
the exchange implementation catches the
painting error exception and returns
immediately
when the login process fails
exchange redirects the http back to the
login pack with an error code
and due to the return we have an oracle
here
if the encryption fails the error code
is zero
which stands for noun
and if we corrupt the cyber tags
successfully
the exchange will try to login with the
corrupted credential pair
and at this moment a result must be a
failure and the error code is 2
which stands for the invalid credentials
by differing from the error number
we have an oracle to recover the plan
text
so now we know we can decrypt any cookie
with the painting oracle
but the problem is
how to get the cookie from the victims
in order to get a cookie on clients we
uncover a cross-sized grouping to train
together
but it comes up with another problem
in exchange all sensitive cookies are
protected by http only
so we can't access the cookies by
javascript or javascript
so what can we do
since we can ask you the arbitrary
javascript on the client side
why don't we just insert the ssi cookie
which is used in proxy logan
once we add a cookie to the browsers we
can sniff and take over all the user's
web requests
all we need to do is to sit on our
server and wait for the cookie to come
back
i will elaborate the process further
we first send a malicious link to the
victim
once the victim triggers our xss
we insert the ssr cookie to pretend we
are the backend of exchange
then the exchange server becomes a proxy
between the victim and earth
we will take over all the traffic and
bypass the http only to get encrypted
cookies
okay in the demonstration
because the tank consideration and i
will also skip the demonstration today
if you are interested you can follow my
blog to see the demonstration
oops
and the last expert i will share today
is proxy shield
this is the explorer with diamonds chat
at pong2 on 2021.
the result of proxy shell is the
center's proxy lockdown
and authenticate attack and an authentic
head attack can ask you absurd command
on the exchange server
but exploit check is different
proxy share is checked with an sdl
bypass in the front end
an elevation of privacy in the backend
partial
and an actual firewire to get rce
so where is the proxy show
this first or the first pre-all spark is
also looked at at the back-end url
calculation
proxy shield begins with a pass
confusion
exchange has a feature called the
explicit logon feature
this feature is used to display another
user's mailbox or calendar in a new
browser window
of course the displayed mailbox must
have to be configured with permission to
publish first
in order to open with a single get
request
the url format must be simple
and the mailbox address must be included
in the url such as the highlight part in
the slide
the extract normalize this spatial url
and reroute it
into the existing handler
of course the past is not the only way
to specify the mailbox edges
we find that a special cast in the
outdoor discovery handler
exchange will consider edges from the
query string if the path ends with slash
auto discover the season
effort after getting the address the
handler tries to normalize the url
you see that exchange won't conduct too
much checking on the patent of the
remote
of the removing mailbox edges
which led us to use the substring
to to address any part of the url
as you can see from the slide
this is the url we will be visiting
and this is the mailbox agers we use the
query string to specify
and here is the part will be removed
from the exchange according to our
patent
with with the address
this is the actual url the request will
be sent to the backend
as for now we can access any exchange
they can't get
also this box is not as powerful as the
ssrf in proxy logong it's sufficient to
answer archery backhands
we try to access the an api in the fast
to identify our priority
from the screenshot you could see that
we did access the backend with the
exchange system privileges again
so here comes the post exploitation part
the approach of original proxy long gun
fails due to some exchange in depth
protections
so we have to
discover a new approach
now let's turn the focus to exchange
posture remote
partial remoting is a feature for
exchange
to automation for automations
through the defined power shield
commands
users can read mail
spent mail and even configure settings
by command lines
the exchange posture implementation is
built upon the powershell api
by calling the api exchange could
realize approach to realize a partial
server and uses the wrong space to limit
and isolate the command execution
all the
are based on the wing rn protocol
it should be note that
although we can access the power shield
backhand directly
we can't still in
interact with it because we are the
system
we will fail the business logic
since this normal box for the system
user
we also can forge our identity by the x
common access token
due to the black list in the front end
so what should i do
we dive into the powershell server
implementation and find a piece of code
that extracts the access token from the
url
the code is sitting after the is backend
authentication
and before the rehydration module it
checks if there is no
if there is no excellent access token
the code will call out another measure
to get the access token from url
the common access token from url is a
short message and retrieves the value of
xrps
clt from current string and then
distributes it back to the access token
as of now we have an elevation of
primary because we can access the
powershell backend
and specify the access token directly
the intention of this operation is to be
a quick proxy for internal exchange
powershell
communication by abusing this feature
we can impress that as any user
but here we use this eop to downgrade
ourselves from the system user result
mailbox
to exchange admin
so i can now ask you the arbitrary power
share command as admin
and then
the last piece of the puzzle is to find
a post-house rce to trend everything
together
because we are the enemy and there are
hundreds of exchange published comments
out here
it's easy to find a postal spot
we abuse the command new mailbox export
request to export a user's mailbox into
the webloot to be our web shield
so let's check everything together
we first deliver our encoded web show to
the target mailbox
and we then launch a windows powershell
client to connect to our proxies proxy
server
we use a proxy server because we have to
modify the wing rm protocol to rewrite
the path lead to the vulnerable auto
discovery handler
which will invest in
eventually trigger the past confusion
bug
and add the access token to the current
stream
once the session has been established
we can ask you the powershot command to
grant ourselves
the mail
the mailbox export law and involve the
mailbox exploiting
and enjoy the show
okay the demonstration but i think the
time is a
little bit
straight so we also skip it today
okay the last let's talk about
mitigations
since it's an architectural problem it's
hard to meet
it's hard to make get a text service
with
with with one single action
all you can do is keep your exchange
server up today and with the support of
the acl or firewall to not externally
facing to the internet
microsoft has enhanced the cls
architecture in april
the authentication part of this attack
service has been reduced in this patch
so if you are lazy please update to the
outro patch at least
and if you are super lazy maybe you can
give a shot at the office 365.
it's kidding yeah
okay this is the end of my presentation
if you have any questions or want to
see the demo with the skip today
here's my contact information and blog
you can visit it
thank you again for being here thanks
foreign