you very much thank you angels for that
nice entry
visor view truncated
the speaker had preceded me when I came
a little early and saw the new and very
wisely given out the best speaker one
before I spoke shows very good judgment
Angeles mentioned that he'd sort of
truncated my career
description of my career maybe this
event likely truncate the career itself
I actually among other things was a law
professor and I remember having a strong
sense about my teaching qualities when a
student came up to me at the end of one
of the classes and gushing with
enthusiasms professor dancing I just
don't know how you do it you're every
lecture is better than the next one
I thought about that for a while and
decided to quit teaching and it led me
eventually into government were among
other things I became secretary of the
Navy and I was he once I thought
effectively but admittedly at some
length when a marine got up to leave and
that didn't seem to me to be
appropriately compatible with the
dignity of the secretary of the Navy so
I stopped him and asked him where he was
going
didn't think the dignity of the
secretary of the Navy was enhanced by
his answer which was that he was going
to get a haircut so I said to him what
did you get a haircut before I began
speaking and he said I didn't need one
so these factors also just to me were
very wise to give out the award long
before I spoke but I think you for the
opportunity I'm going to try and do
something difficult here and that is to
provide sort of bridge between the
technology world that you all know so
well and the Washington policymaker
world that you're now physically
embedded in but also functionally so
embedded in as we talk about
cybersecurity issues and the challenge
in some respects is to talk between the
two worlds and not only to talk in a way
that descriptive and analytic but also
that is prescriptive and suggestive
as angel said the straws in some measure
on a paper that I published this last
you're in this concept of living on a
diet of poison prude this is the
organization's site you can download
from the web if you like you want to
follow up on some details I'm going to
go further than the paper today but some
trunk of the footnotes and the like in
that document will give you a richer
background if you want to pursue it
further
what I'd like to do today is to give you
a sense of the the world as I see it in
terms of particularly admiring the
problem first I'm gonna spend a little
bit of time just emphasizing the
character what we're having to deal with
but then I'm going to try and go deeper
and analyze it and by analyzing it I
means trying to point out some of the
key things that underlie the world as we
see in an abstract beyond perhaps kind
of everyday concepts that you deal with
just some basic propositions are gonna
give you about a half-dozen about why
we're in this situation we're in and
then I'm going to try and move to a
short description welder terrain that I
think would be more familiar to you
which is just come some of the kinds of
things we're trying to do about it
what I want to get to particularly as a
set of recommendations and I'm not going
to tend to be comprehensive in those
recommendations I'd want rather the
suggestion by and large things that are
new things that we're not doing that are
not so much
gender not that I've discovered some
incredible curative unknown to the world
but I think there are things to be said
about about this that are not enough on
our agendas it first so let me start
play as I say admiring the problem
a common phrase used these days is the
notion that this is a wicked problem
that by which is meant that it's highly
interactive has a number of different
components and these different
components create difficulties
in or actions because in fact different
parts of the problem can't resolve it
without connecting with other parts so
technology for example interacts with
legal systems and I've shown you just a
little sort of wheel of concerns here
I'd particularly emphasized that we have
to be concerned obviously with business
realities
it's great to provide patches or maybe
it's not so great but it's something to
provide patches on systems that I've
known vulnerabilities but when you
actually look about why it is that
people don't download those patches the
reasons or highly cultural and relate to
business imperatives it may seem like
well this is just a failure and then I
ought to be able to drive people towards
but the underlying business reality is
that because they're integrating new
software in two systems that are highly
complex because some of these systems
aren't being shut down on anything like
the kind of frequency that would provide
immediate response stores will implement
a few are big chain of stores
a few stores at a time and then move on
to other stores and so you're always
having some parts of their system
lagging considerably in the patching or
power company will have an annual shut
down for maintenance and as far as
they're concerned that's the occasion
for updating
the idea of updating more frequently as
one that they can comprehend but not
readily integrate into their business
model so you find that problems like
this occur with some real frequency
they're also just the kinds of cultural
problems in organizations I remember
talking with the chief information
security officer for one of the really
brand-name companies about his
difficulties he said every rule you come
up with even the most obvious
immediately people ask for exceptions I
said to him well give me an example he
said well are you sure it decree that
says never tell anyone your password
don't share your password with anyone
what could be more basic said to me he
said immediately the CEO tells me of
course you sharing his password with his
assistant how else can hear she get into
the emails so if you're gonna have some
theory of change here you're going to
have to take account of these kinds of
variables I think another aspect of
admiring problem is simply the speed of
change very difficult i think for the
layman to cope with maybe even for you
all is well and the example I used in
the washington national security
establishment to kind of bring this home
is the basic point about the historical
a bit and historical analog think about
the introduction of gunpowder for a
minute into your up circa 1300
that's something that over time
radically changes the character all
warfare which is a central concern of
mine but the characters well of the
state and of the economy now suddenly in
the warfare context or notions of
defense as for example building castle
walls with her straight have to be
abandoned or notions of chivalry and
leadership change dramatically
because if I stand in front of the army
waving my sword I'm gonna be shot dead
or notions of organizations of military
strange because now I need mask for
firepower and I need the ability to
bring my troops into a state of training
that's way more sophisticated than if I
simply reads all performers to be a kind
of policy to go deal with something for
a few weeks so I begin to require
standing armies with trained officers
who even understand something about
ballistics and the like and then the
state changes because I need to have in
the state or a capability for sustaining
these armies which brings me to taxation
and the like and I also need a munitions
industry because i dont have a munitions
industry I'm gonna lose in any future
kind of combat so everything changes the
nature of warfare the nature of the
economy the nature of the state my
observation is pretty simple one which
is the the coming in the information age
is not less significant than the coming
of gunpowder but all the changes that
are just described you take place
essentially over the course of two
centuries and all the changes that we've
experienced by and large major changes
in the information world record over two
decades so the speed of assimilation is
just very very difficult for policy
makers and others and Harrington a
government official put it nicely to me
when we're talking about this and I made
the point of just described she said
yeah the problem is that the technology
changes at the speed of Moore's Law and
the people don't know what's in our
heads doesn't change that fast we have
all kinds of legacy systems operating in
this contact so you see the dramatic
changes that we've experienced up till
now I'm gonna say a little bit about the
the future shortly but what I'd like to
particularly emphasized is that this is
a famous quote from well-known computer
scientist william Faulkner who said the
past is not dead it's not even passed to
have to explain this folder reference to
the soldiers not sure we have these
overlaps these could continuities from
the the world that has passed and that
remain embedded in our systems and give
us fundamental problems you may give you
one example from the national security
world that may be a little subtle and
almost relieved but perhaps beyond your
experience I think its importance in the
way government officials think about
digital information systems that by and
large they were in the works here
context thought of originally and our
biggest development of them in the
context of espionage intelligence the
National Security Agency NSA is
obviously the leading reno of
capabilities in this regard for us it's
striking when you think about the
national security world that it has some
kind of implicit norms in the cold war
spilling into more numerical help me
think this out in the cold war we
basically didn't interact in direct
conflict way with the Soviet Union
whenever possible we avoided that the
battlefield involved various proxies
think about the Vietnam War cuba other
issues like that but by and large we
didn't have direct confrontation in
there was some sense of rules of the
road and have restrained at the same
time in the espionage world by and large
all bets were off we don't go out
assassinating each other's chiefs of
station intelligence officers in each
other's capitals and the like but if you
could do something then that something
by way of discovering intelligence and
the like
directly involved confrontation and
competition comes now the cyber world
and the basic attitude I think became
all bets are off its unrestricted we
don't have these kinds of restraints as
another example if you use a weapon in
DoD you want to introduce a weapon is a
whole elaborate legal analysis almost
invisible to the outside world that says
this weapon consistent with the laws of
war but what happens in those cyber
world is that this same tools that you
were used to and did you would use for
espionage and intelligence gathering can
also be used for offensive purposes on
the battlefield those tools are in fact
treated as though they were simply
information gathering tools and we don't
have the kind of legal structure around
the more the conceptual structure around
that we have for other things and that's
one of the reasons I think that the
government is struggling with the
reaction to the Office of Personnel
Management Act that you're seeing
because the general historical attitude
has been through two kinds of things
there's warfare and there's espionage
but as you know the cyber straddles both
of them and when they straddle both of
them
it creates complications and so we have
historic ways of thinking that while the
world is so rapidly changing those
historic ways of thinking or
handicapping or limiting us we have this
kind of compartmentalization and no
longer no longer works out we don't have
these kinds of understandings of
distinctions between offense and defense
that we used to have they no longer into
work and another example is in the
notion of well private sector is
different from public sector we used to
think about warfare only in the public
sector kind of context what happens when
you buy public sector mean
moment what happens when you begin to
think more freely will I want to take
you back a little bit and just give you
a little excerpt from my Chinese
document written at the end of the
twentieth century unpublished a piece in
the New York Times in 1998 doing what
every Pentagon official thinks is the
most fundamental and wonderful and
important thing to do which was
introduced to new acronym
and I was very proud of it my new
acronym I thought was very cleverly
designed it was called new the acronym
itself neww and it stood for non
explosive warfare and the notion was
that there are a lot of things cyber
biology etcetera that are coming that
really are weapons that don't go back
that don't explode in the technical
praise or not genetic
this head I think absolutely
characteristic success for me which is
to say nobody talks about it but I
nonetheless want to try and revive it by
reviewing it here a long time these two
Chinese kernels in 1999 and they can
advance the notion of unrestricted
warfare which you can read right up here
are the basic notion was that we're
coming into an era of technological by
LEDs that there is no distinction
between the battlefield and that the new
concepts which are hopefully reading of
this screen the new concepts enable us
to do a new kind of warfare and they had
the then went on to talk about all the
new concept weapons we're not trying to
kill and destroy some watchers were
trying to control remember this is 1999
as we see it as a single stock market
crash a single computer virus can affect
these kinds of new concepts and what
we're trying to do to achieve victory is
to control not to kill we're entering an
era of political economic and
technological minor islands some warning
people will wait to discover was
surprised quite a few gentle and things
have begun to have offensive and needle
characteristics
well you in the light of experience the
last decade will not be surprised at
this you you know these things we've
lived them we see it in the world of
business where we're dealing with things
like I T theft and the kinds of
difficulties that I've sketch draw here
you see it as well in in individual
lives and not only the negatives but
also have the positives are intertwined
with the negatives are sharing of data
and the light on and we're seeing it in
general in the context of the new where
warfare that I've suggested to so where
we goin in regards to this I don't know
I don't think you know I published a
paper few years ago called driving in
the dark which got some attention
because the gist of the argument as some
others are made for example Nicholas has
been we can't see its complex evolution
of the complex future the emerging
realities are going to be challenging
for us because in fact our headlights
only go so far and if you look at the
predictions historically they're not
very valuable if you go back to 1990 and
you look at predictions about how
technology change will impact national
security the most striking thing to me
is the paucity of attention to the
Internet the internets there is you know
comes out of DARPA starting in the
seventies becomes relatively robust in
the
the eighties it's all there but we don't
see except in retrospect there's a
wonderful book called everything is
obvious once you know the answer in
retrospect we can see all this one in
Prospect were not good predictors and we
need to recognize that because it's
extremely relevant to the world that
we're dealing with here
the fact is I can point to the fact that
I know something about the pace of
technology change I know that that
transition into gunpowder will continue
whenever accelerating kinds of ways and
I know there's a huge variety of actions
and of actors out there that will occur
in that society is becoming ever more
dependent on these things but I can't
say a lot more I dunno though what I'm
concerned about as a national security
analyst and what I think policymakers or
to be concerned about
and very particularly concerned about
the structure of social process sees
that is say the undermining of
capabilities and
things like the financial system
war the power companies and the like
that provide a backbone 44 capabilities
and I know that I'm concerned about how
things might evolve for individuals
support from the state me my first
reaction as the Internet of Things
evolved ever further was that this
represented a set of risks but from a
national security standpoint was all
that concerned if somebody can have my
refrigerator or if somebody causes an
individual or will be election and the
like but if in fact I'm a terrorist
group like Isis and I want to create a
ver can lack of trust and indeterminacy
in other contexts in America maybe if I
can make people very unsure about the
safety of their automobiles by
periodically causing them to wreak havoc
I can achieve my political ends in ways
that I need to care about so there's a
sense if you will of the character of
the problem and at this point you might
feel a little bit like this is just too
much
some dimensions to think about from a
policy standpoint but clearly it needs
to be thought about among the other
parts of my background I was at one
point of supreme court clerk working not
far from here for supreme court justice
and another supreme court justice
besides the one I was working for
Justice Douglas was well known as a
misanthropic sort of kind of love
mankind in abstract but he did the rest
of us but he one day fell to telling a
story about his father which I think
really was apocryphal but it's quite a
lot he said that his father was an
itinerant minister who wandered around
the Pacific Northwest and one day he
mounted his pulpit and looked out and
its audience and found just one guy
sitting out there and he said to that
guy you really want me to go ahead with
the service they looked up at him and
Justice Douglas said Cowboys said well
preacher understand on the couch and
what if I went to the field and food for
40 horses and found your sworn I
wouldn't let that one go hungry so
Douglas said he thought about his father
thought about that seems to make sense
that he proceeded to give all holes
service full board prayers hymns then he
walked to the back shook hands with his
congregation of one the Cowboys shook
hands with him and he did you wander off
his father couldn't stand it and yelled
after the Cowboys how did you like that
and the Cowboys as well preacher I'm
just lonely cow man but if I went out to
the field with from 440 horses in
founders 10 wouldn't do the whole load
on him
the problem in important ways 'as how do
you get beyond admiring the problem
dumping the whole load on you policy
makers and the like
wringing our hands and then saying we'll
have contributed so I think what we need
to do is get at the root causes and I'm
going to give you a little summary that
represents kind of an abstraction all up
in a store with the phenomenon of the
complexity of these systems Microsoft
operating system they don't reveal their
number
of lines of code ballpark fifty million
lines of code I asked major corporate
financial company person has to meet for
me how many lines of code is company
maintains and he's responsible for
answer one trillion these systems or as
others have observed the most complex
kinds of systems we've invented and that
means that we have extraordinary
difficulty observing them we have
extraordinary difficulty enabling us to
comprehend what's happening within them
and they have exceptional vulnerability
if you take the notion of the start no
shit in one book for every thousand
lines of code doesn't equal ability but
it gives us some sense of what's
involved when you're trying right out
fifty million lines of code in fact in
convened to policymakers this point
which is extremely important I think
their first intuition is you guys
created this problem it's a technology
problem fix either you were too if I'm a
right-wing politician you were too much
bad trip peace-loving hippies who didn't
care enough about security or if I'm a
left wing politician you guys are all
capitalist who just wanted to get the
software out the door cuz that's what
you got paid for and you didn't care so
I'm said to them
ok think about something in the world
you know the USA tax code tax code is
four million words write me a tax code
that doesn't have any loopholes now you
may object that there are a lot of
people out there writing tax codes with
the intention of putting in loopholes
but my point is if you write a four
million Word document
englishman give me an army of accounts
and lawyers struggling to find what are
called vulnerabilities in that document
also find them and you understand that
you cannot create something of that
level of complexity without having these
kinds of errors now give me fifty
million lines of code which are of
course even less observable to the
authors and remember you understand I
think if you reflect on it this is a
mass production operation it's not like
some single person in Microsoft's it's
their rights fifty million lines of code
and comprehensive it nobody
comprehensive it is put together as and
persecution of writing of different
things so don't think that there's a
technical answer to this
readily available at the scale and
complexity that we need it when you look
beneath admiring the problem in store in
analyzing it this is a central point and
it is then compounded by the phenomenon
of extensibility just that I've got a
Microsoft operating system it's gotta
work within Adobe Systems and Xcel
etcetera etcetera and an interactive
effect is going to create complexity
beyond anything that my own system
didn't even if I could somehow generate
my own system it's like the tax code us
to work with a whole panoply of other
business laws estate planning laws it
goes beyond that I have a communicative
problem these systems are designed to
communicate you understand that you
can't begin to comprehend how novel that
would have looked forty or fifty years
ago if you could go back in the late
nineteen nineties the director of the
CIA george tenet of very smart guy says
with testimony in the senate the enemy
is on our system or networks are open
and of course that's the case because of
the nature of the communication in the
more you let people in
in the more you connect functions all
the more you obviously enhance the risks
associated with these very complex
systems and you understand how
fundamental it is that we create that
communicative power it's at the core of
the virtues of the system the system
also concentrates information take for
example snow we've had a story from a
national security standpoint many people
like still people who come in and take
documents whatever their motives and
then hand them along what's unique about
snow is 1.7 million documents we've
never in the history of espionage had
anybody taking 1.7 million documents but
it's a consequence of the fact that in
these very complex and communicative
systems we concentrate information which
is again inherent in the virtues of the
system I want to create a world in which
an analyst can get ahead information
across a number of different domains I
want to have that ability in if I'm
running out of power system for example
I want to see the whole set of
transmission lines and the like or if
I'm running a pipeline system which
valves are open in which valves are
closed I want is it turns out also to
collect information and the information
age enables me to do that
Internet of Things will expand
exponentially my capability to do that
come back to the Office of Personnel
Management threat what we did was to
collect some 21.9 million documents
including from me then ran one to two
hundred pages included fingerprints
foreign contacts histories embarrassing
evidence in the light
put it all in one place and collected it
so than anybody who hacked into that
system could conveniently have at all
whereas in a pre cyber free digital age
that wasn't concentrated in those kinds
of ways and it wasn't collected with
anything like the same vigor because the
new information age
ways we all understand enhances that
capability smart man had a Microsoft
invented the phrase disintermediation
one of the advantages of the digital
world as we take human beings out of the
loop terrifically advantageous if I
start dealing with people who are
intermediaries in making my dinner
reservation or my travel reservation or
buying my tickets
most of the time I wound up being
frustrated as compared with digital
opportunity to do all that directly
myself on a larger national scale it's a
hugely valuable for example in
government that I've democratized access
to information when I was secretary of
the Navy I introduced an internet system
it had all kinds of technological
advantages it saved all kinds of money
but what I really valued was that I
could empower somebody in the
bureaucracy needed a new aircraft part
to simply see me inventory and order it
all without going through the silo of
the warehousing people will just six
people in the like all of which held
information as a source of power and
created division within the organization
removing those human beings is hugely
beneficial but it also removes
gatekeepers guardians people may observe
what's happening
wait a minute somebody's export trading
this financial information
or I got a request not just for a new
password but 450 new passwords or had
all these changes the human beings might
observe and finally the systems are
amazingly flexible they just say we
value the fact that our computers or
laptops can do so many different kinds
of things word processing communications
spreadsheets etc
the basic point I want to offer comes
back to the title of this talk the title
that paper and the graphic I showed you
before this is poison through this is
not a lot of position on taking there's
no way to turn this clock back I don't
want to turn it back but we need to
recognize that inherent virtue just
summarize them on the side is the risk
that to the degree that I concentrate or
communicate or take people out of the
loop etcetera to the degree i buy the
benefits of this technology
each and every one of those steps I
introduced security consequences that
are give risk giving rise to greater
risk the virtue of this system is
intertwined with its limitations its
liabilities in at risk and that is
fundamental it's not just that the
complexity of the system gives me these
problems one reason the technology fixes
don't just get me there is every time i
buy more security I tend to do so in
ways that involve some sacrifice of
mergers
I wanna spend a minute having talked
about software just to see a little bit
about hardware because the hardware
insecurities are quite quite real as
well and you were that easy example I'd
like to give its just people tend to
think about supply chain and all kinds
of sophisticated ways what's been made
to the goes into the f35 latest fighter
aircraft etcetera but I'm struck by is
even if you preserve your whole system
if it turns out that something you used
to power to get more power for your
iPhone as for example simply plug in
adaptor is made we have a device in it
that enables hacking into your iPhone
that connection is fundamental to the
range of issues is extraordinarily great
here and from an espionage standpoint I
just would point out to you you're all
familiar with the Stuxnet experience
listened talked about is the fact that
the Iranians moved to a particular set
of frequency converters and the like
because they became convinced that some
part power and hacked into what they
were buying to install in their nuclear
establishment from from abroad and they
had to begin to produce their own stuff
which then of course set them up for the
vulnerabilities of some of their own
stuff and also introduced a variety of
kind of inefficiencies so the global
supply chain gives us a chance to forget
her ability associated with the hardware
world and I want to show this
sophisticated audience this point but
just giving you a chance to reflect for
a moment on a statistic you're not off
and probably exposed to which is what I
asked a very simple question which is
with respect to the question of
transistors there's a nice little
cartoon that says this guy says you know
it's time for us to begin to spend more
time to us with our children he says to
his wife how many do we have if you
think about that as a problem
think about our transistor world and
imagine the question how many
transistors are manufactured globally
every second
just want you to think about this answer
I'm not gonna embarrass anybody by
having you stand up or embarrass me by
having one of you already having the
only answer let me tell you when I first
began to think about this a couple of
years ago I spent for awhile and did a
sort of back of the envelope calculation
and the number was so unnerving for me
that I managed to get some friends at
Intel to get to work on it may
eventually commandeered the Intel
research department they came up with a
number that was so disorienting that we
then had a couple hours of phone calls
finally we agreed on a number so I want
you to think about this question how
many transistors are manufactured
worldwide per second
just as a measure of how will you
understand those you got your number in
your head every second
14 trillion transistors the complexity
of this system the difficulty of
policing in the hardware side needs to
be appreciated and then of course
there's the human so here's a nice
pictures before snowden we had manning
the openness of the system to third
parties pretty striking one of the
leading series about Stuxnet is iranians
thought they had their system air gap
that there was a distance between their
centrifuge system and its software a
physical distance and the outside world
but of course all kinds of things
happened patches come down the system
needs to be updated contractors need to
go in and one of the theories about
Stuxnet is maybe some contractor got
infected brought in the virus etc if
you're running a a worldwide corporation
Aerospace Corporation for example you
have to integrate with all kinds of
suppliers from all kinds of portions of
the world and that
then causes you to share information
large numbers of people have access to
this information
huge problem and even if those people
are not malevolent the ability to
manipulate these people is pretty great
if people haven't read the next book I
always encourage one of mitnick's books
I always encourage them to do so
almost impossible to read that without
realizing need you too could be fueled
by mitnick and some clever social
engineering every system when you look
at it winds up having this management
problems and configuration problems
outside the software and outside the
hardware I've given you my password
example already so you're familiar with
many of the efforts to deal with this
the counter measures or a long history
we know that we tried barriers and
training but we have fundamental
problems with the leak very badly the
screening in the antivirals you're
familiar with the set of issues
associated with that dependency on
pre-existing signatures the way in which
the antivirals and lag the attacks the
way in which many of them actually
important role in their abilities
themselves and can be used as the basis
for exploits we've done a lot of hunting
the vulnerabilities it's nice to see the
rise of that effort I think it's as I'm
sure you can produce some benefit so is
active defense but that monitoring the
situation and the like
yields also limited benefits we can
create enclaves trip to greater degrees
of very useful kind of thing but again
the information needs to be shared and
as soon as we get into the sharing we
get into all the kinds of
vulnerabilities that are described in
inherent software vulnerabilities that
makes this it's hard for me to believe
and when you talk with the sophisticated
inside operators hard for them to
believe that they can't get into most
anything if you really cared enough and
had enough resources I talk to somebody
makes a career of it goes around dealing
with complex industrial systems and I
asked him how many times he's unable to
penetrate his client he said it might
have happened once it's so unusual the
vice president for security google has
said in a public context that wouldn't
Google organizers red teams they succeed
in getting in sixty percent of the time
there's war did forty percent of the
time that's cool defending itself
against its redeemed
I think we overstate the degree to which
we can defend these systems and what
happens is corporations like to hire red
teams that are firmly qualities of the
people who hired them so you don't wind
up getting good vintage billig good
penetration analysis ultimately about
what serious attackers will do I'm gonna
come back to the church Terrence point I
want to note that a lot of what we're
doing in effect is raising the cost for
attackers not actually preventing them
from ultimately penetrating
began to try and think about ways to
document that one of the things I did
was to get a company that has done some
involved invulnerability hunting at
Export Development and I asked them to
go back and go through their records and
show me through a rough indicator wanna
make too much of this is just a lost
relative on what's happened over time in
terms of their production function for
vulnerability discovery how many
researchers medium quality do they need
to find major
abilities and basically this chart from
2006 to 2011 shows you their production
function and shows you that in fact it's
gotten harder to find vulnerabilities as
we get things like buzzing and a whole
lot of different kinds of vulnerability
on store out there but if one researcher
could producer find choose significant
vulnerabilities in a year back in 2006
and only finds a half and that is it
takes him two years to find availability
on average in 2011 we've significantly
raise the cost for attackers it's now
four times as difficult as it was before
by this rough luster to measure but just
means that if you're hired four times as
many people you can produce the same
number of vulnerabilities I'm
simplifying but I think you see the
illustration another manifestation is
look at the vulnerability market look at
the government productions
here's a certain report every week we
get a description of substantial
vulnerabilities or look at point to own
and look at the successes that are
enjoyed at it by the top-level people or
the even the people who don't win we're
not at the very end of the distribution
and win the top prizes so you understand
all this hopefully this is a way of
conveying the problem and I want just in
my closing minutes to talk a little bit
about my own view about things we could
do to improve your situation given where
we are first of all fundamental
proposition that emerges from this is
presumed vulnerability presume that
digital vulnerability and in critical
systems treat this as though its
contested territory of phrase amicus on
today's used in some in some
create liens systems that is ones with
fewer tax services and recognize if this
is poison fruit go on a diet
ask yourself do I really need this
functionality because it's introducing
vulnerability in that doesn't just mean
enclaves in the like an easy example for
me is a printer most people think that
they want a printer to print seems
pretty evident
don't think enough about what marrying
up the fax capability with a print
capability doesn't terms of
communicating in connection to the
outside world how about the fact that my
printer has a Bluetooth capability that
enhances its vulnerability how do I feel
about memory in my printer most people
are buying memory and their printer and
don't want it I come back for example to
the example snowden he could steal 1.7
million documents could copy them I see
why is an administrator he could get
access but as an administrator was
nothing that gave him a need to take
this stuff out so far as I can tell from
the outside the answer to that is the
NSA people or not they disabled the
computer capability that would enable
replication what's known is not done and
he with a screwdriver reenable it so my
question is why did it have the
capability to begin with and the answer
is because we buy standard kind of
computers in these contexts all the time
they come equipped with this huge range
of capabilities we should be doing is
thinking more about us about slimming
down or systems I think we also ought to
think about the virtues of a demand
systems and about analog so let me come
back to Stuxnet it again as an example
one of the things that striking about
Stuxnet is it was not just a penetration
of the systems that control the
centrifuges it was and we know this from
the public documentation
a system that also deceive Iranian
operators as to what was happening but
playing back to them simply standard
operation of centrifuges when in fact
the centrifuges spinning out of control
fundamental design implication of this
is do not convert your situational
observation capabilities and your safety
systems to the same modality as your
operating systems if the Iranians had
had a plain old analog system that
measured vibrations of centrifuges and
when the vibrations began to get out of
control
sounded of physical alarm that ranked No
digital attacker from a distance could
have thwarted that system maybe somebody
could have gotten in the womb and
disabled one or five or ten but the
centralization in concentration of the
digital system and its community tivity
would have been offset by a plain old
analog system or I have a friend whose
comes out of the central intelligence
world he's paranoid as paranoia leads
him to have video cameras everywhere in
his house but being a smart guy he's
paranoid about his video cameras and
worried that people from the outside
world my tap into his cameras and
observe everything in his house so what
does he do he puts an index card next to
the video cameras when he goes out so
that if the camera is swivel the index
card falls over an analog system all i'm
suggesting is where systems are critical
we ought to be going through or safety
and control systems particularly and
where possible inserting analog
capabilities or creating resilience in
our operating systems
analog stand alongs sampling so this is
a Back to the Future kind of
prescription if you believe that as
always do that the digital systems are
inherently insecure you want this
complementarity here you also want to
separate those systems so the
contamination of one doesn't lead to
others you want in the words of the
resilience the risk to decrease the
amount of coupling the degree of
integration so I like having apple
system alongside a Microsoft System
simply because I've gotten some
diversity of vulnerabilities warden user
phrase the tenderers repeatedly used in
made famous I want to avoid a
monoculture
want to create resilience in this system
from a public policy standpoint I ought
to be saying hey there was some systems
out there of the power system the
financial system that this country
depends on so fundamentally then I'm
going to impose some degree of
requirement on them with a measurable
and security terms they are what we
recognize in other arenas too big to
fail we regulate or airplanes systems
and the like
demand safety standards we need to do
similar kinds of things in my view in
the Internet world but you have to
recognize the speed of change in so you
can turn my real regulated by saying you
must do X Y and Z because when you do X
Y and Z it becomes too straight jacket
and limiting and there's too much
variation between too many different
systems so I would delegate this
regulatory kind of requirement to the
relevant cabinet departments and
wouldn't have some overall fibers or
impose it and I wouldn't encourage them
to use persuasion subsidies everything
possible including ultimately regulation
to get companies to the point where they
provided a convincing case that they've
done what they could reduce these
vulnerabilities they diversified
desegregating the problem is very
important we need I think to recognize
the fundamental differences between
different industries in these contexts
for example of the financing the power
industries are dramatically different in
their business cases come back to this
point about the interaction between
technology and business culture if I run
a finance company I'm being attacked all
the time every day millions of times I'm
constantly refreshing my software please
see my boundaries understand that my
fundamental assets are digital they're
not physical and I'm at the very cutting
edge software and the like what I want
from government is information about a
tax and by and large I want them to help
share that kind of information and I
want them to leave me in a high degree
of freedom if I run a power company I'm
not as used to these kinds of
frequencies of attacks I have a much
slower cycle of operation i my financial
basis regulated I can't pour money into
any given time I have an annual
maintenance downtime period I'm gonna
react much more slowly I have a whole
different set of requirements I need a
lot of basic education from the
government about what's out there and
some reason of my standards with regard
to it in my tension with regard to it
and that's just example therefore I'm
very inclined to push this problem with
in washington to each of the relevant
government departments and enthusiastic
about longer-term
research and development in this arena
I've sketched why it is that I think
that the problems are inherent in the
technology but there are opportunities
in terms of making encryption easier to
use something we just talked about here
in terms of use of formal languages to
scale our capabilities to provide more
protection and the basic design of our
systems with the security focus would
yield I think a lot more benefits so for
example former secretary then maybe so I
say as the Navy develops its next
generation of submarine or destroyer
let's make it a national goal to say how
will I designed this system so as to
reduce its vulnerabilities to minimize
the amount of poison food it consumes
maximize my use of analog and out of
band systems maximize my use of formal
language protections that some key
junctions etcetera and when I designed
that system I'm gonna come up with
something very different from the
traditional battleship or I could do the
same in the context of the power
industry for example in the Navy world I
wanted integration of information at the
bridge a starkly the captain on the ship
to see it all but of course in a digital
age that creates a particular
comprehensive set of vulnerabilities so
how would I design my ship fundamentally
different conceptually if I take account
of this that's a project we're doing
over the course of a decade while we
evolve another system or talk to
recently the IAEA International Atomic
Energy Agency and my basic theme pushing
the analog kind of notion there was hugo
is a really good historically its safety
analysis and regulation and the light so
you say for example that we need to make
up a number here ten different cooling
capabilities so that if one or two or
three fail I've got the ability to bring
in the others and when you get some
significant number you think you built
in resilience and safety now you go
ahead though and improve the
modernization and digital systems that
will control these and you've created
one single failure point in what
previously worked in different failure
points you need regulators to recognize
but also as we design new systems you
need to create good thinking about how
we build them better protection against
those vulnerabilities I also because I
care so much about the business culture
and the like I'd suggest it isn't just a
technological problem and the tendency
overwhelmingly in washington is to
invest in the technology and R&D money
in technology dollars I'd like me
anymore
investments in these sociology and
anthropology associated with the use of
these systems it's why johnnie doesn't
use encryption its puts applied to the
larger system as a whole we need to
understand better what's going on within
these systems we need the number of
people will recognize this better
pooling of attacking formation and I
suggested in that paper your goal is a
nice example of how this is done a
private corporation my tour in the FAA
world
federal aviation world recognize the FAA
collected data on all aerial accidents
but didn't on your missus there was a
whole big issue how do we share
information about near-misses people
said I don't want the FAA regulating it
they set up a private entity in the
beginning only one or two airlines
cooperated over time with airlines on
the board and the like
ever-increasing numbers did it now
covers essentially all of us' aviation
industry FAA has a seat on the board but
FAA doesn't control the information
information is then
anonymized and share more broadly that
to me is readily achievable model I
don't need legislation and the like I
can move forward in that regard
power companies are beginning to do some
of this through first and other kinds of
activities
I'd like to add that very concerned
about the federal workforce and this is
a good example of how we might move in
this context from the traditional ways
of doing business which historically
those legacy systems are so embedded the
past is not dead
we have a whole set of federal hiring
and training standards and methods of
organizing that are very ill adapted to
the digital world that I just described
my suggestion is we could create a
federally funded research and
development corporation and Fri Dec
that's a private company there are many
such that already exists on the board of
one but I'm not pushing this for them
just as a general proposition we could
create a new one that would be a place
for people who were cyber skills to come
together and be hired would you hire
them well I don't really care in the
arena you will work in so much about
degrees and traditional credentials what
I care about is a skill that actually
for example finding vulnerabilities are
dealing with other peoples exploits
so maybe I should hire by tournament
and higher winners who achieve in these
contexts what I want to do in terms of
training and the like I'm gonna put
these people together in a pool because
so much to learn is from on the job
training not just being in one agency
but moving between different federal
agencies and they learn from each
other's peers I want somebody who's
cyber skill to run this think about
putting it in a place like Silicon
Valley why do I need it Washington and
now suddenly I begin to be able to draw
a different kind of talent pool which I
can tell you I think we desperately need
and finally I want to just concluded by
talking for a moment about norms and
deterrence and I want to invite your
questions
lot of fuss now about the challenges of
our conflicts with the Chinese people
indicted in Pittsburgh from the PLA
People's Liberation Army in China we
have obvious sources of conflict over
espionage and over IP theft the point
i'd make though is we also have some
areas of strategic stability we haven't
yet seen stage attack one another to
speak of in the context are shutting
down their power systems or undermining
their financial systems the big
catastrophic kinds of things that I be
concerned about and I think we and for
example tried over Russia have common
interest in avoiding that formal warfare
it's just not good for either of us
ultimately to give you a slightly more
technical but suggestive example I don't
think it serves either trying to or loss
to probe each other's nuclear command
control networks with our espionage
tools why is that because we've
recognized that we have systems that
have gone somewhat under the name of
mutually assured destruction mad let's
say it's better if the chinese have a
second strike capability then if they
don't because if they only have the
ability to strike first and we threaten
destroying their missiles they need to
launch but if they know they have the
ability to survive an attack us even if
we attack foreigners the situation will
be more stable they'll be less likely to
attack and a hair trigger way but if the
whole system depends on cyber system and
the system is inherently insecure and
we're out there probing them and they're
out there probing on us and the same
tools as I said earlier that can be used
for the espionage can be used for often
now have introduced in security into
that world I moved from a world of Mad
two months mutually assured destruction
BC I still retain the same fondness for
acronyms mutually assured destruction is
less stable we can't find her way
towards some Emergen norms that agreed
that there are certain kinds of things
we won't do a lot of problems with this
a lot of challenges in negotiating it
enforcing it and the like we can talk
about them if you want but the reality
is that when we entered the nuclear age
we had no idea about arms control over
how to do it and slowly over time as an
emergent characteristic of the systems
we began to find our way towards some
stability and then we thought about them
and we began to articulate them in norms
and in arms control agreements and so
forth and we need in my opinion do the
same thing in the cyber world so I've
given you a real soup to nuts think it
may be that I've done the whole load on
you to excessively but I want to suggest
we all admire the problem we all see
that it's a brave new
world that these changes compressed into
decades or the equivalent of gunpowder
over the period of centuries that we
can't think as fast as the situation
demands but we need I think to move
beyond that sensation really trying to
analyze the core of our problems in our
tried to give you a little summary of
that today and to thinking not just
about the kinds of incremental defensive
kinds of activities that I've made
reference to but also most fundamentally
to try to structure institutions and or
programs and our norms in light of Borno
assists in ways that can make us
stronger
will we ever be completely protected in
OK in this area but we can improve our
batting average quite significant way I
can guarantee performance for success in
every single pitch that's thrown at me
but I know how it is that I could get to
a better world with a much higher
success rate a better batting average
and boy i wud extraordinarily valuable
so I thank you all for not having gone
out for haircuts and invite your
questions thanks very much
I love their dirty word our business it
would be that when people delivery
product it'd be like you mentioned slim
down there is a wonderful example
yesterday it worked during the
telematics talk given by Stefan savage
students and in that case there is a
device that plugs into the OBD port of
an automobile in modern automobile have
this it could you can control with SMS
messages you can using SMS message like
you send a text message to it and tell
it to update itself from the search your
choice you can have a do anything this
device has all the software on it needed
for compiling but for managing the
system it is not been slimmed down and
of course it has told controllers are
very keen disabling the brakes when
things this is actually more serious and
what Charlie Miller was talking about
his blackout so simply having it why
this happens because people most
developers are clueless they build a
system they're glad it works in the ship
it out the door they don't know that
they need to clean it up and slam it
down and minimize it so the footprint
that you can see from the network is a
very safe one so that would be a simple
thing that we could do ya so I think
you're right I think we see this very
richly lots of different arenas and you
one good example by the way the TV folks
have departed so you can preserve your
anonymity which puts you step out of me
but I think the reality is we're going
to get there were going to get to a
world in which will be more security in
these devices and instruments and the
Internet of Things
the question is help out the reason I
say that is the disasters that you're
worried about and I'm worried about or
going to the question I think will be
how much we can minimize them in advance
and how much we can prepare ourselves if
and when they do occur we're able to
respond with some rapidity
ineffectiveness we can at least program
some capability into those systems and
in my opinion the challenge of thought
leadership in this area whether in
government or within the industry is to
get ahead of the problem it will not be
broadly accepted until that moment but
if for example we have a crisis but if
for example your manufacturer and you
design your automobile to pay attention
to security would mean I'd give you any
market leverage now and everybody may
argue against it within the company but
if you can see that there will come a
time where that would be a defining
characteristic to people will demand
you can have the foresight to make a
financial investment against that I
think that's a winning strategy so I'm
trying to kind of get people as you're
trying to get us to be more sensitive to
this issue so that we move further down
that road and at least when the crisis
comes were able to add that I wish I
could do more
that's the most thanks thanks yeah I
full disclosure I'm Russia so my
question is well that's full disclosure
that's the extent of it had some very
scary because like your nuclear
facilities are connected to the internet
so you're saying that China Couture I
certainly hope your facility is a lunch
meat sales second thing is that how do
you like the news media that Russia's
hacked into pentagon how do you know its
Russian rights nuclear weapons against
China Russia
cyber attack and that's a common friend
and yes right now so I guess I'll say
well if somebody is trying to hack us to
respond to fool you know I write my
where I write like something I would be
addressed and then you know you're
racing a very important question the
question of attribution how do you know
where this comes from I thought several
different things over the years about
months about attribution
I've come to the conclusion that
attribution in the cyber arena in the
digital arena is not dramatically easier
or harder than in other arenas and this
is very contrary to the accepted wisdom
I recognize there is some instances
let's take the Sony where it appears
from the outside of observation from the
newspaper accounts it's relatively easy
government officials have said publicly
this is one of the easiest attributions
they've had occasion to do why is it
easy well it's partly a technical
analysis what IP addresses are used
through what gave ways it's also what
kinds of tools are being used or refurb
million with them are they being used
elsewhere but it's also political in
motivational now is it subject to
spoofing yes 101 stood still more
between North Korea and the United
States I could go through some of these
steps but not a lot of difficulty
getting all the earmarks right and there
were other contexts where attackers are
vastly more subtle but this is not
fundamentally different from most arenas
of attribution involving criminality or
other kinds of instruments when for
example a biological attacks were
launched in the wake of 911 involving
anthrax letters took the FBI six years
to figure out the perpetrator in the end
you use a whole lot of different kinds
of sources and different dimensions not
just technological ones you use some
insight into your enemies systems human
and format
observations about patterns of behavior
and the like and it's hard for attackers
to completely avoid all of those so you
mind up I think with about the same
ability to make an attribute of judgment
as you do in other arenas it's not easy
in many cases it's easier and others
it's always challenging but in my
opinion it's doable you look like you
want to make some mistakes then
promotions mistake and yeah well I don't
intend to launch nuclear weapons based
on one theory in this context but but
thank you tell us two quick questions
first on the FARDC question I'm
wondering what you think of USD digital
service and meet some of those
requirements and how the FARDC idea
would be different for developing cyber
talent in the government and then second
fell upon what are russian friend was
asking policy level but is the
government in a difficult position with
attribution because get a tribute to the
case of Sony doesn't attribute in things
that are sort of widely attributed
anonymously to China Russia in so we
sort of a tribute when it's convenient
we don't want it down and that makes our
credibility somewhat more difficult I
think tribution point or credibility is
challenged by the difficulty of someone
just asked you to come back to Europe
for Dec questionnaire moment but our
credibility is I think diminished by
first or unwillingness to reveal
information sources and methods
understandable were reluctant to do it
and second by the variation that you
describe where sometimes we do and
sometimes we don't what the government
actors different motivations and
different circumstances and different
considerations and then variation in
credibility strikes me as a consequence
of the fact that they're responding to
other considerations and I think it's
natural that they make if for example
you think china did acts and she's in
pain is coming to visit in September do
you want to use this as a time in which
you point that out and inflame
relationships or do you care about other
issues particularly or if you think all
bets are off and government espionage
and you're doing all kinds of things and
you're trying to emphasize that using
private espionage is not desirable you
may have a wholly different view about
about how much you gonna say about this
so I understand that they have these
conflicting pressures and I think it's
not unreasonable I'm sorry just wanted
to ask you offer for Dec question again
because I didn't quite get what you want
me to say
digital service which was developed
under the federal CIO and has been doing
a little bit of this going into
different agencies and looking at Cyber
concerns it's broader than just
cybersecurity readings do how does that
differ and you think that's the other
noble experiment on internally fine with
any yoga lot of different methodologies
for building this labor pool but what
I'd like to do is build a labor pool in
the high hundreds up towards a thousand
or something
of people who move around between
different agencies of the federal
government
went and who have freed to Cork into the
kind we get in Silicon Valley and I
don't think we've achieved that yet it
may be that the corporate environment
you're describing is every bit as good
I'm just using that as an electrical
thank you thank you follow up on the
labor development question so one of the
really great things for all of the young
people in this room is that I can
guarantee that they'll have jobs they
are in one of the best fields to be in
order to guarantee employment I going
forward one of the challenges that you
could even become a professor at some
universities I do not wish that on them
he enters I'm really glad about two
things one is that the TV cameras are
often the other is that your ten years
to my concern to our students routinely
even undergrads will graduate and will
get paid in industry above a gesture 15
rate right and so and there appears to
be an Internet corporate capacity to
hire in security at this point because
it's not a unique prices for example for
the federal government but it is a
private sector crisis as well how is the
federal government to in fact compete
with the demand in the private sector
when they have real needs that are just
not as sexy to our students so I think
there are 3 answers first you're right
the federal government will always lose
people for the reasons you describing
it's a real problem
second though we have tools for dealing
with it that are a lot better than we
have as for example doctors etcetera
we finance their education bring them in
the military in return for a six-year
commitment that kind of thing we paid
people higher than the norm when they
have special skills in areas that we've
historically recognized like medical or
nuclear engineering and the like but
part of the attraction of the FARDC
world for me is that I'm not in the
government pay scale any longer and I
can begin to respond more to market
forces third comes back to your point
about what sexy subject that computer
scientists are always inclined to speak
about the reality I haven't specified
what around the reality is that the
government work is phenomenally sexy
that's why an ass a starkly has been
able to draw people they know they can
work on the best of the tools and the
like you didn't tell me it's often said
to be fair we yes GAO recruits from this
Community successfully with the sales
pitch hey you can be a cowboy with us do
things that you couldn't do legally
anyway out but hey protect our database
does not have the same poll I think
that's right
I think that's right but I do think that
if I could create an entity that has
some brand and that is high and it gets
over a number of problems of government
employment associated with everything
from prudential -ism to dress code if I
could create a critical mass of people
that mass would be attractive unto
itself and because ultimately the most
marketable skill is the defensive skill
not the offensive scale or it would be I
think unnatural kind of training ground
for people and again in the FARDC I can
move people back and forth more readily
between government and private industry
so the first point still stands
this is going to be a problem but I can
do better I think I would have described
your concern for scholarships and
student and I want to share an
experience with you as you know the
military has a fellow in every
congressional office where the member is
on one of the Armed Services Committee
or the budget committee I went to every
really revealing state secrets here but
I went to every single one of those
offices and ask them to support
additional investment in scholarships
for students who want to work for the
united states government or are willing
to work for the united states government
not one of them was interested
it is not a DoD Policy to invest in
these scholarships every single year the
NSA investment has decreased
monotonically and last year the DoD
spent more on than they did on
scholarships so if you actually are
interested in meeting the goals you want
to meet there are very clear policy ways
to do it there are existing existing
programs and so you know this
really nice gosh i'm happier here but
you know trying to spend as much on
scholarships next year as you do on
pencils so it's a nice statement very
gently delivered
I'm known for my delicacy with it
basically you these phenomena has led
phenomenon you know when I was navy
secretary I once gave a talk in which I
put up a picture of a program for the
army-navy football game on December 5th
1941 and it was a large ad that said no
battleship is ever been some from the
air the day before pearl harbor there
just wasn't a sense so it's very hard
for people to adjust to the new so in
the scholarship programs for example the
existing constituencies that care
fundamentally about their allocation
money and when you argue in the pentagon
that we ought to put more money into the
scholarship program not just take it
away from some others etcetera to deal
with the things you're describing the
general reaction is I do weapons I go to
Scholarships so the blind you're
offering which is the right one doesn't
strike doesn't surprise me that you
encounter any resistance but I think
basically your point is right we need to
invest longer term and a richer way in
this arena so I would encourage you to
keep at it
and no train trip and I look forward to
your investment
tell me first whether you're going to
have to be foreign investment now go
ahead and something that stuff on
alluded to which is sort of offensive
capabilities in the areas
the fact that we you know people seem to
talk about security a lot and in defence
but we often have the same organizations
involved in and defensive effort is
offensive efforts and it looks from the
outside and many times it when there's a
conflict we invest in more enamored of
the offensive capabilities and invest in
having more insecurity so that we can
exploit it rather than more security
maybe because it seems more easier and a
lot of ways because you know you can
easily exploit these things whereas to
secure things you have to scroll thing
and so on how how can you how can we
address that and how can we have kind of
trust in the government's efforts to do
these sorts of things well the thing to
point to a fundamental problem then it's
a piece with what we were discussing
with stuff on the attraction of the
offense particularly to professionals
who are more engaged in offensive things
historically put aside digital to new
things
military has been more attentive to its
offensive capabilities into its ability
to defend its logistics supply chain and
proves to be costly in actual combat
when you have that imbalance that you're
you're describing
I do think it comes in many ways to
educational that's really why I'm
invested in trying to explain this may
be the biblical injunction that the
Trucial free right but I believe that if
we agreed that the challenge of
leadership in these arenas to get people
ahead of the crises you have to make it
real to them you have to explain it to
them and that involves not just saying
an abstract for example these systems
are complex and concentrated in a crash
but it involves showing them that they
involve fifty million lines of code or
14 trillion transistors manufactured
every second and giving them a sense of
vulnerability and then of the
consequences of it and I believe through
education on these points leaders can be
brought along to make more the defensive
investments that you're right they
arguing for I wish I could give you a
more powerful as a result some switch I
can pull its planting the seeds here
there and everywhere it's organic yes
National Science Foundation usual
disclaimer about my opinions not the
government's so the
you talked about the difference between
different industries and how banking has
different concerns and threats than the
power industry and so on and i i working
in my personal researchers in the voting
area we we see a lot of
folks saying that we can do Internet
voting because it's it's really not that
big a risk and then run our best to
somewhere in the audience today says we
shouldn't asked why if I can bank on
line I can't vote online but instead we
should be asking if Internet voting is
safe
why aren't they running to the security
for the banks if they figured it all out
so my question is are there other sorts
of parts of the economy
other than floating that have this sort
of miss conception that they alone are
safe and when the rest of the world
hasn't figured out how to be secure but
they are secure and how do we help them
understand what you've been talking
about today I do think there are areas
of confidence in the world which have
varying degrees of legitimacy for them
for example the military classified
system or the NSA system I think people
believe in and in my opinion there are
commercial analogues to that for example
the switch system and the like what
interests me the mechanism for transfer
funds between banks which was yeah but I
think they with some freezing point to a
strong record of extraordinary numbers
of dollars of transactions relative
penetrations but your point is right
that is there's mobility still inherent
in the system would interest me the most
about them is can we generalize about
what makes those systems strong and
about where that vulnerability lies and
what we can do about it so for example
to the degree those systems already some
of them do use analog to protect
themselves or multiple factor
authentication or decentralisation and
decoupling so that the intrusion in one
part of the system still leaves the
system resilient to recovery that's a
very helpful thing and we want I think
vulnerabilities but to the rest of the
world that they have gotten a greater
degree of protection so let me just give
an example I talked about red team in
order to how many companies not only do
penetration testing with their red teams
for their audit committees and the like
but say to the attackers now we're gonna
privilege you within the system see how
much damage you can do before we stop
you that's a very valuable tool it's
more companies use but others more
companies don't so I want to see us
observe these kinds of best practices
and spread them and you're seeing things
like digital as a system for sharing
this kind of information then gears been
running something which swaps
information between these I think that
kind of activity is very useful so I'm
after observing the system is quite
closely both to sensitize their
operators to the fact that they are
vulnerable
Bowyer in my point but also deserve the
best practices from thank you talk to
the meters from the University of
Maryland College Park and I have a more
technical question about your patch lack
of patch deployment example that we've
been we've been doing some work on
measuring deployment and we saw that the
more recent techniques for start silent
patching are actually able to patch
fairly large vulnerable populations
quickly so what do you think are the
barriers to adopting this approach is it
the fear that you might stabilize the
system or that an adversary might inject
malicious batches regulatory concerns
I'm sorry you asked about the barriers
to observation of the system or the
barriers silently without user
intervention the barriers to patching
approach that because that that is the
fastest way to yeah well I think it's
pretty striking to me that all the
systems we come up with
windup being subject to Subversion told
cannons encryption
on Clay's these observational kinds of
capabilities etcetera and with each new
technical innovation it's perfectly
useful step forward I applaud the kind
of work you're doing but it leaves us
ultimately our experiences persistently
that the attackers them find a weakness
in in that part of the system so I would
expect that you're going to see the same
thing in the arena is that that you're
describing over the time immediately
ahead how do you balance you know the
insecurity caused by the problem not
patched fast enough with the possibility
that something you know that the
patching system I might be subverted
yeah well I'm constantly in the patching
system balancing the the the
complications of patching the
introduction of a new system the
business costs and so on
with the security requirements that I'm
getting from it and in my view it's an
order I mean there is no general rule I
can I can offer I feel very different
about it
and different industrial kinds of
context depending on how central
security issue and the like I also
though ultimately believe that the
supply of 0 days for a serious attacker
is great enough that they're going to
constantly find things even when we have
i'm happy to talk about this further
separately though thank you I think less
to questions and then I should stop
Postgraduate School I'm going to ask you
a question of building resilient systems
engineering systems and I'm a big fan of
speed in these contexts in the pentagon
context of this is another example of
the embedded power the past the
procurement process was designed in a
world where we confronted an adversary
the Soviet Union that was remarkably
ponderous the system cold while the
Soviet Union and this is a story of my
life and some dimensions the
if the soviets were developing a new
tank we would learn about it
intelligence and the like they would
have a five year plan succeeded by
another five-year plan we are on our
side became just like them we would
develop a five-year plan to develop a
new tank to perceive as long as faster
than their five-year plan we did ok I
want to give a speech in which are
observed that with the fall of the
Soviet Union the world's largest
surviving operating communist system is
the you s military five-year plans
uniformity you name it
repression of freedom of speech we have
all the attributes of a good communist
system so moving to the speed that
you're right knee pointing out is
absolutely imperative and in fact the
system is designed to do you risk by
constantly surveying what we're going to
acquire whereas it's actually
introducing more risk for the reason
you're right knee pointing out which is
the speed of change so what we need to
do is invest more in spiral development
and take advantage of the fact that
software can be realized and by much
more quickly and by instead of buying
with the notion that the stuff gonna
last 15 or 30 years the life of the
typical airplane orders ship that in
fact it's going to be quickly voted six
months one year two years so that
constantly going to be refreshed and in
my view that's a different system and it
requires an investment of energy to get
us from here to there but your
proposition is in my opinion right and
we need to move down the path you're
describing thank you last question susan
mccur Columbia Journalism School I will
say that I really appreciate the focus
on the application of security and
industry and especially the point you
made about kind of having leader
technologies my favorite example and not
as the Samsung television
recordings what you say in your living
room and transmitted to Sams on my
question is that given that we live in
an information economy and a lot of
business models are currently built on
the collection of information how to
incentivize industry to actually produce
technologies that are leaning that way
when a lot of their thinking about how
they're going to actually make money has
to do with collecting user data and then
selling it for operationalizing it or
something like that so this result whole
big topic that's very important about
the relationship between security and
privacy and incentives to sell data one
thing that's striking to me though is to
me
security is actually more fundamental to
the business model of these enterprises
then the recognized and it's more
fundamental to privacy than privacy
advocates tender recognized for example
I like I think everybody in this
audience do not like the idea of the us-
government reading my email but if I
entirely stay out of the security
business at least in my case I'm pretty
confident that I'm subscribing to a
world with the chinese government reads
my email on balance I like that a little
less or you can say you just like them
both the security requirements are
fundamental to the privacy interests
that I've got and similarly if companies
are going out there and acquired data on
me and the like
at a minimum their business model has to
depend on keeping that to secure and if
it turns out people can read that data
and on target and other people acquire
credit card information from my company
the reality is my company suffers
mightily you would think that lesson
wouldn't be learned it is being learn
but it's being learned slowly you know
JPMorgan I recollect cybersecurity
investment level estimated at 250
million dollars after they got hacked
they raised it to 450 million dollars
public filings with the SEC written up
in the wall street journal we need to
start shutting those doors sooner I'm
still there have fundamental tensions
between or desire in the companies to
acquire data and our privacy interests
as citizens but at least both ends of
this equation order recognize that more
security would protect both their
business interests and my privacy
interest so we're clearly sub optimizing
even before we get to a tradeoff between
things so on this note I think I should
and thank you all very much for your
involvement in patients particularly to
agree you can get involved in this
policy discussion I really feel as
though the fundamental problem is
getting people at the point where they
understand this better policy people lay
people and the like
also professionals like yourselves who
may not normally have as developed a set
of policy interest if you buy my analogy
to the world of gunpowder these huge
changes occurring we're talking about a
number of them in the course of the day
people's minds lag behind the only way
to get us moving further is to bring
people's understanding to reach a point
and for that if you don't do it and I
don't do it whose gonna do it
ultimately it depends on you so I hate
to impose a big national security
problem on you but you are after all
meeting in Washington you have to act as
though you are thanks a lot