ISO enojar peter is investigating the
computer security needs and
journalists and money Mrs McGregor I'm
from Columbia Journalism School this is
work that I did with my co-author
Francisco rosner from University of
Washington and Polina charters in 10 min
holiday who are part of the HCI and
design program also at the University of
Washington said talk a little bit about
the motivation for this work last year
at Black Hat Asia she not only in our
data presentation about the fact that 21
out of the 25 top news sites in the
world were subject to state level
attacks and this is something that was
already kind of known in the media the
previous year
news agencies have reported themselves
that they had been the subject of
attacks the Wall Street Journal The
Washington Post Bloomberg New York Times
and in a couple of those cases the New
York Times and Bloomberg in particular
it was surmised that the motivation for
these attacks was actually just cover
the sources for stories as particularly
in respect to China of course we also
know that the impetus to discover
sources is not exclusive to these kinds
of attacks on the domestic front
metadata and kind of legal attacks have
been used extensively in recent years to
identify journalists sources this was
very much the case in James rise in New
York Times and others so there are a
range of kind of computer security
issues that journalists and journalistic
organizations face in trying to conduct
their intent to conduct their work and
there are in fact quite a number of
robust technical tools that help address
these these issues individually right so
we have things like GPG that can provide
in a static encryption tour secure drop
which is actually designed specifically
for journalism for kind of a document
that dropped case and yet recent
research this was a Pew survey done with
specifically investigative reporters
globally others released in February
found that 50% of them used no computer
security tools whatsoever in conducting
their work another 30% used one or two
but not with great regularity and so the
real question is why not
it's clear that journalists are targets
that there are a wide range of kind of
threat vectors that they face there are
tools that can help address some of
these things and yet for some reason
they're not doing anything about it and
so our observation was that maybe
there's something for understanding
there's something about the journalistic
process that makes it difficult for
journalists to effectively apply these
tools in the way that they need to in
order to conduct more securely so also
drawing from that Pew Research survey
this is a quote from our respondents
saying I report on another as immigrants
a great deal and have concerns about how
to communicate with them without putting
them at risk you know many of them are
not extremely computer savvy and this is
something I struggle with a great deal
so we're experts from the journalism in
computer security communities we went
about this work by conducting in-depth
interviews with 15 full-time journalists
and news media organizations in the USA
and France and in doing this we want to
just focus on kind of the typical
workflow system understand with a
general journalists across was maybe
where there were gaps in that weren't
being addressed by existing computer
security tools we didn't ask journalists
directly about their threat models
because that's really not a common term
in journalism so instead we designed a
set of questions about their risks and
consequences of those risks to kind of
illicit a threat models there and we did
this as a qualitative data analysis so
conducted the interviews had to
independent voters go through the
results in some cases and we have tables
of all these results in the paper you
know had some qualitative data about you
know how these people used a particular
to learn how many of you that particular
tool but also qualitative thing for
themes about what their security
concerns are there general practices
some of the ad hoc techniques they used
to secure their information just a few
more details about the participants
organizations really really range we had
large multinational media organizations
that operate in dozens of countries we
had really small kind of subject area
focused organizations and we also
intentionally wanted to serve a
journalist who covered a range of eats
rights and not just the people who have
perhaps the highest sensitivity
information but also kind of just doing
sort of regular regular reporting
so we did have some people who were
covering government for example you know
we also have others who are doing sort
of lifestyle and city issues even within
this we did find some pretty interesting
pretty interesting anecdotes come out
for example we did have one participants
who reported that his home had been
broken into and only his laptop was
stolen
another reported in working in doing
community telephone communications with
colleagues and services overseas that
technical glitches would often come up
when they started talking about
sensitive information so online or call
is being dropped and others actually
reported being physically surveilled as
if they were aware that they were being
followed and resources are being
followed
restructure this in terms of kind of
general practices security concerns
defensive strategies and also maybe some
computer security needs that that were
as yet unidentified right things that
have an article have been reported are
identified up to this point in terms of
general practices we found that
participants use a wide range of
communication methods so email as a mass
sometimes even social media telephone
but in general
their tendency was to lean towards the
preference of the source we heard
repeatedly that you know the main thing
was even don't want to raise any
barriers to communication with us or so
is one of our participants noted you
know there's also the idea that maybe
the source understands better than you
do what their weather threat model is
and so you know we're going to go along
with the source feels comfortable also
another important finding was that
long-term sources are by far the
dominant case when doing daily
journalism so of course we're all
familiar with you know snowden kind of
big document that drops the reality is
that this is a very very small portion
of how data journalism even
investigative journalism accountability
journalism really happens and so you
know that also raises
sort of a new set of security issues in
and how do you kind of maintain you know
protect the identity of a source perhaps
over a long-term digital communication
audio recording and note-taking digital
note-taking with a primary for his forms
of interview documentation we had a lot
of people using their phones to record
interviews digital note-taking sometimes
on a hard drive sometimes turn down with
through third-party services and that
was also really common thing there's a
lot of yousef third-party cloud services
to to kind of think information and
we'll talk about that a little bit more
later but very few of our respondents I
you know articulated active security
concerns about using third-party
services in terms of the security of
their information and the concerns that
they did have the primary concern if
information will be to be weird to be
exposed was the effect it will have on a
source and that fact could range from
you know everything in the most extreme
cases to a source being jailed or
suffering physical harm but you know
just a sort of plain old embarrassment
you know that there is a lot of
information that they have much of which
often doesn't make it into a published
story and then you know is is retained
but you were to be exposed wood would be
highly embarrassing to the source and a
side of the sort of you know personal
feelings about having damaged someone
else if the loss of credibility the idea
that if you burning a source furnace or
other people who talk to you right
you'll become known as somebody who does
that and it's going to hurt your ability
to do your job it's gonna hurt the
reputation of your organization and so
that's a that's a really big problem
government identification of sources was
also something that came up as kind of a
background anxiety as well as
disciplinary action that both of the
journalists might sort might face within
their organization for having failed to
protect their information out quickly
but also disciplinary actions
again at the source might suffer such as
losing their job you know losing
standing within their community and some
additional concerns over a little bit
more of a surprise where the loss of
competitive advantage this was again
something that was forced to repeatedly
and that was again partly due to the
idea that with if you lose credibility
you know where the source that sources
gonna take their information somewhere
else right in your competitors gonna get
the story that you thought you had a lot
on but additionally that here just kind
of generally sloppy with your
information
a competitor might discover what you're
working on right and b2 publication and
you know that's a case where foreign
organization is also an individual using
credit you know you can have a case for
you spent weeks months sometimes years
on a story and you essentially lose the
advantage of that because someone else
beat you to the punch and financial
consequences so we did have some sort of
talk about having potentially
embarrassing information about a major
advertisers and that if that were known
and I might influence the business
relationship that the organization had
been that advertiser in terms of
strategy is that we found journalists
employing the vast majority of them are
non technical meeting with sources in
person was a very very common practice
but it was almost it was rarely
articulated as a security strategy for
the most part it was because they said
we get our stories this way you get
better stories when you talk to people
face to face something so maybe some
possibly has a security property
although he later that not a complete
security property but I do things like
using code names and no ticking for
example so you know not writing down
someone's true name maybe only
describing them with you know salient
details that they feel are only sort of
interpretable themselves in an extreme
case using kind of intermediaries and
preset protocols to arrange meetings and
make contact
authentication which is actually also a
really big thing that came up so in this
case being contacted by somebody from a
sort of unrecognized
you know digital digital identity and
the journalists saying okay well if
you're really really are who you say you
are then you know post this line to you
know your Twitter account at this time
and using that as a as a form of hot and
hot indication looking at the technical
strategies they use the most common by
far was encrypted chat and email but
importantly this attended to apply to
communications within a team or
organization right so you know maybe in
talking to each other throughout the day
you know this is a journalist sees but
it was much less common in communication
with sources some file encryption as
well so you know
correction device encryption thing they
didn't come up a lot where things like
tour bTW and other secure messaging apps
and you know we have again all of the
details and the use in this paper so
obviously we're interested in why
journalists aren't using his computer
security tools despite the fact that
they have these these needs and there
are tools out there but we also
identified some of the main themes
around why they did you security tools
and for the most part I had to do with
coming into direct contact with people
who explained how to use them or ask
them to use them so very often it was
because I source required it so that I
won't talk to you unless you can do
whatever and chattering email or they
had had some kind of explicit digital
security training to familiarize them
with these tools so some some of them
are internal or external basically
someone had said to this person directly
you should be doing this and here's how
we're participants did make efforts to
protect information there was a sort of
general awareness of like I should be
doing this and I know I know I should be
doing this and maybe I tried to do this
you know a couple of things here and
there but as it was earlier often
incomplete right so they might try to
protect information in one contacts and
buy it but leave it vulnerable and
another so you know going to me to
source in person by taking their their
mobile phone along a mobile device along
or even sort of trying to protect their
communications with that person but then
doing a phone you using a phone to
record the interview which may or may
not be sinks to like iCloud or something
like that so even though you know the
tools are a bus it's very often
difficult it is clear that you don't
have a hard time kind of kind of putting
them together
them together in a way that really
effectively protects all of protecting
against all of the risks they face so in
terms of the obstacles again a really
common theme that came up was the
digital divide is a very significant
barrier to better communication security
because again journalists are often
going with the sources comfortable with
what the source prefers so its
participants noted you know most of the
sensitive sources I worked with are also
people who probably aren't very tech
savvy I don't know what is secured non
intimidating Lee tacky way would be to
communicate with them some of them don't
even necessarily have email addresses
another big issue was the absence of
clear authoritative indicators about the
protections offered by particular tools
so as I'm sure many of you are where you
know there are lots and lots of new
services chat services you know absolve
this that have come out in the last
couple of years in particular saying you
know this is accurate as private as a
protected and you don't have a timer the
expertise to figure out which which ones
are actually worth using
and even if the ones that might be
considered you know that may be
considered quality really understand the
nuances of what they do and don't
protect right and so how to actually
operationalize their use in a way that
successfully protect their information
in the way that they need another thing
was a lack of institutional support so
you know for obvious security reasons a
lot of reporters don't have admin rights
on their work machines right at a
sensible thing to do at the same time
they also don't necessarily they often
don't have you know secure
communications tools installed in as
machines for them even if they can get
permission to install it they don't a
lot of folks don't how somebody or at
least I mean whose job it is to help an
isolated practices in making sure that
are configured correctly etcetera
etcetera so there's a real lack of
resources the institutional level as
well so why don't journalists security
tools I think there's a lot of talk
about usability and and while that does
remain an issue the truth is actually
that journalists used terrible terrible
and usable software all the time and
they fit perfectly well but there's a
big issue of how these things fit into
the journalistic process are sometimes
impede the journalistic process for
example document drops you know might be
great for even for a source like snowden
but they're really not great for the
long-term source that the more common
situation of long-term sources that you
know that don't initially provide
sensitive information so this is a
really important point I think which is
it you never really know when a source
is going to turn sensitive you know most
sensitive sources are the result of
long-term relationships that have been
cultivated over time which means that
you know you might be having a
communication with somebody in all of a
sudden they say something that is you
know that proves to be approved in
retrospect even to be centered over
eight it by that time it's too late to
switch communication channels but that's
very much how that that kind of
information tends to happen the other
thing is that in the vast majority of
cases on a daily basis
you know journalists depend for
authentication for verification
unknowing their sources real identity
yes of course it's possible to
authenticate information even if you
don't know a person's real identity but
it takes
much larger investment of time and
effort to do that and it's simply not
practical to do that for every single
story every single day just a point of
clarification you know so I mean is one
of our participants out here you know if
I don't know who they are and I can
check their background I'm not gonna use
the information right nine times out of
ten it's not gonna be worth it to to do
that actually work and discipline and
verification about terminology here
journalists talk about an anonymous
source saying what they mean is I did
not publish their name it does not mean
they don't know who that person is
anonymous sources in journalism just
means I didn't print it or put it online
but that reporter definitely knows who
that person is editor probably knows who
that person is just sort of facilitate
the conversation there and in the
confirmation and verification is really
at the heart of a journalist you every
day so there's kind of a quick my
colleague uses which is you know the
rules of journalism is if your mother
tells you she loves you confirm it right
so you can never afford to take someone
at their word which means that this
process of finding out whether or not
they have the information they say they
do it whether or not they're really
important so thinking about future tool
design and some of the work that we see
is you know could be informed by the by
what we found here is to think about the
the barriers that are raised to people
who are less expert on lower-income
icing computer security tools right a
lot of people are working with feature
phones they're working with SMS they
don't have exclusive control over a
computer so what are the opportunities
for a meeting
secure communications tools that work
for people who are existing in the
circumstances are a lot of the people
that journalists are working with and
beyond usability also thinking about
stability and reliability in a
journalistic organizations are
businesses even if many of them are not
very profitable ones
and you know what time accessibility
consistency is important for them which
means that they have the same concerns
as other businesses when adopting
software which means that even if the
software is free it's obviously not free
to implement right it's not free to
deploy to train to maintain very often
they don't necessarily have the
connections at the service connections
to have someone who is going to be able
to catch support etc that . software
right so it's very difficult for
organizations to adopt these things that
we sort of identified as existing unmet
needs that hadn't already been clear
before you know it and sort of obvious
risks with knowledge management so it
came up many times as issue of
journalists when they report on stories
they collect a lot of information from
different places across different media
gonna be web footings Notes emails you
know
audiophiles all of these things and
that's touring sinking searching tagging
these these materials were a really I
was just a general challenge of doing
their work in salon of the ad hoc
solutions that we sought to dealing with
our where security vulnerabilities were
introduced so that's what we saw a lot
of third-party a lot of cloud software
come in
was trying to address these issues not
so much as computer security thing but
audio transcription was also just kind
of a big you know that that's a nut to
crack but you know highlighted here by
one of our respondents was you know
someone who had worked in the legal
field for a while you know as a lawyer
you know what say you have a massive
case you the document under 15,000
documents their programs to help you
consolidate and put them into a secure
database I don't know of anything like
that for journalism so this is a really
massive opportunity to not only remove a
whole slew of vulnerabilities that
journalists are creating when they do
this work but also to make sure that the
system that does fill that gap is one
that has strong security properties
secure first contact and managing the
method the tension between anonymity and
authentication came up more than once
responded noting that the first contact
is never very rarely anonymous are
protected it's very difficult to have
that secure and that's often because it
has also because especially in the
Western contacts in journalism more
often than not it is journalists who are
contacting sources first right so again
the major case is you're covering a
story you're probably your first caller
first contacted you within existing
source on that topic and then you're
going to find out from there but most of
it is not people coming to you and so in
that sense it again very source
dependent problems and other things that
i dont metadata protection so again
knowing that especially with long-term
sources you know we don't have widely
adopted ways of communicating that
protect mad at us you know if you do a
really good job for a long time at one
time it feels kind of all falls apart as
a deeper exploration of the journalistic
process and the needs of sources so most
of the folks that we spoke with were not
dealing with a lot of video and photo
for example right and obviously those
needs the table mediator dealing with
changes they need that they have in
terms of security it's something very
different to talk about and correcting
things when you've got hours and hours
of video footage video it or you know
for example you can't exactly use a
pseudonym when you have somebody's face
in material
and then finally understanding the role
of journalists organizations and how
some of some changes within that might
be able to help inform that so are going
this is a sad it was really to kind of
try to bring together these two
communities and and and highlight some
of you that we may be able to make
progress on this front so that's all in
question
over the age of 21
been convicted of a firearm whatever
those sorts of things
technologies be useful to a journalist
in considering a source to be able to
prove that this person is in this role
without knowing who that person is
culturally so foreign to a journalist
that they would never even consider a
technology like that I think it's a
really good question I mean I think you
know definitely but I it's hard for me
to think about what the technical ways
of doing that might be a mean if you
think about just the simple fact of like
somebody having a like at whatever email
address right that's a sort of simple
way of like if I successfully
communicate with you there
you know unless you are super
sophisticated probably you know you're
there so no and I think actually in fact
this is just a lot of journalists would
welcome that opportunity right if I
could know that this person you know
this aspect of their credentials is no
provable without having to know who they
are I think that would be I think that
would be very welcome
technology does exist today it's not in
widespread use but it does exist
yeah no I mean I as i say i mean I think
it's I think it's just a question of
making sure that that maps to the
characteristics that are important to
journalists to verify right I was
wondering about forward secrecy and kind
of ephemeral tools is that on the radar
of journalists at all cuz there's kind
of a big divide between tools of the
femoral jet tools
my message tech secure and then pgp a
lot of times saying journalists are
worried about making sure that they keep
a record of everything and organize it
was there did they think about forward
secrecy at all is that maybe they don't
know the term but do they think in those
general idea yeah I mean I think the way
that they think in foreign secrecy is
you know somebody finds out after the
fact I was talking to the person they're
gonna get in trouble and I think you
know I think I mean definitely chat
tools I mean have been the thing that I
know have have had the most success in
using but a lot of that has to do with
kind of the the lower overhead and a
lower advance work that has to do with
it right you know if you look at
something like you know right it's a
browser plug-in like most people can do
that they can probably do it without
admin rights it's pretty simple to be
like and now go to the chat room with
this name you know as opposed to
explaining a whole occasion flow or
signup sign up processes are a barrier
you know there's something else that I
don't like part of this is also kind of
two cases when you're dealing with
sensitive information and one of them is
that the source and always know that
what they're sharing is sensitive and so
this idea switching channels right and
there's kinda like whoa so there is that
notion but it's not something that I
mean having records is important but I
mean I don't know anybody who wouldn't
be just taking notes on it at the same
time if it was even a recorded telephone
conversations but they might just taking
notes so surprising is just how
self-serving some of the answers
journalists gave securing the sources
say we don't want to speak to source we
don't want to create barriers even if
the source perhapsmaybe you do you think
there
r ethical issues how journalists should
protect sources I mean absolutely like I
think I think it is an ethical issue you
know some of the work that I have done
this was exactly be for that reason I
think the problem is that there's a
tension between you know if if we
restrict ourselves to covering only
sensitive stories that involve people
who also had the saudi and the resources
right i mean we're not just talking
about you know intellectual resources
talking about financial resources do you
own a computer access to a computer you
know then we'd be missing a lot of the
most important accountability journalism
you know and and sort of coverage of the
most important populations right so many
of our most vulnerable populations who
simply need to be covered
you know we are the ones who don't have
access to these tools and resources and
you know and frankly like there's
there's a mean journalistic
organizations themselves are strapped
rate you know you can't necessarily do
you can always fly to Hong Kong to meet
the source
you know you may not even be able to
drive up state to be the source so
there's there's definitely attention
there and there are ethical implications
but I think you know the end of the day
for most journalists about it's about
doing your job and everyone has
concerned about
unduly exposing people but at the same
time you know it's at some point if you
stop doing it work like the list is a
clear where the journalists themselves
strength of published research so the
Jets like
article in the internet right about a
year that compares like jets like both
but never published article about which
tools you know you would use to protect
this also
I mean yes there certainly illiteracy I
mean I think the only thing I would say
is that my experience is also that the
computer security security community has
been kind of a literate about the
journalistic process to know if there
are organizations and public action in a
really great comparison chart of various
tools but I mean this is exactly why
we're here is a kind of open up a
dialogue because you know we feel that
there's interest on both sides and yeah
very much looking forward to trying to
facilitate that thank you one more time