wonderful everyone a good time excellent
very good
so besides 2019 beside to Atlanta 2019
has drawn to a close we thank you so
much for coming out and spending the day
with us learning hopefully making new
friends learning about new stuff and
we've got some details here who's trying
to air drop me good for you
I was pulling images in earlier on
States got air drop anyway so so a
couple stats and this is live because we
had Tabitha who's amazing so we had 760
check-ins that is awesome I think that's
like 260 more than last year that's
incredible so thank you for coming out
spending the day with us my clicker
remote which is really hard cuz I'm very
kind of kinetic and it's it's over on
track 2 so we'll get that later at this
point though what I'd like to do is
welcome everyone to the state volunteers
coordinator staff board people in these
lovely pink shirts if you would like to
come to the stage please come to the
stage now get behind me because we want
to say thank you for everything that
you've done
high fives high fives bring it in bring
it in my hand is gonna hurt so bad do it
we're doing this everyone this is a
thing now that is all right yes yes look
at all these volunteers look at the
staff look at the coordinators right up
yeah bring it up everyone
everyone gets a high-five we have a lot
of volunteers come on oh he's got padded
gloves that's not fair
up high up high yes yes and up high
wonderful thank you for keeping that
clap up cuz honestly they deserve it all
the folks up here and it wasn't just
today many of the people up here were
working on this for months
badges graphics
all kinds of stuff that goes into all
the little details that makes this such
a great day for everyone so next thing
here we want to talk about some feedback
I like doing this at the end of be sod
so we can say like hey we're listening
to you live so this is stuff that when
we do our after-action report and we
generally do a blog post to say hey this
is how we intend on getting better next
year
so at registration we moved away from
Eventbrite frankly because we were
looking at a system that could do
everything for CFPs and the whole kit
and caboodle QR codes really need to
come back for check-in so that'll help
speed things up a little bit we're also
gonna change a few things up probably
next year and you'll you'll see it all
we're really transparent about what we
do and and so other B sides can learn
because if we can learn a lesson they
don't need to then that's great more
tents oh this is amazing economy y'all
like soldering like you like hot metal
and Myint outside so great so we're
gonna add more tents we're and I think
the number we're gonna say is we might
even need to double again so we'll have
to actually talk to full sale if we end
up coming back here to be like how can
we do that but we'd love to do it if we
can so more food trucks I mean we wanted
to have two food trucks and like so the
unfortunate circumstance but maybe what
we'll do is we'll look at three that way
if when you know one ends up dropping
out we still have two we thought we were
good with two but will will definitely
work on that full so did a great job
manager I you guys didn't get to see the
amount of just responsiveness when there
was problems with the Wi-Fi and
workshops or whatnot I can't say enough
for the full sale network team for J for
all the folks just making sure when
there was a problem they were on it so
give them a quick clap by the way they
were they were fantastic but what we are
going to look at is possibly doing
separate Wi-Fi for CTF workshops and
talks will will talk to the
infrastructure folks and see if that's
potentially a possibility and then a
longer check-in registration window so
again we grew by two hundred and sixty
people and you never know when that's
gonna happen so we're all glad you came
but we're maybe say hey if we're gonna
grow at that pace or at least have the
same amount of people that we will make
sure that we've got that window if you
did not get a chance to talk to us and
give us feedback
besides Orlando org do not hesitate to
email us we'd like to hear your feedback
you should also expect to see an option
for a survey last year we did a $100
Amazon gift card because that seems to
entice y'all to tell us things all right
so watch out for that survey it's not
gonna be tomorrow cuz we're all gonna
nap and it'll be some time after we do
our own kind of after-action review
lessons learned etc so at this point and
I know you all want to see this get
given out so at this point I would like
to invite to the stage
David Payton and Zack to talk a little
bit about the sunshine CTF I'll do the
slides for you so you guys can do what
you want to do and you got your monitors
down there
oh yeah just yell loud can we get a
handheld can I get one of these for
these guys I totally forgot Oh what do
we wait no no you guys are good this is
okay today
Talking Stick yeah I'm not in charge
anymore yeah start with some statistics
on it well we'll start with thanks to
b-sides for letting us put this on here
giving us a space and giving us the
infrastructure to support it it's our
fourth year doing it we've loved doing
it everybody has a good time building
the challenges and then coming out day
of and seeing tons of people compete in
it we had pretty full room for a good
portion of the day and then we had a lot
more people competing remote the what I
have up there is the graph of the top
ten teams and how they progress
throughout the day up until four o'clock
and the first-place team was sitting at
2600 and fifth was down to twelve
hundred and eighty a good spread but we
have 24 hours left for it to go or a
little bit more the CTF for anybody who
wants to compete in it will be staying
live until 9:00 p.m. tomorrow Lisa a lot
of people compete remote we had over six
hundred and four users
and probably less than a quarter of
those were in person yeah we've got 15
more within couple minutes recently here
and then on our challenges we had 28
challenges and they had anything
anywhere from 1 to 158 solves so a lot
of people been busy and now on to
actually given the belt out so the first
place in person team with eighteen
hundred and fifty five points is bison
squad and they come up to receive come
on up come get the belt
[Applause]
congratulations and I keep playing so as
you walk by the reaching that box
there's a black bag in there to keep it
in just reaching won't bite there's a
snake nose there you go
that one yeah take it excellent okay
next winner of things oh I think thank
you I get double Mike's air you all that
excellent
Galen don't say anything okay so IOT CTF
this was really cool and Michael Roberts
and Rob Guillory no kind of really owned
this and was was awesome so this is the
same slide from this morning but just to
remind you it was a challenge to hack
some IOT devices put your best little
video on Twitter not showing exactly how
you did it but kind of showing the
result of it and get the most likes and
the person who gets the most likes gets
this wonderful its certificate for net
Wars continuous for a four month
subscription from our friends at Sands
worth over three thousand dollars and
the winner for this is Alexander Cote
come to the stage come get your
certificate
yeah it's the thing yeah well getting
the feathers here you get the feathered
look here thank you thank you
alright so next I would like to welcome
to the stage John from DC furs they did
an auction at their table and he's gonna
give you the results for their auction
and galing up the mic
thank you they aren't oh don't touch
bring it up
test test test I go yeah first I just
wanted to say thank you to Orlando
besides for having us as a community
sponsor as well as queer con we really
appreciate everyone who checked out our
table and everyone who made a donation
to the wisp Def Con scholarships we
auctioned off we did silent auction for
two badges to support that that cause
and it was very successful thank you for
all your support thank you for having us
I'm gonna pull up yeah there you go so
the winners of the badges are richard
jones and todd mcguire or mcintyre thank
you guys so much for supporting us and
whisp Def Con and thank you for
supporting diversity and InfoSec thank
you so much
all right so we've got our silent
auction winners as well and what I'm
gonna do is just pull up these names the
way we're gonna do this is in the lobby
Matt drew Reba out there and I've got
the square reader when we're done here
but in the next couple slides if you
kind of see your name up there and I'll
leave up there for a second
hopefully yeah that's pretty illegible
so if you're eric w u OS monies that was
john ports last year says I'd say John
just bought half the auction so if you
see your name up there please be ready
in the lobby with like I said monies and
we will extract monies from you and
deliver silent auction winnings and then
also again like I said eric w got all
the things i guess so so very good okay
so again we do have a square reader cash
is also fine matt here has all the items
and we'll meet you in the lobby with me
and we'll get that taken care of
so next something we've done for the
last few years is we've done in NVP this
is someone who has risen above and
beyond either through what they've done
through the time they've invested
through challenges etc and this year is
no exception
so this year our MVP conference award
through it goes to someone who dealt
with a mountain of email issues it turns
out we don't send you guys enough email
and so we have a neutral right we're
filthy neutrals and it go to spam and
just fighting that uphill left and right
communications challenge is to manage
our CFP selection and for that we would
like to thank bree hilton so bri come up
here and if you look up here i don't
have it on stage because I couldn't find
it back in the green room but this is a
custom trophy we had made because she is
our dragon tamer and it is a custom 3d
printed dragon trophy because she tamed
it so many dragons this year I can't
even begin to explain and we hope you
like
you're quite welcome thank you for
everything you've done it but wait
there's more
so there's more oh here it is
wonder if L it was gonna be I swear I
thought it was under the rainbow boa I
was like it's hidden under the rainbow
boa so there it is that is very cool and
honestly this is this is something that
we really believe in we put in a lot of
work for this and recognizing our own
and making sure that they know how much
we appreciate them is really important
to us so with that said we've got a
bonus MVP this year and and I didn't
really even discuss this with one but
one other board member but I'm doing it
because I've got the feather bow and
that puts me in charge so this years
bonus MVP award goes to someone who we
had no idea that they would need to rise
to this occasion and we and we have to
recognize them for their unbelievable
efforts today in registration area and
we owe them an incredible debt of
gratitude is is crazy and chaotic as
that registration is getting 620 of you
into the building she handled it with
grace and poise and I cannot thank her
enough for it and I bet she already
knows who it is it is tabatha D Dominico
and because it was last minute I don't I
don't have a prize I have feather boa
hugs if you prefer them or a hearty
handshake there we go thank you so much
for everything you do yeah we'll find
something cool for you I don't know what
yet a feather boa maybe it's yours
congratulations
she's in charge I'm going to drink now
um so the other thank you we won't have
it's actually funny going to drinks the
next slide after this so Full Sail
University we we owe them also a
tremendous thanks they put together so
much work for us you can see it in the
production value their responsiveness
with the network just everything that
they do is
absolutely top-quality all the folks in
the back I won't go through them all by
name because there's just so many but um
they did an incredible job and I'd be
absolutely remiss to not say thank you
from all of us for the amount of work
that they put in to help make our little
security conference look this good so
thank you oh they gave me the fog
machines thanks guys
all right so after party this is the
important part
so Aruba Sports Bra we talked about this
morning so if you're here I'm assuming
hopefully you're joining us and we look
forward to seeing you
arooga is when you walk out this door
you're gonna kind of walk across the
parking lot sorta to your left it's
right next to Chile's you will receive
these wouldn't drink tokens have your ID
ready as you're leaving and you will get
two tokens you can head on over this is
important we were very very clear we
wanted people to have non-alcoholic
options we wanted to have energy drink
options there's gonna be some food over
there etc the one thing I want to say
and I want to be abundantly clear here
if for whatever reason you have a little
too much fun and you find yourself yeah
if you want to know it seriously yeah
don't know where this is going certainly
if you find yourself you have a little
too much fun um and you don't feel like
maybe you can get home find somebody in
a pink shirt have them find me have them
find a board member we will find a way
to make sure you get home I do not want
the end story of a great day having one
of you not with us next year okay deal
deal
alright and once again thank you to
stupid Shephard for our wonderful Gator
graphic we actually talked about putting
a Twitter poll up so y'all can name the
Gator bori McGary face Gator make Gator
face so coordinators there are a lot of
new coordinators up here on stage
incredible people who have put in a ton
of work there's there's too many up here
to even begin the name but I they're
they're incredible if you see people up
here doing this work it is so hard and
we do it all to make sure that you have
a great conference so but if you for
whatever reason have decided that you
just want to lose the rest of your
sanity and would like to join us email
us at info at besides Orlando dot org
subject I want to be a coordinator as we
start heading into the next season we
will go through and search our email and
say hey who wanted to be a coordinator
from last year and we've separated them
out under roles so there's things for
people who don't have a lot of time or
only have time at night there's things
for people who you know can do stuff on
the weekends we can find something for
you to do and it's worked out really
well this year to give people very
specific tasks and say you're in charge
of food you're like Steve Hardy you're
in charge of getting the badges set up
like John Magee you're in charge of like
julienne of making sure the rooms are
organized or speak organized are like
Bree and I like I said I could go on and
on and on so don't feel bad if I didn't
mention your name I apologize these
people are awesome so email us and say I
want to be a coordinator and I'm gonna
say something truly ridiculous because I
just remembered that the staff asked me
to say it and if anything I'm known for
my seriousness we hope you enjoyed our
Florida man hospitality and see you
later alligator
see you next year thank you
ah okay good got it stuck to my it
[Music]