welcome to b-sides Orlando at Full Sail
University come on
excellent we'll call for a second round
of Woo's in a moment our next speaker is
the founder and CEO of threat care he
describes himself as a hacker who helps
people not suck at cybersecurity
he started his technology voyage in the
u.s. Navy cryptology and later went on
to refine his knowledge while working at
the National Security Agency ladies and
gentlemen Marcus Carey
[Music]
Wow Thanks thanks for coming everybody
this is gonna be hopefully I'm gonna
have fun I'm gonna touch some buttons
there's gonna be awkward for all of us
but just bear with me and I think you're
gonna enjoy this presentation
all right so how many y'all know where
this quote comes from that my title I
cool a lot of people know that what the
deal is
so Co soon is album damn and so I bet
you a lot of people saw that tyranny
like damn I can't believe he's doing
this so I'm gonna tell you a little bit
about myself how I got to where I am I
always try to introduce myself so I'm
from a small town they call it a
warhorse town in Texas I live in Austin
currently but this is where I'm from I'm
from there was there was definitely not
it wasn't uncommon to see horses and
stuff in your yard chicken coops all
that stuff so I'm his country is I'll
get up I tell people usually when I come
to a room they play John Denver thank
God I'm a country boy so when I was
growing up my father wasn't there so I
never knew my dad growing up so I kind
of want to know who my dad was my dad he
lived in the Virgin Islands this is the
man my mom said was my dad and I really
didn't know so I grew up without him and
so for all I knew I didn't know any
siblings related to him or anything like
that so I wanted to the search and to
see who was my father so for a little
bit the US Navy was my father
the Navy kind of raised me kind of made
me a man taught me responsibility and
all kind of cool stuff I actually went
to boot camp here in Orlando back in the
day and they called it Disney they call
it Disney World
how many people we have any Navy people
in the house several but it wasn't
Disney what was more like this that
brings my so many memories not that
Disney World for sure but I love Orlando
I have a sister who lives here an area
hopefully I hopefully I will be seeing
her tonight
and hanging out with her family so once
I joined the military the whole time I
was in the military I did a pretty cool
stuff I worked for National Security
Agency central security service and a
Cyber Command it's something new but I
did Cyber Command stuff as well
even before there was a name I tell
everybody I was doing cyber before it
was cool I'm like a cyber I'm like a
cyber hipster first duty station was
Etzel scotland they say when you go to
edsel scotland this is what they told me
you to come back drunk or married or
both so I came back married definitely
got drunk a couple of times eighteen
year old being over there able to drink
so this is my family I'm in the middle
with a huge beard somewhere in the
middle and to the left of me if you can
find me like right in there the middle
that's me my daughter and my wife my
wife I met her in Scotland so I came
back married and on the the left on this
side of the picture yeah right in the
left in the corner is my sister who was
kind of funny because I really didn't
know she was my sister she's my she's my
father I'm using father in parenthesis
quotes he definitely related to him
because she looked just like it but I'd
look nothing like my father so I went to
do a lot of testing how many people were
ever doing 23andme can we gonna hand up
how many people have heard of
ancestry.com ends up Jed match who's her
dad one person I figured he's Noah
Jackie
Jackie's probably already done
everything I'm finna say in my heritage
is another one so what's cool so I
actually got 23andme
I'm gonna talk a little bit about these
things so 23andme I actually did my DNA
test - excuse me
23andme so on ancestry.com ancestry.com
is a really good place and I recommend
everybody check this up because it's
crazy what I love about ancestry.com you
can find out all kind
information about anybody a while ago
what I did is actually did research on
my whole family tree all the way back to
the 1800s and this is like like slavery
times right so some I traced I traced it
back all the way to like 1830 and it's
the forest back I could take it
personally
but some people know their DNA or know
their heritage is all the way back to
whatever land you went to so that's a
struggle like being black you don't know
because once it gets past 1800s slavery
happened and there was no not a lot of
good records keeping some people say
they have they can trace the boat that
their ancestor came on and then maybe
true in some cases but I really want to
know my family history so I went all-in
at ancestry.com but what's crazy about
ancestry.com is all the public records
that are available would be like a
social engineering dream for anybody in
here
you can find out everybody like I can
pick any random person in here and I can
know everything about you
like seriously on ancestry.com so
everybody you should go check that out
since I actually worked at NSA I don't
believe there's any secrets anyway but
but instructurecon would definitely make
you a believer I can find out anything
about anybody in this room right now see
that website 23andme is pretty dope it's
probably the most flashy flashy marketed
site and so I had a cell they had a sale
so I was like boom I want to find find
this stuff out and so what I was gonna
do is I was gonna secretly plot to take
my dad's DNA like I was gonna get his
hair or something of that nature or swab
him when you're sleeping and I was gonna
test him to see if he's really my father
because it's kind of an awkward
conversation hey I want to find out if
you're really my dad for anything about
23andme I heard I heard a statistic I
don't know if this is true or not but I
believe that 5% of the people that take
the test find out that that wasn't their
father 5% that's crazy that's a pretty
high number to me what do y'all think
in my heritage is a free as a
so these next two sites are pretty cool
because you can upload your data your
DNA data you can download it from
23andme and you can upload it see these
other sites
this Jade Mac site is pretty dope
because they have all kind of
researchers and scientists actually
putting in different algorithms and
things like that and you'll be able to
find relatives what's funny about this
is I noticed that everybody that uploads
their stuff to all these sites all the
people upload their stuff to all the
sites so I found relatives on 23andme I
found them on ancestry.com I found them
on jet match and I found them on Mount
my heritage so what's interesting about
this is since DNA your sequence is data
you can actually do some mining effort
to actually mine all these sites for all
kind of crazy people DNA and I'll show
you that later alright so let's get into
this
and I'm gonna get into some
controversial stuff and I hope y'all
y'all play along with me because it's
all love so here's Kendrick Lamar let's
talk about DNA a little bit more about
the DNA this is the DNA video that's
KDOT so when I did 23andme here's my
here's my relative matches I had 100
amino a something relatives on there
what's interesting about that is there's
not a lot of black people on these sites
so almost like almost all of those
people like like thousands probably a
thousand people or Caucasian and again I
don't know anybody white in my family
and so I did this DNA stuff and I'm like
everybody's popping up I'm like wow this
is crazy like I got all these you know
these you know my wife's white but
nobody in my my my lineage that I never
knew that was white so it's kind of
funny because me since I'm a hacker what
I what I did is I actually looked up
everybody and I'll tell you about that I
actually started friending people
telling them I was their cousin and
everything like this that's crazy
so this blew my mind right here so I
didn't know any like I said I don't know
any your
listen I mean forefathers in my family
everybody you know is black my funny
enough that I remember growing up people
told me that I was far Mexican and since
I'm from Texas I believed it I was like
yeah I believe that
I wasn't however here I was part Y I
kinda had no clue we were part Indian or
whatever I think everybody thinks
they're part Indian in America and I
mean you know Native American right so I
didn't know what the heck I was but the
DNA test says I was 60s it says 60 I
mean 76.5 African and mostly Nigerian
and a Sierra Leone really so that was
kind of interesting and I was like cool
all right so I can kind of like no words
Yarger you know from a geography
perspective I can have someplace pass
you know the cotton pickin feels funny
enough my grandmother picked cotton and
all my uncles picked cotton so cotton
picking is not some thing that just went
away by the way it's kind of that's that
blows my mind that my my mom didn't pick
cotton because she was the baby girl but
if she was a boy she would have picked
cotton growing up and this is my mother
she's one of the 50s and they were still
picking cotton in Texas so European
descent
I'm 22.5% Europe in that blew my mind
right and so what I had told my kids
because my kids oh we're talking about
they were by ratio they were half black
I said no your blackness has been
downgraded by at least 15% so they
didn't take that too nicely so it was it
was pretty interesting but what's dope
about that if you see the British and
Irish descent descent funny enough how
the universe of God or whatever y'all
believe in works is because the first
duty station I went to was Scotland that
blew my mind and I married a British
wife so I'm like wow that's crazy how
did all that stuff works huh and so
being in Scotland was it was dope
because I lived in Scotland and actually
I was having a conversation with
somebody that lived in Scotland as well
and I know Scotland up up up and down
my mother you know just like uh you know
a for father or somewhere to do it I've
been all over Scotland then all the cut
all the castles drunk all the whiskey
the hold on
so getting the JED match so so you get
your DNA you can download your DNA and
you can upload it to these sites this
what this is what blew my mind and what
I say this is a privacy nightmare and
what I did on here you see those KITT
numbers on the side you can actually
enumerate these KITT numbers on this
website this is dead match I haven't
done this because I'm a circle and I
would I would you would you should get
permission before you did anything too
crazy but I'm showing you here is a
screenshot of my results on the left is
a date as a kid and that kit number is
related to somebody's submission that
they submitted themselves you can
actually look at the kit by the way you
can look at all these people DNA is that
pretty cool is that craig grant what on
the right on the on this next column is
their full names you see me I'm MJ see
I'm being I'm doing legit research to
I'm not pretending I'm somebody else I'm
saying mark is that threat car.com I'm
like being real loud and proud of Who I
am all these people right here they have
their real names and so what I do the
hacker that I am I'm like looking up
everybody I can on social media and many
of those people like I said hey I'm I'm
I'm your cousin how you doing you know
have you heard of this family name
because I'm trying to really search and
I'm doing legit I'm gonna doing legit
research and at the same I'm doing legit
research on my family at the same time
since I found all this stuff is just
hanging out throw around and all their
email addresses so since you download
your DNA as a stack of data you can go
in and manipulate that DNA to match
anybody on this list so it's 100%
possible to go through her in mind this
whole website if you wanted to do
something crazy like
and here like I'm saying those are
thousands of overlaps so you see there
that red piece right there those are but
that's my DNA overlaps with what other
people so I think it's like really
really crazy that the DNA is out here
because what I believe is I believe DNA
is going to be what's what determines
somebody value in the future I believe
that everybody in here if you look at
like China China is kind of like showing
you a blueprint of what's gonna be
happen to next and I'm gonna give you a
couple examples of what we currently do
and what I believe DNA is probably gonna
be used for later and in the end the
whole point of this is like talking
about the privacy and how you can easily
harvest thousands of people's DNA right
now if you if you just wrote a simple
script so of course like I said I'm
hitting up people a couple of people
replies so I'm actually friends with
some of the people that I found on there
some people are doing crazy stuff like
somebody's a professor in Scotland and
all kind of crazy stuff and I'm like I'm
like really digging this so I got all
this new family all over the place and
it's funny because if I was a bad actor
people trust you because you share DNA
with them
it's the ultimate little card like we're
cousins man I wouldn't do anything to
you right we all know family is the
worst to do you over the worst right so
bringing me back to Vegas how many y'all
go to the Vegas conferences so when
y'all see when y'all see your brother
out in Vegas say hi
cuz I'm always there so say hi to me say
hi when I'm when I'm around I'm out here
I love meeting people I love seeing if
there's an opportunity for me to help
out if I can
so what's funny about Vegas every year
when I went to Vegas I would go and and
and visit my dad's aunt
which was kind of interesting so I you
know he was definitely my my dad looks
like my aunt
so it's the craziest thing so it's like
so they have strong so strong genetics
that they all look alike but I don't
look like them I look like my mom's side
so I still was unconvinced and so when I
did my DNA test I was telling my wife
man it is gonna be so awkward if these
people aren't related to me
can you imagine that so what I did my
when I got my DNA relatives they saw
23andme so the top one is because this
is my aunt
her name is Irma Johnson that's my dad's
the guy that I thought was my dad that's
his his aunt so that right there was
like oh snap he is my dad and it sucks
that I had to find out this way because
I was thinking of all these plots so I
can get his DNA if I can give my sister
tested like all kind of different I had
all these plots on how I was gonna solve
this problem but the problem solved
itself for me and when I noticed of with
with that is like you hear here
sometimes of things like this the crime
scene piece right so on the crime scene
you've heard about now people are
they're finding murderers and serial
killers through DNA right so sometimes I
have these thoughts in my head if I was
a cop how about I catch people I
actually took I think about if I was
still at the agency how would I be
catching some of these people - so I
kind of think of this and so I just
showed you real quick that a lot of
these DNA testing sites are under like
hard water because what they're doing is
a they're agreeing to cooperate with
crimes but I just showed you that the
people are just uploading in their DNA
to any website so if I was a cop or a
boss FBI or the CIA or NSA I would
create a fake DNA analysis site it let
everybody just let everybody upload
their DNA straight to me
and what's funny about this is because
the same technique has been used on like
pastebin sites so you know the
government makes all kind of crazy sites
for people that I've loved so I wouldn't
be surprised in the future there's a go
is gonna be maintaining this stuff
either sarin sarin what do you got Sara
tippling I'm from Texas so forgive my
you know you're not gonna know it so um
so what's happening here is that this
will definitely continue to work I know
in China they're actually doing all kind
of crazy facial recognition for
everybody I wouldn't be surprised if
China actually already hacked all these
websites that I'm talking about and got
out and got all the people that gave
their DNA anyway I would not be
surprised and then I'm gonna talk about
a little bit more technology and what
I'm gonna talk about here is what we
find value what did we see value in so
the reason why I'm bringing this book up
is that this book actually taught me a
lot of stuff about empathy and how big
people have been different so right now
I think a lot of stuff in America
definitely in a lot even like in Asia of
one of my one of my employees is Asian
and she told me that she is funny
because she's not dark-skinned Asian to
me but to her she was dark-skinned Asian
and to every other agent she was
dark-skinned that's like you look real
light-skinned she's like no I'm I'm
actually quite dark and and she told me
in China the lighter you are the better
I'm like what that blew my mind she told
me that that if you were light that
meant you were royalty and didn't have
to work in the fields the people had
darker pigmentation in China she said
that they were they were view as a lower
caste or a lower class even has anybody
heard that that blew my mind I did not
know that that blew my mind and I'm like
well this is crazy like all these people
from different places and there's always
something and I'll talk about this
another book in a second where there's
always something in society that makes
you treat people better or worse right
and I believe again DNA is the future of
this and that's why I think we have to
start thinking and more serious so when
I start doing to myself that book that I
just mentioned it talks about checking
your privilege one of the things it
talks about so my privilege
it's funny because I never always
thought you know I'm black and I've been
you know the story of the slave trade
and all that stuff I'm gonna touch on
that a little bit but the truth is if I
look at myself
what what's cool about my privilege is I
was born in America that's a leg up on
most people in the world when I was 18 I
took a ASVAB test more on that later
and that ass Baptist I got and I got the
highest clearance in the land at 18 I
worked at NSA as a Blue badger for eight
years when I was 18 year old I had this
was in the when the internet was just
coming up I had access to tons and tons
of computers the military and NSA spent
$200,000 on training me so I'm like I'm
like a nerd boys a nerd version of Jason
Bourne and the Bourne Identity so like
that is crazy privileged I got my
bachelor's degree for free I got my
master's degree for free like if you
just took Marcus being black that's the
equation I got a whole lot of privilege
and so that's like man we're all we all
have some kind of privilege and this is
where it's got to get funny because the
people with the privilege to do crazy
stuff like CRISPR technology and stuff
like that where they're going in and are
modifying DNA they're going to be those
people that have money and that
privilege that to spend that money on
their kids and stuff before they even
born that's that's the future we're
living in right now also this book
sapiens have anybody seen this book
before read it read it a couple people
everybody should read this book this
book blew my mind what this book talks
about it talks about the history of
sapiens like us we're sapiens right but
also like the Neanderthal and other
different other different sapiens that
existed all at the same time a lot of
people don't know this but even some
people they have some people in her in
this room probably have a little bit of
Neanderthal DNA
so we were all here at the same time but
Homo sapiens killed everybody else Homo
sapiens also killed all the animals
everywhere they lived - and it taught it
makes all these ridiculous tires on how
people are bad and it's usually for and
it's a follow-up book to this it's
usually based on scarcity we always
think there are scarcity but there's
actually abundance we have more food
than ever we have more anything that
ever but some people are scared that we
don't have enough of something we have
more money food whatever lights
electricity whatever you talk about we
have more of it right now anybody heard
this guy can somebody tell what it says
I'm gonna give you a present if you was
this Lupe Fiasco this guy Lupe Fiasco is
what they call a conscious rapper so I
guess
Kendrick Lamar the other guy he's a
conscious rapper but sometimes these
rappers spit so much knowledge it's
ridiculous this is the this is the cover
of his album his last album anybody know
that is just blew my mind it took me
forever to figure out what this was so I
found it in a forum somewhere and that
is that so what this is called is this
call this is called a manila this was
used at trade slaves so this thing right
here was worth one slave
it's a tiny piece of copper or bronze
like tiny like this big but that was
used to trade one human body that's
crazy to me like that day but it was it
was valuable so what happened is the
Europeans will make these in factories
in Europe they would come down and buy
slaves for this and then in and trade
for this they kept the Africans kabak
guns so Africans sold each other in
slavery - right so the Africans used to
trade one of these for a gun so they can
actually go conquer more land grab more
slaves get more Manila get more guns and
it was shipped to slaves
America mostly I think 85% of the slave
trade went to South America and a tiny
fraction that went to North America why
this is important is because what we
view as value is it blows my mind
because now we have stuff like Bitcoin
and people place value and that stuff
now Bitcoin to me it's a made-up thing
might affect all our money right now
it's not backed by anything it's all
fiat currency even an American dollar
but it's crazy how we we we associate
value with all these things the talk of
this is I got royalty royalty
I got royalty and loyalty I think humans
by nature is loyal until money comes in
the picture I just heard today another
Bitcoin some kind of Bitcoin company
just got you know messed over I was like
13 million dollars um and so I think
that humans are good as long as money
not involved I think that about anything
you could you could talk about you talk
about the intelligence community same
thing here's how that here's how that
slave trade worked and what's
interesting about this is during that
time what people the people that have
money and power sometimes it was the
royalty sometimes it was the people they
had the money they were in control but
they controlled they control the slave
trade and a couple other things that did
y'all know that the slave trading boats
were on stock markets globally so you
could buy stock in the slave trade and
the slave companies and this was a
human's mess everything that were
terrible so we built this amazing
country I'm proud to be an American
definitely proud to be a Texan it's a
whole nother country but what's crazy
though trafficking is still going on our
global scale and there's some tons and
tons billions of dollars being made I'm
still exploiting people it's just both
it blows my mind it's still happening
and if you could do anything to help
stop that there's plenty of organization
out there trying to help do this so this
is still happening today sometimes you
talk about slavery and all that stuff we
talked about oh yeah that must have
sucked like like it's way back in the
day
it's still happy to know also talking
about measuring let me let me go through
this
so the ASVAB test what it did for the
military is he said that Marcus it
identified Marcus Carey that's me I was
gonna be good at cryptography and stuff
like that
so they put me in that position to do
cryptography and that was my privilege
my privileges was I could I could take
test real good I'm a great test taker
right and so anybody heard of CLEP test
or whatever yeah so CLEP test is of
tested you can take for college credit I
did a hundred and fifteen credits like
college credits on CLEP tests I can take
tests better anybody in the world so if
there's a DNA segment that says this guy
is good at taking tests that's me
they need to clone that little that
little segment but but what I'm saying
is that was like I said that was one of
the privileges that I had and that's a
DNA thing that's in my DNA that's in
everybody's DNA that's posted it online
let's say SAT test sometimes the SAT
test is the SAT test to me is more of a
privileged thing because you can do
these preparatory classes and all that
stuff but it could be you just a good
test taker stuff like the AC T same
thing right but what these tests all
have in common is the all these tests or
to measure your ability to do something
and so globally you know what we've done
is globally the people that are the most
successful we've been we've been
bringing them to the States
even at h-1b visa is bringing just the
best people from all around around the
world I mean well I guess what I've said
the smartest according to some kind of
some kind of need or whatever so now
it's a global game and we're taking and
we're not taking on slaves anymore but
we're taking on people and to be honest
with you a lot of these people on these
these visas are treated really bad too
they're underpaid and all that stuff too
and so they can get their citizenship
and nowadays what the immigration piece
there's that that's all that's all a
mess to now so that people wait for the
citizenship forever
so this is another selection criteria
that we use to select people what I'm
what I'm big things I'm saying now is
that y'all know who this guy is this is
the CRISPR doctor this is the one who
supposedly genetically modified twins
and the story the story kind of gets all
kind of interpreted but the story is he
made one of his daughters it was two
twin girls one of them was genetically
modified to not to be resistant to HIV
so his daughter can't catch HIV the same
gene that they flipped or whatever did
they change that also makes them smarter
that one's so this person is gonna be
more likely to pick up stuff and they're
gonna be resistant to HIV like there's a
lot of people with a lot of money that
would pay for that right yeah I believe
that I kind of compare it to this where
far as DNA goes there's an opportunity
for somebody to submit you know
manufacture some kind of could could be
some people say HIV was manufactured
that could be a conspiracy theory or not
but we can definitely we definitely know
biological warfare is a real deal right
so you could certainly go in and you can
see who be resistive or resistant to
certain things can't believe that that's
happening all the time
it happens like what companies like this
they're doing this in the in agriculture
fill and seeds and they're suing people
and all this stuff so what's gonna be
crazy if you can start modifying DNA
which is CRISPR technology you can
immune certain people to certain things
and then you end up and then you can end
up making a lot of money off selling and
selling that cure as well there's a lot
of conspiracy people out there I'm not
really a conspiracy theory person but
it's kind of hard to ignore what's kind
of right in front of your face also like
I said the CRISPR doctor may
has made his kid more more resistant to
certain things there's already what they
call AI or machine learning that's
actually boxing out a lot of people for
instance if you have a certain criteria
this is this is funny as all outdoors to
me so I'm a hacker right so what I do is
I have everybody has a sock puppet
account so I have some Latino accounts
like Marco Marcos
Caruso or something like I have but
there's they're Hispanic names
so what's funny is when I'm when I'm
myself Marcos all my ads I see online
are black ads it's a black marine
national black Marines I'm just playing
our black Marines it's they're the few
the proud but but I get black ads every
ad I see on the Internet is black
because somebody knows I'm black for it
for all do y'all see the same thing like
yo yo yo no sir you don't notice it yeah
so when I switch because they're just
like you so also we know that banks in
and people that pick banks and all that
stuff or actually doing different credit
for zip codes you live in and all kind
of stuff like that insurance rates are
different all these things are different
so I believe that all your tendencies
are in your DNA
everything that's in do you have whether
you procrastinate what do you don't
because I have I have four different
kids and and all of them are different
for different kids that's under where
they are they're all different they're
different different like all on board
so but I believe that all the that in
the future and in China already what
they're doing is you can't leave the
country if you have bad credit that's
crazy
what if they what if they said okay we
know your DNA you have a tendency like
all these people have left the country
and didn't go back you have a tendency
to do that
or
have a tendency not to pay your bills
based on your DNA I that stuff could
happen in the future and it sound crazy
so you ever heard of the Golden Rule you
know what the golden rule is oh that's
it that's the route so there's two
golden rules
this guy's on it you know to go to the
rule don't trust this guy right here
three dollars the way you're gonna be
treated is the one that most people
that's the happy one but the real golden
rule is the one with the gold makes the
rules and I have 100% believe that
because ultimately but what we have to
do
I think the good people the good people
I think I'm a good person if we do if
the good people can be can make the
money and control the goal then we can
actually kind of rewrite the rules now
what's going on now like I'm a crazy
person I'm posting my DNA all over the
place and all that stuff you might want
to tell people not to if they believe in
privacy because what I just showed you
is that that uh you have other people
posting other people's DNA online
sometimes it's legit because sometimes I
mean I'm actually in these forums this
ain't like in ancestry
and I have people posting stuff on my
family and so I had two different people
one of them was was working on my uncle
to get his DNA I mean get his ancestry
done but a lot of this stuff was wrong
so this guy that was doing my family
tree he he he thought my aunt my aunt
through her marriage was my mom I'm like
nah that's not that's not right but
there's people out there fiddling around
with your family your DNA and all that
stuff and you don't even know him I also
bumped into another guy that uploaded
DNA of a deceased person and they were
managing the account for that for that
family as well
right I have I seen people upload their
DNA twice because they forgot their D
they forgot their passwords that are
23andme account and they they what they
did they wouldn't go and bought another
day it wouldn't go the wind go bought
another swab I mean another another spit
thing and they paid for another account
like that and I'm like golly lord help
us humanity I mean you know that's a
dank password reset from hell hey you
got a submit your DNA to get faster but
yeah so big picture is like like no
motor concerns I wanted this to be more
of a high level talk but the facts are
you saw easily all those numbers those
numbers are easily you can easily
iterate those numbers you can grab you
can you can grab all the DNA kids off
these sites and I like that blew my mind
but I'm crazy because I don't care so
hopefully if I do have some good DNA
somebody put that in the crisper and
pass it along to civilization and that's
the end of my presentation thank you
very much for listening or do any
questions that means I did an amazing
job
so one more thing
I didn't plug the book but thanks a lot
for everybody about the tribe of hackers
book and thanks everybody got it son I
really appreciate y'all that that's
that's amazing
that that's all which I'll show love
like that and that's the end of my we
got a question right here yeah so my dad
is actually the guy I thought was my dad
so his name is Joseph Bradford and I
can't believe that he's really my dad
what's crazy about it my dad doesn't
have relationships with none of his kids
and so that's luckily that's something I
personally and that's what I say like
you know the whole nurture and nature
stuff I had such a crappy childhood
growing up didn't make me want to be a
good father and so luckily I don't
believe being a being a terrible
father's in a DNA
but you know maybe we have other things
that we pick up from our family but
thank goodness but yeah my father nobody
likes him my family my sister as my
sister that I'm gonna have dinner with
tonight hates his guts so it's actually
kind of sad but he is really my
biological father and she's my sister
yes so the question the question he has
is is there a greater risk by posting it
on the commercial side versus the
smaller sites and so I believe that just
because you're a big brand and big
company and have a lot of money that
doesn't make you more secure on the
front end though I think that they they
have better controls on the front end
but like that whole jet match thing
where it's showing me thousands and
thousands of people matching all kind of
crazy sequences that's a that's a
problem waiting to happen
so uh yeah so I don't I don't equate how
big company is to how secure it is but
me I don't have I don't believe in
privacy I'm a weirdo so I don't care so
did I report the problems to jet match
is the quote is a question no I did no I
think it's I think it's working like it
says on I don't think the security flaw
so I think that's just the way they
meant it to be so I didn't I don't
report it and also reporting stuff is
kind of a pain in the butt if you like
even if somebody is doing something
blatantly wrong I've seen people in this
room here they reported stuff the
blockchain people and the blockchain
people don't face it but in the Bitcoin
and other cryptocurrencies I've seen
people's you know I've seen the Bitcoin
people try to sue people and all that
stuff so I you know I I just assume they
know what they're doing so there's a
there's an old school thing and I think
it comes from Oakland the game is to be
sold not so I don't really believe that
but anybody oh one more question over
here
so so they caught a serial killer
based on she saying that they but they
call a circular based on DNA what what
he catch other people other criminals
I believe they they will catch they will
catch them and if I'm related to them I
think they should do the crime they
should they should do whatever time they
have I don't I don't really I mean it's
definitely if I have somebody's done
some crazy heinous like that but I
wonder if that's gonna change the
statute of limitations I don't know I
think this is definitely gonna be a big
legal situation I've also thought about
like some experimentation on on
capturing people DNA without them
knowing it like if I if somebody drinks
something like try to swab it and throw
it into container and send it off real
quick let me bb-dub
yeah
yes so basically some of us are genetic
mutants and sometimes yeah windows yeah
how do you keep your stuff from people
that are gonna be the first so the first
part of it was 23andme recently said
they're working with medical companies
or the related medical companies and
they're doing medical research based on
it I think that that's definitely I
think most things that we talk about in
security aren't technical things I think
that's something we should talk to your
congressperson about your you know those
are political things and try to get in
contact with people that are in politics
they regulate the healthcare stuff
starting with like probably the state
level may be your local local
congressperson at a state level and
enter congressperson from a state level
that and the people that are on those
medical and FDA approval panels and all
that stuff but I think that Jeanne may
be out of the bottle for anybody to
already upload their data because if I'm
who reads any kind of you know EULA's or
anything like that you know that Jed max
could have just shipped my stuff
straight to CI or some and you know the
CIA CIA hates X NSA people so I don't
trust them if anybody any CI in her
entourage yeah all right I'm done I
appreciate y'all for listening thank you
very much
[Applause]
[Music]