well we made it did everyone have a good
time is everyone exhausted no okay who
has been to more than one writes con
awesome who has been to three right guns
I'm so hoping we get to somebody who's
been here five times who has been 24
right guns and if you've been at five
rad-con stand up yuck I've every three
times in San Francisco once in vanilla
and went in Rio okay so I mean it's been
an absolutely incredible experience for
me one of the things that I wanted to do
first is to thank the sponsors who have
enabled this conference to happen and so
thank you very much the sponsors many of
whom in the room I've been thinking a
lot about why I think this conference is
a little bit special and obviously
there's a lot of work and a lot of heart
and head that goes into this event and
you know there's sort of moments at the
conference for me anyway which sort of
have a shift in the way that I have
thought about something and I think
about something in a new way or I have a
jolt which influences how I'm going to
approach a new tactic and new a new
strategy or a new practice and then
sometimes it's just a conversation that
actually I found turns it into a
partnership and for me that happened
actually yesterday I went to the digital
disabilities panel and we spent a lot of
time like obviously over the last couple
of months bringing people from all
around the world I mentioned can we put
that slide back for a sec before we go
back thank you uh-huh and so so I went
to the digital digital disability
session and there was a people they
that who we had brought from Indonesia
and there are many people who apply to
attend and people who we funded to
attend which was absolutely fantastic
and i sat in the panel and Valentina was
there from Indonesia who was just an
email address and suddenly she was a
person and she was next to HUD then Emma
who is blind and deaf and I we went
around the room and when I spoke her
assistant Alex were sitting next to her
he typed in what I said and then via
bluetooth it went to the laptop on her
the Braille laptop on her computer and
she spoke back to me in pitch perfect
English and I said to her what how's the
technology platforms that you operate on
and through the process through
bluetooth she came back and she said
like we use Facebook all the time we
update our status we actually
communicate and coordinate on facebook
and on twitter and i said are they doing
a good job she said yeah it's kind of ok
and I said do you know anyone at
Facebook or Twitter and she's like no so
I emailed the guys from Facebook and
Twitter and said hey would you like to
meet this amazing woman working on
disabilities and within 15 minutes
Facebook and Facebook was at the outside
the session and even mad and and the
guys at Twitter said they would come as
well and that conversation happened and
I was a little disappointed that Twitter
wasn't there and then when I was reading
Twitter that smoke looking at Twitter
this morning I saw this and at policy is
actually at Twitter policy and there's
valentina and HUD then on the right and
the guys from Twitter on the left and
then Alex the her system over there so
that was my moment where I was just like
hey this is like these conversations
these communications these connections
that would never ever happen I'm hoping
that all of you have had that some form
of that experience and who knows it as
it will roll out
normally in the closing ceremony of
Rights con we kind of try to look at
some of the outcomes and at this point I
wanted to actually introduce to you the
awesome access now team who are going to
run through a couple of things that
happen throughout the last couple of
days so if I could bring you guys on it
would be awesome if we could have a
rousing round of applause for this
amazing feeling
hang on for this amazing access now team
the reason why there's delay
last of which is Nick D'Agostino who is
the coordinator of rats con
so you guys what have you seen in terms
of the outcomes at the conference or
your personal things you just got us a
minute H yeah so hi guys i'm xavier work
policy for access now in latin america
and i want to focus on latin america of
course it's like my region and well this
i know one outcome is really hard there
are so many right but just for the sake
of an example i will just say that for
instance several brazilian activists
here heard about a dangerous package of
8 bills that have been going to be
pushed into the house of representatives
in brazil and we held an emergency
session different groups and their got
together and that practically in the
same session that you wanted to see it
recorded in youtube channel they came up
with a with a strategy and a declaration
and now that's being insured so so
that's probably one of the things that
shows us the power of convening get
together and and strategizing so you can
find that in the web page of X now in
the web page of internet lab article
1980s real interval says and all the
groups were and CTS on the world to
worry mode so yeah that's my favorite
outcome for today
I'm Amie Stepanovich I'm the US policy
manager at access now one of the things
that I kept hearing a lot about was
encryption and that might be because we
spent a lot of us the first day in here
really delving deep into that issue we
had some of the best participants then
we really worked them hard we had great
session leaders um I see Rihanna I see
Kevin I see Christian really wonderful
people leading these conversations and
we came up with four different documents
for different outcome documents from
that on the cost of encryption mandates
the benefits of encryption ways to
encourage other companies to adopt in to
promote encryption and those are all
going to go up on the crypto summit
website and we're going to keep moving
forward to push against bad government
laws and for good policies oh and who's
that and this is my pet his name is bb-8
hi so I'm Danielle you maybe saw me at
the digital security clinic with the
rest of the healthline team so we
managed to get over 50 consultations
during the three days of the conference
we had everything coming on so people
asking for assistance come in saying hey
I know I need help I don't know what I
need can you help me the awesome
connections it's finally the time for us
to put a face in many people we have
been working many awesome people that we
have been connecting with so it's really
an opportunity to interact with this
community we have for example people
coming out of a session in the demo room
saying hey I've just heard about this
cool tool can you help me it's that
connection is that interactions that
between this community that is going to
make us great and it's going to make us
grow even more so thank you everyone for
being here
hi I'm Estelle EU policy analyst working
out of our Brussels office from a
European perspective I'm really happy to
report that during the conference save
the internet EU was relaunched and I
invite all of you to join the movement
and join the coalition and enter the
online questionnaire in order to ensure
that Europe protect and have strong net
neutrality rules hi I'm ranjit singh
cheema I'm accesses director of local
public policy and the thing I'd like to
share with you is that move through most
of today 32 litigators and digital
rights activists and policy people from
across the world have been sharing
information have been trying to create a
digital rights litigation network hosted
by you know in association with a
fantastic media Legal Defense Initiative
arpita norlander who is somewhere here
we've had people and writer and even to
sharing the challenges that litigators
not just in the US or in a in in
Northern Europe but litigators in South
America in Central America in southern
Africa send South Asia and East Asia
they're all fighting incredible battles
they all trying to share information the
next rounds of fights you're going to
see judgments in the next few months on
things from data retention to
surveillance law from Mexico to cases in
Hong Kong to elsewhere we're trying to
see how we can empower and support the
next range or these challenges but also
make sure that we work together with you
the community technologies activists and
people who are directly lobbying
government and policy makers to make
sure that the courts can be the last
bastion and sometimes the first passion
for digital rights and we hope to be
able to do more than next few months
hi everyone my name is Ephraim Pasadena
neato I'm the sub-saharan African policy
analyst that axis are based in Nairobi
so I'd like this to highlight two things
which I take away from this conference
although this so much take away from
this conference about obsession about
enough talk about the problem let's find
a solution to connectivity in Africa
which was hosted by he bows and such icg
Africa and from that discussion I were
able to see that there is no silver
bullets solving some of these challenges
we need to look at solving these
challenges from a multidisciplinary and
in a multi-stakeholder mana another
discussion that I would like to take
into consideration is de about this data
mining that was hosted by up in Nigeria
this is in the wake of various biometric
initiatives across Africa very as a and
that very few dissipation laws and
looking at dealing with these in a way
that respects human rights and from that
discussion were able to try and
brainstorm ways to support each other to
ensure that our governments our
companies and we ourselves as you handle
data for the population for the local
internet user that it is held in a way
that it respects the human rights so
that is a very start of a conversation
and I'm excited on the next phase on how
we can take this going forward thank you
very much
hi I'm hasn't sent me from Tunis I'm
part of the helpline team I was
participating in this summit with people
from Tunisia and as Tunisian were like
we were telling other people about our
newborn mercury see in Tunis and we were
telling them how much it's important to
like not support only support us but
support our model to be translated to
our neighbors to transit democracy to
our area and technology as a way thank
hi I'm Nina from the Brussels office I'm
from the operations team unfortunately I
noticed that I'm the only one with my
trusty notes in hand but I just wanted
to make sure that I said everything I
wanted to say so this is the fifth
rights Colin and this year we have gone
even bigger this year we have had over
250 sessions we had 10 parallel sessions
going on two at the same time at any
given time and we have had over 1,000
participants from over 70 countries we
have gone we have come a long way
however there are still lessons for us
to learn and to develop some of them are
we are still learning about issues of
diversity and making sure that all
communities are represented and their
voices are heard at reitz con also
learning about how to effectively
convene multiple stakeholders together
so that we can all engage in an open and
participatory dialogue together we would
really appreciate your feedback on your
experience I retcon 2016 and we really
love to learn how we can make this a
more impactful and useful experience for
you and for your important work thank
you
i'm kim i'm part of the helpline based
in New York the demo room was primarily
about stories we had technologists
journalists activists users and trainers
all in the same room so it's that
connection that really made the Dumber
room what it is it's also my really
great team I would like to have special
thanks out to nat uh where is nat stand
up is here yep mm-hmm Eisenberg and from
oti we also have josh king I think you
might stepped out oti as well Colin
Sullivan from Benetech and of course my
colleague and co-chair julio lopez one
final no trainer fest was an amazing
success and that is partly due to
Nicholas Sayre Oliva here from intra
news thank you so much drew Mitnick I'm
on the policy team based in DC so it
wasn't that long ago that we would have
conferences that would focus on
cybersecurity and you talk about
military approaches and you would talk
about critical infrastructure and you
would have human rights conferences
which would be totally separate but I
think we saw entire conference full of
people who could have sophisticated
conversations about cybersecurity and do
it in a way that they were considering
the human rights impact and thinking
about it for me Human Rights framework
and I think that's really an amazing
achievement that we've gotten this far
so I'll just say go on in cyber
and.and I'm Nick D'Agostino I'm based in
New York and the resident Canadian on
staff had access now and I would like to
i mean as much as the the outcomes of
2016 are still going to be i think some
kind of the submerged outcomes will
still be you know coming about i think
it's it's really good look forward and
so i'm actually have the the pleasure of
announcing where Bryce God 2017 will be
and so the host city of Rights Klein
2017 will be Brussels
which is excellent i mean and so there's
many really good reasons why you know
we're bringing you to brussels and i
think the first reason is you know
Europe and in Brussels is is a
international hub for so many you know
global policies and really they're
really the decision makers for a lot of
global policies everything from net
neutrality to data retention data
protection and trade laws and so I think
that we want to really Bing bring the
global civil society you know back and
make sure that they have in and and yeah
make sure that they have a saying these
decisions another reason is because the
global tech companies from around the
world have such it has such an influence
and such a presence in Brussels and we
want to make sure that these decisions
and these discussions have the the tech
community present and lastly you know
you're we want to be you know we want
everyone to be able to bring support to
European civil society and bring support
to to Europe and I think that writes
gone as a community can bring a lot of
this support and so we're very excited
for that and I'd like to it now like
pass off the the ceremonial baton to the
Brussels office and so we'd only have a
time but
thank you we look forward to welcome you
in Brussels and we look forward to
bringing this energy and this group of
people and more diversity event into the
Brussels discussion to the next year be
ready and don't have Excel ok so i think
that's basically it then you're going to
go homes the access now team which there
are other members here as well in the
audience and we're all actually getting
on a bus and we're driving three hours
into the countryside and we're going on
retreat for a couple of days to both
chill out and also to talk about what
we're going to do with all of this
information that is for our coming year
but we're going to love chilling out
first and a couple of housekeeping
things one is that if you see a
succulent on the table you can take it
with you whoever grabs it first and over
once them there is one that boy which is
the bean bags there and am I allowed to
know yes I am whoever is sitting on it
can take it home oh it's my last she has
to take it back to Tunisia in hand
luggage maybe we can give you a little
one so any hash any outcomes hashtag and
rights concert we can put them in
outcomes report yeah that's exactly and
i think that's it so random applause to
you guys for coming attention