slide Oh com tag rights con and this is
the cottage so any questions you may
have during the panel go there and
so hi everybody thank you so much for
being here with us anywhere welcome to
come closer so you were we are cozy and
connected and that's the idea here it's
really connected the next billion and a
half people global connect initiatives
initiative that started with some heroes
inside the US government and has spread
so far all over the world and is also
has become an interagency effort civil
society from around the world has been
supporting this since sep tember last
year when it was lounged and i think
that even with all a lot of our
differences in other subject areas we do
have in common that we want to connect
people and we want to connect that
people well and we want to ensure that
when countries invest in other type of
research infrastructure it actually
invest in I efficient way and bring
connectivity so if you are digging a
hole to install electricity cables why
not put the cables for internet and
fiber optics etc so I think one of the
core ideas here with the global connects
really to change the narrative not be
focused on this and then also particular
companies and individuals within
companies like Mac Zuckerberg and on
internet.org and free basics and I think
there is a common ultimate agenda which
i think is absolutely a development
imperative but at the same time there
are different strategies in place and
the key kind of message that I wanted to
convey in this panel and I'm sorry I'm
not going to be able to stay for the
whole time is that connectivity is not
enough the connectivity must be must
happen and must take place within a
rights framework because what you
ultimately can end up with is people
getting access to part of internet or
people getting connected to an internet
that is censored monitored surveilled
throttled and even militarized and that
is the last thing that we want or need
so that would be my just opening salvo
I don't know if I mentioned the
organization that I'm from access nada
org which is the convener of this
conference and our mission is to defend
and extend the digital rights of users
risk so we particularly look at
connectivity from the perspective of the
user and the human rights that they can
exercise and enjoy within that
connectivity Thank You Brad so much and
thank you very presence i know you are
extremely busy with all the parallel
sessions going on but i think first to
set the ground i would like to hear from
a new to actually explain a little bit
what is the initiative where it is and
how far it has gone and what are its
cargos an objective thank you thanks a
Carolina and thanks to Brett and access
now for inviting us all here today the
global connect initiative is looking to
help bring in additional 1.5 billion
people online by 2020 this is actually
an internationally agreed-upon goal it
was agreed upon at the ITU
plenipotentiary meeting in Korea their
connect 2020 resolution and as part of
this initiative we're actually trying to
give effect to this aspiration we also
we're also trying to really look to see
how the internet and showcase how the
Internet is a way of achieving all the
sustainable development goals that were
recently adopted and I think what I
wanted to do in the very beginning is
just to set the stage the challenge that
we have before us the majority of
internet usage is still in developed
countries something that we all know and
this is a stark kind of representation
of the world today and internet
connectivity and you can see that Africa
is lagging far behind it this is no
surprise to anybody in this room and
then you go to the the next slide you
can see the graph over time in terms of
despite growth how the digital divide is
persisting and so the top graphic there
is of developing countries and you can
see and imagine that
this adoption rate would probably
plateau around 80 85 the developing
countries are still lagging far behind
but again as you look over time the
digital divide is not closing that is to
say that this gap is persisting and this
is all based on I to data and then just
think about the least developed
countries the Afghanistan's the other
countries are in a lot of pain where
they are even below this adoption rate
and then if you go to the next slide you
can see as part of the global connect
initiative we're really trying to also
explain why we think some countries are
lagging like what is the reason that
they're falling behind one of course a
lot of countries would flag is lack of
funds for infrastructure the second one
is we would say minimal technical
expertise corruption political
instability we're also saying restraints
on free speech we're so we're trying to
identify these problem areas as ways
that you know countries when they think
about creating an enabling environment
for growth they should really focus on
these specific buckets the other thing
that we're trying to show is you know
where are some where we seeing progress
where's what are really kind of the
countries that I've kind of showcased a
lot of growth in a fairly short amount
of time and of course these are not any
surprise to people in this audience it's
like Colombia Costa Rica Malaysia turkey
Peru and then even in the least
developed countries you're seeing quite
a lot of progress and they're eating
there are a lot of themes that emerged
here in terms of their investment
policies or competition policies there
are a lot of reasons and things that can
be learned from other countries that are
also trying to kind of adopt the right
approaches in the right policies on the
key objectives so one of the things that
we're about to do is we're having in
just a few weeks time a major gathering
with finance ministers and the World
Bank on the sides of the spring IMF bank
fund meeting and our goal there is to
really get the multilateral Development
Bank's the finance ministers to realize
that the Internet is just as important
for connectivity and should be part of
their development strategies and as part
of the global connect agenda we have
specific objectives that we've
identified from financial institutions
where we're telling the world bank then
American Development Bank all the banks
that they should be prioritizing
Internet connectivity across their
regional and functional practices that
they should be right now for
the world bank's transport ICT unit only
does one percent of lending in ICT one
percent in today's you know whatever
year it is 2016 we think that that is
lagging far behind the demand from what
countries that they should see in it
neglects the fact that icts are such a
cross-cutting enabler for growth across
all sectors of our economy we're also
trying to you know tell both the
multilateral Development Bank's and also
development organizations that they
should be thinking about dig once
policies policies that are kind of
integrating connectivity into hard
infrastructure projects so when you're
kind of playing a road you can also kind
of also lay out a fiber and really kind
of think about ways to expand
connectivity in traditional
infrastructure projects the timeline for
this initiative is it was announced by
secretary Kerry and his speech in Korea
in the spring we launched the initiative
formely when the sustainable development
goals were adopted in September partly
to again highlight how the Internet is a
key driver of the SDGs and reflecting
upon the fact that the SDG specifically
identified connectivity as such an
important enabler for progress and then
we have had a number of high-level
events and our next one is going to be
on April 13th and April 14th with
secretary Kerry finance ministers from
all continents technology leaders to
kind of drive home the point that you
know we need a call to action and that
finance ministers and the investment
community need to be taking more
seriously how the Internet is a key
driver for growth and identify some best
practices for both the multilateral
Development Bank's and also for other
countries we are at the State Department
working to secure the support of other
g7 countries around connectivity
principles that we've kind of drafted
that talk about digital literacy a talk
about cross-cutting impacts that talk
about big ones policies and so we're
trying to use all the different veggies
with the g7 the g20 x GF oecd to really
kind of build support for this
international initiative and then you
know us and then you know we'll continue
implementation and the idea is will have
this event in the spring bank fund and
then working with I Triple E the
old bank will continue to have these
types of discussions and all the bank
fund meetings up until 2020 to continue
driving support toward this connectivity
agenda and the next slide kind of gives
you a sense of April 14th high level
event at the World Bank executive
boardroom with president Jim Kim you
know co-hosted by the World Bank and the
State Department inviting finance
ministers from all contents were getting
a very strong international reaction to
this which is really positive one of the
things that finance ministers are saying
is I think you sent us this invitation
by mistake I think you meant it to sent
it's my communications colleague or my
ICT colleague or my regulator colleague
but no the point is that we're trying to
disrupt the thinking that they don't
need to worry about that they need to be
thinking about this right as a key
priority for their key priority for our
country and so the notional schedule is
to our meeting is you know of course
we're gonna be time and why does this
matter why the internet should matter to
them we're gonna be asking people to
kind of come with commitments whether
it's a country or stakeholder and so one
of the commitments that were exploring
with one organization is to actually
help us track progress towards how many
people are coming online on a monthly
basis and we're talking to kind of
organizations like the international
telecom Union which I could get the data
from governments but there's really no
our active monitoring of progress here
so it's hard to even know you know are
you actually making progress or what is
actually being done for 1.5 billion by
2020 and then where are we going for
here again we'll set out some best
practices for EM DBS for governments and
do a call to action road map from now
until the October bank fund the fall
bang fun meeting and identify all of the
events from civil society the technical
community and elsewhere where we can
kind of really accelerate progress
towards our goals the next slide just
shows you since our launch in September
how many governments have now come on
board to support the global connect
initiative over 37 countries a number of
industry partners really excited about
the civil society global NGOs that are
coming on board 26 again this is a very
new initiative of both sooo awesome
myself have only been working on it for
us in September and in that short amount
of time it's
really built a lot of support from other
sovereign countries industry members and
NGOs because I think it's really
resonating this that there's a need to
now really redouble efforts on
international connectivity and that the
u.s. can play a role an important role
US companies and of the u.s. civil
society community you know what we were
telling folks in the short term
diplomatically is that we want as many
finance ministers as we can from invited
countries to attend April 14th
high-level event many of those finance
ministers are either the countries that
have already expressed support or other
democratic countries that we really want
to try to encourage to attend we want
them to endorse the initiative the
connectivity principles we're seeking
country commitments that we can
highlight in our outcome documents
whether its development assistance
pledges innovative kind of approaches to
tracking and monitoring progress or data
or commitment to like doing studies
about the connection between
connectivity and GDP growth or just
helping us with some data research and
then you know for us we really want to
get a clear emphasis that connectivity
is cross-cutting development priority
and for all of the government's that are
attending that they should also kind of
champion our cause and encourage other
governments to also prioritize a digital
connectivity and their development plans
one of the things that I'll just note is
so I've just done the high level event
on the 14th is to our thing we're also
doing a very innovative thing with on
April 13th is we'll have a full day
global connect stakeholder session that
everybody would be invited to if they're
interested in attending and we're
basically trying to bring together the
technical community ICT ministers
regulators at an all-day session to kind
of really explore technical solutions
for regulators and kind of discuss their
local challenges and how we can help
them by listening right to what are some
of the problems that they're facing in
some of the hurdles and kind of then
bringing to bear the technical
communities expertise and willingness to
help solve those challenges so with that
all kind of i hope that provided a good
overview and we can always take much
structures you know you're talking about
water energy and things of that nature
and what we're looking to do is sort of
bring in if you will the expertise of
professionals technical people
we're working in those spaces you know I
sit in the I Triple E primarily in their
standards division so very familiar with
consensus building and working on
technical procedures if you will and
it's interesting even in that spear if
you will you see the differences between
people who are working in technical
aspects in developing technologies in
the power and energy sector versus the
ITC sector and sometimes it's almost
like they speak a different language
they think differently there's different
processes they have different knowledge
sets so it's in a way what we're trying
to also accomplish you know to manas
point about trying to raise awareness
not only among the finance ministers you
know as you mentioned you know they're
getting this invitation they're saying
wait a minute this must be an error it's
really the kind of change a little bit
of a mindset around that and to try to
connect people that traditionally aren't
you know this sort of maybe thinking of
this as top priority or sort of on top
of their their work agenda better way of
saying it but also to you know sort of
bring down those barriers and start
having more open conversations I think
over the last 10 years in particular you
know with the Internet Governance space
in general and the connectivity
challenges that we have at our outer
feet right now you know a tremendous
amount of work has been done over the
years and you know various communities
of practice and communities coming
together we have civil society technical
government NGO but sometimes I think
what happen is they went through deep
into their into their sector if you will
and I think we're at this really
critical turning point and a juncture
that it's time to kind of come back up
with all that expertise and that
knowledge that has been built over the
years of trying to address these
challenges and sort of bring it back up
to the surface and have a different type
of exchange of information so with that
you know the actively as many are you
may or may not know is a pretty large
technical organization we have about
four hundred and sixty thousand members
and 160 countries around the world and
what's interesting about it and makes it
a little bit unique is that we have the
foundation of the organization is this
sort of its 40-plus technical societies
so we're in power and energy computer
communications
aerospace vehicular and all have pretty
deep verticals if you will into that but
when you look at the connectivity
challenges and where how we're trying to
use different types of infrastructure
and innovative solutions and how we need
to bring that expertise that deep
expertise that sits in those different
industry domains or sectors to connect
that type of knowledge and to cross
pollinate that so maybe different
sectors can learn from each other and
then we can bring that information into
the the nations that are having
challenges and that we can sort helping
educate and bring that building that
capacity for that second point well it's
a very different thing how people define
things and how people approach
challenges and problems you know some I
don't think it's meant intentionally but
for their ways of doing things and I
think it's critical that we sort of sort
of having a different dialogue and yes
getting on the same page about you know
the real challenge is here and how we
can bring that technical different type
of Tenel expertise into it so we can
look at the infrastructure we can look
at some innovative I mean there's
amazing things going on with satellites
and balloons and you know even you know
what we're looking at mesh thank you for
the word I should know that very well
later too um but you know it's how we
can sort of sort again the theme for us
at i triple e saw how we cross pollinate
and how we can beam that type of
expertise and looking at it just on the
bestest the technical side of it but you
know as man who in Carolina so how's
we've been working on this you know you
look at it also from the different
there's a policy aspect there's finance
and investment aspects of this so it's a
really complicated matrix in a way and
it's not going to be easy but I think
that's where we have the roll up our
sleeves and and I Triple E we'd like to
take on a challenge so we were very
supportive of the global connect
initiative and looking to bring our
technical expertise into it thank you so
much carrion and that's extremely
necessary right on and this translation
is extremely necessary but an even
legacy and of technical community that
in many countries were where was the
community bringing the internet right
was they the fathers of Internet in many
countries were
folks from the Technical Community that
part now are part of the wii but talking
about legacy I think our panel was the
first panel try to come with a
representative from the White House so
thank you so much for come down to San
Francisco for this panel is a good thing
so if you can if you can so if you are
special assistant at the White House for
the obvious science and technology
policy which actually has been blowing a
lot of innovative people that are really
worried with connectivity so if you can
bring a little bitch was the White House
perspective on these and why Obama has
put these on highlight and we see this
in us we fly lifeline and other programs
so if you can speak to that would be
grating yeah and you mentioned first of
all thank you all for joining us late on
a Friday afternoon I appreciate that and
thank you to access now we're putting
this entire of amazing event together
yeah you mentioned lifeline a lot of our
work has focused on domestic
connectivity and so you know the reason
why is because you know it's our
taxpayer dollars at work we're putting a
lot of our money into our own people but
this initiative isn't doesn't involve
taxpayer money to at least new taxpayer
money that we're spending this is about
taking the partners we already have and
mobilizing them and and directing them
in a way that's productive and that'll
get the most whether its investments
whether it's financing whether it's I'm
just a band-aid money this is I think
the well the way we look at it is
there's you've got the technology
experts over here like here was saying
you've got the the finance people over
here and you've got the government
people over here and you know they kind
of speak publicly but they never
actually sit down at a table and talk to
each other and and talk about you know
what's what's the issue here why can't I
the technical expert just drop bring up
a map and draw out where the fiber needs
to go or like where you know what I need
to do to get last mile or or why the
regulatory expert you know can't say
well here's why you can't do that but
here's how we could work together
on this that sometimes that the
conversation happens but then maybe the
person who has the money like is out of
that conversation right so why don't we
just get everyone together right why
don't you just start this community to
practice why don't we start having some
more situational awareness and why don't
we start having these conversations
because you know the government you know
isn't going to be the answer to this
what the what the White House what the
State Department wants to do here is get
the right people at the table and and so
that's why we need all of you we don't
it's not going to be us that solves this
problem it's not going to be us that
brings a nice 1.5 billion people online
it's all of you and it's it's all the
experts and that's all the people who
who care about this issue clearly you
guys care about this issue because you
here right now so let's hear your ideas
that's this this was our idea was you
know we want to take you know we
recently spent a lot of money on both
financing you know we have the overseas
Private Investment Corporation which
finances projects abroad we have the US
aid which does a lot of development in
disaster relief but what we've been
doing is going to those organizations
and partnering with them working with
them to see you know what opportunities
there are to integrate connectivity into
the work they're already doing and we
found out there are a ton of
opportunities and you know at this April
14 conference to overseas Private
Investment Corporation is going to
announce two or three really major
financing projects that's going to bring
you no more than 10 million people
online and that was that was sort of
what we're getting at and that's sort of
where we want to go with this so that's
sort of where we're coming from thank
you so much and and if I can provide
quickly civil society perspective here
one thing that is important that I've
been noticing since Pokemon public
knowledge has been involved in this work
is a emptiness of civil society paying
attention to the multilateral banks and
it's very interesting to do that because
the gender movement is there the
environmental movement's there but we
are not there yet and we should be there
because sitting and digging with those
guys
the word bank they and I'm from religion
so I went to look at the the IDB the the
lighting American Development Bank and
it's our country's do look up for these
banks because at the end of the day they
are putting millions of grants and loans
to developing countries to develop a
series of projects and we have to ensure
that when the grants are made there is a
series of incentives that all the
considerations we consider here in the
right scone privacy by design human
rights etc etc are also taking to
consideration these grants when we are
also telling them sat down a fiber optic
cable to connect the next billion so
it's really interesting for us to start
digging in these new organizations and
not I know we are few and we have very
few resources and we already overwhelmed
with UN and trade agreements and all the
other venues we follow but it but at the
end of the day sometimes where the money
the power it where is the money is the
power and the banks do have that power
to shape policies and best practices
through the policy papers but also to
the grants and loans so I'm just
clarifying this and asking more
attention from civil society of what the
banks are doing and get involved with
that there the banks already have civil
society committees and Liars on so just
get involved with that and with that I
actually would like to open up for
questions and our conversation so if you
guys have anything to add and if you
guys have anything to comment please
feel free is really a conversational
thank ok um hi my name is Chen AI Qi and
I'm from research ICT africa-based in
Cape Town my question is with regards to
the perception you receive when as an
American organization funding these
project because I'm following on from
what you're saying with civil society
has to play a role in ensuring what
exactly banks are doing but what is the
perception that you receive some
countries welcome american aid coming
into their and systems but what about
other countries that are quite reluctant
for example i come from zimbabwe and we
all know my dear president is not super
keen about America coming in more in
love with China so what um what problems
you face and what are the solutions that
you have one of the reasons why we made
this multilateral effort it was because
to answer that very question we don't
want this to be a u.s. initiative at all
we want this to be we want as many
countries as possible joining us we
wanted to get the conversation started
but but you know right now we have I
think 37 countries on right now yeah and
you see all those groups but you know if
it were up to us would be 150 so you
know that's sort of there is going to be
that perception initially but I hope
that after the these next couple of
events and after a series of
conversations that we're going to get
started and after a new heroes come up
yes we want people within all these
governments to come out and say you know
this is something not just Global
Connections connectivity you know this
is something we want to support and
prioritize then hopefully we can get
more countries on board and hopefully we
can you know take the u.s. global
collect initiative of the u.s. out of
that line yeah and just also adding to
that in terms of clarification the
funding that comes and there was a word
bank representative hearing the past
session but in- you correct me but the
fund that comes from one word bad word
bank and the various regional banks do
not come from us it might come from us
but come from germany and from other
banks and from other countries and then
they pull the money and distribute under
certain strategies so even this call
that I made get involved if you get
involved you can maybe shape that
strategy or where the money is gonna
gocho so in that sense that's why it's
so important to have this much lateral
banks because they receive and they give
money broadly comments or questions
force the question by chennai i think we
have the real gain oh yes mayland fung
the people sent it internet i'm
originally from singapore I live here
for the last 30 years um I think we face
a new era of potential digital
colonialism and that's actually what's
underlying all this whole bite finance
is just a disguise for that um I think
I'm very very curious about the global
connect initiative how we can take into
account the actual people and their own
voices and not just what we think they
should have or do or the kinds of
opportunities we think they should have
so I invite you to respond I think one
of the most exciting parts of or seeing
is that stakeholders I Triple E the
World Bank are coming together to put a
day-long conference together on their
own to help bring in these voices and to
help shape the initiative and to hear
from local regulators from across the
world whether it's yeah Brazil Mexico
all of them are invited and so this is
you know a stakeholder driven effort to
help support the Secretary of State who
will have a high level event the next
day with the various finance ministers
and for a lot of us here that has to be
really inspiring it is for me when I see
that we basically have a number of kind
of cross-industry international plate
people coming to Washington to kind of
engage in a multi-stakeholder discussion
that's very inclusive to kind of talk
not only very new right this is all kind
of a new a new organic thing that
and I'm just happening on its own I
think for us we're excited to play a
role and excited to support and what
Meili is saying is absolutely critical
that we are very responsive to other
voices and other ideas and really also
talking about inclusion and the benefits
of connectivity and local challenges
which i think is going to be critical
for the success of this initiative and
other initiatives like it yeah I could
just add I totally agree i think you
know getting the local community and the
regional perspectives and challenges and
sort of a bottom-up approach that is
really critical and you know that's
where organizations like I Triple E kind
of come in in a way being a global
organization with a very deep and broad
geographic reach we have many many
technical chapters if you will all
around the world and you know the
concept if we you know take a little bit
further if you look at sort of a one of
the terms that we've kind of thrown
around a little bit as sort of
connectivity core and give a Peace Corps
but account activity for and how we can
sort of leverage organizations like I
Triple E and others there are many
others out there like us that we can you
know get utilize those local communities
to hear the challenges first and work
with the local communities and really
have boots on the ground if you will in
those parts of the world so that we get
that and it sort of comes up bottom up
and we're also you're looking at it as a
global issue but also of the regional
perspective and a local perspective
thank you my name is Leia Seema her and
I am with the San Francisco Bay Area
Internet Society chapter I also work for
internet two systems consortium that's a
well-known company that smell around for
many years doing good work developers of
bind dns server involved with the
infrastructure of the internet so for
the internet society chapter it's
exactly what you were just responding to
tons of a bottom up and really trying to
get and you mentioned the word civil
involving the community to be a way I
want to educate them inform them and
make them participants to understand
really how the internet is structured
the policies that are implemented how
they implemented and how those can
directly affect their lives many people
are so removed from that so we try to do
that again at the bottoms you know
bottoms up we are the boots on the
ground so to speak but my question is
how far when you talking about
stakeholders the ones you've mentioned
so far our organizations and all that
how does it populate when you talk about
bottom up how does it populate our form
the people's views interest in all that
also because i am actually in
volunteering for the internal society
I've seen how challenging it is when you
don't have resources to help you get
that working so how do you do that I'm
glad you you know actually is a very
positive relationship a great
partnership with I saw and for those I'm
sure everyone for the knows who I sock
is but you know they're there are many
good programs are with education and
actually we have partnered with I saw
con with equal wireless for communities
aspect and so more on a
capacity-building side so that we can
educate local communities on you know
this isn't there's many solutions or
potential solutions and options for
connectivity to say the least this is
where more on the wireless side of it
but you know it's sort of you know you
start with those types of partnerships
and working in you know communities and
hopefully you know you can you can scale
out that knowledge and you can scale up
that information and what you're
building and bring it into different
different communities by all means it's
a huge challenge but it's sort of you
know one success story at a time one you
know community at a time and again
taking those lessons learned and being
able to take what works and apply that
in different regions of the world it
does or you know also learn what didn't
work
and learn from those lessons but I think
it is more sort of local level and sort
of bringing those types of programs into
those local communities but it is going
to require resources it is going to
require partnerships and and education
and capacity building and that's why I
think this initiative is so critical so
that we can start raising the awareness
about those challenges among investors
and technologists in you know technical
communities and as I mentioned earlier
sort of like everything that we've
learned over the past so many years to
sort of let's bubble that up take the
best and see what works in different
regions of the world I mean it's not
going to be a one-size-fits-all sale
there are many many challenges different
policies different cultures it's all
contextual but you know the best thing
is we can get the best practices
out of that and build those communities
of practice in and you know it is we're
excited about being involvement but we
know that we're standing sort of about
the little bit of them foot about ever
sent away but it is sort of working in
that local capacity you know so it's
sort of getting the support and the
drive from organizations that can help
you know support that from resources but
also then working with local communities
and organizations like I sock to you
know bring that kind of training in into
the local communities and knowledge if
you will and and just a quick testimony
to that I think that the folks that you
know when you have Domino's in sequences
and started so while we have some years
in the US government that did start that
know me know if domino effect we are all
pieces of that and I think we all should
be pieces of that and why I'm saying
that because every time I come and where
I give suggestions they listen and if
it's possible they implement or they say
why don't you do that so that's what I'm
bringing here because at the end of the
day we come from a variety of
communities right so I'd also do open
education the open educational community
we bring a lot of anecdotes we do stalin
jizz in communities and you bring that
inspiration from bottom up and then you
bring demonstrations of what happened
and what worked on the floor so if you
here has ideas and I hear them think
about open innovation and platforms for
challenge and challenges and things like
that let's sum that that let's plug
those things to the global connect
because the possibility is open no I
heard novela saying that herself so any
idea to plug into this and collect this
grassroots initiative is really
important because just by doing that we
going to learn the best practice from
the ground any other comment or question
Gary hi I'm Gary Garriott primitives I
find this session you know super
interesting partly because I think
there's been a narrative out there for
many years that we don't really have to
worry about connectivity because you
know there's millions and not billions
of mobile phones out there and you'll
sort of take care of itself and I the
graphs that you were showing that the
digital divide is is not closing sort of
the lies that narrative I think but as
karen was speaking I and talking about
the different pillars that the I Triple
E works with including power engineering
it made me recall at least a couple of
years ago when i was looking at pictures
from space of the earth at night and you
know Africa has few lights parts of Asia
and certainly Latin American my guess is
that it probably coincides even today
pretty much with the lack of
connectivity so I'm wondering maybe from
the I tripolis point of view or any of
you if you could care to comment the
specific role that providing better and
more reliable and affordable electrical
power might have to promote this whole
idea of global connectivity thank you
yeah that's definitely one Aspen a very
critical aspect of this because we can
have you know we can beat hours we can
put solutions devices which know people
will definitely reap the benefits from
but if they don't have a power
no that's that they challenge I know
there's a lot of work going on with
smart grid are smarter grid or
intelligent grid and where the world you
live and how they refer to that smart
cities which is a little bit broader
than that maybe a more advanced math and
ICT type of perspective but the power
piece of it is really critical and
actually we are starting to bring in
that and talk about connecting no pun
intended different types of communities
is to bring the power sectors and then
the people who are working in power
power generation transmission working in
smart grid to see you know what we can
do and how that it will help enable on
activity you know it's probably it's
been there sort of underlying all of
this but now it's time to bring that to
the forefront and part of this
conversation and to get those power
engineers and utilities into the mix of
this conversation I think it's really
critical sure and Natalya if you would
also bring a little bit your experience
on I gbn broadband before you join
american university would be great to
hear little bits the investments of the
bank i know you cannot speak from them
for them but anyway so one more question
this is leigh again with the internet
society chapter some cisco bay area and
internet systems consortium the question
I have is are there any local projects
that are being done maybe because there
are some connectivity issues too in the
US are there any incubated projects
happening locally with this initiative
to maybe act as a a good example or
something like that my colleagues
probably can speak more to it it was
interesting I was a couple weeks ago I
was at South by Southwest people are
familiar with that big conference right
yeah great in austin two great city um
and i did follow more of the what they
call their government policy track this
time you're coming from i trouble you
should sort of really focus more on the
whole mtech honest
you know old new technologies but it was
interesting they did attend a panel to
your point about some examples of it was
more on the broadband it was out what
might be going on in some particular
cities so he had Santa Monica which has
an interesting model Kansas City which
is working with Google Fiber but there
was a pardon for not remembering her
name at this moment but there was
someone from New York City and you would
think New York City why would they have
connectivity problems its new york
city's like one of the major cities of
the world but when you think about the
the concrete in the infrastructure and
the old infrastructure it really is a
challenge for them and then they have
some community still after still after
so many years of the impact of
superstorm sandy and knowing what
happened not only from a power
perspective but you know power goes down
on activity goes down literally you know
and I live on the east coast so I know
you know nine days of no electricity
that's no I'm living in New Jersey um
but it was really just I think it was an
eye-opening experience for many city
planners and addressing these types of
issues so one that really kind of caught
my attention was what was going on with
her trying to kick off in New York to
address some of those challenges they
have massive amount of concrete they
have high buildings you know signals get
law and then they have areas that were
you know under sea level that during a
bad storm are just totally taken out so
I think you know although in a developed
part of the world in a very major city
of the world there are lessons I think
that they're doing there that can be
applied maybe to some other regions of
the world so you know I think the more
we can learn about those types of of
pilots and projects an initiative not
only in North America and around the
world the better that will be enough i
think one of our key kind of objectives
along with all this is let's sort of
find out what's gone and going on there
so that we in around the world in those
type of the pilots and examples and
initiatives and what they're really
learning it was best practices thing
that we can apply but i said for me it
was just sort of io family you never
really thought of New York City having a
conductivity problem you know and i
think that's another party like this
awareness that we need to have and what
we can learn from that and i just want
to actually i think that's one of the
biggest flags at the work of for public
knowledge nationally
international part but public knowledge
actually core work is exactly to support
infrastructure and access and we do a
lot of work with african-american
communities and rural communities the
pockets in us are surprising to me even
coming from Brazil and I think we have
to commemorate that yesterday they have
to see actually voted to adopt the order
that for the first time a level allows
low-income subscribers should use the
Lifeline subzi did you help them connect
so even if there is infrastructure
sometimes we they still cannot connect
right so I think it's a great step in
the connectivity direction and maybe
with that there might be more market
incentives and estates incentives for
the expansion of infrastructure so I
Matthew from CDT Center for Democracy
yeah thanks Carolina Matthew share
Center for Democracy and technology
society um great great initiative fully
support its intent a couple of comments
0 and I think you may be being let down
by your slideshow so if you've already
address these concerns don't don't
hesitate to tell me so one of your
slides has four boxes on it and it talks
about various digital ambitions that you
have here this one here so this is great
okay but the World Bank just came out
with a report or digital dividends where
it says that the digital dividend has to
be supplemented by the analog compliment
which is good governance skills
development and good regulation and
competition I'm not seeing that analog
compliment here and I think that's a
very important thing to encompass in
your presentation I'm sure you've
thought about it as a part of the
project but it certainly should be there
and to the point that was raised earlier
on one of the things that's clear when
you look at this presentation is that
there's no reference to
multi-stakeholder them there's no
reference to local community there's no
reference to what you need to be doing
on the ground in developing countries to
make this happen and I think that's a
should be a core part of this initiative
and it needs to be reflected in that
presentation and it needs to be talked
up because right now it's not coming
across
um and I think there are a couple of
other things that really need to be
addressed here I mean as a is this when
the Secretary of State is meeting with
the finance ministers is this new money
this old money is this redirected money
what exactly is coming out of this
initiative and what's the goal from the
kind of support and investment
perspective so I think there are some
key questions here that aren't answered
I'm sure you have the answers but
they're certainly not answered in your
presentation I think it will be good to
get more clarity on that Thanks I think
there are excellent questions we are
pleased to tell you that the World Bank
is launching a digital development
partnership to respond to the challenges
of the world of Elmet report that will
help countries with those analog
compliments and it's really exciting to
see this multi-country program that is
focused on capacity building and policy
development and it'll be a major subject
for the meeting with secretary Kerry and
the other finance ministers where
they're going to be announcing a number
of corporate sponsors for the digital
development partnership as well as
country sponsors and it's helping to
really kind of show the bank's
leadership in trying to also drive
progress towards giving countries help
with those analog compliments Matthew is
right about the importance of multi
stakeholder participation and I think
for us it's really heartwarming to see
the April 13th a global connect
stakeholders event which you know
governments are attending to kind of
listen to stakeholders and also share
information whether it's the Technical
Community the industry the NGOs everyone
will kind of be represented and
participating actively including I sock
will be there because of course they
have done amazing work in local
communities and we are trying to bring
together a number of people from
different air places and people are
traveling from all over the world for
the event so we can really hear and kind
of think creatively together about
really how to mobilize
support for the initiative I may have
missed one of Matthew's questions and if
I did I will now ask soo ah sir keren to
kind of kindly take the mic because
they're also very familiar with kind of
the initiative and its goals and stuff I
thought you cover it all I don't was it
was or another okay choo-choo help man
the memory here we also have the
Alliance for affordable Internet
involved on this and they have been
doing great work on these analog piece
so we hope to bring everybody with its
own expert seasons and some efforts and
they hope is that actually we set a
series of progress checkers and those
questions need to be part of those
progress checkers so join if I may I
think the issue of how is this going to
be implemented and what are the
resources are going to be brought to
bear at the local level is the essential
dimension that's missing here and and
and how are those forces marshaled which
resource is going to be called upon how
are we going to take into account the
actual demand and needs on ground in the
countries that where this projects going
to roll out things so in the US um you
know we are and we've had a number of
meetings with our US development
agencies us financing agencies and we're
talking about how the Internet is just
as important as traditional
infrastructure they should be
prioritizing programs and projects and
funding and financing and so to that
regard the overseas Private Investment
Corporation has already announced a 250
million dollar loan for Myanmar for
2,500 satellite towers that will really
boost connectivity in one of the
country's that's really fallen the most
behind oh the overseas Private
Investment Corporation is also and will
be as was alluded by by US government
colleague another major announcement of
170 million in financing for another
country that being India so this is new
financing money that's really going to
make a difference in connecting millions
of households and we're hope that it's a
model for other donor countries that are
also partners with us in the global
connect initiative whether it's the UK's
divid or osita or other kind of Germany
other
and we're hoping to catalyze more donor
money and attention behind this so we
can help as many people get connected as
possible I just want to be sure give to
Natalya but actually we have
choo-choo-choo-choo then and there is
another session but ok not a lien then
quickly just to reply to your request
through my experience of the world bank
and ND bei i could feel that well
development banks are a development
agency and a bank at the same time so
actually that's an advantage but also a
challenge in the sense that you know in
the end of the day they they want to
have they want to foster development but
in the end of the day they need to have
project and loan so what actually I saw
from the projects like work is that
whenever in broadband ya whenever yeah
whenever it's aligned to the country's
policy that actually makes a huge
difference because if you try to create
something new that's much harder but
when you already have like some sort of
structure and the country is already
looking for the type of things your look
your you can provide that actually makes
it much easier hi I'm wallah casse me
from Tunisia I have an NGO called you
the sights and we work to use technology
to solve society problems so I have two
questions the first one did we think
about the outreach of like people if we
are talking about connectivity if
everyone gets connected to internet you
know that Internet can be used for the
good and it can be use it for the bat to
you know in the MENA region Isis is
using this tool to recruit young people
can we think about projects to fill this
space call it internet this space called
the information technology for the good
and support like n
those who work on that my second
question is how can we express our
support to this initiate how can we
exactly do as government or a civil
society you well you can express your
support by signing up by contacting us
by giving us your ideas by joining us in
all the conversations that we want to
begin either there is a website and i
think you know we absolutely you know
the initiative is literally I think
seven eight months old there are a lot
of questions that we have to think
deeply about like the one that you
raised about how we can encourage
through this initiative the good we
don't have all of the answers or or for
these types of difficult questions we do
think that connectivity is a key driver
of economic growth can help with like
youth unemployment can really kind of
provide a lot of stability in certain
countries that are struggling or you do
see like Isis and other types of
activities right and so clearly there's
the benefit of connectivity in this but
but you are raising good questions that
can only be answered with with dialogue
and really kind of hard thinking and so
this is why we're excited about the 13th
meeting and we're hopeful that we'll be
able to continue these dialogues not
only on the 13th Internet Governance
forum at a lot of different forums so we
can really try to accelerate progress
towards providing answers to some of
your questions perfect than I am
tweeting all the links and um there
there is more material and and and stuff
so first thank you so much all the
panelists thank you so much all of you
that have join us on a Friday afternoon
while you know we are all exhausted I
asked it bread that we
should have shot sue massage chairs for
the next right school so we all relax a
little bit during sessions and please
enjoy the rest of your afternoon when
the final closing session thank you so
much