hello right Scott and welcome to the
second day at nine o'clock so I'm the
first lightning toward speaker as you
can probably tell i'm not speaking at
exactly a lightning pace here i was
going to do a presentation using my
outdoor activist voice but then i
realized that we would be speaking at
nine o'clock in the morning and at nine
other calculor morning no one wants to
hear that kind of high energy least of
all me I'm not sure I can even muster
that amount of energy at nine o'clock in
the morning we have six incredible
speakers for you and I am one of them so
I'm actually one of the reasons I'm
going to be relatively downbeat in this
this first talk is because I'm
discussing a relatively downbeat topic
could we have the the website art please
so in October of last year I i started
my name is Larry O'Brien I went for the
Electronic Frontier Foundation and I did
a small site here called offline which
was to draw attention to the increasing
number of technologists who were being
targeted with detention and imprisonment
around the world and this this this
actually comes from partly from my
experience working for the Committee to
Protect Journalists there's been a long
tradition that we're not necessarily all
aware of of creating movements around
individuals journalists writers when
they're imprisoned to restore some of
their integrity and to widen awareness
of their situation to a broader audience
and my concern when I rejoin the FF was
that in the same way as journalists and
writers are targeted because of their
disproportionate effect in protecting
human rights and exercising human rights
of freedom of expression and assoc
version that the same thing was going to
happen to technologists the
technologists were going to be
specifically targeted because if you
take out technologists you can diminish
the magnifying effect that they can have
on dissent in reform as I worked on
offline now if we could scroll it down a
little bit if that's okay I was I went
through some of the people that we knew
who are being detained from their works
in technology allow Bozell esque
indonesia save my load port and as i was
editing their pieces to present to the
world hopefully a wider world than just
the circle of people who knows these as
friends or colleagues i realized that i
was editing their stories in a
particularly interesting way when you
win you when you write about individual
targets in this way you end up turning
them into heroes you end up editing the
gray areas and the story becomes much
more black and white and this is
understandable for a lot of reasons one
of the reasons why people are detained
and targeted in this way is to defame
them is to separate them from the rest
of society and one of the ways you do
that is you pick on you know tiny flaws
or imaginary conspiracies and you throw
as much mud as you can and I'd hope that
it sticks and and tiring them with a
prison sentence is one of the most
effective ways of doing that um but it
felt strange to ally the shades of grey
if it felt strange to me to be writing
these stories and these people aren't
sinners but they're not Saints either
and one of the reasons why that happens
as well is its distance frankly the
further you are away from a political
situation the easier it is to be
mannequin is Mickey predatory never know
to make it black and white and so we're
sort of familiar of that with with
people outside of our community right
when we talk about journalists when I
wrote about journalists the Committee to
Protect Journalists protect journalists
you know you saw them as heroes
in a country not your own whereas in
that country of course journalists are
as controversial as they are in your own
country you know no one no one has
absolute respect for a journalist
particularly representing an opposite
political view so it's a distance thing
that turns things into black and white I
realize that this is going to be a
growing problem because I think that
that the more dling bet that I've made
by launching off line is that we're
going to see more people in this lifts
the technology is going to be
increasingly targeted and people in our
community are going to find themselves
arrested entertained and because they're
close to us because over there they're
our friends we have loyalty to them but
we also see these shades of grey and
that shades of grey can be debilitating
many people saw sort so Aaron Swartz as
a hero after after his his passing away
but many of us also remembered when he
was arrested and how ambiguous and and
diminished the response was in those
early days if you actually go through
the internet archive and look at
people's responses the moment a charge
was made there was a distancing effect
and people people walked away from a
person who was at that particular moment
most vulnerable a couple of weeks ago a
Facebook vice president was was arrested
in Brazil and I had this interesting
moment of going well well what prison do
we look through at a president of a
corporation who is arrested in that
situation for protecting the privacy of
their users and I think that viewpoint
looks very different if you're in Brazil
than if you're looking from outside
Brazil and we know all these names but
but but I mean does anyone know the name
of the the Facebook vice president I do
but I looked it up it's diego de cerdo
and he was detained for a day how do we
write about that I don't have any good
answers to this and it's very early in
the morning so I don't expect any of you
to have good answers to this this is
something that communities have
struggled with political communities
have been struggled with for the
beginning of time loyalty and solidarity
versus that
but I do have like a couple of those 14
perhaps that i'll leave you with which
is the more i think about this and more
i think about how people are tired by
this brush when they're arrested and
they're detained and they're thrown into
prison the more i be it begins to feel
like it's a problem with our
understanding of justice and as from my
rights a privileged position at the
Electronic Frontier Foundation one of
the things that we get to spot is how
the issues of digital rights are
constantly expanding into a wider world
as the world itself becomes more
influenced by by digital issues and one
of the things I notice is more and more
technologists are becoming interested in
issues of justice it's you interested in
issues of prison reform in the United
States and I think maybe the thing that
I'll leave you with is that if we really
want to both have the benefits of seeing
things in a black and white way and the
benefits of seeing things as they really
are in shades of grey we have to
understand that that we can't just
discard and throw people away when they
enter into the justice system in the
prison system or the court system
because that's that's the the method of
dictators that's that's the trick that
they use guitar good people with an
unfair brush thank
when I was 16 my mom my sister and I
visited my aunt in the city of Caramon
that's my mom's hometown in southern
Iran one hot afternoon we were strolling
the streets when I noticed that my head
scarf was on backwards if I quickly
picked it up and turned it around and
continued we entered a fabric store and
as we entered the door opened up again
so I turned around and my heart sank
there there were two men in uniform with
mean piercing eyes staring right at me I
knew there were the moral police and
they were there for me the men
approached me and said because my hair
had shown they were going to arrest me
mom refused to let me be taken alone so
they piled all of us into a van and took
us in the best that I could come up with
was to pretend that I was religious so I
asked for a notepad and a pen and jotted
down everything they were saying as fast
as I could like a really good student I
was held for five hours and only
released after repenting and writing
next time they warned I would receive
fifty lashes this is life in Iran by the
government's own account in 2013 alone 3
million Iranians were arrested were
stopped by the moral police for walking
ippudo for being out with the boyfriend
for playing music loudly or showing
their hair ninety percent of them women
we are here at rights con because we
believe in the rights of all citizens we
know technology plays a pivotal role in
enhancing and protecting those rights so
how would technology protect Iranians
from the more police
guess what there's an app for that the
same navigation applications we use to
get two locations faster is allowing
Iranians detour the moral police and
avoid harassment and arrest the app is
called gear shod its gear shod is a
contraction of the wards gas to air shot
the Persian Wars for the moral police
gear shots an appt similar two ways and
features its crowdsource and users can
view and report to each other the
location of the more police checkpoints
in real time Gershon was an instant hit
30 thousand downloads within days 1100
reviews hovering around five stars
hundreds of media stories in at least
eight languages that I could count to me
its biggest indication of success
probably came from my 18-8 step son Gabe
he's American teenager rarely leaves his
room or his four screens the day after
gear shorts release when I walked in
from work he ran into the kitchen is
what there's this cool Iranian app
that's trending on reddit it already has
4000 upvotes Twitter in Iran lit up as
well perfect example of civil
disobedience said one tweet each
download is a protest about rights being
trampled upon than another technology
knows no physical boundaries and has
ripple effects savvy woman tweeted that
their moral police is killing them Gary
I 2 point 0 will include Arabic was
tweeted back why is gear shot a hit why
is the Vic technology critical first the
infrastructure exists there are 70
million Iranian Xin Iran more than half
of them have smartphones
a million new smartphones are being
added every month every month the
country is quickly moving to 4G secondly
Iranians are ready for change they're
young they're techy their global seventy
percent of the country is under the age
of 35 this young population is being
ruled by few old fanatics these old men
their inner circle and followers make up
about ten percent of the country yet
they own and control all the schools all
the media all the institutions I believe
in technology I believe in its impact I
see its potential technology will
provide the other ninety percent with a
platform a secure platform to organize
assemble and express themselves
technology is our best bet at taking our
country back with all this potential
need and desire gear shod was the first
app of its kind to be released in Iran
first to good app that we know of until
today right here with you we are
launching publicly for the first time
our latest project Iran Q Bader get it
Iran incubator I founded United for Iran
in 2009 to help protect civil liberties
in Iran we support civil society and
civic engagement through technology Iran
Q Bader United ear open for Iran's
latest project will pair up the
developers and organizers to make a
dozen or so apps similar to gear shot
for use within Iran over the next 18
months team's chosen will receive
operational technical and financial
support freedom of expression freedom of
religion gender equality
all of these are being supported by
gershon there dozens of other rights and
social issues that our best are being
ignored and that worth being caused by
the Islamic Republic Iran Q Bader will
support these rights and issues we're in
conversation with dozens of communities
for months now to find out what their
unique challenges and potential
solutions are we will work with and not
for these communities we will prioritize
security inclusion and accessibility
here are a few examples of the apps that
were starting with one app will support
the victims of domestic violence but
connecting them with each other and
resources another app is similar to Yelp
and focuses on government transparency
and accountability users will rate and
review government officials and offices
other apps that were considering will
focus on the environment LGBTQI rights
and working children as we pave the road
of civic technology I hope for global
impact the same way Gareth will be used
by Saudi woman I envision Iran k beta
apps will be used will inspire and
support and protect citizens regionally
and globally Iran Q Bader would enable
those in Iran to deepen and broaden
their community I'm here with you today
to build our community in support to
them we need support to spread the word
to get media to build our partnerships
and specifically to recruit affordable
app developers I was lucky but I was
held for five hours there hundreds of
Iranians in prison right now for
lifetimes years or life
we're simply exercising their basic
rights working for free Iran is
important work it's rewarding and
important work it's my life's work it's
also challenging work and it takes all
of us though not easy I have no doubt
that our day will come and likely in my
lifetime I look forward to the day that
Iranian woman can wear anything they'd
am pleased that all our rights are
honored I look forward to the day that
all Iranians regardless of background or
belief are free thank
good morning i'm ben rose well i am
actually a canadian diplomat but i'm not
here to talk to you about diplomacy
today in fact nothing and i'm going to
say reflects the views of the canadian
government whatsoever so now that i've
got that disclaimer out of the way but
it does occur to me that those of you
that are in this room that are part of
this effort by access now to protect and
promote access to the internet do have
something in common with diplomats those
involved in civic participation in civic
action are often often say that they're
trying to change the world it's an
expression you hear an awful lot here in
Silicon Valley and that also happens to
be the motivation of many people
including myself who joined the
Diplomatic Service back to the nineties
pre-internet that seemed like the way to
do it there's other ways to do it now
but there is kind of a common objective
now when you're talking about changing
the world you often get accused of naive
idealism we are all Dorothy on the
yellow brick road unaware of the dangers
of Oz but you know that you are making a
difference in the last five to ten years
citizens have been involved directly in
shaping outcomes in global affairs to an
extent never seen before it's something
that we notice it's palpable from within
the world of diplomacy how citizens are
organizing and having an impact directly
often powered by technology how many of
you are members for example of avas I'm
one there's 43 million of us that are
members of Oz that signed petitions to
change outcomes in global affairs
change.org anyone 143 million now our
members of change org then there's
organizations like 350.org which focuses
on environmental issues its present in
188 countries in the world our own
government only has embassies 140
countries in the world when these
organizations bound together and adopt a
common goal as they did with the climate
talks the climate marches of 2000
14 and 2015 they can demonstrate the
domestic pressure the changes
government's views and that in the case
of the Paris agreement in December of
2015 led to an accord that was more
ambitious than anything the Kyoto ever
accomplished thank you internet now that
is a bit of an exception to the rule
however because their 195 countries at
Paris and I can tell you it's extremely
rare that you get 195 countries that
agree on anything significant at all
more often in global affairs global
leaders who we picture as these very
powerful figures have very little power
to affect outcomes in global affairs
national governments have a lot of power
within their within their within their
borders there's no doubt about that at
all but once you get past the national
borders even a country as powerful as
the United States has very limited
ability to affect what happens outside
of its own borders it's difficult to get
195 countries to agree and I think often
activists feel that if governments just
saw things the right way or had their
heart in the right place or had more
knowledge or better knowledge that they
would be able to affect change I can
tell you having worked for 23 years and
diplomacy it's very I do think that
national governments actually have
pretty good knowledge and pretty good
idea of what what needs to be done and
often we do have our hearts in the right
place but it is just extremely difficult
for governments to affect change and
that does point to a bit of a potential
naivete in the petition model because
when you're petitioning you're asking
someone else to take action on your
behalf you're not taking action
yourselves apart from signing the
petition and that's fine if the
organization that you're asking to take
action has the power to do so but often
what you find in global affairs is that
global leaders end up looking like this
guy the wizard of oz himself who as we
know when you pull the part the the
curtains saw that it was a man it wasn't
really controlling anything at all in
global affairs the scale of the issue
dealing with are so important that we
can't leave it to just national
government citizens themselves need to
band together to take direct action in
what Mitchell from the Mozilla
Foundation yesterday morning said
is distributed action the most powerful
method of human collaboration that we've
seen that the internet is made possible
in many different domains of human life
needs to be harnessed for global affairs
now that leads me to another accusation
that we often get when we're trying to
change the world through online
organizing and that's that we get
accused of collectivism this is a famous
book written by Afghani Marcus off two
or three years ago in which he indicated
that a lot of the online organizing that
takes place is extremely short term it's
a petition that might just last for a
few weeks or even dramatic changes in
the in the Arab world where where
revolutionaries came together to change
their governments but a year later those
movements barely existed whatsoever
there's a kind of short-term
short-termism in civic organizing and
often some of the causes that we see on
petition sites tend to be relatively
superficial in their in their reach and
in their impact how many of you have
been asked to sign petitions to save
bees I have nothing against saving bees
but the reason that they're so popular
on all these petition sites is that they
have this wide appeal that no one could
put it action that is powered by social
algorithms so the reason that a company
like Facebook is actually quite
successful in motivating users to
undertake actions over and over and over
again and undertake more significant
actions is because they study the
patterns of users behavior online to
identify what are the algorithms that
match the motivations of users to
attract companies have the resources to
do that the hire people to hire data
scientists to look through those
patterns generally civic organizations
do not but if they were to bound that
together with sharing aggregate data
about the patterns of citizens
engagement in global fit choose we
believe that you could power a civic
organization on the basis of social
algorithms now in the area of global
affairs there's also very controversial
issues and sometimes taking on the
interests of very powerful people that
have the means to disrupt and to punish
those that are taking
action as well and so there needs to be
a very strong basis of security so
perennial aims to build a distributed
model for civic engagement in global
affairs powered by social algorithms and
protected through a blockchain the
blockchain is an architecture which
allows you to separate the key pieces of
information anything that's driven on
social algorithms is going to have
personal data that needs to be kept
totally separate from information on
actions being undertaken by by people on
the site and from the organizations that
are asking citizens to take action into
three completely separate compartments
so that even if the organization running
the software is hacked that will that
organization will not be able to divulge
information because they won't have it
it'll be protected through the
blockchain so that's what perennial is
going to try to do a build a distributed
model for citizen engagement powered by
social algorithms protected by the
blockchain we're going to launch it in
the coming months in one of the issues
that has become the most difficult
intractable problem one of the most
difficult intractable problems in global
affairs which is the conflict in Syria
this is a conflict which has generated
250 thousand deaths the worst migration
crisis of modern times the rise of Isis
is directly attributable to the violence
in Syria and untold suffering inside the
country as well it's a problem that is
escaped the ability of any national
government to try and bring some end to
the violence now citizens uniting are
not going to bring an end to the
violence we need to be quite clear about
that but one of the things that's been
fascinated with Syria is that it served
as a laboratory for moved for civic
movement civic organizations to try and
deliver some kind of assistance to
people inside the country through the
digital connectivity that somehow
miraculously remains inside Syria what
perennial is going to do is build a
coalition of the organizations that are
inviting citizens robel citizens
interested in Syria through a series of
micro tasks to lend support to those
that are trapped inside the conflict and
share the information that comes the
aggregate data that comes so that we can
learn social algorithms of what
motivates citizens to take action I'll
give you three examples
the Syrian American Medical Society
provides medical assistance to people
inside Syria through telemedicine though
Syrian medical practitioners nurses and
doctors who are tending to the wounded
or the the ill inside Syria when they
have access to the Internet can actually
communicate with medical professionals
in the United States and elsewhere
through video conferences to find out
how to treat certain conditions as we
expand the circle of the medical
practitioners outside Syria to provide
assistance inside it gives an
opportunity for people outside Syria to
do something concrete that has an impact
in the lives of people inside the
country a second example the Kurram
foundation provides educational training
to Syrian youth so Syria risks having an
entire generation that that is not
educated because the educational system
has been disrupted by the war and this
is the kind of dynamic that tends to
turn conflicts into generational
conflicts like we've seen in Afghanistan
from the 60s to the 80s there were very
few Afghans that were in school because
of violence and as a result the Taliban
were created and they created it
extended the conflict for another
generation the creme foundation is one
of many that are trying to disrupt that
pattern by providing education to those
that are on the ground in Syria and they
also offer opportunities for people
outside Syria to help if you are able to
teach English or other languages that
they're trying to learn or if you have
other other skills that you can teach to
Syrians to the internet you can actually
provide those that education to Syrians
and even when it comes to the source of
the of the violence itself a Dutch
government is putting together a network
that is mapping out all of the companies
and organizations that are involved in
importing the materials that make barrel
bombs inside Syria barrel bombs being a
weapon that has virtually no military
use whatsoever it's really only used to
kill civilians so the Dutch government
is trying to map out how the various
components of barrel bombs are getting
into the country once that's identified
then as possible for citizens around the
world to name and shame the various
companies that are involved in that
trade and so and and so try and limit
some of the
to which people trapped inside Syria are
subjected so in conclusion perennial is
building a distributed model to help
citizens engaged directly in global
affairs powered by social algorithms and
protected through the blockchain we hope
that you will join us if you have skills
that you could lend whether their
language skills or coding skills whether
you're involved in Syria organizations
or no an organization that might want to
partner with us or if you're interested
in becoming part of this distributed
model of citizen engagement please sign
up at the website here or send us an
email and we'd love to work with you
thank you very much hi good morning my
name is Ferdinand Alberto de on a
researcher at Harvard and i'm here today
to talk about a very simple idea and
that's the idea of online right and
online duty so this is a big topic of
course we're just going to be get to
touch in it today but I want to begin
here I want to begin with this man with
HG Wells who as many of you know was
apart from being a noted science fiction
author and a futurist one of the
earliest and most vocal proponents of
Human Rights the idea that everyone
everywhere should be entitled to basic
protections and freedoms now around
nineteen forty this man wrote a letter
to this man Mohandas K Gandhi in India
asking him for advice pinging him for
feedback we might say today though in
refining his idea his model of universal
human rights hg wells asked Gandhi to
give his perspective as an
anti-colonialist and Gandhi's response
is illustrative in a couple ways Gandhi
responds with this instead of focusing
exclusively on rights well should
instead begin with the charter of the
duties of man and I promise that the
rights will follow as spring
winter now apart from being a sort of
quirky historical anecdote I think this
this exchange is illustrative in a
couple ways it shows us first of all of
a very basic fact which is that the
language of Human Rights is not the only
language available to us to talk about
issues of digital justice in fact there
are many discourses than many
vocabularies we can use and some of
those resonate with others I think the
exchange also hints at the fact that
different vocabularies resonate with
different audiences especially those in
the global north and the global South
especially the language of duty and
obligation which often resonates in much
of Latin America Africa and Asia not to
create a overly simple dichotomy but
often to the anglo-american rights
tradition which focuses on individual of
rights against the state against
infringement this idea of a mutual
reciprocal relationship can seem a bit
foreign but in fact it's part of the
rice tradition going back all the way to
the 40s and I think it can also help us
address this idea of really the language
of vocabulary of duty and responsibility
can help us address some of the limits
and the problems we're seeing with
rights today so I assume if everyone
here is you know attending that you're a
fan of the idea of human rights but in
some ways we're seeing rights language
become over extended and used in ways
that might not you know that might not
be the ways that we that the initial
founders of these rights envisioned them
an example a sort of a controversial
example of this is the idea of the
emerging right to connectivity where the
very fact of being connected to internet
is often framed as being a right itself
a sort of meta right now there you know
there are debates about this and people
claim that connectivity is more of an
enabler of rights of facility
but I think that we're missing an
overall point which is that connectivity
being framed as a human right represents
the sort of this victory for rights
language and an eclipse an eclipse of
other sorts of discourses that we could
be using and in fact what we're seeing
not only with the right to connect with
the so-called right to be forgotten is a
move for instead of rights being being
used in a sort of network of obligation
reciprocity rights are being used to
counter other rights we spoken earlier
at this conference of balance and the
pros and cons of that but in addition I
think I think we go a step further and
say that rights are being used as
shields and swords to counter or promote
digital the particular issue of digital
justice depending on our points of view
and so my my plea my my feed that I'd
like to plant today is just that we
consider going forward here in your
sessions in your workshops as you draft
initiatives as we move forward in
drafting new language of Rights that we
consider adopting explicit references to
duties and obligations of the private
sector and of individuals and that this
is actually not a diversion or or really
an innovation but this goes back to the
original rights tradition and it goes
back to some of the initial
international proposals some of the very
first documents that were lead up to the
Universal Declaration of Human Rights
framed Human Rights just in this way as
obligation here's a great example from
the American Law Institute their
declaration of essential freedom of
Rights which notes the freedom of speech
freedom of expression is the right of
everyone but doesn't stop there it has a
second closet says the state has a duty
to refrain from arbitrary limitation of
this freedom and prevent denial of
reasonable access to channels of
communication and so you know just here
in this little claws we see what has
changed and what hasn't what hasn't
changed particularly much is the first
line you
expression is the right of everyone but
what has changed is our interpretation
of obligation of whether the state is
solely responsible for ensuring that or
whether states and private actors can
collaborators should collaborate and how
those relationships should be defined in
terms of service in statements of
universal internet right so as we move
towards this greater sense of digital
constitutionalism as a recent paper by
the Berkman Center coins coins this idea
of defining Bills of Rights
international norms that are codified
and shared for the Internet much in the
same way that HG Wells was hoping to do
I think we should take a step back and
remember that the language of Duty can
provide an alternative both in terms of
audience both in terms of tone and
resonance but also in terms of clarity
and specificity and that adopting dd's
language can help us here we have a
photo of the drafting committee of the
Universal Declaration of Human Rights
but that the language of Duty is
actually a part and parcel of the human
rights movement and that we as people
who care about the the international
digital human rights regime should begin
to think about adopting that language to
promote digital justice everywhere thank
hi hi everyone I'm the knife from the
rigid Alice and in this session I'm
going to talk very very briefly about
digital intersectionality well
intersectionality is the concept that
has been popularized by black feminism
references definitely her she is
Patricia Hill Collins and in her book
black feminist thought he exposed how
different is the subject of feminism
four different women depending how many
types of oppressions overlap in their
identities for example is not possible
to analyze every women under only one
big layer big lens of gender factors has
class nationality and race to be taken
into account this was a huge advancement
in the study of discriminations and as
people who work in technology and in
human right it's a concept that we
should address for example with fta's as
tbp most stakeholders intend to talk
about general rules about copyright for
everyone without considering the huge
privilege of the north of a North that
has profited for centuries of the rest
of the world culture for free and now in
the south we are supposed to sit with
them and talk horizontally about
exceptions and liability and no we
wanted the abolition of copyright for
our people we want to overcome the
privileges of the North or the case when
we are talking about women in technology
it's very common to hear about First
World priorities as the struggle of
female corporate tech CEOs or female
tech entrepreneurs this is a subject
clearly fundamental here in San
Francisco for example but it's not
relevant to us since our Latin America
and Petrarca societies we have to worry
about
watch other stuff like the women that
every day get killed and harassed and
everything with about the help of
digital resources and in a cost in a
context like this we're not able we're
not available to talk about abs or the
oldest Silicon Valley jargon you are not
this this is a priority well this is a
big issue I believe and we have to think
about ways on solving this let me talk
about some examples that we have done in
Latin America regarding
intersectionality technology and
discrimination and this picture is of
protesting Santiago Chile and they are
the girls from linea or Toledo is or
abortion hotline where you can call and
get information on how to perform an
abortion because in Chile abortion is
penalized under any circumstances even
if your life is at risk because of the
pregnancy even if the fetus is dead
inside you even if you have been raped
12 year old girls are forced to become
mothers and women who interrupt their
pregnancies go to jail and are publicly
harassed and judgeth this is one of the
biggest issues for us chillin feminists
and thus activists in technology is
something that we can not ignore after
considering very seriously this
extremely complicated context we work
together and we activists have been able
to teach on the use of secure
communication channels for feminist
organization to provide information on
how to perform safe abortions now more
and more women are using encryption for
the protection of layered entities and
avoid gale or let me tell you about
surveillance in Chile this is a picture
that actually a colleague from me in
there too sticky Dallas chick we cannot
talk about surveillance without
incorporate the case of them a puta
people in the south they are our largest
native community and they are constantly
harassed by the police and surveilled by
drones who which are bought by military
bodies they are even subject to a
special legislation
where the rights are constantly ignored
because our government considers that
they are terrorists for trying to
recover their lands from the hands of
corporations in a case like this we can
we can't just talk about security policy
in some panels formed by privilege
lawyers this is an emergency and in
tulare activists have provided
information on digital self defense
against surveillance and against police
analyze what kind of drone is in their
land how can you avoid those without
compromising your identity without this
approach any effort as discussion about
surveillance in conferences like this is
going to be not relevant should we ban
white people from this discussion that
that is kind of the question that
emerges we wish but we we know we
shouldn't we know we shouldn't we want
to involve everyone in the quest of a
more egalitarian society but before
doing anything every person should check
their own privileges it's an exercise
that all of us must do before trying to
approach any social issue for example I
hate when women from the first world
only with superficial knowledge of our
circumstances go to Latin America and
tell me what we feminist should do and
because I hate them so much I have to
consider my own privilege in order to
not be like this so knowing people from
the north I'm not in the peak of the
pyramidal of privilege I am a women I'm
from Latin America I'm coming from a low
class sector of society but I have to
put myself in the place of even less
spillage woman than me what about trans
women what about disabled women I want
to finish this talk saying that I
ambition a digital environment where
everyone is seriously taken into account
it's a matter of respect is a matter of
solidarity thank you
keep that clicking hello everyone my
name is Nathaniel Manning I'm the COO at
usha he d all right just start I want
you all to just say the first thing that
comes to your mind okay let's try this
one more time but this time just say pay
attention all right together all right
so we can be a little louder when we're
in unison when we have focus so keep
that in mind o Shahi DS goal is to help
people raise their voice marginalized
people don't have a voice and usually
those who serve them the organization's
the government's the small community
groups despite their best intentions
often or sometimes not best intentions I
have trouble listening and this is just
a fundamental issue how do we understand
what's happening on the ground and the
needs of the people we serve so that's
fundamentally what do shaheedi does in
2008 rashidi was formed in the
post-election violence in Kenya at that
time the country broke into civil war
more or less and I and the founders were
for bloggers who talked about technology
in Africa wanted to know what was
happening on the ground some of them
were in Kenny at the time some of them
were in the United States I and hid our
texting everyone they knew on the ground
right as one would do if your home
basically breaks into war I they start
reading every blog they can find they
read through every Twitter hashtag they
can find everyone they know and they're
just trying to figure
out this question what's happening on
the ground and they started asking that
question and they said okay well is
there a way I could build something that
would do everything that I'm doing
manually just taking a lot of time and
and make it a little easier and so they
built OSHA heating the first three days
oh sure he means testimony or witness in
Swahili didn't think anyone outside of
Kenya would ever have to go to that URL
again but luckily I over the last eight
years that hasn't been the case so in
the last eight years there's been over a
hundred thousand deployments of your
shaheedi across 160 countries localized
in 249 different local languages
gathering over 7 million reports and
that's actually just in the cloud
version of the software open source
because the software is open source it's
on its own server so we don't actually
know how many reports are being gathered
right that's the benefit from the pros
and cons of open source so I it's been a
really powerful story about two years
ago we started rebuilding the core
software about two and a half years ago
I trying to learn and build a new
version of shaheedi because the original
code base was written in 2009 had gotten
a little old and it was starting to be
held together by duct tape and popsicle
sticks and so we we built a new version
a new architecture and to do that we had
to understand really you know the first
time we built it we had a very simple
use case and we had for initial users
right the four founders now we had a
hundred thousand deployers seven million
reporters I that gets pretty hard that's
a totally different problem to solve so
we looked first okay who are the main
people using your shaheedi well there
was three core groups if we think about
it like industry human rights reporting
so Syria tracker doc crowd maps six
years of reporting of firsthand
witnessed
ports of violence in Syria I think
there's now a 8000 maybe even over
10,000 reports on that website one of
the most powerful firsthand archives of
one of the greatest travesties of this
this century and I the second was human
rights reporting so her ass map the the
mapping of and the get crowdsourcing of
of anonymous witness testimonies of
women who were being harassed in Egypt
now actually across North Africa what I
loved was this was just a group of
citizens doing this using our open
source software putting it on a website
and now they are a over 20 person
organization working on advocacy for
women's rights in in North Africa and
the Middle East and and then the third
you know citizen and government kind of
call this transparency this is election
monitoring this is corruption mapping
this sort of piece of citizens trying to
bring attention to to their needs as
well as bad actors so these are kind of
the three big groups but then by the
type there were kind of two different
ways people were using our crowdsourcing
tool the first wise response so this is
I'll say election monitoring or crisis
response if you've heard of shaheedi
this might be one of the ways that
you've heard of it the haiti reports the
japan most recently earthquake the most
recently than the Nepal earthquake and
in this case you're trying to gather
information from what from someone let's
say who's saying help I'm stuck and you
want to help them want to help that want
that one person you want to respond to
that report you want to allocate your
resources more effectively the second is
transparency or sort of advocacy and
this is different this is you want to
gather all as many voices as possible
and and and then try to build a body of
knowledge say this is a problem right in
in Egypt and the harassed map there it
would be really it is problematic to to
try to be responding to each one of
those harassment cases
that's as a small civil organization but
by gathering everyone's voices and
having thousands of examples they can
start to say this is a problem and try
to direct policy and attention and enter
the international community to do
something about it so as we we learned
we looked at kind of the way and thought
about the way that kind of this term
crowdsourcing or just data is
influencing the transparency in response
the humanitarian space and we think
about it kind of like a data supply
chain this is this I think the best way
you have gathering of information so
that's kind of where or I think who
should he D as a tool excels we help
people gather information from all sorts
of different ways and then you analyze
it you compress it you think about the
you filter it you try to gain insight
and then you do something you respond
perhaps to that and and then you you or
you might visualize it you might try to
analyze trends and get into predictive
components so that's that was sort of
the trick chain we were seeing and the
way that we think about our tool and
fundamentally is trying to answer this
question of what happened when and where
you know what's happening on the ground
that's the problem that we're building
tools to help people solve and I and so
to dive a little deeper right what
happens is anyone pens in information it
gets processed you can then not only
crowdsource the information that's
coming in but you can also crowdsource
the filtering and understanding of that
information so everyone in this room
sitting at their you know I was called
armchair volunteer sitting all over the
world could begin to log into your
instance or whether it's your entire I
it perhaps it's your entire staff and
this table could be working on
translation and this table could be
working on just checking location and
that table could be doing first step
verification second step verification
right before it goes to goes out and
then you have your analysts over here
all right then so the tool
you to manage that workflow basically
ask the bait one of the big things that
we built up in the next version of your
shaheedi first was complex forms second
was managing workflow and so kind of one
of the most important things I think
when you're MIT when your crowdsourcing
information go to where the people are
don't build your own app you know that's
like really annoying people have to go
download your app that's obnoxious I
hate downloading apps I don't know about
you so we build in the ability to gather
to information via text message via
email web form this was sort of the
original nuanced abuse shaheedi go to
where the people are allow you to gather
a bunch of direct crowd-sourced
information as well as try to gain a
little bit of signal through the noise
so solving the problem of reading the
entire internet is pretty difficult
there are for-profit companies out there
that do it I think it's quite
challenging in the nonprofit space but
but you can still try to gain specific
insight by looking through our RSS feeds
hashtags specific api's that we then
allow you to filter through like if this
then that type statements so if this
hashtag has a specific word on it and
you know help and it comes from this
specific location during this time then
put it into this bucket of immediate
response and then you can I said you can
filter you can verify amongst your group
and then the outputs is you know one is
a map which looks really great on slides
but it's also you know you can send
alerts you can get a text message hey I
want to know if there's been a instance
of harassment rape or violence in my
neighborhood send me a text message
geofence that send me you can visualize
it you can begin to look at trends and
then you can export the data and put it
into other great tools for analysis that
are out there I so a couple of examples
of the new version I like this one this
is what they're going on an election
it's called vote like a boss and
remembers like vote or die what did I
boat like P Diddy this is like way
better vote like a boss so this is an
election monitoring campaign and I in in
Guyana that is currently operating you
can see the map there you can see it's
not
a little bit of the report section
another exam so it you can go in and and
you could start your own issue he d
instance in a matter of seconds today by
heading douchey he you know conceptually
right of shaheedi is is a software we're
not a place to come and Vic I want to
find it it's WordPress it's not Twitter
you know head there build your own tool
don't head there and say I want to find
that one report right that's that's a
little more challenging you want to find
that one blog post much harder to go to
wordpress or Squarespace we're building
tools for you to do great work one of my
favorite sayings of shaheed ease we are
not double-oh-seven we r q the folks
probably in this audience or the ones
out there doing all the great work on
the ground do being journalists being
working on transparency we're just
trying to make your job easier so you
are not alone we there are some great
the organization's big and small using
the tool one of my you know a couple of
my favorites quake map was a crisis
response to lynn used in the response to
the Nepal earthquake it was a great
deployment the basically communications
channels of the the government fell
apart they didn't really have it well
worked the Nepal Army basically said go
to quake matt oregan report if you need
help so the small group called Katmandu
living labs local organization who had
technical capability had put this
website up was gathering information and
then sending it out to the Nepal Army
for a response that was their their
situation room and I and it worked so
one example I love is you know you know
help medical assistance needed in
sukhani and soon drop the indole cotta
what 12 hours later the wounded were
airlifted by the Nepal Army you know
that's like a direct impact of someone's
being rescued and not I just love love
it when we find those those nuggets so
this is a great example of someone using
of shaheedi and then one of my favorite
that I actually again this is the pros
and Wonder and cons of wonderful open
source software was that I actually
found out recently that the UN
Department of field services the
peacekeeping missions the largest
standing army in the world this
sanctioned international peacekeeping
forces of our world their incident
reporting tool and situational awareness
tool platform is ed and has been for
years and we actually didn't even really
know that so it's probably the largest
impact that we make that we didn't know
about so again pros and cons of open
source but it's it's awesome because
they've been using it and they use it
across eight of their countries they
work in some of the hardest places you
can work Molly Somalia I DRC so it's
pretty powerful and they're using that
internally for their own staff to be
reporting on what's happening on the
ground again trying to figure out what's
happening on the ground so that's that's
kind of the story of shaheedi over the
last few years again we launched that
new version of the platform in October
we highly encourage you to go check it
out there is there's even there's gonna
be constant updates this year of new and
great stuff coming out so keep your eye
on it like like any product new feature
releases all the time new front end
we've been just doing constant UX study
so if anyone wants to help and loves
testing product and giving feedback to
nonprofit technology companies making
open source software come talk to me
we'll put you on the list we love
getting that that sort of help that's
how we that's how we keep going and I
you know I think just the other the last
kind of pieces we do a lot of stuff I've
talked about the platform it's our
biggest piece of work but but as a bunch
of technologists working in and came out
of Kenya you know one of the things that
I i always think rue is kind of powerful
about about our story is not just the
power of our users and the power of our
platform but for me it's the fact that I
am frankly a white American male working
in Silicon Valley in San Francisco
working for a Kenyan technology company
and that really couldn't have happened
five years ago I think that's pretty
awesome that that that's the case I'm
not like I didn't like I know I don't go
to Kenya to like work on a local crop
program and think that I know what's up
that's it's different this is a Kenyan
organization a nonprofit that has
reached the entire world and that
sometimes can be shocking for folks but
it's pretty powerful for us so we've
done a lot of stuff over the last eight
or nine years that works on everything
from technology and the in the space
that we're talking about to just trying
to build the ecosystem of in East Africa
as well so thank you very much and
really appreciate it great cheers