so I am - I mean for me I'm currently a
postdoc in the digital security group at
add value invest in the Netherlands and
this talk is some work that I've done
since the beginning of my postdoc so the
idea or the plan I had was to start with
the categorization system that we came
up with for side channel attack on
mobile devices and the Enmore part was
actually to present one of the cool
attack we did on one of the cool attacks
we did on Android phones so instead I'm
going to flip it in reverse and then
start with the end more part so the end
more part so the cool project that I am
referring to is something we did which
is looking into how to establish a
corporate channel using a USB charging
cable so some of you might already be
thinking oh yeah of course you can order
this transfer data for USB charging
cable but there is a surprise there so
how to establish a cover channel using
USB charging cable on mobile devices so
for this I would like to give you an
intuition and also motivate why we need
a new classification system for side
channel attacks on smart phones and
hopefully by the end of my talk I will
be able to convince you that this is
indeed the case so basically my talk is
outlined as follows the first part will
be presenting the attack and then the
second part I will move into
generalizing all side channel attacks on
mobile phones and present the new
categorization system alright so let's
start with part one so this is basically
a copy and paste of the title of the
paper which I thought was really cool
that there's no free charge there in
fact you can see it's a pun on no free
lunch theorem so you would understand in
a bit wide so essentially the idea is to
build a cover channel via USB cable on
mobile devices so the motivation before
I start with motivation I should
acknowledge this collaboration this was
a work
we're together with the people at
university of padova university of
washington and myself at harvard
university and the paper is online on
archive and will soon be published as
well as it has been accepted for
publication I show you the motivation I
think I do not need to convince you all
that there is an increasing use of
smartphones and this is also giving rise
to what we call battery draining apps so
absurd becoming more and more sciency
users are spending more and more time on
their phone as such they are quickly
running out of batteries the phones are
becoming very powerful and the flip side
of this is that they are also running
out of battery quickly so you've all
heard about the the one of the latest
craze which is Mongo where
people were just roaming around and
looking for those little Pokemon and
capturing them and fighting them and
this as a result was also making their
battery or draining that their batteries
on their smartphone so in fact what was
happening in the Netherlands on the
Dutch trains the people who were selling
teas and coffees were actually also
selling Powerbank
at that time because it was such a good
business that the new people would be
out of battery and we desperately want
to recharge their phones that they were
selling power banks at the time as well
on the Dutch trains so this also leads
to reflect from the previous speaker is
something called
normal phobia or I didn't know about
that term until recently so a few hours
ago so which means that you will not you
will not be able to use your mobile
phone and it's apparently a health
hazard as well so this was where we
started thinking okay so what happens
when this is the case of people will
eventually turn to free charging
stations so during my stroke I'm going
to interchange between public charging
stations charging stations for charging
stations I all mean those towers where
you can plug in your phone and there are
over
USB cables available so this is now now
it is a common sight at an airport you
can recharge your phone in airplanes
they have USB ports there you can do
that in shopping malls you can do that
in museums at the gym in your hotel room
you can charge your phone overnight so
it's pretty much everywhere nowadays and
it's also becoming this emergent
business model so wherever the money
flow that's where the business will
follow so in the u.s. it's quite popular
now it is to have these powers in shops
where people would go in the shops and
while they are browsing at articles or
products they would then just lock in
their phone into those little slots here
you can see if a slot is being used it
will be read so they are given a pin
code and then they will type the pin
code to open the little box here and
then take their phone out and then at
the very top here you have faithful
advertisements so not only you're
getting free power but other businesses
can advertise their products here as
well so I think this is something that
will also appear in Europe if it's
making money in the US it will
eventually find its way here as well so
we said all right what happens if those
towers are actually compromised because
we are nearly really just plugging in
our smart phones our devices into those
towers and then assuming our yeah
obviously a desperately needed of to
recharge my phone and that's when I'm
going to get from this so the question
that we asked ourselves with is it
possible to exfiltrate data from a
device while it is connected from a
public charging station and the answer
is yes so how did we do that so I will
start with our contributions before
giving more details about the attack so
in order to perform the data
exfiltration what we use is the power
feature of the USB charging cable so
irrespective of whether you cut the date
of things in the charging cable as long
as the phone has
going through it from the USB cables the
attack works so we showed that it is
possible to use power bursts to
exfiltrate data from the phone and then
pass it on to the public charging
station to do this we had to build a
proof-of-concept app which I'm going to
refer to as power snitch and how a
snitch
essentially communicate information in
form of power bursts from the phone to
the adversary so the adversary's in this
case is the public charging station and
then at the public charging station
slide we had to implement a decoder so
this decoder is sitting at on the
adversary's side and what it is
essentially doing is collecting all this
power traces and which will then be
decoded into binary information and
eventually into text okay so we have to
set up our attack so we're going to
assume a couple of things so here on the
adversary side so it's the energy supply
side we assume that that person or the
attacker has access to the power meter
so it has been tampered with and that
they are able to monitor and store
energy traces via the power meter and on
the victim side we assume that he or she
has installed the power snitch app so in
the previous talk there were already a
few pointers on how you can pirate to
provide piracy - for a packaged app so
you can do that for social engineering
nowadays if you go to museums they ask
you up if you do not want to pay for a
tool guide you can install our app and
then give yourself a tour via the app I
mean you can have all these kind of
scenarios where you've repackage the app
profile you target and then make sure
that you know what they need is out
there and it's in the form of that app
so that can be done through social
engineering so the features of power
snitch why the drive it will require
access to private data and it does not
rely on any traditional permission to
transmit data so key
once again we're not transmitting data
through Wi-Fi or Bluetooth so which
means we don't even need internet
permission or any form of special
permission for the attack to take place
and note that to have access to private
data it's not considered as being
malicious information flow because it's
legitimate to asks with a permission to
access the contacts again all in the
clear here so here's an overview of the
attack so on the left side you have the
victims phone on the right side you have
the decoders that's where the public
charging station is so essentially
what's happening here you have the
victims private information which is
being encoded by the power snitch app so
of course it already the phone is
already connected to the charging
station via a USB cable and been charged
in the background so here's our snitch
we'll then encourage the information
send it to the public charging station
it will be decoded and then retrieved on
the adversary side so in the next few
slides what I'm going to do is first
start with our switch apps explain how
it is built how it's designed and then
move on to the decorative slide and tell
you more about how the signal is the
power bricks are processed so I will
switch up so this is the app that we use
to establish the coverage channel so
here we refer to a cover channel as a
secret channel that can be used
exfiltrate data from Institute
environment in an undetected manner the
note here that I do have secured in
between quotes because this is all
happening in a secured environment so
it's not a malicious app it's legitimate
for it to talk to outside entities via
the USB cable so none of this will be
detected as malicious so this power
snitch app can be deployed as a
standalone app which means you will
install it as any other app
and permissions on the owner going to
raise any flag because they do not ask
for the app doesn't ask for unnecessary
permission or the it can be installed as
a library in a repackaged app as well
so how to provide a Howard Mitch with
stealth mode so how to make it go
undetected so basically it runs as a
background service so on your phone if
you really go in the lower layers you'll
see there are many services that are
running the background for example if
you have a weather app it's going to ask
for request for update for weather
update so that's an example of a service
that could be running in a background so
this will also be one of the services
that could be running in the background
so how do we make the data exfiltration
happen so to do that we use the wakelock
permission so again now the permission
that's going to reason if like to anyone
so we use the weight loss permission to
weight the CPU up if it goes into sleep
mode so usually they do that to prevent
your battery from being drained and then
once this kicks in then we start
transmitting the phone because usually
you would assume that if you plug your
phone in let's say is fit in a hotel
room you're going to go to sleep and
then you need to somehow reactivate the
phone to start the transfer of
information so this also works even if
you have authentication mechanism so for
example skin or you have to have a
pattern unlock pattern to unlock your
phone sir
now on that interfere with the data
exfiltration so the phone can be locked
the phone can be absolute and it will
still accelerate data and moreover we do
not use any conventional communication
to accelerate information even if the
phone is in airplane mode so you could
be flying your phone could be in
airplane mode again because we do not
use internet permission we don't use
Bluetooth or Wi-Fi sorry NFC
communication to transmit the data so
this should all work even in FM
so you are on the plane we can still
accelerate data from your phone and it
also as I mentioned before this piece of
the existing USB charging protection
dongle so there has been attacks showing
that if you plug in the USB you could
deploy a rootkit that we've done on iOS
platform and one way that Apple
responded to that was to always use the
trust don't trust mechanism when you
plug in your phone to your computer or
to a power source to make sure that okay
you give of already authorized charging
to take place or information transfer so
this has nothing to do here because we
need power you need power and we will
use that to accelerate data so more
in-depth description about the app so it
has three main components the pillared
encoder transmission controller burst
generator so yeah we have the payload so
whatever you want to expel trait gets
sent to the payload encoder and then the
payload encoder will then send it to the
transmission controllers the
transmission control is just there to do
a check okay is it alright to start
transmitting or not so essentially it's
running as a background service or
kicking the service the service will
start will stop the service it can be
optional because if you find yourself
being detected by another entity you can
go into stealth mode and you also want
to check the battery whether the cable
is plugged in or whether the screen is
on on or off as well so because we want
to make sure that this user doesn't get
overly suspicious if they are using the
phone while the detects alteration is
taking place so you can request for all
of these updates and then once we are
okay we can then start generating the
bursts so later on I'll show you more
graphics where you can really visualize
okay how different it is when a 0 and a
1 and a 1 are being transmitted and how
we can then decode the data at the other
side ok
so here I'm on the victims side he would
start the Android demon so this is like
another view of power snitch app and
another view into the power snitch app
so you encourage the private
informations into binary into one zero
so here it's up to how up to you how
creative you want to be the device you
can wait for device to be plugged to a
power source whether its food char do
not it's up to you you can wait for a
signal from the accomplice power source
to say okay yeah we're ready to start
receiving data about the acceleration
process and then you start data
transmission so here you can see when
the data is encoded so that you want in
zero and then what happens when you
generate the power burst you can really
see here that zero
there's no peak and one is a peak so
that's essentially how we physically
abuse ignore processing and power
analysis to do this attack and then from
time to time you're so moany check if
the USB cable is unplugged if it's not
unplugged you continue data transmission
or if data transmission is completed you
then go into stealth mode to stop the
service and then you go in the
background so at the decoder side so now
we're going to move to this side while
the decoder will do it we'll wait for
the device to be plugged in and then
again just because you want to make sure
that you're not overworking the power
charging station you will you can check
whether there's power switch app
installed on that device because you do
have access to the information and then
you can start recording the traces of
really the ones and zeros that will be
sent and then you can do two things
either
if the USB cable is unplugged many or
data transmission is finished you stop
on the other side you can decode the
energy traces to retrieve the private
data so the decoder design consists of
this group the decoder consists of these
components so you have to be encoded
burst
at the very top so this is what is sent
by power snitch then we're going to do
some signal processing so basically
filter data threshold estimation
detection to really see where the zeros
and ones are and then the rubbers
decoding and then you get the private
information out so I'm going to go
through each of those components to give
more description about what they are so
in the data filtering phase so
essentially the received cell signal is
going to be passed through a low-pass
filter to get rid of high frequency
noises so as we can assume on a phone
you have a lot of noise so it coming
from apps running on the phone itself or
whether there's other things that are
influencing with the power traces etc so
we do the data filtering to make sure
that we have a smooth signal to move on
to the next stage and then we apply a
threshold based detection to make sure
that we can get the peak easier so
anything that basically that will fall
below this range we will consider
anything below outside we will consider
as redundant so this threshold really
comes from trial and error so you have
to really study the the signal and see
okay how far you can put the low bar and
the high bar and then consider
everything in-between
so here you can see an example of the
rows received signal here and then what
happens when you apply the low pass
filter on it so you can see clearly
where the zeros are and when the ones
are happening so second and third
components the second one is the
threshold estimation and third one is
the peak detection so again here we're
looking for a present and absence of a
peak so anything that between the
threshold
whether it's no Pico high-low Pico high
peak we're going to convert it to a once
and zeros so yep this is what I've just
told otherwise we considered as noise so
we make a
just arrested and end transmission
preamble because otherwise you will not
know when did of exfiltration started
anywhere it ended so this is up to the
attacker to design how they will notify
the adversary's they okay this is the
start of the data that you need to
consider and that's where it ends so we
make use of that to indicate which Peaks
we need to consider while considering
decoding the data so some results you
have more details in the papers that I
will encourage you to take a look at it
but just to give you an idea of what we
recovered so we considered four devices
the Nexus 4 5 6 and Samsung s5 and here
we were transmitting payloads from the
device comprising of letters and numbers
it was a total of having 512 bits so
here we present the results in terms of
bit error rate so the lower the lower
the B are the better the quality of the
transmission so you can see here there
are a couple of zeros which means we
were able to recover the 512 bits
without any errors on the adversary side
so you might ask why are some of the
names numbers very high so we did
something that was very basic so there
were no fancy tricks no fancy signal
processing algorithm apply new error
correction this is this was just done to
show that it can be done but as you
refined further of course these large
numbers will decrease so and we also
suspect that the power meter that we
were using might have had noise in it as
well so that could be one of the some of
the reason why we think the numbers are
higher there so you can make our finish
more incognito so how to do that so
since we're dealing with a power here or
power burst we want to make sure that
the device doesn't get overheated so to
do this you keep the duty cycle under
50% so this will make sure that if the
attack takes place during battery charge
phase
the battery will take more time to
recharge if it has a high energy being
consumed by the CP user hence the user
might get suspicious as well so we want
to keep it all sort of written at a
normal flow and then excuse me
there is the Android debug bridge so
here it is possible for the phone or
someone to plug in the phone for to use
the phone in Android debug bridge mode
so 8gb mode and they will be able to
monitor the CPU power consumption the
change that we can get easily out of
this as well by making use of the
settings global it will be enabled on
the Android provided by the android
framework to make sure that we know that
ADB is is running or is activated now so
this was just one slice of the pie
essentially sir I'm sure or if you've
not heard of the other side channel
attacks that keep coming up randomly it
might have started all it ended started
in the early 2010 2009 where people
started exploiting the hardware and
software features on smartphones to
realize that you could get secret keys
for example crypto operation or
informations of private information out
of those boxes so what we realize is
that the side channel attacks so for
those who are not familiar with that
term it's little instruments essentially
attacks that exploit information leakage
from computing devices implementations
think of Krypton fermentations to infer
sensitive information that are stored on
the device so here i've picked i've
selected randomly a few work just to
give you a flavor of what's out there in
terms of side channel attacks so it
started back in 2010 so this with the
one of the very early works or the
people titles are quite self-explanatory
so if you do a quick Google search for
side channel attack on smartphone
these other results you will get so you
can see here that anything from
exporting sensor information to even
recently your Wi-Fi signal to retrieve
password use for banking applications
all of these are now possible using side
channel attack or via side channel
attacks it goes even further
nowadays people are all into wearable so
there has been work done to show you
that you can exploit your SmartWatch and
it can be used to infer keystroke to do
keystroke inference attack and recently
there was another paper published or a
few years ago in 2013 that studied the
crypto implementations in Android
applications and if I remember the
numbers correctly out of 11,000 apps
that were studied 88% had at least one I
have at least implemented crypto
incorrectly so I made at least one
mistake in the crypto implementations
now just think about this all these
devices all these apps are out there
being in use and they also give numbers
on how many number of downloads for
these apps they were able to find and
there has been a text shown that with
incorrect script implementations you can
do side channel to get keys out so the
landscape is changing so we need myself
together with a few people at tu class
we then thought about the problem is we
said okay there are people coming up
with all these attacks on mobile phones
but this no one has really defined this
new paradigm shift sir
sai channel studied for embedded system
on smart cards but now it's getting more
and more popular on smart for know if
you want to generalize it for smart
mobile devices but no one has really put
everything together and really
understand is there
any similarities where is the trend
going where are the holes what are
people going to come up with next so
this is what this paper is about so it's
essentially a servant that brings all
the side channel attack papers together
and really understand through this new
categorization system or what we
referred to here as classification a
systematic classification we really came
up with categories that show you okay
where the attacks are coming from how
the attackers are attacking and in what
space it is happening so at the end of
my talk I promise you you will have a
graphic that will show you the landscape
of sectional attack on smartphones and
of course the paper is available online
as well the traditional side channel
categorizations are twofold so you have
active versus passive and invasive
versus slim invasive and non-invasive so
this is what the categories that have
been used for embedded systems and smart
cards so what we mean by active and
passive so you have here your attacker
how extensively it's influencing the
behavior device so if it's actively
influencing it it's an active attack or
if it's passive laser only observing
leaking information so passive attack so
second one invasive same invasive and
non-invasive so yeah it really depends
to what extent you are interfering with
your deployed chip in this case so for
example removing the passivation layer
of the chip would be considered as
invasive the packaging only the chip is
same invading a few not manipulating the
chip at all it's not invasive so these
attacks required the attacker given
physical possession of the device but
nowadays before I jump to the smartphone
area directly there are a few steps and
those three steps are essentially smart
cards embedded system and the word
clouds in the middle before we move to
smartphone so this transition
we went through smartphone and by the
system it went to cloud environment
where we saw that there were more fewer
invasive attacks the most of it was
happening in the cloud for example cache
timing attacks or DRM or buffer attacks
through remote execution and then
eventually it went onto smartphone so
here we will see that more of the
recently published side-channel attacks
are mostly from passive attackers and we
would also stipulate strictly non
evasive ones as well so what are really
the causes for cycle attack to take
place on smartphone so here we have we
define what we call the five key
enablers so of course your smart phone
is always on you're carrying everywhere
businesses will allow you to bring your
devices to work so that's the whole BYOD
phenomenon it's very easy to install any
and every single app that you want and
it's based on a Linux kernel which was
not originally designed from the very
start to be a smartphone platform so it
has been transported from a desktop to a
smartphone platform and then most
important of all you have a plethora of
features and senses that commanders in
those boxes and governors what
information you can lick all over the
place so here what we found is
smartphones essentially vulnerable to if
not all attacks that are existent in the
smart card and cloud computing
environment and this is because mostly
enabled by the five key enablers that I
mentioned before so before I move on to
the categorization system that we
proposed I'm just going to fill in
another gap here which is to really show
you
to what extent smartphones is
overlapping with smart guard and cloud
side channel attacks so here only y-axis
we have what what is it attacking is it
the hardware or the software and then on
the x-axis how is it attacking it there
is it a physical presence or software
only of
so remote attacks and you can see the
grid in red is denote smart card the one
in green for cloud-based attack and blue
is essentially smartphone so we're going
to get we're going to zoom into that
figure later on to really show you what
the actual attacks are so through long
discussions we came up with three
categories again moving away from the
traditional side channel categorization
here we said okay let's look at it from
these three categories the passive
versus active physical versus logical
properties local versus vicinity versus
from your attackers can we through those
career categories really embody all the
attacks they're out there and also be
able to see what future attacks will be
like so here I'm going to really just go
over it quickly so all the details once
again are in the paper so vs. activist
is active that's the same as for the
traditional side Channel category the
physical versus logical properties
they're really here are we exploiting
hardware or software features so that's
the difference between the two local
vicinity and remote so here for local
attackers women are they in possession
of the device vicinity is it a
network-based attacks you could be
anywhere is dropping network
communication and remote attack it's
really software based execution on the
targeted device so we then came up with
this grid so essentially on here you
have the attacker so what kind of
attacker it is so here the side-channel
vector is it a physical property and/or
hardware property as are a physical
property or logic poverty and then here
we have for active and passive attacks
you can see these duplicates here and if
you plot all the attacks
sorry I'm not sure if you can really say
that properly but in the paper you will
have a good view of what the figure
looks like so the dogs in red are active
attacks the
in blue passive attacks and then you can
see here that we've incorporated the
grids again yes sir red attacks of
smartcard attacks in green ones or
cloud-based attacks so they're not all
all but it overlaps with the one front
side channel on mobile devices as well
and you can see here that there are
clear areas where a lot of attacks are
happening or taking place and this also
helps us to see that where the blanks
are and what we can foresee in the
future and by extension also come up
with countermeasures so with this I'm
going to conclude my talk and leave you
with this light to think about any
future research that could be done in
that area and I thank you for your
attention
[Applause]