the only other words which I'm missing
clothes and cybers and
for that and I did this work in
conjunction with two Bs and you guys so
he knows pretty much about it and yeah I
want to give you the short overview over
now what I'm going to present today it's
going to be about cryptocurrency
obviously and what to make
cryptocurrencies of so special what are
their features then we will go look a
little bit at Bitcoin why Bitcoin such a
good example of a very nice
cryptocurrency then we will focus on
alternative coins which are just some
Forks in most cases of the Bitcoin
source code and afterwards we will look
at grid point which is a very nice
scheme of an cryptocurrency which
introduced meaningful computations into
cryptocurrencies so I did many others
presentation on my own but all the
pictures are used yeah I mentioned in
the sources and the last slide so just
you know for me cryptocurrencies put in
simpler world is like a digital system
for Fayyad money and yeah if you're not
familiar with the term Pyatt money it
has nothing to do with automotive
company in eggs yeah it's actually the
current currency we use and it says some
similarities for me to cryptocurrencies
so for example it has no inherent value
so you cannot do anything with our
currency it's just paper which is based
which value is based on trust and it's
controlled by government it's a little
bit of in another point for
cryptocurrencies they are most
decentralized but one very important
part is you cannot go to you to the bank
with your currency and they just change
it to gold so that was possible in the
early years of the last century but not
for now so um that's what I think about
when I hear the word cryptocurrency so
and if you imagine cryptocurrency it's
only digital so there is no real
physical representation of
cryptocurrencies in our world you can
print it for example all the digital
information on paper for example then
you have the digital representation but
they are operating all in the internet
for example
like the names of this they heavily rely
on cryptography they use signatures for
example to create an authorized
transaction to verify this transaction
by a signature verification they use
heavily hash functions for creating
addresses for transaction and to create
proof of work and yeah we'll come to
that later
and what a very interesting part is they
are all decentralized okay so it's a
peer-to-peer network which are based on
it's placed in the internet and all
nodes are communicating together in
order to have the same view on the
blockchain and what also is the
difference they have a finite supply so
if you compare them to our currency yes
we have like 7 billion won euro coins in
Europe and by now and for Bitcoin it
will be more than 1 less than 21 million
bitcoins so the amount is kept as in
maximum and nearly all transactions in
cryptocurrencies Epsilon so there is no
link ability no real link ability
between transaction if you change your
public key and private key often but
there are also coins which introduce
zero knowledge proof into cryptocurrency
so you can use them which then they are
real enemies that's a very nice feature
but yeah maybe you want to know what we
can do it for what we can use this for
and yeah of course we can use it for
stitute a secure digital trading and
they had some features which are very
good in yeah good to use in the internet
so for example everybody of you probably
know the key leaks and if your support
for example for WikiLeaks you had two
possibilities prior to cryptocurrencies
that are credit cards or PayPal
and yeah PayPal and credit card
companies normally a place in the US and
when the u.s. decided ok you are not
allowed anymore to support the key leaks
and the only opportunity to use what to
support dglux was via cryptocurrencies
so they can be used for by everyone they
can be used in order to yeah go around
sender shipment and also frost resistant
and the next examples for froth
resistant low transaction so example
your citizen in some African country
with a high fraud grateful for credit
card for example and then you had also
have the possibility normally to use
this credit card / to online shop
decline subscribe because there were so
many song credit cards in in your
country for example and PayPal has a
very huge amount of transaction fees
they are related to your maximum amount
of transaction so that's also bad and
that's also another scenario where
cryptocurrencies can go into place and
be a replacement for all these yeah
older play mechanisms to pay online you
also can use cryptocurrency for security
for digital context but that's a very
special topic I won't go into deeper
view so maybe a little bit longer yeah
ok cryptocurrencies I promising
many things so maybe it's better to get
an example and there's a prominent
example is Bitcoin and the a
cryptocurrency started to be a research
or the first mechanisms for
cryptocurrencies are very old in
comparison to two big coil ok the first
proposal for untraceable six payments
for example goes back to 1983 from chums
untraceable signatures so in comparison
to Bitcoin is relatively old Bitcoin was
first proposed on the cryptography
mailing list in 2008 and year a few
months later in 2009 in January the
source code and the Bitcoin network went
online and everybody talks when it comes
to bid kind of bit about the trashy
Nakamoto which is maybe a person may be
a group nobody does really know that
sometimes every wildest someone who
claims to be so touching Nakamoto but
nobody had a real proof to to prove that
is really Satoshi Nakamoto
and it's also going to use soon for
trading after the release and here we
have one guy Lazlo in 2010 and he
offered 10,000 bitcoins
for pizza and that the two Pizza
theories he got
10,000 bitcoins and around this time it
was $41 so a reasonable amount for maybe
two pizzas in the United States and he
maybe looks other to this trading now
because Bitcoin prices reached a little
bit so maybe probably the most expensive
Bitcoin at Pitzer ever made yeah 11
million bucks for two pieces maybe a
little bit too high so maybe you wonder
how is it possible to get bitcoins okay
you're you're in your office or on the
market and you wonder how can I get
bitcoins to pay with them so there are
three possibilities for you to get them
first you can go to exchange places and
don't use empty box anymore but you can
use coin base for that and you can buy
bitcoins also by person so if you have a
friend who actually has bitcoins in his
wallet then you can determine some
amount of dollars or Euros or your
laptop whatever and pay with Bitcoin
with that and you also can use in major
cities ATMs so there are real Bitcoin
ATMs in major capitals where you can go
and pay the price and get a Bitcoin
transfer to your address so when we want
to use bitcoins we need actually to
transact them from one address to
another that's very important mechanism
in the Bitcoin world and I got a very
good example from Michael Newton's block
and there we try to you have to try to
imaginary how would you build such an
cryptocurrency okay and he does it the
following way
so imagine money is a bit string okay
and you want to transfer it from Alice
to Bob URL and you want to say okay Bob
I want to pay one Bitcoin for example
then you can do that for example also
and we have one problem it's a person
oversees this transaction she can just
deal the string change it so it's it's
not very secure in any way so what you
do you add a digital signature to it and
when you're sure when Ellis provides a
public keys
Bob can now see that the signature is
generated by Ellis so she has really the
intent to transfer one Bitcoin to Bob
but there's another problem when she
does it three or seven times or ten
times but maybe thing okay Ellis wanted
to transfer more than one Bitcoin to me
but when there would be serial numbers
in there then you would see that it's
not the case she just sent the whole
time the same Bitcoin to him and that's
the reason why we need serial numbers in
order to distinguish one Bitcoin from
another so now we have the intention
from Ellis sending Bob one Bitcoin we
have serial numbers we have signatures
that we have stood another problem and
that's how we can sure that these serial
numbers are unique and one solution for
that is we use the public ledger and the
public ledger is also known as
blockchain so what they do they collect
all transactions done in the whole
Bitcoin network in blocks and chain them
together okay we have here one block and
three transactions and one transaction
for example a transaction one was the
transaction from Ellis and they are
collected and chained together okay and
now we have maybe another example
another example of a problem here and
it's called double spending so here's
milori he has a Bitcoin account with 20
bitcoins in it and he wants to transfer
Alice and Bob the same amount of money
and also he wants to transfer the same
amount of money to a new created account
too so when we look from Alice and Bob's
perspective of in to the upper block
chain here we see that the transaction
11 it's a unspent transaction that's how
bitcoins you are old are called unspent
transaction and Alice and Bob see that
this transaction 11 belongs to Mallory
so they see okay if I get a transaction
from Mallory about 20 bitcoins then it's
a transaction Mallory was allowed to so
when he does is very fast so we are at
block I plus 2 and he now really fast
and transaction through Alice and to Bob
and to his own account then all parties
will think that these transaction were
legit and that's a problem about double
spending because then all this
transaction could be collected in one
block and everybody else thinks okay
that was alleged transaction and that's
called double spending so how could we
prevent it we use proof of work a group
of work is yeah one major reason why
there's so many energy consumption in
Bitcoin for example but I come to that
later so proof of work proof of work you
can imagine as a moderately hard
computational problem okay it's lots and
you can solve it but it's hard to solve
and if you have solution for such a
problem then you can append a block to
the chain and so the problem looks like
the following
you have transaction like before you
have some additional data and then you
have some ones and you want you created
hash about these input data and if
you're familiar with hashes you know
that the output of an unknown input is
very high to predict okay it's like
lottery and we have the in equation here
that these values the hash value must be
lower than the right hand side and this
right value is called the target okay
it's another representation of the
target but he has seven zeroes here and
then you have another string of bytes
here
and that's how proof of work is done and
if you if I give you the Genesis block
which was the first block ever get
generated you see that the amount of
zeros in front of the string is far more
lower than the number of zeros we have
in the current block so the number of
zeros always increasing making it harder
to produces a hash by using all the
strange actions and lance's in order to
create such a hash and that's the reason
why we have so many computers graphics
cards FPGAs is a basic trying so many
transactions so many hash calculations
per second so why would you do that yeah
we get reward for it so if we find a
solution for that we can depend in your
block and the block gets a sneer reward
and that's creating a race so but we
have another problem when we produces so
many hashes per second and we have a
computational network which broadcast a
new block into the network there could
be a situation where we have two blocks
at the same time so how is the how does
the network has a content about which
block to use next and the way that coin
solving this issue is called the longest
chain so always the longest chain wins
and here's the yeah blockchain in the
lower part so the upper part with the
transaction here withdraw or the erase
so the blockchain will continue to grow
with your soft fork here and also when
we have friends action you saw that one
block is not enough in order to say and
one transaction is confirmed so this
coin yeah they say if you have six
blocks in a row and the block I for
example with the transaction two and you
have five further blocks in here then
the transaction is believed to be
confirmed in the Bitcoin network that's
for for Bitcoin that's about 16 minutes
or one hour in order to confirm a
transaction
and the reason why we have the six
blocks correspond to the two attacks so
if you have an attacker for example
which has thirty thirty percent of the
hash rate of the network then he has a
probability to succeed an attack against
the network was fifteen percent and
always line has more than 50% of the
total hash rate in the network he wins
was more than one or he wins with one
hundred percent of success rate so the
overall security of Bitcoin network is
depending on the total number of
computations the honest user can compute
so I've mentioned mining and the reward
and let's come to that a little bit more
in detail mining when we get a new
client a new block again rates a new
block or Newsome's transaction called
coinbase transaction and currently every
user is allowed to generate himself or
generate but o claim twelve bitcoins
it started with fifteen bitcoins and
2009 and it's half the proximately every
four years what every 2,100 yet around
two hundred ten thousand blocks and yeah
it's done by first by computer classes
so that was the first approach to
generate so many hashes per second then
they used graphic card later they used
SPG Athens and a6 I can remember that I
told professor parvat I was able to mine
with my GPUs very many hashes in the
Bitcoin network and earn like 150 euros
at that time and he he probably thought
like oh really you got money from
computing hashes and he was very excited
about it I think maybe two hours later
many students have to program sha-256
and SPG a set day yeah I don't know
actually I never asked him but yeah
there's also a downside to to Bitcoin or
good point what we see here is as the
price
rate of bitcoins and starting July 2010
it goes to what is that March 2012 and
it started here round in September 10
with around zero dollars for one Bitcoin
that's the reason why 10,000 bitcoins
was worth $41 but then in July 2011 it
hit the price rate of $30 so everybody
feels like that yeah we can exchange it
for money and I also tell that way
because I traded my first account there
and then later in 2011 here's the let's
$30 okay so you you know where it's
going and there are thousand dollars so
in July 2014 it hit the price right form
of two one thousand three hundred US
dollar and everybody said like no like
changed or exchanged all my bitcoins at
time and everybody else who didn't
exchange in July two thousand elf eleven
I've had probably like this just
laughing because many many money so
Bitcoin has very very huge success in
the last year but it also has these
limitations and I want to talk about
that for a second as I told you before
developer responsible so there's there's
a source code public available and
Satoshi Nakamoto never did to work after
some 2010 i thing and then develop a
common place and they decided house
blockchain has to grow for example how
the block generations stand how the
number of transaction per block allowed
so they're regulating very very much and
what if you want to change your Bitcoin
protocol because you are not satisfied
with the current situation you want to
use the different hash algorithm or
whatever okay there many examples while
you could be set as not satisfied with
the current situation and your developer
so why should I not change all of that
because their source code is publicly
available
so let's modify it and that's the reason
why we have alternative coins
they're many years in the two points
which has nothing to do with bitcoins
because they just uses it concepts
behind it but many alternative coins
based or found in the internet based on
the Bitcoin source code so their
modified version and they differ in for
example the block creation rate in order
to confirm transaction faster than in
Bitcoin and Bitcoin every ten minutes a
new block is generated and the differ in
different coins
so also the number of no of point or the
number of transaction can be changed so
there are many possibilities for foreign
developer to create its own specific
alternative coins assessor raining
drawback as I said before race of
resources so we compute so many hashes
per second and what we do we waste
energy with it okay it's nothing else
because nobody sauce is hashes and
usually it's a database or something
like this it's just pure energy wasting
and we have here graphic I hope you can
see it on the left hand side it's this
away Nia the country Lithuania with
approximately three million citizens and
it's the whole yeah consumption of
energy and about eleven 11.5 care about
hours per year which is the total
Bitcoin network is consuming so Bitcoin
network consumes more energy than a
country a total country with three
million citizens so a huge amount and
also it's predicted that by through ha
yeah 2020 it will be consuming so much
energy like Denmark so also lots of it
there alternatives to proof of work and
I called a proof of stake or proof of
ownership or proof of activity activity
means here how activity how active you
are and the currency network of the
cryptocurrency but it's there may be a
possibility to use also computational
power behind Bitcoin network or other
cryptocurrency to for example site
cancer or to search for x-rays really
Intel
in radio signals or whatever anything
else but we're seeing it on chart 266
6556 computations so there are some
points which already try to use another
approach for that so one very
interesting examples both times which
use storage space as a proof-of-work
alternative there's also a very very
funny approach datas coin so you use
connections to TLS servers and you use a
I think the the record of method to use
and as an input for the hash computation
so it's an interesting concept to do
something meaningful maybe a bad
meaningful but anything is better than
just char computations and there's also
namecoin for distributed
denial-of-service they're distributed
DNS service DNS and so you saw your DNS
information in the blockchain everybody
can see where where your servers located
under which domain name and search grid
coin and grid coins using boring as in
third party application or system to
create meaningful computations and use
them in the the coin creation so grid
coin as I said before it's using boring
which is a middleware software in order
to delegate computation to to project
and we have spear coin which using a
combination of proof of stake which just
allow one computation per second per
coin your own for third transaction but
okay and it's try to come in combine
both systems together and it's active
developed being developed since 2013
it's on the list of the another top 100
here place 58 in the in the list and it
has a market capitalization of 4.7 nine
million euros so so lot less I would be
proud to have so much money but yeah
anyway it's n also eighty thousand lines
of code and no documentation like always
okay you want to search or analyze
something it's never has the
documentation
and we use the approach just static
analyzing the source code okay that's
also very funny if you never looked at
the Bitcoin source code and you look at
the grid current source code and you see
so much code and for example the whole
scripting language for allowing
transaction it's it's not that easy to
understand what the source code is three
until you realized okay that's just a
copy of the Bitcoin source code thank
you you know you don't have to look at
that okay so and it's still an open
problem how you can integrate meaningful
computations in the blockchain so
there's no situation where you can just
put requests for creating a solution for
one problem into the blockchain and then
everybody else will say okay we want to
do work on that and give you the
solution back and you can verify that
very very fast so that's not possible
that's the reason why great coin using
boring as in replacement for that so as
I said before blank is the software
system you if you are a volunteer you
can participate in a computational
project and do some chunks of work there
so here we have a graphic from state I
at home which is sent for searching for
extraterrestrial intelligence and radio
signals so far they don't didn't find
any signal of intelligence there but in
the elkay you can use it for protein
folding in order to fight cancer and
there are many many further examples for
materials searching or yeah stuff like
that which is done at the university so
boink was created in order to to give
research the computation power which
they don't have money for okay so that's
the reason why Bank was created so
researchers don't have to think about
funding for the hardware and so on yeah
finding fine numbers is also another
example and if you find the correct
solution for for a problem you got from
the server of the point
project then the volunteers gets a
reward it's an imaginary unit called
credits I don't know where the where
they have to stay from but ladies hours
so it's just imaginary it's
has no real value and it's there to
create competitions between all these
volunteers and everyone in here is
identified by a cross project ID so if
you are not participating to just one
project so for example slightly at home
or protein folding that's two different
project by two different owners and you
are identified over the project with
this cross project ID and say use the
real secure hashing algorithm which we
all know and the input is a random
number which is 32 bytes long and the
email address and the cross project ID
is a yeah resulting hash value and all
the credits and cross project ID
combinations are published on static
statistic websites online so we can look
a lot and grid console okay why not
transform the credit into real coins so
before we come to the more details about
how Bank was integrated into a grid coin
let's come a little bit more closer or
look a little bit more closer to
transaction for example we have the
transaction I here and Ellis got a
transaction from from another person
which is Jenson here and there's some
some input in the left hand side and the
Ellis public key and this is going into
a hash function and the resulting hash
is signed by Jensen who originally
authorized this transaction so Jensen
was previously owner of these coins and
now Alice has the possibility to
transfer this coin to another person
using her private key so if she wants to
transfer the money to another person
like Bob then she also used the whole
transaction here as an input for the
hash function also this together with
Bob's public key and sign the resulting
hash and then everybody knows okay what
is now on possession of this content as
a way how everybody can verify that the
transaction is legible so
that's the whole magic behind
transaction for the blockchain it's the
case if we collect all these
transactions but all blocks also have to
block header so all the block headers
are concatenated by the previous hash so
we use we venner generate the hash of
the previous block header including it
into the current block header and also
the current transaction here combined in
a compression function the compressing
function is just a hash tree which is
called makkal tree over all these
transaction so what you have to keep in
mind all these transactions are hash
together in order to create a hash which
is stored in the block head and if we
change anything here also the hash will
change be there and that's the way the
blockchain is working in a way it's
stored so now we come to the question
how can we add a blank work or bank
information Indian and the way grid
client does it they included another
transaction here the first transaction
and it's containing a buying string so
we have all the bank information of the
creator of the block in every every
block so now if we look closer it's a
boy string we see the cross project ID
we see a value cause recent average
credit which is just an average value of
the credits you created over the last
time yeah we have a project name so we
can only claim computational work for a
specific project every time and we have
a great core nervous GRC standing for
grid con and if you participate in blank
project you are called a researcher in
the grid con world okay so everybody
who's using grid con and doing point
work is a researcher so hey and if you
don to point back saying is just an
investor so why would you do ya boy work
in a normal life why not just be an
investor and the reason for that is that
the robot is increasing if you do boy
work enter the values
between zero and fifty so you can really
increase the amount of coins you
generate by just doing boring crack so
you're doing something meaningful and
also get paid for it so hey that's very
cool and obviously the amount of country
you get as an investor's far more lower
than you actually can get vyas bank
reward so how's the black generation is
done we have a project a here we have
two user John Doe and the random value
in here and the cross project that he is
generated and we have also some credits
one hundred thousand here and a recent
average credit which is just one hundred
you don't have to remember these values
it's just an example and a user is doing
a boring work for the projects or the
third party server and they doing point
work and then we have a statistic
website and the Cystic website is
crawling all this information just
across project IDs the credit
information rack and the bank project is
thought on the statistic server and now
we have the blockchain and the users
then happy to generate a new block so he
was able to generate a new block and he
creates this block by storing these
information in here and everybody else
who wants to verify this information
downloads the block when it's got
broadcasted and compared these values
with the statistic website okay this
very simple approach in order to verify
that this information which standing
there is correct but you have the
problem that you don't know it's the
creator of the block is really the
researcher with the cross project ID so
you could just copy the cross project ID
and all these public values from the
from the blockchain and generate your
own block and claims a reward so it's
possible to steal the robot from the
researcher and so how do you prove that
the - really a researcher a good
Constitution is called cross project ID
version - okay very interesting I'm for
that
and it's also stored in the in the bank
string in the transaction and we yeah
look closer to to that implementation
and now we come to house
right good quality and we did this by
looking at the source code and looking
very interesting from from a from a
analysing perspective so I get presented
now a little bit more easier to you so
for for just the reminder how cross
project idea is generated we have a
random value in the email address and as
an input to the verification function or
the creation function of the of the
cross project ID we have the last block
hash okay you keep the mind set as a
block chain and the last block hash is
one input value and the email address
and the random value is also an input to
an X function and the x function
produces across project ID version two
okay so a lot very complex formula here
and now let's take a look what the this
function actually does and again we have
the input values and the last block hash
is yeah again hash here with an md5
function and the email address and
random value are concatenated together
and then we get the first child
each of these resulting strings and they
are yeah edit each other and then a hex
value is appended to the cross project
ID version two so a very complex
function with high security standards
and afterwards all this process was
repeated so yeah they just doing here
some addition of char values and the hex
values appended so the function is a bit
more complex but you get what I want to
save you so that's the way the cross
project ID version 2 is generated so how
has somebody or other in the network
possible to use this function in order
to prove that somebody is a specific
research and what they using they're
using an epsilon for why function and
creating an md5 hash about the output of
the function and then they comparing it
to the cross project ID so and you don't
need to be a brainer in order to
understand what they are doing here they
just reverting what they did previously
so they just use changing the input
values to the output values and creating
the email address and the random value
here hashing all the together and look
if this is the cross-project ID so it's
just pure obfuscation so very very
interesting to use that in order to
prevent revolt stealing and a
cryptocurrency and us was the place we
had when we realize what they are doing
so it has the same security as a site
data and now what we can do first we can
steal all the email address ever used in
great coin which is pretty bad if you're
looking from a 5sp privacy aspect and
you also can still steal the revolt of
all users of all bank users in the grid
core network and we are talking here
about 5% of the total boring work is
done by a grid coin user so it's not a
huge amount but still in very important
value so now we know how to get money
actually and we are good researcher so
we try to very far verify our
assumptions and we did it by creating a
victim computer which participates in
safety at home by a point we implemented
an attacker based on the source code and
we were able to steal 72 4 grid coins
from our victims and here on the right
hand side you see the blocks by height
and for example here we were able to
steer 41 6 5 6 grid coin from our victim
and that's just for one person okay we
if you're doing that to whole network we
are able to increase our Arad heavily so
what did we do yeah first of all we we
thought about a fix you couldn't fix the
whole mess up with the privacy of the
email address so that's the email
addresses are gone and we thought about
a fix for for the second attack and we
did it by using a feature with grid coin
introduced but never used to do it so
it's some kind of special transaction so
like the boring part it's it's also a
transaction and called beacon and we use
this beacon in order to advertise a
public key which we tied to the cross
project ID so we won't want to get
signatures into claiming that we have
that we are especially researchers so in
order to mine some grid coins we need to
make advertise a public key by the
beacon all together with the cross
project ID and every time we want to
redeem a reward for for block creation
we need a signature for that so how does
the the beaten binding of the cross
project ID to a public key works first
we create a nonce which is a 128-bit
random number we create an input value
which is based on the hash of the cross
project ID here II before the cross
product is debug this cross project ID
and the public key and also concatenated
with the nonce we generated previously
and the reason why we need these hash
function here as yeah it's for for
hiding the real cross project ID so if
your if you see for example the
transaction which is big and in the
network you could try to generate a new
block faster and hold back the
transaction with the block containing
this transaction in order to use this
cross project that you pin your own
public key to it and then you would be
still be able to still revolt from this
yeah user with the cross project ID so
we've used it in a hash input so later
everybody else when there is a signature
with a corresponding secret key and the
public key to verify it
you always can say okay that's the cross
project ID I used in the hash algorithm
in order to obtain this type two values
together so that for the first people
but what is if you want to update your
your secret key and the public key then
it's the following way we chained all
these values again together we're
creating a new nonces original hash of
the cross project ID the new public user
loans and sign it with the previous
secret key so that's just an update
function
so we responsible disclose our findings
to the developer off-grid coin and
September last year and we supply paper
document with our findings and the fixes
and to click quickly gather response
from the developer and they try to first
test the fixes or the first approaches
or the fixes and yeah in November last
year and they built in some
countermeasures in version three five
eight zero as seven here in March 2017
and yeah we have still some problems
because that all countermeasures are
working so there's work in progress on
it and yeah we are on it so what we can
summarize of the whole presentation what
did we yeah looked at it we first looked
at cryptocurrencies we give a short
introduction into bitcoins how they are
working well so famous
we presented why there are alternative
coins what they have in common and we
also looked at grid con presented a
simple attack which was hard to find and
presented a very nice six for that and
we also hopefully learned something from
this presentation I just assumed that we
we now know that cryptocurrencies are
complex
we know that bitcoin is the real first
year so it was first cryptocurrency
which has so many features and comments
that it hit the community yeah very good
so it's also very good understood and we
saw why they are alternative coins why
it's interesting to create your own coin
and lots just using Bitcoin in order to
create some meaningful coins they're out
there and what you should know after
this presentation is that you never
trust one cryptocurrency you see out
there is it was not analyzed by you or
by guys you you understood especially if
you if you take the number of
alternative yeah cryptocurrencies into
account so there are more than 500
cryptocurrencies out there
one of them is Bitcoin Bitcoin is well
understood but what with the other
currencies okay the if you if you look
at the current market capitalization of
the whole yeah crypto currency markets
it's huge amount of money in their plate
here and people trusting that the
cryptocurrencies are so secure as
Bitcoin it's not the case okay like we
saw here that grid coin really ties
together things which shouldn't be tied
together so for further reading what
I've really found interesting there are
some very good blog polls they're also a
very good yeah systematization of
knowledge paper from privacy security
and privacy 2015 the bitcoin developer
reference and also very interesting
topic hijacking bitcoins via routing
attacks with security and privacy papers
this year it's very good to read about
it because the dressing yes the
vulnerability of the whole Bitcoin
network which is was never addressed
before or not really analyzed so that's
about all my yeah slides today I want to
specially thank you I and two Bs for
their help and all my colleagues at the
network and data security chair