so we thought let's do something where
the audience afterwards knows everything
from the start to the end about raw
hamburger Tex how to perform ro hammer
attacks and also what related work is
there so it's sort of a walkthrough
guide through a game or we thought of it
like an indie ro hammer the movie so my
name is Daniel goes and currently a PhD
student at University of Technology you
can reach me via Twitter or email and
and my name is Ken Monson Maurice I am
for talk at Curtin University of
Technology you can also join me on
Twitter or via email so I'll stand set
the goal of this talk is that you get
really a comprehensive overview of
rama's like because there have been a
lot of them in the past last few years
and also that you can run the tools on
your own machine and that's also
important see that you understand what's
happening and why it's happening so if
something doesn't work then you know
that nothing is black magic and maybe
you can configure something in that
works so we will start with a bit of
background on tyramine andrew hammer
also then explain you a step by step
first how can we flip it using remote
then how can we expect to beat flips and
how can we beam ticket rohan up before
concluding so it's starting with the
background okay so if we want to talk
about Roy him at first of course we have
to talk about how is DRM organized and
all of us know such a dear and module so
you see the chips there and these
different modules typically you have
multiple of them in your system and the
CPU operates them in separate channels
and these channels can operate
simultaneously so they work in parallel
so we can double the throughput of your
DRM with that also the DRAM modules have
much of multiple sites and these sides
are usually called ranks so here we have
two sides and we have rank 0 and rank 1
there are also dimmed with more ranks
but we won't go into detail here let's
look at a chip instead a chip is
subdivided into multiple banks and these
banks are then subdivided into multiple
rows each row is typically 8 kilobytes
and store
on these eight kilobytes of single bits
in physical DRAM cells to access one of
those rows we have to activate the row
and when we activate the row it is
copied to the row buffer and we will
look at that in detail so when the CPU
wants to access row warning which is
highlighted here in orange you can see
that the row first is activated and then
it is copied to the row buffer and then
the value from the row buffer is
returned to the processor so now the CPU
wants to access a different row for
instance the row two you can see it has
to switch the row so now in the row
buffer you can see this is the orange
content but it wants to fetch the green
content from row two
so row two is activated and with this it
is also copied to the row buffer this is
of course much slower than fetching
something which is already stored in the
row buffer so if the CPU wants to again
excess Row two we will just go through
this example then Row two is already in
row buffer and then it will be a
so-called Rohit so here we have the
difference between a row head and the
row conflict which is very much
comparable to a cache miss and the cache
it so here basically the row buffer
plays the role of a cache the theorem
says we have of course constraints from
the physical world so if you come from
software perspective you think of course
hardware is perfect and has no errors
and everything just works but in
practice these cells leak their charge
over time and therefore you have to
refresh the content of those cells
repetitively so you what you do is you
read the data from the DRM cells into
the DM row buffer and then you write the
same data back into the DRM cells and
with this step you refresh the content
that is in the DRM now this is a slow
step because while this happens you
cannot really access any other roles in
the DRM so you want to review
the number of refreshes to a minimum and
then the deer ddr4 and ddr3 standards
they define maximum interval between
refreshes to still guarantee data
integrity and the DRM manufacturers has
to build their cells in a way that they
can comply with this standard the cells
of course have more effect and one
effect we can exploit that in the so
called row hammer attack is that cells
leak faster upon proximity excesses so
if you access to neighboring cells the
surrounding cells will leak that charge
faster and then we might have a race
against the next refresh here where the
next refresh will be fast enough before
the cells lost their charge and with
that we come to the row hammer attack
the row hammer techs are motherboard
vice described it like it's like
breaking into an apartment by repeatedly
slamming a neighbor's door until the
vibrations open the door you were after
so it's exactly what we are doing here
so we want to change a bit in the middle
row that is colored in wife's between
the orange and green row and we activate
those two rows alternatingly and it's
they are always copied to the row buffer
and if we do that long enough we will
have beatrice in row two so this is how
it generally should work but activating
in drm role that is not a function that
we can just call so we have to see how
we can do that so in order to have these
bit flips
we have several requirements so first
memory accesses must must be uncashed
they have to really reach the theorem as
we don't have this effect on the theorem
we also need to have lots of them in a
very short time because this is really
race against the next pro profession we
need to have as many accesses between
two row refreshes and then they also
need to be quite targeted because we
need to reach these two specific rules
to have been the bit flips in in the
middle so the first question is how do
we get enough and cache accesses here
the CPU cache plays quite an important
force because this is between the CPU
core and the TM so if you
do this naive accesses then they will
all stay in the cache and they will
never reach the theorem so it will never
work
so only non cache accesses reach the
serum and you basically have two
strategies you have these non cache
accesses either you put data in the
cache and then you have to remove data
from the cache or you just don't put it
there in the first place so that the
next access will actually be served from
the DRAM and there are four different
access techniques that I'm going to go
through now so the first one was the
original brohamer paper by teammate Val
in 2014 and they use the CSS instruction
to remove the left on the cache then we
use cache addiction also a wicked use
cache addiction to remove data from the
cache and then in the fact that
basically that don't put it down in the
first place there are non simple
accesses by joe ada and also on cache
memory by santa rita metal so the first
technique is hammering with the CSS
instruction so basically as we said so
when you access data from the ceramic
goes into the cache so this is here in
green what you can do is call this
year's version instruction and what the
CEO search instruction is going to do it
is going to remove data from the cache
so it's not there anymore and we can
then reload data put it there in the
cache and so on so flash reload slash
reload slash reload until we have our
bit flips right in the middle in the
theorem so now this was done the
original study was done on video 3m they
also seek to see how widespread is this
issue so they tried 129 modules from
three different vendors and they
basically see that all but Reaver
we're vulnerable from modules that were
manufactured since mid 2011 also
sibilant alliant from google tried on 29
episodes and so the health wealth
Honorables but until then basically ddr4
was believed to be safe because it's a
different manufacturing process also
something those incorporated some
countermeasures in there but we actually
showed that if you still hammer in a
different way then you can still have
some widgets so the problem is really
not done
yep not solved so as I said basically
rahama you do flush reload / little /
reload and this is essentially a flush
and we load as I can flush and renewed
for the one that I'm not familiar with
it it's a cache attack so from our
perspective it's actually as much as I
can determine as it is one on the cache
so we basically thought okay we can
avoid this user instruction to be
independent of this specific instruction
since basically you have no 0
instruction in JavaScript for example so
our approach was to use regular memory
accesses to educate that from the cache
and not use this year's large
instruction and this is technique from
cache attacks
so basically we're doing we are going to
do row comma not with flushing remove
cache attack but with priming probe
cache attack so it works like this again
we have accepted a from the Jeremy goes
into a cache set and what we are going
to do now is that we are going to evict
these green lines by performing
different loss that goes into the same
cache set so we are progressively
filling this cache set until we have
evicted the data that we want it with it
then we can reload it again from the
DRAM and so on until we have our pieces
so it looks quite simple we just on a
series of different accessible it's
actually not that simple with you
because we have the replacement policy
of the CPU cache that plays an important
role here it says what is the next time
to be to be evicted to make room make
room for anyone and on modern CPUs is
not LRU so we actually had to find a
cache addiction strategies and in this
case it's actually better to perform
multiple access to the same address and
it is to better eviction so using this
we found really fast and effective
addiction strategy on as well that led
to an addiction pedals more than
ninety-nine point and ninety seven
percent but we actually wanted like with
the best one also the fastest and also
the best addiction rate so we evaluated
more than 10,000 different strategies to
find the best one and we managed to have
this hammering whiscash addiction on as
well so here you can see
you have the original attack so we see a
slosh in native environment amethyst
coat and then in green you have the
steel in native code but with addiction
so with no source instruction and what
you can see that we change the refresh
interval in them and basically is your
machine is vulnerable to the attack with
the sensors then is likely vulnerable to
the attack without filters because it
starts at the same refresh interval so
it's a bit less this flips but likely it
will still work now in JavaScript we
have a bit less be slips again and it
works with a bigger refresh interval but
still we manage will have quick tips and
actually the higher the interval then it
matters a bit less we have pretty much
as many bit clips as with the original
attack so itself technique is hammering
with non-temporal accesses so multiple
accesses as when you access data
basically just once and not in the
immediate future so there is no real
need to put it in the cache because we
just dictator that was actually
important and with it will have some
cache pollution so there are non temple
accesses instructions that basically
bypass the cache these non-temporal
stalls the problem is that when you
perform multiple source to one address
they are all combined in this right
combining versa and only the last right
goes to the gem so no matter how many
stalls you do to the same address you
will have only one right Indians so the
rate will not be sufficient so the trick
by Excel was actually to follow this
non-temporal store as we cache access to
the same address so basically it looks
like this you will have this different
axises for these two accesses to X&Y
with this small NCI so moving on
temporal and then it's followed by a
regular move that will put data into the
cache and then you have this loop so
it's just really this tiny loop and the
fourth different access technique is
hammering with and cache memory because
just sometimes everything fails any
first the case especially on mobile
devices every
this is all these three techniques all
state so in arm three seven the flush
instruction is privileged so it won't
work
cash addiction we drank a lot but it all
the time it's just too slow to have any
bit flips and on rd8 the non-temporal so
I actually seed cash in practice so
again no bit flips possible there but
since Android for that I am that is the
memory management and the app skin used
is interfaced if I am to have uncashed
and physically contiguous memory so it's
also not privileged and there is no
permission needed to access this
interface so this is what as I'm typing
in tile used to have this bit flips on
Android okay so the next question is how
do we target accesses how do we perform
accesses to specific drm rows now we
talked about accessing data that is not
in the cache but in the DRAM but now we
want to access specific locations in the
DRAM and we know that there is a fixed
map between physical addresses and DRM
cells but this mapping is undocumented
for Intel processors and it has been
reverse engineered by Mark C born in
2015 for one configuration of Sandy
Bridge laptops and we then went on from
there and we reverse engineer it for
many different configurations on Sandy
Bridge Ivy Bridge has with skylake
Broadwell also on arm CPUs and we
exploit the timing difference here
between a row hit and the row conflict
as you can probably imagine if we can
see a row conflict for two addresses for
an address pair then we know that they
must map to the same Bank but to a
different row so we know that they
actually go to the same chip and then we
can target addresses that go to the same
Bank but two different rows how do I
reverse my own given so there is this
drama repository that we have on github
you can just clone the code from there
and then you
run it with sudo because you need access
to the page map and then you give it
like 50 percent of your physical memory
and then you're looking for something
like maybe 16 sets on my machine I have
32 but I expect that it at least find 16
it's ok to put a smaller number there
and then once you have the functions
from this tool you will put these
functions into the row hammer ijs 2 we
have a native code tool in there and
then you just run make for instance
people for Ivybridge make IV or make row
hammer IV and then you run it again with
sudo for the Caged method need only need
sudo for the page map access because
that was Google's patch last year how
they prevented the attack on on current
systems and then - D - for 2 dims if you
have a different number of things you
have to put a different number there and
then you can optimize the attack speed a
bit by putting F 0 here which says I
only want to take 0 as the first offset
for every row that I want to hammer ok
let's see that in a demo I have prepared
something here the short video where run
list so I first go to the
reverse-engineering folder then I run
the measure tool I I use 50% of DRM the
more I use the better but actually
recording the video was not possible
with some allocating more DRM and so I'm
now generating all these sets so it
looks for sets of addresses that this
does not look very nice but it looks
four sets of addresses which have a row
conflict
the ones that have found 16 sets we were
it runs a simple algorithm to figure out
which is the minimum conflict set here
which must be the bits that lead to this
arm to this bank mapping to this
conflict now we will check whether the
same functions are already written in
the row here my source code and there we
can see okay 14 18 is the same 50 19 is
also the same 16 20 is the same 17 21 is
also the thing here's a small difference
I don't expect that it makes a
difference but still it's better to just
copy the value that we have just
recovered we could also add the big 6
here that would probably also improve
our results because that is what the
hardware just showed us the functions
that the hardware just told us that are
used so if I now run the row hammer tool
I have to again so at first called micro
hammer IV for my ID bridge system and
then I can run the row hammer tool but I
have to run it with sudo so that I have
access to the physical addresses
addresses
there are also attacks to recover
physical address information without
thorough access but for the sake of
simplicity here it is not implemented in
this way and now you have seen I didn't
have any big flips when I hammered a
single row but now I specified only one
offset per row and I have hundreds and
thousands of bit clips here so you can
see every all of the long lines here
that is if every time is one bit flip so
yeah this will continue like this
forever
so many many big strips ok let's go back
to the presentation so the next question
how do we exploit random bit clips
because this looks all very random you
have some did will slip somewhere
actually they are not random they are
not random at all
they are highly reproducible once you
hammer a memory location are there the
chance that you will slip a bit in the
same location as it were you've flipped
it before is extremely high so this is
very reproducible so what you can
do is you just say okay this is sort of
a set one bit to 0 gadget and I can use
that to set some memory allocation that
I usually couldn't write to set it to
zero and so what I do is I choose a data
structure where I can exploit such a
right one which gadget then I scan for
good bit eclipses in my memory and then
I place the data structure at that
location and then i trigger the bit flip
again and now there are several
different techniques to follow this
general attack strategy and I would say
this is a form of a post draw hammer
exploitation the first strategy that we
want to talk about is the one that was
presented by c1 and Julian to escape
from the Google NaCl sandbox and there
they exploited that x86 of course has a
variable length and sometimes unsafe of
codes that are not allowed by the
sandbox are contained in longer
multibyte of codes and this is not a
problem as long as you can only jump to
validators offset in the code but once
you have corrupted a jump you might be
able to jump to a non-aligned address
into an opcode and then use suit code of
code to escape from the sandbox so with
this they flipped a bit in a validated
NaCl instruction sequence and then they
had the capability of an arbitrary jump
and could do anything in the sandbox the
next group of attacks exploits page
table entries and probably some of you
already know page table entries so here
you have a present bit whether it's
valid readwrite grid user XO speed right
through untouchable reference dirty this
is the size bit the global bit and here
we have the execution disabled bit the
NX bit and then if you look so this is a
huge entry 64 bits some of these bits
are ignored if we have a bit flip there
the processor just doesn't care perfect
and then we have the physical page
number so chances are very high that we
get a
page number and also every four kilobyte
page table contains exactly 512 of such
entries so it scales in the same way how
are they used when we want to map our
virtual address space so here as a
virtual every space on the left and it's
directly goes to those page table
entries and these page table entries met
in some random way to the physical pages
that we have here and in this physical
memory we also have a carnal page here
the page table is also stored in
physical memory and that is all
neighboring in Indian not a problem so
far because you cannot access it right
but with if we have some way to
manipulate one of our own page table
entries let's say I can manipulate page
table entry 0 and I can modify the
address and say I want to have it mapped
to my own page table then I can modify
any of the page table entries on of this
page table so for instance now I could
modify page table entry 1 and scan
through the physical memory and search
for interesting pages like here at
wanted page this looks interesting let's
change it because we can now we have
kernel privileges if we have access to
our own page table we can access and
modify every physical memory location so
how do we do that now in a sec so we
start with the search for a bit flip
zone with hammer different locations and
once we have found a location where a
bit flips we will just release this
memory page and allocate pages that we
want to where we want to flip a bit so
here we have the green page which is the
target page a page table and here I have
the example again and now most of the
memory is filled with page tables but
there is still one user page here and
the kernel page here and this is my own
page table and what happens now is I
slip a bit the probability that I just
point the the page table entry points to
just some page table afterwards it's
very high because I filled the entire
physical memory or almost the entire
physical memory with
page tables so then I have access to one
of my own page tables and then I can run
the same exploitation technique as
before so the strategy here we scan
public slips we exhaust or massage
memory to place a page table at the
target location and then we flip the bit
and gain access to our own page table
and external privileges perfect so this
idea was originally mentioned by Seaborn
and Julian are they they proposed this
attack technique for their row hammer
attack but the same idea was also
applied in raw ham ideas in one bit
flops one cloud flops on Zen pvm and in
drama on Android so post row hammer
exploitation yet so this is all post
wrong name exploitation we are we are
talking about what do we do once we can
slip a bit and once we have access to
our own page table and there are many
things that we can do if we can scan and
modify the entire physical memory so
this is really fast scanning through the
entire physical memory you can modify
binary pages that are executed in root
privileges you can modify credential
structs you can read keys crypto keys
from the DRM you can corrupt RSA
signatures you can modify certificate or
configurations and scanning through the
entire memory and finding one specific
page sounds like a bit ok but you would
have false positives right no this is a
4 kilobyte page this is 32,000 bits this
is pretty unique if you find this 32,000
bits somewhere it's exactly what you are
looking for there is one case where we
might have multiple copies of pages in
the DRM and in this case we can we might
have paid to these applications to
eliminate those copies page to the
application so if we want to do a wrong
and I tagged with page the application
we again start with a bit flip in the
beginning and then we have a target page
here that we want to attack and now we
just produce the same predictable
content on our own modifiable page then
the operating system or hypervisor
searches for dublicate pages and
at some point it will compare those to
bring pages and will find it they are
equivalent and then it will deduct
locate the one page to the other and
then we just hammer again flip again and
we have our patria there
so the strategy here is we scan for flip
4-bit slips we place the content for
deduplication so that the flip can be
exploited and then we perform the big
change through row hammer and this idea
was presented by both man and in theirs
and P paper to change a data type in
JavaScript and then to change a pointer
to a good object to to a pointer to a
counter fide object that they injected
and then again in the work by Razavi a
tile they corrupted author at the
authorized keys file on linux so that
you could log in with manipulated our
RSA ssh keys and they also corrupted the
debian update URLs you know that they
are just sort in plain text and then you
have a bit flip there and then they
register the domain and then they also
flipped a bit in the public key file
factorize the key because we know it
because it's added applicated page they
can read it so they were able to slip in
malicious update there so the next
question would be how do we mitigate row
hammer yes because this is just all bad
right now right so different mitigation
have been proposed with different goals
and different expectations so first does
some mitigation set to detect rahama or
the sixth to prevent Rama there are some
that are done in software although in
Hardware also here it's like a hardware
program so it's not really easy to solve
so some solutions aim at finding a short
term solution even if we don't have the
good Jairam order try to find some more
long term solution to really fix the
problem so immediately after the
original paper and also after the Kouga
exploits then there were
hands for quick fixes what can we do
right now to fix the problem the first
idea was to stop using the CFS
instruction and this is actually what
Google did for the chrome sandbox the
thing is that quickly after we showed
that yes you can actually still do the
attacks even with the CF search
instruction so it's still not really
solve the other idea was to increase the
refresh rate the idea is that basically
the more you increase it the less you
are susceptible to hospitals because
then you have less time to perform Emery
accesses and you have been less disease
the thing is that commit I'll show that
at least for this death bed you would
need to increase by seven times this
refresh rate to eliminate all bit fields
and the implementation was not that high
because is also is a problem of power
consumption yeah and also it slows down
the theorem so it's not so good if you
included too high and the implementation
was that bio spindle did increase the
river fit by two times so you see it may
be good for some theorem but not for all
of them
most likely the other thing that people
were looking for is ECC so when you have
ECC protection normally the server can
handle or correct single bit errors so
it sounds like the solution actually
it's not really the solution because it
never has been done for this targeted
bit slips purchase for random pieces
also there is no real standard for event
reporting so not contained did a really
nice white paper and then try to compare
what will happens when we have this bit
flips on ECC theorem so the common
practice it does service counts the ECC
arrows and report them to the US only if
they reach a certain threshold which is
usually an again turismo standard so
that usually more than a hundred pixels
per hour so if you can see that you have
some margin to perform the attack
because not going to be instant
reporting is not going to be instant but
even more bad some several vendors just
never reported gyros to the US so
apparently is okay you can perform this
believes it's supposed to be protected
against this
corruption but it's not really because
the OS never sees this error and
actually then one server did not even
have when pics leaves where non
correctable so apparently servantis has
different expectation of what ECC
protection actually means here so then
next idea was okay if we can't really
have this week's exists then maybe we
can detect the effect that would be
better now than nothing and the thing is
that Rama it causes a lot of cache
misses and cache yes and that they all
can be monitored with hard work person
on campus and it was the original idea
of a Harrison fork at blackhat 2015 and
then we also did a follow up road work
Java type an and Piatt also did a full
web work and so this is all results on
different technique has been done so
either using the sort of threshold or
some kind of machine learning so we just
use the threshold on cache misses and
cache sheets that were normalized by
even from the instructions you'll be and
you can see that here you have all these
three benign applications of Firefox
some game and stress on the memory and
you can see that you can still have a
clear threshold with Russian middle
which is not icon the cache and also
rahama and that basically if you put a
threshold around here then you can
detect cache attacks and rahama with
that so in terms of ideas also commit
I'll add this bunch of maybe we can do
that but is probably not going to solve
anything
so in the original paper they said okay
we should also make better theorem ships
that are not vulnerable but problem of
happening using error correcting codes
which I've talked about that doesn't
rework increasing the refresh rate same
remapping or returning 40 cells after
manufacturing what happens is your old
gem is vulnerable and identifying common
rules at runtime and refreshing and
enables
which would need like really a lot of
it's really expensive in terms of
hardware so all the solution are not
really practical they're either
expensive cause huge performance
overhead or increased power consumption
which is something that move
they had another idea which is called
para for probability at the central
activation and the idea is that when one
row is closed then each time what
adjacent row is going to be opened but
with a very low probability and the idea
that Rosana we have one who that is open
and close but really high in number of
times so if you have this very low
probability for high number of times
then statistically the neighbor rows are
going to be refreshed and there is going
to be no big sister so the
implementation is at the memory control
level so this is not something that you
can just imprint implement on your own
but the advantage is that is completely
stasis there is no need for hardware
that counts which row is going to be
refreshed which we not expensive and
basically for this very low probability
and high number of hammer limbs the
probability of experiencing just one
error in one year is extremely low
this probability okay so for other
countermeasures in the DVR for standard
for instance there was a discussion
whether they would include a target row
refresh target row refresh is also a
very simple idea you have a count of row
and you increment the neighbor rows for
every excess that you perform and when
the refresh when the counter reaches a
threshold the row will be refreshed for
instance the middle one reaches the
threshold first and then the outer ones
also reach the threshold and then all of
them are refreshed over time so no bit
can flip again recently on the Linux
kernel mailing list
coby's suggested that that they could
include a no hammer kernel module and
the idea so we don't have any bits list
if we have eight times the refresh rate
right so the ideas to only allow one
eighth of the maximum of cache misses
and with that old also only one eighth
of the maximum number of drm excesses
and they would measure that using the
performance monitoring system of modern
interest views which is also maybe not
the
idea to do to do that but let's go for
it so if we now hammer one memory
location in one bank then the no hemic
random module would not if I would
notice that and would then notify the
current that it has to hide the
execution because the threshold was
reached so we wait for the Refresh for
the rest of the 64 milliseconds so this
is good if we have a case like here
where we hammer the where we hammer in
memory location but it's bad if we have
a case like this one where we access
different memory locations and then
again we reach the number of cache
misses and then we have to cause the
system again for the next sixty four
milliseconds interline a different
approach is to just attack a stop the
attacks before they actually happen so
we do static analyzes on binaries so
before they are shipped to the customers
we detect suspicious instruction
sequences see as large our DTC sensors
but here the problem is like row
hemorrhages can just perform a sequence
of memory accesses to perform this
attack so mass head also tries to cover
that by detecting weird memory access
patterns one problem here these weird
memory access patterns could also come
from perfectly benign memory loads like
computer games so we have the problem of
false positives and you probably all
know if there are many false positives
in any system you're probably stopping
to use it like a virus scanner that
alerts you with false positives ten
times per day you wouldn't use it though
let's go for the next one and will
anybody was suggested by a vachetta
and they also want to use the
performance culture to first detect row
hammer and then they activate the
neighbor rows to prevent bit clips but
they only do that after they detected
that an attack is ongoing so it's
similar
TRR but it's in software so here we have
our two locations and the red ones are
in danger of flipping a bit so we
refresh them and then the
are finding in more recently there was
the catch paper which presents several
nice ideas the first is the d cat
variant which disables vulnerable
physical memory in the bootloader so I
will come to that in a minute
first G cat this is the one that works
at runtime and here the ideas that we
isolate security domains in physical
memory based on the potential
vulnerability so here in G cat you can
see that I have a blue of green and
yellow page so different security
domains so if I want to have these
different security domains in my systems
I have to isolate them so I have to
leave a gap there so because I would
just use able the vulnerable memory
locations but as you have seen just
before in a live demo if I would run B
cat on my system I probably would have
one megabyte of RAM left that is not
vulnerable out of the 16 gigabytes so
what is the conclusion to this roja
attacks are incredibly easy to mount you
can all do that you just clone the tools
from github and of you go with the bit
clicks so the text work on most systems
on the fact that we are not sure whether
they work on some specific systems like
we thought they don't work on ddr4 or
there are still many laptops where we
couldn't have a bit clip yet the problem
here is that we might not just know the
right D Ram mapping functions if we use
the wrong dear I'm mapping functions we
did that on ddr4 at first we hammer at a
ddr4 system for several weeks non-stop
and no richlip not a single bit then we
reverse engineered the functions and we
had the first bits live after 12 seconds
so this is really essentially to use the
right function as you won't see a big
hit on your system but if you use them
then it's not a problem it's easy to do
and then we have the problem of the
countermeasures most of them are just
too expensive or ineffective and you
don't want to deploy any countermeasure
and then
you're out a month later that yeah it
really does nothing as suspected okay so
if you want to tried it I hope you all
got an appetite for trying this on your
own now and here we have the link so the
drama repository you should start with
that reverse engineer your DRM figure
out what the functions are then put the
functions into row hemorrhages and run
the native to the double-sided hammering
to it and have some big flips on your
system you can also try it on arm so we
have the lips flush which provides you
with eviction strategies and ways to
call slash instructions on arm platforms
so this is this is a platform
independent way of doing slash and
reload or eviction reloads and also the
DRM I repository by the you set this is
also a very nice start if you want to do
hammering with Ione on arm so thank you
for your attention if you want to get in
touch with us you can do that via
Twitter or via email and thank you for
your attention
[Applause]