hello everyone
the purpose of this talk is to provide
people especially penetration testers an
overview of
what a blockchain is how we can look at
it from a security perspective
what kind of tools are available to
conduct engagements
and overall get a general understanding
of this new technology that no doubt
will be a major uh
player in our field over the coming
years
first off let's begin by discussing what
a blockchain is
in terms of definition a blockchain is
quite simply a database
and you can think of it much like how
you thought of it
in your previous engagement in your web
engagement especially when you were
faced with a web application that had a
back end
of mysql or ms sql or oracle
a lot of applications that are built on
top of the blockchains
are much like that they're usually a web
interface
with a backend database that's built on
top of the blockchain so the blockchain
itself is simply
a database but it's format the way it
operates it's slightly different
in terms of features databases have
features that are different from what
traditional databases offer which i will
describe
in detail so with traditional databases
like the mssql mysql
oracle everything was it was and still
is centralized
meaning that there is a server somewhere
and that server
is hosted by the company that needs the
database to
operate for them or that server is
somewhere on
a remote data center somewhere but
it's still owned and operated by the
company that owns it
with a blockchain based database uh the
the game is shifted what we see
is a a database that is hosted by
multiple parties which are usually
untrusted so they don't really know each
other they have no
particular relationship with each other
they they just want to operate the
blockchain they just want to operate the
database
so what happens is each one of those
parties will grab
a copy of the database and help each
other maintain the latest
state of that database and in the
process they get rewarded
now with traditional databases we have
a permissioned way of approaching
objects meaning that uh if you were to
read or want to read something from the
database you need to have some sort of
permission you have to have maybe read
permission write permission
in order to do anything on the on the
databases
that are traditional however with
blockchain-based databases everything is
permissionless
what does that mean means that anyone at
any moment in time
with public blockchains can go and read
everything on the database
every single piece of information on the
blockchain especially public blockchains
are public i say public blockchains
because some blockchains are private
you know you can you can have a group of
people that would operate
a private blockchain and
they can try to keep this information
private but but
most of the industry right now is is
full of public
blockchains so just keep in mind that
with
blockchains people can read all the
information there's no need for you to
have any permission at all
you can just go to to blockchain
reader services and just read any
particular transaction or information
and finally with traditional databases
administrators can modify
records let's say you accidentally
put some incorrect record on the
database you can contact the
administrator of your organization and
ask them to remove their
code or change it or modify it with a
blockchain database that is simply
cannot be done you you really
cannot change anything whatsoever once
you do it once you write something to
the blockchain it's there forever
and that's basically the difference
between traditional databases
and blockchain-based databases
traditional databases have their use
and they will not go away but blockchain
databases
uh add a new use case allow for a new
form of application slash uh
protocol to be built on the internet
that previously wasn't possible
so that brings us quite nicely to
bitcoin and and what is bitcoin and
and how can we use it for our own uh
benefits and
an understanding of what blockchain is
so
bitcoin is basically a peer-to-peer cash
uh a currency that is uh
that has been built on top of the
blockchain uh it's basically uh
an app think of it like an app that's
been built on top of the blockchain
and you are able to as an individual
to transact this currency between
yourself and a bunch of other people
there's no bank that's operating yet a
group of untrusted individual and people
that don't know each other
are operating the bitcoin network and uh
using the
blockchain technology they keep it up to
date
and and they do the transactions but in
the process every time
the people who are operating the network
make a transaction happen
and they earn a small amount of fee and
that's how the network keeps running
that's how we can continue using bitcoin
without the need of any
central government slash company
in terms of features as i mentioned it's
decentralized there is no organization
that that operates bitcoin it's a group
of
people that don't know each other but
they have found
a cryptographic way to confirm
transactions are happening without being
forged so so so they can trust each
other and
and transact in that way everything on
the bitcoin
uh blockchain is public meaning that
everyone can read every single
transaction
and everything is immutable meaning that
if i had one bitcoin i cannot send it to
two people
and this is only possible because of the
blockchain technology
with blockchain technology um you cannot
duplicate your bitcoin and send it to
people at the same time it's
cryptographically impossible
so so so that's basically uh bitcoin is
a product of the blockchain
you just keep that in mind it wasn't
possible in the old traditional
databases but it is possible
and this is one of the many things that
could be built on top of the blockchain
now bitcoin has limitations think speed
think scripting capability what does
that mean
so um once you uh uh
use bitcoin you'll notice that it is
slow meaning that if i was to send you a
bitcoin right now
it will take you probably 30 minutes
sometimes it's early sometimes it's
slightly later but on average 30 minutes
before
you you you get a confirmation that yes
it has been received in your wallet and
you have received the bitcoin
that's a problem because if you want to
build something on top of the bitcoin
blockchain um it will it will take quite
a while for it to actually propagate and
finish
so uh so that's quite limiting and
there's also a problem with scripting
capability
meaning that if you wanted to utilize
the existing network of bitcoin
operators the existing bitcoin
blockchain and build on top of that
instead of
rolling your own blockchain and then
finding people to operate it and slowly
grow just build on top of
bitcoin instead if you want to do that
the scripting capabilities of bitcoin
are very limited
so your your hands are quite tight over
there so
um what was the solution to this problem
the solution was something called
ethereum
ethereum um was proposed by a gentleman
by the name of uh by sally butter and
back in 2014
his his proposal was uh this uh
cryptocurrency is incredible
the the uh bitcoin cryptocurrency and
and
you know what we can do we can use it
expand it
and and and make it even better uh so
how about
we we increase its speed how about we
make a lot of modifications to it
and and he he wrote an extensive
proposition and presented it to bitcoin
developers and
at the time bitcoin developers passed
saying that these are
what vitalik was proposing were major
changes to what the bitcoin
ideals were so they passed on those uh
proposals
and that's how ethereum was born
as i mentioned ethereum is an open
source blockchain everyone and anyone
can build on top of the ethereum
blockchain and um in order for you to
build on top of the ethereum blockchain
uh what you need is is something called
ether
if there is the cryptocurrency use to
perform any actions on top of the
ethereum blockchain
much like the bitcoin uh sort of system
and blockchain
it's decentralized it's public and it's
immutable so
um a large number of people across the
globe
are operating this blockchain network
everybody can read every transaction
and nothing can be changed or forged on
the ethereum
blockchain now in terms of limitations
there are two problems with the ethereum
blockchain one is
gas fees and the other is speed now you
might be asking what is a gas fee
if i wanted to perform a transaction on
the ethereum blockchain
uh let's say i wanted to send some
ethereum from point a to point b
there there are some fees and those fees
are called gas fees
and and those fees will will incur
uh regardless of what the price of
ethereum is if they are mandatory for
every transaction
and if you were to think of them they
are denominated in
in ethereum so if the price of ethereum
goes to 10k or 20k
that fee is fixed so you will still be
uh in terms of ether you will be paying
the same amount
but in dollar value your the fee could
be much higher or much lower depending
on the price of ethereum that day
and that presents some problems because
if you were to build on top of the
ethereum blockchain
then and and your application would need
to perform some transactions maybe move
ethereum from point a to point b for
whatever reason
uh the fee that you or your users should
pay
increases drastically depending or the
accuracy decreases drastically depending
on
what the what the price of e3 is that
day
now um another famous uh
keyword you hear in this industry is
dapps what are gaps
and and i think this diagram really
explains it quite simply
dapps are decentralized applications any
application
that has been built on top of a
blockchain based database
is called adap and and that's all that
it is you hear it being thrown around
all the time
and uh really the easiest way to think
about it is this an application on top
of the blockchain
now as penetration testers uh what we
will be faced with when
we are hopefully in the future or in the
near future
will be doing uh blockchain based
security orders is that
people will provide us a web interface a
web page
and with that on that web page there
will be a login mechanism you would go
and test a
blog in mechanism and you would log in
and then what you presented was quite
simply a
web application initially that that
could suffer from
all the typical issues that a normal
application suffers from
so um if you are going to conduct that
engagement
for the first part of it you would have
to just use the normal os methodology on
the web interface to see what you could
find
and then report on those however with
blockchain security audits there is a
second part to this puzzle
and that's actually doing the code
review
every single
logic that has been written is written
or in in a language called solidity on
ethereum
now with solidity the language is much
similar to javascript
if you have done javascript before in
the past
it would be easier for you to pick up
solidity
and you can use solidity to create the
logic necessary
to do all the operations needed on a
blockchain database
which in this case with solidity it's
ethereum so
with every engagements you get two parts
one is doing the web interface with the
west methodology and the other is
learning solidity
and then trying to pick up common code
patterns that
are bad and and point them to the
developers
uh with the white box engagements and
and to learn what are common bad
practices uh people in the ethereum
community have put in a fantastic
registry of classifications in place on
a website
that you see on the screen swc registry
dot io
on this swc registry dot io you will see
a page
that presents 36 different
classifications
of different types of bugs and and how
you can look for them
how you can fix them what is the
implications of each one
so hopefully once you learn solidity
your next step should be to
browse this page and pick up what are
the
important skills necessary in order to
understand
what code could be vulnerable and then
report it accordingly
now i wanted to walk you through how the
code looks like and then give you a
couple of examples
and show you how simple it is really to
understand the language
and then what kind of bugs could be
found and how bad or good
uh well how bad they can be really so
um what you see in this page is uh
the most basic solidity code you would
see out there
and the first line is just a compiler
version uh you're basically telling the
compiler which version to use to compile
your code
and then every single uh
application that's been built on uh
ethereum at least it starts with the
line contract
what you see here is the name of the
contract afterwards so it's contract
hello world
that's on line three that's just the
contract name and then on line four we
just define
a string variable and we give it a value
of hello world
that's that's all that it is and once
you compile it and then call the
greets variable you will see the hello
world being printed
that's all that it is really now i want
to give you
a sample vulnerable code
if you have done any sort of
white box testing of code before i'm
sure you're very familiar
with overflows and underflows
meaning that if a value
goes over a certain threshold it it goes
back
to its original
value instead so in order to give you an
example what you see on this
on this page is this is a contract
called withdrawal if you look at line
number two
contract withdrawal that's just a
contract name on line number three
we have an unsigned integer that is
for the balance variable so the balance
variable
uh has been or has a type of unsigned
integer eight
meaning that the maximum value it could
have
is 255 so
um the problem here is that
if someone was able to increase their
their balance
to more than 255 suddenly their
their balance changes to one because it
rolls over the variable unsigned integer
it rolls over
once it hits its maximum value back to
one and another way to exploit this
issue is if someone was able to
withdraw a sum more than their balance
make sure the variable goes back to its
max value
then they can abuse it that way as well
and this is the issue that you see on
the screen so on line 4
function withdraw unsigned integer 8 sum
so what you see here is there's a
function that is uh
for withdrawing and the the sum variable
is of the type inside integer eight the
sum is controlled by
uh any user so uh what they can do
is they can provide a number for example
uh
two here or three and uh in the next
line on line five
the balance the sum is subtracted from
the balance
so number three is subtracted from one
which is the balance
and uh because the variable has a
maximum value of 255 so it's
one to 255 and when you do the
subtraction
it goes back all the way up to the
maximum value
and you artificially increase the value
of your balance
because of this underflow issue
another issue and other vulnerability
within
solidity is what you see on the screen
um
the answer is really inside the note
that i provided at the top
so in solidity you can create functions
and you can set functions to be public
or private
and if you forget to properly secure
them anyone can call them later
what you see now is the code itself so
you see
uh progmo solidity 0.4.24 that's the
compiler version
the next line is contract identity
crisis that's a contract name
the next line afterwards is address
public owner it's just a variable of the
type address
that holds the address of the owner and
then we have a function
called set wallet owner and it takes any
address that the user provides and is
set to
public uh and and this is exactly where
the problem is
if you create a function and you set it
to public and you forget to secure it
with other means that solidity provides
people can later call it again make
themselves
the owner and then take over the
contract
and and become the owner and then
probably withdraw
its balance if it has any balance this
exact issue was the source of multiple
exploits as a recent where people
created some sort of function that would
do something
incredibly sensitive but they forget to
set it or protect it properly
and that caused all sorts of issues
and that's really how to how to look at
solidity as as you can see it's a very
in my opinion if you know javascript
it's a very simple language to read
you just have to have the patience to go
over it
once you do the web interface checks you
just get access to the code
go over the code but you have to also
understand what to look for so the swc
registry
is the best way to approach this now in
terms of
tools there are two excellent tools out
there one is slither
is the one i use all the time and
slither is a free tool
and what you do is you just point it to
some
some piece of code that that you have
received from the client
and you let it run it gives you an
incredible number of
uh results however a lot of them can be
false positive so it's up to you as the
reviewer
to go through the results use slither as
as a starting point
to to understand okay there might be an
issue on point a or point b
maybe i should start looking there and
then and then sort of start filtering
down
what is valid and what is invalid and
then take it from there mythics is also
another
good service it's it's paid however but
it's also another good service that does
reviewing of uh solidity code as well
and with that thank you very much