hi
i'm josephine winslows and today i'm
going to teach you how you can save
lives with a smartphone
pretty ambitious but if you stick with
me i'll walk you through it step by step
my background is in building medical
devices and medical device software
in my free time i'm trying to teach
myself cyber security
one of the very first things that i
learned and something that you guys
are probably more familiar with than i
am is that the first step in finding
a solution is understanding the threat
so what's the threat here what are we
saving lives
from neonatal jaundice
this is a medical term with two main
parts neonatal
meaning affecting infants or newborn
babies and
jaundice jaundice is a term used to
describe a yellowing of the skin
and the sclera that's the whites of the
eyes it's caused by a buildup of
bilirubin which is a yellow orange bile
pigment
produced when your body gets rid of red
blood cells
now usually bilirubin is not a big deal
it's
filtered out from your body like any
other waste product it's when this
delicate balance is disrupted that
issues start to arise
there are a couple of different ways
this can happen but the important thing
is that as bilirubin builds up in your
bloodstream it causes
abdominal pain fever weakness fatigue
and at really high levels it can pass
through the blood brain barrier
causing permanent disability or death
this is a massive issue and
it's a global health crisis neonatal
jaundice affects up to eighty percent of
premature births and up to sixty percent
of full
term births it can be fatal and
although it's difficult to prevent it
is quite easy to cure if it's diagnosed
early enough
in less severe cases it can be treated
with exposure to uv
light which is phototherapy and oxygen
and in more severe cases an exchange
transfusion can be used
if it can be treated then why is it
still causing 114
000 infant deaths every year to
understand this we have to look at where
those deaths are happening
three-quarters of them occur in
sub-saharan africa
and south asia and there's a number of
different reasons which contribute to
this
including an increased likelihood of
certain genetic risk factors
like a g6pd deficiency and a lack of
access to healthcare
that the leading cause is the difficulty
of diagnosing jaundice
using traditional methods like visual
inspection in infants with darker skin
tones
it's just much more difficult to detect
a yellowing of the skin
in infants with a darker skin tone and
that's the current standard practice
the need for a reliable low-cost
screening solution
which is accurate regardless of skin
tone is clear
so what are our options in the uk
an infant who is suspected of having
neonatal jaundice
can be given a blood test to determine
the exact levels of bilirubin in their
bloodstream
this is the gold standard diagnostic
technique and
although it's very accurate it's simply
not a feasible option for
many infants in countries where there's
difficulty in accessing
the expensive and bulky medical
equipment that's needed to perform this
kind of testing
it is also an invasive procedure which
can be really difficult for parents of
newborns
as it involves drawing blood the other
methods i've already talked about
looking at the skin tone and the sclera
that's marked on this image the white of
the eye
what we need is a solution that is
non-invasive
and cost-effective a method that's being
tried in the uk is color imagery
that's using these big expensive pieces
of equipment i call colorimetry machines
they measure the color of a surface by
looking at the rate of absorption
of different wavelengths of light i got
to play with some of these in my second
year of university and i got involved in
a project
which was looking at recreating this
effect using dslr cameras
you take a picture with the camera
export it to a computer and then use a
programmer in matlab to do analysis
i was debating back and forth with my
professor and i said
surely this could all be done on a
smartphone and he said
no that's impossible so of course i did
what
anyone else would have done and i spent
the next three years of my life proving
him wrong
we designed an app a smartphone app
which would allow us to complete this
colorimetry procedure
luckily this was possible thanks to the
rapid advance in technology over the
last few years
not only in the sensitivity of
smartphone cameras but also in the
processing power that it requires to
perform analysis like this
we created an app that uses two images
of the whites of the eye to screen for
neonatal jaundice
two things to focus on here firstly the
whites of the eye that's because this is
a pretty consistent color
across infants of all skin tones and
secondly
two images we use a flash and none flash
pair
this is basically done to remove ambient
lighting from the equation
when you take an image with flash and
then an image with no flash you can
subtract one from the other
and are left with a composite image
which only takes into account the light
that was emitted from the flash
excluding all ambient lighting which is
important because yellow light makes the
image look more yellow
and blue light does the same for blue
and we want
a really accurate reading of what the
actual color of the eye
is it's really important for an accurate
diagnosis
quick moment to shout out the
organizations that supported me
in this project it was a collaborative
effort
across all of these organizations and
these charities who are really really
fantastic in supplying financial
support to the organizations that have
assisted
in the saving lives of birth project
i started this app with a proof of
concept that i built over at two months
in the summer of my second year of
university
it was really ambitious i built a very
customizable app
which was designed to be adaptable to
the needs of the user
once i'd proved it i had to go back to
the drawing board
i spoke to these wonderful wonderful
doctors dr
christophel and dr judith who are both
paediatric consultants
dr crystal in akron hospital in ghana
and dr judith
at the university college london
hospital
we sat down and we talked not only to
them but also to midwives and the
neonatal care teams
we asked them what they needed out of
this app this is called user driven
development
instead of me assuming their needs i ask
them directly
i gave them my prototype and they came
back and they had a whole bunch of
requests which was so wonderful
they said we love how customizable it is
but that's not what's important to us
we need it to be simple we're already
dealing with a baby
which can be difficult at the best of
times this app needs to be intuitive
not take up too much of our brain space
we need to be focused on the patient
here we also want you to
remove all of the sounds you've put in
they're really disruptive it was tips
like
this that really helped make the app so
much better
in the end we settled on design with
four stages
uh using the two main principles that
they have prioritized
intuitive design and minimal use of
language they don't want to read lots of
stuff and also
this app will hopefully go out to a
wider reach
where crossing language barriers and we
want to make it accessible
the first stage is just a full screen
camera showing you
as much of the image as possible so that
you can focus on getting a clear shot of
the white of the eye
there is a camera capture button a
little counter to show you how many
pairs of images you've taken
and when you finish taking enough images
we recommend five pairs
and then you just press the tick button
to show that you're done
here's what that looks like in real life
on a prototype version
the next stage it shows you a pair of
images that you have already captured
one above the other the flash and the
non-flash images
which is a little bit difficult you can
see it better here in this image of the
app in use
and because it's very difficult to
capture an image that is entirely taken
up with the white of the eye as i said
babies tend to move about quite a bit
you can then
zoom in and pan using quite intuitive
pinch to zoom and scroll to pan
methods that allows you to get the
sample area
that's this little yellow square in the
middle of each image
over the area of the eye that is
entirely covered by just the sclera just
the white
avoiding any veins or shadows or the
eyelid and making sure you can get a
good sample out of the image
this is larry is actually all we're
going to be looking at in order to
determine
the colour imagery of that white of the
eye
this allows you not only to check that
the image quality is good and that you
can get a good sample
if you can't hit that delete button but
it also
lets you control the image after you've
taken it and focus on getting a good
image
without worrying about making sure
there's no eyelid in it
in the initial stages this
is just showing what that looks like the
little area you want to be focusing in
on here
is the sclera
once you've done that then you just
press next and we get some results we
average out a couple of different images
because this is science this is
diagnostics and we need the most
accurate reading we can
it will show you the scb that is your
projected
bilirubin levels based on the results
what we think that means and then a
confidence rating
because we want the healthcare
professionals to feel confident in what
the app is telling them
if we think it's on the edge we'll tell
you that and you can monitor the patient
carefully
but if we think it's definitely jaundice
then we'll recommend immediate action
after this since this is a research
project we have the advanced results
screen
that means that we can feedback more
intense data
straight back to the team for continual
improvement
this app is based on the camera 2 api we
decided to do it in android
because it gives us much more control
over the camera itself
an api is just a programming interface
it's a bunch of different modules a
framework that allows you
to build your own apps the camera 2 api
is one of the most advanced
in terms of the level of control it
gives you but it wasn't advanced
enough we needed to build a custom
camera capture session module
and that's because to understand that
you need to understand the internal
workings of a camera
this is a bayer matrix it's what the
inside of your camera looks like
it's a scientific approximation which is
nearly as cool
it's a series of light sensors red green
and blue with more green because your
eye is the most sensitive to that
and these light sensors come together to
form pixels four of them in a pixel
reason this is important is because you
can't access individual light sensors
using the camera 2 api
so we had to build a custom module which
would allow us to get data directly from
these sensors
rather than an averaged out version
which compensated already for white
balance
and other factors we needed the actual
data to get the most
accurate reading we don't care about the
image looking good
we just need to understand it from a
scientific point of view
this involved getting the raw image data
something that is not standardized
across different cameras
and not standard across different phone
models either and
transforming that into an image file
that we could read
to do this we used a custom raw image to
dng
file conversion this is something that's
still under development
currently it only works for a few
specific brands of phone
but because they have to hard code
certain values
into the software to compensate for
things like different
color filter arrangements orientation
masked pixels as well as a lot of
different other characteristics
once we've got this into a tagged image
file format tiff or dng
then we can move on to sampling
this is a rough understanding of how the
app is laid out in terms of the modules
used
as you can see there is a large section
dedicated to this raw analysis that's
the green
and the blue sections it's a custom
micro services architecture which is
just a fancy website we built the app
in a way that is highly maintainable and
really testable
it uses a main activity and then hosts
different fragments within that
to perform the different features of the
app once we built the app
we needed to calibrate it as i mentioned
each camera is going to be slightly
different but also the flash is slightly
different on each modular phone
some are yellower some are more white
and they vary in brightness as well
so we needed to calibrate to a known
color and these swatches are what we use
to do that
we take images of colors where we know
the exact color value
under a range of different conditions
and then we look at the output we're
getting from the app
and we calibrate it against the known
color values of these swatches
this is another hold up at the moment
because it means the app can't just be
deployed you can't just download it and
go
the it needs to be calibrated for the
specific phone that you're using
and this really needs to be done in the
lab conditions
again something we're working on and
hopefully in future iterations
of this project this can be avoided and
we can find a way to calibrate it
remotely for the phone
or using an easier procedure because
these color swatches are really
difficult
to get hold of and really difficult to
maintain
they're very very sensitive something
else to consider is
security now as you can probably tell
due to this slide coming quite so late
in the presentation
security wasn't baked into this project
from the beginning
unfortunately i'm a developer
and the rest of you work on the project
as scientists
we didn't have much experience with
security
to give you some background this app is
designed used by healthcare workers
working in really remote locations
who don't have access to reliable
internet and may not be able to download
the latest firmware updates
for their phones leaving them really
vulnerable in earlier iterations we were
sending
really sensitive data completely
unencrypted over the internet
this is not ideal it's not just a
theoretical problem there have been
several cases recently where m health
apps
have been targeted by malicious actors
because it's a really vulnerable
situation you're in when you're dealing
with health data
and not just because we want to protect
people this is a medical device and
there are legal requirements
surrounding medical devices and cyber
security
in order for the device to pass through
these legislatures and
be available on the market we need to
come up with a way of making the data
secure currently our data transfer
solution
is just not doing it over the internet
we keep everything completely manual
on the phones and keep them offline to
try and secure them as best
we can this isn't ideal our other
solution is to ask for help
uh if you or someone you know are
interested
in security and phone applications or
ideally any health security
we would absolutely love to hear from
you please get in touch my details are
going to be available at the end of the
presentation
the next stage is field testing and
we're really really excited
so far we have two field testing
locations one in the uk
and one in accra in ghana 504 babies
have already been surveyed
in acro general hospital in the hospital
so that we can verify these results
against that gold standard blood test
the next step is going to be expanding
to different locations
getting more people involved in the
project and hopefully
saving some lives if you have any
questions feel free to reach out to me
on twitter or you can find me on
linkedin
i look forward to getting more involved
in cyber security in the future
and i really hope you've enjoyed the
presentation today thank you so much for
listening