hello everyone
welcome aboard my name is felipes i'm so
glad to be here to talk
to you for you and today we're going to
talk about discovering cnc
and malicious pdf using
some techniques like you know the
sophistications encoding
any others uh techniques that you we can
see during this workshop during this
conversation
right so let me introduce myself
so it doesn't matter and
who am i but okay anyway i need to
present some
uh contact for me in the social medias
right so i have this
web page and uh you know let me
show you here i have it in my um
virtual machine here so if you'd like to
open your
your avatar machine to you know to
practice with me together
so we can practice together during this
workshop there is this conversation
right so
i have here this um simple kala linux so
you can use in
arcane linux or another linux resolution
is
it's you know for you you can use it
what whatever you prefer right so this
is my home page
it's very simple web page you know
statistical man page
here's information about me and uh
here's some
open source projects that i have been
participating i have been participating
and uh some this project is very
interesting because it's related to uh
a security right so here's it's another
relate to devops and
to help the developers using you know
the
this kind of projects using for example
in a mobile project and web applications
and whatever here's it's another
difference works with uh
different um cycles and something like
that
right so here some presentations some
talks that i did
that i made in some events probably in
the future this workshop
will be here in this website
and here if you'd like to see some
articles about
about me but about some testing that i
made that i did
or you know whatever so here's some
articles
that was published right so let's return
my presentations
again i have been you know i used a lot
twitter and github and uh and linkedin
this is the main
social medias that i have been working
right so
i i have been working at security
research and security advocate at
supernovation
it's a brazilian company and i'm
advocating from this
uh awesome project hack is not a crime
because
uh i would like to talk more about this
for you
it's um you know it's a very good
project um
initiative actually and the idea is to
explain more about the people about this
this thing and this concept right
because hacking it's really not a crime
it's a life cycle uh my life cycles are
is a
lifestyle right it's a creative mind
when you see some software when you work
with uh you know
discover something and this is the
focuses
about this project right so i am as part
of the staff team
of the dcg dcg 511 in sao paulo here in
brazil by the way
i am talking here from sao paulo in my
small office here as you can see behind
me
is my balcony you know i have here some
uh apartment buildings behind me and uh
yes i am security research and
instructor about the portuguese courses
in the hacker security it's a brazilian
company and i'm structure
and the writer and reviewer for the
three magazine
and i have one course about the malware
hunting
right guys so let's talk about our
summary today
first of all i'd like to explain more
details just a concept actually about
the what is
thread and after that we'll explain more
about them our analysis those first
steps
and i will talk about in the end of this
workshop about the structure of the pdf
and i will explain about the demo and i
will open to
you to answer some questions right so
again uh if you'd like to open your
virtual machine during this conversation
during this conversation
no my goodness during this conversation
it was pretty cool right so what is
threat
first of all it's just a concept
according this is it's not
my definitions right it's a definition
for this iso
thread is defined as a potential what
potential cause of an incident
right so maybe you know it may cause
harm to the system organizations
but it means why what flipping exactly
it's a kind of softer attacks or maybe a
death of intellectual intellectual
property or maybe
identity death right it's very common
and the sabot sabotage and information
distortions
are example of the information security
threats it means all those
things it is threat right so uh
everything is related to a software
right so when you build something like
you know some applications and apps for
them to use in an ios
or android it's uh it's a software
right and if you have some hardware
probably you have some
uh a layer of the firmware or
you know some application behind and a
software if you have an appliance you
have a software there
it means you know everything it's
related to a software so when you have
some
at software attack is it is a threat
right so and of course when you produce
something when you
is a software house for example and you
have some tough intellectual property or
if they death is related to a threat so
all those
thing is threat why i need to understand
about that flip
because when you see about that you need
to understand
when you receive some software or some
artifact you need to understand
if this software it was malicious or not
in this case this is the first step
right so the
identification is stopped it's a simple
uh
life cycle uh of course it's just
one opinion and i see this a good life
cycle from
a friend a brazilian friend right so uh
and you in this step it's very important
because
uh you can decide not decide you you
need to understand if this
artifact or this simple right is
malicious or not
in this case probably if is malicious
you have a maor or maldot which means
maori it's a softer malicious and maldoc
it's obviously
malicious document and after the
identification step you can choose
what the best strategy or method to
apply in this
analysis you can define is if we will
use in a
statistic analysis right or dynamic
analysis
and after that you can produce
something very interesting then usually
the manager and the coordinators exactly
it's like a lot
right it means it's a report because you
can present that with
your leader right because when you make
some analysis you can produce this
report so
after this report when your manager or
your boss has
um this report on the table
you can do another actions what
is the next steps step you can improve
your defenses mechanism because
if you see if you understand what is the
real
the real path about this artifact you
can
improve your defenses mechanism right
because
if for example this malware bypass some
security sensor that you have you can
make some adjustments in the settings or
something like that right
if you have a a big company or maybe if
you have a small company it's not a
problem you can
try you know to build this awesome idea
this cyber threat intelligence right
because you can use many
different tools to in you know to
automate this process
to generate intelligence uh
you know against threat that's the point
here
and of course you need to strengthening
cyber resilience
in your team in your environment because
you know the threads
are changing all the time so this is a
simple life cycle
about the mara knights the simple of
course is not
only the only
module you can use another different
it's not a problem but it just
one simple idea for you right so let's
explain more about the statistical
analysis it's very simple
usually we began our exploration right
of moral analysis with the statistical
analysis
which is often the first step
in our studies why because the
statistical analysis describe
usually the process of analyzing a
program
code right or maybe a structure to
determine
its functions for example you have some
code
and if this code has some library
and for example some library called some
function inside
your system operations right so the
program itself
doesn't run at this time you know of
course depending
on what the program you are using right
so this makes the parsing process more
you know
safe because we aren't actually
excluding
it right so it means doesn't run
at this time because of this usually is
the first
step in mre study or using for amour
analysts
right so when you explain for a dynamic
analysis for
other hand is different it's based
solely or only
on behavior it means and in the
interaction that malware has
when it's executed or monologue or
malware is
used also known like
run time and noise you see it's
different
because one of these tests or this
analysis
you uh use it in the runtime
in an order it doesn't run at time it's
different right it's very
simple explanation but because it's it's
very clear and it's not
i don't need to explain more deeply
because it's it's a simple definition
one of these you reside
the mower and you see the behavior any
other you don't you don't execute the
malware you need to see the call the
structure
and you know and understand how this
malware or maldoc
or sample works right so it can be
easily
automated there are sites today
that already performer analysis with the
malicious artifact using you know
the simple concept call it sandbox or
maybe when you're
is performing this simple in um
web application uh scanning and uh
actually it's uh antivirus is kind of
like you know virustoto
ustoto it's antivirus scanning when you
put some
sample inside or url inside inside of
the zeros total
anyways they could this and of course
you have many engines
provide for many different security
vendors inside of this uh jerusalem it's
antivirus is scanning
right so this is a uh is when you talk
about the automated process or a dynamic
it's kind of dynamic analysis right but
it's very common when you use
uh this kind of concept sandbox when you
have the virtual machine
with many engines and you can you know
put the smallers inside of this virtual
machine and then they could themselves
and you can see and analyze the behavior
right but of course in both of these
analysis we need to understand about
this basis
it's very important during this
conversation you need to understand
about those phases it is
very important right guys so okay
before to talk about the physical
logical analysis we need to understand
about this basis that i am talking right
so
let's see here about the identification
step do you remember the life cycle this
is the first step so
if you have now a virtual machine you
can open your
terminal when you're bash you can
execute this
commands with me so first of all let's
see here let's open
the simple the zoo do you know this
repository the zoo uh github you can
write
in this way click enter and after that
you have here
the let me okay here i think it's good
the zoo repository of live mowers for
your your what your
whatever okay you have here let's see
live on our repository right so it's a
project created to make the possibility
of more analysis open and available to
the public
so pay attention here guys because all
those
mowers it is a real right it's not a
fake mower so pay attention here
when you manipulate this different
uh mars you can execute all those models
inside your bar but it's not necessary
for now
right but you can download after that
it's not a problem
and of course remember you need to make
some settings in your network
environment you know isolate your
virtual machine
it's very important to understand about
that right so if you have some question
you can
uh write me you know in the in a github
or can send a message by you know a
twitter on linkedin wherever
you can send me a message if you need
this understand about these
configurations in your network right
so you can click here in ours and after
that you can click on binaries
right and after that boom you have here
the awesomes many different mowers right
and then the right rod and the different
attempts and but different samples right
not samples in this case it's a
real mower right the pitot locker and
some rents over and let's see here the
equation group you know it's an
apt group and i don't know if you know
but it's an apt group
it's a simple of course of this mars
let's see anothers here linux chopros
encoder
as you can see here it's an elf it's a
different of the pe
portable executable in this case it's
for a linux platform
and here to aos
in this case it's natural uh sam
mowers right it's a mac os and let's see
here
oh nice many ram servers to manipulate
be
i know again be careful to this version
because it's totally
real so let's see here another treasure
i don't know if you are hearing but i
have a truck here
next to my apartment now and uh the guy
probably talking
some you know promotions like that or
you know
whatever i'm sorry for that guys but
this is the pandemic you know it's a new
real life
unfortunately and but we have here
another difference
uh take a look at this win3 apt 28
20 32 and
another zip right you can download
whatever you want right so let's see
another here another
very interesting repository just right
in the in the google maw bazaar here
and click enter and uh and after that
you have here let's see
maura bazaar our sample exchange
click here and after that you have here
the mower
bazaar by abuse ch
you can click here in our bazaar
database and take a look where and see
here another awesome project inside
our environment not in our environment
it's a repository right you can and see
many different powers here
again be careful because here we have
many uh mower
you know and of course you can try
during your you know tests your
improvement your acknowledgement
you have here and pe executable you have
here it's a document right
xls and here you have a doc and zip
you can download many different let's
see another here if you have here
and a pdf click search and uh
hit f i don't know if this syntax is
correct
and uh okay tag uh
let's see here pdf again let's see
search and uh yes searching now
and okay it's here let's see here
another pdf
if you'd like to see more deeply you can
download
all those samples and pe and
oh man take a look at this philip it's
me right
guys you can click here if you'd like to
download my not myself actually
it's actually it's a mower that i will
explain during this conversation there
is
during this um
presentations right so when i uploaded
this
mower inside of this platform i lived in
poland in that time but now i'm
leaving and i'm talking from brazil and
okay you can download this and you can
make your testings during
this workshop right so let's return my
virtual machine here let me list
all those samples that i have here
inside of my
machine then which don't mind much oh my
goodness
that i have inside of my virtual machine
and i have here
the amazon amazon doc
docx bl doc pdf invoice.pdf
linux without extension uh
pdf it's a directory it's a folder and
redpo.cso probably it's a
it's a it's a different it's um it's
another
code to make uh if you're using gcc to
create an
elf file and resume pdf and sample pdf
here
folder with a wing uh it's a vf portable
inside of this
let's check here so okay let's
understand what the first step that i
can
as a good themself here in my
environment and uh
maybe i am using the file because it's a
good
tool or good com command to as a good
right
so let's see amazon first of all
let's see what happened here i can
identify the microsoft word 2007 plus
right and another is a file an amazon
doc
docx yes it's it is
okay okay it's obviously maybe
and let's see another bill my friend
view let's see here my friend bill
i like this guy view it's a it's a pdf
document perfect
so let's see here another invoice.pdf
file
and maybe you are asking you
about so i need to execute this
command in all those files yeah this is
the identification step you remember i
need to understand
what it is or what is exactly the binary
right so
let's see again file let's see linux
talk
text it's a text oops in this case it's
not a text
take a look at this it's a elf it's a
it's a cootable
right so it's different but take a look
this here
is the extension in this case it's
doctest but it's not
this case is different it's elf take a
look at this it's very interesting here
because here it's the base i need to
understand how this command works
how this file works and
after before or before i execute
any whatever comment i i can as i could
in this virtual machine or in my
environment i need to understand
how this exactly worked so i can set for
example my
file let me looking inside of this
commandment file
how this works exactly and oops
let's see here okay so man file
it's what it is this tools actually
determine
a file type take a look this then of
course maybe you understand you know
about that but you need to understand
how this exactly works so the manual
page document verse 5.39
on a file comment okay here's some flags
or comments that you can set
when you execute this file and okay so
why
you are show us this philippines this is
a good cash
question because here we have some
interesting information
the magic tests are used to check for
files with data's in particular fixed
formats so perfect so these tools
presenters exactly
different or not different but exactly
particular fixed
fixed formats right so the canonical
example okay
of this a binary executable
program do you remember about the thread
it's a software but when you have some
software
some software we have a software
compiler right
uh it means changing this program
to a compiled program perfect so r
a dot 8 file was format is defined
in an elf dot h so it means here
maybe you have and there's interesting
information here so let's see here let
me
cop elf.h to understand more about this
information let me open another
split vertically okay let me open here
and let me find this not find the locate
sorry
i can use find too but i prefer using uh
let me pass here okay in the beginning
here
uh user include let me check
this important thing here because here
in the explanation of the do you
remember
and the in the in the middle of the fire
we have here the
good explanation about this extensions
take a look at this here
about the here whose format
is defined so here in this file maybe i
have some
format defined but what kind of maybe
it's a elf because
the material the explanation it's about
that flat check here uh
it's uh i use nano you know
lit to read and take a look what i am
seeing here
in this moment in this file
take a look this user include
dash user usr dot
include.alph.h of this file defined is
standard
elf type take a look at this of course
this conversation this workshop is
related to a pdf
but when you talk about the malwares you
can you need to understand about the elf
you know you need to understand about
the pe portable executable you need to
understand about the different docks
uh like you know dock or an xls
powerpoint
whatever and uh and of course the pdf so
here we have a good example when you
read
the manual buddy i flip i don't like to
read the manual
i know maybe i don't like to but it's
very
important why because here you have a
types
and structure and macros right so let's
see
behind here let's move here you have the
structure of the byte so
16 bytes quantity about the elf and a
half
an award and and the next word
maybe all those explanations it's very
cool for another talk
but okay because we don't have a time to
explain all those details now
and here the elf file header this
appears
at the start of every elf
file take a look at this this is the
elf file header one of this part
of the elf structure but philip this
conversation is about elf it's about pdf
no or just to understand something about
demand right so the first idea when you
talk about the header
you have this array
what array this in the first array we
have this
identity when you have this array
and a 16 bytes do you remember take take
a look at this they structure the first
you have 60 bytes in
this structure right so
this is the identity
structure in the header of what
information do you have
in the identity structure you have a
magic number
and others information but what that
means magic number flip
take a look at this one second i will
explain more about the magic number but
you have here others information
so okay let's return our uh man
because i didn't finish the here okay
okay let's continue the explanation
possib
possible uh as exact.he
in the standard included directory okay
this file
but these files has a what a magic
number
what it is exactly storage
in a particular place near the beginning
of the file that tells
the unix operation system that the file
is a binary
executable and each of the several types
uh theoretic the concept of
magic has has been applied
by extension to data files it means
you have a magic number in all those
files in a particular place
in the beginning right so it means
you usually you always have the magic
number so
it means all those bios has a magical
number i feel if i
i already know about that so no worries
but probably we have
some people now watching this video
people didn't know nowhere but every
people now uh know
now right so take a look at this the
information identifying this
here the identification this file is
ready from
what atc magic
and the compiled magic file and user
share misc
dash slash magic doc mgc
it means you have all those informations
compiled here in your
system operations right but i need you
and i would like to explain more details
about that
right about this kind of concept so
uh let me close here again
let me close here this uh okay
uh is it okay and uh here take a look at
this
i download this the real
file code to understand more deeply
about this simple code
the simple comment the simple base right
so let's see here
cd file and um
magic it's a magic i don't remember
let's see here uh it's uh okay magic
magic magic magaziner
take a look at this magazine and what i
have here
so take a look at this i have all those
magic numbers for many different
bios like you know enough pdf
here i have from vmware
or i have here another from let's see
another elf here you know
here take a look at this and uh on
windows we have here windows too
let's see what is the windows here it's
windows take a look at this and web
assembly
and uh we have a pideon might say where
is python here
take a look at this
uh it's here piden
i don't know i lost but i lost python my
anyway we have python here but i don't
know exactly here it's python
okay so let's see uh uh javascript
javascript javascript inside of this
uh it's a database of this many
different uh
magic numbers so as you can see here you
have some rules
to understand when the
file comment we will identify
you know what is exactly that file of
these fire right so let's see here
this is when you have the beginning do
you remember in the beginning
of the particular place in the beginning
do you remember the explanation
here when you have this information in
the beginning you have
what a node.js script executable right
so let's see other and maybe a python
right in here maybe python we have a
different rules
many rules by the way take a look at
this
and there's some reject some strings
here take a look at this
okay and um the same case here take a
look there's a final script
perfect okay let me manipulate something
let me create here nano uh malware
very creative.text perfect and the
malware
is malicious malicious
let's save here and um
okay yes save and okay let me
i will create this sample right so it's
a text take a look at this i have to put
the file command
and that that the tools uh
performance in this uh file and the
file understand how this matching
numbers work so let me manipulate this
file now so first of all
let me put for example let me return
here
and uh okay
no let me see about the javascript
because i really don't remember okay
it's a binging there's a
a simple let me copy here and i
completely forgot
being slash note it's very simple but i
forgot
sorry for that let me manipulate now let
me paste here
slash you know being bash x not being
bashed b note
actually let me save here and like
uh click yes and uh save here and again
file mower take a look at this it's not
a
you know take a look this is not a text
more
it's an ojs you know and uh
if i try to read here it's it's
you know but it's not exactly javascript
because the extension is different you
remember when i execute this
file command in another text it was f
file do you remember
we'll take a look at this let me
manipulate again file
it's a nano okay i will put here
just a simple comment here
let me that here and uh
let me save and yes what
what happened here file mower
it's a python take a look at this
because this is the
do you remember what the name it's a
magic number
because i'm manipulating the magic
number here right
okay so let me let me do another
last manipulation mower uh
or the final material text
okay no it's not i need to put the
correct name
it's uh it's different here
okay now it's okay perfect let me put
here what
uh that money putting percent pdf
and one doc one doc
or six let me save here what happened
because
i don't know how the file works in this
case let's see here
catch mower i have here person pdf
and i have here uh from a pilot script
and here the text so let's see what
works here file malware.txt
it is a pdf document take a look this
why because if you see a pdf here
take a look this they string in the
beginning
exactly a string that i wrote
right so why i explain all those
things to you because you need to
understand about those basis it's very
very important
right so we need to understand how this
tool works
it's not a simple comment right so
another simple example let me return
here root
and uh malware
and yes okay so let's see here i have
different
uh files linux files here
linux okay so let's see for example uh
file linux
32 okay linux
64 and
[Music]
take a look at this if i execute this xd
xd let me check here in xd or xd
okay xd uh
dash any 32 and the linux
32 take a look this i have here
the extra decimal information right and
here i have what
i have string here right so let me put
here
another thing like
[Music]
not 32 bytes i will put all those
uh not let me put in the pipe class here
because i'm
using the terminator here and uh
you know i don't have a good buffer to
show
let me like less okay so take a look at
this
i have here that the all those strings
here
and take a look this
okay not different informations here
just say strings right so
let me turn here and i will explain
one thing about that i have here the
string in the beginning right
if you are using here the strings
strings strings
yes a uh
it means all right and i put here the
linux
32 5
last take a look what happened so i
should i should see
this information right because it's as a
string right so
when you click enter take a look this
went where the place is start
right so i can't see the elf information
right take a look at this
let me explain another thing using
in a different way a different parade so
let me
go to a windows folder i have here
windows file
i have a simple one with cool
very cool simple it's uh this is a p
it's a p
let me check who is it's another pe okay
let me put here in uh xd and again
lex the aminos nominal sorry and the
dash
uh went forward and
put here
sorry oh my goodness
okay perfect take a look at this
in the beginning of the file we have the
mz
information which means this is the one
of this magic number of the pe
right and here we have another string so
let me
put again but no
informations about the the limitations
of the bytes and i will put pipelast
here
because i would like to see many strings
here so mz
and this program cannot be run in dos
mode
and wherever here the pe signature it's
it's here
right and let's see oh here the session
dot text
another session uh
or data right so uh in
usually it's uh not usually not so
related really only it's or
all data it's data it's another session
each
session or src usually related to an
image or you know
or something like that and many other
strings rear
here but if you as i could hear these
strings
take a look this is strings such all
please so what should be the first
letter the first thing string mz right
but does it
happen why
it's a good question but yeah you need
to understand about the what
none of these three oh my goodness i
don't like to read them off philly
it's a totally it's not a
guys
you need to understand about that right
so strings what
print the sequence the sequence of the
printable characters
in files right so for each file given
you know strings prints the printable
character
sequence that are at least what
at least four characters long
because of this don't
show or don't appears the mz because
it's
two characters and elf because it's
three characters that is the key
right so i even understand those ways i
just like to
as i could some or perform some comments
or
using some tools but is i know maybe
it's useful but
it's useless when you don't know about
the basis
right so because of this union we need
understand about the base
so let me return about my presentations
here
and when you talk about the pdf is
different you understand about the
structure because the structure is
almost different
not almost it's a similar of course but
maybe it's uh
maybe it's a maybe similar or not but in
general pdf has a
four parts right first of all it's a
header it's
almost the same when you have another
different full files
and you have a body it's a different
because you have many
information content inside of this body
you have a cross reference table
and you have a trailer in the end of the
fire right so
it means is you can see in this way
in the beginning you can see the header
usually
you can see the version of the number
you see the body with the pages
image font and bookmark and formulas
object because you know pdf it means
uh it's a not a text it's a text file
but with many
polar or maybe you know good images did
you know
i'm joking but you know you have here
the interesting informations cross
reference table it's very
interesting because you have a locations
of the objects
if in the file for a random access right
so
location of the certain objects eating
the body
and locations of the cross reference
table in the file it means all those
cross reference table
it's is referenced
in another object so for example let's
suppose you have
uh 20 objects inside so many of these
objects
it is a reference themselves
right uh itself in in this
way right so i'll explain more in in a
demo now
so not here okay so let me explain about
that
so i will show you i have a folder here
i have a sample here i have a file
that i i didn't have is this file it's
malicious or so i do
execute this first tool pdf id
provided by dj steven by the way so here
as you can see the header you know
percent pdf
and you have object 15
right you have a streaming two and you
have a cross reference table
and take a look this is a very
interesting information here
because usually these tools when
probably when dj steven created this
tool
during he understood about
the structure of the pdf makes sense for
you
and then after that he can create these
tools to scan some informations inside
of the
pdf right so these uh
tools as they put some scanning inside
of the pdf
and they can find for example the name
of the object
if the pdf has some e-stream usually
when the attacker
like to put some a malicious software
they use they stream to put some alicia
things inside of the stream right okay
so this is
these tools um you can
uh or this this tool uh got
to find information inside the uh the
pdf right
and take a look this dash page that
script
encrypt dash slash not dash slash right
so slash object stream
javascript js javascript a a open
actions and another information here
so when you see this slash it
means that all those informations
are inside of this main information
here right so we don't have to see more
about the man
okay of the pdf id but you can see you
can read you need to read
after this workshop these conversations
right so let's continue to see the video
take a look this we have five javascript
inside
of this pdf make sense to you and here
we have another interesting information
open action what is mean what do you
mean filipino connection inside of pdf
it's here it's very
very important informations
and when you have some open action
inside of pdf
it means that the user just needs to
download a file
right and after that when the file
is downloaded in your environment
the pdf can as a good themselves
inside of your environment because they
have this open action
action right this uh
this action defining inside of
the fire right heath and the fire
perfect so if you
when you will analyze some pdf and you
see some open action
or a a it's mean the same meaning right
so
the pdf just the user just need to as to
download the file inside of the
the machine and after that the pdf will
execute themselves right
so okay let's continue to analyze so
after that all
knowing this knowing this information i
execute another common
pdf dash parser it's another tool
provided by dda steven
i execute this with dash that's run it's
been i view
the idea here is to collect all those
random informations inside of this pdf
okay perfect let me understand about
this
uh those results so
here the header take a look this and
after that i have object
one and take a look this object one
referring what
referring object true object three
object four object five six
and seven but in the beginning when
i we started analyze this file we had
a 15 we remember so but i just can't see
here
seven but i have 15.
you know don't forgot don't forget this
number right so
and i have here an object one reference
to the javascript
and take a look at this javascript and i
have here open action
oops take a look this interesting thing
i have an open action
and and there is a good dysfunction
inside of this bitcoin machine take a
look
what action performance
performing or performing this action
performed inside the victim machine
is some action related a what
related to some javascript right so we
can see you can understand this
okay so let's continue to analyze but i
need to unders i don't understand
the code but i know that is javascript
because i am seeing here
so okay let me return
here sorry okay so i have here the
object two
three and take a look this here in four
or i have reference object eight and
object nine guys
okay so now i have eight and nine object
right so we need to see more deeply take
a look this oops
object seven take a look what appears
here the object
tn but in inside of the or eating
the objecting we have a what i have a
javascript
so i have one the first javascript on
the first but i have javascript inside
that object 10.
perfect let's continue to see here oops
object nine i have a reference to object
four right because represent object four
reference
object nine perfect but have here
another object
eleven do you remember an explanation of
the structure
all those objects are referenced in
themselves
right so oh let continues here
the object 10 do you remember we have a
javascript
okay and i have javascript but i have
another referencing
object 12. oh i need to see
there but take a look this a different
information
in object 11 we have a what we have
not referenced but i have what
information we have here
contains a stream it means i have here
something inside of this stream but i i
don't know what
this means in this case but i need to
investigate right
so and when i have another interesting
information flat decode
means i need to decode this information
inside of this
string but i have here the left the
remember the left is
it's really it means it's it's related
to a size
right so but the size is at 36 it's not
too much it's bigger
it's not bigger it's it's more very very
small but have here a object
12 you remember but another reference oh
my goodness
it's 13 okay but here guys take a look
at this
in object 13 i have a streaming
flat the code but take a look this is
the sizing it's
too big so i need to see more deeply
inside of this
maybe here i have some suspicions i have
object 14
and 15. okay so next steps to see what
the 13 object because i have here the
stream right a big stream
and i really could this pdf the cup
because you can use to compress
for a pdf inside but i i will use
another thing to uncompress because if i
can use the compress
i can uncompress the idea here is to
uncompress all those informations inside
of this pdf so i do as i could this
output
in this output is done text and take a
look so
i can find here wow
pretty cool take a look at this
streaming and the size i uncompressed
the code
and i have here the first techniques
technique i found here the
javascript obfuscated so i need to what
there's a forescape of this code
to try and understand more deeply what
this code
means needs exactly in my environment
or in this case indeed in the with my
machine right so
next step i will cop this and i called
payload.html white because i
do remember i'm talking to uh javascript
so sometimes your javascript is related
to a web application
so imc i know and see i
saw some evil parameters and i ch
is changing this parameter to try
uh watch this information in some
uh document right in a in a browser
right and if you see here take a look
these different colors by the way
probably i have something here inside
and after that i can investigate more
that but as you can see here
the two already identified some
different colors here so i am putting
the document right because i will write
this information in a web browser
and take a look what happened i am i
save here
the payload.html right
perfect and i will give the permission
to execute themselves
in the web browser and i will open this
in uh
okay everything it works
wow take a look this is what i am
found a payload you know what
what that means it's very simple here we
have a
package responsible to downloading the
hitman machine
and this package and this part of this
code
is responsible to call back to the
commanding controller from the attacker
you see so inside of this java
javascript
obfuscated i found a payload responsible
to call
to the cnc from the attacker you see
so but here if you see yeah maybe you
need to understand more
about that i am season percent here and
a very
uh you know common behavior not behavior
but
it means maybe make sense to investigate
more about that right
so the next step that i did
in this or that i am doing i do
and oh my goodness i have some problem
with the verb you know
but the next step is i will cop this
code because i will try
to continue to investigate because i am
see the behavior so i'm
setting this nano again and i i will put
i i i put the real payload
right and i pass this i save the folder
right and after that take a look what i
did i set this
the set because i am cut this percent
and i will then my idea is to just see
this real information here take a look
this this simple
encode because here we have another
technique
the encode technique do you remember you
can use different encodings to like
you know um uh
let me another in this case i'll be
using unicode based
in in two bytes it's different but you
can use an
and basic uh basis 64 baby
16 baby you know 32
encrypting the encrypt you can use in
different encoding
in this case the attacker uses an older
technique
it's encoded based on
ec2 based on unicode it means
and it's explained uh you know it's low
because it's
it's uh oldest it's older
it's it's older this kind of technique
because it's based on
ec2 ec2 what pays it in only code
is not any in an ascii right it's
different it based on unicode
because it's too bad as key it's on one
byte right
so here i have the unicode okay but
maybe you are asking
uh if you are asking for example philip
you just show us
about the you know linux platform but i
will go i like to work with them or
analysis with a
windows environment in the works i have
another thing to you i knew i used in
this case mozilla by blobby
it's a very cool platform i passed here
the same
same code take a look at this the same
percent
and i cut this percent of this
information take a look this
and i generate what i generate a x-file
doc binary because my idea is is to
generate this binary because do you
remember the a called
technique using the ec2 by
[Music]
unicode right so i generate in this
casing
using this platform in mozilla the x
file binary and
in the end what i did i use short
search from the dairy stevens again to
try and find
what uh inside of this file x file
binary
if i found some http
request and what and take a look this
what i found here
the server from the
attacker because this code
it is using this unicode right so this
uh command controller it was
in estonia in that time right so i found
the
commanding controller for for the attack
right so if you have now question guys i
am hoping
to talk to you but just to finish up my
presentations
here our conversation during this
workshop
the point here is you need to understand
about those ways that i
explained during this conversation and
during this workshop
and another point here take a look i
found the file
pdf file inside this pdf has a
javascript
do you remember do disrupts just this
javascript it was
uh using the obfuscation techniques we
remember
inside of this pdf we had the open
action it means just
the user needs to download the file and
after that
this open action will execute this
javascript
that is obfuscated inside of this
we found the payload responsible to
uh connect uh
to the cnc right the callback
to the vitamin machine from the cnc the
commanding controller
using what using a unicode techniques
technique to encode the information of
the
eyepiece or the eyepiece of the ip from
the attacker it was in estonia europe
right so guys thank you so much for
being here with me
thank you for having me this event and
again
hear my contact on social media so if
you have any question please
let me know and you know keeping hockey
and if you
need something count everything on me
not everything actually you can count on
me always