a kid it looks like we're ready so
the much time and the drawl no
is with well pronounced yet young for
gay the
were a nice enough to propose a
presentations on the
in prison presentation on my father how
to pronounce it
and it's a good question her sexy
the players about that I'm so you have
the floor
thank you thank you very much so rabies
is your way
I'm with his network's margin is with
the Virus Bulletin
know when the what we think it was an
interesting work around
miss out which we are going to tell you
the story about
what it is and what we saw so
the just as an intuition because the
them
is a better if I offended a yep
and we can security software
but it's a anti-virus anti-spam we
organize annual security conference we
were in Seattle a
two months ago and will be in prague a
next year and we also
published technical articles including
summer with them by people in this room
which is
goood you have something impressing on
the right about
beckel let you know were actually hiring
at the moment
juror the job this one okay
so am the a last week on preparing for a
presentation and I realize that I don't
really know
how these more it's pronounced I was
call it my father
for some reason but it may as well be be
me they'd and one of his Twitter some
russian guy actually told me it might be
a move it. because the
it may well be russian the sorry I i did
i I'll call it my father
but a it may well be me they'd and
some people actually signed bronze
combat call at seven its and
also made as BC's use so
a.m. the goal of this presentation is is
twofold the
on one hand we just want to tell the
story of
I'll Nevada botnet but on the other hand
we want to tell our story of
fighting this botnet chasing his partner
and the
going to show you that to chase botnet
you don't
meet to start with a more sample there
are different ways to do that
at the depth that interesting for people
in from
so a.m.
last week everyone was talking about the
right in which is is very
big scary ball where it
and as a sq problem written
Belcourt people who who noted talking
about call it the most advanced more
ever detected
compared to this halifa before the mall
where
bodies really a tiny mouse its it's not
very advanced its it's nothing that
many people in his room probably have to
worry about because if you
practice general security hygiene and
have a
working at the Varsity problem have to
worry about it on the other hand if you
look at the number of infections
dan Nevada enormous mouse because there
are
million infections whereas wretched is a
is a tiny elephant because the really
only a few
targets we don't know to more but still
they're not gonna be more than a few
hundred
I guess so Nevada first
started to appear on the scene about
three years ago
I think the first public book both
dedicated to it was
from Microsoft who in generated
well added the packaged with Mike
Malicious Software Removal Tool
at the court said in its and
a they wrote that it's this Trojan
Family
moderates redirects about traffic from
search engines like Google
Yahoo and even big an
this report makes it but too bad
admitted more it
as more goatee is relatively harmless
and as a relatively because it is
harmful but
doesn't steal your bank details or
haha equipped your your heart
am after this big to be quiet throughout
Nevada was
not much news doesn't mean no one was
affecting it or looking at it back
it is wasn't very interesting and and
it's good to know that a lot more out
there
not many people are looking at a moment
people are writing about it
as also what if you read the newspaper
be more like to read
security security news you more like to
read the
stories about them technically
interesting piece
more rather than the ones that are very
prevalent and then suddenly
something interesting happened in
September last year want to talk project
y'all know what stories reporter a sharp
increase
in the number of connections from
everything complete and
well as a sharp increase I mean that in
ten or eleven days
the number of connections increase by a
multiplied by fact of life something
which is it enormous made it was
3 moms after at Snowden had come out
which is woods and is a leaks
the team the unlikely that this was the
case even though some
door used a very excited that they find
people using poor
did was very likely but is what was
enormous
and then and it was was one interesting
thing because i sat
but every country in the world so more
connected to network there was one
notable exception and
this is was a divine ok to this on their
authority may limit roger is one of the
people behind
or and he wrote I'm compelled to point
out that
this table has one data point that will
keep the bellies of conspiracy theorist
for four months only in only country did
in game was Israel
and it's actually in procedural we'll
see while 8102 people
israeli a and yeah so am
what was happening well your complaints
by
guy from results box I T in them I know
since spicer
over here seeded with the credit ima
greatly a.m. he he was the one who
discovered what what
because of this outdoor network increase
and it was a lot but not
and effective was its particular but
that was Nevada
which separates at the door components
and and which
weekend but find out what extremely back
wasn't the first botnet
but you store for mama control
communication which I think golan
understand why it makes sense for Obama
to do that
but it was the first one that by doing
so really
skew the door statistics hand
he also found some Mon control services
which
also shows wire what people want as BC
okay to having having said that have
been a set the scene about them a father
Joe I was gonna
gonna talk about that about stuff the
he does and they do which ultimately
lead to
to order artist so
the cordial
showing it didn't buy it is an me with
just to explain to beat
of what we do in the way we do things
because it connects deeply
to how we conduct our research me in
marching on the fates of
a so we developed the Philly
recent call concept around looking at
security fence as as a sort of big data
a and 10 try to come up with the
technology that the Los processing all
these
events that are happening in real time
in large-scale
in order to extract valuable threat
indicators
so know too that we working on two main
pieces
the one that you see on their on the
left side
is of course a right of the formation of
a sort of information that we we collect
a
I mean we have pretty much the bit of
everything from
sinkholes from body parts from traps
everything that you can
think about that houses where wesat
else's Morales's
the whole idea was to collect all this
information
as much as we can and push it as events
as things are start happening into a
high-performance complex event
processing debt we build
so that then we can use that together
with an API
to extract value information from from
the Dayton
and provided to subscribers and is in a
nutshell
its initially what we did then of course
you have on the right side
different ways to access the data the
API which is by far the most interesting
thing
probably for for for you guys or any
researcher
but also dashboards connectors and stuff
like that
but really the central piece is the even
processor
and the flexibility of GPS so in a
nutshell it's really all about streaming
so the its different calls the because
position we are used to looking at
databases and that's not about
it's not what you doing here we just
collecting events and making them
available
as industry in streaming and so we built
this competitive process
it's really foale's publish/subscribe a
model
it's really easy to publish date and to
into
get it out all tall to fit its official
rest
and the all the event tonight Jason
serbia it's really really easy to use
being a competent processor the
idea was okay at not what I want to
access the dayton but I want to do
something we did
in real time I want to be able to
correlate I want to be able to measure
I want to be able to I don't think about
it as well of stuff that
as researchers we want to do on top of
Dayton
and the idea was to make that available
in real time on GPS
so there are a lot of possibilities in
terms of post-processing
which leads to the
one important thing so one of the
sources of information is that we have
is a fair Larson calling infrastructure
which uses besides with this technology
that there was mentioning
as a way to get Dayton about
what we want to sing colin White and
is initially to do that we have to use a
sort of
array of sensors around the world I
don't like the the words answer because
normally has sort over negative notation
with
it's really worries its a we r
collecting information from
several countries them
is initially it it can be other things
as well but nowadays we focus a lot on
on DNS into and HTTP it's by far the
the type of protocols that gives the
givers more
more reach information that we can use
to extract straight indicators
and like I said so this collective and
eyes push towards the complex even
processor
dates available to researchers and their
tools to
work today to and find in fact that that
that was the
mingle and or to finance the or
in this case things that we want to
single the
we of course is the PI and then we'll
look at it at things like don't like the
ones mentioned you
so we look at space Pacific traffic
patterns
we look at the man rotation volume at
six frequency
and and it ultimately what these
allows is to detect what I looked like
to call
a new clothes performing sees since its
inception
which typically leads to normal the new
botnet
which can be new book yet from old mall
where you mall where
its do the detection of these new
clothes the forming
that allows us to to be fairly quick
yeltsin calling you stuff but of course
detecting DG's as well
a like like these two examples
just two examples of disease easy to
detect using
this methodology and I'm not
not going very much detail about these
because tomorrow there is going to be
another
know that talk by peers Camille which is
one of my colleagues
he's going to explain in detail
with his part what we are doing on on
these parks in terms of
of research the end result is also is
always okay let's
this is a bad what net lets you call it
and see how it looks
just some number so that you get you
have an idea
it's very loud large I don't know it's
it's
it's difficult to compare with others
because there aren't many numbers out
there about
colleague operations ours usually we
trek around
a seven million infected devices over a
24-hour
time window which uses a lot and
and is of course generates a a lot of
traffic
and we make that traffic available as
events
so it means that you you can actually
see what's
going on with that with the with the
fact that device when it's checking in
with my control or is dropping some for
information it's not the information
I put their number six thousand but in
reality sometimes its 10,000 15,000
really varies with a lot a lot of the
events happening per second on these
on this projection and of course we
trekked we track
a lot of power families using these
method being one of them of course
and and I was playing how we detect you
but that's using these methodologies
home if it was the indeed the a good
example
that is a an interesting picture because
sometimes it's really hard to explain to
less technical people who old is about
the
sort of living organism botnet art so it
is a good picture about
home if it looked when we first detected
so you have the the common controls are
the
the reddish balls and the rest are
effective missions
so what we saw you know first
so basically what we thought was a
a bunch of prayers and NX means not nor
is over
more resolve Aquarius to fix set of 21
dot issue domains and they very much
consistent with what you would expect
from
an automated behavior you have to have a
certain frequency
certain people see that lead you to
believe that is a
an automated beacon we will see multiple
jugar geographies
of course and the injury interesting
indicator was that we we
I will be we have a pretty good
knowledge of the botnet space
know there's but if you look at these IP
address and compare it with our
knowledge
the overlap was really minimal which
means OK these
something you going on so up to this
point support the decision is okay let's
thats call it and see what happens and
this is what we saw
initially so essentially will get post
requests
against to specific resources cash
or policy pounds but interesting
particularity so
none other requests will never have a
user agent there was always
you use a unique eighty Heather now for
some reason
and the the post will have a cough of
course a binary
bill included so very quickly
after calling a we saw
around 5 a half a million infections
on over maybe a twenty-four hour we know
on the first day this picture that you
can see is
is the geographical distribution of the
fictions
over 10 minutes time frame so it's
what checking under on a CNC measure
over 10 minutes and you get this picture
it's a lot more of course but or 10
minutes is the
is what you see edit speak it reach
reached a bit over one million
infections with its
like marching said it's a fairly big
mouth your
the one interesting fact
was thats their were absolutely zero
connections coming from China I was
don't know why
met thats that effect we didn't do with
any connections from China and then
the up to this moment was okay we have
here some
fairly large what that but we have
absolutely no idea what it is so let's
try to do some
research on top of its because just as a
reminder this was all
based on network traffic observation
rather than samples
mean at this point there was no no
samples to deal with which is good is
big and is that it's good because you
can see
things when they start right but you
it's not
it's not easy to associate it with a
known our family much
okay and so this when I came in I
as you have set the all these they died
Misrata
belongs to an that works is as I put a
very little to do with my top friends
with them
but partner that owns my brain
and my salary so it yeah this one when I
came in a
rows up a a at this this this funny new
but that's very light
using the main from the the Soviet Union
which
as many will knows is very popular among
muppets
yeah with you know what what so we are
was not have a look
would kreitzer is possible seems the
algorithms idea
never look at so many Albertans in such
a short period of time
party won with Matt's which he didn't
but I thought this maybe
it is the botnet moved to a new over
them that's Italian for a while
no wasn't italian a directly competing
for a vault that might be cell
Saudi because of some some similarities
but in the end
not 0x
was in the news when we did research
because October November last year have
been some major breakdowns
and about but possibly try to come back
so kinda made sense that
directors with by newer seems the I were
them but
no wasn't but here we were at a bit of a
loss
and I'm WEA we're a
export before perhaps it isn't the
botnet perhaps it is on bloatware using
some DJ using the Jade not illegal or
anything
brem
well what do you want whenever all else
fails value
look at 10 the botnet sponsors
and you just and some Google we ended
the remainder
the main that's right single Google
seeing if
someone else to do nets that we found
some farce total results:
mural kruzel political happy people in
this room who
and the distance so what happened up the
because a single
farms total nor your query
tell you anything interesting but we
found one interesting
will result summer in Thailand's as a
local network
with you Squid proxy sometimes happens
for all
8 be complications on that network and
its proxy had a and web server woulda
the log at this locus accessible in
public and within that by Google
and it's not still there and it doesn't
go back away from
to where we were evident extremes amber
it's still there
you can see the every day you can see be
going on
you can see a is for one particular IP
address on
on that network for a few days ago you
can even see a
for every domain when it was access what
at
what I'm they accessed 8 you can
bill to pick you up but someone was
axing of course it is completely
harmless because all matter data
and we know method as harmless you can
fight me
you find a lot so we could find out
which use on this network
with no do you would want but some
use on computer on the network was axing
single I found some interesting things
because it happened several times
several days in a row and shortly before
he was always connects
made what is my IP which is
site that tells your IP address and
afterwards was also was a resume to
this free the main on silica I get its
name
didn't know what it meant but yet some
no I P E
the main aim and thirdly we saw some
links to
some at where but but that doesn't say
very much because if you find someone in
fact that that probably
agrees to be effective it is but the not
very
with that security hygiene so probably
running at work too
doesn't necessarily mean that they're
linked a and follow through to its
and it was network censors did find some
other
correlation between these to sleep the
first two domains and
an hour single and then of course
this is that this IP address of course
is the biggest resolved to our
Osama some IP address which
I'm its let's roll thru looked around
and he got
for the day what the but with the the
next up even be
and it turns out if you could park total
the at some point similar
the main aim was off to its oliver Sony
more .biz
which is interesting
especially because the heat and found
that this domain at indeed in serving
Mirada me what's
with okay perhaps perhaps we r tasting
the smaller around the time
Websense published was actually a very
good blog
on on on Nevada unfortunately a
as sometimes happens the blocks it was
added by a PR person who
a wrote at this point loss primary
target in the business services
government manufacturing transportation
sectors in the US UK Canada and India
with sound really scary of course if you
have a book but with a million
infections them be out for some of them
all
be there that they really made it sound
like to come talk to attack them into
people's
came from russia would make even scarier
and stuff like that it's important
because I
really the the result is is one of the
best that's written about that
my father and Anna for example it it all
those
the it said the following that it on
C&C IP addresses in one particular as an
and and appears that I showed use like
to go
we're on the same is an so then we were
even more so than it is once bottom we
found some more
lens and and we
we also found some more his twenty
domains
not and said this is a agility and would
like to set
to that name so again we and it in
Google
if owners only one person at least on
the internet with his name
it's a doctor in summer in America okay
well happens doctors will have a MPI
numbers website where a collective I
don't know what MPI numbers but
arguments about a book tour experts in
number but is this
all of us on me and Google interest me
also find a doctor gotta love a sunny
and a perfume order domains
when I don't know how to pronounce but
the app
again as a doctor that
is this one letter missing in the in a
domain name and
they're not even on using an IP .biz
using another
for your DNS provider and again that the
doctor again with the FBI number
now at this point I thought for a few
days this is an extremely cool bday to
use
what he uses number with MPI number
which had some %uh generates and then
they use this to you got the name of the
corresponding doctor and uses the main
I thought Rd I'm gonna talk Elizabeth
gone everyone will be so excited
and I'll be so proud are turned out to
be it wasn't that
Anna its it's probably just their main
if you're if you're a bother you about
ninety probably have a lot of
data comes from data breaches you
probably have a lot of names
doctors available or you just knew you
can find names are you it's their domain
names because of course
these domains if you would look damn
you could come across them you're in
some research they look on at the loop
in
with them unlike domains
but while so that these DJ's
Bhutto randy mature you produce or that
it's something that is going on so am
conflict at the bailouts I am this is
the
the content of the POST request and X
number of it I'm so you're ignited
a lower opening I don't they it's
completely random
that is a.m. well it looks random like
this
but between multiple were quite schisms
as I said we sell millions the the first
nine
bites always the same and as a lot of
similarities which means that
the its leader just obfuscation
or its encryption with the same
encryption key
we don't know in an as far as I'm aware
no one knows what
is really means what you don't need to
know because you can just reply to bail
out you get something back
and and it if you can see that because
the h2b
response and get some days on back i
three some error but
but interestingly as this problem
mining protocol inherit some more
and which was indeed
a pic on mining server which
which go to this book Matt what's
actually being used to mind but courts
I know is not the most efficient way use
a botnet
from a from side could not want a few
but still it's
its gonna give you some money this is
Hughes botnet
even know from being most effective
older not very powerful computers
okay so
what have we learned the
and we see what we learned about the
book that's all this unknown
the g8 17 that that's real talk about
that's how we call it but they call it
internally before
before we knew it was my thought is was
indeed if I it was a unknown
or variance with me either it was the
split of the door friend of the botnet
or it was always been completely
separate I think
the former is more likely because if you
look at the number of gratitude for
network during October
when we 30 the singles to questions
at every drop from five to four million
around the time
when its routing authority that is from
0 to
1 million side the mood would make sense
but they're might be other reasons why
this happened it might be a coincidence
this book that was very
very light more than one million
infections the
admit what it was in gates in bit by
mining apart from certain hiding with
meds before and then other people had
founded
performing click fraud all three
relatively harmless case of cybercrime
compared to other things
it's not a rat or anything bad but still
bad and of course if you're affected
then in fact is you computer and a good
something worse
its place now since the
to beat it is we because the research I
think in November last year at
and it was never block few things happen
the
Facebook April this year they erode
about
a new go to court knew my father very in
doesn't use store burger book both the
set by
that the new very the what they call 78
I am more or less what we already seen
did not want some investing resorts
confront basically what we saw
a month later
Microsoft the released its this report
about the
last quarter of 2013 and it said that
notorious about mister released a report
about the for three quarters of 2014
and it said that compared to the last
three quarters of 20 13
the number of effected computers dumb
from 6,000 to
18 number key and
and this was not so much you to miss a
lot or seven as the caller themselves
but you too
at where that the fund relate to it Adam
previously
block to clean up its at work because
didn't seem to do anything
arm for nanoparticles be spreading
what's
a day and I think rightly made decided
with made him decide
yet is on for the the cleanup and then
a because there was the cliffhanger
in July 2014 divided yet Michael
published
blog post Friday they found the
a connection with some but some hardware
and what actually found a particular
hardware
this this routing and Nevada
which is developed by Israeli company
called by barry a limit
with with with I think would welcome but
plane by whatever integrated front door
to or from his own more because as we
all know
most moral try to avoid infecting
because in their own country that's the
best way to keep
local police the way up since been told
there are quite a few at work companies
based in Israel
all trying to do legal things but not
always succeeding
insane be gone this I would think with
creek crossing the line
am okay so conclusions
dating but nice doesn't have to start
with more samples even if involve more
samples
we had some samples me run in some boxes
but
there has to be a bit more why doesn't
really up to these days I mean
Meyer my understanding of assembly is is
worse than my friends which has a lot
send you a you can still you can still
do more analysis:
and fine things I'm that's a lot of
useful information about it on the
internet
and detailed on the public Internet
indexed by Google google it
has been will be the most useful to
after a after networks
single singles for his research
botnet some but not a really big
and even if you don't hear about them
but still there don't just bigger
get your ideas from
from the news and finally and we're work
nicely on time
at work and serve more than just at San
and this hopefully will not be surprised
to anyone in this room I think it can be
repeated
questions
how come to or saw an increase
in in visitors from China if
move idea was not in China sorry okay
it they sit did pope from roger was that
israel is the only country that in a
scenic recent war but yet
there wasn't any infection in China a
know does not crack it wasn't any
investment I differently the
different we looked at was unknown
barbarian and secondly
the we don't know why it's not in China
but we sold
every time let's make that a single just
before at like
seconds before at the connection is made
to what is my IP which
which makes me sick make as believe that
the it something else when a if
fire would find it was in China probably
using the same do I P database
that but what it might be used and what
and it was not used to determine
location of connections
given that there were more than a
million different IP address collecting
the 24-hour period I would
the if we're just tryna blocking
something or
then I would expect I'll to show few
stinar walking on on apps and perfect it
was really
na Nov million network Mexican from
China
a bundler programs that were
distributing Sep net yeah
more popular in China they weren't
popular time you never signed
but not popular doesn't I mean icons are
not popular but
no connection from one million
from the largest internet your country
in the world there may have been some
functionality in the under
under programs themselves wouldn't
percent those particular packages in
China but
I mean I I would expect I can imagine
that the and it would be very low but
someone would visit synar with that
became infected
in in in another country so I wouldn't
expect a few
a persecuted at but that I
I don't know but thanks two things from
me first the
am should have publicly thing to me was
for the work you did on going
besos night got that's ok credit where
credit's due thank you very much
you're a great help and to anyone else
in the room I've also gotten
secondly you mentioned you City GA is no
legal
in the UK nothing across most
law enforcement is connected with a
crime
then it is admitted possessing it UK if
its link with fraud rinsing
we can prosecute people just for having
it because an article for use in
connection with fraud so
just the their more ways to skin
capped again I i chipset when I said
there was no I'm not a lawyer a
policeman
have made is up on the flight are
robbing a legal yes you know more help
you know more about Lola night
it's my yearly exercise
a.m. more question regarding
you're singling has more for your
college arm the thing is
from I was willing or you do you is a at
the girls
up for yeltsin called by pushing that
over there
and/or you distinguish arm legitimate
conflict that ends in calling
and yea depends on
on down the mall where we do quite a bit
of work on some
particular families to make sure that
the a request is made against
a single matches what we would expect
from from an effective device
I think that can can can happen
for sure if you mean
the making a request just get registered
as being effective
you can do that to register your IP
address
there there are there are it's typical
that we will see
stuff hitting like rollers like others
rather research group
inquiries SP normal actually cemar
bad guys doing that whenever
never get it you still have time for
another question
to come here to the back as well
hi my name is then is an action from
Israel
pretty nice book thank you Persephone
and no
really its action enough I evidence do
can't have you conducted the guys from
the Israel the two
think responsible for this stuff sorry
havoc on the the guy from
Arcand your name the Israeli company
as a if you think a responsible for
causing this it yet but but but but that
research with what's
Trend Micro polish that mind a lot your
so it's Trend Micro's made the research
and the Canadian Theatre understand and
we
and you have you contacted them
and why the answer and
any bro any any process from there men
I human no answer or interesting okay
her
the red button
that %uh that's kind of what I meant
with all the way up leads over lines
these people were dead we tried not to
be illegal but that that sometimes fail
and we can all set up might not for how
to not because after shooting
at work companies in the first place but
but the best we can do is is work with
damaged or
they don't the Three Little Pigs I think
this company
if the polly pocket about already and I
do hope made clear that the did
companies bit was research by Michael
that's why I speech on their
I just want to all the loose ends getter
that happened since we didn't
thank you