greetings everyone and welcome to my
talk about hunting bugs in javascript
core with codeql
our journey begins when we wake up in
the middle of nowhere and this guy is
approaching us and start talking to us
saying hey you you're finally awake you
were trying to find bugs in the realm of
javascript core huh walked right into
that ambush same as us and that hacker
over there
who are you
so before i'll introduce myself if
you're not if you're not recognizing the
following reference congratulations
you're not a complete nerd like i do
this is from skyrim
who am i
my name is asafseon and i work as a
security researcher at cyberlock i enjoy
ctfing and playing video games in my
free time
uh here are my i'm level 24 of course
here are my character my character stats
so i'm somewhat skilled in code ql but
i'm not so skilled in javascript core
exploitation
uh
my goals my character goals are use
codeql to find bugs in javascript core
and of course have fun
finally my character state of mind is
that i'm 100 positive and 100 excited so
without further further ado let's begin
during this talk we'll have three major
checkpoints the first checkpoint will
cover the fundamentals of quad ql will
get a very good cultural introduction
we'll see some cool and basic examples
with codeql and there is gonna be even a
boss fight so stay tuned
at the second part of our talk we'll
review javascript core as a javascript
engine we'll talk about how javascript
core processes javascript instructions
what type of jit engines there are in
javascript core
and what are side effects in javascript
finally
we'll talk about bed side effect
modeling bugs
a type of a bar class that exists in the
in javascript engines and
then finally after that we'll
we'll find out how how we can use code
ql to find these types of
bugs let's begin
this is going to be a very short
introduction to code ql and i mean very
short this is me on the left side
what is codeql for whom of you are not
familiar with codeql yet codeql is a
framework created by a company called
saml which is now owned and developed by
github
codeql in its core is a query language
it is very similar to sql it lets a
researcher listen with code using tools
from logic
it has some cool syntactic sugar from
object oriented programming like
inheritance and class methods we can use
the code qlcli cli
you should know that the code ul engine
the code urcli is the codeul engine
which can execute codeql queries so we
can use the code qlcli cli
to to turn codebase into database it
supports many programming languages such
as c plus plus java and many more
it has tons i mean tons of great
features
to analyze code uh for example data flow
analysis that we're gonna look like
we're gonna review today but it has many
more i
i encourage you to read about it later
when working with coql there is a
general workflow that will
that we will usually follow
at first the researcher will choose the
open source project and make sure he can
build it
after that
clean the the solution and then rebuild
it again but this time use the code
qlcli
next select a bug class that you want to
discover analyze it understand that
backlash very well and understand how
that bad class might appear in the code
base that you chose
then write a query that finds the
backlash and make sure it works by
executing that query against the prior
known vulnerable version of that project
you chose to analyze that's a pro tip so
make sure that the query finds all
vulnerabilities from that same backlash
in prior versions
finally execute your query against an
up-to-date database and hopefully find
new bugs
query structure so each query will
consist out of three parts there are
very similar that are very similar to
sql we have the from class if you're not
familiar with sql the front class this
is where we're going to define all the
codeql elements that we are going to use
next the word class
although this clause is optional uh it
is the very essence of your query so uh
this is where all the logic of your
query will be in
so
although it is optional it's quite
mandatory if you want to have uh
complex uh queries
finally this is the select clause this
is where we choose how our output is
going to look like
now that we've learned what what is the
general purpose of codeql we can start
our training
okay who is this lovely npc this lovely
npc says hello there do you mind helping
me with some code ql queries
sure
sure thing let's help her
our first quest requires us to find all
the variable declarations in a given
code base and this task is very simple
this is the first mini quest so
this task is very simple at first
we'll import c plus plus this tells
codeql to use the c plus plus standard
library that exists within the coqueur
library
we don't need a where clause in this
query since we don't want to find since
we want to find all the variable
declarations
so let's define the form clause
variable you see form variable var so
variable is a codeql element from the c
plus plus library it represents a
variable declaration form the abstract
syntax tree that represents our code
eventually
then we simply have to select val this
will select all the variable
declarations
amazing so let's see
i use the vs code to run my queries and
this is how the output should look like
when executing that query against the
database created from webkit
we can even click the results and review
them so let's click for example the host
it will take us to the uh actual
declaration of host in the webkit
project and indeed we can see that uh
this is the declaration of host
awesome
in our second quest we need to find all
the function calls to the malloc
function this is a bit more complicated
than the previous one but not too much
okay so import c plus plus we already
talked about this earlier now we know
that we need to extract the calls all
the calls so let's use the
element the codeql element that
represents every call in our code
from function call call to malloc call
to malloc is now
a representation of a function call in
our codebase
then before inserting any constraints
let's select the call to malloc if we
run this query
this will extract all the calls to all
the functions so let's narrow down it
let's narrow it down by by adding the
where clause
well and then call to malloc dot get
target get target will return the the
actual function
the that the function call element
called to
and then all we got to do is uh use the
has name this will this way we make sure
that the function we called has the name
malloc and then execute the the query
here are the results we can see that
there are over 500 calls to malloc in
the webkit project select one click it
and here is the call to
the relevant function
maluk in our case of course
okay we have a boss fight you think
you're clever aren't you find every
expression that controls an allocation
size
every expression that controls an
allocation size
okay
in order to win the boss fight we would
have to use some data flow analysis
don't get intimidated by the phrase data
flow analysis it's very simple
we would simply need to find which
expressions
flow into the first argument of a malloc
function call let me remind you the
first argument of the malloc function
call is the size the
malloc receives one argument which tells
malloc what's the size of the buffer you
should allocate so we want to find every
expression that flows into that first
argument
again import c plus plus very similar
the first part of the query
is practically the same only that we
added a third
uh a third
element this element called expression
uh it represents every expression in a
codebase so it's very abstract it
contains
a lot a lot i mean a lot but we're gonna
use it in a more precise matter later on
uh okay
now the this is the first part so uh
right now uh the function call element
fc
holds all the calls to malloc like we
did previously
now
let's use a predicate called local
expression flow
this
this way we can define the source and
the sink in our data flow analysis now
this predicate says
find all the flows all the expressions
that flow into the first argument of fc
fc is a call to malloc the first
argument of fc
is the
size of that allocation and we want to
make sure that source represents an
expression that flows into that first
argument if you don't understand it
let's see an example how the results are
going to look like
okay on the left column we can see all
the expressions that control the
allocation size of a call to malloc
on the right column we can see the
corresponding call to the malloc so
let's click one of the results uh here
we chose a call to a jstring get maximum
utf
8 string size
two uh
to the size argument of the
milo call let's click the
the result
uh and this is indeed what it's going to
look like
so we can see that
by calling that function the returned
value uh flows into the variable j size
which is then passed as an argument
to the mallow call
awesome
i think that was it yeah that was the
first part of our talk congratulations
that's the first checkpoint
let's move on to the second part of our
journey by entering the rem of
javascript core
that's me hello there
so what is javascript core javascript
call is the javascript engine for
webkit
meaning each javascript instruction
executed via safari is actually handled
and executed via javascript core now
before we'll dive into the fundamentals
of javascript core i want us to learn a
little bit about side effects in
javascript you'll understand why we have
to do it now later on but what are side
effects in javascript
a javascript operation causes side
effects
if it modifies the state
of other variables outside the local
environment of that instruction
that's a long way to define side effects
in javascript so let's see a more uh
real example
let's review it this is an example for
not triggering side effects in
javascript so for example concutting a
string with an empty object uh
i'm sure you know the the answer a will
now hold the this a will now have the
string hello with curly braces at the
end of it
that's the that's a a is now a string
with a low concatenated with the curly
braces at the end of it
but and this is
very interesting but concatenating a
string
with an object that have a function
uh
the if the function if the object has a
function property named to string
this will set the value of a to
something completely different
the function to string does two things
at first it will print to this to the
console the string side effect here
and then it will return the string b
sides
concurring a low with this object will
trigger the call to tostring and we'll
set the value of a to the string hello b
sides
and of course we'll print to the console
the string side effects here now this is
where the side effects occurs the mere
fact that we were able to execute a
different function that has nothing to
do with the concatenation meaning that
we managed to trigger side effects in
javascript now i want to i want you to
understand this is perfectly normal it's
not a bug it's not i don't know a
security flaw nothing like that side
effects are perfectly normal they are
part of the the way javascript works and
they're crucial to it
uh okay
keep that in mind now let's dive into
the implementation of js adnan number
js adnan number is the
is a function that written in c it's
part from the
javascript core engine so
every time we're going to call the uh
use the plus operator uh javascript call
will execute c code and that c code is
the function js adnan number
uh this function implements uh adding a
non-number in javascript core of course
okay at first js adnan number will check
if the first argument is a string let me
remind you the first argument
is the string hello and it is a string
so it will continue next it will check
if the second argument is not an object
now let me remind you the second
parameter the second argument
is indeed an object so this
check will return false
if it will return false it will call a
different function called js ed slow
case which will call
the method
to primitive the this method will be
called from the first argument
it will try to convert the first
argument which is the string hello into
a primitive object a primitive object in
javascript is basically a number or a
string
but the first argument is already a
string which means it's already a
primitive object so nothing will happen
here
it will try to convert the second
argument to a primitive object now this
is where the
interesting part happens so when we
try to concatenate an empty object what
happened is that return we got a string
with curly braces meaning that the chord
to two primitive converted the object to
the string curly braces but now we have
a different function in the that's
called tostring to primitive
will search for the
javascript property to string and if
that property exists and it's a valid
function
javascript call will call that function
and eventually this is where
this function is a function that we
completely control
and this is where the side effects
are triggered
okay
so now that we've learned a little bit
about side effects we can focus on
javascript code as promised
so to understand the guts of javascript
call we should first be familiar with
the differences between javascript and c
sometimes be compiled by a just-in-time
compiler
also c is statically typed meaning we
must declare the argument types and the
return value types when writing a new
function
on the other hand javascript is
dynamically typed language meaning we
don't have to declare anything when
writing a new function the same function
can choose to handle whatever type she
wants to
and finally c allows us to have low
level controls such as
direct memory management and even
control over the stack or heap layout
but javascript is pretty much powerful
for everything else
javascript can go fast
this is where jit compilation comfort
comes for the rescue there are photos
that an instruction can live in
javascript so
the first deal we already talked about
it it's the
low level interpreter compiler
this basically takes the javascript
instructions and compiles them into byte
code it's not
it's not actual code that the processor
can execute
it's by code that the javascript engine
then we have the baseline jit
there is no additional logic regarding
the relation between other instruction
what so on it simply takes the
instructions find
there are plenty of templates in the
javascript call code base and it will
take the template for example we want to
add two numbers it will take the
operation add numbers uh using a
template and it will produce the byte
the the assembly code that represents
that very function that's very operation
next we have the data flow graph jit
compiler
at first javascript
core will represent a given piece of
code or an operation and it will turn it
into data flow graph we will then
see how a data flow graph look like
but it will apply several optimizations
uh on that data flow graph depending on
the relations between
the nodes in the graph
and finally it will compile the data
flow graph using the jit compiler
and the final tier is the ftl faster
than light jit
which highly focuses on optimizing the
compiled code it will simply take all
the optimizations that the data flow
graph jit applied and will ignore the
relation it will simply apply
all the optimizations in it can to a
given piece of code without taking uh in
mind the cost it will take to do so
okay so let's see an illustration of how
javascript core creates a data for graph
for a simple function here we have fu
foo is very simple it simply takes an
argument
it returns the multiplication of the
argument's first
index property with the property y from
this object
now in order to compile the function
using the dfg-jit compiler we need to
execute that function approximately a
thousand times
so to do so we just put a for loop that
will call that function a thousand times
and by doing so uh
we will
compile that function using the dfg jit
after doing so let's look at the pseudo
data flow graph created for that
function
and of course
at the beginning we set arg as the
argument
next we make sure that alg is an array
the reason for that is that
we access the first index property of
out and therefore it must be an array
if it is an array we're going to create
and save this object into v0
and then we will fetch the property y
from this and save it under v1
finally we load the index property 0
from arg
and multiply v1 with v2 and return it
as mentioned earlier one of the biggest
advantages of the telephone graph jit
compiler is its optimizations redundancy
elimination is a core optimization in
the delfo graph jit compiler
by using the relations between the nodes
in the dataflow graph it can determine
which guards are redundant and which are
not which are crucial in a matter of
fact each redundant guard will be
removed pre-compilation and it will save
time while executing that code
so let's take a look at the following
function which which returns the
division of the two properties fetched
from uh arg
so the data flow graph will look like
that at first we'll set alg as an
argument
then we'll make sure that algae is an
object
because we fetch properties from that uh
argument
then we'll fetch one one argument so for
example we'll fetch y
and then we'll check again that arg is
still an object if it is an object will
fetch x as well
and finally we return the division
between these two
if property y exists the second check is
redundant
why
because
nothing has changed in object in our
object so there is no reason to make
sure that it's still an object nothing
happens y exists everything is good
let's save some time during the
execution and that's exactly what
javascript call does
but what can go wrong
if by fetching y it could cause side
effects an attacker can change the value
of alg and change it and change it from
object to a different type
then javascript call will think that alg
is an object because we remove that
check and even though it is not an
object and this could
lead into type confusion bugs which
could help an attacker achieve remote
code execution
we know that removing necessary checks
can allow an attacker to achieve remote
code execution
in order to deal with that issue
javascript call must know which
operation can cause side effects and
under which terms
for example adding two numbers cannot
cause side effects
but as we saw earlier adding a string
with an object can indeed cause side
effects and javascript core must be a
well
so javascript call must read the
argument types as well
the side effect modeling is done by the
function execute effects you can see the
full path
in the slide
under each case
that function will hold a giant switch
case
each case represents a javascript
operation
javascript call under each case will
determine uh if an operation can cause
side effects and if that operation can
cause side effects can cause side
effects javascript core will call a
function called clobber wall so let's
take a look at an example
uh
right here this is a actual snippet from
javascript core
from the execute effects function
you can see both upper operations can
cause side effects according to the
modeling of javascript call because
under both cases there is a call to club
a wall one here
and one there
but at the final
uh operation at the third one we can see
that the javascript call can assume that
this operation cannot cause side effects
because there is no call to global
warming
all right
this was the second part of our talk
we've learned that the data flow graph
jit compiler can be an interesting
surface for an attacker to find new bugs
in javascript core of course when
focusing on the redundancy elimination
optimization combined with side effects
in javascript
now let's try to make the world a safer
place by hunting this bug bugs ourself
using codeql perfect
that's me
now before writing new and complex
queries we should understand the bug
that we're hunting as best as possible
and this tip applies to every bug you're
hunting especially if you're using code
qr so let's analyze together a
vulnerability found in 2018 that allowed
an attacker to achieve full remote core
execution via safari
this vulnerability of course is
triggered by bad side effect modeling
of the instance of operation
let's start with the let's start from
the end
by answering the question how did they
patch the this bug
uh and let's let's understand the patch
it's very simple
both snippets you can see
it's divided to two both snippets were
taken from the function execute effects
the function
that
as we've mentioned earlier is
responsible for modeling for side effect
modeling in javascript core
on the left side we can see the
vulnerable version and on the right side
the patched one the developers simply
added a call to club of wall under the
case that represent the instance of
operation
this is the only
line that was added to the code in order
to fix that bug
so this will
this tells us that the vulnerability
is indeed uh around the uh side effect
modeling the javascript call was doing
to that operation
you can see they only added a call to
global wall in order to fix the bug
we know that the instance of operation
wasn't modeled correctly therefore we
simply need to find how it is possible
to trigger side effect using that
operation
to do so let's take a look at a part of
the exploit
at first
we only need to create two classes two
empty classes
then
we create a new object named handler
that have a single function property
called get prototype off
uh the doesn't matter what the function
does this is where we're gonna put the
malicious exploit but eventually it will
return a class prototype
then we replace the prototype of trigger
class with a proxy object this is very
impro important we replace the prototype
object with a proxy
object and the pro the prototype the
proxy object now has a
the handler that we defined earlier
and finally all we need to do is uh
of course compile uh instance of using
the data flow graph jit and then call
instance of as follow this would
trigger the bug
the reason for that is that javascript
call already thinks that
instanceof cannot cause side effects
meaning that we see now that in order to
trigger side effects using the instance
of operation we need to do something uh
with the with replacing its prototype
with a proxy object that's the final uh
goal of that code snippet let's try to
understand how the operation of instance
off is implemented
so this is the implementation of
it that is inside the javascript call
meaning it's written in c it's not the
javascript implementation it's
javascript core implementation
uh at first it will call the default has
instance
uh
which will eventually uh heal we'll call
the method get prototype
object is the argument so uh trigger
class is our object and the method the
method that will be called is get
prototype
uh of course trigger class is an object
so we're gonna go to the implementation
of get prototype from a js object and
then
oh okay
well what happened here we replaced if
you remember we replaced the prototype
of
of trigger class with a proxy object so
the actual
get prototype
function that will be called is from
proxy object not from js object but
proxy object and that function has a
completely different implementation
this function
uh will actually fetch the handler
the proxy object handler and it will
call the
get prototype of
a javascript function that we control
and this is where the side effects occur
great
we are looking for okay so let's try to
define the
that bug and i hope you understood that
bug
let's try to define that bug using code
ql
are looking for an operation that a
javascript call would not call
cloverwall
under the execute effect function
and b
that function can trigger side effects
even though javascript code assumed it
cannot
how do we define the side effects at all
so there are three major challenges
we need to solve in order to make our
query useful
at first we need to model each operation
for side effects ourselves using colquel
although this challenge is very
interesting to solve i've decided that
we will not talk about this in this talk
because due to time constraints but rest
assured that the entire query is
available in a public repo and i added a
link to that report at the end of the
slides
we'll focus on solving the second
challenge
which is finding which operations can
trigger side effects
specifically speaking we're looking for
operations that can trigger side effects
using a proxy object
so it's the same
[Music]
way that the instance of
operation trigger side effects after
this presentation i encourage you all to
modify the query so that it will find
other timeout strings that's
defining the side effect this is like
the crucial part of the query
so the side effect that we're looking
for
is constructed out of three parts the
first part receives a parameter with the
type of js object or
somewhere during the flow of that
operation a parameter will be converted
into a js object
then there is a method called form that
js object
and finally there must be a different
method from the class proxy object that
shares the same name as the called
method from js object
let's remember we want to find operation
that handles with js object
the simplest scenario
is the following where the operation
receives as its input as one of its
parameters adjacent objects like here
let's write the query real quick
we'll import c plus plus
[Music]
and we have two
codeql elements the first one is
variable which represents all the
variable declarations and another one a
variable x axis which represents all the
accesses to a variable
this way we tell codql that we are
looking for a
variable from the type js object
and then all we got to do is link the
variable access to that variable
and now js object access represents an
access to a js object variable
but what if the operation receives a
generic type and it will then convert
that argument into a js object like this
so here we see that the parameters
are different from js object but
somewhere in the code we convert base
which is a parameter into a js object
okay let's try to do it with coql at
first let's define all the co-ql
elements
we have a function call which represents
all the calls to function and variable
axis which represents all the accesses
to a variable
now that we define the
the expressions
let's let's make sure that
as object will point will hold all the
calls to as object like here
and then we can extract
its argument we we're interested in the
argument so let's link the variable uh
the all the expressions as object
arguments and make sure that they are
inside
that they received as an argument to the
as object function this way
then we'll use data flow analysis again
to find the flow from the return value
of the function as object to all the js
object accesses
like so
the first dataflow analysis
is from uh
a parameter of a js object this is the
first uh argument
uh to the argument of a of the function
js object
like here and then we we simply need to
find the
data flow uh using the data flow
analysis
the second flow is from the return value
of the function as object
like here
to every js object access js object
access is like this one or this one and
then we have to find the flow
if there is a valid flow in a certain
javascript core operation we know that
somewhere doing that execution a
parameter will be converted to a js
object and this is exactly what we're
looking for
now that we find all the interesting js
object accesses all we need to do is to
make sure there is a method called
form.js object
and that there is a different method in
the class proxy object that shares its
name with the called method we found
let's do it with coql
a quick recap by now we were able to
identify every operation that has an
argument which is a js object or
somewhere in the flow of the code will
convert one of its argument into a js
object
now we need to find if somewhere in the
code there is a call to a method from
that js object
not only that that method must share the
same name with an existing method from
proxy object
let's start by defining the codeql
elements so as usual
as usual
jsobject method will represent a method
from the class js object
and this is how we can do it with coql
yeah so
we
we basically bound the js object get
using get qualifier to the js object so
the qualifier to the get prototype
method is a object an object is a js
object
let's bound the element from the element
from proxy this is supposed to represent
a method called form the proxy class
by the way this is
not the only way to bound uh from proxy
this is that's the way that i chose
but
from proxy is an object and we make sure
that the scope of that function
belongs to from proxy a proxy object
sorry
you can choose the different approach to
achieve the same result
finally
we want both message methods to share
the same name so we compare the js
object method name with the from proxy
name
like so
and eventually we need to execute it so
this will find
all the
js
js operations
that
handles with a
proc with the
sorry the handles js objects
and uh
that these js objects call methods that
share the same name with a proxy object
we can now extract all the operations
that can cause side effects uh the side
effect that we defined earlier but that
javascript core assumes they cannot
cause side effects and this is exactly
where the bug lies in
so finally after running our query
against the database compiled
from the vulnerable version of
javascript code we got this result
we can see that there are four potential
vulnerable operations one of them is
indeed the vulnerable instance of so
this is a success already but what about
the rest
although i could not approve that all
four operations are vulnerable i did
found that the operation create this is
indeed vulnerable and this is awesome
this vulnerability was discovered by
cielo and it shares the same
characteristics as the instance of bug
so this is definitely strength my
intuition regarding the correctness of
the query
let's have a quick recap a summary of
what we've talked about
by now
that's me
we are a calculator tutorial
we talked about what is codeql what's
the structure of a query in codeql
we've talked about the building blocks
uh
of codecoil
for example variable function call and
we even talked about data flow analysis
in code ql
then we talked about javascript core we
had a javascript core 101 session
talked about the differences between
javascript and c
javascript side effects
and javascript called execution tiers
the all the jit compilers that exist in
that
and finally we've talked about bad side
effect modeling bugs
what are the po what are the what is the
potential of these bugs how lo how to
look for them and how to translate these
bugs into cultural query queries if
you're interested in further reading uh
you can of course read about uh
a blog post that i posted that talks
about the codeul in more details
and then of course the blog post that i
posted about the mysterious realm of
javascript core
and the
github link
to the query itself
and that's it thank you very much
besides budapest i hope you enjoyed that
talk
and i'm
available for any questions that you
might have
via twitter or email
feel free to contact me
and thank you thank you very much
have a
nice day and enjoy the rest of the
the conference