hello everyone good morning good
afternoon good evening wherever you are
in the world
my name is vivek malik and together with
my colleague kumar vikramjeet we'll have
a short discussion about a project that
we recently open sourced
next
who are we a couple of words about us
we are adobe's security intelligence
team which is part of adobe's security
coordination center the purpose of the
team is to do data science research and
security field we mostly focus on
reactive security and that is basically
identifying threats that cannot be
detected by a conventional ways in other
words we use the logs and security data
that we collect from adobe's assets and
we try to find anomalies and the bad
stuff uh the part of the members of this
team are andre kotai iberi boros kumar
vikram jeet myself vivek malik
next
osas or one stop anomaly shock this is a
machine learning framework aimed to
discover anomalies in a given data set
the open source project represents an
implementation of several adobe security
intelligence teams patents white papers
and other projects the goal of osas is
to make it as easy as possible to
experiment with different data sets
algorithms and feature combinations and
find the most balanced combination for
your own use case as well as data
but most importantly
osas will try to answer why an anomaly
is considered actually an anomaly
to better understand this
uh let's really uh talk fast about
anomaly detection
next
the anomaly detection principle uh this
principle is as simple as pi
anomalies represent extremely rare
events the more complex question is how
there are some well-known algorithms for
outlier detection such as local outlier
factor or the isolation forest k means
and distance from
the center of a cluster error
reconstruction and so on sometimes these
algorithms generate anomalies
and our stock or security experts don't
understand why these are actually
anomalies and the simple answer
anomalies represent an extremely rare
event um that is not enough for them so
coming back to anomaly detection
principle let's look at the picture uh
in the slide and try to identify an
anomaly
everyone's first reaction would be the
egg that is of a different color
that is the brown egg is an anomaly and
maybe you're right but if you look close
enough at the picture
all the eggs are wearing facial masks
except maybe two or three so maybe
that's an anomaly that i'm actually
looking for
the bottom line is the way you prepare
your data is going to influence what
kind of anomalies you generate so the
data preparation is fundamentally very
important
next
now let us try to bring more context to
our egg situation and briefly briefly
describe each one of them
so we see a couple of eggs appear to be
in love one is sneezing one definitely
has eye problems some are mad some are
scared and so on now this is important
because the fact that we have a brown
egg is not the most exotic feature
anymore the sneezing egg becomes
important the egg that is crank is also
unique and so on in other words what we
propose is falling we'll describe each
observation eggs here in this case with
a set of labels and then let anomaly
detection algorithms decide which ones
are actually the anomalies and the way
we generate labels becomes the entire
magic so you see in this
picture
uh
the egg white has mask open eyes and
then needs eye surgery that becomes the
outcome of an algorithm similarly egg
white has mask open eyes and love or has
maybe chicken pox looks surprise becomes
the
uh
outcome of our algorithm that we run
another egg that is white has mask open
eyes but is an angry person so
probably that's the anomaly that we are
looking for so these are the labels that
uh we are trying to implement uh with
one stop and normally shop
next
so let's talk about
the tags or the label generators we have
three types of tags i will start by
saying that when we designed osas we had
in mind semi-structured log data this
type of data is usually found in access
logs or error logs from apache tomcat in
hubble and so on hubble by the way is
another open source project from adobe
but you can check it out
this information is semi-structured
because you can infer attributes from
end
for instance while apache log is x based
you can extract timestamp ip addresses
url response code etc etc one important
aspect is that this data contains many
attributes with unbound values for
instance the ip addresses and urls
usually these attributes generate large
feature space
by comparison the number of examples
that can be contained in a manageable
data set and that can be processed by
machine learning algorithms is
relatively small
these two factors combined generate
uh something known as data sparsity an
unwanted effect that makes machine
learning learning algorithms overfit the
training data and generalize poorly on
previously unseen examples to cope this
or to cope with this osas reduces the
large features based by employing a
tagging strategy on the raw data set
this is done before feeding the data to
anomaly detection or classification
algorithm the tagging strategy uses
predefined recipes for specific field
types now this is based on
three type of tagging strategies that we
use the standard tags the text tags and
the expert knowledge
next
uh
there are five types of label generators
under each tagging strategy uh combined
and we're going to go through each of
these uh separately so let's take a look
at the multinomial field uh
the tags provided by these fields is uh
check for the
data that counts like in detection
algorithms uh it counts for unique
attribute values and usually they're
less than 10 unique attribute values the
kind of models that you can run on the
multinomial fields is either start
statistical distribution values or label
based value frequency and special tax
for any unseen data
under numerical fields
usually you can count for unique
attribute values and more than 10
percent of unique values
are available in uh numerical fields all
values should be numerical or there
should be none uh the type of models
that can run are like standard deviation
mean medial uh label based gaussian
probability
finally field combine field combiners um
the detection mechanism uses all
multinomial fields that can be combined
together uh the models that are executed
on field combiners is statistical
distribution of values in the label
based uh frequency on special tags for
the unseen data
next
a text
field
the type of detection is non-numerical
you can only count unique attribute
values and more than 10 percent of
unique values are available
you can compute the algorithms such as
engram language model compute perplexity
of each example mean or standard
deviation and then label based on
gaussian probability
finally expert knowledge
the detection is manual in this case and
the models that you run are keyword or
reject reject space
the labels are generated for matched
instances
next
the anomaly detection algorithms
by default osas has four anomaly
detection algorithms the isolation
forest local outlier factor svd
based uh
anomaly detector or the statistical
engram the first three are specific to
scikit learn and if you want to know
more about how they work we suggest you
consult official documentation and the
papers associated with it the
statistical engram method is an
algorithm designed by us it uses
statistics to compute the probability of
observing combination of tags and
compute the anomaly score using sum of
sum over what is known as the negative
log likelihood
next
in a nutshell the pipeline contains
three main
modules on the left side we have the
data acquisition mode which uses a
security uh
incident event monitoring uh for runtime
and statistically uh compiled data for
training the middle section is called
the labeling or data grooming module and
it applies labels for each
interesting attribute type finally the
right section is the scoring module
which uses one of the three strategies
to assign scores to examples
the three scoring strategies are get
tagged label data compute uh supervised
and unsupervised scoring models and
generate a supervised risk-based anomaly
search for your scene
during training we use statistic data
sets to compute
static data sets to compute statistics
and language models for the attributes
labels label the data set and compute
the model for three scoring strategies
at runtime we just apply all three
elements of the pipeline using
precomputed models and generate a score
for each individual example
previously unseen in the dark side
next
now let kumar take over
thank you vivek
so i'll i'm kumar here i'll go through
the demo so in this demo we'll cover
three important aspects of oss
first we'll look into how to
get it up and running
next we'll run oss with
default
configuration and after that we'll
customize
oss with expert knowledge
and we'll compare how the behavior
changes and how the improvements impact
oss results
so let's get oss
oscs up and running
so in the git page
we can get all the links to get started
with
so the git page has a quick start guide
there are basically two ways to install
oss
you can either
download a pre-compiled image which is
the easier way to get it up and running
and alternatively you can also
build the image locally
and another way can be to just work on
the git repo
and
make changes as per your need
so next we'll go to the
folder where our data set is stored
so in this folder we see there is a csv
file which is our default data set we
are going to use for this demo
so this data set has
around 5 5 000 events and we have also
inserted some of the malicious events
which we want to detect as anomalies
which is our end goal
so we can start with pulling the docker
image
and then we'll run
docker run command
so in this command we are specifying two
ports so the first port is for exposing
oss web service
the second port is for exposing elastic
search kibana front end
the last argument you see where we are
exposing the local folder to osos so
that it can access the default dataset
that we are using
so once we run it
it will
uh
it will initiate the two web service
that uh is basically the front end and
back end of oss so we'll go to the
console link
or we are opening both kibana and the
so once we go to the console
uh we can see whether the
the our test data set is present or not
so we also provide three other oss
endpoints which are not mentioned in the
readme file
but it can be used
so the console basically provides
command line interaction with oss
using the automated pipeline you can run
the entire workflow
and using the generate config endpoint
you can generate the config
so
in the run full process you can run the
entire process without any intervention
and generate config you can generate the
config
by just using the web interface
let's go to the dashboard so this is a
default installation of kibana dashboard
so you can go to
the dashboard link here you'll see there
are like five dashboard links you can
customize as per your
need
here you'll give you'll get all the
stats related to your anomalies
next
so how what what are the steps involved
in building the test pipeline so
basically there are three steps
first you generate
a config file by executing
auto config script
so here we will
execute auto config script and it will
have input as the data set and the
config file that you want to generate
so this config file is basically a set
of configurations for
label generator and
the anomaly detection algorithm that you
want to use
it it contains all the
uh
label generators that the
model will be using
and once you execute it
it will also contain the parameters that
it needs to
execute to contain to generate the model
so after this you have to train the
pipeline
and train pipeline use the last config
file that you generated
and the last step is to just run the
pipeline which will take as input the
model file
and the
input file that
that is our default data set
so we'll look into it
in depth once we start working with the
data set
so these endpoints are not mentioned in
the readme but you can access it so
these are still in work in progress but
this will be fully built
once we are done with it
so now next let's let's use a default
data set and go through the oss
execution
so first we will use the console link to
go through the entire process so let's
check whether the data set is there or
not
so let's see
our folder is apps folder inside the
default dataset is present
and next we'll go
we will proceed with
getting the config file
so we'll execute auto config
and will pass the
dataset as the input dataset
and we'll give it a default config
argument
so once it's done
if you want if you want to edit we can
just go and edit it so we can see that's
present there so we can open it in a
text eraser and edit it as per our
requirement
at the bottom we can see that we are
using statistical and gram anomaly
detection as a scholarly scoring
algorithm
next
we can go forward with
uh training the pipeline
by using this config file that we
already generated
so this will generate the model file
that we want to
uh
run the pipeline on
so once it finishes we will get the
model file
there is a small typo i'll just rerun it
again
after this we have to execute to run
pipeline
that will use the
default
model file that we just generated from
the default configuration of oss
so we'll pass
the same input file
and model file will just need to specify
the output file that is the results file
that we want to use
so once we are done with that we can see
the results in the kibana dashboard
now we'll go to the
dashboard link
and we'll see the results and stats
related to the
execution so it's a default keyboard
installation so the username and
password is just admin admin
and you can configure this front-end as
per your requirement
so in the dashboard we can
see that there are like 5 000
observations and we have used
statistical and gram anomaly
scoring method
and next we can see that there we can
see the max score and min score
that we got for the data set
and
there are around like 43 unique labels
and next in the histogram panel we can
see the score distribution of all the
observations
so most of the
observations are centered around zero to
one thousand and then there are small
humps
where
we can see like lesser number of events
and there are other panels that we can
explore
we can see the rarest 10 labels that got
generated and also top 10 labels
at the bottom
uh
there is a panel for the top 10
anomalies
it shows the tag sets and the scores
that it
generated so
labels or tags are specifically
important
if you want to see why that
event is anomalous
so next we go to the discover
link where we can see individual events
which were characterized as anomalous
here we can add a filter so say we want
to see all the events that generated
score greater than 1000
so we can just
create a filter for that
and we want to select to score
and command
fields and next we'll sort the
score by descending order
so that we get the max score at the top
so these are the
most anomalous events or commands that
are seen in the data set
and we can go through and analyze them
so this was the default configuration
and we can see that there are not many
anomalies which might not be malicious
in nature specifically
so we can go
investigate it
next we'll look into how to enhance the
process
and how we can improve the detection
so in this
anomaly set
we'll see a netcat
command
so the netcat command that we are seeing
here
so this network command is the command
that we have inserted in the data set
and
it looks like it is pretty it has a it
is anomalous but it lies pretty low in
that score
so we'll see how we can improve the
detection process in the next step
so next we will add some expert
knowledge which is security based
and we'll improve our labeling by using
that to
knowledge base
so we can run the entire process using
the console
or we can just use the web interface
let's go through the web interface here
so here first of all we can just
generate
default configuration just like we did
last time
well submitted
once we submitted we will be presented
by the default configuration we can then
go again you can confirm the
configuration
here we'll get an option to change it
once we submit
so here we are
getting the option to change
the config as per requirement so we have
used statical and gram anomaly and we
have other four that we can choose from
we will choose least outlier factor here
sorry local outlier factor
and
then we'll
remove some of the label generators
as we don't feel that those fields are
adding any
of value to the analog detection process
so yeah we are just removing some of the
label generators
and the fields that can just be random
and it's not useful
for score generation
so next we will look into how we can add
the
knowledge based labeling
so
we'll use generator type keyword based
and we want to add our knowledge based
keyword for commands so we'll change the
field name to command
and we need to change the keyword list
that
that we have selected
so i'll just copy paste here
and this this is the list of uh
command keywords that we come up with
by using our
see by
by doing our security research
so we can use
we can just add keywords or we can add
regis based keyword that you see in the
next example so this is example where we
are just using
regis based labeling it can be ip
address or it can be paths
so
yeah
so once we're done with it we'll just
save it
and we can see the file name is named as
a tailored underscore the previous file
name
next we'll go to console and then we'll
repeat the whole process first we'll
check the config file that we just
generated that is tailored underscore on
the previous file name
next we'll
train the pipeline using the new config
file we will supply the same input file
which we have been using
and
we'll provide the
new config file
and we'll just let it execute
yeah we also need to specify the model
file that we
uh
gonna generate from the string pipeline
process
so it will generate the model file which
we will use to run the pipeline just
like the previous process
so once we have the model file generated
so it's a good idea to have a model file
which is named differently than the
previous step so that you can repeat the
whole process
as many times as you want
next we'll run the pipeline
using the same input file
you can change the input file to
completely new file to test it
with respect to the model file that we
have generated in the step
or you can just use the same input file
depends on
your requirement
so once this is done we'll again go to
the dashboard and
check out the results
so again i'll copy the
dashboard link
and in the banner front end we'll go and
observe
does it cause any significant changes in
the anomalies
so this time we have used local outlier
factor
anomaly scoring method
and
we'll see the score range has changed a
lot and we have generated around 125
unique labels that is three times last
time
and the score range is also
very huge
and if you see the histogram
score distribution we see that most of
the scores are located near zero and
after that there are very few
events that have very high score so it
looks like it did very
good clustering of the anomalies and we
are not
getting anomalies that have like very
high score
next we can look at look at the real
state labels so these labels got
generated
because of the keyword based labels that
keyword based
label generated we have used so you can
see
they are named command underscore
keyword
uh and there is a command
which we have put as a
as a label generated keyword
you can also see top 10 labels here
and same as last time
[Music]
you can look at the top score anomalies
labels and scores generated by them
we'll again go to the discover link
and
check out the
this course again
so we'll use the same filter and then
we'll choose
score and command
and labels
if we sort the score
to descending order
we'll see
that the netcat command that we have
observed in the last iteration it is
appearing
to have the highest score and then there
are other
uh commands
that we have inserted that also have a
higher score
so they appear to have the so these
are the inserted malicious commands that
uh
that were injected in the data set
and it's very very very relevant to the
security investigation that someone
might be doing
so
we can use oss in ids logs or service
logs it's it has a very
open implementation
so as we have seen that oss is very easy
to deploy given its integration with
kibana and docker it's very easy to use
and you can repeat the whole
experimentation process many times by
changing the configuration file
and adding expert knowledge as per your
requirement
so in general as
as with any ml approach you have to test
the features which will add real value
to your ml process
and you have to
test out all the ml all the anomaly
algorithms as per your requirements and
see which will give you better results
next we'll go forward with the questions
so this is the github link where you can
go and fork the project
please feel free to try it
and if you like the project please start
the project also you can get more
details about the project in this medium
link
there are other adobe related resources
where you can go and check out adobe
projects
thank you hope this was informative to
you and please
feel free to
reach if you have any questions
thank you