good morning sweetie pleasure and
privilege to be here speaking to a
community of expert said such of
yourselves and thank you for sticking
before lunch and enjoying this last half
an hour before the meal is served she
would like to thank the Nanog program
committee for viewing accepting this
this presentation I left my name is
samba drawn and picked co technical
advisor with the intersociety business
Ottawa Canada before I used to work for
Cisco left as a single architect being
based in Ottawa two days when I left was
minus 27 degrees Celsius so it's a very
positive change to come here and see the
Sun with some warmth actually shining
the point of connecting digital
communities in North America is
something that really the intersociety
occurs about a lot and we will preview
here some deployments that we have done
over the last year and we are embarking
on as we speak as well as some key
lessons learned from these engagements
we will talk the status of connectivity
particularly in the Canadian north last
talks in nano Austin might our partner
matter antenna and spoke in detail about
connecting tribal lands in the US so
this my talk will complement this this
point but looking further into the
Canadian Canadian North challenges but
giving examples from both Canada and the
US so the file of community networks are
we look at examples as I mentioned and
look at issues that relate to capacity
building challenges opportunities as
well as three point of lessons learnt
for a start maybe a few words about
Indian society maybe some of you know
what do it but just as a refresher we
were founded in back in 1992 by the
founders of the internet within five
years we are global nonprofit
organization dedicated to ensuring an
open accessible resilient
internet for the use by by everybody the
authority is based on we have a network
of about sixty four thousand members 130
chapters
worldwide and special interest groups
one on for example connected digital
networks or community networks as well
as we have more than 100 organization
members we work a lot to our chapters so
it's really a bottom up can kind of
approach collaborate on broad topics
from the technology policy issues
technologies particular that keep
internet safe and secure and resilient
and we serve as the organization home
for the IETF internet Engineering Task
Force if you look at the connectivity
status in the Canadian north basically
we have particularly in the eastern
eastern part of the Canadian Canadian
north northwest territories looook
territory
we have majority of the connector of the
communities our satellite dependent more
than 42 communities have been counted by
by I said the ministry of innovation
science economic develop of canada in
one of the last census the communities
are these particulates are completely
dependent a very small number have
access to other backward technologies
microwave or or fiber inside satellite
and these communities is quite expensive
to say the least
and four core worth a fortune he quite
unreliable any one example one of the
communities that we are going to talk
about more detail when you have tech
although the the Inuit although the
nominal speed should be around five
megabits per second for the whole
community but they see is we typically
load on one megabit per second for the
whole community challenge another
challenge is small number of riders no
competition really and there's no
appetite to invest in that part of the
of Canada because the return on
investment is small in small population
remoteness and difficult train make it
make the appetite for operators go there
invest quite quite lacking and this is a
map of the eastern part of the Canadian
north and we see here the communities
are satellite satellite reliant and most
of them are
have really bad bad connectivity in
terms of broadband so this is really
something that impacts the communities
in that part of of Canada
deeply in terms of economic development
education and development delivering
health services all these I'll debit
definitely negatively impacted by lack
of adequate broadband services to these
communities the government has started
some some initiatives in trying to bring
broadband connectivity to the north by
committee to invest to two billion
dollars next five years in terms of
infrastructure in terms of Universal
broadband fund in terms of running a
census a c6 and a-- to find out the
details of what exactly are the
communities suffering from in terms of
broadband connectivity unfortunately
this is very good but it takes time to
deploy another project but
infrastructure Canada Bank back in from
Canada will link a fiber cable from
Greenland to the Canadian north from
gradient which is far sorry which is far
east to to the Canadian north here this
will take at least five years to deploy
and its cost because has not started yet
is increasing from 114 million now it's
200 retracted and if it doesn't start
would even increase more before it even
starts
so the situation is quite difficult the
approach here is to build a network
allow the community itself to build
connectivity for its own use and its own
benefits and try to harness the benefit
of having a broadband connection for a
dimension educational services health
services and economic prosperity the
foundation concept of which networks is
it to do it to a self kind of solution
the community members themselves bring
rally along each other and the build
their network by themselves learning the
technology and getting the hardware and
building the network from bottom up
buying by themselves in many cases by
from accept by external support experts
or from funding by external sources such
as such as the AIESEC
in society this kind of approach is
completely community dependent the
community has to rally behind this cause
and make it one of itself its priorities
to build the network and see it up and
running
not only that but keeping it up and
running in the future and grouping for
models for sustainability of funding of
this kind of project it's a huge effort
to be led by the community to be built
by the community operated by the
community but relying on larger sphere
of supporters technical funding side
regulatory side to help these
communities flourish and grow and be
sustainable and humid networks are
really complementary to network provide
it for commercial use by by operators or
by others they don't replace the
component in the words of one of the
inhabitants of all who have tech and
opinion north as you will see she says
with networks creating money in the
within the community by operating our
own network and create training and
employment opportunities for residents
she has to pay more than $250 a month
for simple connectivity for simple voice
connectivity which is really something
that is quite quite a burden on this
type of communities what we want to
examples we have an example in Hawaii an
example in the Canadian north if you
think about Hawaii
you think video about why Tiki Beach
think about the commercial strip think
about the view the beautiful landscape
food beautiful scenery 45 minutes drive
on the other side of the island lies
this community
Punahou no Omaha no the sanctuary over
monado is basically a community what
they call themselves station of Hawaii
and base about thirty or forty thirteen
homes on the side of the mountain and
they really lack fundamental technology
they have they have voice white screen
activity over 4G network but in terms of
broadband to the to the houses this is
completely lack in the words of one one
of the
inhabitants he has to run to the hope to
the house of the chief and still the USB
USB LTE dongle
use it for his home was was doing his
homework when the chief is away and by 1
or 2 P a.m. in the morning before the
chief returns back he runs to his house
and puts it puts it where it's supposed
to be the other story is that it's a
habit that the children school-age
children have to be put in a van for and
put to Starbucks for four hours to do
their homework that's the only way they
have access to the Internet this kind of
community really became a pioneer in
asking and running behind implementing
Community Network projects in there
under under land the solution that that
we have opted in opted for along with
our partners is basically an LTE
unlicensed licensed spectrum credit kind
of network at five gigahertz and what
was sufficient for this size of the
metro to deploy it will no not bees and
in this here in this location it will be
facing this direction and this direction
and then having CPS outdoor cities on a
number of homes that have typically
children at at least these homes and
that inside the house a spiritual city
is you have to have Wi-Fi routers to
have larger larger coverage of of signal
signal coverage this community has been
quite quite lucky there was fiber
termination just outside the offence of
of the of the village from from the
local operator so the community really
had to dig a trench for where the
junction box is to install their own
land to where the node B termination
will come and they did it on our
voluntary basis of the inferno on their
own land they themselves did it by the
own what the equipment and did this kind
of of termination
and the cost has been has been lowered
by the by the operator - about four
hundred dollars per month for cooking
meat per second capacity this is the
picture of the note in obese and the DCT
is on on the only houses these are lists
list of partners that were engaged and
this is this approach and we see here
nanog listed and Edward Edward was kind
enough to participate in this effort and
show support nano support to make it to
make it successful the second example is
the Alou habitat and northern Canada
although habitat is here at 71 degrees
north rosante north and it's a very
small community of 350 inhabitants that
really supplied dependent one megabits
per second is really what they see on a
daily basis we are planning to deploy a
new solution in this network as well
based on the partnerships that we have
with particular provider the the how it
came about through discussions in the
digital entities summit which is summit
that the intersociety got implements on
a yearly basis bringing community net
communities indigenous communities from
across Canada and the US together talk
about the challenges and the examples
and things that we can do together
bringing in also government government
officials and academia and other other
experts so they short support in 2000 in
summer 2019 identified either leaders
who want to make this happen within the
community and we began the training for
both old hog-tied and Hawaii in the
summer of 2019 for three three months by
December were ready to deploy the
network in in Hawaii you will have tech
network is still not in the deployment
phase mostly because of logistics of
shipping the gear through the Canadian
North is really very weather dependent
and you have twins if you wait for the
spring batricia to ship any antenna or
any termination points that that far
north the another challenge in India
with this kind of network is the
the cost of the satellite termination
and as we will see that we all want this
to be really from juice station
satellite moving to low Earth orbit
satellites to use that are coming at the
end of 2020 or to a 21 and this makes
the solution quite expensive this is
another obstacle for deploying networks
in such such a territory we had
significant training done and this is
very important for the community to
grasp the skills the technical skills as
well as assistive soft skills types of
business acumen financial planning
project management how to access funding
how to request funding and of course the
technical skills how to build a network
and operate the network not a finite
final part of this train that delivered
either face-to-face or mostly in the
preparatory phase online through about
16 online sessions done by community
members that have run through this this
in the under only our communities an
important aspect is the local hands on
training the handler training is really
for the community so you see here and
these pictures the ladies within the
community were the ones that really at
the forefront wanted to learn how to
terminate the ethernet cable how to plug
in to the CTE how the configuration of
the load EB is it is done and this
picture shows the chief of the group in
committee in the woman a log teaching
his grandson how to terminate the
ethernet cable he asked him to stay out
of school stay at home with the fidelity
on Friday so that he sees this firsthand
he can teach him how this is done and
this is a way to make this project
successful community has to pitch in has
to learn themselves operate build and
operate the network financial services
sustainability is a key is a key point
that these two have this project up and
running for a long time and an
assessment successful fashion in terms
of Technology directions
this this section we'll talk about three
technology directions one of them as I
mentioned is the part of moving from do
station satellites that that are at the
height of 300 35,000 or 36,000
kilometers to some that is much lower at
1200 1500 kilometers from from earth and
then overcomes latency issue the to
weight agency of produce station
satellite as the order of half a second
for low orbit low-earth orbit satellite
oreos it should be in the tens tens of
milliseconds so this is really improves
a lot the latency the performance and
the promise of much higher bandwidth
availability then that for produce
additional satellites in this slide we
have two two operators that are focusing
in this space one web and and telesat
and they promote a fiber kind of
bandwidth hundreds of megabits per
second one of them talks about 1 1 or 2
gigabits per second that download
obscure upload capacity that is the
promise to be delivered but within
specific timeframe Telesat talks about
what 600 satellites by 2022
one web starts already a launch of 40
satellites few days ago that was
successful the promise is 360 satellites
by end of 22 I love this year moving to
port 2000 satellites in the in the in
the future again the promise is fiber
virtual fiber kind of connectivity
capacity and resiliency at hopefully
with this kind of competition for
operators are in that that space that
prices will be more attractive for
communities that are we suffering for
lack of bandwidth in the northern Canada
or on tribal lands
of the backhaul as being the peach one
of the key challenges three to deploy a
community network particularly in remote
indigenous communities in turn Society
has put together a fact sheet that looks
into different options being Wireless or
being wireline options Wireless we have
a microwave we have satellite judiciary
we have left low-earth orbit satellites
we have Wi-Fi of course or TV white
spaces all these are technologies that
are being adopted for deployment of
backwall solutions on the wireline side
typically this fiber optical fiber
optics available it's most
cost-effective future-proof kind of
backhaul background solution but
unfortunately is not available
everywhere and so quad was really
cost-effective in places like the
Canadian north where distances are huge
and you have to align on some sort of
worlds capability this Factory is
available online and it can be accessed
through the URL that is here the the 20
that has been used in Romanello is an
LTE LTE architecture and this the choice
was was of the existing partnership of
the with the vendor that proposed to
deploy the the hardware for for free and
also which is very important to help
with the support and training of
community members and the online support
after after the plant this is very key
to make this project successful and we
were happy really that we have partnered
with them this kind of architecture you
have the end-user equipment which in our
case the outdoor CPE the radio access
network of course in our case selected
unlicensed spectrum at 50 Hertz and then
you have the evolving avoid packet core
in some cases it's hardware based or
this kind of solution or this kind of
vendor its software that lies lies in
the cloud it's cloud based solution one
element that is not shown on the slide
is the local gateway local gateway has
to be configured as part of the solution
its function is to split the data train
from the control plane data plane
remains within the local gateway the
control train goes to the cloud does all
the control and functions and comes back
again with any
from Asia needed so this is what has
been deployed and it's hard to say that
it's an elaborate solution in terms of
configuration effort that needs to
happen to deploy the solution
successfully of course you have to
register the end-users their interests
through the sensor in the CPS and if one
of the Sims is not registered the right
way
connectivity does not happen so this is
a learning curve for poetry members
learn how this is done
and typically what we have seen in
within the community it helps a lot if
at least one or two people are Network
savvy have some PAC background or
networking and they can grasp the
elements of this kind of effort or this
kind of cooperation work easier than the
rest of the community which can help
with the other other types of
installation activities the third
component in the technology direction
has to do with spectrum and spectrum as
course you know it's really scarce
resource and in the u.s. the FCC has
embarked of making part of the spectrum
available it's the 2.5 gigahertz band
what's called education then the
spectrum usually was restricted to use
for schools and libraries for usage on
tribal dance that are recognized
recognized tribe indigenous tribes it
was allowed to use for other services
for internet connectivity or fixed
wireless services with with restrictions
the restriction is instructions are the
rate of deployment has to satisfy strict
metrics 50% of the of the area and then
the tribal land has to be covered or the
population has to be covered within 2
years within 5 years 80% of the
population on the tribal land has to be
covered so these are significant metrics
that the tribe tribal councils when they
apply for this spectrum has to really
plan for and make sure they can deliver
on this commitment the window
application for the tribal tribal
communities have have opened and the
beginning of rabri in February 3rd and 4
for 6 months the FCC is accepting
accepting applications from tribal
communities and this is very important
for
four tribes input in the US to apply for
for this spectrum it's a really a scarce
resource and the FCC has made it
available after consultation with the
tribes would many entities including at
the ICS in Hawaii in last December and
made the window for six months to allow
for for this kind of input from tribal
communities what we see as challenges
and barriers of opportunities from this
from this work that we have done with
our partners of course in terms of
challenges to geography where these
communities lying the remoteness of
these communities bringing them bringing
not only hardware and and we have to
quit but also bringing people bringing
experts there to go to the Canadian
north from Toronto whatever cost you at
least eight thousand dollars for one
person and about two days each way so
that is challenge to to get into a
community the cost of the bring the
hardware and also of the operating costs
moving moving on as we seen from the
case of all new habitat we need at least
two hundred thousand dollars to maintain
connectivity at the capacity that weeks
make certain that make makes a
difference licensing a permits this is
an important the case of Hawaii if the
digging of the fiber was in not on the
land licensing and permits was really an
issue and that we have taken 66 months
to a year access to funding and access
to spectrum as we mentioned our he he
challenges that have to be overcome by
the community
although funding can can be content can
be available from from the government in
case of the Canadian government but the
funding criteria makes a significant
barrier for example to apply for for
funding from from I said you have to
have five years of other total budget
from from from the community which means
it's not available for start-up kind of
project or you have operational
experience for five years or and or
operation experience for five years
which is also something that is not
available in such such a permanent the
opportunities are really numerous
that a community support if it is there
it has really the
a grantee to make the project successful
and funding is available from different
sources including civil society
technology does not have to be
complicated there are solutions which we
can be can can be deployed without too
much knowledge which help with experts
around around the community other
technologies news and so on maker will
make backhaul solutions more available
and we have we have it has been done by
communities across the globe and there
are a small network of experts what we
call special interest groups that really
share experience share know-how and
share their knowledge how overcome
challenges together and this is a much
needed support for uprising communities
or new communities the lessons learned
are basically in two categories one on
the community side and one on the
technical side and the community side
it's absolutely necessary to find a
local local champion and local community
to rally behind the project and also you
should take time in preparing the
community members past building skill
development before the start of the
deformed this is really key they should
not be just observers to the network to
be deployed and operated they have do it
themselves so they have to learn and may
concern the hard hard way see the
network not upon running something is
wrong
this configuration they have to learn
how to do it themselves with the support
of the extended community technical
hands-on training and deployment the
community members is is key as well as
we're verifying the details of the
infrastructure and connectivity before
at the start of any deployment as we
have seen in case of Hawaii we had we
didn't really know before the in-depth
site survey was done that the junction
box was this distant away from the
community and we had to dig to crime to
bring the fiber inside so these fans
this kind of information has to come by
strong engagement with the community
multiple site surveys
lying on experts being there and
identifying the challenges and you have
to take your time I have to community
building is a time and effort consuming
activity but this is the only way to
success
what we would like to show now is really
a video of the woman I love deployment
that the intern Society has done a glass
a of the point this already changed my
life because I feel like I really can't
do it by myself
I mean I find because it really really
pops us and in this state it is really
hard to me to survive it really is hard
to survive so us having internet here we
don't have to leave this place we now
can make money from home we can do a
business for me I mean it just means
freedom to us
and
[Music]
you
[Laughter]
so being independent you have to do your
own stuff you have to run your own power
you have to run your own water you have
to build your own roads and we've done
that over here for the last 25 years we
built our own houses now we've built our
own community broadband network our
internet service prior to this build was
very spotty at best we had cell service
there is one house that was getting
Internet off of this one pole here but
other than that everybody else's
Internet was really terrible
they had a dish service usually
satellite internet and in order for that
to work
other people had to not be on the
internet so you could only do one thing
at a time it's gonna be independence
what we live here for no I'm Anna we
strive for total independence from the
fixing of oil we've been under illegal
occupation of the military for the new
United States of America this allows us
to continue our stance of independence
on the web
you
personally for me it makes me feel like
I have allies all over the world I have
allies and in different sectors that we
can reach now because of our internet
and it'll make our job easier and it'll
make our nation's job easier my kids I
stopped offering and they were father
kids often times had to go down the road
debt to go to McDonald's they had to go
to Starbucks to finish uploading their
projects so and it was frustrating for a
lot of the parents because they had to
you know they had to kind of rearrange
their lives and just to just to keep
their kids from falling behind we
started to realize that the kids were
all online you were learning everything
online in school it made me realize that
without this technology without the
involvement in the digital world that
our kids were falling apart which would
mean that they would even have you know
hard hard time in their homes with their
parents
[Music]
already we have ideas in the works to
possibly create a library possibly
create on educational material and and
educational media so that we can
broadcast from from our village so that
our message gets outside of the village
and gets outside of a way and connects
to places all over the world we've been
really trying to advance ourselves
trying to get ourselves out there so
that we can be sustainable so that we
can be independent from from everything
else that stops us from moving forward
and this is just one more step in that
direction thank you all questions great
I think people are ready for lunch thank
you very much