okay good morning a quick little
introduction on myself
a principal consulting engineer for
Nokia scipy and optical networking
division my focus is on network
automation and Sdn controller solutions
alright quick little background on
myself I've gone through an evolution
right I mean I think that word gets
abused and used quite a bit and a lot of
these discussions but I started to the
in the industry about 20 years ago okay
and so over those 20 years I started on
fixed access portfolio alright SONET due
to the loop carriers ATM then
transitioned over time to IP type a
networking infrastructure eventually
into network management assurance
capabilities and now into obviously a
lot of this automation capabilities
right which is another word that gets
abused quite a bit alright but a lot of
the automation as well as the
optimization capabilities now my intent
for this presentation is not to discuss
necessarily collapsing of these domains
right into one physical domain or
getting into any type of specific optics
integration discussion my intent is more
around the value of centralized type of
hierarchical controllers all right or
software leveraging or providing the
awareness of course across these
different layer domains right providing
a the obviously the linkage between
these domains the infrastructure
awareness across the infrastructure
weariness of course of the reliability
of each of these domains and leveraging
all of that to build service
infrastructure right across that that
still meets the performance demand right
especially performance tab and that's
going to be becoming higher and higher
right as we look at these next
generation of application flows that are
coming in okay
so taking a little bit of a page off the
book of Prakash's keynote presentation
yesterday if you were there he mentioned
the some key requirements right as as
cloud IOT and 5g and the horizon are
gonna be impacting this all right and
and to be honest these requirements are
brand new in the industry these
requirements have always been there all
right but he talked about the massive
scalability right
what has changed there's obviously the
demand the speed of the demand has
increased on capacity he talked about
the horizontal growth capability that
you need to maintain right to quickly
deliver the obviously platform in a in a
timely manner deliver the service of
course
all right deliver the capacity right for
for faster capacity growth he also
talked about the capability of obviously
right again that's nothing new but the
reliability aspect of it right that
still hasn't changed you still need to
provide a performance across that
infrastructure approval provide
obviously reliability right across these
different layers right as well as the
security to maintain again that
performance intent for the service and
then lastly obviously where there's been
quite a bit of an evolution is on the
automation side as I said right
whether it's abstraction of the API is
whether it's defining obviously
configuration workflows defining of
course event-driven workflows defining
that intent for that particular service
in that particular infrastructure and
how do we maintain that infrastructure
moving forward right maintain that
infrastructure relevant to the service
ok so I'm not telling you anything new
here right I'm not showing you in
anything new in this particular slide I
think everyone is well aware of
obviously when looking at these
different layers we all understand that
the underlay whatever that underlay is
right has an impact on that particular
overlay infrastructure right it
obviously has an impact at a service
itself as an impact of a performance ok
well what's missing here is awareness
awareness of the infrastructure above
and awareness of the infrastructure
below right the correlation isn't there
today so I'm highlighting a few things
here right
basic questions have come up over the
years and trying to understand all of
this right so for instance is there a
more optimal performance around for
services all right so today obviously
when you're looking at the layer the IP
layer its next-hop right what's not
being looked at is obviously that
optical infrastructure right that could
that particular IP path that one hop
could be taking a longer path than what
you expected right as a result and
impact of latency okay so how are we
understanding that we're taking most
optimal path for a particular service
infrastructure okay now the other part
that comes up off and it's it's just not
about automation right there's also a
post side of the house it basically how
do I troubleshoot all right how do I
obviously narrow down or decrease that
time to identify the impact at a service
this is going to become important
obviously in a long term from a
closed-loop type of capability right but
alarm correlation alarm correlation is
always important you need to have that
awareness of all this infrastructure how
do you know that a particular optical
service the performance on that optical
service is what's actually impacting
that MPLS path all right how do you then
identify that and then and basically
address it the other part there sorry
went ahead a little bit but are these
services on a diverse path okay so you
know when you look at these primary and
secondary service infrastructures we
want to ensure this jointness diversity
right we don't want to identify or
leverage a particular link or an
infrastructure that if there's an impact
to it it's going to impact both my
primary and secondary again nothing new
but what's not what's been missing is
obviously that awareness of the optical
services underneath last but not least
all right what what services again again
kind of going to that awareness
standpoint right what IP services are
leveraging that at that particular
Lander that particular optical link okay
now I think most of you may know this
maybe not but you know in the great
words of GI Joe I think everybody
understands knowing is half the battle
alright so again it's awareness
understanding what infrastructure
there on that particular optical
infrastructure what IP services what
does the MPLS infrastructure that's
leveraging that in case I need to take
some kind of maintenance proactive a
reactive type of capability across that
right or some what-if predictive and
alice analysis across that right what
what are the optical services if I make
a particular event or a maintenance
window and I address a particular link
what am I going to be impacting I need
to have that do I need to then move that
traffic if possible right so what are
the use cases that's there in the
horizon that's going to be impacting all
of this from a transport point of view
is 5g network slicing right why right if
you look at obviously this networks
slicing what does that mean it's
basically stitching of resources across
different segments okay sounds simple
but but when you look at this right when
you look at obviously this resource
allocations for these use cases
all right you have obviously and in
general three different domains to
simplify it you've got a ran
infrastructure you've got a core packet
core infrastructure and then
interconnecting all of this is obviously
these transport into connectivity
services okay but when you look a little
bit further to that then there's
disaggregation at the ramp all right so
now you're breaking that ran component
further right you're virtualizing it
you're introducing more front hall mid
all backhaul I transport services in
between that right you still need to
maintain performance you have data
center interconnectivity that you've got
to keep in mind within within that
disaggregated ramp right and looking at
the core same thing obviously you've got
data center and connectivity within that
data center or packet core that you've
got to maintain all right and there's
depending on the use case you're peering
points the services the different
customers there's a high level of
obviously service infrastructure that's
going to get created so you've got to
maintain that there's obviously
performance requirements across all of
that infrastructure all right so you
have this high skill transport
infrastructure that's being built out
you've got high requirements on
obviously the performance of each of
that each of those infrastructures now
we've sliced and diced transport
services in the past right this is
nothing new but now when you look at it
right as I mentioned all of those
different segments right whether it's
obviously uh
vx land segments routing within a data
center the BGP type of segment routing
capabilities that are there right your
hard slicing with photonics right to
looking at the different data centers
that you're going to interconnect with
depending on your cloud exchange connect
right your edge data centers which have
that that disaggregated ramp right so
you've got a higher complexity there
that you need a type of transport
control capability alright and just
another thing to keep in mind right as
as 3gpp is you know focused on obviously
this ran and this course licensing and
trying to stitch all of this what's been
lacking to be honest is is that
transports lines standardizing on that
right because at the end of the day
regardless who the vendors underneath
there needs to be a level of abstraction
right as I mentioned automation is an
important key ok so this is going to be
obviously one case on the horizon it's
going to have a big driver from an IP
optical transport capability now over
those recent years obviously there's
been evolution at the device level all
right so we're all well aware of a lot
of the capabilities that have been
introduced right from segment routing
the drive that again high skill
capacities scalability like
configuration right across BGP IGP
infrastructures cdcf right to provide
wavelength switching or routing right
from a control plane more further
restoration capabilities with gmpls
alright so again more capabilities at
the at the actual Kwas functionality I'm
looking at deterministic waz and looking
at the minimum resources deliver those
particular services right for the
traffic engineering right with
capabilities like Pisa in being able to
look at holistically across a a
particular service or particular path
end-to-end
right and with that right and a lot of
this capability you need the
programmable interfaces right you need
the data mining capabilities so there's
been an evolution there and right we've
gone model capabilities with regards to
yang modeling right that introduces net
conf
that introduces your PC GMI type of
interfaces piece effective interfaces
like I mentioned already to be able to
automate that MPLS infrastructure
path computation functionality across
that right and again the data mining
right the data mined it becomes
important here as obviously we're
looking at not only being able to
automate this but then we've got to
maintain and ensure those particular
infrastructures are meeting the
performance dates all right so I need to
look at data there's a lot of data
coming in now but I want to put the
intelligence on the device to provide
that data to me right to provide that
KPI that we're hitting okay so rather
than that pole type of mechanisms it's
now the intelligence is there to push
that utilization detail or the
performance issue now likewise there's
an evolution that's been happening on
that vertical IT stack right so I know
I'm showing present mode I like to look
at his past mode of operation but it's
still present all right so when you look
at you know obviously the different
domains
you've got integration to each of these
domains you've got different vendor
integration to each of these domains
maybe to a management system right maybe
direct into a particular vendors device
all right so what does that mean that's
obviously configuration issues high cost
of OSS integration all right
there's in correlation there between
between all of that so when you look at
obviously some of these OSS systems that
have been they're trying to put that
correlation with her from
troubleshooting a fault management it's
it's very costly right to map all of
this and there's heavy heavy errors that
always come in from a configuration
standpoint when looking at these this
current solution we're what have we done
obviously there's been a collapse right
you're taking that control plane
awareness right you're taking those
management capabilities you're taking
this this model functionality of
abstracting these interfaces when
collapsing it into these domain
controllers why you want to abstract
that interface leveraging standards
alright like tapi ITF certain IETF
standards that are there to integrate
into these n10 service orchestrators
right to simplify whatever that domain
controller needs to focus on right for
that in service controller I want to be
able to just say hey I need a path
between n point 1 and point 2 and this
is my SLA right that should be
abstracted you let that domain
controller figure out the infrastructure
figure out what it
needs to maintain that performance right
and build it out and then what does it
need to obviously maintain the
reliability of that infrastructure okay
so what are some benefits or to be
honest more more around expectations my
operators for a multi multi layer type
of solution all right you can break it
into these three pillars in my opinion
right
it's simplifying the operation all right
again there's a post a pre and post side
of the house right I want to be able to
to maintain I want to be able to
troubleshoot I want to be able to do
what if type of analysis I want to
understand if I knock a particular link
down right what what services will I
impact what IP infrastructure will not
impact as well right there needs to be
that correlation there I want to be able
to have a coordinated maintenance right
capability what do I mean by that
obviously not having that awareness of
what the IP infrastructure that's
overriding that over way across that
particular optical infrastructure I
don't know what services I would be
impacting right first you want to have
that awareness but second if I do know
that I'm gonna have a maintenance
activity maybe I want to gracefully move
those flows right rather than letting
fast reroute all right or LF a reroute
that infrastructure based on what it
perceives as the best next hop I'd
rather have a view of what the in a path
should be for the particular LSP for
instance and define a maintenance and
then define okay here's where I will
move that LSP to address the performance
also resiliency right so each each layer
has an expectation from a performance
and expectation for resilience all right
you have a CH a capabilities at each of
these layers all right but I want to be
able to to leverage obviously
information at these layers but also
identify that let's say there's a
restoration event that that's occurred
right or there's an issue that occurred
in an optical link and then leveraged
and maybe gmpls there's going to be a
possible restoration is going to happen
there do I want to move infrastructure
back that's already been that's already
been moved all right do I want to give
it a little bit of a timer to take a
look all right are we going to go back
into an optical infrastructure or
particular link that is having some
powerlevel issues right which is then
gonna cause obviously the surface impact
again potentially right the other thing
to look at is obviously correlation of
all that information right taking a look
at latency information as well as the
shared risk group type of details at
each link at each hop or their IP or
optical and then last but not least
right the utilization so I'm looking at
utilization I want to be able to run
hotter right I want to be able to
obviously as things are scaling I also
want to be able to add that right I
wanna have the path computation
capability to adjust right being able to
spread traffic across across these new
new links or paralleling so of course
any new link to a new Janu aspiring
writer right so you need that capability
to address that right from a computation
standpoint but you also need to deal
with obviously certain failure scenarios
as mentioned before all right
rather than having a one to one
redundancy which becomes pretty pretty
costly maybe you might want to have a
one to end in which identify particular
lag group in instances as a highlight
here and if there's a particular port
maybe taking advantage of a port or link
failure and leverage these workflow
capabilities right based on events such
as a state change to a particular link
and then modify the particularly group
to leverage a backup type of interface
to still maintain that utilization all
right as well as modifying obviously the
optical service right to modify the new
optical service to map it to obviously
your optical trail that you had
associated and the previous the previous
connectivity okay now so within Nokia
we've been focusing on some of these use
cases right how do we address this right
what are some use cases to start with
move forward and build on obviously this
correlation between these different
layers obviously this is still a
starting point that's going to be growth
that's gonna be happening here as I
mentioned with a lot of this intent
based networking that's coming in being
able to define machine learning
functionalities that are coming in and
there's use cases that are being defined
there and how how will the network learn
and how will we adapt so there's going
to be a growth here but we've started so
far on this right on this path and so
some of them I'm gonna go through some
of these but the first one this is the
critical one
opinion right this is setting the stage
again it's that awareness right it's
that linkage right and today most many
operators that are out there still have
spreadsheets right still have
spreadsheets of IG p lengths that are
mapped to particular optical services
and they're trying to leverage that
information to look at performance on
these optical links and then hopefully
then manipulate traffic engineering
metrics to influence where traffic
should go right so there's a heavy
spreadsheets that are out there and this
is not a tear through tear to I know
there's global operators that are out
there that are still maintaining it in
this way and you know you know who you
are if you're here right if you have
some of the type of capacity management
going on today
right but ideally I'd like to obviously
have a real-time view right have a
stateful view of that infrastructure all
right but but the key is that
correlation that connection of that
those two domains all right there's
different ways of doing that right
mapping that particular client interface
on the optical service that I IP
interface you can manually do that but
really you need to start taking
deterministic type of approaches right
in some of the solutions that have been
there so the initial ones are leveraging
for instance lldp snooping right
being able to sniff obviously that
particular LDP transaction going between
two different routers and identifying
the two endpoints so that way we can
automatically then identify the linkage
others could be obviously looking at
packet counts right looking at the
packet count on the IP interface looking
at the pack packing count on the optical
client interface and looking over a
period of time to match that it could be
power levels right looking at the power
level of obviously the egress and the
router and the ingress of a particular
client or facing able to switch and be
able to again match that right to be
able to provide that because once you
define that connection
you're basically now have correlated
your Reformation correlating your layer
3 interface that on optical service now
you now know at that optical service
here are the ODU channels here is your
your DD billion service that's tied to
that client interface you now know one
that IP interface what layer three
services are associated you know what
MPLS infrastructure is leveraging that
interface so now you've tied your IP
service you've tied your
your MPLS infrastructure - you're
obviously client interface to that
optical service okay so that starts that
starts the baseline for everything some
other use cases are optically a disjoint
IP routing alright so I talked about
diversity right and being able to look
at not only obviously your IP layer and
providing diversity across these IP
links but understanding diversity across
the optical links as well being able to
identify these shared risk groups that
these optical services are are
traversing all right being able to take
that information and then influence the
IP infrastructure that IP path right if
you're looking for diversity complete
diversity across all of these links okay
the other part to that is obviously an
auditing capability right so it's one
thing to obviously define an algorithm
to avoid obviously these shared risk
groups or shared risk links right for
your primary and secondary paths but
then there's also the obviously this
infrastructure that's already there how
do I go in and basically audit is there
diversity in a particular IP service
right is there diversity on these links
right on these optical links do I have
optical what are what are the optical
services that are obviously going across
the particular link right what are the
IP services that are sharing a
particular resource again understanding
what's going across that way then I can
define a leveraging a disjoint type of
algorithm to either do no link
disjointness not only at the IP layer
but I've also composed the optical layer
as well ok and this one I talked about a
moments ago coordinated operational
control right so obviously there's a
maintenance event on a particular link
right we want the operator to have the
ability to identify what are the
services what are the IP infrastructures
that are going to be going across the
link right that's the first part but we
want to have the capability of a
proactive or reactive ability to move
that infrastructure right not letting a
particular all of a sudden then do as I
mentioned before a fast reroute Ornella
fee of that particular infrastructure
right which is only going to take that
next top neucom remember there's SLA is
defined to that path
doesn't intent to that path I'd rather
the controller right in that maintenance
mode setting basically defined here's my
my MPLS paths that are there I know the
constraints associated with those MPLS
paths let me compute a path and move
that infrastructure now it could be a
manual or an automated approach right
but again I want to identify that
infrastructure and then give the
operator either a manual approach to
move that all right without impacting
the service or an automated way with the
control of the IP controller to move
that infrastructure across okay now cost
effective multi-layer protection right
this is what I was talking about load
sharing or are floating ports right in
an earlier slide and I talked about
obviously this one-to-one protection
right do you have you've defined a
particular ecmp path or a lag group and
obviously if you wanted full protection
one to one you've got another interface
that you define or a group of interfaces
that you define obviously this becomes
costly and so some solutions that we've
been working on with operators is
identifying a backup port right an
optical link that's already there that
could be leveraged across these
different lag interfaces all right the
intent is again leveraging this intent
driven or workflow event-driven
capability identify that there's a state
change to a particular link a link has
gone down take advantage that backup
port manipulate the particular lag
member Association manipulate the
optical service to now be tied to that
new optical that new client interface
that's tied to that backup port again
it's a workflow based solution to
leverage that across there there's what
if type of scenarios right again this is
the Stark but I look at this is more
eventually traffic engineering capacity
planning type of scenarios but again it
goes to these maintenance windows all
right having an understanding when I go
to a maintenance window alright and I
want to simulate these particular
failures or I want to simulate the
worst-case failure right and the impact
to that as I look at it any type of
matrix demand matrix capabilities need
to have the simulation functionality
right you need to have full awareness of
all of your infrastructure on both IP
and optical
you need to be able to then obviously I
have everything correlated together all
right but now then you could take that
capability identify a particular link
understand what are the IP
infrastructures that are gonna be
impacted and then be able to identify
rule the controllers be able to
manipulate move the infrastructure to
still meet those algorithms or policies
defined for those paths okay I mentioned
hierarchal right it's not hierarchical
just from a IP and optical standpoint
it's hierarchical across across the the
same domain as well right there there
could be particular IGP domains and
there's different ways of addressing
that but with optical you're gonna have
obviously different vendor domains as
well so you may have a Nokia optical
domain you may have a Fujitsu domain
that's there but the intent here is to
be able to sit across that leverage
these abstract interfaces that are being
defined is for instance in onf and
defining this transport API or I
provided that abstract capability to
create the stitching between these
different domains all right so that way
you could be interfacing these
controllers could be interfacing with an
NMS or a controller for each of those
optic or vendor optical domains now I
mentioned earlier right as I mentioned
her there's also the troubleshooting
aspect of it right it's not just
automation you need to be able to
maintain this you need to be able to
have your operate operators be able to
troubleshoot this network so if it comes
down to route calls analysis the
correlation as well I've identified
obviously we're we're focused on
correlating all of this information end
to end
obviously that's very relevant to
building and maintaining in influencing
the infrastructure but at the end I also
want to have the ability since I've got
all this correlation to provide route
costs across across these domains right
instead of just throwing something over
the fence I can't figure out why a
particular LSP is down or I'm dropping
traffic on an LSP I don't know it's
impacting a particular service right I
need the ability to understand that you
know the impact that we're seeing here
is being caused by a particular
performance issue on the lambda
wavelength right I can encorage Anette
to the actual LSP is the services that
are leveraging that
narrow down that troubleshooting time
okay now last but not least right it's
this evolution path and you we've
started down this path already and with
Enochian trying to leverage machine
learning right this AI this capability
of learning right being able to have a
some feed information at being able to
obviously take all this data this large
volume of information identify patterns
right
identify how we can address those
patterns right as we're looking at all
these events coming in all of the
utilization data the intent there is
okay now let's identify these patterns
right identify the actions that have
addressed pad these identify patterns in
the past these situations and then
moving forward identify obviously these
baselines of utilization all right some
of the KPIs across the infrastructure
identified then potential workflows that
closed-loop type of capability and and
learning having the operator still have
the feedback loop there that he can
obviously make a decision based on some
feedback that's provided based on
information that we learned under the
apology state performance information
right all of this data that's coming in
alright so this is where we're we're
going right especially as further and
further right there's evolution in that
intent based networking all right you're
defining these intents on these
infrastructure these services now let's
start leveraging the data that's coming
in and providing that self-driving
capability right so this is what we've
started already our float our first
focus was around obviously identifying
patterns of issues that are going on
all right so that way we can identify to
the operators these are this is a
similar pattern
all right that's causing a network
flapping issue so instead of looking at
thousands of events you're looking at
maybe 2030 situations that have been
identified that are meeting this
particular pattern okay and then give
the operator some choices on how they
want to address it so this is our first
implementation but then it's going to go
further from there okay so just to
obviously kind of bring this all
together a little bit right and looking
at the benefits our focus is obviously
and I think everyone's focus is
obviously simplifying operations all
right
decreasing in providing the toolset
that are there to provide that
correlation across this by providing the
interconnectivity across the service
infrastructures increased network
utilization right we talked about
large-scale
adding more spine routers or adding more
infrastructure to handle obviously the
the particular services and the demand
that's coming in you need to have
obviously the capabilities to compute
that infrastructure and maintain that
right one thing I didn't mention is you
know we talked about this growth you
know let's say a leaf spying type of
architecture but with that you're
spreading traffic across the network
potentially right you need to be able to
identify let's say black hole type of
events now that you're you're spreading
traffic across the network how do you
identify that there's an event that's
occurring that's dropping traffic
somewhere that you can now address it
and then avoid that particular path so
you need to have that stateful awareness
across need to have topology detail
obviously you need to have utilization
information as well coming in network
resiliency as I mentioned right we're
looking at all these different
resiliency capabilities that have been
introduced over both on the IP side and
obviously on the optical side would you
MPLS and some des capabilities there
with cdcf and the flexibility right
being able to take all of that into
account and be able to make your
decisions all right on that
infrastructure and then speeding up
planning and processing right as I
mentioned these what if these demand
matrix capabilities and looking at
whether the capacity is there to handle
failure scenarios or worst-case failure
scenarios right and look at
predictability of how much services you
can add potentially where do you need to
add potential scale right as well as
obviously speeding up the agility of
introducing these services right as
mentioned in these presentations the
automation aspect the modeling the
abstract modeling right the workflows to
deliver those configurations okay and I
think I think that's all that I've got I
know I've kind of gone above a little
bit at the time are there any questions
with that I know them before lunch so
thank you for the time obviously there's
any questions that you know send me an
email my email information is on the
slide deck as well okay thank you