for those who don't know me I'm Edie
Rubik Nair and I'm the executive
director of nanog and I'm going to be
addressing and talking about some of the
things we're doing in the organization
that's just kind of outside of the realm
of the program Steve and cat will be
coming behind me they're gonna be
talking about some of the areas specific
to the program itself now one thing that
we do hopefully want from this is to
make it a little more kind of
interactive we're trying to communicate
to you what we're doing as an
organization what our strategy where
we're going in the future and so this is
kind of a part of that so this is part
of our commitment to transparency
openness and helping to promote and
expand the community so when I first
start out talking about our outreach
events outreach has been kind of a big
part of what I've wanted to do as an
executive director I kind of in some way
see myself is partially an evangelist
for the organization and I'm trying to
make it grow and get more people engaged
within our community for the benefit
nuts for us but all for the industry as
a whole so I've had the pleasure of
doing a couple of these are events that
have happened since I last saw you at
the last meeting so first up is I had
the pleasure of attending the indigenous
community summit in Hilo Hawaii it was
put on by I sock and it was a great
opportunity to be a part of that and to
see what's going on
now before we wondered okay I was in
Hilo Hawaii
I never even set foot on the beach I
flew in one day
there for the conference for two days
flew right out but I had an incredible
experience it was held at a university
there in Hilo and it is the largest are
clearly saying the only indigenous
language school in the continental
United States or not sorry in the United
States and there they focused on about
building community in the relationships
and advocating for people in indigenous
communities the connectivity that we
take advantage of in our daily lives is
sorely missing and it was a wonderful
opportunity to hear people from all over
North America talking about the
challenges the successes the
tribulations they went through in
getting the
access within their communities it also
gave me an opportunity to share about
nanog the mission of Education and
community to promote Nana's vast library
of online content to encourage
enrollment in our mailing list where so
much information can be had in addition
to discuss the educational community
value of our Nana conferences Nanog
university this is something that's near
and dear to my heart and that is getting
university engagement into what we do as
an organization if you look throughout
our industry you'll find that there's a
huge deficit organizations are trying to
find more people to employ and we're in
stiff competition with other areas and
technology so part of what I myself do
and volunteers in the organization where
they're trying to evangelize our
industry the opportunities and talk
about what we do so I had the wonderful
privilege of joining several of our
community cat not this cat cat new
Microsoft and also Eddie and others
crossing and delivering our first namma
university tour we went to three schools
three days and we saw about a hundred
and eighty plus students University of
Illinois urbana-champaign Purdue Ball
State here's an example of the agenda
that we had done during the conference
it was a raving success the students
loved it they were engaged as I was
sharing with the PC earlier this morning
for most of you in this room you guys
have been in the industry for a while
and you're a little bit jaded you're
looking for and a talk what are the
little pearls I can find that really
kind of matter to me for these students
they're they're new to the subjects a
lot of them weren't even in field to
technology but to see how engaged they
were into the process how hungry they
were to know more and how we saw people
shifting and saying well I could see
myself within a career in this industry
so it was a wonderful privilege to be
able to get in front of young minds and
to encourage them and to see what are
the opportunities they have within our
industry Montgomery outreach so there's
a gentleman by the name of Marcus who's
a part of our community who's from
Montgomery for first time is executive
director he came up to me and said
Hey in Montgomery would really love to
have you come and talk to us okay yeah
yeah I'll see what we can do pass it on
the program committee he kept going it
kept going to keep going so I said
finally I will go I'll come and see it
was one of the best experiences of my
life I had a blast they were very
welcoming they had me on a schedule I
would start at 7:30 in the morning and
they had me going field nine o'clock at
night I was at Air Force bases I was
talking to Alabama State University
students it was just an amazing
experience so he was just kind of just
the things that I was able to expose
talk about nanogram message talk about
career opportunities to young people it
was an amazing experience and I really
hope that for any of you out there who
want nanak to come to your community
please reach out to me or others on the
pc we want to be able to empower and
educate your communities about what
nanak does who nanak is and how we can
benefit their communities
now there's one particular incident that
I have how's it the valiant Academy and
the value of Academy is a it's a
non-profit private Academy that is
tuition free to students they reach out
to students who come from you know
difficult situations and try to turn
their lives around and sometimes when
you're presenting to a group of people
you have these moments where someone
comes out and does something special for
you that young man with a circle in red
he asked me a question and I used to
teach for quite a while and occasionally
a student will present something to that
kind of turns your head upside down and
I was talking about my career my
background what I had done to get where
he is and he asked me this question he
said so how do you do it when you said
you something that's really really hard
what do you do to get past it and I pass
through and I said sometimes failure is
not an option
sometimes it's hours times commitment
sometimes you don't sleep and I think we
all have faced that in our lives to get
where we are now that we face these
challenges and we just didn't relinquish
we didn't give
and it was a great opportunity to be
able to share about my life and my
experience and hopefully that you come
the volunteers here get a chance to do
the same so we're looking to people to
become a part of this community to help
out with our outreach to broaden the
message of Nanog and having the
opportunity that is really special when
you can give back future outreach events
so we're going to st. Louis we're going
to be there March 27th here's where
we're going to be this is an outreach
meeting we call this a professional
outreach so if you know people in the
area that you can kind of drive to come
to this event we'd appreciate that if
you are willing to volunteer and help
commit and present at this outreach
event we'd love to hear from you
if you ever want to talk to me go to our
contact page there's a little drop-down
on there and you can says executive
directors you can always send me an
email I answer them all I read them all
so please anything you want to share I'm
there to listen
building community so talk about a few
things at a community based first thing
that I want to talk about is membership
so I've been pitching you guys let's
come on become a part become members
also we add some changes to our form and
I'm happy to say that our membership has
jumped up now to 800 people we have as
members and I hope you can see that move
that that that number grow more than
just making that number grow I want to
see more members but I want to see more
engagement and I want to see more
involvement so now that wants you so
what we're looking for is if you become
members we want you to be able to vote
because it helps direct and guide where
we're going as an organization mentor
the next generation of network
professionals teach the best way to
reinforce anything that you know is to
teach someone else present share your
knowledge and experience with others
evaluate serve on the program committee
and sponsor Nanog is an organization we
depend upon sponsorship to do all the
things that you do
the dollars that come from your joining
and become a member the sponsorship
all go into helping us do those programs
outside of the meeting and in the
meeting that allowed us to reach out and
expand our community and help to shape
the world around us we're going to be
releasing an annual report part of our
commitment to transparency and openness
within our organization that staff and I
have worked toward building out an
annual report right now it's in draft
mode you can expect to see it probably
in the next several weeks it'll be out
on our website we'll promote on our
mailing list social media etc this is
just an opportunity to share with what
we're doing as an organization the
financial health of your organization
what we've accomplished across the year
and 2019 and we'll be continuing to do
these each year meeting budgets serving
costs associated with these events are
rising we're seeking options to kind of
manage those things still be able to
deliver you a great experience and
sometimes we're challenged with what
things should we keep what things should
we add with things we remove and so
we'll be releasing a survey soon please
support our community and our org by
filling out the survey giving us your
feedback we value it it's very important
we are a community organization and we
function best when all members of our
community are engaged and involved in
what we're doing subscribe to our
newsletter we have staff Britney and
Brandi and Lee in particular who are
working very hard to make sure that we
have nanog originated content that is on
our website and promoted on YouTube etc
when we did our University - or we
interviewed students and there are some
great videos on there articles that are
written by people in the community about
the direction we're going and what's
happening so please subscribe to our
newsletter if you go into the bottom of
our website and any page you can find a
link to that so you can subscribe to see
what we're doing and then our
organization there's some really great
content that goes in there
so in december late december the board
and i went through a series of exercises
and planning to kind of shape two-way
nanako's going into the future so we're
looking at kind of a strategic
advancement for the organization so in
that session we covered the questions of
what is nanog what should they not be
what are Nanak's most urgent needs where
would worship now not be in three years
and also a swap analysis now by putting
this all together the board came out
what would we call strategic guidance
now again this is not a strategic plan
it's a strategic guidance we're going to
be using this guidance to actually
create and build out a strategic plan
that will push our organization forward
for the next three years
so here the areas where the board saw
significant important that we as an
organization should focus on education
enhancing community online collaboration
strategic outreach mentorship improved
community building and facilitating
business engagement so as I dig into
each one of those things education so
the direct guidance that I received from
the board is to form an education
committee to investigate I gotta fix
that investigate the following areas for
board consideration making structured
online you know I'm human structured
online education training and education
outside of our conferences that would
for example nanog university neutral a
vendor neutral certification non
technical professional development
programs content development in
collaboration with the program now this
does not mean that we are going to
actually be able to accomplish all these
goals these are kind of some high level
ideas for these committees to address
there are proposals are going to be
built and put together by these
committees that will be subordinate or
consideration enhancing community online
collaboration here the guidances staff
will research and present proposals for
the board for consideration a knowledge
base for networking professionals modern
online forums again this is not to
replace our existing forums and commune
this is to enhance those who kind of
attract a younger and generation improve
online presence to reach new
participants better integration with
existing social media platforms better
tools to support meeting attendees
improve mobile accessibility of current
tools strategic outreach again staff
guidance here encourage more young
people to participate in the industry
help develop the next generation of
networking professionals and leaders
reduce attendance barriers for junior
engineers and students advanced
adversity in networking community expand
outside traditional operators and
develop programs to support veterans
mentorship we're in the form of
mentorship committee and that committee
will go about focusing on how can we
mentor the next generation of networking
professionals professionals mentorship
programs and training to support the
next generation professionals a
membership portal to for continued
support and engagement mentors and
mentees will meet face to face each
meeting mentor sessions will will be
facilitated and topic based develop
membership become internship guidelines
foreign code of conduct and create
training programs for mentors to assure
consistency and experience across all of
our engagement improved community
building again staff guidance here
explore the support for parents and
children's at meetings build smaller
community based based on affinities and
specialties create monthly webinar to
encourage continued participation reach
out to local nogs to recruit speakers
for upcoming meetings in their facility
and systems for tracking community
request and last is facilitating
business engagement business engagement
has always been a part of these meetings
and it's actually grown in scope the
board recognizes that and we're looking
at ways to make it easier to do business
some people come here specifically to be
in this room and listen to the content
others are here to take make connections
and develop business contacts and
facilitate business arrangements and
we're committed to making that easier
for our attendees so we're looking at
trying to get more private meeting space
online room reservation systems easy
scheduling systems survey sponsors for
input on updating responsive offerings
research what would generate greater
participation from current and potential
sponsors so these are just a few of the
things that we're looking at again this
is all about guidance we're between
staff and committees we'll be building
this out and finding ways to better
serve our community so that being said
if you have any comments or feedback to
any of this anything that you want to us
to look at an address that we haven't
please communicate to us so we can kind
of add that to the field of things that
we're looking at as we hope to make the
our community even stronger and better
so here's our timeline so we're looking
at all of the charters to be submitted
to the board between now and the next
meeting the next meeting the request is
a proposal will be submitted to the
board the mentorship Education Committee
and member members will be selected then
we'll look at outreach proposals that
happening in Nanog 80 the board
directives will award we'll take that
off-site all these directives of
information and come up with here's what
we're gonna do here's a plan here's what
we're going to budget toward that once
we got the green light we'll start
working on the online things and then by
nanog 81 we will announce all the
programs and hoping to see everything
happen in nanog 82 all right in memoriam
as Steve expressed or in the meeting we
lost a significant member of our
community and as part of the people who
have started down a get made of what it
is we're at that point where we're
tipping this is going to become more and
more frequent thing that's going to
happen within our organization and we
always want to pay homage to those
who've gotten us to where we are so on
our website we're going to be creating a
page is going to be devoted to those
people within our community who have
passed and who are no longer with us so
if you have anyone who's already passed
anyone who you know passed in the future
please go on to our website submitted to
myself or to the board
and we will make sure that they are
properly honored on our website now
we're on to the program thank you so I'm
Steve Feldman representing Katmai
representing the program committee I'll
briefly go over our structure I know we
talked about it in a lot more detail at
the last meeting so there's no point
repeating too much we have a chair
Vince salindra who is working on
something he leads all of the program
committee meetings and basically drives
the entire process I'm the vice chair so
my job is to stand up here when Vince is
busy and and help them out and Kat is
our secretary who is responsible for a
lot of things but primarily making sure
that there are things up on the screen
to display that come from the
presentations that you also bit so I'm
going to talk a little bit about some of
the enhancement hi Tigger some of the
enhancements that we've been making to
streamline the process and make things
better for you guys the speakers and the
attendees the question that I have been
asked for ever since I started working
on nanog is why can't the agenda come
out sooner so we're working on exactly
that right now we have a couple of
initiatives the biggest one being what
we're calling a continual call for
presentations where you don't longer
have to wait until this meeting is over
before you can submit a talk for the
next one in fact at this point if you go
into the program committee tool you can
go in submission tool you can submit as
far out as Nanog 80 right now and we'll
keep rolling that out so you can do at
least two meetings in advance from now
on so that means that we can start the
whole review cycle earlier means we can
accept talks earlier and get the at
least partial agendas out earlier and
hopefully make the whole process
smoother and improve the quality of our
content as a nice byproduct of that
there are some enhancements to the tool
that make this a lot easier like the
ability to as I said submit for
future Nanak's and also we have the
ability to take a talk that was
submitted for this dialogue and if for
example we had a lot of these they came
in past the deadline we could just
switch them to be in early submit early
consideration for the next standout and
to get a head start that way so I'm
making the process smoother for
everybody
we hope the other thing that we're doing
new this time and it's almost too late
for that but we have a program committee
help desk out in the lobby area I think
it's only staffed until 10 o'clock this
morning but feel free to go out there
there should be somebody out there to
answer any questions you might have
about the submission process if you're
interested in submitting something and
want some advice if you're interested in
serving on the program committee
although it's too late for this year
cycle maybe so I think he really about
some be candidate next year so that's it
a cat I think we'll talk a bit more
about the submission process and what
we're doing to improve that and where do
you tell and here's the clicker and I
think the next slide has the wheel on it
there we go so as Steve mentioned we're
working in this continual call for
presentations where you no longer have
to wait until a few weeks after to begin
so you know even if you won't be here in
June but you know you can come to
October and you've got a great idea you
can put that in now and start working
with someone so once we begin receiving
proposals the first thing that we do is
we assign a Shepherd from the program
committee who will guide you through the
whole process so that if someone who's
going to be one-on-one with you they're
gonna review your slides give you
initial feedback before you ever get put
in through voting to the rest of the
committee and yes even if you're Smitty
fortuna Anton's that will still start
working with you now to hone those
presentations and make them ready to go
and have a chance at succeeding in
voting and getting into the agenda so
once you've got your presentation in
we've given you a Shepherd the sooner
you get us slides the easier it is for
us to help you and get you prepared and
also the earlier we can vote once you
are finalized with those slides for your
shepherds
so the earlier we vote the earlier the
chances of you getting on that agenda so
it's always good first to have your
slides early basically and that's why we
want
the call for presentations continually
instead of having to wait because we can
really help you guys prepare that's also
why we do the program committee helped
us now because we want to be there for
all the questions you guys have and be
more forefront in that vision that's it
as Secretary I must remind you that
slides do have deadlines if your slides
come in too late unfortunately then I
can't help you anymore because we can't
vote on something if the slides aren't
finalized they're not there so it really
does matter that you get those slides in
before the deadlines we need to see that
early we need to help you through them
and then we need to vote in time once
we've got all the slides finalized
everything's in voted on that's when we
try to get the agenda published so the
sooner we get everybody's agenda yeah
sorry the sooner we get everybody's
slides and submissions in the sooner we
can publish an agenda for the rest of
the community so you can start going to
your bosses and saying hey there's these
great talks coming up can I please go to
the next nanog and then the circle is a
little outdated now because conference
begins and we don't know we no longer
have that call for proposals restarting
it's just always open now
but yeah so I hope that explains the
general process to you just get slides
in early we'll work with you we'll help
you get through the process oh yes so we
do value your feedback and this PC tool
has been really great in helping us do
just that by having multiple nanog
submitted but we do recognize that PC
tool is new it is not the same one we've
used for many years so feedback is very
welcomed for us and for the developers
have been working on the tool for us
they're a great team so please let us
know if you go to upload something it
doesn't quite work as you expected
you're not sure where to find something
on the tool please send that feedback in
because we want it to work for you guys
as well as for us and the more feedback
we get on that the better we can make
the tool for everybody yeah one other
one other thing I want to mention did
earlier could the other program
committee members in the room please
stand up if there are any I guess
they're all getting coffee but I did
want to mention that cat and I
are part of the PC leadership which
means that we help herd the process but
the real work is done by the committee
members they spend a lot of time
reviewing shepherding and making sure
that we have stuff to listen to during
the rest of the conference so please
thank them and you see them oh and one
last thing we'd like to take a moment if
anyone have any question about either
your organization or the program that
would be happy to answer so the mics are
open and if any of you have any
questions or anything you'd like to ask
please do yeah just a quick thought do
you have any questions for us the
broader membership any questions that
you think you'd like to get like a straw
survey of hands up what are the
questions that you'd like to ask this
group I'm gonna do that next time I've
got a bunch of them rattling through my
head but yes I will use that as a forum
to get a show of hands because that's a
good thing - thank you for that yeah I
actually have one that I'd like to see I
can't spend the time here just really
have left for four minutes left but one
of the things I like to see reflected in
the survey is how do you feel the level
of the material or the mix of levels of
material beginner intermediate advanced
is there enough to keep everybody
engaged and keep bringing in new people
while still keeping as Greybeards
interested so the study of the right mix
of presentations to accept is ketose
mm-hm
Tony Tony Taylor Comcast
hey I was on the PC and it you know
earlier years and I think you touched on
it but I I know well hopefully this is
still correct but to reiterate to people
like the slides like the program
committee can't really evaluate
something without slides correct like
people I know people would come to us
and they'd say oh I put in an abstract
and I'm waiting to hear if you're going
to accept it and then I'll do the slides
and that can't work you know what I mean
according to the process that I
remembered because you need to know like
the level and the detail and that's you
know it doesn't they don't have to be
totally finalized but they have to be
something with some serious meat so that
the program committee
can assess them otherwise they just
can't so if you're in that way of
thinking you have to actually get to the
slice yeah and I would say this almost a
flip
give us the slides in the abstracted
come like yeah because they have
struggled to millions it being more for
what we're gonna publish on the agenda
page but like you said the slides are
paramount we need to look at those and
really understand what you're trying to
present so the kelpie through those okay
so I do have a question how do you guys
feel about I mean especially those who
this is your first time attending an Ann
hog meeting did you feel welcome did you
feel like it was a good comfortable
place to be yes you felt welcome good
yeah show hands so those who knew who
come here the first time hands up
how many your experience was good okay
are you gonna come back even okay that's
your ease you're gonna be gonna come
back that's very good yeah there we go
thank you
any be anything you guys need you need
that you have a bad experience anything
happens here you don't like or even
positive or negative I'm always
available I check my emails all the time
so something happens let me know Thanks
I would like to mention something else
about the discussion around slides
slides are not required to submit your
ideas for lightning talks it is really
just meant to be a crazy idea you've had
so submit those you can get those slides
in by the morning of the day you're
going to present the lightning talk
appear accepted but don't think you have
to have a bunch of slides prepared just
because you want to do a lightning talk
you need to be prepared to create slides
for me but they're not required for that
submission process at least yeah alright
well thank you all for attending nan
again for giving us a little bit of your
time appreciate it