ki everyone thank you so much for coming
it's been a great meeting and I
especially want to thank those of you
who came and participated in the boss
the man i bought last night as well as
the purine bluff of course but we got a
lot of wonderful input we really
appreciate the first people to think are
the people who came back Elise thank you
for the moderation and Bill I think bill
are you still here I think both bill and
Craig left Solis Thank You Randy I'm
sure you're here somewhere okay if he's
not here i will be truly honest Randy is
remarkable his hosting has oh hi Randy
this whole thing has been so
extraordinary that the meeting has been
yeah the meeting has been really for
merit and for the people from cisco and
university of oregon and dwayne and so
on who work on the meeting it's been
remarkable Randy thank you so much and
also to Robert Watson for coming
yesterday and welcoming us and i want to
mention everyone on Randy scheme Ron
neil has been around all weekend
handling all the electrical provision
and so on thank you to rick Morton
Stephen Cole's Frank sue rule Ivan
merchant Corey Bannister Gary McGowan
Franklin könig Gary saloni that's
probably wrong shahida jaws I know the
lobby Gary watch me act on Houston and
Melanie Reeves thank you so much all of
you
a bunch of the people from Merritt are
taking down the terminal room and Carol
is never here when I say thank you you
all probably feel like you know Carol
because you've exchanged emails with her
Carol not only handles all of your
registration but all our vendor
interaction and our hotel setup she's
remarkable and gets a lot of help from
dawn our network is handled by Bob civil
Betty Burke and David Gilbertson I want
to thank all of them Jason for our real
media Charlie through Joyner Felicia
Maloney for general aid and support when
it comes to the University of Oregon
next the first very cool thing to
mention is that Lucy is hosting us next
fall for our joint meetings with Erin
which is an incredible stroke of luck
Lucy is very talented and also likes to
have a lot of fun Lucy thank you for
joining us again for multicast
you said something but I didn't hear it
wonderful if anyone remembers our last
meeting in Eugene at an actual party
where people dance including Randy Bush
coupe Dwayne handles a lot of stuff
first way thank you for being around
this time from Cisco we get help in the
background before the meeting planning
multicast that comes from Mike McBride
and John miler also fiscal gave us a
bunch of wireless cards that we that
helps beef up the amount we loan out
which by the way is dwindling I think we
loaned 3035 this time which is a big
change for us means most of you have
cards also the number of Ethernet users
over there in the corner is down to 60
80 somewhere maybe less read back thank
you so much for feeding us yesterday
afternoon don't forget to turn in your
wireless card and if you're going to the
airport tonight book a cab now with the
hotel be warned in the next 10 minutes
or so your network connection may be
withdrawn with no warning now that's
because we want to go home too so please
do try to wrap up but seriously after
five or ten minutes be prepared for the
wireless to go down fill out your
evaluation and next fall do say beyond
our usual sunday tattoos the analog
meeting I won't give you exactly the
same pitch as yesterday that would be
boring but Erin meetings are interactive
in a way that is very very interesting
and a lot of fun so we'll see you then
thanks