I tell he was i'm dan Maffei this is
joint work along with Randy bush and a
number of other people that make up a
DARPA project on essentially
infrastructure protection and more
interested here in doing is talking
about the routes leading to top-level
servers in particular we all know we
have a critical point of failure near
the 13 route and 13 gTLD servers gTLDs
are covering the comm net and org and if
you you were to lose all the 13 root
servers we've all heard you know network
will fall away and that bad things will
happen but there really isn't potential
here for a disproportionately large
impact of a fault if say 13 bogus 13
bogus routes deny you access to the root
servers or even with one bogus route
since we don't have any kind of
authentication inside the DNS if I can
trick you into believing a false root
server or false calm server I can do a
substantial amount of damage so there's
sort of a high risk for this attack but
we're only looking at the very top of
the tree gives as you move lower in the
tree we have sort of a natural defense
of scale you certainly can take out
somebody's servers just the absolute
pure number of servers makes the problem
less interesting and the naughty not
less interesting to the site being
attacked but less interesting to the
global network and of course the scale
is somewhat limited there all right so
we actually have a lot of ongoing
measurement and I'm sure everyone knows
in your BGP routing table you have some
routes that got there by
misconfigurations possibly attacks some
kind of errors you know there's a little
bit of fun floating around there and
these of course can include the prefixes
that reach gtld in root servers and just
to give you an example that this really
does happen the PG TLD usually sits over
192 2692 30 and we noticed one day that
prefix seem to have moved to a small ISP
in europe and filter lists ideally would
have caught some stuff here this wasn't
the only route that that's back out but
it did go out to the general networks
and from where we were sitting at our
monitoring points
four of the nine ISPs we were watching
adopted this route three of those ISPs
held on to the route and continued to
announce it to us for about 20 minutes
one is be held on to it and announced it
for three hours and and then eventually
it was actually killed at the source
never reappeared and and nothing you
know never could be seen again and of
course this isn't the only example but
but we all know bad routes escape out
there and sometimes they hit servers the
ISP in question here wasn't trying to
imitate a sea route server but you could
imagine if somebody was you can sort of
direct a denial of service or maybe
director redirection of traffic attack
against some number of ISPs how well you
can control how far that spreads is an
interesting question but but certainly
it's a its possibility all right so we
have kind of an interesting idea for a
solution here current BGP provides
dynamic routes which is certainly a good
thing and here we are coming with Randy
and myself and a bunch of academic
people saying wait let's look again at
dynamic route so what we're doing is
actually trying the opposite extreme
just to see what happens so what we're
going to do is we're going to say select
a single route to each one of the
servers so we're going to put in their
25 fixed routes we use a s pass filters
to make sure that the only advertisement
we're going to accept so when that route
is gone we can't reach the server we're
also of course going to apply more
specific so that you can't sneak a more
specific route into to get around our
filter and this route is going to change
on a frequency of months if at all so
we're not going to try to accommodate
link failures we're not going to try to
do any kind of engineering traffic
engineering the only time we're going to
change is if root server IP address
changes so you know not frequently or
possibly maybe an origin a s changes or
we see some real legitimate change and
transit policy that we were forced to
adopt two and we're only going to adjust
to this new route after we do offline
verification right so essentially we're
static routing to 26 servers
alright so why is this even something
you could consider in theory well
there's a couple unique features here
that we're looking at first the scale of
the problem is limited to a small number
of routes we're looking at 25 routes
that actually did so they're 26 servers
but one shares a prefix so we have 25
total routes and we have no problem of
exponential growth if you count the
total number of top-level servers even
including things other than commnet in
or if you still have no relatively small
set and it's not growing not grown fast
at least we also believe that it's okay
to actually lose one of the routes to
the servers for a while you know it's
actually much better to have a lost
route than a route pointing you to an
invalid server and we all know DNS will
will deal with the loss of a few servers
it's going to time out it's going to
retry whatever survives and as long as
we provide that the surviving servers
are able to handle the load and maybe
we're a little bit early to pay a little
cost and delay on timeouts the DNS is
still going to work we also claim that
we believe there are some predictable
properties here these servers don't
change without non-trivial effort right
this is not this is not a web server
hanging off somebody's dsl modem at home
this is a root server that you're going
to have to talk to I can to move and
it's fixed also we believe these fits in
places that have highly available
locations and you know part of the
ability to run a route or gTLD is
hopefully you you have the ability to
keep your network up you know
substantial amount of the time or or
possibly you know you don't you
shouldn't be running a root server so so
in theory we believe maybe it's a good
idea but of course the only way you ever
really find out is you have to look at
some actual data and so what we did is
we took an analysis of BGP updates using
the right data set I think everybody's
probably heard of right because you
haven't basically we have an archive of
all bgp updates sent by a number of
peers we're in particular looking at 99
ISPs US Europe and Japan
variety of of qualities for the isps the
data we use goes from februari of 2001
to april two thousand two also a couple
data collection note now we only use
peers we restricted our thing to our
results to peers that exchange full
routing tables so we're not losing any
dynamics because somebody's export
policy is hiding around and also one
unique feature of a lot of the
monitoring points is they use multi-hop
bgp to connect a remote router to the
monitoring points here and basically
that's really pretty much unique to the
monitoring of the structure and those
peering sessions do tend to reset a
little more frequently than would happen
in a real ifp so we try to discount a
little bit for processing restocks where
the session goes down same wraps get
riad ver tised as an assess immediately
comes back up I would hope you don't see
that in your operational networks if you
have your you appear on a direct link
and you're frequently seeing a session
restart you may have more or concerns
okay so so the actual some actual
numbers here this is taken from a
typical ISP in our study it's a u.s.
it's a tier 1 although as I understand
everyone here is a tier 1 but so that
the top line counts the number of
servers you can reach and the percentage
of server percentage of time they're
available so if you look at the red here
this is P is able to reach 13 of the
server's about ninety-eight percent of
the time okay and if you look if you
want to reach 11 of the servers so you
pretty much have a hundred percent of
the time where you can get to 11 servers
and so that that's good now you apply
our filter and you are going to lose
some routes because remember we're
restricting you to specific static
routes so your app goes away no backups
are available so the number of times you
can read 13 servers drops dramatically
so you're down to 75 percent of the time
you get all 13 servers
but as you get up to certainly 10
servers the results with and without the
filter are pretty much indistinguishable
10 servers with the filter I'm still
reaching all of them without the filter
I'm still reaching all of them the
difference of course is I'm going to
ignore any any bogus routes that are
sitting out there when I apply the
filter so I've actually gained something
and and I'm going to try to claim that I
haven't really paid a big penalty in
terms of what I've lost now when I say
static routes I mean how static is
static right things do change in the
network and so over our 14 month period
for example if you look at the a root
server we had to do three manual changes
to the filter we had to axonal valid
changes in origin a s and a few other
non valid but the two were really actual
occurrences May nineteenth the origin is
changed from 6245 to 11 8 40 or geneious
changed again on 640 one and if you look
those up those all belong with the
organization you would expect so these
are legitimate changes we also saw one
change in a transit ASI outing policy
that caused our filter to reject routes
and that's where somebody stopped
pretending as is number so 10 9 13 was
pretending it's a s stop doing that in
hindsight perhaps our filter could have
been a little little smarter to allow
that so that not sure that's really a
static change versus maybe a oversight
and filtering so but of course we did
lose something so so what really got
lost so if you look at the data set from
the beginning of the study until that
first AF change where we switched pass
our filter reduced the reach ability to
the a server from 99.99 7 to 99.9 04 but
we actually saw 18 events where the
trusted route got lost and was withdrawn
two of these events resulted in isp one
actually losing connectivity to the
server so we had one event or 28 seconds
with no route one event of 103 seconds
in the round
now interestingly we only had eight
instances where we use the backup route
that survived for more than three
minutes and three minutes is a somewhat
magical number we took from some work by
Craig and sort of other once a possible
point for saying this is maybe a
legitimate change versus this is not and
of all the backup rats we used the
longest backup route we had stayed
around for 15 minutes so that was
probably a legitimate or out the rest of
these changes you may have been okay
actually throwing them away and these
results now we have nine ISPs and 26
servers so I can present these graphs
all day but this is essentially a
representative one and on our website
and on a paper you're welcome to look at
more data so just to give you a sort of
an example of what got filtered out so
so here's one event we initially start
with this is our trusted route to the a
root server and I'm only selling the
tale of the AAS path trusted Ralph gets
withdrawn and replaced by this guy at
1606 now our filter would have dropped
this but the ISP is still claiming I can
reach the server oh he lost a wheel
Austin is there but 36 about 30 seconds
later we had another another path change
and yet another path change and then
finally we declare no route right so
this is this is not unexpected in BGP I
mean people who looked at bgp
convergence aren't going to be too
shocked by this result and if we had a
fiber filter all those would have been
thrown out and instead of declaring i
have no route at 1608 30 i would have
declared i have no route at 1606 32 and
you know in so in this case throwing
that away maybe he's not such a bad
thing to do not sure how much reach
ability you really had in that interval
so even though our graph look pretty
good I'm going to claim that the results
are even better if you consider when the
route really gets you to the server of
course there's always the worst case and
so of the nine this is
worst case in our study and and here you
can see a drop in root server roots
ability but i think is actually worth
thinking about and it's a little bit
worrying if you're this is p so
initially this is p 99 percent of the
time you have 13 servers you apply our
filter and you only get 12 servers sixty
percent of the time so forty percent of
the time you've lost at least one or two
servers and we only start to catch up
with the real routing around six servers
and you only need one assuming not
everybody switches to the same one so
you know the isp would still work still
yeah the other graph looked a lot nicer
so so where did this leave us just left
us with all right we don't actually want
to come to nanog and propose put static
routes in your backbone that's that's
not really what the the point of the
talk is here but we do think that you
know there may be a balance to look at
here and some problems with our approach
are we did require in frequent updates
to the filter and this would have been
especially useful to automate because i
think there's a natural tendency that if
it's a task that must be done and is
done sort of periodically there tends to
be a tendency to either forget the task
or when it comes up forget what were the
steps i did to update the filter so it'd
be nice to either update the filter
frequently or automated also if we
allowed more than one path obviously we
improved robustness our simple filter
allowed only one passed got pretty good
reach ability we could have improved
that is p three draft tremendously if we
had said let's allow two paths into our
filter because that is p was sort of
often switching between a main path and
a well-used backup so really the
question here is can you strike a
balance between simply accepting any
route through a root server that someone
advertises and the other extreme of
saying i will only follow this known
valid route to the server and of course
we have a claim that we have an
algorithm to do that and so the main
idea behind the algorithm is just to
sort of
slow down the dynamics and they had some
optional verification depending on how
secure you want to be so we apply some
hysteresis before accepting a new path
so essentially the dynamics for these
routes are actually slower than what you
would get in the real internet and if
you want you can throw in an optional
module here to either leave the route
simply because it survived in the table
a while use some probabilistic query in
response to make sure what you're
getting back from the server really is a
real answer or maybe trigger some
offline checking for instance bas of the
root server has moved let's ask the
administrator if that makes sense and
maybe even male market bear sign or post
on nanog did did da trute server really
change and if you want the details of
the algorithm you can get those in a
paper on our website and i'll have a
reference at the end here but but so
what happens if you sort of try to
strike this balance between adaptivity
and static routes and so this is is t1
and I think we've we've done a pretty
good job of improving overall reach
ability we're still getting 97 s % reach
ability to 13 servers and even at 12
servers the difference i think is
negligible and a lot of that losses
routes that you wouldn't have used to
get to the server anyways you look at
the gTLDs a similar story what's more
encouraging is this was our worst case
and is still our feelings are worth
worth case and for isp 3 by just
allowing a little bit of adaptation
we're able to still protect against the
forged route that or the misconfigured
route but we still have a high degree of
reach ability same story for the root
servers but for the gtld servers and so
it's really a fairly simple story but i
think hopefully an interesting one so
our conclusions basically are that look
we've been we've been looking at data
from a research perspective we're
interested both in securing BGP and
securing DNS for however you might
define securing and here's sort of a
unique special case where maybe you
really can do something and we did
observe faults in the internet we think
there is a potential
for denial of service so we would
encourage people to it at least watch
this and see if you are believing bogus
routes to top-level servers and and be
worried that if you do believe 13 bogus
ralphs and you'd probably have 13 bogus
routes from your table now the wrong 13
and you're in trouble and we propose a
solution here a sort of the counter
intuitive thing maybe dynamic graphs
aren't all they're cracked up to be but
certainly we want some dynamic
adaptation to topology changes ability
to use backup routes but let's consider
making these less dynamic this is
clearly limited to this problem we're
not going out there and saying let's put
a static route for the entire table
right this relies on the unique
properties of the root servers in
particular scale ability to lose one and
the belief that these are highly
predictable and the stable locations and
we will lose some robustness to failure
so certainly anybody considering doing
this needs to look at your own topology
and make sure you have disjoint enough
paths so that if you are going to filter
you you allow yourself enough robustness
so that one link won't cut all 13 root
servers you fall over to backup pass
which aren't allowed in your filter but
that's for the most part our data says
you won't be in that case and you will
gain some protection against invalid
routes and then also what we had hoped
is maybe some some feedback from the
general hottie and son on what is
essentially the merit of the problem
slots of concern over the general
problem security for bgp and dns do
people really think this is an issue and
we'd be welcome feedback and certainly
restrict this to the special case we we
have filter its academic research so
it's publicly available it does not run
in your router can run in your router if
it doesn't have to essentially builds a
filter and time parameters you control I
want to I want to let routes change on
the order of hours weeks months what you
can tune the parameters and also if you
feel we're totally out of the water here
the data we have says it seems to work
so we'd be very interested in any data
you can give that would give us a
counter example and that's that's pretty
much it questions
student Stewart today I think I'll be a
fruit a few questions one what's up a
dynasty three I mean did they suck or
what are you doing the bad thing to them
well I think hi sp3 suffers from two
problems first I told you that two
servers sit in the same prefix right and
they have trouble with that particular
route so they pay a little extra penalty
there and for that route essentially
what they're doing is I think it's too
short term to be traffic engineering but
they occasionally do lose their primary
route and when that happens they fall
over pretty much immediately to a backup
route that will stay around for an hour
or two hours until the primary comes
back okay when you say they lose their
primary route is that a function of
losing their primary provider hi or is
just that rocketing withdrawn that route
getting withdrawn from the we we've had
some we're trying to have some
discussions with them we don't really
have a good explanation from them as to
why that is why that is going away but
it is periodically going away and trying
to trying to back up that question
number two is how much does your data
change if you start locking down the AAS
path from one end and increasing by 1
right that's the locking down the entire
path what if you start from the Dean own
origin of the prefix and work your way
that way and conversely what if you
start with what you know to be your best
next hop a s and work that way okay I
think there's actually two interesting
things there is one I mean there may be
sort of a cause and effect here that if
people really did this we would see a
much greater change in the dynamic of
the root servers which could in turn
change the results from our study and
learn faster absolutely yeah but i think
you know basically we we look at that i
don't have good good data on that right
now what we can do is we can say you
know based solely on what i know about
my routes all i can do is just choose my
past
this is what I select and if i do it i
get this result we certainly we hope to
have more data in that direction by
don't have something for you now if
you're going to follow it that would be
interesting to know okay yeah thanks
what time period would you like to have
these filters work on I mean are you are
you looking for mechanisms which sort of
time ratio would you like these filters
to exist on well we believe we have a
pretty good based on the ISP data we
have we believe we have a pretty good
trade-off and our current trade-off
allows the route to change at most once
a week and if you allow that you're
you're getting reasonable answers but
but I think it also can depend on your
particular spot of ecology ready so
that's that I think the strongest answer
soon as it to spent depends upon how you
but you're a fan out is right what your
up screens fan outs are where your
honest apology
if I'm sitting extreme case of courses
i'm sitting there with one up screen you
know I listen I believe