thanks everyone thanks for coming and
kind of feel a little shy actually
didn't want to do a big introduction but
I do have a slide so all right so
welcome to this talk and first I wanted
to see you guys probably saw on the
agenda we have two full hours of
containers yay no well don't worry so
Josh and I sink top ahead of time so we
know who's gonna talk about what so
you're gonna get really good material
for the boat two hours if you wish to
say for two hours so let me start with
who I am and I'm currently a director of
solutions engineering engineering at
Eclipse him which does hardware and
firmware security I was also a did a
stint as a security architect for check
marks and people probably heard of
checkmarks focusing on application
security and then before that I was
leading a group of professional services
for Identity and Access Management so
I've literally been up and down the
security stack and over the years I got
a lot of spirits and everything and just
a lot of experience in being a hardened
site of the stack so what the stock is
not gonna be about I'm not here to talk
about docker
well actually I'm probably not kidding
anyone I'm you can talk cannot not talk
about docker I am gonna be talk about
darker but just not just about docker so
what I'm also not gonna be talking about
here in this presentation there's
everything that's low on stack so I work
in Hardware infirmary security and I
work with those exploits but a majority
of my experience is actually dealing
with an enterprise level security as
you've seen so it's everything up above
the the hypervisor stack it's in the
kernel seconds the user space stack
everything else you see down below I
hope everybody understands if you get
owned by one of those things
you screwed anyhow right your your
really yeah there's no talk about
continuous at that point so but I'm not
going to talk about it I'm gonna talk
about containers and when you talk about
containers in is if anybody's been into
presentations about containers
you know you have some obligatory slice
so here's a slide about container
history alright I'll just move on okay
here's here's a slide about broken
containers broken they're horrible okay
here's a dead whale okay dead whale for
you guys okay good now no that's out we
can actually get to the presentation
okay so I wanted to share his story and
its story about me about a year ago so
and this is where I've inherited what I
call traditional some people call legacy
I like to steal a call traditional
security product it's a monolithic
products it's focusing on enterprise
level security it's it's focusing on
certain things that developers do and
it's trying to analyze the work flow of
the developers now developers are on the
forefront of technology as I'm sure
everybody have noticed sits they you
know they're screaming containers
they've been screaming for five years
for six years they've been screaming
microcell services for four years they
now screaming serverless been screaming
for two years there's all the cool and
new technologists are coming on the
market and they really want to try it
they wanna you know make an impact build
something cool build build something
quick and they are my consumers I'm
essentially working for them I need to
provide a product that lives in their
ecosystem and I'm stuck with the legacy
product that lives in the ecosystem of
Windows you know dotnet development you
know services Windows services and a
sequel and all that stuff and I need to
I have certain goals I need to make it
secure I need to make it fast and I also
need to make it so it fits inside of the
DevOps infrastructure so essentially
Dell ops is serving doubts and devs are
making their crazy decisions and ops
wants to put everything in the fast
pipeline you want to put something in
where you you can get a turnaround for
their servers for the Dells and now I
need to make that product the legacy
product work in that pipeline and so
so go okay well let's start with this
let's start with you know why you know
containers are pretty cool I heard let's
start looking at what what are they for
and looking at it you realize that these
are actually two goals and they're not
necessarily competing goals there
there's that's something that developers
need and they're trying to close this
gap and they're closing it in to kind of
dissimilar ways but one and the more
important one for the devs is
distribution is how do i package it up
in applications so it works smoothly in
all the systems how would I you know put
it in my dev box and then give it to the
ops guy and then he can run it with no
changes so that's the distribution
problem now the second problem is how to
run untrusted code and by untrusted in
in the dev sense it means somebody
else's code it's like you know it's no
js' I don't necessarily not trust it but
it's no genius who knows where it can
get out so it's better if I close it and
that's the sandbox problem now they're
not like I said mutually exclusive and
this is where containers kind of come in
play alright so back you know five seven
years ago when you talked about
container so you mentioned sandbox as
the VMS came up right and we all been
using VMs for a long long time vm is
actually pretty good about container
raising applications right escaping from
a hypervisor all to the systems you know
not a thing for the past five six years
is it possible probably is it likely
very unlikely so they've been really
good at keeping the close eye on you
know everything that happens in the user
space in the kernel space and then down
to the hypervisor so they're actually
pretty secure now the trouble with them
is they're good for security they're not
really good for distribution if anybody
tried copying you know 10 50 and 50
gigabyte VM off to ops machine you know
that right so there have been systems
they've been solutions to try to make
them a little more portable to kind of
like we sold the sandboxing problem now
distribution maybe we can solve it with
vagrants if anybody tried vagrant you
basically your infrastructure as code
you push it out and creates VMs it's
good I use it I actually daily use it it
manages the VMS alright but it's still
kind of clunky and it still takes time
and it's still not very sufficient same
thing with sheriffs and puppets who try
to manage the infrastructure at the code
level - it works I mean it's a good
workaround but it's really still not
solving the distribution problem and
this is where we come to the kernel
level containers you know those things
that kind of live in here and this is
where docker is right so the kernel
containers are the things that isolate
your security at the level of the kernel
assist level calls and I I feel
obligated to mention the the ways that
are they're made if you actually want to
find out more about the details of what
goes into making a container go to the
next talk josh is gonna talk more about
those but I'll mention them here so when
I say concur non-level containers are
not first order primitives that means
that they're not things in themselves
there's sort of aggregation of other
things it's like a container is a thing
that's put together very cleverly and
it's that there are other things that is
put together with are the capabilities
which limit the process privileges the C
groups which limited resource access
then the namespaces that isolate kernel
functions and then the second filters
that filter the SIS calls into the
kernel and finally you've got an overlay
file system and an overlay network so
take all those pieces by themselves
they're not very much worth it but you
know combine them into something new and
you get something like rocket or docker
and that's how containers came to be and
so there are multiple ways the
containers are done actually I'll start
from the bottom
you if anybody used Heroku you've
already used containers you didn't even
know that here okay we're the first ones
who actually created containers now
they're not public containers that you
can you know run hiroko containers in
your box but they're the ones who
actually came up with that concept and
that's because they run untrusted code
on their infrastructure but later after
that and you can go back to the history
slide if you really want it but lxc
containers
there's still a thing Alex see is what I
call a hardened wood container it's like
you know you're good
all those primitives and you're the ones
in charge and putting those together and
you're the one who's enabling this and
then once you've put it all together
then you've got your car assembled and
now you can actually run with it and
canonical is trying to help they're
building something like lxd to manage
those containers but it's still kind of
like hardcore mode containers for you
people use it especially people in big
companies that need very fine-grained
control over containers now the docker
containers and this is where the whole
thing took off right this is the easy
mode containers there's the ones that
you go and do you know docker run blah
blah and that's suddenly poof you've got
your system that's like we're cool and
as you can imagine there's some cost to
it we're gonna come to costs of the ease
of use
now there's rocket containers and I'm
gonna talk a little bit about the
security of rocket containers but they
they were created to be secure were like
better River than darker okay and you
know the other thing that I wanted to
mention is when you talk about container
level containers you actually do have
really fine gain control control and you
can run you can turn on and off features
in those containers and do really cool
stuff so for example I'll give you
hopefully you can see this so here's a
here's a container that runs a Microsoft
by the way my I'm running Linux on here
but here's a container that was gooey
this the whole thing is inside of
container if you not familiar this is
sequel operation studio that Microsoft
put out for managing sequel server and
you'll see my talk why I need to manage
the sequel server but this is the Linux
container with a gooey front to it and
it's running it and if you actually want
to look at it give it just second I'll
put this so that's this guy you see I
just forward X and I'll run the
container and I get the X so that's your
gooey container you're actually running
stuff inside of the container but you're
interacting it on the gooey level with
it
all right so
the other thing really cool things is
you can run obviously Windows tools will
come to it and you can run a algorithm
so back at home I actually have a little
lab where I'm running Nvidia CUDA deep
dream Network and I create images with a
deep deep dream Network and it's all
running inside of a container so I
didn't install anything I was like
really really we were cool I got AI on
my desktop with no like investment into
building the crazy you know Python
modules non Python and everything that
goes with that and so I was really
really interesting and the big point I
want to make here is with all that
flexibility comes responsibility so
there's a lot of things you can shoot
yourself in the foot with and we're
coming to this but before we go into
containers into kernel level containers
I did want to mention the app level
containers and those are the things that
you probably seen too so for example if
if you ever tried if you run a gnome and
you ever tried to install something from
KDE like the Kate I headed err in KDE
and I really like hidden you do the
usual just you you do the usual app
install Kate then I comes to you and
says okay I'm gonna upgrade in 2-0
packages I'm gonna install a hundred and
fifty two packages under your system and
do you want to continue yes or no and
the correct answer is No
so obviously canonical and Debian
everybody recognized that little problem
that it brings to you and they tried
working on it so snaps happens snaps
happened about five years ago and what
what it is and if you watch
Mark Shuttleworth presentations he's
actually really good about describing
them but they're he's describing them as
the things that are here they're not
containers in the sense that are
isolated from your system they're
containers in a sense that they're
packaged up so essentially it's a
packaged app application that has
limited view into your system but you
also get a full use of that system and
so there's been a very solid change if
you guys live on Ubuntu you'll notice
that sooner than later if you before if
you type in a name of the tool that is
not on your system you'll get
prompt and on goal like this Camille not
found use apt apt install for that
program now if you do this on 1804 or
1800 1810 Lubuntu it comes up with this
not for all programs but with this
notice a little difference you see this
pseudo snap they want you to run snap
now so so what's happening behind it's I
don't know if it's good or bad it's it's
a thing now
they basically they're pushing people to
using snaps more and more and they
actually have their own operating system
I'll mention that then the balloons a
core that's all about snaps but snaps is
just one thing in the canonical space
now and you can see it's basically thing
in the user space it's not extending out
anywhere down into the kernel or the
hypervisor level but there's things that
existed for a long time and you've
probably heard about this is an app and
the thin app and Microsoft V apps now
there are other packages like a Panna
Jazeera installing flatback anybody
who's lived in Linux probably knows
those they you might not know but each
tab in your chrome is actually container
sandbox by itself and it's running
inside of its own pit namespace meaning
that the programs within that tab can't
see anything else so it is a container
it's like a sandbox inside of chrome now
there are only containers in the sense
that this is a container so that I
continue yeah but that's the app
container so as I looked through all
this different technologies in the past
and as I looked at my challenge I it was
pretty easy to realize the amps were too
hard in distribution the app containers
were to open so I was left with the
middle I was left with the containers
that are in the middle of space now I'm
gonna give you a little lay down this is
this is not me from a year ago this is
me from today and this is like if I knew
what's happening with containers this is
what I've showed myself back here but
this is what's happening with the
containers now so to the very so right
here you see your VM containers right
this is the application that's running
on a guest kernel that's I
isolated by the hypervisor from
affecting anything on a host kernel so
essentially your level of isolation is
this hypervisor that's VM now the
traditional kernel level container is
like darker live in this space so you
have an application you have a bunch of
controls and syscall filters that
prevents you from abusing your host and
this filter is the one that's
responsible for security of your
containers and then you go down to the
host kernel now the thing that happened
probably a year ago maybe a little more
is the Intel clear container so the Cata
containers so what they looked at the
same problem and said okay VMs are too
hard
Cisco filters are kind of too flexible
how do we combine the best and they came
up with a mini OS special key SM kernel
that this really fast booting kind of
quick to execute KVM you know qmu
combined into one package and simplified
so you run this essentially it is a kind
of VM container but it is also very
transparent so you get the best best of
both worlds in theory and then Google
looked at same problem and Google said
all right so how about we instead of
doing that the hypervisor thing in the
Cisco thing we actually create our own
kernel and we do it as a shim kernel so
all your calls from application go to
that shim kernel and then we filter it
out and we kind of look like a kernel
we're not actually a kernel but then we
whatever we get from the horse kernel
which sounds really really cool right
it's like wow why why not do this and in
it's all the cool ideas that the trouble
with this is they're all introduced a
lot of performance downgrades so
somebody and I have a link at the bottom
somebody did a performance analysis on
all those kernels and the Google G visor
came the worst it's like the slower than
the freaking VM and then they looked at
the Intel CC and I was like it was
painful to do those two and so when you
actually look at the performance graph
and I don't have it here because I
didn't want to copy it from that web
page but essentially says your docker
things are the fastest
your CCS are probably in the next then
the GM's and then the Google G visor
now that's could change in the future so
in maybe at some point in time they're
gonna you know own up and really build
it onto something really cool and maybe
that's the next thing in containers but
so far it's it wasn't and obviously a
year ago it wasn't a choice for me
either so another thing that wasn't a
choice for me is the scone and the scone
is the next cool thing that kind of
happened so containers that are running
in IntelliJ X and claves and that's
another idea it's like yay how about we
go one level down do you people know
about us Jax I see I see so essentially
it's a it's a completely independent
encrypted area for code execution and
for data manipulation that only the
processor can access and you can switch
the doubt and clave and then execute
your trusted code on that so it really
kind of pokes way from the application
down to the hardware level and then
brings it all up to the application
level so that's like you can't get any
more secure than that and my question to
you is did you foreshadow it yeah do you
guys anybody see what I did there
yeah all right for those who didn't get
it for Shadow is an attack on those GX
enclaves it just came out fairly
recently and that's the thing that
breaks stuff in the STX enclaves and
plus they are horribly slow to you
imagine bringing all the stuff down and
then we encrypting and bring it all up
that somebody estimated it's like
actually the original paper that
proposed these years and claves and
containers coated that there were 18
times slower than a normal container so
there you go
III think it's an interesting technology
to watch for but that's probably even
farther out okay
so at this point a year ago I made my
pick darker and other containers were it
I needed to provide the flexibility I
needed to provide the performance doctor
was fitting I need to have reasonable
security and I was planning to run
trusted code I wasn't you know running
our clients code on that
so I I was fairly you know confident so
that doctor will do it fairly well
without resorting to the amps and the
next thing that kind of hit me is was it
was Windows so now I have to both
windows on darker it was like okay well
windows for darker was the thing already
at the time for probably two three years
and I you know don't deep down into the
space of windows containers trying to
figure out what what the hell's going on
there well I'll give you a quick gist
I'm not gonna go into a lot of details
but there used to be a Google darker
toolbox which was running containers
inside of the VirtualBox installed on
your windows then Microsoft kind of
owned up to the whole thing and they
said all right so how about we just for
Windows 10 which is probably devil
machines we can use hyper-v to run your
docker containers but for Windows Server
we create a Windows Server container
subsystem that actually does run
containers so essentially they did
provide access to the NT kernel features
from within your container so you don't
have to have any any other stupid VM
level in between because I'm sure you
understand putting a VM in somewhere in
the middle kind of negates the benefits
of docker
speed right so the trouble is hyper-v
use exclusive istic that means you can't
run VirtualBox when you're on hyper-v
although I actually did beat it into
existence and I can show I'm running
hyper-v on the k vm in linux inside of
the VirtualBox and it's it's horrible
don't try it at home but if you ever
feel masochistic I can't give you
pointers so windows containers they run
on Windows Server and Windows server
core the images windows images have to
start with only two distributions like
if you know docker you can start from
scratch you can go and build your darker
from the beginning for Windows you have
to start either from the nano server
which is their version of Windows server
that can run anything but 64-bit and
only dotnet core applications and if you
don't know dotnet core is the lighter
version of that it's more
Linux friendly they're actually porting
dotnet core to Linux and then the other
thing is or you can base it on Windows
server core which is an 11 gig based
distribution and then you run it with
dot net and you can have fooled at net
and you can have 32-bit and of course
telemetry you know Micra so what you're
doing you can turn it off but by default
it's on and you don't even know it
okay so that's how you run Windows on
docker containers inside of Windows and
then you can run Linux but that
introduces a hyper-v VM there's no
tricks to it you can't run Linux kernel
on Windows kernel you have to have a VM
and between that does something for you
and that's their solution so I'm not
sure you can ever expect Windows to run
Linux containers natively but when you
run it just know that there's a hyper-v
VM underneath it and I'm going to talk
about it in a second - so and then when
you run Windows containers on Linux you
can actually do this and I'll show to
you so just second hopefully you can
hear me still so I'm gonna switch to
another shell and this is this is my
darker that's well I can't type so look
at those two things so this is the
client and the client is Linux and then
this is the server and the server is
Windows so if I do a darker image I have
a list of images and you see whoo I can
run Windows server core I can run
another server I can even run Microsoft
sequel server on my daugher so that's
pretty cool
notice the sizes - this is you know this
is a little different from Linux
containers but it's all possible but the
reason this possible is not a big trick
really what what I'm doing actually in
the background is I'm running this
little thing the Ronix linux docker host
which is a Windows server core VM which
I'm forwarding the docker management
interface out and
and I'm connecting to the darker
management interface and this is why I
all talk about the darker management
interface in just a second so come on
complete for me yay all right so that's
the trick
so I'm feeding off a different system
and running it here and my Linux
environment okay so with that out what's
the catch and the catch is simple it
still it works Microsoft's is still
working on it they're bugs all over the
place they're still on the implemented
features did not working is buggy and I
fortunately I had to spend like two days
you know now debugging the network where
it would die in the middle of a very
intensive stream and it was horrible but
I still have headaches about it but so
another thing is nana servers headless
you can't run any Google nana server
windows server container it doesn't have
an RDP built into it so you can't RDP
into it so what that means is you can't
have that nice GUI windows containers
what I showed you from Linux just a
second ago you can't have that on
Windows it's just not possible so maybe
one day when Windows when Microsoft
actually goes into implementing the RDP
into Windows containers maybe then you
can have your GUI from the windows
containers and you also don't there's no
way to update Windows containers and I
go wait wait what what no no update on
windows so yeah containers are immutable
in the way that my croissants you to do
it is they want you to re-upload vbase
your image rebuild your image so every
time you pull an image you actually are
building on the latest fixpack that they
build in so what it means to you if
you're running Windows containers you
have to rebuild your images that's the
only way you can get a Windows Update on
the windows container alright moving on
so let's talk a little bit about
security of the windows containers
because that's windows you have to talk
about security and a couple of things
one is apparently I have no idea why
they do this but when darker porter
their stuff
two windows they rewrote it in dotnet
instead of go and what it means to you
is that now you can look at the source
code you now you can reverse the source
code and look at the go because you know
there's dotnet just like Java you can
you know look at the dotnet code
reversed from the white level code so
one guy did it he opened it up he said
all right cool let's look at the darker
core DLL you know he found this little
thing that passed packets from the
docker control interface and he said
let's se realized I wonder what I can do
there with this so what he did is he
built a DC realization attack on the
docker dotnet DLL and he got himself to
escalate the privileges from from the
normal darker D into a darker user with
net Authority system so that's the thing
just making you aware that's not a
horrible thing but it is a thing another
thing that people did with Windows
containers and this is really cool
attack i I I will walk you really
quickly through this because I think
it's cool it's worth knowing about it
was demonstrated at blackhat 17 and it
relies on several critical windows
components basically what it is is
somebody I developer goes out to on
malicious website and a malicious
website has JavaScript and that
JavaScript wants to target your docker
instance and by default just like you
saw me here exposing that interface
developers do expose the internal
interfaces out to their systems and by
default that will be bound to zero zero
zero meaning to any interface so docker
is listening on your machine on any
interface for any action you can do with
docker
and what they do is that malicious
JavaScript then reroutes back to the
darker daemon on your machine through a
little tricks with DNS rebinding
Microsoft has this LLVM thing for
assigning DNS names but you can trick it
is essentially saying you're going to
pwned something and then that poll now
resolves to your local Dhakal German
darker daemon so the JavaScript from the
browser is now talking to the dark
on your machine and from that point on
you have full ownage because you can
actually create new containers they
created a new containers they put a
shell script into that container that
container actually because you're
running at boot privileges and I'll show
them a second to that infected the mobi
VM remember I talked about the VM
running on Linux so in fact that made
persistence and so at that point in time
every time you spawn off another
container on your machine it was already
rootkit it so if you're interested find
out more about this they go into a lot
of details but that's just it a kind of
cool thing that you can do with the
containers okay so another thing that I
had to deal with is that I was working
with very sensitive intellectual
property I was dealing with encrypted
installers because that's sensitive IP
you don't want to get it out I had to
have a sensitive deployment I had a
special licensing protocol that I had to
do basically I had to protect my
employer at the time and I had to make
it secure now well so just to explain to
you what's going on here with secrets
and by the way there's not a conference
talk going on about secrets at the same
time but why do you show you something
so let's say I'm building a container
and I want to look at storing secret
information and I build something like
this I look at look at my darker file
and it's something like I've got a
secret here maybe I can store it my
secret in the environment variable but
if you look at darker you know that you
shouldn't really storing this I can try
to store it in the build arguments I can
copy my super-secret file into and then
delete that super-secret file maybe
that's good enough for me to build a
docker container and actually you know
get my secrets into the container
without exposing them to the end-user
well so I'm sure you guys heard about
docker history if you haven't you should
and the darker history is this so I
should probably build this so I'm
building it
so I'm doing this and I'm gonna do this
I'm gonna add a build because I'm smart
I miss I've heard about security and I'm
building a build arguments to assign my
secret password at the build time so I
can save it and not have to give it out
to the customer so it builds and then I
do this I just want to check how it
built I do a darker history I do my
container secret
come on complete for me I don't want to
type all right and I see something
really odd in this history so instead
you know it kind of looks ugly but I
build this little tool called darker
historian and I do this and it gives me
oh my gosh it gave me back my docker
file and it gave me with the the secret
here and well thankfully the file is
deleted so shouldn't have any files in
that but it also gave me this like key
to secrets so all your secrets are
exposed you can't save them in a docker
file well moreover actually take a look
at this so here's my docker historian
for let's see what do I have
oh the sequel my my little Microsoft
sequel file sequel o sequel Express ok
so here's here's my secret my docker
file it's essentially reversing this the
docker file back into what it was so if
you ever get an image and you want to
find out how was build run this you're
gonna get your darker file back with all
the details moreover you know actually
see this part is what darker did
themselves this is how they built the
image that I built my docker file from
so you can reverse all the way back and
just to show you I'm not I don't have
anything up my sleeve here's here's my
docker file for Microsoft sequel so this
is what I did and this is from
docker so this is it reversed you see it
looks a little bit different obviously
it's not the same syntax but then this
is what I got from so if I ever want to
rebuild Ubuntu like they did and I can
just run this file so that's easy
alright so that that was about history
now another thing is like all right what
I do about the file and there's darker
save and I do darker save and I save my
secret to ah dump and let's see what's
in that dump and I go start my my little
tool it stores right here okay I have
the dump file and I look in the dump
file sorry look in my dumb file and you
know what's going on I okay
so I look in the dump file and there's
several layers in that dump file and
there's a JSON in that dump file that
actually uh interesting to you can look
at all the details of the JSON file and
see what's going on there you can see
the secrets too if you want it to but
what's more interesting is that docker
file has layers and in one on the layers
I find the super secret file and this is
because that's what docker does it never
deletes stuff it actually creates layers
yeah the file system is right on or
create on right so whatever you write
something it creates another layer so
your secret super secret file is still
there don't worry about this okay so
that's about secrets and that gave me a
huge headache I had to look at it in its
like oh my gosh I was building darker
and I built this well turns out they're
solutions and the solutions are either
squashing or multistage built I'm not
going to go into details unfortunately
that's not supported on Windows so I
wasn't nowhere you know pretty bad move
now there are open source solutions like
docket of old and others like hash warp
and kubernetes and swarm that wasn't
overkill for me at the time so what I
did is I build a standalone docker
container to
contain all the secrets so during a
build time they can get the secrets from
the standalone docker container but
that's essentially the extent you have
to go to to actually build a secure and
reasonable solution and then last thing
I have to do is okay now I have to have
a standalone Linux container so let's
look at the Linux security and the Linux
security has gotten a lot of attention a
Linux acha contain container security
got a lot of attention over the past
years so I'm not gonna go again into
details if you're really interested in
figuring out if they're secure the short
answer yeah layer secure no talk goes
about referencing just Raziel and her
container AF thing basically it's
proving that they are secure unless you
do stupid stuff and I appreciate people
do stupid stuff but there's you can do
protections against the DOS you can
there's cap net raw capability in the
Linux containers that in theory give you
men in the middle but in practice nobody
actually proved it there's also a
knowledge set of tools that allows you
to look into the application side of
your container and and defend from the
application level your container but
there are tons of food guns and food
guns is something you know you pretty
much do to yourself and this is how you
screw yourself over so here's a typical
scenario if you ever run know the inside
of a docker container you probably
encounter this when you hit control-c
the container doesn't terminate and you
do what you Google right and the first
thing that pops up is this guy from
darker thread saying okay if you can't
terminate it just add the - - bid equals
cost and and you're good with it no
change to the code and you're like yay
well what this does is it exposes all
the processes from your host to your
dock in containers so whatever is
running inside of your container can now
you look at the command lines on your
poor host and it's like yay so the
actual answer is to add single handle
inside of your app there are other food
gowns that people do to themselves like
the rude thing so let me show you the
rude thing so never run containers root
you might have heard this but here's to
use the actual proof so
docker run
and do interactive with the volume of
slash mounted to slash are on your
container and do all porn because it's
small and run this so this is darker
container and notice I'm running it as
myself right it I'm user I'm not doing
soo do anything but then I'm kicking off
this container and I do inside of that
container I do crap for roots inside of
/r remember that's where I mounted in so
I basically got a root on my machine
without being rude and the reason it
works is because the Dr Dee container is
running as root and I'm a part of the
doctor group so that last group that
essentially gives any container Iran
root privileges so if you run root
inside of you container you root on your
host that's it
there's no joking about it so don't just
don't okay the other thing that people
do and I actually did it in front of you
guys if you haven't noticed its
supposing the socket so socket is the
way the doctor D communicates to
yourself so when I showed you my little
trick with Windows that's the socket in
Windows case this is a TCP socket in the
Linux case it's the actual socket so
when I'm exposing my socket I'm exposing
myself to that attack I just showed you
earlier and that's not just Windows
Linux - if I can write to the socket
Windows doctor doesn't do any
authentication it'll just trust it it's
like you can you can talk to me alright
I understand I'll run the container for
you and if you you're running it as root
2 so if you if you do something try not
to do this darker sock thing exposure
sometimes you have to do it and if you
need to do talk to me you know how to
work around it but yeah windows is kind
of like that just to show you again why
not to expose your darker socket in 2018
the darker had had 18 back toward images
the remaining Manero and it's a known
thing you know docker kind of warmed up
to it and they killed the this