[Jessica:] So, hello, good morning, today we're going to talk about building security people.
normally when I give talks, I tell things
like incident response stories, or I talk
about attacker trends, or maybe I talk
about cool malware, or if you know me
really well I'll tell you weird tricks
to hack Windows, like plugging in a smart
card to run arbitrary java as system. A
lot of times you'll hear me talk about
Event ID 1102. Who knows what event ID
1102 is? That's your event logs for
cleared. It's probably the event log
monitoring that you should be doing. A
lot of times in my talks I troll Will Harmj0y, but that's not why I'm here today.
Today I am here to exit my comfort
zone and I'm going to talk about
security people. I'm a security person
you're probably a security person if
you're here. Security people, have,
unplugged my laptop.
[ Audience Laughter ]
I don't think it's me.
Okay so I'm gonna turn my laptop around and you're gonna watch it on this little screen.
[ Audience Laughter ] Alright here we go.
I told you that we would be ad-libbing
and doing a rap battle.
Alright cool, so, security
people seem to be cool. Security people
seem to be relatively well compensated.
They seem to travel around. They seem to
do cool things. They seem to be able to
do things, like aftermarket editions that
invalidate the warranties on their
otherwise boring Volkswagens, which are
totally done responsibly and in
compliance with all laws of Washington
State. Security people are cool, so
everybody wants to be a security person.
I hear a lot of people saying I want to
be a security person. Is there a roadmap
to being a security person. Do we have
any way with- we have one single path to
get to being a security person. And
oftentimes, I get this in the form of the
question of. "How did you get to where you
are?". At which point I'm like, no, no, no no
no, this is danger. You really don't want
to know this. You really want to stop.
Because the reason that I'm a security
person and the reason that I'm on this
stage giving you a keynote today, or have
given any talk in security, is because I
am an epic failure. We're gonna talk
about me. This is awkward and
uncomfortable, but let's talk about how
my life was supposed to look. So I
actually started college at 14. That was
kind of cool because I come from the
middle of nowhere where people don't
even go to college. And then I was a
dancer. I was in a pre professional
ballet company. I thought I might
actually graduate from college. I thought
I might become some sort of forensic
pathologist, dancer, ninja, secret agent,
and maybe I'd become Carmen Sandiego.
[ Audience Laughter ]
But what really happens? So I started my
college at 14, got that part done. And
then I got incredibly ill and actually
failed out of college. Okay. But then I
went and I actually got a job at
Carnegie Mellon. I went to school at
Carnegie Mellon and then I dropped out
of Carnegie Mellon and I took an
incredibly awesome high paying job at a
very fancy law firm, where I was promptly
fired for being a jerk. [ Audience Laughter ]
But then, I received a call on my cell phone that
had this 425 area code and said
Redmond Washington and I'm like why, why
are you calling me? and it turns out it
was Microsoft. And I said I never want to
work at Microsoft. I don't really like
Microsoft. And someone gave me the advice
of, well if you want to change something
perhaps the best way to do that is from
the inside. So now I work at Microsoft.
[ Audience Laughter ]
But all throughout that entire chain of
events all throughout my life and
probably yours
there are turning points. There are
decisions that come up to you and there
are chances for you to kind of make a
change in what you're doing. And often as
you're going along you're going to hear
negative voices. Those negative voices
might come from other people or they
might come from inside your own head. And
those negative voices might tell you to
stop what you're doing, or do something,
or because you fell off the path that
you intended in life that, therefore, you
are bad at everything. [ Sighing ] Okay, this is
actually something someone once said to
me they said "I wouldn't bother applying
there don't get your hopes up." Well that
was for Carnegie Mellon, and I did apply
there and I did get that job, and okay.
This is something else that someone said
to me. This is actually a comment that
was left on an internal presentation I
gave at Microsoft in 2016. "Presenter has
been presenting on topics they don't
have sufficient background in" Well
considering APT's were only invented in
2014, who the heck has sufficient
background in incident response. Because
that is what I was presenting on, so
we're all insecurity people.
[ Audience Laughter ]
Because it turns out, that those negative
voices once you get them outside or in,
do make you feel a little bit insecure
but I also like the phrase "insecurity
people" because when I decided to become
a security person most of the people who
were famous for being security people
were insecurity people. They were breaking
things. They were hacking things. There
was not a lot of discussion about fixing
things, and there certainly were no
presentations on the windows firewall.
[ Audience Laughter ]
So I joined Microsoft. It's been a little
bit of a journey. It's been a little bit
of a winding road, like everyone's life
is. There have been moments where I could
have absolutely mic dropped on what I'm
doing. I could have left, I could have
chased money, I could have chased titles,
I could have chased other things, but I
joined Microsoft with a reason, and I stuck
it out, and eventually this happened.
That's pretty cool. But when we think
about that, when we think about what we
do in our life and why we do it. Here are
some things I've got to do as an epic
failure. Well I got to do this, I got to
do this, I've done this. Somebody in the
audience likes this cuz they tweeted me
at it. I did that. I presented on the same
stage as Raymond Chen. I discussed
the best way to make kale salad with my
coworker, while incidentally we were being
filmed for The Today Show.
[ Audience Laughter ]
I did this, which is a presentation on
demystifying Windows Firewall so now
there exists one. In my life as an epic
failure, where I did not intend to be a
security person, I've got to go lots of
cool places. I've been to Switzerland,
I've been to Poland, been to Hong Kong, I
went to Hobbiton, I took a selfie with an emu
[ Audience Laughter ]
one of my talks is actually in the
new hire training for my division. Okay.
So if I'm a failure,
and it took me getting to be a failure to
become a security person, I'm pretty
fuckin good at it. [ Audience Laughter ]
Okay, so I've talked about myself. That
was really awkward
we got that part out of the way. HXS
files are actually just portable
executables. A portable executable is
something that can be used to execute
code. You can make things with different
extensions that are also portable
executables that don't end in dot EXE or dot DLL. This is one of them. Okay, I feel
better now. I'm not the only one. When we
talk about building security people, so
many of my friends have a story that
looks like that. A story that looks like
I didn't actually plan to be here, I had
to suffer a little bit to get here, and
nobody really gave me instructions on
how to do it, so I'm gonna talk about one
of my awesome friends. I'm gonna talk
about Devon Kerr, human being. Devon Kerr
has since changed into that, where now he
is the director of response at endgame.
You may know him from this amazing whitepaper on WMI. Literally the whitepaper
on WMI. If you haven't read it, go read
it. So let's talk about Devon's career
journey. Devon's career journey looks a
little bit like this
he worked on a farm. He was a junior
Linux admin. He did UV pasteurization
systems for dairy farms. He worked at
college he did humanities in college. He
worked at a restaurant, multiple roles. He
did an e-commerce startup, then he did
technology retail. He did bridge
maintenance. He did college again. this
time for network administration then he
did roofing repair, specializing in tile, slate and copper.
He then moonlighted, did a little bit of
last wire. He did some more moonlighting.
He did barn restorations, specifically
the 1880 to 1920s period. [ Audience Laughter ] He then did masonry, he's actually very good at
masonry. He did ISP operations, he did
some highly available infrastructure.
Wireless infrastructure, did some
forensic lab construction, a little bit
more forensic stuff. He did security
operations he did IR consulting at
Mandiant, then he did IR consulting at
Mandiant: A FireEye Company. [ Audience Laughter ] and now he's director of
response at Endgame. So lots of people as I talked to
have this sort of journey in their life
where things are not necessarily laid
out for them the way that they should be.
So okay, now we're a success. We're
successes, supposedly.
We're pretty cool, we have cool jobs, we
do cool things, but now what? We had Blue
Hat a couple weeks ago.
Blue Hat is Microsoft's wonderful
security conference and our keynote
presenter had this in his keynote he's
like, "why am I here?"
and he's talking about a conversation he
had with someone where he said, "I didn't
know you were in security" and that
person said, "yeah, it's pretty great." and
he said, "I'm burnt out" and I, um, totally
not me, said, "You should write a deck about that." So that's what our keynote
came from, because in my version of that
conversation which, incidentally and
coincidentally I totally had a
conversation like that too. I said, "the
thing that keeps me going is mentoring
people." I do a lot of cool stuff on a day
to day basis. I get to fly around the
world. I get to actually save people's
infrastructures or in one or two
instances literally save people buy
stuff for that we're doing. I get to see
a lot of cool stuff, I get to do a lot of
cool things, but what's really given me
the most optimism recently in my career
has been being able to actually take
people and uplift them and build my own
security people. Because it's really
weird and kind of uplifting to be able
to take someone who comes from a similar
background to you and save them some of
the steps in the journey. So we're gonna
talk about one of the security people,
we're gonna talk about guy named Justin.
So Justin, he prior to 2018, had work
experience that includes climbing
telephone poles, he was of doing wiring
of telephone cables, and he had submitted
over 152 job applications. In 2018 he
joined the Windows Defender ATP
hunting team as a vendor, he works for us
as a vendor on a contract.
He logs his investigations that he
does into the Intel system that my team
runs. One of the things he did was he
discovered a massive malware campaign using
an Oracle WebLogic 0day which was
followed by Eternal Blue to move
laterally throughout Networks.
Achievement unlocked, Senpai has noticed
you. [ Audience Laughter ] So I was like wow, okay, this is kind
of cool, you're actually doing really
cool work and you're really smart. What
can we do with this? It turns out what we
can do with this is give him absolutely
anything he will work on it and he will
learn it. So what he does now is he has
found a massive human operated
ransomware campaign, he discovered over
three apts on customer networks that
would have been undetected, he presented
at blue hat with me and he held a 30
minute conversation with a guy named
John Lambert. You may know him from
Twitter about hunting methodologies. John
Lambert's what's called a technical
fellow at Microsoft. I don't think Justin
understands that most people don't hold
30-minute conversations with John
Lambert in their first year as a
security person. So what makes this
different right this is a person who
applied to 152 jobs and didn't get them.
This is the person who is almost the
same age as me why did they not get a
security job until then? They are clearly
disturbingly threateningly brilliant
and motivated. Why? It's opportunity, right?
Opportunities are what allow people to
thrive. When you get a chance to do
something and you get a chance to have
somebody who's going to guide you along
the way. When we think about how we build
people up and how we give them things to
learn. Justin actually went to college
for network security he has a degree in
it, but it didn't work, right? It did not
get him the opportunities that he needed.
Opportunities come through different
places and we need to make them a lot
less random. Because when they're random
opportunities that's how you get career
paths that look like Devon's and mine.
What can we do to get those
opportunities to people and help
identify them faster? As a side note
yesterday I actually learned that it
wasn't me who inspired Justin to be a
security person at all, he actually went
to a Nine Inch Nails concert with Andy
Robbins who wrote bloodhound in 2014.
Okay. Andy showed him pen testing on his
laptop which apparently changed his life
and made him want to be a security
person from that five-minute interaction.
So this is yet another example of a
SpecterOps person being cooler than me.
[ Audience Laughter ]
Incidentally he discovered that because
one of the things that I teach the
people that I'm mentoring is that their
main responsibility is to give back in
whatever way they can
and Justin chose to do that by donating
to MDA which is the big cause that Andy
supports. So if you like bloodhound and
if you want to give back donate to MDA.
Also, I haven't actually seen Nine Inch
Nails in person and I love them,
so I'm jealous. But impact. Impact in
those 15 minutes that Andy didn't even
remember occurred he changed someone's
life. He showed them something that he
didn't know existed, right? Those 15
minutes of Andy firing up his laptop and
doing whatever he was doing in 2014
changed Justin's life. You can do that
too, right? This is an opportunity that's
being presented by exposing people to
things they've never seen before. Where I
come from, in the middle of nowhere
Pennsylvania, nobody knows it's actually
possible to work at Microsoft. It, like,
the career options or drive a truck or get pregnant.
[ Audience Laughter ]
I wish I was kidding, I'm sorry. But that is an opportunity
for impact and an opportunity to give
someone opportunity. Talk to people who
don't even know security people exist
and you can have the creation of an
opportunity for someone. But opportunity
alone doesn't actually give it. People
that really succeed they have success
helpers and they have things that are
maybe innate to them. They're people
that are called self-starters, in
Silicon Valley speak. They're people
who kind of like just go with the flow
and know what to do. That is in no way
shape or form something that's natural.
If you're a self-starter you probably
learned it through failing a lot as a
child. Maybe you played Mario and kept
falling off of things that's how you
become a self-starter. So what does a
success helper look like for a
self-starter person? How can you give
somebody who you've given an opportunity
to, the groundwork for how to move
forward? Well, with
Justin's case, he takes his notes and
then he shares his notes with others he
mentors other people to make them better
he actually reads and watches what I
suggest. Shocking. There's a lot of people
who will say, you know, "teach me your
magical stuff" and then I hand them a 30
page document and a bunch of videos
and then I asked them what they thought
of them and they're like,  "Oh I didn't watch
them", I'm like, "Oh... okay." He has questions. It is
okay to ask questions, like, I'm sure it
probably was pretty freaking
intimidating the first moment when I
looked at him and said, "that's not how
DNS works.", [ Audience Laughter ]
but then he said, "please tell
me how DNS works". So if you're
working with someone, questions. The
biggest thing though is he built on his
knowledge and tries new things as he's
learned new stuff he's developed new
ways to hunt inside of Windows Defender
ATP telemetry. He's built on what he
knows to increase his capabilities. We
don't just stop at what we know. I did
not just stop at Windows event logs, in
spite of what my blog might say. You
learn more and you go beyond that, right?
And you bring their own perspective and
uncover new things this is important. New
people see things differently than you
do. They see things in a different light
based on their life and their cultural
experiences. Someone who has come from a
different background than you is going
to see things differently than you and
that's gonna give you new perspective. So
when you give someone an opportunity you
can also give them a framework for
success by teaching them how to do these
things. So we can scale success. We can
actually make this carry on because this
is Michael. also known as PB. PB is who
Justin is mentoring, so we can scale this,
because you'll notice that what makes PB successful is he takes notes, he reads
them, he shares them with others, he
watches the stuff he suggested to,
he asks questions, he builds knowledge
and he brought a completely new
perspective to things because he comes from
a different technological background. But
what came out of both of these people
when I was working with them? They went
to school together.
They went to school, they did the same
program. And what they told me out of
everything I taught them, by yelling at
them, was. "we didn't learn any of this in
school".
So these are people that literally
followed what should have been the
roadmap to being a security person. And
I'm not throwing their school under the
bus. They learned really really good
things there. They learned a lot of very
practical knowledge, but actually, Will
Harmj0y, a person who I troll in every
talk, told me the other day that he had a
dev background. He knew how to code but
he didn't know how to apply it until he
met the guy who runs SpecterOps. He's
the one who taught him how to actually
apply the knowledge he had. So what
didn't they learn in school? They didn't
learn how to apply what they know or how
to think. This is the real-world
experience that all of us grizzled
veterans who have tried to fix something
on a Saturday morning know. So how can we
kind of get that moving and what can we
do to make that better? Because the
important part about security is it
involves humans. So humans are a
fundamental flaw or gift to security right
so we get a lot of flack on humans in
security because they do things like
enable macros, [ Audience Laughter ] but humans are also,
thank you, thank you, but humans are also what
allow us to scale and change and build
how we think, right? So when we think
about what we didn't learn in school we
didn't learn what you have learned from
your human experiences. And when we think
about humans let's think about teams of
humans. So, I am not a manager nor do I
play one on TV, so we're gonna talk about
my boss. My boss who is known as Ryan "it
may not be a security boundary but that
doesn't mean it has to suck" Kivett. So
Ryan's background is Windows internals
and security in the operating system.
He's a hardcore debugger. He's a hardcore
dev, who majored in business in college.
So another person with an interesting
path. And his prior experience at
Microsoft was literally, he decided he
wanted to own UAC for a while, User
Account Control that thing with all the
bypasses? Ryan's work caused it to be an
RS5 all of those bypasses went away.
Shh. So most of the user-mode comm stuff
he took away, right? So this is his
background. His background when he has
made it to be a principal level manager
at Microsoft is in deep kernel nerd
stuff. But then, we needed to form a team.
And we needed to form a team called
Windows Defender Threat Intelligence.
There are multiple threat intelligence
teams at Microsoft. There are multiple
red teams. There are multiple blue teams.
We all have our own role. With Windows Defender Threat Intelligence we had to
fit into a niche that was different and
we had to think differently than other
people because we track both commodity
and targeted threats and we do it
through behaviors versus through other
ways that other people track them. We
track what is bad happening and then we
worry about who was doing it, right? So we
had to think differently. So Ryan's a
very smart person when it comes to
building teams of humans because what he
did is he got somebody with a
traditional military sig intelligence
background, he got somebody from a
traditional AV background, he got
somebody who does a lot of dark web
research and he got me. So in building
this team, with the IR professional
vampire on the end, we could have had a
lot of risks there because a lot of
times when you bring people from
different backgrounds with different
ideas you can build silos. Because you
may dig your heels into the ground and
you may think this is the right way to
do it. I have been doing this for two
decades. This is the right way to do it.
But that doesn't have to be that way,
because you can be a good teammate not
by protecting your contributions but by
scaling your contributions you can make
other people know what you know and you
can make them work together. So in the
case of our team we have all of these
people from diverse backgrounds and I
mean diverse backgrounds in several
different ways there and what we did is
we sort of all merged and we formed a
hive mind. Because if you want to level
up and you want to move behind a
quarter-circle punch, that's a street
fighter joke, you have to learn new
skills and you learn new skills from new
people and new experiences. And that
brings us to change, because change is
really really scary for a lot of people.
And when you build new security people
they may be experiencing change. You may
be taking them out of an economic
situation that there
comfortable with. Their life may have
been bad and you're giving them new
things. They may suffer from what is
known in the security industry as
impostor syndrome and that may actually
affect their ability to do things, but
change is big for all of us as an
industry too, because when we talk about
things like scaling and building
diversity and things like that change
means putting our money where our mouth
is and actually going out and finding
new people. Because new people with those
new ideas, they typically may not be
coming from your top shelf universities.
They may not be coming from computer
science backgrounds and they may not be
coming from the normal places that you
recruited everyone else on your team.
Change is scary. If we want to have new
ideas though, we have to go find new
people. Did you know that OCX files are
PE files too? [ Audience Laughter ]
OCX files are like ActiveX
controls and you can use them to execute
code. And the interesting thing about an
OCX file is you can load it in Microsoft
Office as well as browsers. OK, so what do
we do? [ Audience Laughter ]
Jessica, you've given me like your
life story and someone else's life story
and you've kind of made me depressed and
whatever. So how do we build security
people? How do we do something besides
just handing them a collection of tools
and leading them to confusion? Because on
the internet right now you can literally
learn almost everything you would need
to be a great security person. Which
things do you start with? What do you
learn? How do you know what type of
security person you want to be? Did you
know that lawyers are security people? At
Microsoft we have an entire division of
like 500 lawyers that are also like
software engineers and help us do botnet
takedowns and everything else like that.
Politicians can be security people, right?
Human resource managers can be security
people like there's a lot of different
ways to be a security person besides
being a reverse engineer or a malware
analyst. You don't have to be a red
teamer. You don't have to do anything
like that, there's a lot of different
ways to success. We have all the tools
available to us for free so people can
come from less enabled backgrounds and
they can learn this stuff, but literally
how do you make sense of it it's like
IKEA.
It's like putting together flat pack
furniture. It's really confusing so how
do we make success a repeatable path? How
do we make it something where somebody
doesn't have to spend 20 years of their
life wondering if they're going to
become a dancer or a
forensic pathologists or doing masonry
repair. You can help, because you can do
influence without power. you do not have
to be a manager a director a CIO or
whatever at your organization to help
start the change. You have the power,
because what you can do is you can
impact people and you can help to change
stuff just by yourself. Little actions
that you take can enable other people to
become security people and you can help
to build these sort of road maps to our
"choose-your-own-adventure security way".
So if we're gonna continue to use video
game metaphors let's talk about
single-player. So, what can you do just by
yourself to help build security people?
Well the first thing that you can do is
you can document what you know, right?
Amanda, malwareunicorn,
is amazing at this. She's
documented reverse engineering 101 and
I've used it to train a lot of different
people. This is cool, right? It may not
seem like rocket surgery reverse
engineering,
even though Amanda's 100% capable of
that. It may have seemed obvious to
people who are reverse engineers, like
why are we documenting this? It has, in
fact, changed multiple people's lives.
I've heard of people getting jobs
because they started with Amanda's
training. So what do you know? What do you
know? It doesn't matter if it's
duplicated already on the internet. Your
style of presenting it and your personal
experiences in talking about it may be
what makes the difference to someone. I
know a lot about Kerberos as it relates
to making Macs and Red Hat Linux work in
an Active Directory realms. Someone finds
that useful. Another person might find
Kerberos useful purely from an Active
Directory perspective, right? We tell it
from your story. Tell what you know from
your story. Document it so that other
peoples know it. Even if you're new at it.
So this is actually Michael and Justin's
blog, where they are actually documenting
their processes of building an attack
framework so that they can actually see
what the defense would look like. Because
their current job allows them to see,
well what went wrong. You know we get a
lot of Defender telemetry of what went
wrong and they're very good at picking
through it, but they don't actually get
to see the attack side. So they said, "what
what about, in our spare time, if we built
an attack framework so we could kind of
replicate it and see what signals we
might be missing?" and I was like what's
spare time? [ Audience Laughter ]
But this is what they're doing they are
literally like, they were working until
midnight last night working on making
this so that they could actually
replicate what was going on.
You have impact and you have the
capability to document something. This is
not world-changing knowledge. They do
talk about things that I've already
blogged about, that other people have
already blogged about, but it's a
different perspective because it's the
perspective of somebody who's looking at
it from fresh eyes. So in single-player
mode you can document things. You can
make things better and you can find gaps
an existing documentation. Who's heard of
logon type 9? Logon type 9 in windows
means that you're invisible that's my
present to you. My finding of a gap in
documentation is because there's nothing
like being up at 3:00 a.m. at an
incident response and googling for
something and having your own name come
up. And you're like, "No, she doesn't know."
[ Audience Laughter ]
You can also cause trouble.
So in single-player mode you can break
stuff before the bad people do. So Will built Empire, Jared Haight built PSAttack,
BloodHound built by Andy and Rohan.
This is stuff where I actually defend
things and build antivirus signatures.
And I love every one of those people.
Because this type of work that you do as
you cause trouble and break things
before other people do, usually when we
go back and look someone has already
been doing it, right? So if you want to
break things you can still help fix
things and you can find niches and gaps
that didn't exist because bloodhound
didn't really exist before they made
that tool. There were capabilities and
there were enterprise grade software, but
the typical normal person, like those
people that sit in the audience of
security conferences,
did not know that you could query the
membership with a local administrators
group on any Windows computer as a non-admin user. By the way, if you enable the
Windows Firewall, that doesn't work
anymore.
So, you can do things from that
perspective too. Bring what you have an
experience of looking at broken things
or your ideas about how you might break
it. When we think about like IT
professionals, IT professionals do not
get enough credit. People talk about like
let's get new people into code. Let's
have coding boot camps. Yes, woo,
coding. Coding is cool. I learned coding I
did do computer science in school, but
you know who's really valuable too? The
person who manages Group Policy, and
System Center, and Ansible. Because you
know what a really great way is to attack a network
and have nobody detect you? Embed
yourself in the Ansible system, right? So
like you can bring a perspective, even if
you want to cause trouble and break
things, from an IT perspective of how you
would remain undetected on a network. So
you can come from that perspective.
Single-player mode again. Embrace
curiosity. Just mess around with stuff.
Opening up ProcMon and watching what
queries a system, you will sometimes find
these things called elevation of
privilege. You will find literal 0day in
Windows if you know what you're doing,
right? Be curious. Learn how stuff is
supposed to work. You can do TCP dumps.
You can, you don't even need to worry
about having Wireshark, like fire up ye
olde Linux server and, you know, look what
normal traffic looks like, right? Because
MYSQL should not be doing some of
the stuff that you see it doing on the
network. And understand the fundamentals,
right? so this type of thing where people
now have all these tools to enable them
going forward, I kind of worry about
BloodHound in some ways, because
BloodHound is so awesome and it is so
cool I'm afraid people are gonna forget
exactly why it works. And they're
therefore going to not understand how to
break it, right? So understand the
fundamentals, and then share the
fundamentals because as we have these
new security people coming on and
they're taking pen test courses and
they're taking college courses and
they're exposed to wonderful things like
Metasploit and PowerShell Empire, I
actually interviewed someone the other
day who is a fantastic hacker and has
won multiple CTFs. They're very young so
they were very surprised when I told
them they didn't actually need
PowerShell Empire to create a reverse
shell and you can do it natively with a
batch file. And they said what's a batch
file, so
[ Audience Laughter ]
and I said something that won't get
detected by AV, and they loved me again
so it was okay. So understand your
fundamentals and share those with people.
Because the fundamentals that you
learned may still be around, but people
may have forgotten about them, right? This
is why IQY files which is like this
weird legacy thing inside of Excel
really, really did wonders for the
Necur's Botnet a couple of weeks ago,
because everyone forgot they existed.
You can speak of things speaking of
things it's cool, because as you speak at
things, be brave your voice matters. A lot of
times new people think, "I don't have
anything to say there". You know what I
love? A talk by a new person about all of
the things they screwed up as a new
person on their way to becoming a good
person, right? I have just revealed a lot
of things I failed at. I try to be
transparent as I like do labs and I do
like documentation of, this is hard, I
screwed this up. I don't know why this
works. If you want to give a talk at any
conference that I'm on the panel of or
the content advisory board on your new
perspective? Kwas, a red teamer, who gave
her talk at blue hat that I recruited
her to do because it was baby's first
keylogger, It was literally the first
keylogger she wrote. And other people
were like who cares and I'm like because
it's about her journey. Oh, and by the way,
her keylogger bypasses all the AVs on
virustotal. So, you, you can bring a new
perspective and it's actually
interesting. So think that your voice
matters and this can be your
single-player mode of therein. But you also,
don't completely go solo, do a kind of a
team match. Because if you work with
others on your talk, whether new or old,
this is where you get new perspectives.
Some of the best talks that I've given
have been where I said to somebody and
said "hey you want to give a talk with me?"
And Gerald Steere and I did
BSides Seattle last year, just simply
because we wanted to. Thanks BSides Seattle.
And we just said like well okay we want
to do a talk on red teaming you wish you
were doing. And that was a really, really
fun talk that totally wasn't recorded so
you're never gonna see it. But we, we
dropped though 0day, one or two. Um, but as you
work with people you're gonna make your
talk better and you're going to network
with other people. And you're going to
show
something really, really important as
we're trying to build security people.
You're going to show that we are not
single pillars of truth we are a
collaborative organization. Security
people don't really have a reputation
for being team players. We have a
reputation for dropping zero days on
Twitter, and doing bad things, and all
stuff like that. We do not have a
reputation for being a kumbaya come
together, work together team. If you stand
on stage with another person, especially
if that person is a red teamer and
you're a blue teamer, or if that person
works at another company than you, I've
presented with our competitors before
that's fun. You can show that what really
matters is protecting people. That's what
security people are here to do we're
here to protect people, right? So don't
worry about egos, check them at the door.
Stand on stage with somebody who's
different than you, or don't speak at
things. This is not a requirement. This is
not a requirement. Like I am super
thrilled that I actually got coerced
into having speaking on my resume. I
never ever ever ever wanted to do it. I
did a presentation for Microsoft because
the other guy was sick that presentation
got a hundred and seventy-five thousand
page views in 24 hours so there was no
turning back. You don't have to do this.
You can be impactful in the community in
ways that allow you to be shy and scared
of people, right? You don't have to do
this, but you can still work with people
on one-to-one smaller scale type of
things there's ways to be connected. So
let's talk about team play, right?
Because connecting is a big part of why
I'm standing here trying to make eye
contact with as many of you as possible.
So what can you do if you're trying to
be a team player? If you're trying to
actually work with others to build
security peoples? Well what you can do is
you can give someone a chance, right? We
sometimes have the capability to sponsor
other people to do cool things. I
sponsored somebody to go to DerbyCon
training. It was something that I was
able to do, so I did it, right? So this
person is actually a very good reverse
engineer who is having a hard time
getting people to give her an
opportunity because she's so junior. She
goes to job interviews. She's learning
she's new she's very young and people
say "well you're just too junior for this
role". So this is the problem of someone
who is super smart and really studies
because I sent her to a training and I
made
do homework to prove that she'd been
there. I'm a cruel mistress, sorry.
They're not giving her opportunities,
right? So this is where we have another
case of a person who is smart he's not
getting opportunity. So give somebody a
chance give them something they can put
on their resume. It doesn't have to be
DerbyCon training. It doesn't
have to be super expensive, right? But you
can work with somebody to like, let's say
publish an app, right? You could do an
Android app, you could do, you know help
them get a web page a blog type of thing
out there. Something on github. If you
give someone a chance, then they have
something that they can reference that
says, "I'm not a new person, this is what
I've done". So you can help. You can also
be available. So all you have to do
sometimes is just be there for people. So
the BloodHound gang people are really
really cool because what they do is they
actually are just available for anybody
to come in and talk to them. So find a
group like this. Be available. Make road maps. You can actually make your own road
map for somebody. Who knows how to become
a Windows forensics person. I do and I
actually shared that road map on my
blog somewhere. But you can think about
like well I am a reverse engineer. I am a
Linux admin how did I get here? Come up
with your training plan. Like start with
this book, then you're skilled enough to
go to this book, this one, this one, this
one. And then publish it. Publish it
somewhere where somebody can see.
Mind-meld. Go out of your way to partner
with people who think differently than
you. Go out of your way to sit in the
room with an iOS jailbreaker if you're a
Windows person. I have learned so much. Go
out of your way to find the people who
are different and maybe even against you.
Some of my favorite people that I've
learned from are the people who are
actually part of the Xbox Underground.
The group that was actually hacking
Microsoft, that's cool.
You can teach. So you can actually teach
things so when Jared and Sean gave this
course on modern windows attack and
defense, I thought this was so cool this
was so fresh this was so innovative,
because they weren't just teaching a
defense course. They were showing you
practically how these things apply. So if
you want to build a security people you
can show them how this stuff applies in
the real world. Because it can get really,
really, like I'm losing hope and I'm gonna
go do something else if you don't
understand that you're actually gonna
have impact. And when you do teach, go
teach in unexpected places.
Community colleges, high schools, homeless
shelters. Did you know that a lot of the
homeless people on the west coast
like we're accepted to Stanford before
their parents kicked him out for one
reason or another
I learned that when I moved to Seattle.
like a lot of the people that are in the
youth shelters in Seattle have really
good educational backgrounds.
They're just lacking opportunities. So
there's a lot of places that you could
go teach where you could do a lot of
unexpected impact to somebody's life. Now there's sponsorship and there's mentorship,
and these are actually two different
things and a guy named John Rodriguez
taught me that in my first year at
Microsoft. A lot of people ask for
mentorship. Mentorship is like where
you're actually teaching them how to do
something, but there's also just
sponsorship. Everyone that I showed you
in this deck today just got sponsorship
from me, because what I did is I gave
them opportunities I gave them
visibilities. What you can do is you can
quite simply just take someone you know
is smart and put them in the room with
another smart person. Like, oh you're
building a security app, but you're not
really good at c-sharp? I know someone
who is. That's sponsorship. Okay, so what if
you want to do massively multiplayer
mode building of security people? Well
security is not a global constant.
Did you know that like what you might
consider to be a security thing here,
like, whether that be living to the
letter of the law or a security setting
might not actually work on another
country? There are certain group policy
settings and windows that you can set
that will actually violate the laws of
other countries. Because they're not
allowed to have like an enforced
language so if you set the home page to
Google in English you've actually broken
the law. Cool.
I learned that. But you need to learn
this by like understanding also your
adversaries, because a lot of times in
our news coverage nowadays it's like,
they're bad, they're bad, they're bad. Yeah,
and they think we're bad, so you know
security is not a global constant. Think
about it from like learning the
perspectives of other cultures. There's
even things like, as you learned that
security is not a global constant, like
when you look at an event log the colors
red don't necessarily mean the same
thing in every culture like in a Western
mindset that means error. In other
countries it means, I won!
[Audience Laughter ] You can start a
movement, right? So join organizations.
Whether that be you know an established
organization that's actually mentoring.
There's the rural tech fund. The rural
tech fund actually does a lot of work
for donating to small schools and gets
some tech things. You can change
companies from the inside. You can help
to actually change how a company is
built and how it is by recruiting,
recruiting, recruiting, right? And then you
need to push back and actually fight for
your recruits.
Because if you hear something like this
person is too junior or this person
isn't good enough, well then you make it
so they aren't. And then you get them
back in, right? You have to actually be
able to do this type of stuff to get the
global change. Or you can start something.
There are opportunities to create small
scale organizations that will be able to
change people's lives. If you want to
create your own using LattePanda small
computer devices to go teach people how
to code and do packet captures, that
would be a relatively small investment
you would be able to help 20 or 30
people and they would now know a whole
different set of skills that they didn't
know. So, if there isn't an organization
that you like, it's really easy to start
one. You don't even have to bother with
the whole nonprofit thing. But perhaps
most importantly, escape the echo chamber.
If you look at security Twitter it's a
whole lot of people talking to each
other about things they already know.
Okay, but what you want to do is you want
to talk to people who don't know it and
you want to talk to people to get those
different perspectives. If you talk to
someone who actually uses software they
will explain to you exactly why all
those vulnerabilities are there.
90% of what I know about comm hijacking
comes because I worked at a law firm
where all of the Outlook plugins
required comm hijacking stuff. So you
will actually learn why bad stuff exists
and why it's hard to fix. You will also
be able to connect with people who can
help you fix it. Because if you escape
the echo chamber and you actually talk
to lawyers and politicians and
C levels, who aren't technical
C levels, they will be able to help you
enable and enact your change. If you want
to enable and enact change by changing
the face of the youth and what they
learn? If you connect with a non tech
savvy teacher at an elementary school,
you have now escaped the echo chamber
and you understand why it's difficult.
Talk to people who don't find what you
do easy for a lot of us this probably
came very easy to us we were probably
teenagers we sat down in front of a
computer and said
I got this. For some people it doesn't
work like that. Go find people who it
doesn't come easy to. And what you'll
find is you're capable of thinking
outside of the box then. This is cute, huh?
I'm just checking to see if you're paying
attention. So if you can think outside of
the box that will allow you to innovate
and change and also help to support
those people, but the most important
thing you have to remember is you have
to remember empathy, right?
This is empathy as we're designing
security systems and as we're building
the security people that we're working
with. A lot of us made it to the way that
we made it through those paths where we
might have struggled and we might have
forgotten what it's like. We might have
forgotten what it's like to not know
what eventid 1102 is, or that rdpclip.exe
starts when somebody logs in
even if you don't have it a login type
10. You need to be able to understand the
people you're working with and you need
to be able to understand their
motivations for why they're doing it. And
that's gonna help you actually build
these networks and be able to enforce
those people. And you have to also
remember that failure is always an
option and failure isn't a bad thing.
Because if you try really hard at
something, you learned something. If you
fail at something, you absolutely took
away everything that you learned at it.
"Chase dragons" in the words of Devon Kerr.
Because as you chase that dragon you're
going to either get a stronger sword arm
or whatever the metaphorical thing would
be. I do a lot of stuff that you never
see and I suck at it.
And that's ok, because I keep trying at
it and I learn from it. Whether that be
stupid things like today, where I came
out and gave a 100% non-technical talk
and really didn't feel comfortable doing
it. If I failed it doesn't matter because
I learned something and that's what we
need to remember as we're teaching
people and as we're building our new
security people. To teach them that it's
ok to fail and that they didn't actually
ruin their lives and they can continue.
Did you know that dot MUI files are PE
files too? [ Audience Laughter ]
So these are localization
files and you can actually side load
with these too. It's really, really cool.
Thank you for coming.
[ Audience Applause ]