hello I'm Paul
I can barely see your laptop your
privacy privacy screen works too well
Matt I'm sorry
so the typical disclaimer I'm not
speaking on behalf of my current
employer Matt isn't either
and we're definitely not making any
announcements or talking about specific
product features or vulnerabilities so
let's start by talking about what we're
not talking about we are not gonna be
addressing virtual machine' security
here we're not gonna be talking about
runtime security here we're not talking
about securing laptops and desktops
those are out of scope and honestly very
very hard relative to even the problem
we're trying to solve here which assumes
there are guards at the door to the data
center we're also not talking about the
TC G and T PM's and so on and I know you
are all here because the super micro
thing but we're not talking about
defending against Hardware implants or
vendors who are doing bad things so this
we are talking about allowing customers
to run on the bare metal that as you
will see is a metal bear on a cloud so
the particular thing that we're
concerned about in this context is the
firmware on the devices the customer can
actually access in a VM context
everything is abstracted away they don't
have can't get to the low level but we
want to secure things and give people
directly direct access access to the
hardware so again the firmware we're
concerned about if you look at a modern
modern server in the cloud today it will
have between 50 and a hundred different
places that have mutable firmware or
writable data that might be accessible
to an attacker individual chips
scattered throughout the throughout the
platform we know that customers can run
the firmware update utilities the
manufacturers give them to them and we
can't it's hard to just turn that
capability off when you don't need it
and turn it back on because it's all
wired directly into the hardware if
customers do that and very often fleet
management utilities you know the
automated tooling that they run in their
data center will change to a version of
a firmware on Hardware that they trust
they say oh you know we only qualified
this old version we know our workload
works as that so let's just put it back
to that while we're using this hardware
this is a great flexibil very good for
being flexible for the customer and
that's them do what they want with
hardware but then when we get it back we
need to make sure that it is not
malicious we need to make sure that they
haven't stuck an old buggy version of
the firmware in the hardware and we need
to do this consistently and reliably we
want it when you ran to the system we've
got you have do what you want but when
we get it back we need to be able to
restore it to pristine state and it has
to be automatable this has to be to be
able you have to be able to do this at
scale and it has to work every time
update routines that defend depending on
the firmware itself doing a good job of
updating it fail more often than you
think they would unfortunately so and
the the other thing that we need is we
need to be able to say even if this
device had a bug in it and maybe we've
discovered and fixed it we still need to
be able to assert that the version we're
giving to the next customer not only
doesn't have that bug but that bug
hasn't been exploited to backdoor the
next the next customer
all right so as Paul was mentioning
there's a lot of things if you look at a
modern server platform even a laptop but
servers are just more of the same so
there's a lot of things in there you
know how does it get built how does it
end up it obviously doesn't appear fully
formed in a data center ready for us to
use and rent to customers right the
manufacturing line the process that gets
it there is actually pretty long and
complicated and intricate and I don't
know if anybody's ever had to actually
try and build a real physical server
it's a lot more painful than you could
imagine if you're used to dealing with
software so not a whole lot if you if
you're familiar with the old PCI
architecture diagrams of like what does
this computer look like right things
haven't actually changed that much over
the last 20 years the i/o buses have
gotten faster we've taken some things
that used to be discrete parts and put
them onto the same package but we've
still got you know memory controllers
application processors IO devices some
management stuff storage the the general
layout the general architecture the way
these components interact hasn't
actually changed a lot even though the
protocols may be a little different now
one of the things that has changed
though is that literally everything has
a microcontroller in it right it used to
be all Hardware pre-programmed
functionality State Hardware state
machines that's kind of gone by the
wayside everything uses microcontrollers
and they all have firmware of some kind
so like up on this picture I think the
blue ones are the microcontrollers and
the orange ones are firmware so you've
got you know even for the DRAM you've
got some bit of data there that tells
you how big this dim is and what the
timings for it are right because if you
want the system to support a hundred
different dims from different
manufacturers with different settings
and sizes you need something to tell the
system what those are so it knows how to
set up memory
this gives the system a lot of
flexibility it allows you to build
things it allows you to fix things after
you've built them it allows you to plug
different things together and hopefully
they all work because they can sort of
tell each other what they are and sync
appropriately but it now also means we
have a bunch of things to deal with
right
there's a whole lot more places things
can go wrong and we've now got a lot of
people who are not software developers
writing software to run in places that
are not like easily visible or
accessible or verifiable and it's really
like this is this is still the
simplified picture it's worse there's
more stuff in there right
most modern high-performance devices are
no longer single core they have multiple
cores they might have multiple different
firmware images running on them
your emmc storage for your embedded
controller probably has its own firmware
in it you've got other things on the
board that may not be documented that
you know clearly have some kind of
non-volatile storage on them sometimes
it's as simple as some Part D
identifiers so that when you need to
return something to the manufacturer
they can identify which part this was
and send you an appropriate replacement
sometimes there's actual like
microcontrollers in your battery keeping
it from exploding so there's a there's a
lot of things right your your hard
drives all have them your USB Wi-Fi
device probably has separate
microcontrollers on both the usb side
and the Wi-Fi side there's a lot of
things in there there's a lot of places
if you want to persistently store
malware there's a whole bunch of places
you can stick it right and the ability
of the system to go investigate what's
in the hard drive firmware is generally
pretty limited because if you look at
the protocol specifications for like I
say the hard drive it doesn't have a
command in there that says hey tell me
exactly what your firmware is it's got
like an update routine that if you go
look at the Linux utility says very
clearly don't do this you'll break your
hard drive so not only can people not
inspected but they've been told
explicitly not to even try updating the
firmware on a bunch of these devices
because it's dangerous and it can be if
the manufacturers done a bad job
building the device but that also means
you're not getting security updates when
there's problems with it
so that's what's in a server how does it
come to be a server like there's tens of
thousands of different components in a
server right individual components from
passives to small ActiveX components
like muxes and other things to you know
the big CPUs that we think of as being
the actual part of the server that we're
interested in and they're like they're
built all around the world you know
South Korea and Taiwan and Israel build
a lot of individual components right and
these sort of get farmed out these are
in most cases commodity things so when
you say I want to go build a server I
need ten thousand of this resistor to
put on the motherboard you know somebody
in your supply chain organization goes
out and orders 10,000 of those from
wherever they can find them either
available or cheapest and then they show
up at the contract manufacturer in the
contract manufacturer uses them and
there may or may not be good tracking of
those all along the way from the place
that built them to the place that
packaged them to your contract
manufacturer but even assuming you you
have that right we've we've got
components coming from one set of
manufacturers we've got PCBs being built
in entirely different places there's
plenty of places that have a lot of PCB
manufacturing but the components and the
PCBs are not generally manufactured
together right the components come from
one vendor the PCBs come from another
vendor and then they all go to a third
place where they get assemble right and
this is the the assembly is usually
where we talk about contract
manufacturers where we get all the
pieces in the same place and somebody
saw there's them all together and that's
great but if you don't have tracking on
what comes into the contract
manufacturer you're not really going to
have a good idea of what you're actually
getting is that the thing you wanted I
know there was talk this morning about
the this part of the supply chain aspect
where you've got a whole bunch of coming
things in I think it was Joe feds that
made the comment of just replace it real
right like at the contract manufacturer
they're just gonna have buckets full of
the specific components
instructions on where to solder them
down on the PCBs if you can inject new
things into the supply chain at that
point this is sort of where they was
talking about it happened somewhere in
the process of taking all the individual
parts putting it in the same place and
soldering them together that's a really
hard problem to solve tracking all that
we didn't really attempt to solve that
problem we were worried more about just
the firmware because all of these places
all of these components all of them that
are programmable at any point in this
process somebody could be putting hands
on it programming it testing it in fact
hopefully they are putting hands on it
and programming and testing it make sure
it works before they assemble everything
and send it to you and so there's gonna
be firmware on these devices right
everything that's programmable by the
time it leaves the contract manufacturer
is going to have some firmware on it
because hopefully if they have done some
level of testing and if they haven't
then you get really upset with them and
you go yell at them and make them do
that because you want them to send you
working devices and then once you have
them they get shipped all over the world
right so I know there's the the stories
about customs interdiction of devices
and reprogramming of them because they
have to cross three or four borders to
get from point A to point B because like
as you've seen from the slides you know
probably every part near servers been
around the world two or three times by
the point it lands in your data center
so they're been plenty of opportunities
for people to touch them test them
reprogram them and you know do something
that you might not actually have good
record-keeping of and probably not good
ways to verify before it gets to you and
you're ready to start using and running
that server with you know whatever is on
it so a big part of the problem we're
trying to solve here is once the system
arrives it's in my data center it's now
in a secured physical location how do we
know what's really in there right
there's been some testing
obviously that is verified that the
system functions or we would have
acted it and sent it back but in most
cases the firmware on there is not going
to be what we actually want the the
process of building this server has
taken on a good cycle three months
so whatever versions of firmware were
installed on this thing to test it as it
was getting built are almost certainly
out of date by the time we get it and we
want to run it some of them might still
be okay but the the odds are that
everything on theirs out of date
probably has known bugs that we want to
fix and get rid of under mediate and
test and verify that hey we've got this
thing in the data center how do we know
that before we hand it to the customer
we want to give everybody a pristine
system with a known set of firmware on
it how do we verify that on the system
when it's ready to deploy when it's
ready to use so before we go into the
new thing we're talking about what what
we did to solve this problem I'm going
to go through a few of the existing
solutions to this that are in the wild
today so the first place you want to
start is with signed firmware this means
that you have vendor signs the bits that
they put into the device and this should
prevent unintended code from running if
they have done everything perfectly and
have no bugs this most most devices are
moving to sign firmware the majority of
manufacturers care about this it keeps
customers from breaking their devices so
that's generally a good thing and this
really wants you to do that
this works best when one vendor controls
the system end to end the limitations
though you have you know it all the
signature is saying is these are the
bits that I intended to put in it
doesn't say that there are no bugs
it doesn't say there are no backdoors
and it doesn't even say that we aren't
that it can prevent unsigned
code for running it just says using the
normal process we try to try to run only
sign code the other problem we have is
that runtime firmware could prevent the
installation or the update of the new
firmware you want to put in this is a
fairly common feature of the BIOS
backdoors when people have been
developing those they want to prevent
you from taking their backdoor out and
so accepting accepting accepting an
update and saying great I've applied
that and then dropping it on the floor
is a pretty easy thing for for a runtime
firmware to do and it's very hard to
verify that that sort of thing hasn't
happened the next technique that people
are using is what's called secure boot
this is definitely better it generally
consists of a ROM a very small ROM this
mask um to the device which takes a
checksum of the firmware that it's about
to load and make sure that it's signed
by the vendor before it actually runs
the firmware this is great because it
means that you your code is checked at
every every boot the downside is it
doesn't give you any runtime protection
and it also still has the issue
associated with associated with
configuration which is expected to be
changed at runtime by the customer the
vendor can't sign that because it
doesn't know what the right answers are
there and oftentimes we'll see exploits
that are actually the exploit is written
into the configuration area and that
exploits a parser that allows you to
leverage code execution even though the
device is running signed code from the
vendor the other difficulty with this is
it's very hard to end up with a
functional room revocation mechanism
where if you have a downgrade
vulnerability or the you know vendor has
lost their keys updating often requires
actually just replacing the hardware
that's hard to do at scale and it's very
expensive the by the way the
configuration
vulnerability that I discussed is how we
got into the Intel I me blast what was
that the most recent one so the other
thing that we have in devices is or that
we would like to have in devices as a
way to measure what firmware is running
this is rarer we're working on making it
more common but usually this this is a
process where the device signs sign
something using a private key stored in
the device gives you back that value and
when this is implemented correctly it
gives you assurance that the code that
is running is the code that you intended
to load so TPMS are supposed to work
this way Google site and chip works this
way the limit this is also limited
though the biggest one is very few
devices support it and the measurements
are often unstable as firmware changes
as pieces of configuration change you
you can't pass over the configuration
for the same reason you can't sign it
and unless you're in an a very very
carefully controlled environment and
even then serial numbers and MAC
addresses and so on mean that you don't
have don't necessarily have matching
hashes so this is this is hard to do at
scale it's easier if you have very very
similar hardware but it's it's difficult
to do effectively so our challenge
signing is insufficient as currently
implemented most devices don't give us
measurement and we need assurance about
the running firmware we need to know
what is inside our device so
so as someone noticed from my water
bottle here I've not always done
security before I did security I did
hardware engineering and validation and
you know one of the things about
pre-production Hardware just like you
know your first attempt to compile
software it doesn't ever actually work
the first version of something new is
going to have a lot of bugs things that
you expect it to work right even very
simple things very critical things are
not going to work right and you're gonna
end up with either a very expensive
doorstop that you thought was going to
be a prototype you could use for
development or you're going to waste a
lot of money building more prototypes as
you fix every little bug that gets cost
and time prohibitive real quickly if you
have to do new production cycles every
time you need a bug fix as you're going
through trying to bring up a new piece
of hardware as I mentioned earlier
manufacturing is hard and takes a long
time so hardware manufacturers do have
capabilities to take something that is
not working right that doesn't have good
firmware on it that has bugs in it and
still do something with it right in the
process of taking sand and turning it
into a computer involves a lot of work
and a lot of debug and a lot of
validation and the hardware engineering
community's put a lot of effort into
figuring out how to do that how to
determine hey does this transistor work
hey does this CPU work hey does this
laptop work without throwing it out and
building a whole new thing so you know
what what happens is when you're doing
firmware development right you've got a
platform you know hot off the presses
you've got this brand new thing in front
of you you're really excited you want to
boot it up right you just want to like
get BIOS to run through so you can get
to an EFI prompt then test some things
the you first get that there's no
firmware right you've maybe done
something in an emulator that you have
to put on here like the very first time
there's nothing on the system to even
accept the firmware update right you
can't run a capsule update
before you've got the very first bios
installed the update routines are often
not the first thing you develop right
you're not worried about updating
something if you can't even get it to
power on and like accept commands very
often when you're doing firmware
development you will make a mistake and
the system will hang and it's real hard
if it hangs before you can get back in
to update it to get your new code in to
see if you're bug fix or bug fix works
another big problem even if you're doing
signed firmware if you have implemented
that incorrectly you now have a problem
because now you can't update because
your signature checking is is broken in
some way that prevents it from accepting
an update you know very often hardware
features don't work if you're
non-volatile storage controller has some
bugs you may not be able to do rights
like there there may be protocol issues
there may be other problems that just
prevent the system from working as
intended so if you're used to dealing
with production hardware that mostly
works you're like we'll just run the
update and that is just not something
that's possible in pre-production
hardware you can't rely on most of the
normal functionality that you would use
to do things because it it is either not
they're not implemented or just not
working properly
these have largely been solved right we
are able to ship new systems I think
most of the people in this room can go
out and buy like a new computer or you
know work on new systems this obviously
isn't blocking us from shipping things
this is not an unsolvable problem right
and what's happened is most Hardware
both components and higher-level
platforms that are you know components
put together have recovery mechanisms
that allow the developers to continue
running tests - you know load new
firmware into the device when it's not
working and these mechanisms don't
depend on certain levels of
functionality of the software right
they're explicitly designed to require
as little of the system to be in a
functional state as possible so things
like JTAG is really designed to work
with a very very small
number of transistors actually operating
normally and let you find the other ones
that aren't right so if there's if
there's problems with the system as long
as your JTAG controller is working you
should be able to get in there and go
start querying other parts go put
instructions in and make sure they're
executing properly and do things to the
system in a way that it doesn't really
matter what the state of the rest of the
system is right it's designed to work
regardless of what is currently
happening on the system or what has
happened in the past because it was
designed under the assumption that
probably everything is still broken
right and we need to go and be able to
diagnose and figure out what's going on
and then make it work again lots of
systems have recovery mechanisms built
into ROM right there's real a real
common implementation is you have a
jumper on the system and you put the you
know put a jumper on a header and now it
goes into some failsafe mode that allows
you to recover the system into a known
state lots of systems have like debug
serial ports that are active all the
time no matter what the actual firmware
is doing and there's like way too many
other proprietary mechanisms to attempt
to go into all of them but you know
everybody who's done this has had to
come up with something to allow them to
go back and recover the system when it's
not working because you know you can't
brick all your prototypes if you want to
ever ship product so we asked ourselves
like hey there are mechanisms in the
server we can use to force it into a
known state like our firmware developers
are using them during the course of
their day jobs can we leverage those for
security - I don't think anybody got the
joke this is the band yes
I somebody suggested we like play the
song there and I'm like I don't want to
rely on audio working so yeah the answer
is yes right we can use these recovery
mechanisms to get very high assurance of
the firmware on our platform right we
can go in up apply the updates to like
the runtime the mutable firmware without
relying on any code that's actually
running on the system right and this
this gives us assurance because the the
mechanism we're using doesn't depend on
the runtime code it doesn't depend on
what's currently on there that we don't
know right if if we assume that like
very malicious things are on the
platform or it's just been completely
erased and the thing is a brick and we
can't can't run the normal update
routines like this gives us a mechanism
to go in sort of regardless of where the
system is now hit it and bring it back
to where we want it to be and so this
gives us assurance because it doesn't
really matter where it is now we believe
the mechanism works regardless of what's
currently on there and when we're done
using this mechanism and pushing the
firmware we want into the system we have
very high confidence that you know when
we start executing that firmware that's
gonna be what's really running because
the mechanism we use to put it in you
know was kind of oblivious to whatever
else was going on at the time and so
there's there's lots of ways to do this
as I mentioned just a minute ago options
from you know booting the device into
you know a specific recovery mode
JTAG often allows you to load known code
onto a system and then start executing
it regardless of what's there most of
this ends up being somewhat specific to
the device the process is always a
little different but almost everything
we've looked at has some mechanism
to do this because that's the thing the
developers of the system have been using
to do this now I just covered most of
this so you know real common one is is
sort of the jumper thing and the device
will go into you know it's usually
called a recovery or an anti brick mode
and very often it'll just sit there and
wait for some custom undocumented vendor
utility to supply it a new firmware
image that it will then like write to
its storage and then when you reboot you
come back up into a known state and if
you can convince yourself that that
mechanism will actually you know write
the firmware you're giving it to the
storage regardless of what's on there
then when you can be confident when you
reboot that's what's actually there
[Music]
sometimes the it's a multi-stage process
right sometimes you update just the
bootloader and then you reboot into that
and go do a normal update from the
bootloader sometimes it's you know you
can use JTAG to force an own thing in
there or provide an image over a serial
debug port that the runtime firmware
doesn't actually have access to
interfere with the mechanisms vary a lot
like I say and it's quite device
specific so I thought this was in the
next section so how do we use this right
we've got tens of thousands of servers
in data centers you know putting jumpers
on things is great when they're sitting
on your desk that doesn't work when you
need to do it to ten thousand systems on
a you know daily basis potentially so in
order to operationalize this we built
custom hardware we kind of had to it
gives us connectivity to you know
whatever the interfaces on the specific
components we're trying to require are
it has things like you art in JTAG and
other interfaces that we can plug into
different components
we intentionally tried to make it
flexible enough to support lots of
different devices from lots of different
vendors and it's actually just sort of a
simple thing and it gives us a path to
go from our server management system to
actually go you know drive whatever
interface on the specific device we need
in order to put it into the recovery
state and because we're relying on this
right this is this is now becoming the
thing we trust in order to repave all
the firmware on the rest of our server
we very explicit made it not run time
updatable so if we need to reprogram it
we have to we do have to put hands on to
reprogram our recovery device and that
was a very intentional choice because
that means that there is no mechanism
from software running on the system to
modify our recovery device there's just
no wires there there's no connectivity
it can't be done because it's not
connected that way and that means that
when we do use this we've got very high
assurance that you know we programmed it
it is what we expected you know we've
got the firmware running on our recovery
device that we expect and because we
have physical possession of the systems
and control over who has access to do
that programming we have pretty high
assurance that it's actually working as
intended
okay
so as I was saying we did build custom
hardware it's actually not interesting
it's not much more than an Arduino on a
custom PCIe form factor card it turns
out if you want to stick something into
a server and you need connectivity to
something outside the server you don't
have a lot of options for what form
factor that's gonna be this is the there
are PCIe edge fingers on there
the only thing hooked up is power we
draw power from the server and that's it
turns out we don't need to recover
servers that don't have power doesn't
help much so it's like it the the form
factor is kind of irrelevant it's
basically an Arduino on a custom PCB and
like I was saying it's got connectivity
to a bunch of things so we can plug some
wires in make the operations people very
unhappy about the extra wires and use
those see nodding in the back very
unhappy and and use those to you know
instead of having to walk up and
physically place a jumper onto a header
we now have wires going to it that we
can flip through a GPIO on this thing
questions now is fine
it's not much oh the time wearing it in
I don't actually know that I remember it
like the cost per board was trivial like
it you did take a while to get the
people that is that is a feature not a
bug I don't know how many firmware
updates you get from your vendors
I get a lot some of them don't work sure
how many of your firmware internal
firmware updates have critical errors
so I mean we have we have in fact sorry
I should be close to the mic so we have
in fact where this has where I know this
has worked and where this has saved a
lot of time and money is we actually at
one point did get a firmware update from
a vendor to fix a bug that introduced a
new bug that basically bricked a bunch
of devices and we were able to use this
to roll back to the previous version on
a bunch of devices that were otherwise
inoperable and would not have been able
to be rolled back automatically so all
the pain it caused to try and install
and use this thing everybody was real
happy we had it when we started needing
it
and so let's talk a little bit about the
limitations including what you mentioned
we have we had to build this custom if
this is not something that we could you
know if we gave this gave you one of
ours it wouldn't be very useful to you
for your servers the other thing is you
really need to cooperate with the
manufacturers that you're doing this to
you need you need information from your
server vendor or you're gonna spend a
lot of time reverse engineering stuff
what you made anyway even if the vendors
are being cooperative
unfortunately they often don't know how
their device works either but it's it's
a bunch of work especially if you're
trying to do it without cooperation the
other issue is on many of these devices
they the flash chip is used for
debugging it's used for runtime metrics
logging and so when you have the data
center of reliability folks who come by
and say hey we need to figure out why
this thing failed can we look at the
last hundred hours of logs or whatever
if you say well it went to a new
customer and we blew that all the way
great the previous customer can't
backdoor the new customer with that data
not so great we don't have the data
anymore as you mentioned also the
cabling is really really annoying for
this because most devices are not
designed with the idea that their debug
ports are going to be wired up during
production in the data center as we move
forward with this and we work closely
with the vendors and we redesign our
boards the cabling gets better but it's
still not it's still not perfect you
know cables falling out headers that are
pins rather than latching retention all
things that Enterprise Server people
care very deeply about for reliability
reasons I already mentioned reverse
engineering the other thing about this
is that it very often requires you to
cycle power to the device to take up the
new firmware you've installed if you're
in a shared environment you have
multi-tenant something like that that
may not be tenable for you
depending on exactly which hardware
you're taking this approach to if you
are choosing say a network card vendor
you've got to look and see who has this
capability and how they've implemented
it again you need to sit down with the
sit down with the vendor and have some
have some conversations that they don't
usually answer correctly the first time
around because it's hard to understand
the question you're asking the and so
you know if your chosen vendor can't do
this then you may have a problem you may
have to switch vendors or ask them to
build the feature for you the other
thing is for some devices the flash chip
is inexpensive and you only have 10,000
rights if you do this all day every day
eventually going to wear those out and
then then your device stops working so
make sure that that is something you've
taken into account before you do it the
other thing is part part of the reason
that we ended up doing this was because
we knew that it was possible for someone
else to do it if we have this low level
known to blow it all the way at the
hardware level functionality we don't
need anti roll back protections like you
were mentioning because we know that
when we put it into the state that's the
state it's in and it's not you know it
can't be backdoor then not in terms of
the firmware it's not a the bugs that
were in the previous firmware can't keep
it bricked it will only have the vendor
supplied back doors at that point yeah
I'm giving everyone the same back so did
you have a question before
a great many of them yeah it was so the
the PCIe card it was wired to all the
other hardware yeah there's there's
custom designed more than just the PCIe
card this is what he was saying that
like we could give you one of these and
it would be useless if we don't give you
the server to put it in also so talking
about things going forward here one of
the things that we're working towards is
figuring out how to do this in band on
the device for some kinds of devices
this is already possible but you know so
going in over the PCI Express bus rather
than having to squish firmware down over
serial cables dangling around the inside
of a server is definitely optimal the
other thing we'd like to move forward
with is getting it to the point where
you can do a full firmware reset on the
devices without resetting the host this
has both the nice property of if you're
using them from multi-tenant you can
still get them back into a known good
state but also means that the recovery
can go much faster one of the challenges
of this is servers are very slow to
reboot if you have to do this a bunch of
times you end up with you know an hour
or two hours the our first on
unoptimized variant of it took a very
very long time and if you have that in
the data center folks are gonna be
complaining about you know we could be
renting these servers why are they
taking so long to recycle so getting
that time down especially if you can do
it online without a full power cycle is
very ideal to opportunity the other
thing that we are hoping hoping we can
move forward with is being able to
detect if firmware has been modified
right now the best you can usually do is
ask the device hey what's your version
number of your firmware it tells it to
you and then
I believe it or it was lying and you
can't tell that it was lying there are
some folks who have done some very
clever things with looking at the timing
it takes to do that to try to figure out
whether or not you're actually running
with what it says it it is but at the
end of the day that's it's an arms race
that I don't think is practical to play
the better solution is ask the vendors
to tell to give us hardware securities
to figure out what the firmware is and
when we talked about this last time I
said that a vendor was working on this
for us but I couldn't tell you who now
there is a intel has actually published
the drafts back of their hardware level
firmware attestation and the way that
works is they have a rom in the device
that does a checksum of the sorry it
doesn't have yes I won't say it does the
hash of the of the firmware before it
boots it and then it puts that into a
locked PCIe register so you can get that
value out of the device and because this
all happens at the hardware level you
have very strong attestation of exactly
what booted in that device what you do
with that value is up to you but it it
allows you to see in in a way that you
couldn't before
so I strongly recommend taking a look at
that and commenting on it with them
there are some things in there that are
also solve other problems but the bits
about getting the hash at the firmware I
think is very interesting the other
thing other limitation this doesn't do
anything for runtime integrity that's a
very hard problem we'd like to hear your
ideas but the the fundamental issues are
until we have boot time integrity trying
to solve for runtime integrity is maybe
not something that that is worth the
effort until we get this out of the way
and we understand which firmware we're
running on but that's an area of a lot
of research still so conclusions here
gaining assurance on your firmware is
hard but it is possible
ask your vendors for these capabilities
the more we go to the people we're
buying hardware for from and say I would
like you to do these things for me so
that I can secure your hardware in my
data center the more likely they are to
do it if we if we present a unified
front to them in asking for these things
it's much more likely that will actually
get change and with that we'll take
questions to the network its externally
controlled right it's not something that
comes in through the system we issued
commands to it from something else that
gets plugged into the network by some
other thing it is it is like a BMC for a
BMC in some ways yes and it's much less
complicated and much easier to do very
careful audits on how it functions yeah
several orders of magnitude less code
so as I said it's you know it's small
enough that it in terms of the
functionality and the code that an
individual can very carefully validate
what it does it is not updatable one of
the concerns we have is all enterprise
hardware is built to be updatable in
situ because that's how you deal with
bugs in it we really don't want that for
this piece of hardware so once we put
the firmware in because it's simple
because it's only doing a few things I
mean it doesn't have the ability to it
doesn't have enough storage even to
write out a backdoored firmware and it's
doing things like toggling GPIO pins
yes yeah so that's being handled
basically the same way so on on a whole
bunch of devices we have to rewrite all
of the configuration settings when we do
this yeah we have to do things like
restore the serial numbers and put them
back in we so we store the store those
states store that data when we put the
system into the data center and we
restore with known good values not not
the ones supplied by the customer if the
manufacturer is screwing with us we have
different set of problems and we're
trying to say yeah yeah we're trying to
ensure the vendor supplied back doors
and not the other customer supplied back
doors there's nothing that prevents us
from doing that it doesn't usually
happen in practice because if just sort
of the rate at which machines come back
to be recycled the the process like
current processes involve as Paul was
mentioning a lot of reboots so we only
do them when the systems are not being
otherwise used we have to move stuff
around to vacate systems in order to run
the process so we don't generally have
like a hundred of these going all
simultaneously and some of some of the
limitations in terms of how long it
takes are some of the processes for
instance involve squishing firmware down
over a fairly slow serial link so that
that can only go as fast per machine as
it can but but there's nothing that
prevents us from running it there's as
far as I'm aware there's no limit on how
many of these we can do simultaneously
but the process is like it's it's
individualized so you have to run
through the set of steps on each server
and the right order
won't accomplish a whole lot so you have
to go through that on each server
individually I don't know that we needed
anything but three point three honestly
how many voltages how many different IO
voltages did we have to support we had
at least one device that we were worried
was gonna have but I don't think we are
currently doing anything that is other
than three point three right now but it
it ends up being a small number right
everything in the server is running
generally on 12 volts 3.3 or like 1.8
and there's not that many different like
main voltages that you have to interface
to
we build it into all the servers it's
always there yeah the it wouldn't scale
if we had to put it in every time he
wanted a new server
I mean we build clouds right
one of those yes the device itself is
quite simple I mean at the end of the
day so at the end of the day it does
need to be connected to the network to
automate it so we do have to control
access to whatever is managing access -
right like yes we we have we we do lots
of other things to control access to
this to make sure that it is not misused
at the end of the day if the people
walking up to the server want to do
things to it we have different set of
problems you have to walk up to it to
treat it to it you have a firmware yeah
and and we have actually that process is
somewhat involved so we do have some
mechanisms for verifying that this has
happened correctly and device was
programmed correctly and we know that it
hasn't been modified it's if you walk up
and just try and touch it and do
something not terribly clever we will
notice there there are some bits
involving crypto that they asked us not
to talk about
between customers it takes long enough
you don't we now we'd like you can't
stop customers on bare metal from
shooting themselves in the foot it's a
feature too right you know it is a very
legitimate use case to say I know that I
have qualified this network card
firmware for my software and I don't
want whatever the name of stuff is
Enterprise does that all the time and
customers want to do that so we let them
so this is talking directly to the spy
flash as directly as we can so the
original firmware may be back doored
it may have a bug it may have a bug that
allows someone to get it into us you
know for example about every year there
are vulnerabilities in SMM that allow an
attacker to write to the firmware or
write to the bios on a machine because
we're not using the bios itself to do
this kind of update they then even
though even in the context of a world
where we know there are either either we
found them where we haven't but we know
there are that kind of bugs because
we're writing directly the spy flash we
are bypassing the kate the possibility
of those exploiting the update now we we
explicitly don't want to use the
firmware update routine we're trying to
use some hardware mechanism that does
not depend on whatever the firmware is
at this time any other questions
all right thank you very much
you