I've actually had the pleasure of
working with Nisha Kumar our first
speaker today I also had the pleasure of
actually wearing the prototype of what
she's going to talk about today at
DEFCON 25 so and I had the only one and
that's why this came out and I'm really
pleased that she's here to talk about it
today
so anyway Nisha Kumar it has is the
badge designer for the DC 503 badge that
they used at DEFCON 26 this year all of
this stuff is available out on our
github it's the PDX Badgers github PDX
Badgers 2018 bangla she also maintains
an open source project turn which is
working with docker containers with
docker containers on finding out what
you've actually got in it and so anyway
without further ado Nisha Kumar okay
okay I do not know how to operate Google
Sites obviously there's a triangle
button
oh yeah present okay and right there
sweet okay hi so this talk is about the
making of the bangle it I have one on my
hand which I will try to demo and while
I'm trying to demo I'm going to talk
about all the wonderful people that
actually worked with me on this so
there's route killer John Han and secure
leaflets and odj and peers all of this
stuff that I'm talking about the code
the docs
all the Gerber files everything is on
this github special thanks to the dog
crate who got me involved in all of this
in the first place and the family who
were ready supportive while I was doing
this quick question how many are under
21 nobody under 21 good I don't have to
have a filter then
all right so a little background about
this
so back for Def Con 25 which is 2017 DC
503 made this lovely wagon badge how
many of you are familiar with the wagon
badge yeah
it was awesome it had this regard owed
BMD 300 module that was Bluetooth
enabled this badge did not use any of
the Bluetooth features but it also came
with this 64 megahertz ARM Cortex with
the giant amount of flash memory and RAM
so you could run a little video game on
it and that was pretty cool but there
was no Bluetooth and that was something
that the DC 503 folks wanted to include
this time around in 2018 meanwhile in my
corner
there was Mickey asked me to make her
bangle that had blinky lights on it and
this was a weekend project that I built
really quickly I had the I knew what to
use but I had no idea whether I could do
it or not and so I just tried over the
weekend to do it so this is what it
looks like she took it to DEFCON and
everybody wanted one apparently I do not
I do not know because I didn't go to
DEFCON this is what I heard
this is third-person the feedback that I
got but that was when later it turned
out to be right because dc5 wordplay
approached me and asked me if i wanted
to make one that had basically a bangle
and all of the but the BMD 300 so
Bluetooth enabled bangle which I will
try to demo for you right now so here's
my phone here's the bangle in passive
mode it just has blinky lights well it
just has like static lights it doesn't
blink and through the
app on the phone I can connect to it if
I could find it because there are so
many I should have connected to so they
think this is Hoyt well anyway here it
is it blinks it's got a pattern there
there's proof people have seen it and I
will this is unfortunate
ya know well and it's also like
rebooting a number of times so it's
obviously not foolproof but there's lots
of the things that it has is that it's
got in passive mode it just detects any
nearby Bluetooth devices and based on
their MAC addresses it will glow a
certain color and that's what it is in
right now then based on the number of
Bluetooth devices it sees you can unlock
special pattern like blinky light
patterns with it so as far as the design
is concerned this is inspired by a de
fruits LED bracelet there's a link to it
they have all of their files for this
available on their github as well they
have a tutorial on how to make their bad
about their bracelet and it uses the
Adafruit trinket which is like a tiny a
teeny eighty tiny 85 based dev board so
their their bracelet basically has a
slot for the trinket to go into now over
here the dev board that we base this
upon was the Adafruit feather which is
much bigger than the trinket so we had
to place the board horizontally rather
than vertically
and so there's a lip and there's a slot
over there for the board to sit in there
is also a slot for the LED strip to go
around and the LED strip actually is
soldered on top of the board so even
even though the board is placed on the
slot there's an LED strip going around
it so on the outside you see like it's a
one continuous strip so then there's
also like a neodymium magnet thing which
snaps on really satis it's got a really
satisfying snap like a normal bracelet
john hanis made this thank you John
the board design is mostly borrowed from
Adafruit feather board which is also
available on github if you want to check
that out this board layout is also
available on github on the on the link
that I showed earlier I'll put that out
if you want
so the SOC for the Adafruit board we
replaced that with the BMD 300 and the
we shrunk the board down by basically
removing a bunch of components from the
Adafruit the original feather board we
only routed out one data line we didn't
have any reset switch or any on-and-off
switch the Adafruit feather also has
like a DF few ons on switch which is
like a factory reset we didn't have that
and this board was designed by me that's
my github and root killer who helped me
the board programming uses a Adafruit
s-- bootloader which we burn which we
weren't using the regard of board as a
what a jst programmer and so nordic has
a way of this
based on the NRA 52 832 Nordic SOC and
they have a way of making a bootloader
but we just use data fruits cuz we were
we didn't really have much time and we
programmed with Arduino I know Oh DJ
said that he's an electrical engineer
I'm an electrical engineer too so I
cheated here so all the programming was
done by Dean Pierce okay and the board
programming this is actually one of the
cool things about this board is that
Nordic has UART ble service so you can
it it converts the service allows you to
talk to the D to the device so you can
actually use one of the you can either
use a de fruits blue bluefruit le app in
UART mode or you can use one of those
serial Bluetooth terminal apps they're
available both in Android and in iOS and
you can use any one of them to send data
to the device so we had made it such
that if you parse the data and you see
any of these key words it'll tell you
what to do so yeah the the bangle
actually has a shell which is I think
this is one of the coolest parts about
this so yeah it just scans scans any in
passive mode it just scans devices and
reads the data from the rx buffer and
figures out you know based on the MAC
address what color it should blink the
lights and this the fact that it has all
of these different things like the
Nordic Development Board is really
powerful actually so you could you could
operate the device in either central
mode where it just scans for nearby
devices or you can operate it in
peripheral mode where you can talk to it
from a central like your phone or you
can operate it in dual mode which makes
it behave like
oh the central and the peripheral so you
can make it do all kinds of like mesh
networking stuff there's actually like a
GATT service for mesh networks that I
haven't read about so programming wise
the possibilities are just amazing for
this one and you know we can they're all
the code is out there so if you want you
can hack it and see if you can make it
work because within the time we had I
like couldn't figure it out myself okay
now for all of the gotchas so the design
because we were probe we were designing
the bangle and the board at the same
time I really didn't know the exact
dimensions of the board beef before the
bangle was designed so we needed to
secure the board to the bangle with a
with heat shrink so we use clear heat
shrink there this made assembly horrible
we spent lots of time just trying to
stretch the pain over the board and we
had to also secure the battery that way
this didn't turn out we didn't plan it
this way this is just like how
everything turned out and this is
basically hacking to make it sit there
so another thing is that we only had one
size we were hoping to have many sizes
for like vigorous as well as small
wrists I have a tiny wrist and this is
the only one which was tiny and the
reason I could make it work was because
I dremeled out a slot for the board to
sit in so basically when the whole
design was shrunk the board slot was
also shrunk and so the board couldn't
fit in it there was a lot of Dremel in
happening as you can see we also had to
Dremel and carve out slots for the the
program the USB slot as well as the
battery slot so along with the original
design there was a lot of hacking going
on but at least that now
we got a good idea of what to consider
when we're designing this board as you
can see this is how this is how we made
the this actually turned out very well
like I thought that we did pretty a good
amount of forethought to think about
where the pads ought to be on the board
in order for the strip to be soldered
onto it as far as the line mint is
concerned there was a lot of arguing
going back and forth with regards to
this but I thought it turned out very
well one thing I didn't consider when I
was designing the board was that the
strip the strip thickness so it actually
sits a little slanted on the board
because the board was not wide enough to
accommodate it these things
there were many devices on the original
feather board that were specific to
Adafruit so you could only source those
spots through them and I mean I
understand why they do this they they
need to make money but we had to find
alternatives for that the USB
alternative was reasonably easy fine but
the jst one was really hard because we
also had to consider what batteries we
had on hand so these are these lipo
batteries are used to
they're used in drone design like drone
hacking so that was the kind of
connector that we had to work with and
so we had to find a compatible connector
and we also had to consider whether it
was housed or not and depending upon
whether there's housing or not we can
make the connector fit so they were very
I spent a I spent a lot of hours looking
for the right connector for this so
these these are actually available on de
jakke so this
out in the end oh there's something over
there that says I am a noob this is
actually my first board design I had
never done this before so in that itself
was like I I was I was terrified
so when I started off I actually didn't
do anything until your root killer told
me did you do anything you got to work
on this so there was some there was some
hesitation from my part but and I'm so
glad that it worked really like relief
that it actually worked otherwise it
would have been like you're never doing
this again
yeah so these are things that we or I
did not consider when we were doing this
it was well for one thing the planning
to put all this together was just
enormous I had no idea there I mean you
had to think about assembly timelines
and and this is not just board assembly
this is like board fabbing this is born
putting the parts on the board soldering
stuff onto the board putting the board
in the bangle I felt like if we spent
more time thinking about how much time
it would take to assemble this it would
have gone much faster we I don't think I
think we did consider whether the bangle
is going to be easily assembled but not
to the extent where we're thinking we're
trying to shave of seconds in the
assembly we were just like oh it takes
us two it takes us a minute to do this
it's not gonna be that bad well you know
two or three minutes multiplied by one
hundred and sixteen hundred and twenty I
don't remember one hundred and sixty
that's a that's a long time to assemble
there was also like 3d printing dates
along
the bangle was 3d printed they were 3d
printed up to day of event by people in
the community like people actually said
I have a 3d printer and I can print
these things for you and I don't think
we would have gotten all of the bangles
printed if it weren't for people helping
out like that so this took a lot of
people hours okay and people tell me
that this was received well but so take
this with a grain of salt i assault I
didn't go to Def Con so I don't really
know yeah no that's secondhand I don't
know I will I will be the judge of there
I guess some of it happened like some of
the feedback I was getting was from the
one hackaday article about all of the
DEF CON badges and they barely had
anything about this so it was probably
because I wasn't there to explain like
you know this is all the cool stuff that
it can do how they saw was this tab
angle with like blinky lights and some
diffuse stuff and everyone would and
lots of people had them so I'm wondering
you know just looking at all of the
other badges that are out there maybe
this wasn't that flashy a badge first of
all it wasn't even a badge so it's kind
of like one of those things DC 5 or 3
took a gambit on like they took a risk
saying well it's not a badge but you
know it'll be cool but it wasn't garish
and I wasn't really looking for anything
garish but maybe it ought to be garish
I'm not sure they're I mean so I I'm
still looking for feedback on that maybe
it maybe it ought to be subtle I don't
know
DEFCON badges doesn't they don't seem to
have subtlety built-in so I wasn't maybe
this was just like a mismatch of vision
but the fact that it actually worked
was something just amazing to me we
there wasn't much as far as expertise
was concerned this looked like something
that required expertise and we didn't
have that much of expertise and we guard
ourselves up to speed on it you know big
shout out to control age that had all of
the equipment it was in state-of-the-art
equipment but we were still able to use
it to make something like this so it's I
am just very thrilled that this worked
out the way that it did and my hats off
to everyone at DC 503 and control H to
be able to help me pull this off so with
that I'm saying thank you
and I don't know do we have time for Q&A
five minutes for Q&A okay does anyone
have any questions yes sir we thought
that we would but we actually didn't we
thought about it and we were like oh
crap maybe we you know but no we didn't
have any interference so yeah no that's
a good question okay so I am in the
process of thinking about it one of the
ideas I had was maybe make beads use the
mesh thing and make like individual
beads that when they when you string
them together will produce different
effects so I'm kind of thinking in the
way of like mesh networks but I do not
have I do not have enough knowledge of
how the platform works in order to pull
that off I am also helping with the
Diana initiative and that's I am that's
gonna be like a very simple earrings
kind of thing but not with this that
that'll be like more my style which is
like subtle thank you yes sir
well so I mean there are several ways we
could have gone about this
I suppose the fastest way we could have
done that is make a mold you know and
then outsource it to some kind of mold
producing thing but really what what the
3d printer allowed us to do is to be
more flexible like I said I was
designing the board while the bangle was
being designed and we were actually able
to make some changes with the bangle
based on how the board was changing but
I think that that's a good point like
you know if we had a prototype all set
and we say okay this is and this is how
it's going to be then we could probably
find a supplier who would produce a mold
for us that would require long like we
we did this in three months so that
might involve you know more six months
period so yeah there was also like some
consideration of making fly using Flex
PCBs but again we do not have any
expertise on making Flex PCBs so I don't
know how that would that would have
worked out but yeah
mass production was not something that I
was considering thank you for the
question
[Music]
I think we worked with whatever we had
yeah the the black one I actually use
super glue to stick the the strip on top
of the black one
we thought about clear PLA s the before
but I don't think we had any on hand oh
yeah you have one okay I think thank you
[Applause]
you