okay hi I'm Justin I work for a local
company it's not super important but
over the past few months I have been
able to partake in two of the most
fulfilling things I've ever done in my
information security career I'm here to
tell you about one of them spoiler alert
it's about cyber education in April I
heard about a talk by a guy named Tobin
shields who's sitting here in the front
row he gave a talk about cyber education
at our company and I didn't get to
attend the talk I just got the slides
for it and I went through the slides and
I thought this is something that is very
very important the pipeline for
information security personnel are it's
it's drying up cyber education is not as
popular as we'd like to think it is a
lot of it has to do with some of the the
culture a lot of ask to do with the the
job situation but the education that
does exist tends to focus on threat
research in academia you go to a
four-year institution you learn how to
stay in a four-year institution but
there's such thing as blue collar jobs
in the information security field how
many people here defend a company raise
your hand how many people are on-call
sometimes Believe It or Not you are the
blue collar of the information security
field and you are underserved by the
community at large by the infrastructure
for education and by conferences and
this is why I'm super excited that track
B is all dedicated to cyber education
and defense this year this is a not a
first for B sides but it's it's a long
time coming and we should give a round
of applause to the B sides crew for
putting this together because this is
awesome
so why why is education targeting attack
research and academia because defense
isn't sexy
we are underrepresented at conferences
because the things that we do aren't
sexy they're not going to get headlines
you write policies you do risk analysis
you write firewall rules you don't talk
about you don't have fancy names for the
things you do and icons for the things
you do the training you get is either on
the job or the training you get is from
some certification authority that you
have to pay an annual maintenance fee
from academia is failing you so in May
after listening to Tobin's talk in May
my boss Steve Mann seen and I sat down
in a coffee shop with a local
organization called there now called in
for all they used to be called back the
business education Compaq they're an
organization that puts together
internships for underserved education
educational institutions high schools
and colleges mostly every every almost
every intern I've ever dealt with at
Intel and at my current employer silence
has been from the Beck and they've all
been fantastic and the Beck is fantastic
to work from because it's not you don't
have to go through your intern
procedures at your job you hire them as
contractors you go through your
contractor procedures and you get
interns at a low rate to do jobs for you
and their long-term interns they're not
just for the summer we have one of them
sitting here in the front row so I'm
gonna call him out
why did you get so we sat down and I
thought - we thought to ourselves we
should get Tobin and his cybersecurity
program in touch with the BEC to put
together internships for cybersecurity
students so we can generate a pipeline
from high school to internship to
college to job and they were talking
about doing something in around 2019 hey
we can get something for you the summer
of 2019 and here comes the first curse
of the night I've got I need to get
done now so we started talking about it
and the I'm talking about is
controls testing what is controls
testing controls testing is just one of
those things on a list of a never-ending
list that you have to do it's usually
only done once when you put the control
in place and then you count on your red
team's or your vulnerability test to do
it and they can't do it red team is by
their very nature can't test every
control in your environment and
vulnerability scans often don't don't go
deep enough so you need to do these
controls tests on your own but no one
ever does them because it's just another
thing to do I are our Enterprise put
several controls in place to protect
domain administrators it's a very hot
button topic of mine I'm kind of good at
it I'd like to think I am and but I put
these controls in place and we weren't
seeing any results no either no one was
pinging domain administrator or my
controls weren't working and I wasn't
sure which was which so the goal was I
need to test these controls I need to
make sure that they're working and those
controls I put in place were against
four very specific tools we can go into
that later how do I get these things
tested purple teaming purple slide
I like purple teaming I think purple
teaming is a better way to go about
testing your security controls than red
teaming and adversarial approaches
because adversarial approaches to
testing security controls only tests
your security and your knowledge at that
particular point and any gaps in that
knowledge don't come out until the very
end and if you analyze the data you have
to rely on the red teamers to take
Goodenough notes for you to analyze that
data so you can improve purple teaming
means that your red team and blue team
work together that means both of them
are learning and growing at the same
time they work off one another they
learn from one another and during the
course of the event both of them gain in
skills so I prefer purple teaming so
between May and mid-july I hated
controls testing we got this internship
developed with the ion controls testing
funded and staffed by the end of July we
got in this program we got two students
and two instructors to come and sit with
me and test these controls out the
program was designed around four tools
I wanted the interns to use responder
PowerShell empire bloodhound and was the
last one to open maybe cats over the
course of five weeks they tested each
one of those tools in their environment
in our environment while I watched them
and I got to watch them interplay with
the tools I got to help them use the
tools they learned they taught me some
things about the tools I didn't know at
the same time I got to sit and watch
them through my environment how they
affected my environment where my
controls worked where they failed the
over the course of four weeks they
tested those tools they also took one
more week at the end to write a report
and give a presentation working on those
soft skills that a lot of the blue
collar information security people need
the most your ability to talk to other
people outside of your organization's is
almost as vital as your ability to log
into a firewall
put in a rule the the the way the work
would go was over the week I got them
for 18 hours a week six hours a day over
three days the first day I would
introduce a tool and the control I
wanted them to test the next day and a
half they would spend testing that
control and then the last day I would
teach a two-hour class on this is the
control we put in place to stop you from
doing what you did here's how successful
you were here's some ideas on why I did
what I did and what it means to our
organization how this is how I would
respond to it if in case this ever
happened in my environment and these are
the tools that I use to do my job from
day to day so how did it work
as far as I'm concerned this thing paid
for itself in the first week our interns
were able to find a control that we put
in place that had a typo in it that made
the control completely ineffective
completely ineffective fortunately that
control was only put in the week earlier
so there wasn't a lot of time but paid
for itself in a week the students got to
play with I know their attack tools and
they did some attacking but they got to
play with those tools in a live
environment and they got to see what
happens when you apply defensive
measures against those tools they got
exposure what it takes to defend a
network against the tools and they got
experienced drafting a report and giving
a presentation to an executive about
exactly what they found and the report
was awesome it's everything I could have
wanted from report it showed where we
were strong it showed where we were weak
it gave us a direction to go to to fill
some of the gaps and fix some of the
problems we had in our controls it's
everything you want from controls
testing or a Red Team report the
teachers we had two teachers they traded
back and forth the first was Terry
brought from the Center for Advanced
Learning which is a technical high
school here and then halfway through
Tobin came in and Tobin works at Mount
Hood Community College at they what's
the name of your program the cyber
security and networking program at Mount
Hood Community College and Tobin's
giving a talk at one
and the reason why I'm giving this talk
is because I love the way this guy talks
so I highly advise you guys come at one
listen to his talk the teachers got to
see what live defense looks like in an
environment they got to see the tools
that I use the processes and procedures
that I use they got to ask me direct
questions about their curriculum versus
what the real-world implications are and
the the benefit of this is that they get
to now tune their curriculum in such a
way that they can give students
real-world experience and real-world
goals to attain to so when they leave
Mount Hood Community College which is a
two-year technical vocational program
they're gonna walk out with the skills
needed to get that level one blue collar
information security job additionally
additionally the teachers got a program
got a program that they could deliver to
the state to allow them to get funding
to possibly apply this program to more
companies so more people can take
advantage of this particular thing as
for me the things that I got from this
was a I got a better understanding of my
environment than I had before which is
if you are a jaded information security
person that's actually gold because you
think your environment is one way and it
creeps over time and being able to resit
and figure out how it's changed over
time is absolute gold I got to learn
better the controls I put in place and
some of the weaknesses of they are some
of the controls I put in place worked
amazingly well but had one fatal flaw
that needs to be addressed that I didn't
know existed until this but this
particular point I got her I got a
report to deliver to my bosses that
showed that I was doing a good job but I
still had some work to do but most of
all and this is super cliche and I
really hate that I have to say this I
learned as much from the students as
they learned from me that's super cliche
that should have gone on a slide but we
work in a very negative environment
where it's easy to get jaded and cynical
and sometimes working with fresh faces
and fresh ideas and the energy that only
comes from the youth is just the Shawn
the army need to get get out of your own
way and move forward
how do you get how do you get some of
this action
this is actually pretty easy and I have
I highly recommend going to Tobin's talk
and then talking to him afterwards he's
going to have all the best information
on how to do this but I do have
obligatory content first of all get out
your list of never ending list of things
to do and find four or five of those
things that are measurable achievable
and short-term projects don't focus on
long-term goals don't focus on research
focus on things that are actionable and
measurable break the lists in to achieve
over projects and make sure the barriers
for achieving those projects are removed
if there are things that you put in
place to stop people from doing things
remove those barriers so they can
achieve them you have a compressed time
frame you want them to be successful
baking opportunities to impart knowledge
the you have a bunch of knowledge that
the educators don't have because you
have lots of experience in the field
doing real security work and you need to
bake in opportunities to impart that
knowledge on them and don't shirk on the
soft skills if learning how to talk to
people about what you do is just as
important as your ability to do it and
then at the end contact Tobin and Darren
marks Darren I don't have Darren's here
he's not here
Darren marks works at back firmly back
now in for all he was their point
contact at at getting all of this put
together he was the person who got us
our interns the program he and Tobin are
performing are putting together is what
we took advantage of and thanks now this
usually has a bunch of questions so I'm
prepared to take a lots and lots of
questions
anyone yes they were on my live Network
yes they were attacking real stuff yeah
we'd haven't worked that out yet
controls testing is one of those awesome
things that never not need not needs to
be done so I always have controls that
need to be tested they can't possibly
test all of them I put in place and they
need to be tested regularly so they can
always come back I have no issue about
bringing them in as frequently as they
can possibly be brought in it depends on
their school schedule and stuff the the
part we're dealing with is funding and
one of the things that Tobin and Darren
are putting together is trying to get
state funding so that we don't have to
pay the interns the interns get paid by
the state rather than by us a
medium-sized company that's not terribly
large yeah yes sir
where it's basically I'm a corporate
defender I defend my company from bad
guys I could take this program to any
sector I could take this anywhere
because there's always things that need
to be tested there's always small little
things that I need to get done that I
just don't have time to do
the cycling of controls has nothing to
do with the interns the cycling the
controls go in place as they're needed
or has the technology changes or as the
infrastructure changes there are
standard sets but there are things that
are hey this would be a good idea let's
try that yes sir they were told don't do
that
I was I was watching them and monitoring
the whole time that's the point of
purple teaming and the only control that
they could have done harm with was a
responder in our environment and we we
didn't the if you put barriers in place
for them achieving their goal they're
not gonna learn as much you're not going
to give you the full amount of testing
that you're going to want if you give
them a fictionalised environment you're
going to get a fictionalised results so
yeah don't don't put them in a place
don't put them in an opportunity to fail
put them in an opportunity to succeed
mm-hmm yeah in in a small environment
where we have a few resources yeah I did
I'm not gonna lie it did take my ability
to do my day job but the the benefit is
I am better today than I was before him
and that's all we can be is better so
that's what the Center for Advanced
Learning does it's a technical part-time
Technical High School where you go to
your regular high school halftime and
then you go to this high school and
inside there they have technical tracks
tobin's probably gonna talk all about
that at one o'clock our interns were
high school graduates moving on to
college programs yes sir yeah they were
sitting right in front of me whole time
they don't get free run of the building
no yes sir
it's it's all about it's all about
keeping the the task small if you keep
the project small and you keep them
bunched together so they're all thumb
attica li lined together so you don't
have interns jumping from one idea to
another idea to another idea so I don't
have to do the reset and that you make
the the everything measurable in the
short-term your amount of work for pre
work is just getting him on boarded at
that point and then maybe setting up the
environment so that they'll be
successful that took me a little bit of
time I'm not gonna lie it did take me a
little bit of time the report I got out
of it was well worth my time yes
I had to present this to my my VP who
was in charge and I sold it with Mount
Hood Community College offered to
renamed their computer lab after us know
the thing that I brought in is you sell
it as a this is good for the community
you live in a community your your
business lives in the same community
you're going to be trying to pull
information security personnel
eventually from this pipeline learning
to fill the pipeline helping them fill
the pipeline so when they graduate
they're perfect for your job and getting
interns into your environment means that
you get to see the new crop of
information security personnel and
you're going to see how they work and
that gives you first dibs so that's how
I sold it and the lab thing wasn't bad
either my questions
that would make my job way easier yeah I
totally I boarded that the the as long
as they achieved the goal which was
testing the control so if they if they
use another tool instead of we're at
windows credential interns that I made
me cats fine great that test the control
yeah that was the purple teaming part of
it when I originally drafted it I I kind
of set it on a red team and just let him
go and then and then just let him do
their thing I found it was way more
beneficial for me and for the company to
actually sit with them and not
necessarily walk them through the steps
on how to use the tools let them do
their thing let them learn give them
give them tools that are not difficult
to master and then I get to watch them
on the defensive side and when they have
questions I'm there to answer them I'm
here to fix problems I'm there to at one
point in time they got away with
something they weren't supposed to and I
was there to stop them so I think I
think sitting down with them and doing
the actual purple teaming is worth your
your personnel time because they get to
learn the environment way in ways that
they didn't know it before
I did not but I work for a security
organization so I'm cheating the the the
thing that why this was such a perfect
report because it did show that the
controls were working in most cases but
there were gaps that were unforeseen
which is why it was the perfect report
because it shows that I was doing my job
that I did good that are our defenses
for domain administrator actually pretty
good but I still have a little more ways
to go I have more projects to do I have
more things in the pipeline to go so
those are the exact kind of reports the
ones that show me that I'm doing
everything right I'm suspect it's like
it's like well my doctor says my blood
pressure is fine I'm like I don't think
you know how many fries I experience
because they're not jaded and set in
their ways their brains work in lateral
ways that mine don't anymore because
I've lost that elasticity so
yeah cuz I still think that that's
adversarial your your white team doesn't
know what's going on they have to detect
it right yeah so purple teaming the they
know exactly what's going on they know
what time servers were compromised they
know exactly what servers are
compromised they know how they were
compromised that means they can go
through all of the data to see if
there's anything there to build a new
control with yeah yes
business in fact I recommend taking a
blue person and sticking him on the red
team teaching them had a red team and
then while they're doing that also doing
their blue team activities I think who's
got the time cuz I think my time's up
no they're supposed to be someone who's
got my light nobody has the light all
right well 11:30 that's my time's up
everybody I got four minutes all right
any more questions we write the report
and as they were writing the report I
was editing the report saying hey you're
talking to these types of people you
need to include this information you're
need to move this this type of
information because executives don't
need all the details and some people do
need all the details I help them write
the presentation to make sure they
delivered the right information to my
executive when they give their
presentation yeah that was I was
actually trying they and they did the
whole report the right out of the report
and the presentation in one week how
many red team organizations have you
ever dealt with has done a report in a
week
yeah probably if I had them that's great
I just didn't I just don't have him yet
yeah and and he accidentally breaks all
the things no using internal poisons is
great if they're interested in and the I
I really enjoyed using interns because
one thing I learned when I was in until
I went down to Costa Rica and went and
taught a class down in Costa Rica to the
sock down there and sock personnel if
you how many people are in a sock you
job sucks doesn't it it sucks it's it's
it's a very stressful job and it's it is
repetitive and not necessarily rewarding
and when I went down there and teach the
sock people some apt hunting stuff they
were so excited about it they were just
wanted to learn they just wanted to be
there and learn everything that they
could because their career depended on
it to get him out of the sock and that's
what that's what the interns were like
they just wanted to learn they just
wanted to be there they just wanted to
play around and show me things that I
hadn't seen before so great sure
it's the ultimate blue-collar job yes
and no but you can also make them hungry
ones if you can learn how to talk to
them in the way that they want to
understand it yeah so one of the things
that one of the things is super
impressive was two weeks before they got
there a harm jury released it goes back
and goes pack doesn't come in a binary
format it's he only gives you the source
code and compile it and while the
interns took it home and compiled it and
brought it in because I didn't I didn't
do it I just and we tested it and it was
awesome but then because our tool
detected it I'm like well we should try
to obfuscate this so he taught himself
had to obfuscate what was it
c-sharp c-sharp code I brought it back
in and we tested the Optus kata versions
of it so yeah
way too early this is we just started
this program and they're just now
starting college
one of them's going to my alma mater
which I feel for him because it's in
Klamath Falls I said I'm sorry I'm
Austin we lost that guy forever alright
there's supposed to be something
speaking right now That's not me
I'm sorry I didn't mean to take your
time I tried
[Applause]
you