[Applause]
so I'm going to talk about cyber PDX
this is a camp for broadening
participation in cyber security that we
run every summer or we're trying to run
every summer and I start the camp with a
quote quote from Barack Obama and a
cybersecurity summit and it's one of the
great paradoxes the technologies that
empower us can also be used to undermine
us and inflict great harm and to
paraphrase him it's more tech more
problems and so how do we begin to solve
these problems as a society so I'm an
academic I teach so we learn and then we
try and teach it to the next generation
and so that's what what we do and so
this is the point of Gen cyber which is
a collaboration between NSF and the NSA
to build the next generation of
cybersecurity professionals and this is
targeting high schools middle schools to
try and impart some of this knowledge
earlier on in the pipeline so that
people are aware of that as they go and
and pursue perhaps an undergraduate
degree okay so these are camps to
develop this next generation but what
does a cybersecurity person look like my
daughter is in eighth grade and the very
first thing this the science teacher had
her do was draw a picture of what a
scientist looks like just to expose the
kind of stereotyping they might have to
try and sort of like defeat that and so
I thought about what does it look like
like if I ask a kid what does a cyber
security professional look like they
might give me this which is I mean if we
have a diversity problem that's probably
gotta be a large part of this problem
and so this really is a bit of an enigma
because I look around this room and
nobody here looks like that which is a
problem right so what we try and do is
we try to expose them to all the
different roles you could play in this
discipline so including you could be the
cryptographer so you could be like
goldwasser and Macaulay you could be the
politician so Ron Wyden gave the keynote
two years ago here at besides you could
be at
at level influencing cybersecurity
issues you could be the research
director so Deborah Frank runs the
research programs at PNNL you could be
the journalist Brian Krebs Glenn
Greenwald impacting cybersecurity
through their writing you could be the
bug hunter
so Natalie Solana vich Tavis Ormandy you
could be finding those deep
vulnerabilities that nobody else can
even see you could be the filmmaker so
Alex Gibney was did the zero-days film
which is a highly influential
documentary on the Stuxnet worm our
virus or whatever you malware you could
be the systems developer so this is
Jesse Frisell who has worked a lot on
docker which is being used in a lot of
enterprises today you could be a
television producer how many of you know
that mr. robot is on for another another
season
it's a highly into a fourth season I
think this is last week you could be the
professor so Laurie Craner professor at
CMU went to the FTC developing all sorts
of interesting ideas on password
security or you could be the cartoonist
it's Randall Munroe influencing
technical ideas using cartoons like this
one down here on the bottom right this
is what I teach in my web security class
it's like yeah here's here's some
entropy right here yeah and the bottom
right just read this cartoon and you'll
get what I'm trying to teach you oh yeah
there's the heartbleed cartoon that that
also is an interesting explanation for
that you could be a Crypt analyst so
this is a book that just got released
two years ago on the most successful
Code Breaker in world war one in World
War two Elizabeth Friedman you could be
the comedian so we play the job clips
from John Oliver especially when he's
interviewing Edward Snowden you know
getting to the heart of the fact that
yeah maybe some of the things you did
you know helped but maybe some of the
things you disclosed might not have been
appropriate to to disclose you could be
the podcaster and I know Joe is not in
the room but he just gave an interview
to two weeks ago on on risky business so
you could be Patrick gray or Adam wallow
you could be the lawyer
Susan Hennessy who works on all
different kinds of governmental policies
and legal policies dealing with
cyberspace you could be the ethical
hacker joanna rutkowska of cubes and and
blue pill you could be sue Nomo
shimomura catching hackers like kevin
Mitnick or he could be an author so this
is a picture of Veronica Roth she wrote
this short story on penetration testing
based on the fictional divergent
storyline how many of you know about
divergent if you have a kid they'll know
about it and this is what we used for
our one of our threads in this camp
because we thought it was an interesting
way of weaving the arts into
cybersecurity so with this in mind how
do you offer a camp that speaks to all
of these diverse roles right what do you
teach and how do you teach it so this is
what I'm going to talk about cyber PDX
it's a one-week residential camp for
introducing cyber security to high
school students and teachers so it's
really important for us to get at the
teachers because that's where your
leverage point is because they can bring
that curriculum back to their schools
and then and then you get this sort of
this beneficial effect that you can't
get just by teaching students directly
so what's our approach we have a
curriculum that integrates technology
and the liberal arts we think that they
go and hand in hand and if you were at
the keynote you'll understand some of
these problems have to involve the
liberal arts focus on collaborative
cooperative and peer learning exercises
and not on competition because
competition does drive out a lot of
people from this discipline we have
exercises that allow each student to
practice different roles in
cybersecurity so they're role-playing
different aspects of cybersecurity just
to try them out who knows what's going
to stick problems we focus on
problem-based learning that that we have
exercises that are intrinsically
motivating for them to want to complete
and this is something I talked about two
years ago
the design of the crypto threat in fact
was based on a bunch of puzzles and who
doesn't like to solve puzzles
we have multimodal instruction so to
engage like the physical learner the
visual learner different styles of
learning and teaching to engage students
wherever they are wherever they're best
at at learning scaffolded exercise and
the real important thing here is that we
want these kids to have to feel like
they're both competent and have
confidence in anything that they do in
the camp the goal is to have every
single camper be able to complete every
single exercise in the camp so that's
that's where the design is really I
think important we inclusively target
students from underrepresented who are
underrepresented not only in
cybersecurity but in college so we're
looking at socio-economic deep diversity
we're looking at ethnic diversity we're
looking at gender diversity and we're
telling the teachers who are doing the
recruiting for us find the students who
you would never think would go into
cybersecurity or computer science or
even better
none of those - or to college those are
the people that we want in the camp and
then finally we run alongside of this a
teacher camp and we have these teachers
develop curriculum projects of their own
based on the concept that that have been
presented to them at camp and this
allows them to own a curriculum that
they can then go back to their high
schools to actually teach to their
students so just to get a little bit of
a more detail about what we teach in
this camp we have four threads we have a
cryptography and security we have a
programming thread a filmmaking thread
and a cyber policy thread so the
cryptography and security thread we
talking about how ciphers work how they
can eventually be broken we talk about
different security tools that are used
in industry and and how they work and
this was something I described a couple
years ago at b-sides we base this we
have this divergent theme capture the
flag and urban race and basically this
the the content modules there are five
of them
we start with the historical impact so
we're always focusing on motivation why
would you be interested in in
cryptography and security so we do some
history we cover different ciphers in
World War 1 World War 2 and how they
really shifted the course of those two
Wars and then we go into basic encoding
because cryptography is done into
digital domain so we have to teach them
what binary is and and these sorts of
things and ASCII and and all the
different ways you can encode digital
information we go to simple ciphers that
can be broken fairly easily and they
sort of analyze these things and reverse
engineer their encoding we talk about
modern ciphers and how for example
public key cryptography works and how
that how it can be used to secure
transactions over the Internet and then
we talk about men in the middle attacks
so that even if you do have public key
cryptography if you can't get someone's
public key appropriately and if you're
in the middle so basically the NSA
program by the Flying Pig program we
talk about how that whole thing can be
subverted and in this thread they can
now see from the beginning sort of the
initial sort of forms of cryptography
all the way to modern programs that are
trying to hijack the security of people
so they actually feel like they have a
pretty good understanding of these
concepts so this is all built into a
scaffolded CTF activity that leads to an
urban race where there the whole thing
is role-playing inside of the divergent
plot which is from the short story which
is a ripoff of that short story and then
right at the end there dropped into the
plot live their messaging this Twitter
bot that that's basically cyber 4 and
they're trying to help this character
out to save the city so save Portland
because Portland is about to get blown
up and then the idea is that every team
should be able to save the city and so
far every team has most more or less but
they're running all over campus like
some of the things they have to decode
and solve there they're running all over
the Portland State campus and having a
grand old time all that content is
available so this is actually being run
in like Lewis and Clark at Lincoln High
School Village home resources so we
actually have this curriculum the
instructor material is there and people
can just you
and run this anywhere you'd like all the
all all the material that you need to
run this curriculum is public the other
thread is the programming thread and the
idea here is a lot of them haven't seen
haven't been so a lot of these schools
don't have computer science at all so we
try and teach them sort of the ideas of
programming and what we really want to
impart is the the the idea that
computing computer programming is it's
fraught with errors right like and you
can't start to rely on code without
understanding that a lot of code doesn't
work so that's one of the things we try
and talk to them about so we start them
out with blockly and then we go into
Python programming with turtle graphics
we talked to them about you know
encapsulation and abstraction and sort
of these software methods for managing
complexity and then they do a final
project to it with that includes a code
walkthrough at a showcase another the
third thread is the film thread so we
talked about the influence of movies
historically on policy and then and how
they how it changes public perception
that leads to things things like laws
changing and then we talk about the
techniques that are used within each of
these films to get that emotional impact
because if you develop an impactful film
using all these different techniques
then that's where your highest lever of
change can be as a cyber security
professional and so some of the movies
that we have shown we show the imitation
game we show wargames just for the
impact that these particular films have
had on on perception and then we show
hidden figures as well so we also teach
them the film methods right so a lot of
them have never done any sort of
filmmaking they're shooting a lot of
videos on their cell phones but they're
not really composing them the way that
you would want to to to influence
perception so we talked about camera
angles camera movement camera shot size
and its effects and then they get a
daily film assignment that they're
forced to incorporate themes of the camp
themes of security themes of
cryptography perhaps in a film that
speaks speaks about those topics they
edit
load these things and then we watch them
and give them feedback and then the last
one is the cyber policy thread so we
talk about social and legal problems
brought about by technology and the
importance of having policymakers who
know something about technology I think
we're lucky to have Ron Wyden as our
senator but not everybody is like that
not every senator is like that and
they're voting on these things that
might actually make things a lot worse
so we also focus on collaborative
problem solving to address these policy
issues and so this speaks to the soft
skills we have to have students in this
next generation to be able to go
face-to-face with someone they
completely disagree with and still find
common ground so we completely lost that
in you know in today's fragmented filter
bubble sort of makeup and so we with the
cyber policy thread we talked about
constitutional law surveillance programs
security versus privacy spearfishing and
fake news and how we need policies to
manage all of this stuff but we need
policies that have all the stakeholders
agree on what that policy is and so what
we do is we give them role dossiers of
all the stakeholders in a debate so for
example controlling fake news well you
have like the head of the NSA the lawyer
the ACLU lawyer the journalist you have
all these people with different views
and different stakes in this problem and
then we have them we have them learn
their won dossier really well and then
they network with each other to find all
of the information about all the other
dossiers so they have a good
understanding of all the different
stakeholders using this student mixer
and then we have this cyber summit which
is modeled after Barack Obama's cyber
summit from 2014 where they do nine
rounds of alternating discussions to try
and formulate policy right and so they
go back and forth between caucusing with
other students who have their same role
to get more depth for what what they
need to be advocating and then they go
back to the negotiating table and so we
have ten tables trying to develop ten
different policies to address a problem
like fake news and then we go through
them after and
talk about them this leads to a pivot so
this is sort of the climax of the cyber
policy / film thread where it's a crisis
situation modeled after the cyber 912
competitions which are undergraduate
competitions sort of like the Model UN
is and so they synthesize what they've
learned into a five-minute film that
addresses the crisis that addresses the
policy concerns in a video that we end
up showing at the final showcase so in
the past when Pokemon go was was the
thing two summers ago or three summers
ago we had the zero day exploit that the
NSA was using to track terrorists and
criminal activity and so what is that
good policy or you know what is the sort
of the trade-off between the privacy of
a legitimate user versus trying to you
know fight crime so that was that was
one of the pivots last year we did a
nation-state attack on the 2018 election
which hopefully isn't gonna be replayed
this election I don't know okay so
evaluation we've been doing this for a
while 2014 and 2015 it was a cyber
discovery camp the last three years it's
been a gen cyber camp it's offered to
rising 10th grade students and this is
to give them time to take this content
go back to their high schools and be
able to sort of spread that right to
those folks these are the ten schools
from last July if you have a freshman in
any of these high schools get them these
are likely going to be similar to the
high schools will be participating this
coming year get them on the cyber PDX
team and we hope to see them in the in
the summer if if the end of gen cyber
gives us money for it this is this is
our results so we have the 2016 and 2017
Student Survey results so 60 plus
percent female around 40-ish percent
ethnic minorities and then 20 teachers
each so about 60 students every year do
this if you look at the ratings they're
above 4 in terms of they had fun they
learned a lot they feel the other one
they were glad they attended the camp
this is what you want as a first
experience in cybersecurity and this is
why the curriculum and the exercises
were done the way they were to get that
first positive experience in terms of
comparison to other gen cyber camps one
of the things we do is we target
underrepresented groups so if you look
at that first row you see that for Gen
cyber participants the pre camp intent
to pursue a career in cyber is lower
than the national average but we do more
for the the people then if you look at
the change between before camp and after
camp it's quite substantially higher
than the national average so yes in
progress a longitudinal study of
students is currently in progress we
have someone from the School of
Education who is going through IRB
approval to do some tracking longer term
just to say yes this is the approach
that that we can say you know first for
sure well not for sure but it does seem
to work okay so cyber PDX 2019 we're
actually looking for sponsors just in
case Gen cyber cuts are cuts the budget
we're also looking for volunteers we're
trying to do an extra day at camp we're
trying to maintain our teacher stipends
where where the gen cyber is trying to
get us to basically cut them in half the
teacher program is essential for us it's
like we can't wait like it makes no
sense if we're just teaching students
like we have to teach the teachers
otherwise the the leverage is gone we
are trying to start up a Yubikey module
to FA for all so we're trying to raise
money to get a whole bunch of you bikies
to us and teach a Yubikey module a
two-factor authentication module in camp
that we can then send teachers with this
curriculum and a whole bunch of ub keys
back to their high schools to get to
factor for all and this is something
that we're begging for money for so this
is why and I'm begging on behalf of
Ellie Harmon who's our camp director she
couldn't make it today
but if you are interested in helping out
that's her email address there this is a
link to this site and one last thing I
have a marketing slide sorry it's a
little bit of a sales pitch I'm at
Portland State we're trying to hire new
faculty so if you know of anyone who's
interested in tenure-track faculty
position that's the link and then we
have adjunct faculty positions available
for teaching security courses this is
the list of courses that we have if you
are interested in offering other courses
to influence the next generation of
students we I'd be happy to talk to you
about that and then I'm also looking for
I'm chairing this USENIX advances in
security education we're looking for
submission so if you have something that
you want to submit that is there and
with that I am done
[Applause]
the programming thread was it this one
oh that one the curriculum
yeah crypto cyber PDX org hopefully
hopefully it works let me know if that's
down
we there is this informal learning
program that NSF runs and so we're
applying to have this being done as an
after-school an after-school program at
like Reynolds high school that's the
that's the one high high school that
we're we're thinking of sort of people
who need at after-school experience like
maybe their parents are working and and
they have an after-school program and
they want to learn something this would
be a curriculum that we could just drop
in place and then have them run over
over the course of five yeah yeah after
school middle school and younger there
are yeah that's true yeah we have
something we had ideas about doing maybe
Parks and Rec they might have programs
that do that or or maybe even a Girl
Scout if yes so the curriculum is pretty
portable that you could yeah you could
probably run that thanks thanks very
much sorry sorry to cut off quickly but
we're on schedule I've got a gift for
you