okay so I'm not really used to doing
these kinds of presentation so I hope
you bear with me and that no one brought
eggs okay so welcome so this talk is
called surviving Syria days reducing the
window of exposure my name isn't Desmond
and as John said it was John right I'm
from Sweden okay so mandatory slide
about me I work as a security analyst
and architect for a company called I
secure Sweden we do a lot of security
operation stuff so I'm I'm more of a
hands-on security analysts than them for
example the ones working for 451
research for example I used to work for
bald whitey work there for 10 years
doing different security stuff so I've
always been a defender started out in
network security and moved on as I
imagine most defenders do and if you
want to chat with me and twitter is
probably the best place so if you want
to follow someone who has opinions about
everything I'm your map okay so what I'm
going so what am I gonna talk about I'm
going to talk about software
vulnerabilities and exploits and how we
are currently protecting against
exploits in software vulnerabilities and
I'm gonna suggest a way of improving
what we do because it's not really
working and it's actually not that hard
to get better okay so most companies i
work for enterprises i do consulting
work for enterprises so most companies
enterprises organizations they have a
like a defense model a security
architecture that's meant to protect
them from threats from attacks of
different kinds and this is usually
built from the concept of defense in
depth and defense in that you all know
everything about that I think it's a
great
concept it's a bit abstract so it can be
interpreted in a lot of different ways
and it's been around for a very long
time and when this was you know first
turned into an implementation on the
corporate level it looked a bit
something like this and everything and
everybody is doing it pretty much the
same way so you had a lot of focus on
the on the network on the perimeter
stuff so you had the firewalls in the
proxies and the IPS and the VPNs and all
that and then you had access controls
and you did some basic system hardening
and you had antivirus and that was about
it and at that time that was pretty add
add with it and then time rolled by and
our defense this evil so now we got all
the legacy stuff but our legacy stuff is
better because you know our IPS is our
better or at least more expensive our
antivirus has evolved and all the stuff
is getting better we we're not using
ntlm anymore we're using Kerberos but
we've got more stuff now we got CM and
we get the DLP in application firewalls
and maybe if you really advanced we got
fire i but it's basically just more
tools because in enterprises when you
have a problem you buy a two that's how
it works you don't really you know get
to the root cause of the problem that
often and sometime during the last maybe
ten years and this this not new attack
vector but one attack vector started
gaining prominence and that was
client-side attacks and I'm talking
specifically about attacks on
client-side software and this has been
around a number of years and it's
statistically the biggest attack vector
we've got right now and it's the ones
that the apt for example is mostly
targeting because it works so if we take
a look at this security architecture
that would get or the defense model that
we've got water
the components that are actually
protecting us from this so it looks a
bit like this so we get the firewall and
it's you know the really advanced
next-generation firewall that can do
dynamic content inspection and all that
stuff and we get the IPS which is really
expensive and has a lot of signatures
actually doing a pretty good job and we
get the antivirus or the endpoint
protection suites that does a lot more
than just antivirus so I've spoken to a
lot of penetration testers around the
world and I've asked them do you see
what I see when you attack people when
you attack client-side is this what you
see and they've said yes pretty much
hundred percent said yes and then I
asked them do you have a problem by
passing this and they say no and I'm
pretty sure they're exaggerating because
the offensive side of security you know
they like to look down at the defense
side of security but even if they are
exaggerating they're still able to
bypass it to a degree I'd say and so
this whole model actually assumes that
the target is behind the first two
controls and we all know that's not the
case because we're very mobile now we go
to to the coffee shop on the corner and
we connect our computers and the
firewall and the IPS goes out the window
so and that and what about Syria days
unknown vulnerabilities are these
controls able to catch that well some
people say that they do but I'd say that
mostly they don't and we can talk about
that later if you want to and so what
does this mean well it means that our
perimeter has changed the perimeter
isn't on the network anymore but our
defenses didn't really change we're
still doing it the same way and I'm
talking corporate I know a lot of you
are working in the antivirus in
it and you know better but in
corporations in enterprises we're still
doing defense the same way as we've
always done we don't care about what's
happening in the outside world so that
basically leaves us with antivirus and
Andrew said just that a couple of
minutes ago that there's a lot of things
depending on antivirus and I don't think
it's fair because antivirus is one thing
can't catch everything it's impossible
so do you remember the New York Times
hack so earlier this year it became
public knowledge that the New York Times
had been hacked and that an allegedly
Chinese group called comment group or
apt one whichever you prefer had spent
something like four months in the New
York Times networks and the New York
Times was using semantic as their
antivirus supplier and a lot of people
in the security industry started
pointing the finger at symantec saying
why didn't you catch this so you're
useless why didn't you catch this and to
me they were asking all the wrong
questions because to me the question is
why are we only using antivirus why
aren't we doing anything else I mean we
know about this why are we expecting
antivirus to do everything it's it's
it's a good thing antivirus I like
antivirus but it's not a magic bullet
and semantics responded with this blog
post and I think that last sentence is
very true and I think as an industry we
need to start teaching our customers
this and I know some people are but I
know some people aren't too and that's
antivirus software alone is not enough
but then again we patch right so it's
okay right
well kinda but we do it slowly even the
people that do it fast do it slow
because there's always a window where
you haven't patched and the patch is out
and it's going to get reverse engineered
really fast and sometimes we can't even
patch because you know we might have a
legacy system so third-party systems
that are going to break once we roll out
that new update so how many VPNs break
every time Java is updated and those are
security vendors I mean there's a lot of
things that that are breaking every time
something is updated and people who
haven't worked in an enterprise doesn't
know that and these are generally like
business critical systems so it's not
really an option to just get rid of Java
you have to do something else so and
another thing that comes into play when
you can't patch is something called HD
Moore's law and this was something that
Josh Korman of akamai came up with
earlier this year and he basically said
that once an exploit is in metasploit
the potential number of attackers
increase exponentially and this is
because when an exploit is in metasploit
you don't have to be skilled at you know
exploit development or you know in
anything other than basic clinics and
metasploit and that's really easy anyone
can do it I can so it's fairly so that's
not a very good thing and what about
Syria days I mean we can't patch them
and but is anyone really exploiting
Syria days does that happen or is that a
myth because I tend to find that my
corporate customers they're like okay so
we'll just take sierra days and we place
it over here with the Red Riding Hood
and the other fairy tales but you know
Microsoft has a report out called
software vulnerability exploitation
trends and this is a very good
report I suggest you all go and read it
if you haven't already and there's a lot
of interesting information in this but
one of the things that really stood out
to me with this so it turns out that
forty-six percent of remote code
execution vulnerability in microsoft
software was actually exploited before a
patch was available during 2012 so
that's about half that's like something
like 15 vulnerabilities if i'm not
mistaken and you'll know about what's
happening right now there's an Internet
Explorer cirle out that is actively
being exploited so yes sira days are
being exploited for real and do you
remember this so back in december 2012
in january 2013 there was a watering
hole attack on an iOS developer website
and something along the lines of 10 15
maybe 20 companies was compromised by
this java zero-day that Oracle knew
about but hadn't gotten around to
patching and among the companies
compromised was Microsoft Twitter
Facebook and Apple so companies that
you'd expect to have a pretty good grip
on security I've actually discussed this
with one of Twitter's security guys and
he said yeah we had nothing that could
have prevented this and we do a lot of
stuff but it didn't work so my point
here is that no one seems to be able to
use anything that can actually prevent
the zero-day exploit or defeat certain
exploit and this is kind of interesting
I think because it's not really that
hard or and I can see a lot of you now
going so wait a minute I feel cheated
wasn't this guy who's supposed to be
talking about flashy seared a defense
and yeah I am but there's no flashy fix
I mean there's no two
you can't go out and buy a tool for this
because we've tried that it doesn't work
and it's no red button that you can
press that's going to make this go away
this is going to go on and on so we need
to get our priorities straight because
we need to actually decide what we're
going to defend and who we're going to
defend against because right now you
know how many companies do actually have
to deal with apt attacks I mean maybe we
don't know but if I can take a guess I'd
say that it's not the majority at least
so a lot of our customers actually have
other concerns more pressing concerns if
you've got configure running wild in
your network maybe you shouldn't be
focusing on catching a pt's first maybe
you should handle the basics first so
and I mean the client side is a huge
attack vector that we're not doing
enough to protect so what I'm suggesting
is that we get back to basics that we
actually start working with our
environments like for real working with
our environments working on
configuration and things like that
instead of buying tools and that we
actually start using the tools we have
because we have good tools that really
expensive IPS isn't just expensive
because it says tipping point it's
actually pretty good if you use it and
we need to start focusing on what
matters like what really matters where
can we actually make a difference that
we can see so and how do I suggest we do
that well I say we do hardening and I've
already said that we do hardening
because I said that in the legacy
implementation of defense in depth but
that's on a really high level
and what we're doing there is kind of
legacy too so because that's mostly like
we're disabling the administrator
account and you know we're enabling the
windows firewall and we're you know
we're not allowing users to build local
admins or if we're really advanced you
know we're not allowing users to start
cmd.exe but that's that's sanitary stuff
we need to do more so why don't we do it
to the software because if you think
about it the software is actually the
gateway to the system and the
environment for an attacker and to do
that we need to identify what software
we need to protect and Mark Twain said
once upon a while that once upon a while
what does that mean so history does not
repeat itself but it does rhyme and this
is true because two things to exact same
things rarely happens twice but similar
things happen all the time so what can
we learn from history done well we can
learn where we have seen vulnerabilities
before in what software and we can see
what those vulnerabilities were and we
can see were these vulnerabilities even
exploited because if you look at for
example Google Chrome and you look at
the number of vulnerabilities that has
been found in google chrome and then you
look at the number of exploits that have
actually been used for google chrome
you'll find that it's not very many if
you look at internet explorer you'll
find that there's a lot of
vulnerabilities but they're actually
being used so maybe internet explorer is
we should focus more on internet
explorer learn on google chrome and we
can look at so what could we have done
to defeat these exploits that we've
actually seen in use and so what I
suggest that we start doing now is
something I call software hardening
and we can do a number of things here
these are just examples but we could use
some very basic exploit mitigation
techniques like making sure that a SLR
and DP is enabled and we can use the
enhanced litigation experience toolkit
which is really good and we can you know
actually make an effort to do secure
configuration for these softwares like
we can set the software restriction
policy and we can actually use the
native security settings in the
applications which we rarely even touch
it's all default so and this sounds like
okay but does this work so there's this
thing called the exploit intelligence
project that's run by a guy called Dan
Guido of trail of bits and these are
he's been doing the exploit intelligence
project since 2009 and these are some
some of his statistics for 2009 and 2010
just to give you some history so what is
done is that he's taking the d 15 top
exploit kids during this time and he has
looked at the the exploits that these
actually used and it turns out that it's
27 and if you look at it so out of 19
memory corruption bugs 14 of the
exploits for them could be defeated by
enabling dep 17 by enabling a SLR and
all of them by using the enhanced
mitigation experience toolkit so why is
this why is it's so easy to protect from
this well because attackers don't work
harder than they have to why right and a
SLR bypass if no one is using a SLR
right ok so that was history
does it work now well there are some
things that have changed and we have
actually better native defense is now
because windows 7 is more secure than
windows XP was and Internet Explorer 9
is more secure than internet explorer 7
loss and but attackers you know people
writing mass malware you know doing math
attacks they haven't really you know
caught up so and that means that there's
actually been a reduction on number of
attack vectors that they can use because
because like a modern standard desktop
build are actually using a SLR and dep
and sandboxing so you there's not as
much room for attacks anymore and it
turns out that if you look at where
exploits that these exploit packs are
using now where the exploit come from
these people aren't really writing their
own exploits they're begging for scraps
from security researchers and when
someone publishes an exploit technique
using by any apt they pick that up and
use it but they don't develop their own
so if you look at where exploits used
today in these 15 exploit kids are
coming from we can see that all the
memory corruption exploits came from apt
campaigns or whooping and whooping isn't
really gonna you know publicly disclose
their coolest most advanced techniques
which means that the people writing
exploit packs are actually you know left
with what whooping considers to be
pretty lame so no cool bypasses and all
the job exploits came from security
researchers so that means that well
they're not really upping their game
their attacks are still working to a
very low
degree mainly because of Java and we're
not doing anything about Java except
somewhere so if we do these things if we
do these very basic things or we secure
well no we're not because things like
apts and similar threats still exists
which is why we can't stop there and
this is also problem we tend to you know
do one thing and then okay we're done
I'm gonna go do some something else so
we need to keep working and we need to
do more hardening we need to actually go
back and do our system hardening again
based on what we know today not what we
knew 15 years ago when we did it the
first time and we didn't need to do it
on the network and we need to actually
start using the tools that we have based
on what we know today and we knew and we
need to go back to the people and the
processes and look at okay so what are
we doing that makes us more exposed like
do we actually feed a behavior full of
bad security practices like are we
accepting invoices emailed to us in PDFs
because that actually feeds the behavior
of I'm gonna open this attachment no
matter who sent it so maybe change that
and by doing this we can actually reduce
the window of exposure proactively
because we're actually in erasing our
security baseline we're improving our
security posture proactively we're doing
it before we're doing it and but if we
do all these things eventually the bad
guys are going to have to you know
improve they're going to have to up
their game and when they do we need to
make sure that we've got the threat
Intel that we need to detect these
changes we need to know when trends are
changing
and so we need to know that when we're
seeing software vulnerabilities in
software being exploited and this
software is not the ones we've
identified as critical to protect we
need to change our defenses accordingly
so we need to keep in touch with what's
happening in the outside world something
that we're not doing now either on a
corporate level so we need to go back
then and we need to plug the gaps that
was left and we need to do this based on
what we've learned and we need to you
know and this is going to keep our
defenses current because as I said we
have a connection to the outside world
and then we need to do it again and
again and again and again because the
world is going to change sooner or later
the world is going to change and we have
to change with it so to summarize
priorities is everything priorities is
key we need to get better at
prioritizing what we're going to do and
we need to get better at helping our
customers prioritizing we need to stop
feeding them about apts all the
time it's not working it's not helping
anyone and we actually need to get back
to our environments and start you know
getting to know it from a security
perspective and this work will never be
done we have to keep doing it over and
over again and finally keep calm and
defense in depth
thank you very much are there any
questions so if you if you do have
questions I'll just remind you to put
your hand up and microphone will be
brought around to you I think there's a
waiting in the meantime we just have a
minute or two so do you see that there
is a long term solution to this problem
at all and you know like a standardized
long-term solution yeah I mean it
instead of playing catch-up all the time
you see that there is an end game at any
point and not really i think you know as
long as there's there's a there's a
drive and as long as there's there's a
way to capitalize on vulnerabilities I
mean the bad guys are going to keep
doing it but this is actually a way to
of getting ahead of them they are gonna
have to know do catch up with us and we
don't know I know exploit writers or
exploit pack authors we don't really
know what their capabilities are so we
need to try them win we need to push
them and see if they can actually push
back or if the landscape is going to
change any anyone else have questions
so either you understood me or you
didn't understand me at all great ok
well let's thank our speaker again and
we'll get the next next folks up here
thank you