communication resources and faster and
more reliable I had fun last night so
lots of lock picks now what kind of what
I hope to accomplish with this talk is
so a lot of security conferences you're
going to see like lockpick villages or
you know lockpicking it's a related
discipline especially with a physical
penetration testing and what I hope to
accomplish with this presentation is how
even if you aren't like a security
consultant you just do security at your
work your blue team stuff or even if
you're just the IT guy and you wear many
hats I think everyone can benefit from
knowing about lock picking and being
familiar with it as well as like how it
can you know make you more aware take a
look around and see what kind of locks
you have at your office Tom we're going
to kind of stick with this agenda but
it's going to be fairly open if you have
questions don't hesitate to ask them and
I'll pretend to be able to answer them
so go into intros explain some stuff do
some disclaimers and legally stuff we'll
talk about the anatomy of the lock types
of pics other lock and manipulation
tools not necessarily pics but other
tools and we'll do some demos and we'll
talk about after that what kind of shift
gears and talk about security consulting
and ways you know can concealing locks
and lock picks sorry just lock picks so
yeah if you haven't yet next door is the
lockpick village that's really awesome
this is the first year i've seen it here
at bsides salt lake city it's really
good they have some cool demos you can
get familiar with it try a bunch of
different locks and I spent a time over
there it's pretty good right after this
they're going to be going over security
pins we're not going to touch that too
much here and then at three they're
going to show you how to make your own
boga topics which I'm going to mention
here there's they're really cool lock
picks so
alright disclaimer got some of this from
tool org or tool dot us that's the open
organization of lock Pickers so if
you're going to start picking locks you
know don't pick locks that you don't own
or don't have permission to pick and
don't pick a lock that you depend on so
like don't pick your front door lock and
mess it up so bad that you your key
doesn't work anymore you know go go buy
some logs go to a dollar store you can
get some easy cheap locks to start with
di Habitat for Humanity you can pick up
some I mean walks are everywhere um this
for educational purposes not to be used
for criminal malicious intense bottle
off okay really quick it's your
responsibility to know if carrying and
possessing lock picks in your area is
legal there's several laws about it tool
has done lots of research for the
different states but you know it's up to
you to know your own stuff and if you
want my professional legal advice I'm
not a lawyer and offer none so don't
take anything i say as legal advice and
oh one thing I did want to mention about
this with all the lock laws that I've
read and researched it seems like it's
classified as possession of burglary
tools and the main focus of it is the
intent so just shout out real quick
other than lockpicks what are some
burglary tools just hammer yep what
crowbar yep Slim Jim the the beef stick
or the car thing the car thing love
brick a rock so technically if you carry
a brick around you could be carrying a
burglary tool but all depend or what or
Mason yes if you're a Mason or a poser
Mason and just you know but you know it
comes down to a tent and you know here
in Utah I don't expect you to read all
of this but this is the Utah law
basically comes me on to don't be stupid
don't burgle don't attempt burglary
stuff like that so why lock picking an
infosec reason why is you know they are
related disciplines you know locks are
literally a brand
physical security one of the 10 domains
type thing and you know knowing how to
pick locks you know especially if you're
a security consultant doing physical
penetration tests things like that you
can get access to a lot of stuff you
shouldn't have access to like you know a
lot terminals laptops and routers
network devices you know access to
internal network you can plug something
in you know wiring closets usually
aren't monitored well I guess it depends
where you're at you can even access a
data center like you know always do this
with permission if you do do this in an
engagement just saying and access to
satellite branches or whatever one thing
so physical security breaches can be as
damaging as a computer breach in the
sense that you know physical access is
almost always better because you can
just grab a server and walk out and then
you can you know take it into your own
home pull hashes you know get domain
information you know anyone know the
going rate for a laptop on the black
market with the data on it I heard it
somewhere like some people will pay like
14 thousand dollars if it's connected to
like a corporate account and has
corporate data just so they can have the
data off your laptop I thought that was
interesting I don't have a source on
that but I heard it once I did read it
on the internet they don't let anyone
post stuff on the internet so so
continued I'd kind of mentioned this
earlier definitely security consultants
you know Red Team people that are hired
for engagements you know no lock picking
what about regular IT guys how often are
we in a server room and you know if our
server acts are locked and you don't
have the keys or like you know Bob the
network guy is on vacation and the keys
to whatever is on his keychain maybe you
need it may be you have permission to
get into that don't expect you to read
all of this but this it's interesting
how companies will invest hundreds of
thousands of dollars in the latest
next-gen firewall equipment you know all
this different stuff and then they will
protect it with
cabinets walked with just dollar just
like cheap hardware store locks and even
basic rooms like basic door locks like
but we're supposed to lock the server
room so here's this a generic brand
thing lock in our server room kind um
this is a study done by some pen testers
that was anyway they found that more
than fifty percent of the cases neither
server rooms nor the racks were even
locked probably for convenience it's
just I don't want to have to unlock this
every time and do maintenance on it and
they also do a lot of stuff for Latin
America and they say Latin America is
ahead and far advanced when it comes to
physical security around S&P markets and
stuff like that and they're not as many
breaches as in other countries due to
the physical security that they have so
you know understanding that take a look
around your organization think about
your server rooms like how important is
your corporate data and how are you
protecting it not only like you know a
network and everything but physically
how are you protecting that stuff so
first I'm going up physical security is
something that everybody deals with but
just by show of hands how many people's
job is the security at your company okay
I would argue that everyone's job is
security in one way or another like if
you see something say something type
stuff and you know especially like we
need to you know due diligence say like
hey that's a really poor lock that's
really dumb I've got a couple examples
here in a second yeah but this is just
something that a hacks hacks and vil
mentioned at the b-sides in Orlando see
and this is from high chaos at rubicon
he says no matter what security measures
are implemented physical when physical
access is impossible or wow it's early
no matter what security measures
physical access is still the worst kind
of access that you could lose so
ok so how effective are locks I have a
good friend of mine he's a doctor and he
he does pick locks and he got hired on
and they were at their their urgent care
there after hours clinic and you know
they had a medicine cabinet and their
company policy was you know prescription
and controlled substances keep it locked
in a medicine-cabinet he was looking at
it you know I had like vicodin percocet
her you know who knows what in it and
he's like and as he was going through he
says that is a horrible lock and that is
terrible I was like oh well we have to
keep it locked it's like let me show you
something he didn't even pull out his
lock picks he pulled out the little
Swiss Army knife keychains Swiss Army
knife and picked it with that and opened
it up as like this is in the patient
area we should really get rid of that
cabinet or replace the lock because that
is dumb you know just putting a lock
their doesn't necessarily deter people
another example how many people have
something like this at their work where
you have a key closet you know what what
are the keys inside it to what
everything a lot of times they have this
in custodial closets because custodians
need to go in after hours and clean
stuff you know what if you get in and
access that what if it's where you keep
all your motor pool keys and you know
somewhere in your statement of work if
you're doing an on-site like access to
corporate assets you're like well those
are corporate owned cars i guess i could
go park the cars in a big circle in the
parking lot see if anyone notices
because it is you know but if you look
at that that's protected with just a
simple wafer wafer lock very simple you
know so think about like how you're
protecting things and some people think
hey if I see a lock you know it's going
to deter me it's all on how you
implement it if it's a really dumb lock
or you're just dumb and you implement it
poorly you know you're not going to stop
some people thanks infosec reactions for
that one so why learn lock picking it's
easy everyone can learn lock-picking you
don't have to have an awesome linux
background and hardcore Emacs like you
know you've coded you know compile your
own distro type stuff it's like it's a
physical thing it's like anyone can
learn to pick locks kids learn to pick
locks it's really easy to get a set of
pics you can even make a set of pics
there's lots of materials you can make
them out of hacksaw blades street
sweeper bristles the metal from
windshield wipers and you can make your
own it's kind of interesting and also
locks are everywhere there's probably
locks around your house that you've
never used like on cabinets and stuff
and it's really easy to get locks you
can get them all over the place you can
go to the local locksmith and say hey
I'm interested you know do you have any
locks you don't care about her locks
that you've cut off and don't need
anymore you know lots of places to get
it Newsbeat so and another thing the
reason I want people to know
lock-picking is to understand how
vulnerable locks are to be able to take
a look at a lot can be like that is not
a good lock you know we should
definitely invest a couple hundred
dollars or even the hundred dollars to
get a better lock to protect the
thousands that we're protecting behind
it you know due diligence you know II
it's your job to you know speak up and
say you know speaking from a security
standpoint that should be you know
better protected and then and then if
you do have a red team if you go on site
and you have a team you should have at
least one physical penetration
specialist provision lock-picking as
well as others there's like under the
door tools and you know shimming and
stuff like that but if you do do
engagements like that you should have at
least one person proficient in it so
we'll go over this a little bit i will
explain the different parts of a lock so
for those of you that aren't familiar
with lock picking this is a basic pin
tumbler it works the blue pin that
you've got on top that's called the
drive pin and then the red pin on the
bottom is the key pin it's the pin that
actually comes in contact with the key
and the key pins are different sizes and
they match the the correct key and then
if you look from the top view which is
what that this one is they aren't in a
straight line like the holes aren't
drilled in a perfectly straight line
they slightly stagger a little bit and
the reason for that is one makes it a
little harder to pick not really but it
also presents a major flaw so when I
show you how to pick in a second the
drive pins will actually catch above
and the key pins will fall free and once
all the drive pins are set it'll turn
and then when you insert the correct key
basically what it does you'll notice the
drive pins are different sizes and the
key comes in and then once they all line
up on that line that's called the shear
line you're able to turn the lock
basically what we're going to be doing
with picking locks is getting it lined
up on that and then turn it without use
of the key so basic types of pics almost
any lock pick set you're going to see
it's going to have these first there's
hooks and feelers this is for single pin
picking where you would go in and pick
individual pins hooks feeler pics um Jay
hooks sometimes it that's the thing
there's lots of different names for pics
so you know you can call it at least a
relatively understandable name this is a
snake pick or an S rake because it
shaped like an S and they come in very
different variations some have like lots
of squiggles sometimes like a half s and
things like that there's a half diamond
which has a little diamond shape on the
end there's full diamonds and full
circles and things like that half ball
there's some that have to they call them
a snowman anyway most difference and
then this one is especially for people
who do like kind of a raking scrubbing
type pick method it's called an L rake
some people call it a saw rake or a comb
rake it's not really a comb rate or a
comb pick that's a different type of pic
but so you know so you need a lock pick
and you also need a tension tool any
lock fix that you're going to buy is
going to come with attention tool
because it's a necessary part there's a
couple different kinds these are like
double ended ones some are shorter
somewhere longer if you have like a more
recessed cylinder and then these twists
flex they have a 90-degree twist in it
and i actually prefer these over i
prefer these over the straight edge one
because if you have a heavy hand they'll
actually bend a little bit more than
just a rigid rigid tension on it and
that's good because you want to be
really really light on how how much
pressure you put peterson is a great
supplier of lock picks wise they have a
peterson pry bar and what i like about
this one is it has a serration on the
and so it doesn't slide out very easily
once you have it in the pic you can also
pick it from the top of the pin or the
top of the cylinder so you have all that
real estate for your pic to go in
underneath whereas most of them you put
them in and you're kind of sharing that
real estate with your pic and with the
tension tool I'll show that here in the
demo explaining how that works Bogota
pics so this is what they're going to be
doing at the lockpick village at three
but these are basically the pics can be
either a tension wrench or attention
tool or a pic and they usually fold
together they're really concealable
they're really good pics if you're only
going to carry it like the bare minimum
of pics those are some very good ones to
carry um see other non pics I'm not
really going to go into this too much
for getting into cars there's this thing
called Auto jigglers you don't use a
tension tool for them you basically like
jiggle it in and out and you can open
most cars there's pic guns a lot of
people that don't want to take time to
learn like a law enforcement officers
for example if they just need to get
into the door they'll use these pic guns
and a similar picking method is also
bump keys bump keys are keys specific to
that locks like quick search like master
American but they have their cut all the
way down so there's just little bumps
and you basically tap on them you bump
them and it will cause the drive pins to
jump up and then you can get in if
there's time I have a little extra thing
to show on that it works on the same
principle as like a line of billiard
balls you hit the ball and the one on
the end pops so that's how the pic gun
and the bump keys would work there's
also shims like slim jims and things
like that plug spinner is a locksmith
tool like if if you can't pick it one
direction you pick it the direction that
would end up locking it and they use a
plug spinner to spin it so fast that it
goes past the reset point it doesn't
reset the pins and then there's other
tools that are non pigs it's like an
under the door tool did anyone to attend
the physical pen test shop last night
the workshop did they go over this at
all I didn't attend it but so basically
this is this something you stick under
the door and you have the little cable
part and the ad a compliant lever
handles you can go right under the doors
and then you know pull
it and it will actually open it and you
can open the door from the inside yay
for compliance but it's an interesting
tool but those are non pics not going to
cover those um a couple different types
of picking so there's just you know you
have your hobbyist like I lock pick you
know I pick locks for fun you know some
people consider it an art it's quite an
art form you know do it this way there's
also quick and dirty which you know
learning that you almost always started
out doing like some sort of raking there
scrubbing the lock kind of thing
jiggling is where you're just like
shaking it and hope you get lucky sort
of thing brute force now that's not
necessarily a type of picking but like
you know some locks you can stick in a
screwed up these are very cheap locks
sticking a screwdriver and turn it and
it will like pop the pins or whatever
you can turn the cylinder brute force
carding the lock that it would be like
shim or something you know come and just
card the actual shackle in the door sort
of thing um yeah covert entry um so this
is like highly specialized stuff like
you're very familiar with the alarm
system and you're very familiar with the
locks or what they have in place and how
to bypass them and I'm not going to
cover that stuff because I don't know
much about it so this is basically a
single pin lifting or single pin pick
spp this is good to start learning it
the key to lock picking no pun intended
is really being able to fill inside the
lock and because you can't see inside it
and being able to feel like k is this
one pushing a little harder than the
other ones it's probably a taller pin
you know and because if you remember
they don't line up the holes don't line
up in a perfect line so that's why even
though you're picking it above the shear
line it doesn't quite set it's probably
not the one perfectly you know offset
enough like the other ones are so you
know you just go through and you try the
different ones and if there's no nothing
pushing back then you know it's set like
you don't feel any spring pushing back
then once you get them all picked
because you have tension on it it'll
twist and then you've got the lock open
so that's a single pin picking see and
then this is more like raking and
scrubbing type stuff
where you'd have your different rakes
and you know you kind of just shove it
in you kind of get it and kind of goes
this this works on a lot of locks some
of them like some people actually like
get it in they will they'll quickly
scrub the lock and set like three or
four pins or something and then they'll
switch to to like a feeler hook it it's
really like what works for you kind of a
thing so yeah scrubbing a lock stuff
like that so time for demo let's go to
see now i will get this going hey that's
my face okay so coming down here I'll
show you oops okay so this is a
transparent block so you can actually
see the individual pins hold it up like
that you can see the individual pins you
can't see the key pins very well and
then what you're going to want to do is
you'll get your lock pick this is one
that I carry with me every day this is
the RCS tool company jackknife it's very
very good you can get it from southern
specialties I really really like this
one and this locking lever kind of works
like the forks on your bike securing the
tire so it locks it in place and these
pics don't move they don't wiggle it's
really nice standard comes with you know
eight different pics yeah I really like
it so I'm just going to go do a single
pin picking I'm going to pull out my J
hook and then lock it in place now you
can see this is not going to move yeah
it's in there good comes with the
tension tool so basically this is what I
was talking about earlier you're putting
your tension tool inside it's more ideal
sometimes depending on the lock really
to put actually up above and then you
have all this real estate in here to put
your pics whereas a lot of times you're
going to end up putting your attention
tool inside the lock and then you have
to share real estate with it
so I'm going to try to do this okay
you're going to see that okay it's
upside down but it's easier to pick that
way so basically I'm just going in and
I'm pushing up individual pins just like
in that animation earlier and then once
you get it like they're all lined up and
I felt it kind of move and I just move
the rest of the way and you're in does
anyone want to see that again one more
time awesome so actually this time let's
do it instead of doing a single pin pick
let's just do a scrubbing type pic i
will actually use more often than not i
use an S pick because I learned first by
scrubbing and you know single pin pic is
good because once you get a better sense
of what your fingers are telling you the
inside the lock is but for the moon for
the most part you start out with this so
picking it upside down again but you
know this one you can just kind of push
it in you can you know very similar you
know put in and move it in and out kind
of thing get it working and starting out
I suggest you get a you know some cheap
blocks as well as some clear transparent
one you can get them on Amazon hacker
warehouse they sell them scam school has
some different places first lockpick I
ever had was this South Ward jackknife
they don't even make this one anymore
they make a metal one but I picked
probably over 300 different locks of
this thing and it just wore out over
time I've been doing this for about 10
years and similar thing it's great it's
everyday carry it's on my keychain you
know it's great stuff but sadly I wore
this one out I loved using it but let's
see now i would encourage if you're if
you're serious about this getting a
bigger kit getting some different stuff
this is a this is my first big kid i got
as a south-south or MX MPX s62 um I have
some recommendations at the end and
south or doesn't pay me to say this but
this has lots of different tension tools
you notice how it has a lots of
different feelers it has much a
different
pics like that and a lot of times you do
this long enough you'll notice that
you'll actually start carrying a lot
more tension tools I've been given a
bunch of way out of this kit so I don't
have as many and have a couple different
things and really it depends on the type
of lock you can become familiar with
lock some people have gone through and
said you know with this type of slag we
recommend using this sort of lock and
things like that you know it's a really
good kit I've been pretty happy with it
it's bulky it's heavy you know it's like
a very fat wallet you can get starter
kits for like 15 bucks 20 bucks stuff
like that I sort of stick with my
favorites it's sort of like taking your
teaching yourself you know piano or
something like that you do what's what
works for you which you're familiar with
more often than not I i use my s pic i
use one of these to feel ur pics i use
this one which is pretty standard this
one's kind of a reach around pretty
curved pic very slim and then i use the
half diamond quite a bit so let's see so
the ones i use are these
so these are probably the four most
common pics that i use i only use this
one kind of like in and out set the pics
and then i'll switch and do like the
half diamond so i can get like the
individual and not bump other pins that
are already set kind of thing but really
you know try a bunch of different locks
get proficient one of the things I like
to do I actually have a big set of
padlocks that are just locked you know
on to each other and then while I'm
watching TV you know I'll just be
sitting and I'll just you know not
thinking about just go through and pick
the different locks it's it's kind of
good because sometimes if you're
focusing you're like really like pushing
too hard and oh that's one thing I did
want to mention so tension is like super
important for one tension you can fill
kind of the different cliques once you
set the pins so I don't know how well we
can see this so that's about how much
tension you want eat if you're pushing
so hard that you can start seeing the
blood run out of your finger and it's
white you're pushing way too hard it's
surprising how little you have to push
iron geek Adrian Crenshaw says think of
it like you have a pet ant and you you
want to pet that amp that you love so
much but you don't want to squash it so
you're literally pushing that little bit
on it so if you just can't get it or if
you're pushing and like none of the pins
are moving your your tension is way too
way too hard a lot of times I'll use my
index finger to push however if you're
starting out it's a little more awkward
but push with your pinky if you're if
you have a heavy hand push with your
pinky like it's so much lighter and
easier there are some like you pick the
other direction and you know I'm right
handed so you know use your thumb but
then again your thumb is one of your
strongest fingers and you have to really
let up something to know let's see
switch back over to this channel switch
gears for a little second we have like
different so you're going on engagement
maybe you're going to secure facility
they don't let you take cell phones or
something like that there's lots of
different covert pics rift recon makes
some
gentlemens Bogut odds are really kind of
dapper looking bogotá pics I got a
pitch ramon on the next slide fake
credit cards I'm sure you've all seen
this before it's a fake looking credit
card that is actually a sleeve for lock
picks inside it this this is a very
interesting one this is a penetration
tester in China our name sexy cyborg she
made shoes for her on-site engagement
she's a physical pen tester and then
these gentlemen covert pics that I'll
talk about in a second so here are some
pictures so the guy with the lapel
probably can't see too well but those
are to Bogota pics pressed up against
each other and he has a little spring
from inside a pen and a paper clip or a
safety pin and you can pin them on your
lapel you can pin him inside your pant
leg so like you can sneak omit lock
picks you can sneak them in a lot of
places especially if they're titanium
because typically titanium won't trip a
lot of metal detectors they're more
expensive titanium has anyone seen these
lockpick cards they're cool they're fun
to carry around your wallet tool makes a
really good one I'm told I actually
don't have it that's kevin Mitnick
business card and he gives out to people
there they're great you know but once
you pop them out they're used and you
can put them on a keyring or whatever
and then that's a picture of the
lockpick credit card which doesn't look
fake at all you know card owner is James
Bond expires a January 2003 so no one's
going to notice that it is about two to
three times thicker than a standard
credit card so it is a little bulky but
then again it's it's reusable like you
pull them out it's not like you snap
them out you can't snap them back in you
just put it back in the sleeve so this
is a these are some shoes some platform
wedges now I didn't have a picture of
her she usually wears like a miniskirt
cocktail dress and a very low-cut top
and that's what she does all our
engagements on so she has no pockets no
places to hide you know a bulky lockpick
set type thing so for a lot of her
engagement she actually designed these
she 3d printed them and inside it she
can put
wireless router that she can plug into
the network and then access remotely and
then on the other side she has you know
her key logger she has a little you know
extension thing and then she has a
couple set of pics and some tension
wrenches and she also has a padlock sham
I didn't talk about padlock shims at all
but and she all of her engagements
that's what she brings she doesn't bring
a purse she a lot of times she has to
check in her cell phone I mean you can
hide padlocks and Eric Wow you can hide
lock picks in your cell phone case like
if you have an external case I've done
that before so really clever and she
goes through and explains how she did it
was it was really cool really inventive
so some of the problems this is a that's
a picture of one that i have here with
me so this is a lockpick card that i got
it's actually a seer card like a
survival evade resist escape card so as
like some padlock some handcuffs shims
and stuff too let's get that out of the
way sorry and then you know it was cool
tried it out but the thing is like as
soon as I popped out first thing I
noticed like it's very small but also
the little tabs where I had the where it
was connected were really sharp I didn't
like that I did and it's a one-time use
thing this the tension tool is flat so I
actually had to bend it at a right angle
to use it and it came with just you know
your standard filler and rake I mean
it's cool four in a pinch as like throw
away pics and that's kind of what their
intended for one one time use so
switching back so some problems that you
might come across you might be at a
facility where you know there's metal
detectors and your steel pics you can't
get them in you know titanium would be
great if anyone can think of a
nonmetallic material for lock picks I'm
very interested carbon fiber at that
thickness isn't strong enough it's
almost like a dry twig like it might
work as a pic but as a tension too
little snap almost immediately I know
maybe some kind of you know g10 or like
some sort of polymer or something I
don't know it's a pet project of mine
trying to think out good pics can take
up space
granted if you're going to take if you
don't know what you're expecting you
want to be prepared so you might end up
having to take a big you know bulgy you
know lockpick set I avoid it when you
can but more often than not have
something small concealable if you can I
actually went to a courthouse and you
know they caught me for this and as I go
good good catch also lock picks our
approved are okay with the TSA because
it's a a tool that a non bladed tool
under 7 inches it's ok to carry on board
you still might get you know the you
know power-hungry TSA agents be like oh
you can't take that but anyway so you
know wallet cards one time use you know
sharp snap off tabs granted i have i
have this one I'm told the tool one is
very very nice i want to get that and
probably doesn't have the tabs as much
how many mission possible fans do we
have the TV series 12 so this is from
season 7 episode 6 this is called
underground basically he's captured and
he's in a room where they take take his
ear but they take his you know empty as
Wallace take it take his a pockets his
belt everything and you know he's in
there luckily he had his 1970s white
collars and so he could fit so he
actually fits a full length pic in it so
for perspective that's a full length pic
and this is my neck so I mean if you
have 1970s callers you're good granted
you have the business end of the pic
usually pretty sharp like inches
centimeters from your juggler I don't
recommend that but yeah if you're doing
an engagement you have a 70s caller go
for it hide in plain sight you can get
these on etsy right now they come in
paint confucian a variety of colors but
their earrings so if you want to wear
circa nineteen eighty shoulder dusters
awesome you can have some lockpicks now
if anyone's familiar and I think you
know a security professional should be
at least from they were like if they see
something like that looks like a
lockpick why are you wearing though
you take those off you know maybe you're
at a place where the totally clueless I
don't know but you can get those on etsy
they're like 35 bucks so this was kind
of the thing I was thinking about I was
up late one night thinking like how can
I make a reusable lockpick that would be
cool and you know easily concealed small
and this this is just something that I
was trying out and I want people's
feedback but I came up with these things
I'm calling him gentlemen covert pics
that you know patent pending by the way
and I got the domain name last night but
anyway these are some lockpick collar
stays that I designed a little while ago
they're nice they're easily concealable
comes in a set of four and you fold them
over each other those familiar with
collar stays you know you fold them like
that and they fill out the shape of the
collar State dapper classy it's kind of
James Bondish span boys would totally
heart this ultra concealable I mean even
if you don't wear a collared shirt you
can hide them in your cell phone case
you can hide them in your wallet these
are steel if I do mass-produce these in
market them they be available in
titanium as well so yeah I make them
with a CNC machine I have a machinist
that makes them for me this is a pretty
good job and I'm actually wearing them
Oh demo time so yeah you'll notice they
aren't the full length one so it's not
going to stab me in the neck is just
like you know good four inches away and
so I designed these let me switch over
to this again so I carry these just
because I'm trying them out I'm right
now I'm just in design testing and stuff
like this so what you get is you get
your three pics this isn't a sales pitch
by the way but if you are interested
talk to me I really just want feedback
like if this is a good design pic is it
practical I've got a couple sets of them
here so i'll have them over in the
lockpick village if you want to try them
out so anyway comes with the your half
diamond your snake pick in your L rake
and then also a tension tool i went with
kind of the hockey shape hockey stick
shape design because if it was a
straight 90 degree angle sometime this
part would get in the way of the lock
and
I wanted it kind of angled like that so
time for demo fail so very minimal you
know Bogut oz would probably work better
but this is a fun little pet project I
didn't want to do like a straight type
tension tool because I didn't want to do
something like this because I prefer the
twist flex because this one has no give
whereas this one you know you can bend
it a bit and you have a lot more
forgiveness I guess you can call it but
basically you know very similar and I've
tried this on a couple different locks
and seems to work fine but you know I
come in here and if you want to get good
a lock-picking do it in front of an
audience by the way so your nerves can
be like totally shot or whatever then
you know just oh oh oh so still still in
the design stage but this is something
that I thought you know it might be sort
of fun see if there's a market for it at
all okay let's try a different one
that's the thing if you're starting out
with lock-picking like sometimes you
might be real comfortable with a with a
certain type of pic and it just for the
life of you it is just not working with
that lock you should be able to use a
bunch of different locks you know
basically more tools to your arsenal
okay come on now these do work I promise
did it this morning before I got in
front of people oh stop it
maybe yeah this is why we don't like the
audience try a little better it again
still in demo stage by the way but there
to do do can you guys still see what I'm
doing not even great oh I just picked it
and it popped out embarrassing anyway
you get the gist um so still these are
prototypes this is still something I'm
still designing I'm still you know i'm
interested in people's feedback this is
something that you know you could I
don't know boca topics are nice these
are you know dapper classy whatever you
want to call it but so hey it does work
alright everyone take a drink so anyway
that's a little pet project I was doing
if you're interested you can talk to me
afterwards about it i'm still designing
it ok recommendations how many of you do
have lock fix just by show hands maybe
about half how many your kind of
interest going to look into it after
this talk yes I accomplished something a
couple different sets southward makes
some really nice pics the PX s 14 has a
14-piece lockpick thing it's it's a lot
slimmer I think I saw one at the village
yesterday if you're going to have an
everyday carry type pic i highly highly
recommend this one from southern
specialties the this folding knife they
call them jackknives i really like it
and when you order it you can actually
pick which pics you want in it so if you
want euro style or things like that i
recommend this one because i own it I'm
you know it's it's nice it has a lot of
stuff it has both thick handled which
are more comfortable as well as just the
thing i think they call them thin lines
pics as well peterson pry bar i'm pretty
active on the lock-picking subreddit
they rave about this thing
it doesn't slide out very easily I've
actually thought of integrating it into
mine but it's it's a really good pic I
want me to go back for that okay
recommendations so these are some great
websites where you can get more
information about it tool is probably
one of the best open organization of
lock Pickers I'm la quickie Schuler Town
South or does the supplier south or they
are better quality locks sometimes when
you're looking at locks you might notice
that it looks like they just took a
hacksaw blade and they kind of cut it
out there sort of serrations on the top
which one is there like a really smooth
one that's smoothly cut out something to
look for when you're looking to lock
picks southward also has a clearance
section so scratched or blemished pics
you can get them at a discount because
you're going to stick them in a metal
lock anyway and scratch them so whatever
the subreddits really good also two guys
that I follow pretty closely iron geek
and deviant olam's they have some cool
lockpicking videos deviant teaches that
black hat iron geek puts up all the
bunch of security conference videos and
he's really into lock-picking I actually
send him a set he and I have been
communicating so that's all I had does
anyone have any questions I think we got
15 minutes or 10 minutes yeah Thomas
mm-hmm do you mean like like the
padlocks like the have the different
dials type things or do you mean like
the actual dial walk on a safe okay I
know what you're talking about so he's
talking about are the combination locks
more secure and the answer is it depends
there's a master lock right now that has
it's got the 10 it's got the four pins
and has the 10 digit numbers on them or
you roll them and then you pop it open
that actually has a bypass flaw in it so
I didn't talk about bypass tools those
are basically like pics that you would
put like along the number tumblers for
example you can actually reach and flip
the ER like catch the release lever and
pop it open that master lock one has is
a known vulnerability actually on my
this tool or on my lockpick card so on
this this is a handcuff shim but you
notice how it's a point I wouldn't take
this on a plane by the way because they
could argue that that's a blade I would
take this but this is can also function
as a bypass tool it's very thin you can
actually put it between those tumblers
and go in and disengage the catch
release so something to consider yeah it
really just depends there's some that
are great secure there's some that are
not secure at all but any other
questions
so the question was what's a good lock
and actually here in the extra section
this is deviant ohlins list this is what
he said he recommends these are
different locks scorpion get a schlage
Primus they have a instead of the they
have the regular tumblr pins but they
also have a security pin in it I'm not
covering that but at 11 they are albus
basically any kind of they're called s
fake or SF I see it's a small format
interchangeable cylinder they're all
good locks mr. locksmith he has a lock
he's a locksmith based in Canada he has
a pretty active youtube channel but he
says the a ploy protect to high-security
deadbolt is the best lock you can buy
for deadbolt he's its pick resistant he
argues it's pic proof the reason why
it's been out for like a year or so now
there are no known vulnerabilities there
are lots of people trying to pick that
and no one has been able to he puts it
on his he he says it's unpickable until
someone has done it but no one's been
able to do it so if you have a hundred
seventy-five bucks do that medicos are
good so I don't have any slides of that
but if you look at a medco key you'll
notice that a lot of keys like they're
just cut straight on so you put the key
in its cut straight on medco keys they
actually make the cuts like this the
reason why is the pin hole instead of
like a circle like this it's actually
flatten and the pin has to be twisted a
certain direction before it'll go up
medco keys are really nice like they're
a bugger to pick so yeah those are some
that they recommend I haven't tested
them all out but they have so hopefully
that helps any other questions cool I do
have a I did mention on auto jigglers I
do have a set of those up here or
somewhere but so you'll notice this
isn't a tension tool type thing you
literally put it in and you just kind of
jiggle it and most car automotive locks
are a double-sided wafer lock which is
similar to a pin tumbler lock but a lot
weaker and you can see how easy it is to
get in it really depends and you just
kind of
you pull it in and out up and down and
you twist it slightly they're that easy
to use downside is you can't really most
cars are chipped you can't really still
a car but you can get into a car you
could get the registration info and find
out where people live you could do all
sorts of creepy stuff I didn't mention
bump keys this is just a little image of
help bump keys work I have a set up here
bump keys are cool those that consider
art pick or lock picking an art kind of
you know they're like this isn't picking
this is just burglar manipulation like
block manipulation stuff anyone can do
this the downside to this if you're
trying to sneak into a house you're
literally knocking on the door you're
trying to sneak into it's very loud you
know you get a screwdriver handle or
they even have special like mallets
toward sort of things so you know there
are bump keys interesting stuff but yeah
oh that was a picture of a cell phone I
used to have but I used to carry those
with me and I just used the S rake but
yeah there's not any other questions
that's all I had yeah thanks guys