communication resources and faster and
more reliable that go higher performing
all right and I'm kind of a walker so as
long as you guys can see me okay I'll
stand down here my apologies to the guy
ass tease the camera and follow me all
the time yeah my name is John / bah i'm
the founder and owner of info secure a
local firm that does information
security consulting kind of creative on
the name and the talk i'm giving today
is about building a secure development
lifecycle I've done this twice now for
companies that I've worked for and I do
it quite often now for companies consult
with and you know there seems to be this
prevailing concept that one building
secure code is difficult and to
developing coming up with a secure
development lifecycle is a very
expensive process that requires bringing
in large companies with big bills like
digital and I can tell you from my own
experience that that's not the case in
fact you really can do this on your own
without any outside help so that's kind
of we're going to talk about today I'm
not going to tell you what your secure
development lifecycle should be because
that's sort of your decision not mine it
depends on your culture depends on what
you're trying to build it depends on
your regulation and so forth what I am
going to talk about are some of the
strategies that I've used in the past to
build a secure development lifecycle
talk about some of the resources that
are available to you and answer any
questions that you might have as we go
along please don't be afraid to
interrupt in the middle of the
presentation I do have a question how
many people here are actually developers
write code and then how many are
managers and how many are infosec okay
all right good great so the first
question you have to ask yourself is
what is a secure development life cycle
and the way I like to talk about it is
simplified it's the tools the skills and
the process is it that we need to build
increasingly secure code I never say to
build secure code because how do you
measure
that what is secure code what's secure
today will not be secured tomorrow the
idea is that it's an iterative process
having an STL is really all about moving
from being reactive to being proactive
that's that's all that's all it is
reactive well proactive in terms of what
hackers are doing today proactive in
terms of the the current attacks but
also proactive in terms of regulation
and other requirements so it doesn't
cost significantly more to build secure
code than it does to build insecure code
because in the end you're typing
characters on a keyboard right in the
end you're writing a line of code and
you can either write a secure line of
code or an insecure line of code takes
about the same amount of time what it
does take is some knowledge and some
understanding of what secure code is and
what it looks like the things we'll talk
about today we're going to use a lot of
water folly terms only because waterfall
was first I'm very agile in the way I
like to work in the way the teams I like
to work with and so forth and everything
will talk about will fit well into agile
and it does apply it both the one time
projects if you're building code for in
an IT organization but also for product
software that's going to be iterated on
over and over again so in to start out I
want to throw this image up on the
screen this is the Microsoft sdl and
really honestly this is about how simple
it is to build a secure development
lifecycle sit down and think about the
processes and like I said these are very
very waterfall processes right in
training requirements design
implementation verification but if
you're agile and I have some slides and
appendix if we get to it we will if
you're agile you may be doing activities
in each of these columns all at the same
time you may have a piece of code that's
in verification right now while you're
implementing something but oh you got to
work in at 9am you have to go do a
meeting to talk about requirements with
some of your users okay so that's how it
kind of fits in in agile as well
throughout each of these phases
microsoft has some recommendations of
different activities you might want to
do this is a secure development
lifecycle it may or may not be your
secure development lifecycle a secure
development lifecycle is basic
kind of a document that the sky
describes a process that includes some
or all of these that may have some gates
for when you get to exit a given phase
whatever works for your organization
this is kind of a model for it what
we're going to do today is break this
down we're going to go through each of
these phases and talk about kind of the
goals for each phase and what you might
want to do during that phase the things
you're going to look to have we'll start
with training like I said it's just as
easy to write secure code as it is dry
insecure code you just need to know what
you're doing and that's what training is
all about the goal is to prevent the
mistakes how do we get training well you
know there's a training program that I
talked about a little bit here that a
friend of mine at Salesforce implemented
and now Cisco I was at the IC squared
security Congress in October and the
person in charge of the secure
development life cycle training at Cisco
presented on their program and it's
pretty much the same thing they call it
the security dojo they did sort of a
karate belt approach to training where
everyone got fundamentals so it's kind
of like your white belt and then people
that went ahead and did some oh awesome
top 10 by technology got a yellow belt
and so on and so forth where you know
people who maybe go get their GSS p from
sands become kind of the experts once
they've done some applied training do
you have to go outside to get all this
training no not at all we'll talk about
that down the road a little bit a lot of
this is stuff you can learn on your own
i have i've done a number of
certifications you know I've got a G
whap cissp I've got some other sands
certifications but have actually not
done the GSP yet I'm self-trained to
read a lot of books I look on the
internet I talk to a lot of people when
when I find a vulnerability in a
client's code we talk about that
vulnerability I learned through osmosis
and that works very well for me and it
works for a lot of other people the key
here is to have the commitment to learn
I've worked with so many developers that
are just like I want to hear about it
you know either a it's not a security
bug right I'm the smartest guy in the
room you're not it's not a bug or be
okay fine it's a bug tell me how to fix
it I'm going to go ahead and write this
same bug tomorrow and you're going to
tell me tomorrow how to fix it because
that's how much I care about my career
right it all depends on you and your
attitude and your team's attitude okay
when you move to the requirements phase
really the goal of requirements is just
to determine how much security is enough
security how much do you have to pay to
figure that out not very much you have
to take some time to understand your
clients your internal expectations and
your regulation I have a really
interesting conversation with business
leaders quite often where I'll sit down
and say okay how security we want to be
and they say we want to be secure secure
everything we want all the security in
our code great okay so i think the bill
for that will be about seven hundred
fifty thousand dollars because here's
what we're going to do all of a sudden
all of the security things are no longer
as important and as you talk costs you
begin to figure out what your company
really wants to do and what you'll
notice is there's usually a gap right
you want this much security and your
company wants to pay for that much
security alright but really building a
secure development lifecycle is part of
the requirements face is really figuring
out what it how much security is enough
and what's your risk and then also
setting what the engagement process is
going to be like okay so figuring out
when the rhythms our feature reviews
when when you sit down a look at new
features and review them for security
how frequently will you do that how will
you measure security what's the
definition of done when do we know that
we're finished with our security these
are some of the things that you're going
to think about coming into your
requirements phase and then put them on
a schedule put them in your backlog if
you're agile put them on your calendar
otherwise make sure they get written
down and that's one of the key themes
for your own sdl is that you write it
down a lot of people especially people
in agile hate that idea and this really
is the one place where kind of break
with the agile concept of not having a
lot of documentation really we want to
have the sdl documented and the
activities in the sdl somehow integrated
into your your processes a lot of people
think well I'm agile or I'm
a water waterfall agile which I call
water fragile or we're just random
Cowboys but you know what no matter what
your approach is you actually do have an
approach it may not be written down and
defined in IBM method blue with a
hundred thousand pages of documentation
you have a culture then the idea is to
figure out how to integrate your secure
development practices into your culture
so it takes some definition and it takes
some observation but it can be done okay
design phase this is where we're sitting
down and trying to figure out okay how
are we going to build this new feature
how we're going to build this new
product and here's where we start to
really talk about how are we going to
meet these security and privacy
requirements it the idea here is that
we're not backing into the security of
our application we're actually planning
ahead and thinking about ahead and
that's the only real difference with a
secure development lifecycle like I said
we're being proactive instead of
reactive what third-party components are
we going to use and let's do a review of
them before we do I can't tell you the
number of times that I've done pen tests
or static code analysis for clients who
have taken on third party dependencies
and the holes in their applications all
came through their third parties because
they didn't think about them in fact we
had to do a major bit of work because I
had a client building mobile
applications in the healthcare space and
they picked up a platform so that good
right you know iOS and Android at the
same time and it turns out that that
platform unbeknownst to them was cashing
all sorts of data and we discovered it
in a pen test and it took them a couple
of weeks to really figure out how to get
the cash data out and the root root
cause analysis for that was simply we
picked up a framework because we knew is
going to accomplish what we wanted to do
but we didn't have the time as
developers to analyze the framework to
figure out what weaknesses it introduced
and that's really what this design phase
is all about is figuring out if I'm
going to take on a dependency what's it
going to do read the documentation play
with it do a little bit of pen testing
on your own look into it a little bit
and figure out what risk you're taking
okay I like to talk about the ABCDE of
security
when we're doing iterative software
processes where maybe it's a product
that we've built or something like that
I like to ask questions about ABCD and E
actors are we going to change in this
phase of our product design we're going
to change who interacts with the
application may be up until now the
application was internal only but now
we're going to open it up to external
clients well that really changes the
world right it changes all of our risk
assumptions and it changes the
technologies that were dependent upon
and so forth B is business so what are
some of the changes are going to happen
like I've got clients that have come to
me and said hey up until now our product
does not contain any HIPAA regulated
data but we want to change that ok
that's a that's a business change
channel you know a lot of times we'll
build I worked for a company once that
you know had a bunch of HTTP
applications https applications they
wanted to move to mobile so their answer
was to take no j/s server and scrape
their HTML pages and then manipulate
them into something a mobile application
could consume right it's it's a strategy
maybe not the best strategy but it's a
strategy and it's a decision people need
to make and talk about data what data
are going to store in the system I have
a client who we have always had this
requirement that there will never be any
pH I stored on a mobile device well they
they decided recently that there may be
a business case for that so we had to do
a business case review and talk about
the security of it and by the way this
clients very agile very small team
there's about 10 developers total we did
that business case review it sounds so
formal doesn't it I mean it sounds like
we all flew into a major city and you
know got a bunch of white boards out and
stuff like that nah we did in an hour we
just did a phone call documented the
results of the phone call this is how we
do agile in healthcare world they have
these quick calls we do a lot of stuff
on slack document it with email and we
have a place where we store all these
emails so when regulators actually show
up we can show proof of oh yeah here's
our feature review for XYZ feature
finally environment whether if we're
going to change in the environment you
know what happens today whoo-wee let's
go take advantage of the clouds so we
were running stuff in in on-premise
servers and we're going to pick those
on-premise servers up and move them
EMS on the cloud what could possibly go
wrong okay so these are all things in
the design phase that we think about I
love the the idea of just ABCDE just
keep driving that home in your mind
what's you know what is changing this
time around okay when we get to
implementation here's where we talk
about you know like users what we call
requirements and waterfall are the user
stories and abuse cases in our agile
world all right and during
implementation we want to make sure that
the code that we've designed and
hopefully we've architected in a secure
manner we want to make sure it's
implemented in a secure manner right are
we avoiding cross-site scripting
vulnerability sequel injection
vulnerabilities the real easy things
this is where I'm a big advocate of
static code analysis it is the cheapest
way to prevent or find a lot of these
low-level simple vulnerabilities and so
yeah question I actually my business I
own check marks they're actually here if
you want to get a demo of them there
it's a great tool I work I consult for a
major financial organization right now
they use fortify I'm a big fan of check
marks you can get some of that
functionality out of brakeman and lint
and so forth but to really get a good
scan you want to invest in a tool or
find someone who'll do it as a
subscription service for you which is
one of the services that I offer for my
clients as well and when it comes to the
shoestring budget this is where i
recommend you break a shoestring spend
the money it takes to either acquire a
static code analysis tool or to use
someone on a regular basis to look at
your code and the more frequently you
look at it just like anything agile the
more often you look at that code the
faster you find the vulnerability is the
easy it is to fix them okay and you know
this is a great time for all that
training to be put to use i teach a
course called a wasp top 10 programming
countermeasures it's about a six hour
course and you would think with all of
the
talk now about web vulnerabilities and
stuff like that you would think that
that course would be boring that the
developers would never hear anything new
I mean how many times have we heard
about sequel injection vulnerabilities
right it amazes me though every time I
teach the course how many things people
learn and a lot of times what I'll do is
I'll combine I'll do static code
analysis and then I'll take the results
of the static code analysis and actually
put it into the course as the sample
code of what not to do it's hilarious to
see the finger pointing right oh my gosh
that's Joe's code look at that it's
really incredible to see that kind of
live interaction and see developers
recognizing their own code in their own
mistakes the the very simple basics it's
the top ten is just the top ten it's not
all of the ways you can write vulnerable
code however it's the ten most common
ways that you can write vulnerable code
it's a great way to start for two
reasons number one it teaches developers
how to write more secure code but to it
really just raises awareness developers
start thinking about sequel injection
and stuff like that really the goal of
your training in this phase or before
this phase the goal of them of the
impact is to have your developers ask
the question what could possibly go
around because what is a developer focus
on features that's right they never
think about the unintended consequences
I had a really cool experience this year
I got to speak with a company i'm
actually going to work for in about a
week at CES okay we the company has
started a cybersecurity summit at CES
which is actually really well attended
just probably good thing but i had the
opportunity to wander the couple of
different floors at CES and look at all
the new devices and all the really new
cool things that are out there and i
kept picking these things up thinking
what could possibly go wrong what are
the unintended consequences of this
device and it was amazing i mean you've
got health care devices you've got
shirts that you can wear that have
sensors in them right so what happens if
i can do something in like actually send
shock waves you know electronic pulses
through the shirt instead of reading
them just all sorts of really wild
things the automotive place was really
scary
self-driven cars people didn't really
like me cuz kept asking hey who who does
your security like how do you how do you
figure out these things are secure and
they didn't really like having security
people ask questions about their their
product I don't know why and make sure
in this you know one of the things that
a lot of people have success with is
making sure they have unit and
acceptance tests integrated into their
including security and keep in mind
during your implementation phase that
secure features are not the same as
security features how many times have we
had gone to a client and our vp of
engineering who used to code tells the
client eyewear secara we use we use
windows form forms based authentication
and HTTPS we're good okay so keep in
mind that every feature needs to be
written securely not just the security
features and by the way we're having
some explanation about how to do secure
code we're going to jump to how to build
an SD l in a minute here so verification
phase and I'm running a little bit
faster verification phase the
opportunity to validate your security
features okay so if I built the login
let's make sure the login works it's
also your opportunity to make sure all
of your features are implemented
securely this is where you do fuzz
testing this is where burp comes in
really handy having it knowing how to
use it best investment you can ever make
in security three hundred dollars for
burp it is the most powerful tool in the
world a lot of times I'll do rfps and
people will ask me well what tools do
you use and i'll say i use burp and the
command line and well what about all
these you know they list all these
dynamic analysis tools and all this
stuff and I'm like no I use burp in the
command line with what do you need all
the other tools for right burp has a
great scanner in it actually that works
pretty well so it's a good dynamic
scanning tool you can check that box but
really burp just puts a lot of power in
the hands of the person that's using it
this is where your agile abuse cases
will be used and this is where you
confirm your logging auditing and
incident detection capabilities we'll
talk about that in a minute the time to
find out that you don't have auditing
logging and incident detection
capabilities is when you have an
incident don't don't learn about it then
okay I just wrapped up an incident for
someone we got away really really cheap
on that one
but they learned a lot about their
systems and what they don't have they
were lucky okay release phase this is
when you want to make sure you have an
incident response plan this is when you
conduct your final security review I had
a boss that used to talk a lot about the
NASA red light green light and this is
really where you want to do your
security red light green light have we
done everything we need to do to prove
that the product is secure enough that I
can go out the door alright and then
this is also where you want to certify
your release and archive your bits why
would you want to archive your your code
any ideas if you have an incident
response and you guys are 17 features
down on the on the the main branch and
you need to do innocent response and you
can't unravel everything you've coded
your about 24 17 new features out into
production to resolve your issues and
I've seen it happen it's very painful
and very ugly the other thing that
happens that I've seen work for company
I found a wonderful critical
vulnerability it was awesome there was a
password reset feature and as a
convenience to their clients they had
this concept of a default password so
you know someone forgot their password
you could set the default you just reset
it say oh well it's the default password
and everyone in the company knew the
default password was very convenient
well the problem was that the default
password was actually sent down with the
password reset form where you would
request the password reset so you'd
click it and it would auto populate your
next password login screen with the
default password really convenient right
and it was in the HTML source okay
stupid so we fixed it that's great three
months later the new release went out
and guess what was back someone lost the
change so taking good care in the
release face of your bits really
important and then finally response face
this is not the time to find out that
you don't know how to do response it's
very very expensive to bring someone in
to do response for you my clients are
lucky I'm a terrible consultant I don't
don't charge what I should but you know
if you actually have an incident where
you have to bring in an incident
response team like
and Ian or someone like that you pay
through the nose for it and when you
could have prevented it or at least made
it a lot easier by actually preparing
your it's in a response okay so this is
this is what an SD l is ok so now let's
talk let's go well any questions to what
an SD l is first before we go on this is
kind of the core components of a secure
develop my life cycle clear as mud right
ok good all right so how much is going
to cost so you'll notice here my wife
yelled at me she's like no one can read
that and I kept saying yeah I know that
I just want you to remember that we had
a slide on training ok right there what
do you think he would need in the
training face what's the goal of a
training face build competency yep it
what sorts of competencies who do you
want to build if you were going to train
a product organization I was going to
stop and get candy bars and I just I ran
out of time this morning I love throwing
candy bars out for answers
so you want to build awareness of not
all the different ways something can go
wrong but awareness just of the fact
that things can go wrong I like to talk
about developers who've not been trained
in security I compare them to owning a
Rottweiler which you know a lot of
people have this really negative impact
of a Rottweiler they're just safe or
dangerous than any other dog but think
about a Rottweiler it's not trained so
you have all this power and all this
strength with absolutely no self-control
welcome to the world of developers okay
so here are some basic things that you
might want to train about one would be
your stl process probably want to teach
people how to follow the sdl you've
designed it would actually be very
difficult to argue that you have an SD l
if you can't produce to a regulator some
aspect of training around that s do
other things threat modeling right so
typical block and tackling aspects of
secure code you probably want to teach
some secure coding and guidelines and
then also offer individual training on
coding and testing we'll talk about that
a little bit more but you know you
probably want to have one or two experts
in your company who really really know
about secure coding and or who are
really good pen testers because they can
be on loan those services aren't needed
24 7 but you know what every week or two
someone's going to pull on them so send
a couple of your people away to a sans
course you probably don't have to have
everyone go and get certified in Java
or.net but having one or two people do
that as a great idea okay so how much
this is all going to cost well you know
what I mentioned earlier i'm pretty much
all self-trained I do have a GU app so
you know I spent a fair amount of money
on that everyone knows how much sans
training costs and you know you might
want to probably send someone to a good
code training and maybe you know instant
response training you might want to get
one person with a GC IH certification so
you've got you know any level of
investment but really honestly all of
that stuff is available freely as long
as you find someone who's passionate
about them and give them the opportunity
to be trained or to train themselves
that's what's important so your training
budget could be anywhere from zero to
24,000 if you want to send people to
what three or four sans courses or
higher if you want to send more okay
so here's your shoe string budget
training where are you going to find
your best training owasp is a great
source for we're going to talk about
sources in a minute but just you know
it's out there it's everyone on the
internet requirements what do you what
are your goals during the requirements
phase and what do people need to do to
accomplish those goals ideas so the
requirements phases where we're trying
to figure out how secure our application
has to be we've got to understand
regulation and again you can bring in
consultants and sometimes it's a good
idea right if you have someone if you're
moving into the hip of space and you can
reach out to a consultant and pay them
three or four thousand dollars to come
in and help you understand how HIPAA
will impact you that may be a cost
savings but on the other hand you may
want that training internalized into
your team so you might want to train
have someone spend time reading up on
HIPAA reading up on how to how to write
secure codes in the HIPAA secure code in
the hip of space in fact that's a book i
really want to write i wish i had time
to do it you know it's it isn't rocket
science actually there's just there's
not a lot of regulation around it it's
more about documenting what you've done
this is also when you want to have the
ability to write good user stories and
the definition of done what's
interesting is when it comes to user
stories there's a project called safe
code it's a little bit old it's been
around for a while basically Microsoft
Adobe some of the big vendors five or
six years ago realized they missed the
ball that owasp had really beat him to
the punch and a lot of this stuff so
instead of piling all their energy into
helping owasp they said let's build a
room so they built one called safe code
it's very redundant except they have a
fantastic list of users you use cases
user stories for agile you can literally
copy and paste them in depending on your
organization's maturity safe code is the
link okay so you know how much does it
cost to define what done is a half an
hour and well I'm sorry let me try it
again half a day arguing a bunch of
developers testers and program managers
right it's not that big of a deal all
right in the design phase design needs
really again this is a zero dollar
investment you need to understand you
your
security review and documentation how
are we going to conduct a security
review what is a security review that's
looking at a feature and asking yourself
what could possibly go wrong with this
feature based on the answer what our
requirements to make sure the feature
isn't broken okay it's this is a
low-cost thing that you just design into
your SD l during the implementation
phase this is one place where like I
said earlier I advocate spending money
static code analysis is probably the
cheapest way to prevent vulnerabilities
either by engaging with someone who will
scan your coat for you on a regular
basis or by purchasing static code
analysis tools you can start small lint
is a great start brakeman is a great
start right there's some things that you
can do almost for free if you're running
a mobile application you can do sort of
a combination of static binary dynamic
analysis quark is a tool that was built
by linkedin that's now open source it's
a great tool for analyzing android
binaries to look for most common
vulnerabilities things like you know
intense and so forth that kind of stuff
so there are some free tools out there
they're not going to cover everything
but they'll get you started while you're
trying to make decisions on other tools
so that's your big spenda static code
analysis but other things you do code
review how much does it cost to learn
how to do a code review not much at all
sit down look at the code I one of my
favorite code reviews that I ever did
was was my very first one and we were
looking at the logic for the login page
and in the log in class there was a
boolean is authenticated equal to true
and then I went through a series of
checks and if it failed to check it set
it to false okay upside-down logic what
happens if I break somehow in the middle
of that authentication process before
true gets set to false it's true if I
can break out of it I move forward okay
that's the kind of stuff that you do in
a code review doesn't take a lot of
money to train it you just have to
decide we're going to do the code review
and then sit down and get it done okay
security unit tests also need to be
written at this point by the way I call
out in in design phase I called out
security standards
an implementation I call out security
guidelines standards and guidelines
documentation if you're agile you're
freaking out about this right and in
most cases i agree however in an
organization that writes software as a
main component of their business having
written standards that say things like
we will only use the following
encryption would be a great idea drown
how many people heard about drown less
was last week right okay if you had a
security standard for what ssl you would
support six months ago what would your
standard have set minimum level for
ssl/tls 1 point 0 are above SSL itself
no would you be vulnerable to drown now
how many people have a standard for what
level of support they give to SSL a
couple a couple do there's a lot of
value in writing those standards and
also guidelines how many times have you
seen encryption implemented poorly oh I
forgot to salt it right or you know just
a number of different ways that you can
break it up so having written guidelines
and this is a concept that I've come up
with called sdl in a box and I swear if
I just had a year to sit down and do it
I would wear you you know you could just
inherit these standards and guidelines
instead of having to write them yourself
they're kind of out there the OWASP
developer guide is pretty good a lot of
the cheat sheets for OAuth spar great so
that stuff is available really you want
to grab it there are there these are
just patterns right there just security
patterns instead of patterns for
accessing a database or patterns for
logging people in and so forth okay you
want to write those down that's that's
in a time sink but it's worth the effort
it really is a verification phase this
is where you're going to do feature
level pen test so I wrote a new feature
I'm going to give it to my pen test
people to have them look at it do we pen
test every single feature know what we
do is back in the design or in the
requirements phase and in the design
phase we tag user stories that have
security implement implications so we
know when it hits verification that
feature needs to be pen tested every
once in a while we want to do a full pen
test we also want to do some fuzz
testing a dynamic analysis this is
another phase where I would recommend
that you
kind of break your shoe string budget
pay someone to pen test your application
a lot of companies will say well we've
got a guy who knows how to do pen
testing in house okay that's great how
many hours are you going to give one of
your developers who knows how to pen
test how many hours will you give that
person to test your app any guesses I
mean do you think you could strip a
developer away for eight hours how about
for 60 hours okay it's not going to
happen so this is a place where I
recommend making an investment maybe
it's self-interested because I do a lot
of pen testing but i really recommend
that you bring in outside help for two
reasons number one your internal
staffing requirements will not allow you
to dedicate the amount of time that
needs to be dedicated to do a real pen
test number two someone a pen test day
in and day out will find stuff that your
internal guy won't that's just the way
it works so you know is how often is
often enough annual is probably the
minimal amount that you want to do with
the third party and then depending on
the sensitivity of the data you're in or
the regulation in your industry you
might want to do it more frequently or a
combination I have a lot of clients who
do their own internal pen testing and
then they'll have me do an annual pen
test for them and that works out really
well okay so you want to make sure at
some point that you do some pen testing
and this is where I would say you want
to spend some money all right in your
release phase again releases zero dollar
cost to get ret to build into your sdl
you just have to stop and think about it
what are your release gates we talked
about defining the definition of done up
front this is where you make sure you're
actually done before you go out the door
so you do your final security review you
make sure you have a response plan if
you've decided to use a vendor for
Incident Response you make that decision
who it's going to be make that decision
here sign the paperwork here I did an
incident response recently where I
actually dug in and we we stopped the
bleeding but their internal contracting
process to two weeks and it just SAT for
two weeks on hold and their CEO kept
asking what's going on what's going on
where we hacked where we hacked where we
hacked and we
saying they kept saying we don't know
yet we haven't gotten through
contracting so if you're going to
contract for an external people do it do
it now before you need it and then
monitor verification so this kind of
weird concept for people that we might
actually want to monitor stuff that's
going on in production more than just
who's clicking we're right we talked to
product owners and their idea of
monitoring is mixed panel whoo I know
that users go from here to here to here
to here that's great okay the real
monitoring that you want to do is up
time on your servers right because
that's important if you're in IT and
you're being measured by it but also you
want to monitor activity and you don't
know if it's going to work the you don't
want to find out whether it works or not
when you push it to production so here's
we're going to do your final
verification of that and then you do
really sign off ok this is process
oriented this requires agreement if
you're in an agile world how long does
it take for you to say hey did all of
our security user cases get executed
half an hour someone looking at it right
how long does it take to say we have a
response plan okay well you had to write
one and you might have to go and review
you might have to spend an hour to
reviewing it not a lot of time invested
there and monitor verification that
might take a little bit more time that's
some testing to make sure this monitor
is going to work and can integrate into
your organization interesting side note
so I mentioned I'm working for a major
financial firm we just had this big
breakthrough because a person I went to
high school with years and years and
years ago well before there was managed
code let's just put it that way is now a
sim engineer and was just hired and we
sort of just realized at some point that
we were working at the same major
financial firm which is kind of cool
anyhow we were chatting and I was
chatting one of my co-workers about how
I knew this person who was a sim
engineer and he he was all exciting is
like oh that's our phase three we really
want to figure out how to tie our
applications into the sim so it actually
works so we want to build a living
breathing almost self-aware system okay
that's this concept of what's going on
in your release face it's a maturity
thing if you're brand new to doing a
secure development lifecycle making sure
your application team is writing to tie
into your sim is probably not something
you're going to
do the first time out okay all right and
then in your response phase here you
know you might spend a little bit of
money buying response tools the most
important thing is to tabletop your
response exercise case in point this
hack that happened a couple of months
ago for my client the IT team had
absolutely no clue what they were doing
their response to their WordPress server
being taken over was to reinstall from
backup okay what did that do well number
one it reintroduced a vulnerability that
caused it in the first place number two
it absolutely wiped out every single
piece of evidence the only thing I could
tell them was I have log data up until
this date and I have log data after this
date so clearly you were owned for these
35 days how no idea I can't tell you
because I can't look at the logs because
you wiped him out what did they do I
don't know how do they attack you I
think it was this right so if you
tabletop your response and include your
entire response team it will be a good
idea what will happen is your IT
administrators will realize they're
absolutely clueless about what to do
during a response and you'll teach them
the five things they can do to preserve
evidence simple right your management is
absolutely clueless they have no idea
how long it takes I swear managers think
we're going to call this guy he's going
to come in an hour later we're going to
know what happened right it's like I'm
pulling my car into the the tune-up
place and then going to open the hood
and connect a computer to it they're
going to tell me what's wrong with it
that's not how it works incident
response takes a fair amount of time
especially when you have either a lot of
data or no data because with no data I
keep looking and looking and looking and
looking okay so you really want to spend
the time to do a tabletop response how
much does it cost for you to do that
take an afternoon buy some pizza buy
some soda get everyone in a room come up
with a mock incident and then start
talking about okay how are we going to
where are the logs what logs do we have
what tools are going to use to go
through those logs so on and so forth
okay all right we're moving right along
resources when it comes to the building
in stl
the whole I love Jax slide about
standing on the shoulders of giants
don't do your own sdl Microsoft has
three different s deals that you can
work with they have the microsoft sdl
which describes how we built software
internal to Microsoft I used to work at
Microsoft on that they have the
simplified sdl which is basically whoa
that's kind of the crawl walk run
approach simplified sdl is just easier
and then they have the sdl a which is
aimed toward agile sdl activities be sim
is a great resource as well and by the
way all of these resources are free
besom is it is really kind of the sdl
that everyone models themselves after
the nice thing is it's a maturity model
which means you can rate yourself in
maturity and figure out where you are so
if you're just getting into it you'll
pick their easiest maturity level and
it's like two or three things from each
category it's pretty easy to do it
represents a great ramp up in your
initial six months that kind of thing so
besom is fantastic and then I mentioned
safe code earlier safe code has some
good documentation a lot of it's kind of
a repeatable you'll see on on the
Microsoft stl and BCM but they have
those user stories and those use of
stories are really valuable if you're
sort of a formal agile shop those user
stories will really integrate well into
the into your processes okay what if
some other resources like I said best
$300 you'll ever spend is burp sweet
I've tried owasp zet attack proxy I'm
not really thrilled with it doesn't work
well for me maybe I don't know it I mean
you know it's like it just reported my
reformatted my Mac I've been a lightroom
user for years and years and years I
tried nikon capture for about 20 minutes
and threw it out I'm sure I can do
everything with capture that I do with
Lightroom it's just that I know how to
use Lightroom okay or another analogy i
used i skied all through my childhood
when i moved to utah i tried
snowboarding and I was like tumbling
down these blue circle runs thinking to
myself why am I doing this I just want
my skis on again okay so you go with
what you're comfortable with but burp is
just an awesome tool owasp developer
guide in the OWASP tester guide if you
can read
if you can have your developers read
these or if someone can prepare training
for the developers based on these
documents you have gotten probably
twenty thousand dollars worth of
commercial training for free just the
amount of time it takes to build stuff
you know build slides around it very
very thorough resources okay and then
the Microsoft file fuzzer is an example
of a tool is available out there so if
you have a web application that accepts
file formats use the file fuzzer it will
fuzz all sorts of different file formats
for you and you'll find all sorts of
great problems with your with your
application okay so really the idea here
is that number one in building an STL
it's already been done it's already been
thought of grab those documents read
through them pick what works for you
what doesn't work for you come up with a
plan we'll talk about this in a second
kind of a step-by-step plan to get to
the point where you're mature with your
security the other idea here is that
there are a lot of tools HP and IBM want
you to believe that the only tools out
there that are going to work for you are
super super expensive and they come with
a forced workflow process okay that's
that's really not true they're good true
they're good tools they were great tools
before they got integrated into all the
other tools that people want to sell you
but there are tools out there that are
inexpensive that work really really well
or even free all right so kind of a wrap
up slide here things to do yourself look
you can do your own training right Oh
Hospital developer guide tester guide
technet apple developer android java one
of the things I was doing was writing
the mobile security guidelines so I
wrote over the course of the last few
months 20 different guidelines that
included sample code how to do things
securely can you guess where that code
came from most of it came off the apple
developer website and off the android
site and was then modified okay these
are great resources to go for code when
it comes to stl design we already talked
about that tools we've talked about as
well things to consider buying it might
make sense to pay sands or someone else
to do more advanced stuff or if you're
really really pressed for time and you
don't have the time to do those basic
fundamental training courses then bring
someone in you can find people who come
in and do that relatively
affordably okay requirements you may
want to consider looking to consultants
who have expertise in an area that
you're moving into if you don't have the
expertise there it's not required again
it's a trade-off between time and money
I really feel strongly about static code
analysis break your bank on static code
analysis break your bank on pen testing
have a third party coming into your pen
testing right so how to get started how
we doing on time poop scope your project
what are your goals why are you doing
this why do you care about this figure
that out to determine what your the how
you're you know that you're building the
right sdl okay if it's if it's
compliance with a regulatory board then
you're probably gonna have to go look
and see what their sdl requirements are
as opposed to we just want to build good
secure code congratulations that's great
okay maturity start small be realistic
leverage existing knowledge and then the
key here is to document it have it
written down and have your executives by
in on it and be part of it okay I wrote
the most beautiful secure development
lifecycle I have ever in my career I
spent on a couple of weeks researching
it taking some of the expertise I had at
Microsoft in other places and putting it
together and it had absolutely zero
support from management so it was shelf
where don't don't do these projects
without getting approval and buy-in
because it's just a waste of your time
you might as well game all afternoon
designing and implementing your stl is
an iterative process it's a crawl walk
run process figure out what your goals
are pick your framework figure out what
you already do find your gaps address
those gaps implement it and then do it
all over again step by step by step
eventually you'll come to a point where
you have enough security and you'll know
that you have enough security you'll
feel right about it management will feel
right about how much time and money
you're spending you that's when you know
you've arrived at least for that week
and then the next week everything will
change okay so that's the end of the
presentation are there any questions
that I can answer yes
good and bad examples in a secure agile
environment of what how to know when
you're done huh that's a great question
so the bad examples are easy the bad
examples is our that you haven't
measured anything the good examples
really I would say are those teams that
push user stories into their rhythm and
in fact here I'll show you really
quickly here so in agile this is the
Microsoft diagram they have this every
sprint requirement they have the idea of
buckets so they got one time things that
you do once for your product design they
have every sprint things you do for
every single sprint buckets that you do
every once in a while okay a good
process is where you've defined those
items and you're actually following them
what those items are will change by team
and by technology and so forth but
that's the best really the idea here is
that you're proactive and you've thought
your way through it
Oh
I
mm-hmm
you should be up here it's great answer
great answer good other questions yeah
do it recommendations in terms of
technology or strategy or all of it that
could probably be a talk in and of
itself but first my first recommendation
is do it and start with you know it's
funny windows what's the default logging
for windows logins what is it only log
by default anyone know successful okay
so my client got hacked what is the
first thing I do I go look at the
windows event logs and guess what I find
nothing well all successes right I
couldn't find any evidence of failure
yeah so so log your failures they're
more important they're more interesting
repeated failures right or if you're
using something like iptables and failed
a man log your log things that break the
threshold things that go above the
signal-to-noise ratio is that helpful
it's a good start there's that's a long
conversation we could have other
questions so let me wrap it all up by
saying what I started with I can't in an
hour teach you what to do in your secure
development life cycle because number
one there's not enough time and number
two it's different for everybody it
really should be different for every
team hopefully we had a really high
level overview of what a secure
development lifecycle is training
requirements design implementation
verification release and support right
and then we talked about I tried to show
hey look really all you have to do is
think about these things and write down
your plan you don't have to spend a lot
of money to get that done a couple of
places where you do probably want to
invest money but most of it is just
stepping back and building an organized
approach and the last thing we talked
about were some of your resources out
there there's all of this stuff has been
done it's published it's free it's out
there all you have to do is grab it
synthesize it for your organization and
get into it step-by-step crawl walk run
into it okay
hopefully I complished the mission and
you feel like you're our was well spent
if you have any questions feel free to
contact me my email address should be on
every slide but it's not so we'll go
back to the beginning here I
unfortunately can't stick around today
I've got some things I have to do at
work so I need to leave otherwise you
know grab me in the hallway if you could
but my address is John info secured I oh
and I'd love to answer questions I give
away you know all sorts of information
all the time because that's I like i
said i'm a terrible consultant so hit me
with an email hit me with other whatever
questions you may have these slides I
will be putting them up on the what is
it join join in sight but also have them
on my info secure site in a few days so
you can go there and actually I'm going
to annotate the notes so there's a
little bit more information some of the
talking points that we had all flesh out
so go grab the slides you know at some
point and feel free to ask me any
questions so with that word up