communication resources and faster and
more reliable I children walking around
so nobody's going to see me in a wet
t-shirt don't worry but we're going to
play a game and the winner will get a
t-shirt not this particular one but just
like this one we will talk about if we
have time we're going to talk about
potential risks of developing nodejs
although this is not the prime goal of
the presentation well we have 30 minutes
all right let's go how did we come up
with the idea well a couple of my
colleagues actually wasn't me there were
it black hat a couple of years ago they
know we're walking around and saw a big
wall with code snippets on it and a
bunch of people just staring it at wall
it turns out they were looking trying to
find vulnerabilities and in other
people's code right have you ever seen
things like that yeah it's pretty cool
right now at that same conference a
study came out that bio asp no less that
the top of the sea so concerns around
the country around the world probably is
that developers don't have a lot of
security training they're not trained in
developing secure code there isn't
enough awareness of the need to develop
secure code so put one and one together
and we have a game of hacks website we
built a game for developers to test the
application security knowledge all right
we'll launched it
at again black cotton 2014 in the first
24 hours we had over 35,000 players
responses really caught us by surprise
completely didn't think it was you know
check marks is not really a big
household name wouldn't command a whole
lot of attention from media since then
it's been over 300,000 games played the
game is actually still up available free
completely free no sign ups needed so
actually let's take a look going to
switch to the browser Scott works you
can play our self you can charge your
colleagues it's always more fun and
great should have done
kind of like some popular TV shows of
trivia games right right you look at the
code you pick the answer that you think
is correct well I can't really read the
code I know about you so I'm going to
pick one and it's either right around by
the way this oops the answer was wrong
so the idea of course is to answer as
many questions as you can in the
shortest possible time you get points
for doing that and if you win your name
is at the top of the leaderboard well
what could go wrong right when you when
you invite when you kind of talk about
this at the hackers conference sorry the
black hat invite hackers to play game
against other side so let's see I'm
going to go back to the presentation I
do encourage you to check that game out
right so what else was behind this
development it wasn't just the game we
actually developed it using new to us
techniques at the moment we wanted to
extend our services to cover nodejs for
example so we use no GS nodejs was nude
to our development team I will still
decided that the game definitely would
be attacked right so we try to plant a
few honey pots to see what the hackers
would go after first not everything
actually was planned on purpose I admit
some things did surprise us but so let's
talk about what happened right
these are some messages from a from the
message boards right see that some of
this was not very flattering some was
okay but these are kind of high scores
notice the problem none of these class
scores look real I can get that much let
me get points so let's see how how this
happened I'd said game of Fox
architecture there's a web client
JavaScript web client there's no GS on
the server hosted by Heroku scores our
users are kept on a MongoDB database
very simple right that anybody has apps
that that look similar to this one
probably not that uncommon on the actual
client page you have question you have a
question you have source code you know
can object of the question you have the
question itself answers count score
difficulty level in the timer pretty
simple these all kind of objects in the
client-side JavaScript so the first
problem was that wouldn't actually keep
track of which answers were answered
right so what happened was that there
was a call back to the server to submit
an answer turned out you can actually
call this over and over again I didn't
have to to run the client so once you
figure out the right answer you can just
call it and call it and call it and get
points and get points and get points
what's the mitigation well you actually
had a flag whether the sensors been
submitted or not and so that prevents
somebody from trying multiple times
seems kind of logical but oh so it's
good to have somebody else find it for
you right interesting makes life
interesting timer in in the first
version of the app the timer was handled
by the client side JavaScript you know
its 60-second timer you you put your
submit n surplus time spent on the
answer as part of the request to the
server what could possibly go wrong well
JavaScript if you know on runs on the
client doesn't really take a whole lot
to modify the JavaScript which runs on
the client so you can submit a time that
you want with your answer right negative
very very low it was all been I was all
built being done by um by users so app
send ANSWER Answer one and time spent
negative billion or whatever there's ten
billion so you see the hacker community
is very helpful right it kind of tell
each other how to how to hack the game
it's pretty cool so we had to modify the
game a little bit and start competing
time on the server there's certainly
possibility for a lag being introduced
all right but now with decent Wi-Fi and
decent direct connection that's typical
not an issue right keep that in mind for
your own development this is a soul for
your benefit
now what else now these are kind of
things we thought about writing in
advance but there's the interesting find
that somebody did and you play this game
and it actually there's a
mobile-friendly website too if you play
it on an iPhone you're going to call
down your finger to the word web browser
and it stops the time so you can pause
figure out the correct answer and then
click it now that I have to say I really
would get no clue to expect couldn't
expect that some hacking the hack all
right so I mentioned the contest this is
going to be a different type of
presentation I'm get you're going to
encourage you to get your phones ready
laptops one people connect to Wi-Fi
Wi-Fi we're going to play a game I how
many of you have never written a single
line of code nobody admits to that but
that's fine so we'll find out a promise
that some light some questions everybody
is going to be able to answer some
questions so here's what you're going to
have to do
you're going to have to go to Kahoot dot
IT and enter the game pen and while I'll
give everybody a few minutes and in the
meantime enjoy the the goats web goats
if you want to prefer so let's see i'd
say we probably have got about 50 people
here 40 i expect that number to match
number of players
fascinating is that it was that a
question at the back in the back no 46
47 look at that okay you can still enter
I sink anyways where's my is my
alright 10 questions same ideas game of
hacks right you have to answer you can't
change your answer after after you
selected one of the answers sorry don't
try to use your back button okay let's
get on with it told you everybody can
answer some some of these questions now
let's see last chance to join these are
warm-up questions okay warm-up questions
don't worry
boring so who is doing fine is doing
fine whoever is fine mr. so now it's the
real stuff right thousand points at
stake how can you see it actually oh I
didn't think about it
don't you two make the code larger hard
to see out
all right nicely done everybody what's
the key combination to zoom in somebody
remember ctrl + is that control shift +
you know all right now think might be
better oh wait I'm not playing well that
happen well namesake in the audience
great is it better back there a little
so the previous one was pretty simple
right there was a format string so no
check what kind of format string you are
using the for unformatted uncontrolled
format strangers to vulnerability path
traversal anybody tell me what can
happen when you do that you can open any
file you want you can overwrite any file
you want basically whatever the
privilege level of your application so
what happens serious stuff all right hey
what happened to you or can do better
then you pay actual remember this very
politically incorrect cartoon ok I don't
know I never I don't think my kids
actually I've ever seen that bonus
question what's the what's the mouse
named there you go good
All Right see we have a clear winner
ah this is nice the questions by the way
our random out of the database so I
don't really know what's what's going to
be next every time I play save save with
game of hacks there's a big database of
questions and now it's some sort of
random order I'll have to say these are
sort of a beginner level questions right
right ah how many of you got confused by
all the sequel statements in there there
you go Igor's pretty close getting so oh
you know what I should have talked about
that when client randomizes the how the
answer order right actually the server
sends the questions the client and the
client presents them in random order in
order to prevent script script running
right if the client does it there's no
way for the server to match what was not
was number one what was number two Oh
ABC whatever it is but you know good
good try questions there you go things
back on track
so where should we validate the answer
any cultural references in here
that should be easy right right those
are because that server good answer this
that client think of what could happen
right what happened to our game of hacks
right you can submit any answer you want
and I think we have the last now next to
last
I think this might be the code snippet
straight from our game you just had to
pay attention we didn't really have to
look at the code have to say check the
pay attention to the presentation and
now you also have to pay attention to
the Commerce to the presentation
alright so i have a as i mentioned i
have t-shirts here see me after the
actually raise your hand who's a nicely
done i have a couple others who sues
number two number three alright thanks
everybody hope you enjoyed it rest of
you hope you enjoyed it but the
presentations are over yet don't worry
i mentioned we're going to talk about a
couple of know GS they have five minutes
who's there where is there folks running
the show I guess I do it's nobody else
here what is specific to know GS that we
talked about a couple of logical flows
flaws in the app that sort of allowed
hackers to to to to hack the app on I
really want to say hat but abused or
bypassed the verification of the rules
so what are things that that you should
remember about programming no GS in
general nodejs is a single-threaded has
single ferret architecture there's an
event loop that calls out workers to do
actual job for non-programmers among you
this is the metaphor right there's a
single thread order taker and maybe
several people who go around and fulfill
the orders the problem is that if the
single thread is busy right the order
taker is busy there are no more orders
coming in and customers aren't being
served so the attack is the denial of
service I see not everybody is laughing
but you should be I mean so actually
kind of a very appropriate a picture
here now every simple piece of code like
that with sufficiently large bound
boundary condition can actually hold up
your kick-ass machine for yep seconds
which is typically enough to do denial
of service if you do it on a large scale
so the key is not to put any
computationally intensive code inside
the main thread and no GS so first thing
that you
probably get burned on but yet people
still get burned on it and I guess the
protection also is to verify any input
especially if these boundary conditions
come from user as my eyes 3pm here well
yes okay well we'll we'll run quickly
from a couple of others just actually 11
so another interesting thing about no GS
is that it's all JSON based right um
language you can do queries against
databases based on JSON objects you can
you can easily manipulate JSON object
right so typically you can use actual
JSON values for the fine method now this
if you do this let's say to validate a
username and password it's very easy to
bypass this this validation by supplying
something that actually looks will be
interpreted by by the database as a code
and the conditions that will be
interpreted by databases code so what do
people do the typical defense against
this is to find the user first and then
compare it to to the password stored for
that user but remembering that jace that
no GS is a single single threaded app
it's easy actual to supply a regex for
that last password parameter that will
hold up your server by this big crib
compare hold up your server for a couple
seconds it's also not good leads to
denial of service rep regex to the
health service sorry we didn't have much
time to to to to go in details to this
but a couple of takeaways
applications application development is
difficult to secure application
development is even more difficult
developers learn much better when they
are part of a game right special if they
compete with each other so anytime you
have a chance to integrate elements of
games into education take it and also
you know all different all the same
rules apply to programming in newer
frameworks like no GS as they applied to
Java for example validate input and be
careful with them with strings ok so
this is it questions thank yous phrases
you know what's the best thing to do is
to stop by our booth you can you can win
beats headphones alright thanks guys