communication resources and faster and
more reliable that go get afternoon
welcome back you guys all have a good
lunch did you guys have lunch yeah my
name is Jeff man and I'm a security
evangelist with tenable network security
which means yes I do work with Jack
Daniel have a very similar role except
for I get the dubious pleasure of being
much more anonymous than he is I don't
have quite the beard that he does this
is my information if by the end of the
talk you're interested in following up
with me feel free to reach out to me i'm
on twitter at mr. Jeff man where my
email is simply j man at tenable com
purpose of this talk today is to first
of all explain to you why I lay claim to
being a Jedi Master talk about a problem
that I've been noticing in the industry
for the past year and a half or so while
I've been doing this speaking thing for
tenable try to provide a little bit of
insight of what I think we can do to
improve what I think's missing and you
hopefully make it a little bit
entertaining yet I wanted to be as
interactive as possible and really just
try to get to a place where we're a
little bit better off by the end of the
talk in terms of how we're approaching
this thing called security and how we're
getting that message out to our
employers our customers our neighbors
and friends out of curiosity by show of
hands how many of seen the new Star Wars
movie that came out last September's
December great how many people have seen
the original Star Wars how many people
saw the original Star Wars when it was
released in theaters in 1977 more than I
expected great so a long time ago there
was this movie called Star Wars
and I sort of created this talk because
this phrase came out of the whole Star
Wars lexicon called the Jedi mind trick
does everybody know what the Jedi mind
trick it these are not the droids you're
looking for the art of making somebody
else do something that you want them to
do whether they know it or not it
occurred to me that I shouldn't give a
whole talk in the Jedi mind trick
without making sure everybody knew that
I was talking about since this is a talk
at the end of the day about
communication star wars the the
franchise is owned by disney so I'm not
allowed to use unless we pay ton of
royalties use any imagery so this is
somewhat movie and tech media themes but
there will be no star wars references
directly in the top throw this out there
right at the very beginning I've been in
the security business for over 30 years
and I've got my start at that place if
you guys want to talk to me later if you
want to buy me drinks I might talk to
you about my views on Snowden or the
views on the recent FB i-- apple thing
but you have to buy me a drink or two
first I got my start at NSA as a manual
crypt analyst I worked with these things
one-time pads in the old days it was all
about communications security and the
communications were either encrypted
before they were transmitted if they
were encrypted before they were
transmitted you could send them anyway
radio telephone Ashley Morse code code
used to be used even when I was working
there but obviously technology was
advancing and manual crypto systems were
changing and I actually got involved at
the very beginning and some of the first
software-based cryptography which was
simply implementations of a one-time tag
to try to put some reference on it
everybody's seen the moot well have you
seen the movie and now I'm blanking on
the name thank you the invitation games
everybody seen them anybody seen that
movie so you know what that is it's an
Enigma machine when i started at NSA in
the mid
ATS the fact that and that US and its
allies the UK had cracked the crypto in
that was still a secret why was it so
low secret because there were still
countries using it it was not
Declassified that we had broken that
which happened way back in World War two
until the late 80 just trying to put
some reference on it that I'm almost as
old it but not quite as old as Jack
Daniel I left almost 20 years ago go out
into the private sector having learned
how to do some penetration testing which
later became known as red teaming with
in NSA wanted to go save the world and
make make more money go out in the
private sector so I became a pen test
around the outside and you know kind of
at the very beginning of this whole
internet web security thing so back in
those days it was teaching people how to
if you're going to be on the internet
you really should have a firewall you
should really start thinking about
having some sort of a security program
and essentially all the things we're
talking about today you know changing
passwords changing default settings
removing hidden default passwords you
know this should all sound familiar that
we've been talking about this for over
20 years ago I guess I made enough
people angry enough at some point that
somehow i stumbled into pci and i ended
up being a qsa for 10 years i like to
call that my pc I purgatory days the
tenable saved me about two and a half
years ago they actually hired me to be a
PCI subject matter expert and try to
help the company you know help to help
sell into the PCI marketplace but also
because of my extensive experience they
said you know we want you to hit the
road and do the speaking circuit as well
why I'm here today I was giving a talk
over the last year called the state of
information security that's that was for
the hacker cons if I was at other
industries I'd call it cyber security
and my message was essentially nothing
changed but as I was going to different
conferences and hearing other speakers
speaking I kept hearing some themes
emerged and the biggest thing that I was
in the vibe I was getting from all the
talks that I went to was you know this
community particularly the b-sides
hacker
community we know a lot about how the
technology works and we know a lot about
the security aspects but if you look at
the if you look at the media it seems
clear that something's not working that
our message is somehow not getting out
to the people within companies and
organizations that need to hear the
message why because major breaches are
still happening and they're happening in
all in all sectors and all verticals and
all industries something seems to be
missing this mean came out just a couple
weeks ago and I think this illustrates
one of the problems that we have in the
industry which I will be bold enough to
mention to you guys sometimes we have an
ego sometimes when we are smarter than
others and we know more than others
sometimes we you know we get a little
bit of an ego I think that's part of the
problem so my basic premise is we need
to learn as a community how to
communicate better to all those other
people that are needing to hear and know
what we know and I've actually been to
several talks over the last year that
attempted to do that and there were some
good elements in those talks but I
thought there was something a little bit
miss him still and I've been a
consultant for 20 years I've spent 20
years going into literally hundreds of
different companies different
environments different you know hostile
and non-hostile audiences but always
with the goal of I'm a security expert
or I know a little bit more about
security than you do I'm here to teach
you educate you in the PCI sense I need
to get you to a point of compliance of
course i always wanted them to be secure
and i would make them compliant but
that's another talk but essentially i've
been in a role of educating and
awareness training in my role of a
consultant for 20 years so I thought you
know there must be things that I do that
smart people have figured out techniques
but there but these are things that are
probably worthy of sharing with others
as a way to learn how to communicate
differently and better I also think that
sometimes a lot of us don't really have
a lot of opportunity to speak you know
there's the stereotype that that the
hacker types kind of stay in closed
rooms usually without windows and
they're they're happy to be in front of
their technology and you probably know
people like this maybe you are people
like this but put these types of people
sometimes in front of a small audience
in front of people that they don't know
a large audience they don't necessarily
have a lot of good communication skills
they're not comfortable with speaking so
the goal of this talk is to try to bring
up some points of tips and indicators of
how you might learn to talk better and
that's essentially what I'm trying to
get at is what I think is missing so for
example I think it's important when
you're speaking to an individual or a
group to get to know them now I've seen
a talk in the last year where basically
they said well you know you've got
google go out and find out everything
you can find out about that person
including social security number don't
need to go that far but it's helpful to
know that the person might be interested
in sports or they're not interested in
sports or you know maybe their kids are
on ball teams or maybe their pet owners
maybe they love skiing try to get to
know a little bit about them because
that gives you a little bit of an idea
of where they're coming from and it
gives you also some tips on later when
you're trying to communicate with them
common reference points or knowing where
they're coming from so as an example by
show of hands how many people think the
greatest hacker movie ever made is flat
pat good nobody ever raises their hand
for that we'll skip over to war games
anyone one person 23 sneakers the
overwhelming favor what does that tell
us about this audience what's what is
significantly different about the movie
sneakers then for example the movie
wargames which is my personal favorite
more technical I think there's also the
introduction of social engineering in
sneakers much more so than war games
which as things get better in security
world you have to learn more social
engineering techniques to be successful
anybody think hackers is the various
movie hacker movie of all time
what if Angelina Jolie who hadn't been
in it well I'm in the interest of time
I'm trying to be expedient here but
swordfish anyone Halle Berry it's all
about hacking but to have something like
that if you're speaking in a group large
or small some kind of icebreaker gives
you an indication a little bit of where
the people are coming from you know this
proud says sneakers so I know this crowd
largely is thinking about social
engineering maybe they're a little bit
deeper in than my old favorite war games
which is how i use to hack which is over
a modem the next thing is I have learned
to listen over the years which sounds
may be counterintuitive but the best way
to learn how to communicate it is to
learn to listen and that's in all walks
of life that's no matter where you are
and what you're doing it's important for
several reasons I think one of our
biggest problems is and I think it's
pretty well understood we tend to speak
a different language than other people
in organizations and other people in the
industry we have a hacker speak we have
a technology speed I saw TV show the
other night and it wasn't a technology
show but there was a scene where a
waiter brought some dessert out and the
person said what is it and the waiter
says this is raspberry pi had nothing to
do with the show but i'm thinking the
writer has to know techies and he put
that in there just as kind of an easter
egg and even in easter egg is hackers
fee so learning to listen means you're
learning the language of the people that
you're talking to because you have to be
able to put what you know in terms that
they understand at the end of the day
it's it's not okay we're just talking
about this at lunch if you're speaking
to a deaf person raising your voice and
speaking slowly doesn't do a whole lot
of good if they don't understand your
language they're not going to get it if
they speak a foreign language how many
times have you seen this you try to
speak slowly and loudly and that person
that doesn't know your line
which somehow they're going to magically
understand what you're saying it doesn't
work the only thing that works is to
learn their language we're Americans
they're supposed to learn our language
but that's a different story not a movie
but it's all about frog protection right
fraud protection we're on the same page
is a TV commercial do you have it out
west when you when you learn to speak
their language you're learning the
language of the business if you're
working at a company if it's a customer
you're learning what their motivations
are what their drivers are these are all
necessary things it takes persistence
sometimes you know you have to keep at
it it take I think it takes practice I
used to in my years of consulting used
to sit around the dinner table with my
family and try to explain things to them
and none of them are really technical
but if I could get to a point where they
were understanding what i was talking
about then I thought I was ready to go
to the customer and usually that's where
the frustration would begin because I
didn't have that much time tell stories
you know I said you know understand
their background understand where
they're coming from try to pick the
stories that make sense to them sports
analogies you hear them all the time but
not everybody is a sports enthusiast
I've been in audiences is going to sound
sexist but you know an audience that's a
group of women they may not be into
football so they may not know sports
analogies related to football as an
example it's really interesting if you
go to a foreign country and that's when
I start to notice all the idioms and
axioms and colloquialisms that I have is
an American and as I'm saying i Mun
realizing you know people in the UK they
don't know American football so they're
not going to get the football analogy
anyway so what does this mean in terms
of soccer and real football and so on so
forth anyway for fun anybody know what
movie that is to shout it out big fish
very good I'm a crypt analyst by trade
and I've been to many talks about crypto
and
you know cryptos in the news lately
about iphones and things like that but
you start going to technical talks about
elliptic curve cryptography and
symmetric and asymmetric cryptography
and public key and private key you start
to lose people very quickly so I it down
into very simple terms even if my simple
terms aren't even technically accurate
sometimes if I can get the point across
and the people that are receiving
understand oh you mean encryption means
you take something I can read and turn
it into something I can't read and
there's something in the middle going on
yeah that's all they really need to
understand sometimes and then you can
start talking about the costs associated
with it and and the benefits and the
frozen the kind i think it's essential
if you're in your own company or if
you're if you're a consultant and you're
working with other companies you have to
understand their language which is very
offered their business it's great to be
a secure is you can be i used to get
customers all the time telling me well
we don't need DOD level security because
they knew i had a DOD background because
we just sell women's underwear or we
just sell shoes or you know the CEO from
target when they were breached a couple
years ago he was quoted as saying we
sell hammers why should we care about
security you can disagree with that but
you also have to find a balance you have
to find a way to work that attitude and
educate them and enlighten them but also
help them to connect and sort of find a
middle ground movie thank you I'm not
people a person in fact I think I have
that role in my company now as a side
job which is embarrassing this is also
essential you can think you've done a
great job explaining a concept ask them
where did you just hear me say you'd be
amazed at how many people times people
will come back and you can realize very
quickly wow you had no idea what I was
talking about let me try again and don't
try again with the same story with the
same technique with the same language
you got to try something different you
got to try it from a different angle and
again the goal is to put it in language
that they understand
movie this is the stumper remote nope
one of my favorite star Geena Davis long
kiss goodnight very good never make an
assumption because you make an ass out
of you and um shun oftentimes when
you're presenting especially as a
consultant you have to give results
you've gone in and done a pen test a
vulnerability assessment some sort of an
analysis and you've got to you got to
explain it to them I have learned this
technique actually from my father but I
always found it was good to start off
with you know say something good like
you know your website has a lot of
pretty colors but and then you move on
to the bad you know we found some issues
and then you drop the bomb on them and
the ugly you know there's some default
passwords in there so the good the bad
and the ugly is the movie that one's a
dead giveaway oh my dad I have to share
with this this part of it when I was a
kid I never got straight A's but one
time I came home with a report card like
six days and one beats the best I'd ever
done my dad first thing he said to me
was why did you get a be scarred me for
life I'm still suffering from it so
where do we go from here practice try to
try to attempt these steps you may think
it's daunting and impossible how many
people want to take the red pill how
many people want to take the blue pill
it's hard it is not easy to communicate
with other people and get them to a
point of understanding those of us that
have been in the industry a while
probably know that you know all too well
I would say don't give up it may seem
sometimes like it's not worth it I'm
sorry everybody know what the movie is
I know what this movie you were again
now the message of the war games of was
you know the moral of the story was
don't play the game because of my
cryptanalytic background I prefer to
think of this more as a puzzle puzzles
have often more than one solution but
there is a solution so you know if one
thing doesn't work try something again
try something different don't even think
of security as a game think of it as a
puzzle and recognized at the end of the
day that it takes time it's difficult to
do when your especially when you're
within an organization and you're trying
to change corporate culture and trying
to get them to think more securely
because they have to that takes that
takes time it takes hard work it's like
steering the there you go so this is a
whirlwind you know 30 years of
experience into a 20-30 minute talk but
be the change you want to be try
stepping out of your comfort zone if you
haven't done this before and
communicating you can do it in a small
group setting do it with a friend you
say hey I want to run something by you
try to find somebody that isn't as smart
as you or isn't in the tech crown try to
tech crowd try to find somebody that
that's outside and say hey I want to run
something by you give it a whirl see if
it works ask them what they've heard try
it I mentioned the the ego thing at the
very beginning with that you know I wish
I was stupid yes sometimes we do no more
than others but a lot of its just
education and awareness I find it
challenging to try to teach people and
get them to a point of understanding and
I feel like if I can't do that well
maybe I'm not as smart as I think I am
so that keeps me humble I used the and I
still talk about how I'm bilingual I've
developed over the years the language of
the tech community but I also speak the
language of the business non-technical
community
and I have found it essential to get
things accomplished in my customers and
companies I've worked for to be able to
communicate with the non-technical
community probably more so important
than talking to the tech proud because
it's really easy to talk to the people
to catch you on the back to yeah yeah
yeah I get it I get it I agree with you
to me after 30 some years in the
business I think what really is going to
make a difference ultimately because
everything we've done up to this point
doesn't seem to be working very well and
the technology certainly not getting
easier we still need to be able to teach
and educate what are still the basic
fundamentals of security knowing what it
is you're trying to protect knowing that
you have to do certain things knowing
that there is no such thing as ultimate
security and so on and so forth we have
a few minutes left does anybody have any
questions this is your chance to
communicate you have you must have come
in late you have to ask me that after
you've purchased me an alcoholic
beverage I'm a rap by Jedi mind trick is
button buy me alcohol buy me alcohol and
I last note any other questions comments
you you that were older that's all the
original Star Wars agree disagree we're
good
sure
hmm
so the comment is if you want to get
some opportunities to practice join your
Toastmasters club local Toastmasters
club look it up find one see if there is
one my immediate question is what is a
Toastmasters club
so it's a group that gets together and
tries to practice communication it
almost sounds like there's a little bit
of improv in there okay very good great
if any of you guys happen to be more on
the East Coast later in june I'm
actually putting together a training
course to try to actually put some of
these techniques into practice to try to
give the opportunity to teach a little
bit some of these communication skills
but more importantly than teaching I
want to give people the opportunity to
put it into practice in a safe
comfortable environment I should look up
toastmasters and and steal their mojo
anyway that'll be at Circle City con in
indianapolis in june that's it thank
you