- slightly start over art Mannion cert
Coordination Center we are sir Torg
we're one of the possibly the first
c-cert ever I lived on the planet Earth
EML University software Deering
Institute was a long long long number of
things I have to say that get it all
correct I work for the I manage the
vulnerability analysis team assert we
deal with software vulnerabilities all
the time we're software vulnerability
nerds talking after Pete there's a piece
of risk that software vulnerabilities
that's the piece I focus on that's
actually a lot of what this talk is
about keep in mind that if a piece of
risk and that's one of my complaints
with CB SS I'm going to going to be
getting into today roughly two parts of
this talk
people use CBS s based scores I'm going
to claim that they are horribly wrong
and should not use them I'm going to do
that with a bit of you know a bit of
concern I'm involved in the CBS s
development group I'm in the sig I've
been working on it for quite some time
so I feel bad complaining about it but
I'm going to and my justification is I'm
trying to help at the same time so not
just complaining I'm complaining and
trying to make things better I'm gonna
have to apologize to that group probably
tomorrow though
so right trying to make it better okay
I'm old enough to have seen this movie
in junior high whom you might be as well
it wasn't particularly good but for some
reason when I were the CFP for this the
the thing popped into my head the
identity crisis theme from the movie is
actually a little bit relevant cbss
people want to know we want to make a
better risk decision right I got a bunch
of vulnerabilities that's part of my
risk equation which ones do I worry
about sooner or later first second how
bad are they going to be it'd be great
if that were free information from a
reliable source
like NIST and VB what we get though from
cbss base is sort of the immediate
direct proximate impact and severity of
the vulnerability and you get numbers
and that number is nice because it
reduces complexity to a number it's also
bad because humans see a number and then
they're like hey it's seven and stop
thinking about sort of what went into
that
you've just decided and made your
decision at that point to be to be fair
some vendors are providing some temporal
environment scores which we'll get into
in a minute so it's not always just the
horrible bass I've got a cool thing here
see I put CBS s logo and freebase scores
from NIST NBD great good enough I've got
numbers I've got data I'm going with
that no reason to think much harder
about it
our folks familiar with CBS s generally
is anybody horribly not okay
brief history around 2004 it probably
started some folks from Cisco were kind
of behind the individuals behind a lot
of the original work transition to first
version two and 20 2007 version three
fairly recently is out I don't like
version three I'll get into that most
the developments for CBS s has been
large kind of Enterprise commercial
software vendors who get their
vulnerabilities are scored with CBS s so
they clearly have a care about how
they're how they're scored vulnerability
management and scan some scanning
vendors and some vol database people
start included OS B DB is now for the
risk-based security is valen DB nvd
folks are involved this folks are
involved they're a very quick overview
there are three groups of vectors
there's the base group which is about
the vulnerability inherent
characteristic characteristics of the
vulnerability some portal metric is
trying to measure sort of threat what
has changed over time
exploitation up or down patch
availability up or down confidence and
them in the report and environmental is
you know we all have the same we're all
affected by the same flash vulnerability
but your environment is different than
mine environmental is trying to measure
that it got much worse than v3 so
severity is you know I'm some using some
dictionary terms here to try to sort
this out of this severity is sort of the
intensity the seriousness of something
and bone severity of a vulnerability is
not severity or risk they are not the
same thing
very important priorities what you do
first or second and risk but you know
and also say much since peaches talked
but there's a risk equation I use lost
instead of impact here but when I think
about sort of the risk factors what are
the biggest of those three terms I'm a
vulnerability interest I think about
vulnerabilities all the time I would
suggest loss maybe threat are the
biggest the most sort of influential
terms in that equation if no one's
attacking you do whatever you want
you're fine right if you have nothing to
lose you've got very little little risk
you might put threat first in our in our
space with loss you know and the idea
that the catastrophic loss could put you
completely out of business cost lives
cause physical damage so that's the
higher factor in my mind the least
influential factor min there I think is
probably vulnerability and yet that's
what you're getting with CBS s base
course you get CBS s base CBS s temporal
is about threat a little bit but it got
worse it's not it's not good I'll say I
call it broken and environmental went
away with v3 so we're not not doing well
this is my one I think second good meme
i right around the holiday break when I
saw the the the CFP for this talk come
out I think I've been on a CBS s call
probably the day before I was still mad
24 hours later from that phone call and
this was the what else popped into my
head we were this happens in standards
element right you your narrow you're
focused on the four on the the trees the
small part of the problem we're talking
in circles about backwards compatibility
all these things and completely avoid
the big picture discussion which is what
what really kind of matters and what
were what we're missing target
distribution right how many things are
in my environment that were vulnerable
or how many users are affected by this
thing I'm going to say critical
environmental metric gone in Version
three
I complained a little bit but you know
that's that's what happened CBS s takes
the vectors and turns them into a number
and there's some math the way this
was developed is the experts scored a
bunch of vulnerability expert system
that's fine sort of ranked them and just
in severity and that's generally okay
had some smart folks much smarter than
me figure out some math that would make
the computation sort of match what the
experts did that's that's sort of all
okay but you get some really weird
weights in there just kind of make
things fit what I'm going to pick on is
you know the do 0.94 shouldn't that have
been zero point nine three zero point
nine five doesn't matter in the least
this precision I'm going to suggest is
just not not necessary in fact it's kind
of a guess and it's kind of the shoehorn
math into reality and not a great not a
great plan I think I've sorted this out
but it seemed as if there was an
expected distribution that CBS s scores
should be should be a normal
distribution or should be evenly
distributed and that if you don't know
what you're what they what real vaults
have already looks like you can't really
make up a to make up the numbers to fit
it scope change in Version three
there's a reason for this the idea is I
attack something and I get access to
something else or I impact something
else fine in theory the examples are
cross-site scripting I exploit a
vulnerability on a web page but the user
on targeting is who you know their
browser gets attacked VM escape is maybe
a little more direct example there were
issues version two assumes the operating
system is the is the only thing you're
after Oracle for instance had a great
complaint about this an Oracle database
on an operating system if I can own the
database who cares about the operating
system oh I didn't get root Oh fine I
have all of your database so it doesn't
really matter CBS SB two didn't cover
that well scope is an attempt to do that
it's difficult it's awkward is hard to
explain and the real question I haven't
looked at this yet is does that does
that scope metric and the value it
brings that that mean anything to the
overall decision in the first place I
think it's too soon to tell we'd
probably have some more data to figure
that out I talked about threat being
broken exploit code maturity the weight
the
the value for the metric of high so if
there's a worm going around autonomous
code lots of exploitation it's a 1.0 if
you don't know what the exploit activity
is it's also a 1.0 so this is inverted
in my mind if every vulnerability was
exploited heavily I'm sure this would
make sense there are how many how many
vulnerabilities publicly disclosed in a
year anybody know anybody counting want
to guess somebody guess how many yeah
twelve fourteen did you say I say
fourteen because risk-based security
council 14 which is higher than CVE and
nvd in case you're counting and it
matters to you does anybody you know so
yes this is this is this is conservative
so that's fine right I don't know I will
assume the worst-case scenario
the problem is you have fourteen
thousand year you assume the worst case
scenario on all of them we certainly do
not because I'm not running around you
know we worry about 100 a year tens
doesn't really really worry about them
we don't worry about the PHP Gulf it's a
ten or any of those things right so
another issue in this happens of all
standards development is sort of the
backwards compatibility discussion but
this this is just backwards to me dan
Guido I think it's now in CC group has a
presentation from several years ago
about exploit intelligence basically he
takes vulnerabilities for 2010 or
something and he says if you didn't have
you couldn't patch but you you know
block flash and turned off Java and did
a couple of things you block all the
exploit activity for the year without
patching anything and he's got you know
pretty good logic on that there's a
couple of papers by a couple of Italian
guys alodia and Misaki spelled that
wrong who basically they're they look at
sort of conceived ESS predicts exploit
activity for anything and the answer is
generally no and furthermore they go on
to say you know if you if you actually
had a policy that said cbss hi
I patch within you know ten days or
three days or five days you're investing
badly because you're patching a bunch of
stuff that is not being attacked it is
not that severe so it can't predict it
can't predict attacks very well there's
like there's a current sort of
discussion going on where you've got
different platforms and it's hard for
CBS s to sort of be scored pearl per
platform basis
the v3 way it deals with environmental
scores might help here because
environmental in v3 is just the base
scores run for a different sort of
environment but it was not not well
resolved yet what I want to stop for a
minute on is the pivot pointer right
anyway the exploit code maturity and the
non predicting of attacks they can't
actually can't predict a negative either
it can't predict it it won't be attacked
so you get no information either
direction out of it this is basically
the slide that supports me of my claim
that the threat part of it is just
worthless it's just broken completely
yes
so they're there their papers look at
they missed the NIST NPD scores so it's
base only which is it's lacking the
temporal which might be a lack of data
because no one's known as providing
those in bulk and they didn't go to
score them by hand or do anything like
that so there may be a data problem
there so they did one of the things I
would like to do search scores full
environmental but not for very many
vulnerabilities we score based and
portal and environment I would love to
do their analysis on the full scores
that might address the one question
about is there data missing but from
what they found they were just through
complete misses doesn't doesn't
correlate anything doesn't predict
anything Bad's bad sensitivity bad
specificity just almost almost nothing
yes sorry Oh anyone knows this want to
pop your head for mobility nerds tve yep
heartbleed yes this is a little bit
cheating but I'm going to it does
illustrate some CBS s issues the base
score is a five the immediate direct
impact right the proximate impact is I
can leak bits of information I have a
partial confidentiality breach right
okay real-world risk right I can read
your secret TLS keys and then personate
your website and sign things and break
crypto so it's horrible the full score
in version two if i dial all dials the
best I could without cheating I got it
to the six point four and that's by
claiming that the confidentiality and
integrity requirements of open SSL a
crypto library are high it should always
be web trusting it to be confident in
integrity integrity and when it's not
the bad bad bad failure so I could sort
you can sort of tweak it with
environmental v3 help with this instead
of partial and complete for the impact
scores they went with a high medium low
none I think so you can say hi and
basically accommodate a horribly like
case
so I'd mention this but I'll make it
more clear make it more make it a more
clear point at cert we don't publish
every vulnerability we don't keep up
with nvd or the bolan databases I looked
this is a twenty twenty twelve thirteen
fourteen CVEs that cert published and
NBD published and we we do our analysts
do a full environmental score with CBS
SB too so this distribution on the left
is actually 80 thousand CBS s base
scores and you get let's see high as
blue so you get a third high a bunch of
medium and a small amount of low right
for the for the sample set I use the
2012 2013 2014 vulnerabilities in DD
base looks like this so not not much not
not dissimilar and the cert base looks
like this so you know certain is not
scoring the same as nvd we usually make
mistakes and they taught us the
corrective and we try to do better but
we're not scoring exactly the same way
here so these are this is base only
distributions and they're pretty whether
you cover everything or a sample set
they look similar when you add the
temporal score in it changes like this
and you add full environmental for v2 it
looks like this so you know nth high
that feels about right I don't run
around worrying what every vulnerability
I see every day fourteen thousand a year
I'm a how many day that is but it's a
lot of day right so this is my picture
version of real-world distribution what
you get with CBS s base and again the
the real issue here is the misuse of CBS
s base for something that's not able to
give you it's not the CBS s is
inherently completely wrong or broken
although a couple places it could be
better it's the it's the missed the
presumptive misuse of it that I'm truly
trying to to complain about here so all
that complaining can can we do any
better so what are we trying to do this
is conference about defense I'm going to
do vulnerability information because
that's what I know for defense we want
to make a better risk decision right do
i patch do i get insurance do I buy and
add-on products do I
stop using something right am I going to
get hip and I sort of mentioned earlier
that the risk factors the the importance
of risk factors threat and loss are much
higher than vulnerability I think and I
think day to day I feel like threats the
most kind of important meaningful one so
am I getting hit by something other
people getting hit by it my neighbors
are getting hit it's probably coming my
way right how bad is it going to be when
it gets me this is my loss and the
narrow impact the the heartbleed leaking
information is in isn't it that's fun
for vulnerability a nerd like me trying
to catalog and keep track of things but
that's not as interesting as the overall
sort of problem right open SSL is
everywhere target distribution count
that and be you know the second order
consequences it gets your breaks or TLS
everywhere CVS base provides the things
you don't need that much the approximate
severity and the proximate impact of the
vulnerability InfoSec right we have we
have missing an incomplete information
all the time colleague of mine Capetown
stumble across a couple of cool acronyms
a week or two ago those folks of heard
these yet but the second one I really
like those words volatility uncertainty
complexity and ambiguity if you stop and
think about it or go read the paper
they're they're distinct problems
information right it's a kind of a way
to break down the world we try to make
decisions in here so we're making risk
decisions with with uncertainty big time
and the suggestion is and even if this
goes even beyond what CVS is trying to
do find smaller questions that require
you to gather less information or less
precise information focus on the things
that are the higher the higher influence
on your equation so threat and loss and
if information is not helping you don't
spend any energy dollars money time
trying to get it even though it's
available it's not helping you don't use
it so I'm going to run through a handful
of none of these are solutions by any
means but these are ideas that that I
have noticed or had or assert has looked
at over the years to try to do the
sort of heuristic you know functional
but not super precise not very detailed
not very costly vulnerability severity
or risk severity sort of estimates one
concept is triage if you ever work in a
few working socks or you know handle
incidents handle cases you've probably
familiar with this term in the opinion
in post-second World cases come in they
get a first pass and you can classify
things very quickly this is actually
stolen from sort of health and I think
around World War one it became sort of
popular well popular to triode to to
classify wounded folks the idea was you
know this person with attention could be
saved this person's a goner and this
person can has a broken leg and can wait
so it's classifying very important
things for a very high priority next
very next step the thing that certainly
that normally does what I recommend in
general is you do a triage pass with
what's coming in first and you do a
second pass for severity later on when
you have more information right depends
all the triage you might want to do
something else either waiting for
someone else to come up with information
you can use or spending time finding it
yourself can give you a better decision
after you've made the first sort of
classification folks are familiar with
plus CI a confidentiality integrity
availability was a guy named Don Parker
with two N's who adds three more to this
interesting if I like to say par caring
and hex-head but also you know we're
focused on CI a a lot this thinks about
some other some other effect other sort
of vectors that might play into impact
or severity possession is I've stolen a
laptop I may not take anything off it
yet there might be encrypted but I don't
have the laptop anymore so it's out of
my possession utility a little bit as
well I can't use something I don't have
in my hands anymore or if my security
broke the thing I lock myself out
I have a loss you know I have I have a
loss there but it's not that someone
stole the data it's just that I can now
can't get it because I tried to be to
secure authenticity I have to keep
reading why that's not the same as
integrity when I go read the page on on
part area next ad but again the idea
being you don't have to be
stuck with CIA if that's not sufficient
for your needs another medical another
steal from medical world our focus with
the Apgar score okay there's a woman
named Virginia Apgar a doctor who came
up with this score it's basically sort
of triage a newborn is scored on as a
backronym for what they're looking at
and her name appearance pulse grimace
response to being poked activity and how
they're breathing and this is done
immediately at first and it's done
usually five minutes later and sometimes
other intervals and typically the baby
gets better and that's a good sign again
this is sort of a triage it's meant to
catch catch problems early
if the Apgar score doesn't improve you
know you've got a problem so yeah no
reason to reinvent it we'll just steal
this and make one for vulnerability
severity this was a point in time at
which these are some of the things
certain thought we cared about in our
sort of Apgar our decision was whether
to accept the case for coordination or
not a bunch of people asked us for help
disclosing we do not take all the
requests because we're small and can't
afford all of them sorry to give a
question or were you waving me down five
minutes okay all right yeah kind of
kinds of things we worry about when
we're deciding whatever take on a case
you can make up your own at plus one
plus two minus one a couple of little
numbers add them up and you'll get
something the Microsoft exploitability
index specifically they say it's right
on the page they're providing additional
information to help you evaluate your
risk and they're providing their guests
as the likelihood of being exploited so
they're telling you threat probability
right for the whatever bulletin just
came out and that you're worried about
it's not your whole risk assessment but
it's threat information and it's just
that doesn't need to be super precise
they have four categories and one is you
know one is 100% yes one's 100% or sorry
one is yes it's being exploited were
proven and the rest sort of back off
from there that's the level of
granularity that probably you'd need to
do anything useful
some years ago I spent some work that a
project at search that we
all this vulnerability response
decisions assistance I used to call it
an expert system or decision support
system in reading about those two things
there's a difference I don't quite
understand what the difference is don't
particularly care the issue for this
project was that it required a lot of
upfront time someone someone choosing to
use it had to decide what actions they
wanted to take just wants to give you a
score this tells you that you should or
should not publish an advisory should or
should not patch should or should not
insert the case you know except except
for coordination or not or perform
certain activity or perform a certain
publication so you have to tell it in
advance what you would put your what
your actions might be and you have to
train it it's training ahead of time so
it's the next expert engine you have to
put in the training data have experts
put down the answers and then spin the
thing up and let it run this shaded area
means that the the machines guess was
off by you know zero or one from the
human analyst said so we are trying to
reproduce human experts here in a
computer got reasonably close but those
concepts might be something useful the
system we built is not around and was
probably over overly cantankerous but
the ideas are still something you might
want to consider another option for CBS
s this is distribution of the base score
counts so there's a whole lot of 7.5 the
whole lot of 4.3 is cross-site scripting
I'm pretty sure I'm not sure what five
turns out to be it might be local local
privilege escalation 7.5 is if you do a
Kuwait that's here 7.5 is probably on it
on an authenticated remote access but
only partial like a user compromised
remotely 4.3 is cross-site scripting so
I don't know the best way to bucket this
but instead of having the math on CBS s
it might be sufficient to map
combinations of vectors to the high
medium low directly or to some specific
thing you're looking for and kind of do
away with the fancy math part of it so
and then small to finish up about two
more
pointers here CW not v s/s from lighter
because it starts with C and ends in
three or four letters in it I have to
imagine that that that mitre and
probably Steve Christie didn't like T vs
s when it started and what literally
went off and wrote their own I think
that's actually what happened
Steve Christie things on this so I'm
allowed to allowed to say that time
there's the CW CW SS it looks a lot like
CBS s if you squint right three
different vectors combined to a score of
scores from 0 to 100 as weights and
values like CBS s it's kind of like
Betamax and VHS nobody looked at this
and it didn't didn't quite make it on my
list so many things to do is evaluate
this compared with CBS s scores have not
done it but it exists you take a look at
it
minor went one step further and does
this thing common weakness risk analysis
framework the acronym is unpronounceable
C wrath basically based on this picture
I can tell you it's too much trouble and
it's just too it's too complicated right
14000 year you don't need to run this on
all of them right
anyway quick summary CBS s has issues
based scores particularly have issues
horrible threat information horrible
environment information and those are
the two things that are your more
important in your risk decision than
what you do get from CBS s base a
handful of things to sort of help if you
point people in a better direction no
answers but those are the ways to think
about it smaller questions more
heuristic bugging a lot of information
low precision is okay but something and
maybe something you can repeat over time
and then measure yourself okay questions
more questions
yes sir for something that is too
expensive to go pick and if we have the
resources which it should take off the
line and throw away
thank you having to medical gas so I
think I may not be an answer to me stop
using them saying you know take it down
that should be a consideration I don't
know is that something you want the
triage analyst doing is probably like a
corporate mule organizational decision
that job is absolutely an answer
he has slide that said removing his
house removing courts removing devices
those risks yes over there so you're
absolutely perineum Texas non-agenda
some major busy man oh gee about 30
years ago and my argument ahem was that
this three additional elements were in
fact sub elements of the existing triad
and that as we had more complexities to
our analysis of whatever aspect of
network security
we're in everything does fit inside of
additional layers triad versus grid and
hex atom which is basically unstable
when it scaled that and I'd like your
comments on that as to whether I'm full
of or here its history and history
would indicate that CI a pretty good
because a lot of people use that and you
have to go hunt for are carrying X ads
to find out so nation nature may have
chosen CIA I mean I just said this I can
I cannot I cannot differentiate
integrity and authenticity well without
reading carefully convincing myself for
five minutes and then forgetting again
and why there why they're different you
know possession and utilities seem
pretty similar so I I will say I don't
personally put a lot of value in the
three extra ones you could usually argue
that they're they're already covered
pretty well and they might be good
enough my point in showing this is in
case you're feeling strained by CIA we
don't know the are moving so to the
consuming shock to that next step and
great verses that - let me clearly state
that that's important it's also backed
off by containing a little bit the idea
what CB SS is the person scoring base
vendor who knows the vulnerabilities of
all database or NIST notice that part of
the information they put the analysis
they can give you a decent score for
that and it's fine for that my complaint
is that one of my complaints is that
users go and built through the other
steps they don't add some foreign
environment helps you go out to use the
base and take some action I'm warning
everyone not to do that you're way off
base if you do that hey three numbers
I'm good no no no no no three input do
something else and then you're good to
do something else part really important
I think has it people just skip that
entirely
um there's that part I do a beef about
exploit maturity being inverted and I do
have beef about target distribution I
think environment the environment
measurements got worse than three I
think it just did I tried some exercise
to score be three I couldn't change my
environmental support I require changing
the base
very very smart phones yes absolutely
that's it that's that's point number one
yeah absolutely okay thank you
[Applause]