okay getting an early start on this I
guess so good morning um I know that the
title of this talk is a little bit of a
mouthful a lot of this is going to be
about why this is important as much as
what this means to say in many parts
how can it be concise what do we mean by
concise in this context and what is more
complex than deterministic context-free
and why does that matter are all
questions that I hope to answer and so
if you've been following at all the
research that's been coming out of out
of language theoretic security which is
an initiative that was largely
spearheaded by Sergey Broadus emeritus
Patterson Lenz Assen and several others
you might have noticed that earlier this
year we published a taxonomy of
essentially root causes of parser
vulnerability so we took a little bit of
beef with with existing sort of cwe's
around around how we deal with broken
parsers and applications this is
gathered mostly from existing research
in the area and is essentially just a
systemization of previous papers all of
which are available at Lane tech org
um the one that I've highlighted today
is actually the one that's given us the
most pushback and so I thought that I'd
take the opportunity to explain on the
record exactly what it is that we mean
by this why it's important why it can be
done um it follows very closely as I
mentioned in a previous talk on this
very very very few parser
vulnerabilities actually fall into just
one of these categories most of them
have multiple connotations and in
particular this concept of an input
language being greater than
deterministic context-free is very much
associated with shotgun parsers so again
if you've been following our research it
will become readily apparent why this as
well as that are critical oh why exactly
do we want deterministic context-free
well deterministic context-free is a
class of languages it kind of falls in
between on the Chomsky hierarchy it's
right below context-free it simply means
a context-free grammar that you can can
parse and generate deterministically um
this particular class of languages is
the most powerful class of languages for
which we can solve a number of problems
general equivalence is one of the main
ones here which means that you can tell
that two parsers or in fact more
formally two grammars but in effect in
practice two parsers are equivalent for
any any of these classes of languages
another point is that there decidable
which means that in a finite amount of
time or at least a known amount of time
we can figure out whether a giving
string is in the language and valid or
out of the language and not valid and
then the third point which is what I'm
going to cover today which is that they
are actually sufficiently complex for
general use and if you go any higher
than this and you end up with more
complex languages which I'll get into in
a little bit then it becomes impossible
to decide especially decidability in
general equivalents and we find that on
the whole these tend to be the locus of
bugs now it's important to remember as
well that this refers to the language
that defines your protocol your data
interchange format between various files
this is absolutely nothing to do with
what language you program in of course
nobody is advocating that you use non
turing-complete programming languages
for general-purpose programming that
would just be C and it wouldn't help
this is mostly about making sure that we
don't have a lot of purser bugs and this
is actually really important I'm sorry
to recap so much but we did a short
survey of OpenSSL bugs in the preceding
year or so before we published our last
paper and we found that the over 2/3 of
them were actually parser bugs and not
cryptography bugs and we wondered surely
there must be something that we can do
to see to it that the locust of bugs and
the project is actually things that are
related in some way to what it's trying
to accomplish not ancillary things for
which there are general-purpose
methodologies so what we proposed is a
software engineering methodology that
allows us to prevent these sorts of
vulnerabilities from occurring in the
first place and what I mean again the
thing that has been most contentious and
difficult to implement is this concept
of deterministic context-free because
simply not a lot of people understand
why that is and it's important that for
a piece of security to be usable it be
understood both by security
practitioners and by developers exactly
how you implement
um so in any event this is what we think
of as a deterministic context-free
language from the practitioners
standpoint from an academic standpoint
it's very different but it does
essentially reduce to these things um
essentially the key feature that we're
looking for is that validity of a
protocol message is only ever determined
based on based on a context that's
established along some nested hierarchy
what this means is that you can't say
well parse the whole document and then
correlate these two pieces within the
document that do not nest and then see
that they match up for your validity you
can't do that it turns out that when you
do that it becomes impossible to prove
those parsers you'll just have to
believe me this is only a half hour talk
um it also means languages that we could
process with the deterministic pushdown
automaton which is another one of those
annoying formalisms what that means is a
given a finite amount of state and a
stack that is potentially unbounded
although no real stack is given those
two things you can parse this protocol
and you don't have potentially an
infinite accretion of state that you
might assemble that can't be put onto a
stack and popped off orderly it means a
language that is similar in complexity
to matching balanced friends but but no
more complex than this so for example
XML tags as long as those XML tags are
properly nested and don't have cross
references and external entities and
weird imports of document type data and
maybe XML is a bad example that
certainly JSON JSON does tend to follow
this I'll get into a little bit more why
that's not enough but these are the
features that we look at also it happens
that DNS and associated associated
grammars BBN F and a DNS also tend to
generate languages that fall within this
class so if your protocol can be
specified that way as in with an RFC
you're fairly close one of the things
that I'd like to highlight there as well
before I continue is that a lot of the
times when we do specify protocols using
a formal structure like a B NS we tend
to include little you know angle
bracketed remarks in there that say
check some of that it turns out that
this is okay and that's that's one of
the things I'll be following in the
coming slides
so should recap again why this is
important
previously I just did a search for four
bugs that had to do with with cycles
unbounded cycles unbounded recursion in
protocol parsing we found these it also
happens that the hijacking of the
etherium dowel falls into this there are
many bugs and the one thing that all of
these bugs that are cited in this way
have in common is that the structures
let that what you'll see there it's
possible to generate a document in which
there is sure some overarching elements
but within it there are three
non-hierarchical elements which which
cycle in this way and things will happen
like for example adobe PDF parser will
happily try to generate an infinite
index simply because something refers to
its current which thread again refers to
its child and it just keeps going back
and forth so it is this this structure
that is responsible for listing our
protocol away from at worst
deterministic context-free into at best
context-sensitive which is one level
above in the Chomsky hierarchy and all
of the formalisms around proving that
the parsing of it will ever terminates
or can be determined valid or not or can
be equivalent to go out the window you
simply can't do them so we proposed in
language theoretic security that this
listing is kind of a problem in much the
same way that one of these thunderstorms
will flip an airplane over if it's all
these sorts of things will tend to cause
your program to crash so we wonder as
well with respect to language theoretic
security why it is that there are so
many bugs in software well know you I
see a lot of grimacing no it's simply
not the case it's not because
programmers are careless it's not
because they're foolish it's because
more often than not the specification
that they're trying to implement sets
them up for failure because it's things
like too ambiguous or too complicated
and it has these problems where it's not
amenable to formal verifiability
and it's also not amenable to mechanical
verifiability of the type that we hope
in the future will be provided by static
code analysis tools which is why we're
proposing this as a cwe and
we also wonder also the previous
examples that I cited a couple of slides
ago were all about denial of service
attacks it's not just about denial of
service attacks I'll mention again the
etherium Gao hijacking the example
whereby general recursion in a known
turing-complete smart contract language
was essentially used to steal all of the
money out of mysterium blockchain
contract structure without any computer
system being able to see that this was
going to happen or any human really
being able to anticipate this in a
general sense it was bound to happen
eventually we also saw in many many many
papers published weird machines a weird
machine is a term that I believe Sergey
broadest coined which which has to do
with kind of an unintentional structure
of computation that exists within a
program tend to have a hand-in-hand sort
of relationship with exploits um so what
we're trying to do with respect to this
recommendation of keeping your parsers
to know more complex than deterministic
context-free is to minimize parser
complexity we're taking the Turing
machine away because we don't want to
give the attacker a Turing machine and
our parser is our first line of defense
again with respect to avoiding shotgun
parsers it means that we have a very
discrete boundary in comes the input and
if the input is untoward the parser says
no pasaran we're just going to reject
this so it's a tall order reducing the
complexity of our input languages is
something that has it's a very strong
counter currents to what we spent most
of the night he is doing when we started
introducing a lot of active content like
flash and like Adobe Acrobat and like
JavaScript immediately we found that our
content became a lot more rich there was
a whole world of things that we could do
with with XML and DT DS and infinite
extensibility of x.509 and all of this
stuff but we find that now that we've
developed our engineering practice more
and more there's a common kernel of
things that we tend to see occur over
and over and over again in protocols
that we definitely need to do and then
there's all of these other things that
represent huge complexity and have in
the past led to vulnerability which is
why I chose the examples that I just
chose of how it is that we kept lifting
ourselves above this
um people ask me this a lot ultimately
the answer is well kind of we have a lot
of walking back to do and this is just
one part of that and I hope that in the
future people will propose new new
protocols that follow this
recommendation and avoid that type of
complexity avoid general-purpose
computing that you can just kind of
voiced on other people before they can
tell whether it's right to do it or not
so of course these notions on you see
here the postel principle all kinds of
other things we we have to be careful to
ensure that although we can't get rid of
them today
we don't perpetuate these problems a
Bigfoot is this abstraction and
dependency injection are another one I'd
like to specifically call out because
they generally lift Yuja turing
completeness um so yeah like these these
things have continuously been problems
and they will continue to be problems
until we solve the specific problem and
this thing where the input language is
above deterministic context-free is
actually a common recurring theme in all
of them um I already went through that
example but essentially again if we
don't do this it won't be amenable to
computational solutions um so here's the
standard of proof for whether we can
tell if an input language is safe based
on this criterion alone remembering that
there are six others in the previous
work um that all of the idioms that are
within it are within deterministic
context-free and that there is closure
under under the accretion of these
idioms into the protocols so the way
that they're used doesn't end up
creating some kind of implicit cross
reference or something that would look
the language the idiomatic field should
simplify that proof may occur only once
in the context and the data upon which
it relates to for validity is within DCF
so in other words if it does not in and
of itself create those patterns that we
cited in one of the previous slides and
it can be computed by a finite state
machine that has a stack then we're all
right to use it so let's not briefly see
if there are a few things that we can
find within deterministic context-free I
promise that I'll keep this short these
are essentially proofs but I've
try to make them comprehensible without
too much formalism so the first one that
I would like to point out is protocol
state protocol state is something that
we run into a lot almost every protocol
has state and we wonder well it's very
hard to read a regular expression or
it's very hard to write DNS that gives
the protocol state but we can do a spec
proof here to show that in fact protocol
state is perfectly acceptable and
retains your access to the tooling that
we can develop around these types of
simple protocol um so we let P be a
stateful protocol we include the the
context that it sits in context tree is
in this respect a little bit of a
misnomer it simply means the context is
only hard call not that there is no
context at all
so we can take this this context in
which the packet is being parsed and
treated as though it we're in
encapsulating element um then we can
simply do this we can say we'll draw up
a state machine using our existing
protocol 15 from these previous states s
and then we'll simply add the the
validity of the message to this we'll
construct a new state machine that that
essentially adds arrows to a reject
state for all of the messages that are
not valid given our current server state
and there we have it we've just shown by
construction that it happens that this
is just me citing exactly how you do
that construction draw those arrows in a
formal way we can see that having a
protocol state alone isn't enough to
lift the language above even potentially
regular it is just a finite state
automaton because the protocol state
machine is a finite state automaton if
it's not then unfortunately this doesn't
work it's important to note that this
didn't even change our actual protocol
specification there is a large family of
protocols that do not need to be revised
with respect to this recommendation we
need to only zero in on those particular
things that would list the language so
if for example the protocol state
machine were able to force you to look
back an arbitrary number of packets to
see previously whether your current
element is valid rather than
to keep that protocol state finite
within the machine and it didn't allow
you to put that into a stack like thing
rather it intended that you keep on the
infinite lengthy index then it would not
work and we would hypothesize that that
would be a locust of bugs um we see as
well with respect to authorization um
this is my next example by the way
authorization is not specifically
guaranteed to be deterministic
context-free and in fact I have a number
of examples where non deterministic
context-free authorization has resulted
in authorization by parties these
examples are Android master key and PKI
layer-cake both of them very different
in the interest of time I'll only
discuss Android master key if you recall
this was a vulnerability whereby an
Android app is essentially a zip file
and it contains a manifest there were
two different parsers um one of them
looked aside in one direction forward to
the first manifest and the other one
looked in direction to the second
manifest the two parsers had two
different functions the first one
essentially was to determine whether the
manifest was valid and the second one to
determine whether the package matched
the manifest so the attacker could
tribulus simply generates or take a
valid manifest tack it on to the front
and then make a new invalid Lee sign to
manifest that actually correspond to
what was in the jar jacket onto the back
and it would validate does this
structure sound a little bit familiar
because yeah um so if we ensure that our
authorization to follow certain
properties we can avoid this type of
problem from an engineering perspective
and it just won't happen again a little
bit of formalism here
I feel free to read along but
essentially what I'm saying here is that
if we ensure that the authorization
fields that that convey the proof of
authorization are in some way in a
hierarchical relationship with an
unambiguous hierarchical relationship
with the thing that they are authorizing
then there can be no potential for
confusion this is an exercise and
explicitly specifying what it is to
which this authorization applies and
seeing to it that this authorization is
the
specifically associated with the thing
to which it applies um because again if
you have those cross references you
can't really show what's going on so
this is also going to come up when I
talk about checksums later on the third
one that I see most often is is an
objection to length fields and people
say well how on earth do I construct a
finite state automaton or a stack
machine that deals with myleik fields
this it turns out is not too terribly
difficult on there's a device that we
use in proving these things out called
unary or with meticulous tat le you know
five one uses five um that might begin
to looked a little bit to you like
matching balanced prints um when we
match balanced parens essentially what
we're doing is we're creating a stack we
push the paren onto the stack when we
see an open paren when we see a closed
paren we pop it off the stack and see if
it's the same if it's not saying we
reject if we reach the end of the in
putting the stack is empty then then we
accept the message and that is just a
formal way of matching brackets no
actual computer would do this you would
use counts but nonetheless that's how we
do these proofs um
so matching balanced friends in unary or
Kentucky it turns out is exactly the
same as matching matching characters in
a message to a unary tally established
by the link field so as long as we see
that the length field is in a
hierarchical relationship with the thing
to which it applies then we can validate
the packet this it turns out is one way
that we could do something like avoid
heartbleed you might recall that hurt
lead was essentially a light field
validation attack problem if there had
been a parser somewhere in the beginning
that had said I'm going to now keep a
tally and see that I get as many things
out of this message as it claims that it
has in it we wouldn't have had the
problem in the first place it would have
said no peso Don you're gone by um so
we've just done by the way a proof by
reduction here we've shown formally
without doing really a lot of mass at
all that it happens that links fields
are within our death
deterministic context for a TV you might
as I mentioned want to implement the
stack is an unbounded counter or better
still you might want to be very explicit
about your specification inbound the
counter this is an interesting point
because no actual machine really is able
to implement a full pushdown automaton
lacking infinite stacked it's simply
impossible I'm a very common bug that
I've seen unfortunately I don't have a
reference for it handy is one whereby a
language will fail to specify that a
given length is signed or unsigned at
64-bit or we're still it will demand
that that the length field be up to you
864 max this is kind of a nightmare for
Java programmers because they have a
bound to sign 64-bit integers and when
you have that problem a lot of people
take shortcuts so you can see how this
also ties into the needs to couple it
with an explicit specification of the
language for you to really gain the
benefit of it but both of these things
are required you must also do that and
then bugs like heart leads will be a
thing of the past on the most
complicated example that I have of this
is checksum digesting signatures and
this is where I look again I mentioned
when were specifying protocols in RFC
adnf usually we just say signature goes
here don't worry about it in the context
of this formal description of the
language well that's all well and good I
don't especially want to draw up a
regular expression that validates is the
correct md5 sum of what preceded it
either I'm technically it's possible to
generate a regular expression that does
very simple things though like for
example one that matches divisibility by
an arbitrary natural number for all
members of radix are that is to say if
you told me
give me a regular expression that
matches all binary numbers that are
divisible by 7 I can actually draw that
and I'll get into the reason that that's
also in a little bit rather than boring
you with the regular expression it's
actually miles long but it does work I'm
the characteristics that we're looking
for here in this proof
are simply v6 it has bounded computation
time so we know it'll terminate and this
means that it's it's not got a rice
theorem baste proof of Turing
completeness it means that it's we look
for the fact that it's guaranteed to be
both complete and either right or wrong
this again means that it's decidable so
we see that anything that is undecidable
cannot all looking the definition of
deterministic context-free happily
that's why we chose it we see that it
can depend entirely and only on specific
input that means that it has that
hierarchical relationship that I was
talking about before simply the fact
that it's tacked on to the end or maybe
it's somewhere in the middle but for
purposes of computation replaced with
all zeros as long as this process is
fully deterministic and fully decides in
advance to what it is going to apply
we're actually fine to use it and so
again doesn't care about input semantics
is basically the same thing constant
output length simply means that it will
be within regular if it had an unbounded
output length then it could be at best
context for you simply because it would
not have bounded state and then composed
of mathematical operations in finite
fields which is what I was just
mentioning with the whole you know
divisibility by five the way that we
construct that finite state automaton is
basically by creating a machine that add
by adding and shifting computes the
modulus continuously of whatever input
it gets and so if we bound ourselves to
things that are conclusive mathematical
operations in finite fields which is
basically that we can show that they can
also be implemented by regular
expression we just don't want to
implement them by regular expression
it's seriously enough to show that it
can be implemented with a regular
expression so since we have this we can
actually do math in our programs right
we can as long as we keep ourselves to
cyclic arithmetic like that to
arithmetic in finite field we don't need
to go beyond regular which is one level
below deterministic context-free as long
as the computation looks like this
we're flying we also don't need to to go
and specify details BNF representations
is exactly how you compute an md5
in a description of the md5 algorithm
that follows these six characteristics
is enough um so what this means is in
conclusion
most of the idioms that you actually use
them need that don't generate those
structures those cyclic structures that
I was talking about before and that
don't cause your parser to do arbitrary
computation like the Dow hack or like
parsing active documents and somewhere
everywhere you're you're actually going
to be alright to not have a lot of bugs
so make sure that when you specify a new
protocol or when you have the
opportunity to amend an existing
protocol looking at HTTP - and most of
the things that you use are the things
that you need don't add things that
don't follow this it's premature ability
and features that lift the input
language to context-sensitive or above
are almost always the loci of bugs
all of the examples that I was talking
about before and make more that are
cited in our other papers are directly
traceable to the inclusion of complexity
such as this this is truly the
embodiment of complexity is the enemy
dirty so we find that the language
theoretic advice to keep protocols
within deterministic context-free is
feasible to implement it's actually not
too far from the way that we do things
now there are only very few things that
depart from this and if you avoid things
like this it won't be a problem for you
so I'd encourage you to look at what
this work is a further explanation of
which is the paper that we published
earlier this November at I Triple E SEC
debt as I get everyone at a security
conference to scan my QR code I promise
it's not XSS and yeah thank you very
much for giving me the the time and
opportunity to do this I'd be delighted
to take questions both now and I at as
little does anyone know there's a
language theoretically curity conference
embedded in I Triple E Oakland as a
workshop and we'd love to see you there
- CFP actually just opened a couple of
days ago thank you very much I'll open
for questions if I time
no questions okay you can assessment how
much work that would take versus what
that basically doing a paper attacking
comprehension analysis formation okay so
question essentially did I just propose
that we read you the whole internet and
can we do a cost-benefit analysis on
that um well so we we don't have to do
it all at once first but we actually
we've already started um so the
cost-benefit analysis is largely being
done for us now we're seeing a lot of
enterprises doing things like disabling
active content in web pages by
prohibiting the installation of flash
disabling flash plugins within browsers
we we see a lot of macro disablement
policies and office documents we see as
well that the cost-benefit analysis is
rapidly being done for us by those that
side against ransomware because that is
almost completely dependent upon turing
completeness in document format um so
unfortunately I don't have a
cost-benefit analysis right here but I
hope that the anecdotal evidence of
every time we see one of these bugs and
they all do seem to fall within this
problem we immediately begin mitigating
it by disabling large swaths of features
from the internet that we put so much
work into developing I would say that it
will probably be extremely favorable
when sometimes someone gets around to it
alright anyone else
okay I'll be around all weekend
[Applause]