so good morning everyone so what we want
to get asked me and Steve to talk with
you about kind of how the discussions
again they led to to Getti saying you
know what effort I'm making a conference
so as most great well before we get into
that I want to so this is a this is my
the book was into getting a tender for
secure for InfoSec right so I do
enterprise security architecture large
skill systems design implementation I
have supported DoD for quite um at a
time in the past and commercial
customers most of time I do systems in I
can help out with systems engineering
processes mentoring and building out
socks and stuff I need a j'l engineering
and integration processes and always
looking for additional mentors so this
is mine Steve Warren I'm the federal
chief technologist for Intel stuff I do
is government security and architecture
anti-tamper hardware root of trust
vetted security cloud all the things the
government cares about these days what I
can share is reference architectures
enterprise architectures and what I've
found most useful folks is understanding
the government use cases requirements in
terms that you can then go to build
against I can share activities I've been
doing an authentication system security
and I can give good Scott's
recommendations I'm always looking for
good Scott's recommendations as you'll
see in a moment but the other things I
need are solutions that are affordable
at scale one of the things that a lot of
companies will small and large tend to
forget is how do you actually deploy
this thing in real world and then more
insight into the sectors and the actors
not just the vulnerability but what's
behind it was a motivator
and I always want good scotch
recommendations so as most great things
that this started in the bar this is
actually a picture of the bar this is a
it was a Friday at the last Def Con the
one just this recent and we all just as
you do at Def Con wonder around until
you find a group of people that you know
or you find interesting and you start
talking and drinking so seven and a half
hours later of drinking and I believe
you were drinking Macallan 18 and I was
drinking doubles of Booker's and lots of
other folks were consuming so Steve
Mancini was there totally Kleinberg
Gaddy myself and then several others
wandered in and out over the course of
the seven hours and this is a
representative bar tab it would have
been close to this amount
it was copious amounts of alcohol were
consumed so whatever we were talking we
started coming it was kind of the high
how you're doing how's work going and
then we started griping about about the
the all the problems and different
things that we have seen in the
presentations today and yesterday and it
really got to the point of well how do
we fix this of what do we do so the
problem and by the way we started taking
notes
so taking drunk notes and then trying to
decipher then type them up the next day
with the hangover that was a good
challenge in bearing in mind is for all
of you for future reference if you are
going to have the drunk conversation
having the notes is better than not
having it is true this is true so the
problem that we came up with is
information security doesn't have a
discipline in the same way that other
engineering domains do and our solution
is to create measured consistency and
completeness to manifest discipline to
bridge security architecture and
engineering pretty good for that much
alcohol right so instead of a model we
use to view security with
questionable we came up with a new idea
to use the model of the RFC as a
template to list the qualities of the
models that we want to develop need a
new way of looking at things with where
we look at discipline so the guidelines
that we kind of came up with we've heard
this one at least twice
it's a taxonomy we need a common lexicon
and a way to communicate with with each
other and with our stakeholders so then
we wanted inter domains look beyond
computer security use analogies and
frameworks from other industries again
he was just talking about this as well
derivative value value the model must be
useful I love the boxes which was
actually in another presentation that
George box you know all models are wrong
some models are useful but to make these
useful if they're not lets evolve them
until they are so one of the reasons why
we're talking about some of these things
is because when we go off into our
groups these are some of the thought
processes that we have of about how can
we judge whether we have done something
useful so consistent level point of view
of abstraction we need a consistent
point of view normally our point of view
changes based upon who we're talking to
or the recipient of the information we
need a view or a set of views that's
standard and documented in a common way
having multiple documents that describe
the exact same thing in different
language or a different standard way of
communicating it all it does is burn
time because we don't necessarily have a
way to communicate very well I think
this was brought up and you're you know
you're talking as well this notion of if
we come up with if we're talking about
the same problem at different levels of
abstractions we're going to continue to
talk past each other coming up with it
what are those Atomics we're those
fundamental building blocks that we can
then agree on is the starting point to
build out the model it's just as
important as having a common language
because I'm talking about the support of
something and you're talking about what
rises on top of it
both describe the same thing but we're
not getting anywhere and so we need to
figure out what are those fundamental
abstractions and agree on so the
abstractions we use because things get
complicated we want to make them simpler
but we need to as you talked about the
Atomics we need to figure out a way to
more ourselves into something that is
common so models have to be rigorous
consistent that have consistency be
practical and have broad applications
some of the models will have exceptions
obviously so we came up with two models
and there is the state and time model
which describes the robustness of the
bridge and those types of attributes to
describe how the bridge is built the the
types of qualities in the systems
engineering world we call these illa T's
and then there's the lifecycle model
which is using and maintaining the
bridge so the state and time model
interactions the components call the
time slice the vertical thinking is in
snapshots and time time slice has to be
attributes called Atomics and each of
the interactions of components the only
thing that matters is the state of the
interface it's the what not how the
inter and how the interface is used
characteristics and the state are
qualities of the asset at a moment in
time and then the assets interactions
are core to the model so it's not
necessarily about the the overall system
and looking at an abstract level it's
looking at each of the components of the
system and seeing how they interact to
have the emergent properties of a bridge
so it can be viewed as a function of
risk trust and asset notice we don't
bring the the attacker or the user into
this because we're you have to look at
it devoid from from any of those types
of interactions because you're
describing the the system itself so I'm
going to skip some of these for for the
sake of time and then there's the the
lifecycle model which is basically a
series of time slices with a common
context or story if you will and so
looking at in a temporal view it's a way
to describe that lifecycle is really a
series of states and so it's coming in
from a completely different angle and
you make the city a decision changes
based on the context and that's again
the context is based on timeline so it's
recursive decisions are answers to many
problems and in this context answers
tend to be recursively defined the
question which can be problematic but
there's a lot of value in this
horizontal thinking and so the question
excitedly we start to try to take it go
after complex problems so what we did
and this is the promise removing bits
out of two and a half hours arguing
about which model life was writing and
what actually came out of that after we
got tired of talking about that from kid
is that we're both right you're both
wrong and the reason we wanted to talk
about not just the different models of
legend instead of giving you the answers
this is the conversation that each of
the groups needs to have today that's
why we're mic sorry when each of the
groups have to do I have to think about
today as they're working through their
exercise is talk to the things that even
if the amount the right one but the
process is going to get you to the right
answer and so what we came up with is a
combination of the two models because
both are useful to describe the system
depending on what your goal is and so in
being able to get to a consistent
engineering discipline for cybersecurity
you need to take the best of both wall
above us the bike storage area so the
idea is is that the the the life cycle
and story that goes over the top that's
our second model right but it describes
the the system in its usage state which
in some ways is what a lot of us can
care about but others want to care about
this vertical thinking right the state
and time and acknowledging which point
that we're looking at and noting that
they both have value and about how they
interact it lends us to be able to have
better communication over the over the
course of time so if you look at the
vertical pieces you've got state and
context there's an atomic model of the
interactions of the
components during that time to make up
the system and then you have assets and
the interactions right so you can talk
about at a specific point in time this
actor and this user or these specific
things in this time slice interact with
the system in a very specific state and
a system in a state is described by the
Atomics that and their specific state
and it's an aggregate of those so when
you start to break down the problem like
this but can have a map of where the
abstractions are it rapidly lent it
rapidly allows communication to occur
the other thing important to note is and
we put it in there sort of stylette the
beneficial and malicious but really from
the models respective it doesn't matter
their interactions with the asset
whether they're legitimate or it's an
attacker shouldn't change the model the
model should be independent of how your
interactions are having the same thing
with the asset it's the target today
tomorrow it's the email server you all
use the kind of interactions that that
and it's all Phi the interactions but
the app is a they're still just
interactions there's tree them that way
the model can hold up the other thing
that's really important about why you
don't want to just focus it on a
vertical only is because the livestock
allows you to do things like forensics
was you just do root cause so you look
at what happens and you look at what
happened at multiple states and then you
use the lifecycle approach that to be
able to get the correlation and that's
why they have to work together and you
can't just have one or the other
the old adage of having forced entries
some people see the force some people
see the trees but the reality is a story
is the force is made up of trees let's
go to the to a pretty picture before we
go to the next picture this is not
something that is done right this is
something that is still evolving and the
important thing to remember is that when
we're having these discussions it's not
necessarily about getting to an answer
it's about asking better questions and
realizing where we break down and what
additional things that we need to work
on so this is a model that I pull
together
display and this is a was part of my
master's thesis this took a lot of time
to get a model that was functional just
in concept that's not what we're
necessarily asking for today but I'm
showing I'm going to show this and then
the executable model to show that you
could eventually migrate these concepts
and these solutions to model thinking
because when we have model thinking all
of us get on the same page much faster
and then we can create simulations and
then we can test our theories in a way
that is consistent and we can also
convey that to the operators and and to
to fellow researchers as well so I'm not
going to get into explaining this if you
want to know more about it please come
see me and then this is the same model
but this was done in vensim and it's
about being able to execute that model
and the whole idea it was a model for
cyber conflict with you had the
attackers and the defenders that were
related symbiotically by the tyre
population of the internet based upon
compromised and non compromised hosts so
it's a way to talk about that conflict
that the Getty was talking about and
it's a way to model that so the idea is
is that it's going to take a lot of
thought it's going to take a lot of time
we're not necessarily always going to be
correct but if we keep chipping away at
it this is hard work and I think that
that's one of the things that separates
attack and defense is that defense is
long work for small games and then you
have this evolutionary breakthrough I
think one of the things that we like
about the the notion of this kind of
model is allows you to describe events
in a common way across multiple types of
events whether we're talking about DDoS
which I know was one of us we wanted to
talk about or we're talking about a
application-layer attack or a whole
campaign a network-based threat versus a
USB basic the model shouldn't have to
change for the kind of inner
so we need to have a common way of
describing those events that works
across the different domains and across
within cybersecurity but also means that
we'll get policy or other areas it
should go to those other domains and
still have the same construct and again
that sort of things we want to get to we
don't have to answer but we have to
think about that's the endgame and use
that as the mechanism for determining
the model and determining the Atomics
for that model all right thank you
a couple of notes on this and then we
have five minutes to discuss what we're
going to do after lunch and we're
breaking for lunch so very quickly going
back to this during the 7s our
discussion where we had a tab around
$10,000 and drinks I didn't I drank only
water by the way I did we got stuck at
some somewhere around our three because
I insisted on thinking like an engineer
and saying I need cars to go over the
bridge in Joel insisted on I need a
bridge to be up and we didn't speak the
same language please today consider we
speak different languages and we often
need to try to figure out what the hell
we mean
okay that's number one we don't have our
own set of language yet insecurity we
all agree on it's thought for later on
not going into those hours and on this
the original model here started with
risk based model when we spoke about
vulnerabilities risk threats I insisted
on putting trust in there as a basic
building block of security but
eventually brought it down to
interactions and assets just be sure we
can break it to an abstract level but
then when this became an atomic language
that was when I was kind of the problem
when I insisted no this is not good it's
not useful to me to have long formula
that they can't really use day to day
when you want to describe a whole
process and life cycle and I really
hated those words because unnecessarily
late one to the other across time it can
be any type of life cycle we got stuck
on that for two hours just about the
language if we call the life cycle now
that means it might be a circle or it
might be something else ten years so now
all models will only look like a circle
or line or whatever we just got stuck on
for two hours but essentially if it if
it's not useful in the way of its
mathematics and I'm never going to use
it if I'm a network operator or an
analyst or it's not very useful because
in the future I'm always going to think
in line we created the atomic model
which is not perfect it's far from our
model we created a lifestyle and it
works together layout layered and the
reason I want to speak for a couple
minutes was to add to the difficulties
we had in even discussing things and to
show what we could potentially work
through today and emphasize what Joel
said when I was the problem and they all
called me an idiot
for two and half hours they still listen
to me and we reached something but they
did call me an idiot
so it was a combination of cannae
weather hell do you want from us shut up
and we're going to listen to you until
we reach something and then the language
issue of we all speak different
languages so today when it breaks
different groups we need to figure out
what the end goal is can we make
something abstract enough for something
useful enough something basic enough
insecurity we can build upon or are we
going to waste five hours or five long
hours in discussing some something that
we'll learn from have fun with but
eventually come up with nothing as far
as results and we've all been in many
situations where we discussed problems
of the internet and security for hours
on end so good at ourselves and doesn't
do it again the next year so keep in
mind what's the results we want to reach
I think Sunil and April have something
for us when we come back or maybe we'll
do it now and on that note thank you for
listening in April it's yours
[Applause]