in the back anybody that cares okay
great good afternoon good afternoon I
know we got the blood sugar issue
hitting we've had lunch we've had water
there's not been much caffeine we're all
sitting so you know do I need we can get
up and do jumping jacks here for a
second if we need to my name is John
Brown I am a operator of a network based
in Albuquerque New Mexico we run
basically fiber-to-the-home fiber to the
business one of the things that scares
the bejesus out of me is great I'm
putting fiber to these wonderful homes
are getting full gigabit it's a
symmetrical pipe Wow packet rate all
kinds of fun things so we're working on
trying to figure out ways to help make
the network better and make sure that
our customers aren't causing other
people pain and so we do a very various
the bits and pieces of things one other
thing I wanted to talk about is source
boosts packet filtering and some things
that we do in our network it might be
applicable to help others mitigate stuff
I do not believe that there's a silver
bullet that solves all problems fiber
isn't going to solve all the problems
Wireless isn't going to solve all the
problems you know firewall doesn't solve
all the problems so your mileage may
vary based on the things that we do here
in applying them into your own networks
or making recommendations to others the
other little caveat that I would throw
out there is before you implement
something you should always turn it up
in a lab test it make sure you
understand what its implications are to
your network a little bit about me I'm
in based in Albuquerque I will track
travel for packet food and really good
single malt scotch the rule about scotch
is of course you never drink scotch less
than half your age I'm getting expensive
I'm a technology trainer for several
vendors in a past life I ran was a
technical lead for our I can tell root
DNS for about three years
took over that role after the 2002 DDoS
that hit all the routes that was kind of
fun I've built some ATM networks my
network we've got about 700 bgp peers
we're in la San Jose Ashburn and we'll
be at am six so how do we prevent bad
packets packets on i'm sorry typo there
how do we prevent bad packets on our
network you can write ACLs I mean that's
what everybody sort of immediately
thinks about in a small mid-sized
service provider market you can put them
on the edge and you know they're very
easy to maintain especially when you
have hundreds of routers to deploy this
across not so there's got to be a better
way to do this and one of the ways that
we do is we leverage BGP as a signaling
protocol and we leverage unicast reverse
path forwarding as a second way of
helping prevent and do things on our
network and we'll talk a little bit
about each of these first let's talk
about you RPF unicast reverse path
forwarding so it's defined in RFC 3704
that's the current RFC that I found out
that it talks about it
there were a couple of previous RFC's
but the current one is 3704 basically
unicast reverse path forwarding is
designed to limit the impact of source
spoofed packets so the gentleman up here
from perimeter x is sending me a packet
but it's coming to me with a source IP
address that's not on his network then
he's potentially spoofing that packet
okay so what unicast reverse path
forwarding will do is we'll look at that
packet we'll look at the source and
we'll look at our routing table we'll
make a determination issue is that
source packet reachable back down the
same interface to him if it is not drop
if it is forward some people will say
you are PF is unicast reverse path
filtering it's not filtering it's a 40
the making a forwarding
decision to Ford or not to forward in
car and so there are people out there
that will say well we can't put you RPF
and our service provider business
because it's going to break things the
world's gonna fall apart it's difficult
it's hard I mean I've heard these
arguments on the Nanog list and various
other lists I'll tell you I've got
thousands of edge connections we run you
RPF on every one of them do I get
complaints no we drop the traffic if it
doesn't come from an IP that I've given
them I drop it now what do I do when I
have a multihomed
customer that's running BGP yes I have a
little bit of a different world I have
to work with but when I'm looking at DSL
or cable modem faced or Wireless ISP
faced edge customers your 8020 rule if
you want to think about that way 80% of
those interfaces I can protect to make
sure that I don't get unicast reverse
path I mean source spooch packets coming
in everybody here know who Keita is
Arcadia a researcher KC cloudy and threw
down what is it UCSD yep they have a
tool that you can implement into your
network that will actually do spoof
checking and so we run a little tool
that they have the SIS there and once a
day once a week whatever their time
period is they try to spew boot packets
out the door towards their collectors to
see whether or not we're blocking them
and generally they don't ever get passed
it's like the roach motel they they
never leave I believe that if we
implement BC p-38 we prevents or spoof
packets we're going to see a good chunk
reduction in what happens on our
networks and what's happening as far as
abuse as I said how do I go how does it
work but real quickly we make decisions
on the destination is what a router is
usually doing it's looking up that
destination we're not looking at the
source so the attacker is leveraging the
fact that we're looking at things the
forwarding decision based
destination IP not source you RPF lets
us now look at that source address we
can look at it and do things in two
modes we can do something in strict mode
we can do it in loose mode strict mode
says that if it absolutely didn't come
from this gentleman drop it
if that's not reachable back loose mode
says well it's not directly down this
interface but there is a route in my
routing table that says that source is a
real source so I'm going to still allow
the traffic to flow okay if the source
is reachable then good else drop now
here's an interesting thing in loose
mode if the next hop is null which your
routing device thinks is the null
interface it will drop the packet and
hardware so I can turn around and throw
things away by just making sure the next
hop to a bad address is no switching bgp
black holing this is a opposite i'm the
upstream isp I'm gonna say I'm big ISP
and I don't know what's your name sir
Eugene Eugene's my downstream ISP
customer I'm big ISP and I'm flowing a
whole bunch of attacks towards one of
his web-hosted and customers we know the
destination IP but I'm saturated here's
one gig link to the upstream world
because of all this malicious traffic
flowing in towards him alright one way
he can solve that is he can pick the
phone up and ring me up and say hey
would you please drop traffic to 1.2.3.4
because that's my customer and they're
getting attacked but it's eating up the
rest of my bandwidth now he's got a
weight for me the customer service rep
okay what was your name Eugene how do
you spell that
and what company are you with and what
you all get the point right it takes a
while for that to happen now if we have
established a bgp session between us he
can actually use bgp as the signaling
protocol to tell me automatically to
throw that traffic away so he can tag a
route
and send it to me within a pre agreed
upon a bgp community string or community
tag and send that to me when I received
that route from him I will set next hop
in my router to dev know
so now sudden that malicious traffic
coming into his subscriber 1.2.3.4 is
being thrown away upstream and hopefully
the rest of his pipe is back up and the
bulk of his users are back up and
they're happy you've pushed the problem
upstream your victim is really now a
victim but it's sort of the lesser of
two evils
right you've killed one to protect the
rest of your network you can use BGP to
tell others whether their peers or your
transits to drop traffic so now let's
say your customers getting ddosed you
can go through the black hole as I just
went through and now off you go
sometimes I get ahead of my slides I
apologize so let's see what happens if
we can start to mix some of these
together if we enable strict mode you
RPF on your single home customers will
prevent source food packets from
entering the network this will help ddos
victims out there so i'm not making
money on it when i enable you RPF on my
interfaces
I'm helping Eugene's network I'm helping
that make sure that my network isn't
causing a problem for somebody else and
I think this is a mindset that we have
with some service providers is it's not
really killing them so why do they care
and why do they need to push this across
their network it's that their business
is actually impacting everybody else I
talk a lot to small rural ISPs and a lot
of them have their backbone connections
or over microwave fixed wireless
connections and so they're spending
money on time slots to send that traffic
down across their wireless backbone so
if we can help them figure out ways of
fixing that upstream that helps save
them money it helps save them bandwidth
cable
abilities I will stress these points
make sure that you test these things in
a lab before you start deploying them
but I can't just drop everything if I
drop everything my customer will be dead
can't I just write an ACL yeah you're
right an ACL drop 3000 slash 32s
build that deploy that across to a whole
bunch of routers and then your attacker
realizes that you're now blocking those
so we'll go ahead and and spin up a
different set of IPs
well we can do is we can use you RPF
lose feature we can inject a route into
the fib of the forwarding information
base and we can set that route to be
black hole or null and now it happens is
your router will look at the source IP
address and we'll drop based on that
source IP because it's in the FIB
pointing to death null so now instead of
necessarily Eugene telling me to kill
traffic going towards his customer if
there's a way for me upstream to be
intelligent about looking at all this
traffic
maybe I see a whole bunch of just send
floods and I can extrapolate out the bad
send request versus good sense I didn't
then drop all those bad send source IPS
in my big service provider network
heading towards him his customer is
still up and running now in fact some of
the bgp scrubber guys that's what they
will do so we inject a source IP we set
it to next hole to next hop to be black
hole and then poof basically our traffic
from that source goes away and you can
use tools to inject so what do we use to
inject I'm a big open source person if I
can do it an open source I'd rather
spend the extra bit of time to setup
open source then necessarily buy a
commercial package because I think a lot
of the stuff has already been solved an
open source we know it's round it rolls
it's called a wheel let's use open
source if we can so have an injector
machine put routes on that you don't
want
receive from these would-be sources tag
those routes with a couple of
communities you definitely want to make
sure you tag it with no export because
what I don't want to see happen is I
don't want to take that slash 32 that I
think is a bad actor IP and announce it
to cogent my transit provider because
all of a sudden now if cogent BGP
filters aren't set up right I'm going to
see a lot of traffic for that slash 32
coming into my network more importantly
someone's probably going to complain and
say hey wait a minute why are you
announcing my space so you want to set
no export you also want to make sure
that your production routers have
specific explicit filters in place that
do not cause these prefixes to leak out
of your network routes can be updated on
the injector all your BGP edges devices
will start dropping from that source
caution caution caution I wanted to put
the little warning warning Will Robinson
robot up here but didn't have time to do
that
RFC 21 19 defines words like must shall
may should and in this case must you
must not redistribute this source must
make sure your BGP filters drop these
prefixes and I again strongly encourage
you to test before deployment what can I
use as a BGP you could use I think bird
is one of them you can use X to be GPS
with I use I like active EGP it's free
it works it has JSON support API you can
control it from a variety of different
methods and you can run it on simply
something really simple and stupid low
cost piece of hardware we have a sequel
database that we put routes into we have
a whitelist table we have a blacklist
table we do some aging of those IPs that
we get we wash before we push it into X
to be GP we wash it through our
whitelist to make sure we don't
accidentally drop well-known sites etc
so that's basically what my presentation
is is all about last week we had a DDoS
it was a
NTP attack against one of our
downstreams two-and-a-half gigabits per
second I'm not really that big in the
grand scheme of things we had about
18,000 slash thirty twos that were
hitting us we grabbed those we injected
it into our BGP in a couple of minutes
that downstream ist was no longer
feeling the pain we were dropping
traffic from those IPS at our edges to
the rest of the world when we saw that
the attack went away we were able to
turn around and pull those out and move
on if we see IPS that keep coming up in
our list we keep putting longer age out
times on them and just let them sit
there for a while unless somebody comes
and screams I work on the squeaky wheel
principle if you really don't like me
drop in that traffic you'll call me up
and yell at me about it and we'll talk
about why I was dropping and what you
should do to not have me drop it in the
future
other than that I know I was kind of
just buzzed to do this fairly quickly
was I don't think it's a super advanced
topic but thanks to to Gaudi and the
rest of the folks to putting this
together and to our sponsors Intel sales
force duo
Baylor etc there's where you can find me
and I stand for questions
we haven't gotten to millions but the
the core routers we have or memory-wise
are able to handle large quantities of
oven Jack we've gotten up to around 100
and 120 thousand source spoofed on one
attack so I haven't I haven't stressed
it up to millions
that's why we have the whitelist so so
we we try it's never gonna be perfect
none of this is perfect we try to to
have well-known services IP addresses in
there has somebody gone out and tried to
figure out what is our perimeter tools
and then what's the weakness and all
that no we haven't seen that I'm sure in
about an hour I will go ahead
so let me quality what I was saying it
doesn't benefit doesn't caught it
doesn't make us money or cost us money
stuff like that basically I was using
that as an excuse that I've heard from
other big service providers say why they
haven't done source booth filtering on
their network for our position when we
turned on you RPF about two years ago we
saw about an eight percent drop in our
overall traffic so from from our benefit
perspective I believe we're running
cleaner pipes now and I know that my
downstream ISPs are happier because
we're able to they can either use BGP to
tell us to drop something or we can see
something that happens and we can go
ahead and drop that traffic and it keeps
them up and running when they're in
Durango Colorado
it was BGP SEC no I haven't in the back
I don't have a good way of looking at
that yet I'm in some of that analyst
world I am but Padawan learner which is
the other reason why I'm here today is
to try to suck up as much knowledge as I
can and and take to come in with the
position of I run a network how do I
help make my network better to put you
out of a job which will never happen but
you know I want to be able to build a
better mousetrap on the service
providers side
I think part of it comes down to at
least from the the school the internet
that I've been involved with over
20-some odd years you know don't don't
do stupid things on a network and own
chloral harm and if there's a literally
a 1/2 line in search you can put on an
edge interface
I need him get your junior tech to start
rolling that across each each community
each region etc to help prevent that
then you sort of get rid of that problem
I mean the I guess the flip side would
be somebody earlier today was using
medical as a as an example as to the way
we're thinking about and trying to solve
some of these problems and hey we got
really great hospitals so who cares
about cholesterol probably can still
live after the heart attacks is just
good drugs and a good hospital for it or
should I be taking and eating better so
I don't even have to go there I would
say that I don't care if your largest
provider in the world down to the
smallest you you shouldn't allow traffic
into your network that is faked and we
have the same problem in the white
telephony world right we have tons of
spoofed caller ID and origination of
phone numbers we've got to solve that
problem to mostly reactive I do get some
data feeds from a few folks that I trust
that I'll take those IPS in they'll tell
me they're their command-and-control
BOTS other things along those lines and
we'll just throw them into our our
system and drop traffic well we're
playing with there real quick is we're
now working on where we can set next top
to actually go over here to a sensor and
so I can see all hey wait Billy Bob over
here is now trying to communicate to the
CMC what's going on with Billy Bob and
can I help Billy Bob clean up their
environment
right where we're playing with MSN and
some other flow a net flow stuff to be
able to get smarter about that and most
of that's in internal development code
wise in other words me and what another
person is we run the business and have
time to do some coding so yes I would
love to be able to sit there and look at
what is a normal state for a particular
customer's connection when do we start
going outside of of various thresholds
on that and an alarming we are doing
that right now purely on bit rate and
then also on packet rate cuz I consider
the two of them very separate indicators
I think the gentleman in the blue suit
nope
[Music]
yep yes so you can in mana you can
convert that into a monetization that's
a savings or I don't have to buy more
capacity my capacity purchased I'm now
just got pushed out six months twelve
months what happened right other other
questions comments green pardon
at flowspec
we're playing with it we haven't
completely dived into it I've been more
of a net flow person because
historically we've been a Cisco shop and
over the last 12 18 months we've
migrated over to the Jay company and
we're running a bunch of fairly
good-sized MX's now and we're happy
my last GSR 12,000 will go out to to the
shooting range and a couple of weekends
and we're going to see what the Barrett
50 does to it it's not bulletproof
other other comments questions is this
not a bad idea to do is this a bad idea
for us to be doing is this good you
think this is good okay yeah wasn't that
called Telstra well good well get we'll
get Geoff Huston to do it all over again
[Laughter]
now one of the things is I don't know if
there's researchers that are in the
community here but one of the things we
have done with a couple of folks is
because we can steer some of this
traffic off to a collection device is
we're happy to work with researchers if
you're a real bona fide researcher send
me something in PGP and I'm happy to
work with you and chat it's my network
I'm the guy that makes the decision so
there's not much in the food chain other
comments questions
okay well thank you very much
[Applause]