fine good morning very nice to be here
so this is a conference on defense my
experience is that actually the best
form of defense is to stop them doing it
in the first place we can actually
defeat the bad guys at at the front door
then we stand a much better chance so
I'm going to tell you stuff you will
probably should already know if you
haven't seen the headline from 2016 yes
one two three four five six is still the
most common password number two one two
three four five six seven eight um
hacking phishing sofa engineering are
simple the bad guys are winning running
malicious code is pretty trivial getting
someone one only one person you don't
need one person inside the organization
to run the malicious code and ultimately
it's all about the money so currently if
you haven't seen the figure credit card
fraud is running at about thirty five
billion dollars a year and ultimately
what credit fraud is is the ability to
persuade someone that you are the card
the card is yours
its identity theft and then the date an
identity failing that causes it we all
know it's broken
yes the industry's dirty little secret
yeah it's a 1960s computer mainframe
model of identity the computer is God if
you're lucky enough you get an account
on the computer and then you get lots of
access yes we've made it distributed but
ultimately it all boils down to that
1960s mainframe technology and this was
what you call an identity to mindset
we've got a bunch of disparate computers
we need to join them together so we're
going to federate them we're going to do
sam'l we're going to do whatever all we
need to do some privacy so we better
invent um a anyone using um a anyone got
it to work yet this is the result in
what we call a locus of control problem
and the locus of control problem is
really simple it goes along the lines of
I'm a security professional and if you
give it all to me in my
identity system I can put my arms around
it I can make it all work for you and as
a result what we've ended up with is I
can make it all work for you if you come
and play in Google's ecosystem or
Apple's ecosystem or Microsoft's
ecosystem or Bay Dells ecosystem if
you're in China and of course if you're
inside a corporation let's shove it all
inside my active directory because then
I can make it all work and woe betide if
you actually want to communicate outside
of those individual locust ease of
control and so we get into things like
Federation and Federation is an N
factorial problem you can make it work
at about any query any more than that it
just fails miserably and what this
results in is is multiple disparate
unconnected accounts who here is over
200 accounts yeah you should all have
your hands up you'll do you just don't
realize it
yeah I've got three sheets of a4 for my
70 year old mother-in-law with all the
things that she has no to do with
computers and the accounts that go with
it it's crazy
she doesn't even do online banking and
we all know it's broken it's too complex
the one thing I have learned about doing
security for the last 30 years is if
it's simple it stands a chance of
working if it's complex you don't stand
a snowball's chance in hell this is from
some stuff that was done around n stick
everyone no one entered is the US
government's national strategy for
trusted identity in cyberspace this was
some stuff that was done I'm not going
to comment on good bad or indifferent
this is but look at it is it going to
work this is from an inch thick paper to
make this federated environment work you
need all of these things and the same
paper goes on to say actually the issues
are user correlation risk from liability
chains of trust third party proofing and
verification issues we're not going to
make it work as we currently
do what I'd like to call identity - so I
favorite quote is let's just keep doing
that the same way we do it yeah insanity
is doing the same thing over and over
again and expecting a different result
we haven't learned so some background to
what we think of the way forward so
where does the work originate from yeah
originally out of the Jerrica form an
open group Jericho is that guys who
bought UD perimeter ization originally
10-15 years back this is a bit of work
we did on thing called identity
Commandments what's broken what are the
fundamentals what are we doing wrong and
how do we fix it it's fed into for those
of you who do cloud the cloud security
Alliant guidelines version 3 most of
domain 12 was done by a team working on
this and then into the consolidated
paper white paper out of us so I'm going
to rush very quickly because there's
about three four years of research here
to cram into 20 minutes so trust me
three key tenets of identity should be
really important for you me and everyone
else in this room a my privacy primacy
and agency privacy am i able to keep my
personal information private primacy can
I control who has my personal
information an agency is can I control
what you do with my personal information
and you should really care about those
three tenants and if you take nothing
else away from this talk this should be
it here's the gotcha and it took me
about six months to get my head around
this one properly only 100% anonymity at
the root of an entity's identity will
solve those problems yeah I'll debate it
over a beer tonight if you want to
debate it but just bear with me for two
seconds and trust me for a second it
solves all the problems that we have it
puts
individual entity in control it D
centralizes the identity ecosystem so
you don't need someone managing three
hundred and fifty million Americans in
one government ecosystem because that
will be the biggest target on earth for
the hackers it minimized the attack
service the attack services now seven
billion people it solves problems like
anonymity voting really important we're
going to get eighteen year olds voting
again it solves the locus of control
issue there is no locus of control it's
totally distributed and this is the
important one one of those active tests
governments can accept each other's
digital identities and this is what we
went out and did some research back in
the last year this is what the people
want who should be in control of your
personally identifiable information
eighty-six percent said I should who
should control how it's used
eighty five said I should I should
probably you'd all agree with that
unfortunately the US and the UK
government think it's a commercial body
from a list of proved by the government
is the answer you should be selecting
that's what they're putting in place for
you right now whether it's UK or US
government slightly different approaches
so the next one any identity ecosystem
must encompass all the identity types we
are fixated on fixing this for people
and this isn't going to work going
forward if we're going to fix problems
around like density of things around the
fact that we get malicious code into the
system the fact that actually we really
care about organizations because
organizations are legally people in the
eyes of the law and of course coming up
real soon now
lots more agents whether they're
electronic agents or they're people
doing things on your behalf we have to
do identity identically across all five
entity types
and this one sameness is the key to
anonymity ultimately most of you don't
know me from Adam here but humans do it
with phases sameness is done with phases
so if you meet me in five years time ago
all they remember you you were in Austin
words you're presenting yeah its
sameness I'm the same person you William
first met me will be today and will be
tomorrow it's as simple as that
and the majority of the time we don't
actually care whether Paul Simmons is my
real name or not it might just be an
alias yeah especially if you go to Def
Con lots of aliases at Def Con and
ultimately it's all about taking risks
and we talk about a lot about risks in
this industry and actually we do it
really really badly this is from CSA
guidance and it talks about making a
risk-based decision about access to data
and systems based on the trusted
identity and attributes of all the
entities and components in the
transaction chain what does that mean it
means if I'm doing an e banking
transaction if I can understand
everything about that transaction chain
from the person who's actually at the
end of the mobile application to what
they're running on is it rooted does it
have any strange code running on it is
the unsecured protocols do I understand
where it's geo-located what level of
transaction they're trying to do I can
make a better risk-based decision about
whether to transact and get my losses
down from 5% to 3% or 2% or even if we
do it properly the more you understand
that 1 or 1/2 percent and that's serious
return on investment for four banks out
there and finally let's fix the
liability problem so I spent three
tither we did a bit of work on on end
and I spent three days in locked in a
room with American lawyers trust me you
lose the will to live the reality is
what they were dead scared about was
this liability question if I attest that
some if I'm managing all these
attributes on behalf of youth which I am
NOT authoritative and I attest wrongly
what's going to happen chances are you
know right to life liberty in sue people
isn't it in America you know I'm really
get sued it's basically if I'm a large
company like Verizon or one of the other
guys playing in the end stick space so
the rule is very simple you only sign or
a test for attributes for which you are
authoritative really really key we need
to fix the risk and under and we talked
about that just now the key thing here
is never ever to turn a maybe something
into a binary they definitely are so
Active Directory is the big guilty one
for this I come in with a password user
name and password into Active Directory
and what does Active Directory do to say
to all those 80,000 other devices
he really is guaranteed Paul Simmons and
that's the root cause of our problems
we've turned a variable he's used a
password we don't know how strong it was
but it passed muster as defined by IT
and AD then says he definitely is going
head trust of his pulse and we do this
all over the place who here uses secure
ID cards yeah for two-factor
authentication
now we do exactly the same yes your ID
system except we pour more trust in that
because it's two-factor authentication
the fact I'm picked up this thing in the
street and it's someone's written the
username and and secret pin on the back
of it is it relevant because it came in
by secure ID so it's bound to be better
than just username and password isn't it
and the person taking the risk has no
idea because there's this intermediate
system that's turned it into a binary
and you only play your part and no more
don't try to do anything else
than put the bit for which you are
authoritative so let's get on to some
real examples let's play a game let you
imagine how this thing would work so
here I am first of all I need my
remember I'm not 100% under view the
root so I need my anonymous root so as
you can probably tell from the accent
I'm British yes so I'm the post office
now the reason I the post office is the
post office in the UK the postmasters
there are vetted by the spooks so every
postmaster in the UK is actually been
through a vetting process so I walk into
the post office now I'm in America so
I've got a $20 note yeah so I pay my $20
to the postmaster and the postmaster
says certainly sir you want an anonymous
form of your route what would you like
I've got five in my safe so I'll get
them out here are the models you can
choose from that's good isn't it I like
that there we go so I've got five models
you can choose for anyone using one of
these things which is called a Yubikey
this is the first one here yeah this is
a Fido compliant device for those into
Fighter absolutely brilliant plug it in
authenticate bits and pieces all you
need to do is press the button so you
want to be me
access my email here we are
you're now me thank you so I've got
these five devices and the bottom three
are compliant for border entry they've
been signed off by the spooks the other
two are because the key thing here is
what we call immutable linkage is when
we express risk do we understand how
wetware is connected to the firmware
with what degree of certainty am I
connected to the device and if I go to
Yubikey as we've just done
Max is going to be able to impersonate
me without any problems because the
level of the mutable linkage is zero the
Baghdad is clean that Fuli
where is on the right hand side I say
I'm gonna have one of these this is an
in the wristband an Indy wristband does
a heart biorhythm biometric so I slap it
on my risk it does a heart by rhythm
biometric and level of immutable linkage
probably 95 you know ninety-nine point
nine nine and we can argue about how
many knives over beer preferably so I
choose mine in lis wristband they all
work to a common standard or should in
this nice brave new world they can all
Express the model but not the serial
number remember anonymity and from the
model you can divide functionality you
can understand that this is a heart by
rhythm device and put my own risk
assessment on whether I want to transact
with someone using that versus that so
now I've got my anonymity at the root
but obviously that's totally useless as
you will be sort of sitting there saying
I can't do an anima T so I'm going to
get some some credibility behind it and
the way we do this is really simple is
we do a digital join between me and
entity organization like my Austin
Capitol icon since we're not able sorry
anyway so we do a digital one-way join
and create what we call a citizen
persona now this is a British citizen
persona because I'm a Brit and what it
consists of is the stuff of which UK
government is authoritative which is
only five attributes which is date of
birth place of birth sex at birth name
of birth citizenship the only five
attributes for which UK government is
Authority basically taught on my birth
certificate and I wonder in with my
passport of my birth certificate and say
please would you give me a digital join
between my device and you entity
organization government entity person me
is a
in Persona this now gives me context and
I can leverage that context for all it's
worth and they give it back to me as a
cryptographic blob that only I can use
so I can now store that wherever I like
I can put it in the cloud for
safekeeping I can put it onto my my
phone I could put it on my corporate
laptop I can put it onto my personal
laptop it can go on my desktop go over I
need it to go because I'm in control of
it so let's give a real example of how
this works so here's the here's the
business requirement can I buy alcohol
over the internet so I'm in America over
21 is the legal requirement will I get
paid business requirement address not
Fordland which is the risk reduction so
I come along with my various attributes
and even though I'm in America I can
give you an assertion signed by British
government so that's fine that I'm over
21 from my Visa card persona is the fact
you're going to get paid from my Royal
Mail here's my home address and because
they are all linked to me we can issue
those to Amazon or whoever a triple
assertion cryptographically linked that
could only come from one entity because
the route is common rather than
individual now so as to Amazon or
whoever can say only one entity could
have asserted all those I've met my
business requirements tick-tick-tick
thank you very much we'll ship him the
alcohol simple as that and of course if
we're playing at authentication sameness
and personas that gives us context which
leads us to be able to apply rules or
entitlements to it which allows us to
take good risk-based decisions and we
can enhance those that context the rules
with a whole bunch of other stuff so I
like that I like normative transactional
profile that's a banking one which
basically means disease
this money type of money normally rather
than does he always ship 6000 towels to
a Russian bank so now we've got this
trust or let's leverage it for all it's
worth
let's use it therefore I can Center so
here's my Google join my googa googa
persona and I go into my mailbox and
because I have a bit of crypto in my
device that says this is my Google
persona when I start talking to Google
it goes I've got a match so now I can
turn the entire URL green to say not
only has it got a green padlock but
actually you have a working relationship
with these people that I stored in my
trust store in the ARM chip on my phone
such that I know it is guaranteed to be
Google and not someone who's managed to
replace the two O's with a couple of
dodgy Chinese characters and registered
the domain I went on holiday last summer
to Dubrovnik Greg play clean have been
to Dubrovnik thoroughly recommend it as
the fantastic they filmed Game of
Thrones there they've just filmed the
latest Star Wars there and I went with
Tooey Tooey for the Americans here is
the largest travel company in the world
so I went with Chewie I'm doing
fantastic I have a two-year relationship
obviously which is my digital join
between 2e when I booked the holiday and
me which creates my 2e persona I got an
email the other day it said 300 pounds
off what could be better
classic phishing email but because in my
crypto store I have a persona from tui
it goes thomson co uk party to e that's
absolutely fine match thank you very
much we turn the banner green to say
this is someone genuinely V you already
interact with we kill it stone dead you
can say use the same trick to do it for
voice for video DRM crypto on the email
itself now you've got a consist
one place to look for crypto credentials
you're golden and we can leverage it all
over the place to defeat the bad guys
here's something gum slightly more
complex this is some that we as you talk
to more and more people about this it's
really interesting so you know the
biggest problem we've got the moment is
cars are coming in I can't afford an
algae that's internet-enabled but here's
my Fiat 500 so here's my
internet-enabled an IOT device a car
that comes internet the biggest
challenge with buying a car tomorrow is
going to be I just paid $50,000 for this
car and it's still their car because
it's connected to them the entire time
how when I bite out the show and I make
it my car well the answer is really
simple the cryptographic joined between
me and device in this case of Fiat 500
if my Fiat 500 it has a unique set of
crypto its own persona that says it
pulls car here's a guy's a worker he
works at Tescos Tesco's is the largest
grocery company in the UK we're going to
call this person Fred
he works for them he's a delivery driver
and the biggest business problem Tesco's
have with home deliveries at the moment
is everyone wants between 6:00 and 9:00
at night and they've got this entire
fleet of drivers and vans trucks sitting
idle for most of the day and of course I
don't want to have to wait in during
that three hour time window they give me
because I want to go and do something
more interesting so wouldn't it be nice
if we could take his fred persona yeah
that he's a Tesco easy employee employee
persona function delivery driver and use
it Lou here's how we do I go onto the
Tesco's home shopping site i order my
groceries for the week and Tesco's start
preparing it in the background what
happens is I push a security rule
invisible to me as a user I don't have
to do anything it happens automatically
to my car
can talk to my car because it's got
crypto in it that says this is Paul's
car Paul can therefore send it security
rules which says allow a Tesco's
delivery driver who can assert that he
is a Tesco's delivery driver signed by
Tesco's access to the trunk between 2:00
and 4:00 o'clock in the afternoon in the
company car park so now test goes win
because they get to deliver in the
middle of the afternoon which is the
lacs period I pay less for my delivery
because it's an off peak time and when I
get to my car at the end the day my
groceries are already in the trunk of my
car
register drive home I don't have to wait
in for 3 hours in the afternoon
it just works so in conclusion where are
we with this well the answer is all the
work that is being done with a lot of
really clever people I'm just the
spokesman up here but a lot of work
that's been done has said lots of you
know people have been involved in
basically we've got the blocks we're not
inventing new stuff out here
it's just rebuilding using the blocks
differently to build a different model
so where are we we're looking for people
to get involved we're looking people to
sanity check this refine the business
models that are out there does it work
does the model work in your organization
and ultimately define the final model to
actually go out and build and test we're
a global not-for-profit why very simply
it's got to be neutral and safe we've
got to have one way and Sysco working in
the same room to the same building the
same standards we've got to have Google
and bayed out in the same room working
the same standards it
yeah I know I know I know I know okay no
I'm an idealist um but if it's neutral
and safe it stands a chance
it's got to be global in nature it's got
to be cross accepted by cutting by
governments and ultimately there needs
to be someone to hold whatever IP comes
out of it such that it is royalty free
and open-source for everybody which is
what's in the Charter he says and that's
it then if I got time for a question or
if we're okay yet how does the
revocation last credentials work in
abscess so lost lost so lost credentials
are fairly straightforward there's been
a lot of work going on in it
bottom line is you do lose the the root
of your identity the bottom line is
you're stuffed and you go and get a new
one
same as you lose your Visa card and have
to reach but there are ways around it
so that there's there's a whole bunch of
scenarios that's been worked but you
don't bring that up is that in the
current systems that are broken for the
reasons you talk about though when you
create all those linkages you feel
there's one identity you don't destroy
all the other cracks cute it's what if
the root dies all those linkages go with
it so if the root dies all the bits go
with it I agree with you and said that
one's being solved the key one is
because it's on a persona base if you
lose if Tesco's goes and screws up and
has a breach then what they do is they
lose the Tesco's persona which only
harms then not me
because they're not going to get to my
date of birth my postal address my
anything else yes no I agree yes if I if
it breaks I'm screwed but there are ways
around it