morning my name is rich mcvish here to
talk about primarily analysis and
thinking right so yesterday was a lot of
good discussion during JB's presentation
you know there was a little bit of back
and forth about bias but the comment
that he made that I think really kind of
struck a chord with me was as a field
you know we're producing people that
come out into it coming to our industry
with a bunch of facts but not really how
to think about what we're doing alright
so what I want to talk about is how to
think about thinking right some people
think this is a little fluffy my
original presentation which I showed you
a few people they all came back and were
like well it's a little preachy and not
concrete
so reworked it a little bit so that
we're actually going to go through some
of the different methods that make up
structured analytic techniques and five
actual concrete things that you guys can
take home and use and a strong
suggestion for some resources that you
can go to work through these things on
your own
so if science is nothing more than the
refinement of everyday thinking we
really all need to be aware of how we
apply rigor to our everyday thinking
right how do we reduce errors in our
thought process all right there's a very
large body of work out there most of
most of what I'm drawing from is by a
guy named Richard's here and another guy
named Randy Pearson did a lot of work
funded by the government for the US
intelligence community I am NOT a
psychologist right I'm a I like to read
the psychology part but really a man
this practitioner so I'm more interested
in how I can use these things to make my
work product better before we can really
start to talk about making our thought
process better we need to start with
identifying why our thought process is
broken why we're not aware that our
thought process is broken and all starts
with thinking systems how do we think
about things on a day-to-day basis we
use system 1 thinking it's fast it's
intuitive it's sort of efficient it's
mostly right most of the time it's
usually unconscious but it's also the
thing that allows us to get through our
lives right it's a thing that allows you
to decide which line you're going to get
in at the checkout which check-out line
you're going to get in when you want to
leave the grocery store because you're
like I want to get out of here the
fastest so what do you do you develop a
quick heuristic you look at the lines
you say that one's the shortest after a
while maybe you go to the same grocery
store and you notice that there's that
one cash register operator who's always
slow so it really doesn't matter how
long the line is you start to avoid that
that lot that register system - thinking
is slow deliberate conscious reasoning
ok now generally speaking we don't use
the we don't use this system in our
daily life right it's not how we that's
not how we function because if you sat
down before you wanted to drive to work
every day to analyze the route that you
were going to take based on the late
absolute latest possible information
that'd be a big chunk of your day and if
you decided to do that every day you'd
kind of you'd start to fall apart I'm
mom so we're going to do a quick
experiment anybody who's seen this
picture or knows what this picture is
please try to reframe your mind back to
the first time you saw it anybody want
to call out what they see here right
it's a bunch of rocks okay one of these
rocks is an eye Edie anybody want to
venture a guess which one which this one
right here the bottom left all right
where's that is that laser pointer I
don't know I don't know how to use this
thing so had it easier to you went
through this what you probably did
you're like I'm not a geologist right
I'm not a certainly not probably an ie D
expert I don't really know what I'm
looking for so you did as you started to
look for maybe some attributes that
signified something was different about
that rock okay it's actually this one
dead center in the bottom right right
around six o'clock notice the little
darker the textures a little different
it doesn't really fit with all the other
rocks okay this is called attribute
substitution it's something that we use
when we're looking at a complex problem
our complex reality right that we can't
fathom all the data and sometimes we
don't have the data we need so we find
something that's different is a pretty
common it's a very common key eristic
that people will use to look for things
just to look for things that stand out
the problem comes when we use those
heuristics either inappropriately or
unconsciously and arrive at the wrong
answer right so just like we were I was
talking about earlier with somebody here
in our industry we commonly have the
threat vulnerability Klain and the terms
of sometimes used interchangeably
because they're introduced together
they're seen as flip sides of the same
coin cognitively we'll connect those two
things and we'll say and sometimes we
pick the wrong side of the coin the flip
side of a heuristic is cognitive bias so
you see something that looks like this
walking down the street if you just
spent the last three years of your life
in Afghanistan looking at piles of rocks
to recognize IEDs and you look at this
pile of rocks you might instinctively
start looking for an iud even though the
context is completely wrong right you're
in your neighborhood right it works the
other way too if you spend all of your
time in your neighborhood looking at
something like this your heuristic is oh
look at the pile of rock that could be
disastrous if you're walking past this
pile of rocks at the wrong time right so
there is a very large collection of bias
available we are all subject to all of
them all right what's interesting to me
is today there are memes about things
like cognitive bias my mother called me
to tell me about how her friend fell
victim to cognitive bias or and about
confirmation bias excuse me how her
friend was hauling dicta the
confirmation bias and was only using
facts that supported her case during the
conversation she never once acknowledged
that she's doing the same thing right so
we all do this it's not something that's
limited to any one party this is
fascinating stuff all right if you go
out and you like click on one of these a
day and read about it it's great what I
have found for me as a practitioner is
knowing all of these has done zero to
help me actually get around them right
being aware that I have confirmation
bias hasn't done anything to help me to
prevent it
in addition to these problems there's a
number of external forces that are
acting to undermine analysis work
product and what I'll really say is
rigor right increase tissue complexity
so things are getting harder to analyze
sometimes some people will say that
there's too much data others will say
there's not enough data a big big issue
is multidisciplinary teams right so
maybe you have the security aspects of a
problem maybe you have the legal aspects
of the problem then you have how do we
integrate how do we come up with a
solution that's actually effective right
that's both legal and security or the
flip side of that how do I use these
things how do I usually the legal
aspects to inform my security decisions
security decisions to inform legal
positions increase information sharing
the big it was a big assumption out
there we're going to talk about
assumptions in a minute that information
sharing is always good right that's a
big push especially by companies that
are trying to sell information sharing
there's a big push for that within the
intelligence community with the
government everybody's got to share all
their information the reality is if you
don't take that within an operational
context of why you want to share the
information it doesn't mean anything
the benefits of this can be that you
have differing perspectives from
different organizations and more
perspectives are always good diversity
of thought is always good expertise this
version if you're a technical expert you
might not be an expert on well in the
news on say
rushon information warfare doctrine or
the Chinese information warfare doctrine
or why somebody from Russia might not
care that their malware and that their
entire off was blown right because
because you don't understand the culture
you're looking at the technical aspects
and that assumption can lead and those
assumptions can lead to two problems
because you're not a domain expert also
the lines are starting to blur between
who's collecting information or who's
collecting information who's analyzing
that information who the decision-maker
is right so you might be the
decision-maker for what to collect
because you think it will inform the
analyst right and if you're the next one
is the magis mental models this is a
huge problem all right when you don't
have diversity of thought you're going
to come to this everyone's going to come
to the same conclusion everybody and
that this goes back to attribute
substitution right if you're where
people are forcing diversity through we
need more we need more women we need
more minorities we need these things
right that does not guarantee diversity
of thought I agree that we need those
things for other reasons but it doesn't
enforce diversity of thought the only
way you can enforce diversity of thought
is to actually map out what people are
thinking and compare them right so if
you're not measuring your diversity of
thought you things start to fall apart
but how do we do that we need to
externalize our thought process right so
everybody's been talking about models
there was lots of discussion about
models what really are models there a
way to externalize our thought process
right there are things that allow us to
community communicate and convey what we
are thinking
sometimes we do the we do this for
ourselves typically we want to external
eyes so that you shared built on and
easily critiqued we don't generally like
that last one
nobody wants to be critiqued all right
however if you want to build rigor in
this field if we want to build rigor not
only in analysis but in security we have
to be open to critique with it be open
to making the wrong assessment and we
have to be in this this is one of the
reasons that I'm I was so excited about
this conference right because that's
really what this conference seems like
to me it's it's a place for people to
come and openly bring ideas without
being concerned about being right or
wrong structured analytic techniques so
this is we're going to get start getting
into some practice right that's there's
55 odd structured analytic techniques
that are part of this taxonomy okay
they're roughly broken down into well
it's on the slide so you've got
decomposition for and which allows you
to kind of break down the problem idea
generation a lot of that is just
variations on brainstorming scenario and
indicators and then you know hypothesis
generation that's a big one that right
most people will go with their one
hypothesis built built they'll take that
thing that they think it is and they'll
just run with it and you've got you know
assessment cause and effect challenge
analysis there's a if you're not
formalizing the the process of
challenging your own ideas in what you
do then you cannot really claim that
you're being rigorous and conflict
management so up here we got decision
support but I want talk about conflict
management once you start challenge
analysis you're going to need a way to
deal with conflict okay because if
you've got three or four people who have
strong opinions sitting in the same room
they're going to disagree and they're
all going to stick to their guns and
they're all going to so there has to be
an actual formal process a big part of
this of this process is externalizing
right it is capturing the entire process
right it's writing it down it is using
the tools that are available if you go
out and do it and do a search online for
this there are - like every every
analyst in the world has recreated the
spreadsheets needed to do this a
thousand times there are also online
services there's things that you can buy
there's packages park did one of the
first tools for for this and it's
released publicly because it was paid
for by the government that was part of
the agreement but from a practice Randy
Pearson wrote an article for general
strategic security a few years ago that
that kind of broke down what Master
thinkers do right how do they do it
if you're not a master thinker right if
you practice enough you will become one
and what what was the interesting thing
to me is that if you do system to
thinking enough if you do that rigorous
analysis and using that reasoning enough
it pushes you to start using it
intuitively it just kind of happens on
its own even when you don't externalize
it when you don't write it down even
when you don't use the tools this can be
a lot of fun at parties when you're
playing devil's advocate all the time
and then shift your position when you
win over the other guy right it makes it
makes conversation a lot of fun for
other people anybody who knows me has
probably called me on that a thousand
times so what are the five habit one
establish a culture of challenging key
assumption
we're going to go into each of these and
how to do this in a rigorous
externalized manner writing things down
always consider alternative explanations
including the null hypothesis and
deception alright in IT security
everybody jumps to the deception right
like how many people at some point we're
like oh my computer rebooted I'll be
happy right so you start looking for
malware at some point in every ant like
technical security analyst work life
they've done that typically it's pretty
early on because after a while you stop
caring
or you're taking precautions to protect
yourself so you don't have to care next
one is instinctively looking for
inconsistent data so that you can dump
the hypothesis is don't matter right so
the ideas that you have that don't
matter aren't supported by the data that
you have you can dump now there are some
problems with that because if you don't
have enough data right then that can
lead to a problem but there are other
formalized processes to deal with that
too
the next one is focused on the key
drivers that best explain what it's curd
is about to happen
so here really what you're doing is
you're looking not so much at the the
might grow of a data right you're
looking at big picture stuff right
what's larger than the problem that I
have or the question that I was asked
anticipating a customer's needs and
understand the overarching context for
analysis again this is kind of expanding
it out even a little bit more right so
that you're kind of trying to expand
from the specific question that you're
trying to do and you go out and then you
slowly come back in with different
perspectives so the first one the
challenging key assumptions so there's a
a nfat statistical analysis technique
called the key assumptions check so this
is a very systematic approach to
qualifying the assumptions that you've
made now the thing about assumptions is
their assumptions you might not know
that you've made them so if you don't
have a formalized process to actually
run through these then you're never
really going to know that you made an
assumption and whether or not it was
right or correct many of these things
actually require two or three people
because you need to bounce off of each
other right it's kind of hard to do some
of this stuff solo it's hard to find
identify your own assumptions so the
reason we do this is well it's up here
you guys can read the slide but
primarily it's about identifying your
assumptions so that you can remove them
so here's some examples of assumptions
that I've actually heard come out of
people's mouths or are related to things
that I've had to to work on so hacked by
hack back provides cyber deterrence okay
all right like why how best practices
will keep me secure I hate the term best
practices I know some other people in
this room if you said that same saying
yeah so like specific to an elf's
project I did several years ago Mike
reviser products improve security and
micro visor products will sell well now
those are flipside you know those are
interrelated right and I was asked to
identify whether or not a Mike reviser
would improve security and whether or
not it would sell well it turns out that
it did that the micro visor itself
improved security but the system in
which the entire ecosystem which it
relied was fundamentally flawed because
it was based on trusting DNS so
okay so I think you guys can all kind of
see where that goes
however the flipside of that was yes
they will sell remarkably well for a
while right it's just part of a business
intelligence project that I worked on
about whether or not we should acquire a
company so the method is it's as simple
as listening list you're working
assumptions right so how do you do that
the easiest way to do that is to go back
to the thing that you're trying to
identify you're trying to get a question
you're trying to answer and write your
answer and then systematically pick it
apart this is where having other people
help it's good right because you are not
going to probably be able to identify
your your own ascent assess each
assumption for support for example an
assumption might be that microfiber
products improve security great okay why
how what do they do is there a larger
ecosystem around it that there's a dip
that it depends on does that improve
security if I rely on it what happens if
that system gets broken down so as you
refine your assumptions you can boil
them down and then when it comes to your
unsupported functions like hey this is
yes the micro visor is great it's super
solid but it has this reliance on dns
for its functioning maybe we should go
take a look at how it interacts with DNS
as part of its trust model to see if if
that needs to be researched further
consider alternatives so the statistical
is going to say SAT kind of a mouthful
to keep saying there's a there's an
actual process for generating multiple
hypotheses we do this because by
generating in a formalized manner
multiplied policies we get confidence
that we're going to kind of cover the
right scenario
right it also allows us to challenge any
preconceived ideas if you go in with
your hypothesis of Iraq has weapons of
mass destruction and that's the only and
that's the classic example in this space
right Lee and you don't even check the
null hypothesis or the fact or you don't
check for deception because you don't
know that the source that told you that
it's correct then you're going to fall
apart so what's the method defining
issue by asking a question you jump in
with a lead hypothesis in this example
we're saying hey is an animal rights
activist group going to try to create a
negative sentiment using social media
against my company you flip that around
you turn it into a statement right you
go from the question the statement you
branched our variations on who what when
where and why typically only to pick two
or three sometimes you only need one
ends on the question so here we've got
PETA Viva nature watch so and then you
have to say well why would they try to
do this well primarily they probably
want consumers to not buy my product
they're trying to start a boycott they
might be trying to influence legislation
that's currently up right for it so you
can look at the timing it might be jus
just to try to gain media exposure but
petitions means whatever so you break
these things down you start to map them
out right you create variations and then
you stack rank them you just give them a
number do I think this is going to
happen - I think this is going to not
happen what's my confidence here again
this is primarily about covering a wide
range of ideas and then ranking them
against each other
identifying inconsistent data this is
now taking the data that you have and
mapping it with Tom about amount
okay good all right yeah I might the
timer didn't work so I'm going to burn
through this right competing hypothesis
method external eyes it basically crude
map like this by the way I have no
association with Direct Connect right at
all or like but I literally did started
to do this and found theirs and was like
okay this is good enough right
but basically what you're doing is
you're taking your data you're going to
map it this is actually not a very good
analysis because basically they take for
or against verses up I lost my place
here versus like kind of a more granular
scale but it gets the job done right so
if you've got to do something fast there
you go
focus on key drivers so what are the
folks what are the forces that you're
going to that are going to influence
what's what's happening next this is a
little graph about what's going to
happen to domestic radicalized groups
within the United States depending on
what happens right are they're willing
to play by the rules what's in a
mobilization capability right so if
they're let if they can mobilize and
they're not willing to play by the rules
and we're gonna have sporadic violence
if they can mobilize right you can look
at the graph so it is a fate and
understand I'm gonna go through that I'm
just going to blow past that other than
to say that really this is where you get
into like pre-mortem analysis and that's
when you get towards the end of your
project and you flip back and say okay
it's six months from now it's five years
from now whatever the timeframe is for
your analysis and you say I was
completely wrong why was I wrong right
that allows you to go back and check
everything from from a very wide view
down through your analysis
so this is actually one of my favorite
quotes you toot of mind is a sacred gift
and the rational mind is a faithful
servant we've created a society that
honors a servant has forgotten the gift
all this talk about rigor and science
and pushing things out and externalizing
and using system to thinking should
never undermine that of your your sense
to listen to your gut to create it at
the outset all right your instincts are
the product of your experience and if
you're an expert in your field you
probably have some pretty good instincts
about it the issue is when you're
starting out you don't have that
expertise how do you how do you get
started all right so that's it I don't
know if we have time for Q&A but I will
say that if you want to get started this
is the place okay if you if you want
kind of the early work by rich and fewer
psychology of intelligence analysis it
is it is a goldmine of information if
you're just looking for I want it now I
need I need something I can use right
now the the second book by your fierce
instructional techniques for analysis I
have copies of these books if you want
to flip through them this is a how-to
book it's a full lexicon it's a full
taxonomy it is everything that you need
to get started here and then if you want
to practice there's a great case studies
book that's it done any questions
I think I'm being punted so you can
answer