on the play of workers on the farm it's
like a terrible bad joke but what's the
picture of the cabin there the family
Swan had a family for 180 years or so is
here Bloomfield Iowa kind of the south
center of the state their cabin we was
the original cabin built by the Mormons
off your way out and cleaned up donating
that cabin to the Davis County
Historical Society Nick's on his site
with a bunch of other historical
buildings that's that's my plane to a
long long-standing tie with either a
couple the other things mandatory got
the sack ministry service which means
have to pay hundreds of dollars every
year to renew those and people's
organizations funded so I highly
encourage people from those
organizations about I have to paint
visually look we've been involved with
the works and here things they may see
yeah which worked out or listening which
worked out here there may be one or
towers he's off he's been around for a
number of years he's one point
and we had a congressman asked when why
would anybody ever do departmentof and
I've never used the Internet to attack
us I just seen yourself but he also
started to fill more gone back in 94 and
last year one said hey I'm being real
attire group so I may be a little bit
older whatever I don't want to keep
organizing this every year we can take
over 40 yeah sure
immediately followed by what did I just
do that's the important 20-plus years
army communications officer and a few
years of what trying warfare so we talk
about the drugs why why are we
interested in running for Bill fill this
out a little bit so I think most people
when you think of a drug what do you
think of coppers doing this day of you
you got that and there's somebody's got
a really cool YouTube video a real
small-scale what I think of okay we're
thinking of the like a rerun or
predatory bird yeah okay so my big boys
okay about that big
little something that crawls walks full
credit
like amongst our own water we've seen
one sorry on the surface or subsurface
and some of that due to search and
rescue that's been a driver like the
little bitty small land ones
how do I go in there there's been
earthquake there's this class building
and I've seen for years where people try
and single camera in there now to
actually have something with treads and
it will go through these little spaces
they help verify Thursday another reason
we people can't drones can I get an
economic or competitive advantage with a
bit of technology the biggest reason for
using drugs is to get to areas that are
hard for humans to access or they're
dangerous for humans taxes think about
it using the the earthquake example or
can I try the tree can I get to
something else that's hot it's hard to
reach if I could if I hadn't pulled
ahead and change the light bulbs in here
and I had something I could do where I
didn't have to be the ladder that would
be pretty nice working that's actually
the real reason
I'm now doing research and I can out
justify those Amazon purchases and
figure out when but it's now officially
a tax write-off
because it is for a research talk about
the replacing humans and dangerous
situations and some of that's because
it's a hazardous environments there's
chemicals those other things that you
don't want to actually get into yourself
and we sort of need them for industrial
uses where how how many just look like
how many people will work on a farm how
many people would have worked with the
mortgage machinery yeah if you have this
is power take-off shaft so it's on the
back of tractors suspending thing you
connect equipment to it is the spinning
bar with no shield
if you touch it that would happen so no
people that lost farms lifetime's law
fliers
in dangerous thing if I can look there
I'm going to be doing something about
this ah to me talk about the size of the
drum you're looking at totally long 20
feet long
why can't I have a little tractor be a
bro why can't I just go ahead and look
at my happy to say you've got a robot a
robot back there or you can look at the
app and you could say go ahead and clean
this room will do this
what can I just say go ahead plow this
field go ahead and harvest this go ahead
and send over the green truck so I can
have a combine empty is loaded to that
and they keep going a big driver for a
lot of the technology is laborers
expensive now it used to be that labor
was pretty cheap and equipment was more
since lolcat equipment is expensive and
we have labor that's expensive
so how do we knock some casa well maybe
if I keep the expensive equipment I can
get the human labor cough I'm going to
be able to take money and become more
efficient more profitable
one thing with any new technology it
ruins old television shows movies worst
enemies in the world why is last he keep
putting tinny in the well well now
because I had thrown that was following
I know that lastly some want to keep
putting Timmy in the water
these lassie separated from the boy I
don't have the problems anymore and no
longer have a television show but look
at you the screen movie screen movies or
horror movies but they had a cell phone
they just say hey where are you person
so I'm going to walk down the star
hallway texting groans a lot of that
just a little bit on the search of
rescue movement of people and animals
from the farm folks you know absolutely
livestock they knew people like lagoons
where they're trying to get large groups
of people from one room to another
whether you know you know different
things were meant for the cops there was
last week was Carolina Panthers saw
there was inclement weather that was
coming in so the big screens of the
stadium work everybody go stand in the
access corners and got this quash of
people coming in and you had a few
security people trying to get back up
into the stands to shoot a few people
out there right I'm just going to sit
here and wait it out because how bad can
it actually
looking at math roll
what kind of details something most
people use like Google Maps these ways
I'll find your areas you can see the
satellite video you can look at the
tress rather you get impressions with
that I'm looking at forward hydrofoil
use we are looking at a board with an
area that's heavily trafficked and they
want to use drones field going and help
map was there that satellite which is a
few weeks old if I'm trying to figure
out I've got two weeks in between drinks
where I've got a few days of the field
router area where do I need to go first
which ones are getting most recent where
we're going to do direct my efforts
first loss the highest priority if I can
send something into goal over and not
taking that human cost not taking that
labor to get in there
also what monitoring anybody like hiking
or hunting spending time outdoors and
seen game cameras or pictures of the
game cameras where people at Dundee the
scaredy goes person that was standing
behind her shoulder because it's like
videos you saluting them we think a lot
of times somebody they put the game
camera out there and then they echo back
out and one of the things that we've
looked at with the drums is get the
motors are the big power rating so if
I'm going to have this but I set it down
I can run the camera for many hours what
if I have to go out leave my house it
goes out it's that's where I went to
satellite rail looking at an access fee
to a property security type aspect is
there monitoring is the camera it could
be up linking through GSM sending images
back that way when the battery is
basically sort of bubbles when they come
back to recharge yourself I don't have
to walk out there every time and I know
that being regular objects once again
saying labor of safety time
Thank You loose
how many of you moved just add that
couple toys let's hold them together
okay how many spouse would say that you
pulled it together some toys to see what
would happen
this is an example this one was actually
developed in child their reasonings
around they have you see three out power
lines if you've ever worked around when
Trinity typically you're going to be
doing something like that you've got to
go in you've got to do shut down the
power that's going through there there's
a lot of coordination that has to happen
you have to be able to get
work on power limits you have to do a
little coordinating as I shut it down
everybody did it's down the screen they
no longer have electricity so you're
disrupting that or making more of a
problem for other people you have all
the safety to make sure the people are
going to actually be working on blinds
don't get electrocuted kids
in this case look turtle yeah I've got
this drum I can go in I can fart off
this agree it's within the certain
amount of our time I'm going to be
damaging the evening of the logins or in
the insulators or any of the towers or
other structures so it's within
acceptable parameters I don't have to
disrupt our to anybody else I'm able to
go ahead and just deploy this whenever
there's a large-scale storm and some
understanding is Iowa's been doing quite
a bit of work of getting their power
lines below ground is that through my
through your area
distribution but not transmission okay
there's still a fair amount then after a
storm that limbs the went down somewhere
we're taking out power line and few
folks away from ever come back and had
novel work baracy and some
the line wasn't actually broken the
Linley's having me on the line and they
had to go ahead and shut down power so
that you really went well if they could
go ahead and just go ahead and run that
down
[Music]
let's talk a little bit about what if
somebody uses drones one look into what
actually goes into building your own
drum and you can pass this one around I
will send this one around the other side
believe it or not this one actually the
same direction and ones next to each
other are going to be rotating jobs and
directions to the pigeon wings to be
different that's what a thousandth of
stabilization at the quadcopter they
were all turning the same direction it's
just not going to be a happy day
you have your flight forward if you have
your battery you've got a receiver you
can have cameras we have other things
attached to it but real basically this
this is what it takes to get one one and
we do have videos from drone warmers
where we're applying this base
that's just that way you can look at
some well you know I get a different
form factor you don't want to be able to
do something else with it
my wife's pretty sure that was my first
attempted we need to gather a drum
well that's the actual component C or
the weather is a quadcopter like that
remember something that's terrestrial
all drugs have a but one thing in common
is the system may think okay I've got
that
that's the drum well that's a piece of
that actual system look at it on the
bright side so I've got the drum and
this is going to have its payload it's
going to be dealing with he'll be doing
collection ie it's got a camera I want
to be able to see what's out there
we need the Liberty I need to drop off
so using the partner would be really
nice sometimes and out in the field for
six hours have you had much of a break
and being able to get a nice glass of
iced tea brought out with impressive
life I've heard a few people that said
hey I would really like on the weekend
if I can press the button the drug would
go indication it would Rebecca a
beverage the navigation that's what's
between the controller and the drone
usually we're going to be looking at
something that's running on a heart a
lot of the drugs out there
once you're spending thousand downloaded
or less on it's very public frequencies
or something that's license it's very
easy to interfere with those I was
talking with the president of the drone
recently and
we've got 11 channels and our goal is
what we tell people did
here's your channel assignment don't
turn on your controller while somebody
else's reason to switch more medication
in there more protection on what's
happening that got the operators it's
not a technical technology piece but it
is a key part of the system if you're
put if you have somebody to make a
hurricane response or something for me
other a bigger disaster and then you
have I need to have this drone system go
in there and take a look or be able to
go do recovery form stuff off power
lines now only got one person did it
that person happens to be out of the
country on vacation well your drone
system has a useful effect if you're
looking at more from the nation state
how I'm concerned about it if I was
going to be attacking drone systems I
need more focus on the left side where
are those components who's been able to
do so
the plan for this we need to do stuff
with distributions what I'm ordering
actually what's going to be out there on
the system
what listener would see ahead type of
Nephi one this the first driver on Mars
prior to curiosity but you think about
that that's their only spend some
additional proper challenge is when
you're dealing because you've got very
long delay time between we are setting
up your your message
TURN RIGHT 10 degrees and when it
actually does turn right it's not like
something where we have our whispers if
you offer one of those that could be
dynamically interacting with your
looking at our doors usually between the
command being executed be able to see
what happens regardless that when you
get to perform some of the same
components in there looking at one of
those clodhoppers or the clipboard is
going around you're looking for
stabilization is there Jarboe that's
going to be not like the cool kid toy it
works all this thing is inside
axes and arrows but that's what's adding
the stabilization being able to look at
PMT position navigation your time so you
can pull like that we call all about GPS
what if you're Mary where GPS isn't
working right now and by that it's not
like you're going to go out there and oh
no satellites are working in the middle
of slaughter but there's somebody else
that was running and tilting on the
streets but it is wherever it was
talking about mysterious other places
where people are turning on cameras and
New York City they were having some
probably the tvbs-g at one of the arrows
it turned out what was the cause of it
there was it the delivery guy and his
company is sort of trapped in their
vehicles with GPS he didn't like being
tracked and he also might have nap in
the afternoon so he were really small
GPS here and he was putting his people
he turned it on be able to have his half
in the afternoon find it happened to be
on the approach to Newark so they would
suddenly be planes coming in to land in
their cruisers yes
causes long story FBI involvement
delivery driver is a trouble particular
yeah and they take a very dim view of
interfering with license
frequencies yes and it was like that he
has the map of what's happening with TPS
looking at single spring it's like 14
zeros
before you actually start to see numbers
so a 1 watt transmitter on GPS
frequencies is going to pretty much
knocked out anything
a small has anybody seen at the picture
to scale up on geosynchronous satellites
in Norway they are so to heavily
bastardize that if this is the planet
right here this is laid out here and to
get the full transmission from GPS
satellite as it goes through that cycle
one is very low power is that this big
transmission angle and so they correct
me if I'm wrong it's like 11 minutes or
15 minutes to get the whole transmission
so the people GPS system - - however
long it would take quite a while before
you have to get your position line now
there's the photo in both the full
ephemeris data is transmitted every 10
minutes by each burn their offset I've
done GPS spoofing work for various
reasons
so the longer you the GPS devices these
days will cache the information and
because the birds don't maneuver they
can extrapolate forward the older
devices didn't so took them forever to
get their additional effects so you can
get reasonably accurate fairly quickly
just offer the initial positions
you still need for birds to get decent
that's all the time like you know where
they're all transmitting a time-based
signal you're basically mathiang based
on based on what the time base is speed
of light to where the ephemeris data
says that the voters should have been at
the time the transmission and it's this
a key assist for system of equations
that has to be solved back yeah that's
good math thank you back and make my
brain also if you look at your phone
whatever you're doing the location
settings on your phone you have a
results of pulling off the cell towers
around advertising technology that you
just put in there will consider what
happens we start looking at bio-organic
and if you search for your own
cockroaches you'll find two different
things
where they were steering the Madagascar
hissing cockroaches university- the
other is there's actually this big
cockroach drum you can get off Amazon
that looks really freaky and if you have
children and your children pullin cables
through that wall yes yes looking at the
four McCartney example life they're
starting to make like three we've got a
bulldozer stuck okay well these happened
next well I need to go get this cable
and I need to go to slaughter for them
on it and get it hooked in the southern
front I can you probably have a drum it
is going to pull some 550 cord out to
you and then you can use the cord to
pull the cable and you're not slogging
through as much but wait are actually
doing in this iteration of this durable
cockroach
- and work implementation they their
approach to the 2n campus and it's
basically like I will shock your head
over here or I'll shock your head over
there the they've been working more with
me I wanted to go do this to this
location or I'm going to actually start
or stop or extend its wings or press a
button and actually disappear that
that's good for regional research some
of the rest issues have some grad
students that figured out how to write a
grant unless it sounds pretty cool but
think about how that can get built out
more World War tip Russians were doing
is either the Russians of the Nazis
somebody will under the category of
adversaries of bad guys we're trying to
train dogs to blow up tanks it's the
Russians it was the Russians in that
they were training that the t-34 and
when they turn about loose under Nazis
they like
and well it produced you to the melting
the tracks in water and what did we
simply start the dogs we will put food
under the tank the dogs would run under
this name to get food and then they were
going to take them out of the
battlefield we are going to strap
explosives to it so it's now a suicide
bomber and we're going to print loose
and it's going to button to the tanks
for the other side and blow them up but
then they forgot that their tanks were
closer to the dogs and want the dogs
were already trained on so big service
if they had the circuit court divided
opinion of dogs here and send it across
the field but they didn't I could
definitely see we're looking at really
small sizes if I buy organic thing I'm
not we're as worried about everyone we
talk about the using the drum for the
camera and the motors taking most of the
stuff well I'm not having to run the
focus it I'm just running the
transmitter because the motor is coming
out of whatever the cockroach's
generating power from and if it stops
and eat something because it's not
terribly selective break it'll continue
to operate longer and actually the works
gonna be powering the circuit board yeah
but I'm sure there's red still working
already pass around the airframe on
there talked about this event power
source the counter-rotating plays really
whatever you're looking at anything that
any drone swap becomes a big
consideration not so anybody know what
swap is good size weight and help it's
kind of like a three-legged stool I want
you to figure out what I'm going to do
in the drug war so like we got some
really tiny little drums they hated
guards type their goals and they've got
cameras you can do for horses beautifly
we've got your life one to five minutes
on the outside you get longer flight
time with one more guy it's also going
to have more noise it's going to be able
to have more of a payload it's going to
take more time to charge and it's going
to need a bigger space to navigate
through so let's look at those different
considerations I need to balance this
law generally you're going to want to be
able to get the most of like time with
most operational time so looking at
those different things if I'm able to
definitely whatever's got a carbon fiber
frame so that helps reduce the power
requirements this particular drug called
the danger girl funny how efficient Fox
they were showing that at con and where
it was being used to attack networks or
attack systems one example they were
showing they'd had to go hover outside
an office and it was attacking through
the Logitech USB dongle so nobody took
over the computer the drum board folks
we've got a design in the call skyjacker
they're working on in version two right
now that will get publicly released but
it's kind of modular arm so if you want
to run bigger blades or bigger motors if
you do that exactly
essentially swap out what you want to do
and when looking at that this journal in
particular
example the ARBs are actually they
aren't attached for solo dealers are
there they'll snap on and snap off
previous generations of drones listen to
anybody it's dealt with industrial
applications are on the farm you know
space it really adds up how many people
the best version following out for
airplanes the general rule is they get
some phenomenal dad's two is one one
it's not so if you jump you have two
parachutes and you're certified just
want to generally jump into one
parachute treat like I've got enough
because so if I have to absolutely get
something done before work I like ever
done in systems where I'd like to have
something as a back what the
things that we're doing with villagers
we're having detachment payloads and
with that you send the drum then you can
drop off the payload and do whatever you
need to do that's running a camera so
you can watch the game colonel great if
it's got Callie and some customization
on there so you're using that as a pivot
point to get into the network because
you want to get John Deere's new designs
or maybe you actually want to get the
farm work for the tractor and protected
and downloaded from some Ukrainian
motorcycle because they don't want
people he wants to be able to do
maintenance on their tractors that might
be something that big you're interested
in Galilee legalities I'm primarily
looking at supply trucks are going to
have more restorations because they have
a some of the self restrictions you
still have if you're looking at real
drums or once they're holding a little
bit of water or two there
and you know it's really the changes to
look from city to city but you can ask
yourself a few questions about okay I
want to fly this trip
you know the operating space is it I've
got 100 acres I'll probably be bothering
somebody else do I have makers that I'm
in the flight line for an airport
probably got working servants I need to
go look at what else is in that space so
great I highly distasteful God and his
neighbor was flying a drum there's some
different reports over whose backyard it
was flying in but the gentleman that
legal proceedings started said his
daughter was sunbathing in the backyard
agree to the trial with a shotgun so
then you have a person I just worked
with trouble placing you have a person
discharged by her firearm in in a
neighborhood lots of things that you
know
so if you don't mind our if I'm going to
be sending it up in the air or the
neighbors having a pool party is that
going to cause some issues even it's not
a legal issue
it's probably an issue with the
neighbors and I like to get a lot of my
favors
of course it goes the pikey our personal
firearm we've actually never seen
anybody like that in the US that's may
have counterbattery fire
looking at countermeasures what are you
and I probably don't want to get into
shooting there for the neighbors because
I had a drum
my wife won't let me buy any more
schools let me put the toys on Amazon
with that okay great I got the system
you I going back whether it's the supply
chain or the cold work diner and her
being or interactive that system to make
it worse no less less life maybe there's
a few things out there talk about common
data channels sometimes it's easy you
just get another controller you're
clicking on channel you do a few
different toggles and their drums not
playing a few of the commercial drums
everyone's got to use bill we're using
Wi-Fi here the drum was a Wi-Fi access
point so if you send a neon packet then
you became a race condition who could
connect to it and take over control from
some of the drums if they lose can lose
that deadly to this control station
they'll have a return to basic and they
will go back to where they originated
they go home
testing if there had to be lose the GPS
signal and it would lose the other
signal the control signal it might just
sat down but they lost it in a certain
sequence like GPS person to control a
few drums before didn't flip over to the
program which I really didn't like the
neighbor and they haven't had that model
drone I would probably be interested
Betsy
I was looking at a calculator what's the
cost any basing the equals there that
somebody was talking in Europe so it was
pretty cool it's one of the Nordic
countries I believe they trade people to
take out girls and like many other
things that makes them awesome YouTube
video but then you gotta maintain your
heel in the US is the paperwork and the
license seem to be able to have an eagle
this is a lot like hundreds of thousands
of dollars
it's very pretty yes but also anything
remain this so if I want to do the
system great I'm going to have this
powder system and if you search the
counter Julia s what kind of drunk
there's lots of companies out there
Bishop Fox they look at once the ninety
different claims on what was available
and they actually validated with two of
them but let's let me say I got this
great thing people jammed it'll do this
one company another technology was it
would identify multiple drugs and it
would talk to one running at times been
stopped but he can only talk to one at a
time so it's kind of like I'm Mario when
you have like your goes but if you look
at the go to the stop and think have a
lump in your faculties to and in the
circum the agony and it really look like
that when the drugs are coming
they work at the frequency I'm not
talking about the transmission
frequencies but how often can I use them
great a few hundred thousand dollars
I've got to deal okay I can do these one
equal to take out a drum well there's a
second drummer I want to deal with that
my Eagles still resetting it does eat
lunch it's like 30 minutes just like
don't go swimming don't attack a drone
dr1 so how often can you use valuable or
if you're using a pending system how how
quickly can I take that into
consideration
yeah so Talk That awkward activities
that we use with drug seems something is
happening right now
fishing talk about hunting wildlife my
father worked for the conservation
department you'll see where they were
tagged a bunch of waterfowl they send
out fires big net across the field
but being able to send a drum into an
area to see what's going on I've seen
whatever it wasn't a journal but they
went in to place the camera on an eagle
nests you can see how big chicks were
developing information at recreation
area month whether it's during a storm
or it's just getting ready for what's
next
sometimes it's a team camper hounds or
lakes or where they're trying to
regulate how many people work for you
it's a shared resource but they know I
need to be able to or Park Rangers then
or I need to be able to do this or it's
just too suggestive that they're able to
that side of the lake people come in
through the access date the other side
anybody have any idea what's that's
hanging below he'll cover for someone
did you decide wait they're actually
begin it in the water and they hunt
submarines
if I got here from arcane things
anybody's gotta do something else has
friends what
fire of the boat we're not a remote
version where they can send it out there
has hovered defective water that's
generation C fire good thing where it
actually drunk are being used in fishing
this is an implement your closer to the
coast so there's some examples when
people are using it to get the bait out
beyond the surf this is it already hit
for you and they can actually see have a
better view where the fish are actually
in the water just like all the weight I
was miss judging based on temperature
and other things I was going a little
bit too far and maybe a little bit
further out so agricultural activities
to talk a little bit out of expecting
fields and crops working people that
have dealt with farms in the area do you
ever have the opportunity to sell the
grain so if I'm a little man I'm the
person buying the farmers I won't be
able to sell their soybeans to China I
need to buy for farmers and you sell for
more I need to make a problem I might be
interested if I
the pharmacy you like based on these
conditions I'm going to offer you this
much
really degrees Sultan and how are you -
turn that I'm going to send out some
drums over there fields I can look and
see with her standing water here over
these other conditions and I can make
that estimate earlier than advance -
maybe two weeks before harvest that
gives me a competitive advantage to
market because I was able to go out and
gather that information and there's also
a consideration of I don't own that
field I have something might have to
stuff over the admission is max in the
delivery if I make it I've recently sure
did a Kickstarter whatever it says bring
me a beer and get drunk live off and he
goes and comes back with the beverage I
could probably get $150 every male
between 1645 in the US I need to get off
the stage hominids are the questions
from the group
yes fans make the ability to make good
not make as much noise absolutely
I've seen her on that didn't write down
the prices I'm gonna Stacy's $2,000 so
the government type price is not obvious
or amateur but if the drum was like up
there the ceiling it
not here and it had a few clobbered
arrange and the other thing is moderate
fighting some the drumhead and I can
location but also if you look at silent
computer cool there was a lot of work
that's been done on the shape of the fan
feathering the back edge it changes the
airflow changes the noise was drawn
that's my chance to lift as well
epic answer any other questions in the
hallway as well as beyond the edge has
go vertical to post in the drone
portability to see what's being built
there or your hands on something
encourage you to do so so the drum parts
reach out to us they're happy to give
you additional information and for the
work on the conference when it's look
how it started and we've got that going
deliver first through third in the DC
area and Midlands directly to reach me
on Twitter thank you all for your time
and thanks