and this is kind of the spin off of that
law I'm going to be talking about using
cyber attacks or how they are cyber
operations and how they've been used to
leverage economical warfare against
countries right so this is what this
talk is is not done you want to get
technical would have to do something
else
okay so let's talk about economic
warfare this is not a new term right
countries the big news there for a long
time it's the use or the threat to use
economic means against the country
borders the weekend is coming and
therefore it reduces the political
military power and we all we all know
you probably must you watch Fox News
right
no see so we have all these trademark
dos been going on forever it's a run in
other countries that we have boycotted
sanctions tariffs have you ever read any
documents from the State Department of
the UN especially for like Iran for
their nuclear program I mean they've
been blocking Iran in all kinds of ways
I mean they first twelve billion dollars
and capture that and gave it back didn't
pay any interest on their twelve billion
dollars they had secured for what the
decade or more so this is not something
new country's been doing it for a long
time back in World War two harness
special operations in the British
military
they ran a program for Special Ops
called the Ministry of economic warfare
so we had a 16,000 person unit that was
also tasked with sabotage struck you
know destroying things and going out and
doing reconnaissance operations the part
of their mission also was try to go
ahead and cost economic chaos in the
Nazi countries and you in
take down factories bowls or whatever
they need to do and they would call this
chaos and so they ran this whole program
and the only way I found out about this
is I think I was doing a lecture to some
intelligence people that written in the
church or wardens and it was walk down a
hall and I saw this thing ministry of
economic warfare and I had never heard
about it so that's how I know about this
but this this rant for throughout the
war in his stop what we're going to talk
about something new this concept is is
fresh
when I say fresh within the last couple
of years and the concept is called
cyber-enabled economic warfare Cee
theather and this was from the Hoover
Institute was one of the first papers
they came out to doctors and Hooters
dude they wrote up an 18 page paper of
42 page paper on this topic and it's
been several other papers but there was
the best papers they are so what it
really is if you talk about it if the
key word here is warfare we all know
what more Paris the modifier is cyber we
actually have economics and that a
modifier cyber is a weapon but the
targeting is the economy and the
objective here is to win some type of
war whatever that word is
okay this is a definition you can read
it but it really is about using spider
to go after another nation to actually
weaken their economy in some way whether
that's military power or political power
is there everyone is in whatever red
just nice look soft power it's a it's an
old book salt powers the concept if
you've ever read that book or you've
heard that term I'm sure salt powder
salt powers when we apply diplomatic or
economic pressure in some other country
instead of using the military so we try
to influence another country in some way
but not with military power and cyber
here what they're trying to do with this
is trying to influence and company a
country in some way to actually cause
some type of damage whether it's
political damage sentiments but make the
country unstable somehow war caused and
not be able to actually have national
security so but we have to classify
these attacks and not every attack falls
into this bucket the first thing for
these attacks they have to be the
cybernated right Stuxnet if you look the
Stuxnet we all know Stuxnet and
[Music]
such that was not economic they wouldn't
fall in this category because it wasn't
about economics without undermining
Iran's nuclear program it hasn't caused
some type of economic harm and that's
the big kicker here how do you actually
figure out if an attack causes harm if
you if you've studied any of the 10 K or
10 Q reports that come out of the SEC
for any of the corporations that have
that had cyber attacks I know every one
of you has gone out to the SEC right and
read these reports of like when Sony had
an attack know so if you read these
reports you can find very little cost
damages in there related to an attack
it really doesn't show up on their
bottom line at all and your stock market
prices normally it has very little
impact so these are really hard to
quality and it has to be great national
security so the Sony attack doesn't
qualify because it was only about a
movie and it has to have some type of
strategic intent it has so any attack if
it's any classified and economic attack
you know the cybernated like not
it hasn't that these four categories so
if it doesn't it doesn't qualify so in
an economic war tear for you if we just
look at economic warfare in general chai
Hut is living against the United States
you know they have a long term game to
actually become the superpower of the
world it's been going on for decades and
eventually I hate to say so that the
United States will not be a superpower
and your lifetime it'll actually not
China will become a superpower probably
another 15 years or less and it's really
about economics China has had the long
game if you know anything about China
and companies going to go in there Intel
went to China decades ago and Intel when
they went there that we're going to
build a wafer factory and so the Chinese
government mandates when you take a
company there you actually have to hire
people that are Chinese and trained it
in research about your technology so
they went there to save money because it
was cheaper labor to go there but they
also had to pay Chinese PhDs master's
degrees and so to actually start
learning how to make chips now trying to
make makes pretty damn good
and but if you read the reports back
when this actually happened
the soccer court said they were not
worried about China because they said
that China is at least two generations
behind it so they were not afraid that
China would actually leapfrog Intel but
they're pretty close to getting ahead of
in time that's a long-term game it took
decades to get there
okay economic warfare or espionage so I
got dragged in one time to help this
company they it was it was actually
about their technology for some reason
they were not being purchased every
other company around them was getting
purchased for billion dollars but this
one company wasn't even purchased so
when I started digging into the company
I started finding out that the patent
they had was I looked at the bat and
they had and then I looked at the
patents related backwards to them you
know little pieces they took of other
people but then I found out that some of
the employees that had worked there that
left went often took the stuff and
created this these new patents for this
company made me pay attention to it and
so the reason they were not getting
purchases because there was this is they
had this better technology out here on
this side
so the question that company had and
they're out of business now they lose
for all their money and they couldn't
make anything after I think they got 168
million in investment and they went down
the tubes but the question that came up
is you know would this be an economic
warfare attack or an economic espionage
attack and really it was about SP now
it's not warfare because it's internal
employees it took the information and
left and then recreated it and then had
a better company than the one they left
okay so we're going to talk about this
program right here the Joint Strike
Fighter Joint Strike Fighter is the most
expensive military program in history I
mean these these planes have been going
on for decades being built they're being
sold to part two our five eyes so New
Zealand Australia Canada and UK the
United States was part of the five eyes
that's what they call it and so they did
sole sole there and they still haven't
been 100% built yet so as you know or
may not Joint Strike Fighter program has
been compromised
I actually got told that you never go
back to a defense conference again
because I showed up at the defense
conference and they give a lecture
collecting information from the internet
and how to use it for espionage and it
was about Joint Strike Fighter program
and so I had all this detailed
information I had weird classified
shipments of certain materials were
coming from I think I actually found a
FedEx shipping information where it was
going
I actually knew where they were getting
their armaments and bullets everything
for the system some of the electronics I
also was able to find through the
metadata and some of the documents that
are out there that someone in the
program was stealing diamonds and
putting on their iPod at the time and
they're putting under a file called
Aretha Franklin's greatest hits and they
were stealing these documents is putting
them on there and taking them out and
then bringing it back you know it was
like Tom
what was going on so I got banned from
the conference because I put all this
out there and Lockheed Martin now as a
counterintelligence program because of
it they tried to sue me for word and
everything else then whole
counterintelligence program so this
information is easily to obtain if you
do any data mining and let me tell you
about data might see one of those some
about the Joint Strike Fighter program
figure out every place the Joint Strike
Fighter program existed then what you do
is you collect all the information from
Lockheed and all the suppliers it's all
publicly available fusilat you go look
at the patent databases and then you
don't have to get all that open source
information they start going to the
universities that are close to these
facilities where these things are being
built because guaranteed employees at
Lockheed or going to universities and
they're getting PhDs and master's
degrees and writing the papers theses
and dissertations on subjects that are
interesting now you can collect all
those masters and dissertations and you
pull it together and now you have a
great picture of the Joint Strike
Fighter program very easy and so the
Chinese have also had traditional spies
were in there the Chinese also did
bought equipment that was a big Whittle
in other places and they stole laptops
and eventually they got enough
information to build a fighter
it is our improvement and out the door
it looks almost identical
firefighter almost they had so the
United States spent tons of money
billions and billions of dollars to
develop this fighter and the Chinese
walked right ahead didn't have to do all
the rnd they got all this information
and they'll build their own fire and
they've done this over and over over
over in the United States that's why I
did the did the defense industrial base
now has really strict cybersecurity
requirements because they've been
pillaged by the Chinese
okay so anyone have a security clearance
you didn't
were you in this breach I know I was so
this is OEM officer Berson hansman
they do a lot of the security clearances
so if you ever have to do a security
clearance you have to fill out the paper
I think it's an SF 184 or what is it
what is that number or 84 so this is a
big long form you have to fill out and
if you're getting the top secret
clearance top secret STI clinics which
which I had for a long time you have to
fill out a massive amount of paperwork
they then send people out to interview
the people you told them to interview
and then they find new people to
interview and they find more people to
interview and eventually they have a
whole dossier I mean seriously
because I have mine it's like this day
and they get it all together and then
they give it to the OPM guys who's doing
this and OPM stores all this information
and maintains this record but also part
of this record set their information
fingerprints so what happened allegedly
the Chinese broke into Opia across the
internet how the heck they
and then we're able to find the data
which was in database and they stole 20
1.5 million records
so these dossiers were all electronic
they were all started some type of
database I have no idea how to restore
you know if there were raw document
printouts you know digital images I had
no idea and they stole it plus long debt
if you ever got a clearance you have to
get your fingerprints and your
fingerprints
you know it's on a basic card you give
it to the part of your security
clearance and they take it and then they
take those fingerprints and run up
against the FBI FBI database
they don't they'd run it against the FBI
database and the FBI says hey you know
boom burners printed on you he can't get
a security clearance or he's clean he
can have security points well so the
Chinese allegedly got all this
information and there wasn't something
that happened recently that people are
now saying what was it the Chinese but
partisan system bigger print said that
the big Agra came back and said and they
got five point six million fingerprints
it doesn't really matter they came to
anything with it okay have you ever
taken a fingerprint card you get
actually on here to printer card if you
can take the photograph of the
fingerprint for biometric systems it
does if you can send that signal because
if you take the fingerprint off then you
can actually take that do the math
against
in the database or a certified metric
system and you can set that fingerprint
into the biometric system without
actually presenting and actually
fingerprint and so you can actually
falsify someone actually accessing
something that comes back this is proven
technology I've seen it work so stilling
these fingerprints for people that have
security clearances that potentially
have to law go with some type of
biometrics is a big deal because
eventually biometrics are going to be
common some people you're going to log
on into your house you know over a
computer system right you're gonna have
some type of login I mean on your eye
like on your iPhone you sorry got my
fingerprint right I always have to use
my favorite perfect so this is a big
deal but one of the things that just
came up recently was there was a malware
writer that was allegedly type this they
got caught writing malware and you also
had part of this data the question is
you know was he given some of the data
was his malware actually used in this
attack there's a lot of little questions
going on so it's not clear if that guy
actually was involved attack or was this
a scapegoat somehow
so yesterday during my lecture you heard
all about Saudi Aramco with my theories
on the attack again said this is not
about that attack so let's talk about
Saudi Aramco because this is why someone
would want to attack them Saudi Aramco
is still based on this chart was brutal
is producing the most amount of barrels
of oil in the world and the second of
their you see is gas bomb who knows
where that is that's Russia that's the
main Russian oil company so Saudi
Aramco's this is most oil here how do
you think that this Kingdom and Saudi is
fun does anyone know through oil
the country's revenue from Aramco the
oil companies Aramco is 87 percent of a
brand Coast money goes to fund the
kingdom and to and if you ever been to
the series I mean I've seen more Rolls
Royces driving down the streets and it
parked it you know places it's
unbelievable I've ever met neither who
went out of the pond where start a
well-off guy bought a sports car drove
it off the lot in salsa went out to the
same sports car and he took his car back
because it couldn't have the same car
someone else in the country this is how
this works
so when 87 percent of the country is
funded through oil
recently the new crown prince that was
coming in to take potentially take over
the Kings place in the future he wanted
to actually create mega ramp coat a
public company right now it's a it's
owned by the state he wanted to take 5%
of the company only 5% and put it on the
stock market
how much money do you think 5% of Saudi
Aramco is worth what a sniper come on
take a guess five hundred billion two
trillion dollars
five companies were they estimated that
Saudi Aramco they could put in Donald
Trump president Trump wanted it to be on
the u.s. sake change so he was
advocating on Twitter about unity or
suctioning it would have changed the
whole economy because they had investors
from all over the world they got they
would have had to make infusion of cash
and it would have helped the Saudi
regime and you know they've been buying
tons of new military by the Trust's and
they've been putting down protests and
killing activist and a bunch of other
side well
not too long ago would it mean Saudi
Aramco's now been attacked twice and you
can have it yesterday I don't believe
arrived in the first attack recently
they have a new attack against them
because the Saudi Aramco goes down the
whole revenue that they have they lose
it for whatever how long they down so
they can physically destroy equipment
and these wall fills or the the
refinement centers that's a revenue for
the country is drops because they make
this this company makes billions and
billions a day
I mean it is France really pours cash
so of course people are seeing is a lot
this would be the second one
you know 2017 you know now it's a nice
modest Ron everything's about Iran
he's unclear if this was a Ron trying to
take down the oil it could have been any
other anyone else it could have been
Russia want to take it down to become a
leader that area it could be a wrong but
the key here is its Saudi Aramco is a
huge part that's how they get that
people are going to continue to go after
and and what they're trying to do is not
you know damage the wool company per se
they try to dance a Saudi lifestyle they
try to damage the regime is currently
there and try to do some type of
replacement because there are people in
Saudi right now that says that countries
to moderate because now they're allowing
women to drive and they want to go back
to where women aren't driving where
women are wearing more traditional Islam
Muslim cut clothes wear burqas and face
shields stuff they want to get back to a
more harsh Islam and that's what's going
on in the country they're having this
dual fight right now
and this
whoever uses the advanced operators on
Google alright so right here I wanted to
know based on the slide that's for this
it told me what type of product was
attacked
what type of ICS product was attack so I
went out and just did a quick LinkedIn
search for that type of product Saudi
Aramco
I didn't want Maillard because people
post articles online and they post up
only technical articles or little blog
entries so they post something so I've
been home malware cyber attack including
thousands of employees within the
company that that are there so if you
were going to target this potentially
they could have been some of the targets
were actually you know fish to get into
their systems
this is the way you actually if you have
it if you ever go right now where I'm
not advocating you do and you want to
target a company Blayne 10 is your
friend LinkedIn will give you so much
information when I was doing the counter
made against like a party I built a
large profile of individuals through
LinkedIn and that's how I figured out
some of the relationships that were
under the radar from Lita because people
don't care though about anyone only did
of course he's got a rod we've had
sanctions then the sanctions were kind
of lifted we gave some money back to the
we gave some money back to them now
President Trump is throwing that
agreement out the door that President
Obama had worked on now Trump is working
hard put sanctions back of it but
biggest piece at present Trump is done
that he wants done his Swift does anyone
know a mess with that's right it's a
private organization and there's but I
think 2,500 banks or another thing
insane if it is if it is insane
this is how banks move money between
each other so President Trump is has
requested that Swift which is a private
organization remove Iran from the
international banking system and right
now there's a court case going on
because it relied by the view from the
baby system that country can't do any
trade and move money around the world
they can't take money for their oil that
they still sell right they sell the oil
just not to Europe I mean they China
will buy their well criolla by there is
no we don't get a lot of oil from Iran
we did nothing I was yeah so this means
so it's been blacklisted but they they
were selling black you know dark craters
they would fill old tankers up pull them
out of the sea and China would come up
and suck all the pole out at sea and
then pay them and they take the
back that's one that they were really
restricted about selling oil they also
go through the Suez Canal and go over to
Sudan and give them a little wave Sudan
you know if you know anything about
China and Sudan and Darfur China is one
of the main reasons that Sudan or Darfur
happened because China went in because
southern southern Sudan which is now
northern the southern Sudan vast and has
a large crude moral desert and so trying
to drop all the pipelines up through
there and that caused a lot of chaos
between the two factions one was spirit
of Richmond was very poor and it caused
the farm Darfur and China you know that
was the first place they had
peacekeepers something off track give
you all the history of all these
countries
state-sponsored cyberattacks the first
state-sponsored side attack allegedly
was the one against Estonia if you ever
been there it's a beautiful country up
and there's sometimes I write there
nationally the first national cyber
exercise they I have developed their
first exercise and ran it for the
government and they can impress me there
and we can go to the US that this is a
long time they pull their car up on the
side of the street any weird and blood
the phone the key in a partner that was
like oh my god car anywhere and they
have to pay for the phone and they can
market part if they get it gets built to
their cell phone they when they get a
cell phone you know we go to the cell
from to TiVo ATT etc we just needed
someone but their cell phones have two
levels of encryption put on it so they
can use their cell phone for banking
with level one encryption or medical
records for voting they have a level two
encryption for voting which is higher
it's built into the phone they were
required by the law to put it the phone
there's no when you go there no one asks
you for money ever you know black money
I'm going to pay it's all electronic
everything's electronic I mean you're
using furious and edit cards most of
time you doing wire transfers you're
paying by your phone I mean this country
so technology advances
believable this is the birthplace of
Skype by the way right site was born in
the snow do so when this attack occurred
in lasted for 10 days it couldn't do
anything you could not go to the store
and buy bread because the networks in
the country was saturated so you
couldn't use your debit card to get
bread so part of the national security
exercise of the rand was there's a bank
there called sweet bank they were trying
to figure out how do they issue cheques
a physical check a checkbook in case of
a national emergency because they don't
have cash so how do we issue people
checks so they can write a check you go
to the grocery store and it was
unbelievable some of the things that I
never even thought about occurring
because once this attack occurred it
shut the whole country down all
electronic medical records all although
devoting everything we got Ukraine
another Russian problem United States
and Europe fight their medicine if you
know this is related to gas because
Ukraine's actually transshipment area
and they tried to increase the cost in
the in the pipelines and then we've got
crime here which the North Sea Base of
Russia was the country and we have had
two attacks out against the electrical
grid
and both attacks to pound portions of
their grid in two different locations
there's some of the attacks that have
taken place in 2016 it was like a whole
campaign in December 6 we had the
knowledge services tax in the best
against ministry of finance secretary
pension fund 13 defense minister we had
railroad per month railroads hit
infrastructure electrical grid seaports
I mean this is a pure out campaign in
the country to take it down
I mean imagine that this happen in the
United States
we'd be considered at war and all of
Ukraine is fighting that it's trying to
rush it out of their country but it's
Russia was to take the country over you
can so let's talk about the rather
attacker equated their computer systems
of public portals were impacted all the
pastor VIII was taken travel history
payment information
great master systems that were
completely automated
they had go back to manually dispatching
trainings they had interruption of
partnership phase they their manifest
were unreliable they had some questions
about what was in the car and all their
internal business systems are offline
this is a pretty substantial attack and
then we also have the Ministry of
Finance it was said and ATC see why they
control controls and budget for the
country pretty much and
- for their some of their infrastructure
equipment the networking gear go damn
it's just like they rip the system's we
tuck this with ends it's not always
about destroying what you offers so if
you connection our cases our comeback in
that loss disruption financial
transactions you talk about the crane
power attack real quick this is the one
that was the last they had and you one
of the comments I really like here that
experts
there's no experts say that the country
appears to be a testbed for cyber attack
if you use around the world I don't
think it's a testbed for anything I
think Russia really wanted a country
over there not testing their attacks
using someplace else they're using them
here because they want to take the
country over so let's go to the next one
here is the electrical attack so we've
heard and 2016 at that location I don't
know why it occurred at 23:53 it's just
an odd time it occurred on December 17th
it hit the substation they took it down
perfect and he came right back up you
know the question on all the technical
courts are out of this no one looks it
like why why pick this substation you
know what was the reason this substation
was picked versus it
wasn't easier to get in was it not no
there was other reasons there were
geopolitical reasons they picked this
substation I mean this this town itself
is one of the key manufacturing centers
in the entire country it produces most
of the opera bills in the country that
to honor the bill factories there it
does all the steel production in the
country so all the steel mills are there
so far we got a couple of industries
that are key for you know work out of a
bill manufacturing and still
manufacturing it has multiple chemical
plants and it's also the seat of some
stuff that goes on in Poland the other
question the other thing here is
December 17th is a big day in history
right this is when the Russians at the
time tried to have an all Ukrainian
Congress that were all Russians and that
created a revolution so December 17th
was just not some random date they
picked this is actually a place
that's it any questions
No