hello everyone today I'm just talk about
how to automate either find the bugs in
Windows 10 our topic is about logical
privilege escalation bags first let me
introduce ourselves we are all from
Tencent
Tencent is the name of a company for
nobody works for any tensions and
Tencent is also a largest social media
and entertainment company in China well
from tension a secret issue a new lab
now we are just a focus on real world
security research and I am win she here
is my partner shooting I divide today's
presentations to five steps the first I
will introduce you the logical box in
Windows turns systems services and then
we'll do some case studies based on
historical bags then we will know how to
do back discovery and the automated is
processing finally we'll do some works
about exploit development so you may ask
me why I choose logical backs the first
is about stability so all of us knows a
memory co-option bagus is not already
stable with a 10-count wall or other
competitions the competitor is just
wrong their exploit again and again by
say ODIs that is very euro and the
signal why is it is very easy to exploit
for there is many medications in Windows
10 the day just a lack CFG te pasa are
that is many mitigations true value is
family asura found two caches virus
and combine them together to game
privilege escalations
so what could not you best do that is
the answer is or that memory corruption
Paris could do that could you
and including sandbox escape or code
executions and privileges creations
today we are mainly focus on privilege
escalation backs so let's see the
pictures the medium interpreter users
who communicates with the system
services and system service could do
fire operations and the registry modify
or to copy some handlers or to some deal
operations just like a lot of some
libraries or do some other scenes so for
for examples we'll choose two ballasts
for the kids studies the historical
example we choose the aviary
representives example one is about an
arbitrary tsa rewrite back after we
explore it we can gain full control of
any fare we want the back to is just
about arbitrary faerie bag and then
contains the following problems the
first way is a past elimination problems
it's very you are in those
vulnerabilities and the second of why is
time of check and time of use and let's
say the first bag is seen task scheduler
service and when we call an LPC
interfaces we could figure this of an
abilities and the can control of any
fail
before analyze this part we need to know
some fundamental knowledge ease about
her a RPC and AOPA is called advanced
local procedural cause which is a part
of Windows IPC so ideal which called
Microsoft in the interface definition
language is a bridge between claims and
a surveyor in LPC so that LPC becomes a
bridge between the client and a server
and a we could use the ideal to
communicate with a system service and a
co is function so how could we analyze
those interfaces we need a tool named
obviously V or it is a very strong and
powerful tools that we could analyze
those interfaces and also there you can
see the futures the registered LPC
interfaces is marked as green so that
means we could just call it directly
with ideal code and interfaces but this
tools is not very beautiful in some ways
because some of these have structure may
be missing so that you need to do the
reverse engineering by yourself with a
top row and the fix that has structure
when you are able to fix all 10
structures this software could fix it so
the problem is clear we need to find a
targeted tol which is related to the
help you see interfaces in a visa viewer
and use Ida Pro to do the reverse
engineering
you should beware of the sensitive
operations and some function call which
is to say we grant the SL to some fail
or if some fail for this one abilities
we could see the interfaces in the
target idea fails and we could have find
its in the coyote affair and a reverse
it to job university that your idea of
code and you will find this collar is
you to print DSL to torch Apfel the data
structures just look like this it
receives two parameters the first one is
a pass and a second Y is a si si s TBL
strings which is security descriptor for
the FL and after a reverse engineering
we find the string is just convert to
the security descriptor for this DSL
operations and if I were to use update
functions to update the target fails the
SAO
so you can find if you use the
cannulation bags to limit late the pass
to task
photos so how can we passage some of you
may know we have some ways to reflect
those file operations to another place
but today we are talking about the
technology behind them so
Mike Posner shooting could you please
share the details behind them yes yes
there are three ways to do this Junction
Harley ink and to a SMAP let's look at
junction first windows powers or command
name dough make link in CMD to make
symbolic links this picture shows of
this command we can use this augment G
to make a directory Junction
as the name says Junction is o is only
create it only can be used for true
directories can't create with file and
directory or fell and fell but what
happened in the make link command let's
take a closer look
okay this finger this figure shows the
rewards code for the inflammation of the
Macklin command we can see that it
removes the NTFS control fail function
to create a junction but what is the
NTFS control well as we know the windows
API to SL l control is used for
communication with Colonel travels from
user mode space in fact Demoiselle
control we'll check the ioctl tab if the
ioctl is FS CTL it William walk and he
FS control fell function the NTFS
control fell function is responsible for
handing file system created requests it
receives the panels from the user mode
until create the airpipe exit and send
it to the fastest in tower according to
this figure we can see it in walk and he
FS control fell with FS CTL said repass
point control code to him the import
power is associated with the control
code when the control code is FS CTL
said we pass quite the input power is a
repast date power structure okay and
there is a field named we passed a
repast tag in the repast state powers
crowd
it can be said through different values
but the most common will values are I
alway past had a simple link and our
repast tab mantra point let's took
another look at the progress figure we
can see that the aisle we passed tag
match point tag was used when creating
the junction
the make link command also has a
function to create simple link leaks it
will realize our new windows API create
a simple lead link the windows a peccary
the symbolic link is located near
Canopus about the RL and this figure
shows the rewards code of each we can
see create a symbolic link invoke the
NTFS control fell with IO repast had a
symbolic okay let's take a small summary
there are two commonly used repast ever
why is our repast ergo symbolic and the
other is a repast head mod pointer when
you awoke her NTFS profile with our
repast Hephzibah link the filesystem
trailer will create the NTFS symbolic
link and it can be used for file or
directory we invoke NTFS control fairies
will reap a segment pointer the first
system trail will create the NTFS mount
point it only used for directory ok we
now know how to create a repast point
the next tab is estate o we want to know
what happens when we open a repast point
we will maybe open a file the Windows
kernel first looks for this object in
the corner object directory but the
kernel object manager only knows the
entry pass so a concision is necessary
for example when we open sea test test
of fail the until was passed name to ng
past named function how was that
pass through Antipas in the corner
object manager OPP vocab object name is
responsible for founding and named
Colonel object in the corner object
library the object directory is composed
of Directory objects but if the current
path is not what you actually object the
OPP lookup object name function will
call the past function of this object
tab in this figure C is a kernel
symbolic object
note that chrono savelic object and NTFS
symbolic links are two completely
different scenes because c is a kernel
symbolic object obj lookup object name
we'll call his pass function the past
method of the Windows kernel similar
link object is OPP pass symbolic link
function it covered
the symbolic object to the real
directory object now the file path is
the res heart this volume 9 test test
affair how this volume 9 is a Pronovias
object OPP lookup object named realized
it is not a directory object so ovp
lookup object name will invoke the u.s.
objects first function i hope you pass
the west and passing the romanian name
as argument to LP path device function
created or kernel
object as the contest of this open
operation it in Crete RP package and
said it to the associated a file system
grammar but if we have already created
past point F as a well return status
repast true IOP past us function then
the IOP past us return the status
reports to OPP lookup object name
function the OPP look happen object name
function returns made the stateís
theatres will you return the better
underlying if is status repast it will
be passed again use the return value but
this is the implementation principle of
we passed point and the Microsoft
provide some information that how
Windows APs there is the repast point
you can find you to add MST a some
windows APR 19 2014 11 2001 delayed fell
went in a file function open fell you to
use until open file function with the
fell open repast point flyable and each
will now to return status we pass code
we also can use make link command with
to create our hardening is invoke the
windows API create high link W the
windows API created link W will a walk
and he API and he said information fell
function and he said information
function allocate or add eiope with rpm
G said information major function code
and set fell information class value in
our piece is that location struct and
then until certain information fair
standard disruption to the diverse
object which the kernel fell of the
kunafa object associated with in Iran
that us associated wrist of wisdom fell
object is the filesystem
device so the FST will receive this
error purist and it will set the HAR
link a better way
the highly only beautiful reflect fell
double cut above has remarked in and he
pass is usually appoint you to global
double cut remark pass for example
double pet remark global route is
pointing to global turbo petrol mark
global route but if we point double
hazard map to paste named object Schrute
US map then when we open double has
remarked global route the directory we
actually opened is paste
named object global root the important
thing is that all windows API and up use
double question mark pass therefore we
can use the as map to redirect objects
that windows ApS operations for example
parks proxies a want to open a file
named C test the pass has to fail before
the open operation we created us map for
process a map question mark bubble
question mark point to place named
objects then we create a chrono symbolic
object named phase name the object C and
link it to give us heart this heart is
volume for know that the real TC is
reverse hard disk volume Mario when the
prophecy say opened fell C test pass has
the film firstly seat has surpassed SF l
will chord to Tom Poquette remark seat
as a pest has a fell in an TTL thought
ERL by RTI otis pass name to and he
passed name secondly topo question mark
retract to face named object by device
map and OPP lookup object named function
try to pass face name objects see it has
the pass has the fail
suddenly OBPA look up object name
realized the sea is not see is all
symbolic object then redirected sure you
ask hard disk volume for and test pass
test fell is the remaining passer
so the for pass is device hard disk all
in for tests pass test fell no-till OPP
look up object name awoke LP passed us
and passed test has peso fell as an
argument with hard disk volume for us
now we have redirected C can surpass
tensor fell to T test the pest tester
film successfully yes okay that's my
partner to share him as so many skills
to bypass the pass eliminations so let's
just say the solutions for the example
one who can say that our target you to
grant a DSL to Atari fell so hard ink
could be used to do this if we quit our
herding or DSL set to this Harding also
reflect to a telephone so it is very
simple we just put herding to the target
file we want to care for control and
then we figure s LPC interfaces so our
sins is done let's see the second man
abilities it is located in Windows
installer service but the most
importantly is it is not a OPC in the
it is a function called MSI advised
product functions which is used to
communicate with the Installer service
the function YouTube validates the
Tigers FL and it with a copy of the
tiger FL so there is a certain time
between the copy happens and the check
you can sync if the copy the file is
read by the normal user he could break
the rule and end up with privileges
collision so let's see how to win this
risk condition problems let's talk about
relax for Microsoft it says Obelix is
used to design to reducing network
traffic times and the improve the
response time actually it could use to
win the risk conditions by only one time
Hyuk is based on a function device I'll
control and you could lock the fell just
certifying a callback functions to it
will the file options actually happens
you're getting notified
I just execute your Cobra functions that
is to say we could just rewrite the file
two junctions to the attack level so
that we could read it and another way is
a function named read directory change
establish this where this functions is
no luck so that is to say when we do
file operations we will not concern
about the locks
just like if I like to file with Alex I
could not do any operations before
actually if our operations come so it is
just to you to detect if there is any
changes on the taxi directories
and when the directors actually happens
we could do the operation and we see the
solutions for the example to which a
Soyuz read directory changes functions
to do it but as you can see we could not
use relaxed so beautiful is also needed
it takes many times you just to try it
and we got notified and the rewrites
this Junction you could see the piace
we just set read read affair functions
and the trying to catch the content but
this when the bt is not so beautiful
because the CPU rate will reach about
100 percents so after do the case study
and find so much so many ways to bypass
those 50 chairs we need to think about a
problem how to do back discovery many of
us knows that technology details but few
of them could refine new bugs I think
there is a certain way that we could do
it so I developed Ida Pro plugins to
assist us find the new bars the main
problems for us is actually find the
most vulnerable functions and detect if
there is any bars so let's see the
plugins
and actually provides a lot of
interfaces to help us writers plugins we
could get function attributes together a
function start address and then their
dress and then we will use their
memories in compare our constructions a
based block you could say they in these
pictures is the straight line code
sequences with no branch so for in the
rules and right sides we could find all
of the above operations and just find
the targets functions with this progress
if at either address is in the test
segment then we go back to the Steve
Irwin to retry this so talk is cheap
show me the code so let's see the code
is very very present to find those
vulnerable functions we just to try to
find all broad color blocks and detect
if there is some operations by this way
actually we found one new back reported
to Microsoft it is located in program
completed his assists in the service it
is arbitrary file metadata read back
also the main problem for this back is
in correct impersonation and the time of
check time of use let's see the
disassembly code we'll see this a LPC
the face is located in peace
a sec top deal so the functions name get
fire information from past use a safety
check to make sure that the creditor
user have the accessibility to gain to
get the tag no files metadata if it
first using impersonation to bear
country users token and then use
critical functions to try to open a file
the developers things if the current
user is successful to open a file so he
must have the privileges then he just
reverted to system privileges so let's
see how to break this draw which has a
create a file name which is similar
which is seen with a toggle fail and we
lock it with the objects then we call
the interfaces in a RPC after we can
notify by the rocks I need to say the
system service try to open the tangle
affair with contributors token and we
rewrite her Junction to the tiny folders
we want to read and then we bypass a
check and the system service rewards to
system privileges and get to the method
back to our yours
so that is Tuesday week in the targeted
how is a normal user privilege
[Applause]
it's very simple to write a saturated
support which asked the need to set our
barracks and can the callback functions
after is that was found we have seen
many times on reverse engineering just
about all the interfaces in the system
services we have ruined more than
hundreds of interfaces back and nothing
you have so many people are trying to
catch backs and test is not easy to
reverse all interfaces so we started to
think how to automate you this process
and get new van abilities we may knows
now we are very easy to beautiful errs
and use it to detect memory proficient
by automatically let's see the red side
of this picture is so very traditional
fathers it's just cleaner examples and
the right with targets exclude hero just
detecting if there is a crash so I start
to think is there something similar with
a crash in logical vulnerabilities
the answer is yes by a first we need to
know how to catch those sensitive
operations we start using about the
process monitor sort of the system
internal toasts but unfortunately is
there is that not an e command-line tool
so we make it and left her interfaces
for our framework to catch it system
operations just like testing on file
operations is very similar to a crash in
catching memory proficient bugs and it's
very easy to validate those operations
satellite hello we validate crashing
memory provisions if there is any use
after free or Auto bounce rate and I
found two operations is very easy to
abide it
the first one is said security file the
second one is setted this composition
fell and I will build the framework
based on them and there is a problem can
we just use this frameworks to automate
hit analyze the IOPS interfaces but
unfortunately the answer is no it cost
for too much times and hard to do
reverse engineering
so I gotta another way how to trigger
system service or let me to say to
interact with him i justa gets a sort
from the example to that have talked
about you need nobody you see interfaces
as a function relate here true system
service so i say i just to read her
spoiler and a click of ammunition list
related to system service and also the
details in MSDN should be correct for
further usage a spider Kali is very
simple we just collect by keywords
related o to system services and give
her a list for list we could
automatically try all ism and catches
our operations we do find some useful
things in her or interested in the inter
but now about unfortunately real
non-muslim is vulnerable so I started to
think about the system system of
afflictions everyone everyone of us use
system operations in Microsoft developed
by Microsoft in Windows 10 in our daily
usage so I started to thing about if
they should communicate with system
service for there is so many functions
to be developed so this problem is
sought by and Mac Siddhant
mr. Fisher every one of us knows it's
his car the windows car the stores one
day I just click the install button song
this is applications and I find that
there is so many sensitive operations
just to come and I find if I need to
trigger all of the modules of those
evictions the best way is just to do UI
interactions instead of just do so many
reverse engineering works so let's draw
our conclusions I first I clicked
execute finalists from the system photos
and do some random stuffs so what is the
random stuffs I made up a list just like
Napoleon's start and exits the targets
applicants and the simulates the UI the
interactions with the UI patterns or
press some keys the the applications may
interact with a system service and
trigger some functions by accident so in
one word there is a vulnerability
template in our framework first I just
hope the sensitive operations and to
interactions cylinder at every repair
replace that affair with the hiring
course amar Singh's
and validates the SAO of that file if I
try to write something into it when I
success that you to see it was
successful so I just a generator by the
reporter which is similar to a trashy
report in memory provisions let's see
the architectural diagrams
if it is very simple right you guys may
ask me or it is so simple it really
works
you are just kidding me but actually we
use this framework to catch four batters
in just two weeks but you are still
under fixing by Microsoft so today which
has a total two of them two new bugs fun
by this framework and all of them use
about DSL rewrite bagger
it's a very useful because you can get a
full control of NFL and the Reta
anything into it and the problems is
just as same our old friends
impersonation and time object mo use the
first one is located in epics
development service when we start the
system camera it is a Windows app it
will try to call service cooking owner
of the settings file so the citizens
file is just allocating users folders
which any users have abilities to write
anything into it and the target the
system service will try to set the SA of
weight so we just said a harding and
pointed to the tiger fire we want to get
full control of the result is the
country user is said to the owner of
this tagging affair so that we can could
read rather anything read it or modify
it
let's see the video for this one ability
first either a channel dsl for the
attacker file you could say there is no
access privilege for him I try to read
something into it by field then
I just deleted the settings file and
instead of her linked to the tagging if
I were one to King owner of now I just
start to the system camera and do some
random interactions we should we could
click the button just do some keyboard
events and then we could find this
operation use triggers so let's check if
it is successful we just try to run
something to eat here again you'll find
successful so let's check if the content
is really right yeah
you'll find out the DSL is actually
revised in before trigger this one a bit
here and after we get a full control of
the toggle film it is a signer with our
CV numbering Microsoft has April
security advisory and the fixed for this
problem is very easy just impersonate
with the card users token so that you
could only set with say himself's
privilege and the next one is a standard
is located in standard collector service
there is no impersonation again seems
Microsoft always forget to edit when you
try to click that debug buttons on with
your studio
will do the following operations first
you to create s as the a tch foul and
again it critter with with the same file
name by the way
extension is different and they'll try
to set DSL and they'll get flow control
of him who se is adjust to this
operation without any impersonation so
if the chapter you system privilege to
do those things so how could we trigger
when abilities will create such files
will use read directory changes to
detect if the value is all that sings
and create a high link before the second
of our was crates then we look at the
owner of the title affair so if you are
from a Red Team you may ask me or all of
your parents is about final operations
residency injuries but what I need is a
common command executions so how could
we tour the file operations into a
command executions with system privilege
instead of just writing something into
it with system privilege so you may
think some service the DPO files
libraries could be writin but actually
there is a trustee the installer protect
for those services you can certainly use
a third party come third party software
like Google Chrome or antivirus services
to do those things but what we want is
everything is installed by default you
could say all
most of the windows service deal or
library is protected by trusted
installers some of them is not protected
but exclusive because of a service is
around default run by default and it's
just a loaded deal houses so when you
try to rewrite it he says I mean usage
usage so we need to find something wrong
only were used and not protected by the
trustee the installer so we can one
cartridge the chap here spring the XPS
printers it is called the printers for
service it would get loaded when printer
Java XPS document the DFL would be
modified by the system newer users and
it was found in a wide exploit of that
vulnerabilities and the attack it's deal
fairway we want to rewrite is the
located in such photos when you try to
create according to this fell and a
trigger of an abilities your finery font
Windows services
sorry running your tears will be loaded
and you will get a code execution with
system privileges you just need to
hijack the deal main functions and all
things will be done and here is some
reference in our projects we'd like to
thanks James photo for his works
logical bag researchers without his help
we could not do this project and Mary
der junge give us many advices about how
to find new bus and trend adding his
expert in Statuary o and K in the in the
pom-poms edge competitions do you have
any questions no questions from the
audience
no hands but I'd like to ask you to give
one big hand to the speakers once more
[Applause]
you