hi everyone thanks for attending good
afternoon I'll be presenting this talk
about I own your building manager system
it's about hacking access control
security platforms and building
management systems altogether so let's
start with just short introduction I
work for applied risk which is based in
Netherlands in Amsterdam which is a
company that deals with industrial
security control penetration testing
covering a variety of sectors and
industries like maritime pharmaceuticals
water chemical manufacturing oil and gas
transportation and including of course
control systems one of them is building
management system which is parent let's
say about of access control systems
altogether so a little bit about myself
my name is Joe Cocker stitch I'm coming
from Macedonia I'm also have 15 years of
experience in the security industry
member of the International saboteur
Task Force founder of zero science lab
ethical hacking instructor I love doing
vulnerability discovery exploitation
finding zero days on a daily basis and
of course I'm a ping pong amateur
somebody's interested in that so let's
get right to it
agenda for today I'm gonna introduce
what is a BMS or building automation
system we don't discuss about different
jargon or terminology used in the
industry the architecture of the
implementation of the system itself
security research key takeaways and next
steps so in Susa jargons we've seen all
around different types of jargon or
terminology used for these types of
systems which is building management
systems or can be building automation
systems or building energy management
systems including PLC's SCADA and of
course energy monitoring system I've
told you about electronic door access
control which is a soft category of
entire building mattresses and solutions
so in this research that we've done
together with my colleague and main
contributor to the
mallamma we've done research against
five different products for from four
different vendors but not in total in
total there were various or large number
of products and vendors that we've
analyzed but due to the nature of the
exploitation and the discovered
vulnerabilities we chose to just had
five of them and this is going on from
last year in May so it's one year almost
of course most common currently
interested terms are building management
system and building management and
control systems basically it's like a
you know centralized solutions from
controlling an entire building so what
is a BMS or bas is a intelligent
microprocessor based controller systems
that is installed in an operator were
station for example in the local area
network controlling a building
controlling buildings technical systems
and field controllers various devices
we're talking about sensors access
control physical access controls and or
gates doors and gates and elevator
access also we're talking about
accessing live streams from a camera or
modifying the streams it's installed in
every major building so far in 2019
we're gonna see a lot of different
variety of that advertisement and we
were focusing on the exposed ones on the
Internet itself so BMS for end-users
this is a typical let's say structure or
architecture of a building mannerism and
the components that it holds around it
so you have radiators of course you can
control windows blinds you can control
lightening system the the hydraulics
ventilation and air conditioning system
altogether including as I mentioned the
elevator access and the physical access
controls you have temperature controls
you can change the temperature up and
down you can you know the Vav or the
valuable air volume level you can
control temperature of the water the
boilers the sensor of a gas in the
garage the gates for the garage the
access to the house as well entirely and
the weather monitoring system as well so
there are a lot of different components
compiling a single building management
system we're gonna discuss several of
them so what does BMS do as I you know
informed of course this is a Google
picture of Sydney offices in Australia
there was an incident a couple of years
ago where a researcher found a zero-day
in 3d omni agarra framework affecting
more than two hundred and fifty thousand
two hundred four five yeah two hundred
thousand around devices around the world
controllers which had direct impact and
was used as an authenticated remote
route code execution malleability so
that was i'm not sure which he here but
yeah we're using easy i/o controllers or
tedium near got a framework that
attackers managed to find zero days and
exploit that remotely because the
systems and the building itself was
exposed to the internet directly so what
does BMS do the role of BMS today today
building operation to control to measure
the monitor control applications of
course some of the building control
applications can involve zone
temperatures monitoring and control zone
co2 monitoring main plant chiller toilet
carpark kitchen gym lightning fire
system and a lot of system as well after
hours between control and as i mentioned
as well Vav temperatures well not to
repeat myself is like this is a typical
system components for field devices
within a single building management
control system is a controller at the
bottom you can see what it can control
it can use different variety of
protocols but most of them is using the
buck net for the whole business open
protocol or long works or pure tcp/ip so
you can connect the chillers and boilers
damper actuators variable speed drivers
because these airflow pressures as well
temperature relativity humidity voltage
currents as well you can also monitor
and modify
and power overview and billing
information for a building I'm gonna
discuss also where the coverage games
comes into play so typical components
this is the network you have the
management network and then your
separates are segregated by internet and
network segregation of course two
additional field controllers and then at
the bottom you have the PLC's using
Modbus protocol support these are the
interaction with other building
management system you can use like for
surveillance and access controls which
we'll discuss here live fire safety
systems as well lightening systems
temperature monitoring digital video as
well all packages like that is using the
user interfaces so there are plenty of
different user interfaces for a building
management system typical user
interfaces are maybe as a thick client
on Windows machine or Linux machine that
connects directly to the controller
within a local area network some of them
also can be built in this place
separately or specifically for that
purpose and also of course web interface
exposure so we will be focusing more on
the web interface disclosure or exposure
sorry and to see how much devices are
really exposed from the ones that we've
done research on so security research
we've done some testing against these
type of these vendors let's say and
products this is the building manager
system and electronic door access
control systems which you can see as
it's like a variety of different types
of vendors we all know some of them of
course we'll be talking about
specifically for Nortec security and
control access control platform the
operative building management system
dreama systems of course about access
control as well this includes including
computrols which is a yeah us-based
company as well so we can you know we
can discuss the exposure of this systems
in a bit
so this advertisement for 2019 provide
access to all functionality via a
standard browser over the Internet as
dangerous software shall have a
companion mobile apps you can is 100 can
just try to analyze that as well
designed to control monitor HVAC
lightning access and fire alarm systems
all in one location in one centralized
place perfect for commercial industrial
banking medical retail hospitality and
other businesses where users need to
secure the facilities manage access of
personnel create and analyze reports and
monitor the system from any web browser
so this is an indication if you hear
like you know the systems are accessed
from a web browser over the internet so
this is a attack surface is just plain
old directly trying to attack the
building itself there are a lot of
famous buildings we've seen in our
research so these are the targets that
we've analyzed so far within this year
so this is not a cleaner energy tree
which was also there are some research
done two years ago all about it from a
Google security researcher Andrew
Griffiths
published also not to be very much 50 P
or 5,000 P is a different product
different code base so it's also an
access control platform which allows us
to just remotely without authentication
open doors unlock lock access the
elevators a stream of cameras and yeah
after G proton or Enterprise building
management system prima systems access
control platform and compute all CBS web
building masses and these are all the
targets that we've chosen to present in
the research paper the research paper
will be available in June it's gonna be
a technical white paper around 138 pages
so you can check it out on applied risk
website so first things first
of course we've you know try to have a
black box approach for every target
possible because you know it's not it's
a bit of cheating if you have everything
you know in place in front of you so
we've tried to do what a real attacker
would do to just try to
imagine that we have only access to web
interfaces so this is an example of leer
emerge and Nortec of course this is how
it looks like for optela Jeep wrote on
enterprise and prima assistance is also
as access control protocol access
control platform and of course the
seabass building management system of
course so a little bit of data over 2500
standalone control system accessible
from the internet as of now maybe more
the number of the exposed services or
the exposed systems were increasing on
bi-weekly basis especially for Nortec
leaner more than 10 million people can
be affected potentially because this is
based on you know specification of the
product any product as allowing for a
person to of people to be in the
database more than 500 more than ten
thousand or it depends on the system so
we calculated this and based on the
exposed services and that specification
of products physically can be you know
10 million people can be affected
physically not just like stealing data
or private information 30 thousand doors
can be opened within 20 seconds or all
around the globe in 200 facilities this
means that this is separate from access
control systems building manner of
systems and access control systems so
let's see what software is used or
software technologies in controllers
this includes the access control and the
building manager system as well so we
have unit Unix Linux file system as a
firmware for the web server of course
for the web interface we've seen Apache
nginx and you know light httpd go ahead
PHP is used as a web technology
front-end Java JavaScript as well Python
bash CGI ASP protocols back net stack
with does some research as well on the
back net stack back net protocol itself
but yeah this is out of scope for this
paper Modbus protocol support as well
database management systems my sequel
Postgres sequel and database management
of course Firebird interbase there was
an interesting disclosure of firmware
but we cannot discuss this a bit later
so what we've did in the usual approach
in the applied race laughs we managed to
do a variety of services let's say and
sorry yeah
so of course once we get the firmware
and I'll explain how we got the firma
from all of the vendors we've done some
further analysis of course static and
dynamic program analysis as well so we
done protocol fuzzing and reverse
engineer and the binaries and we've
found a lot of issues basically we found
every possible vulnerability existing in
the security industry so you can just
think of title we can say yes that
product has it of course at the end
exploit research and development so we
develop exploits as well for all of them
and it's interesting how we got the
firmers of you know different vendors so
we're gonna discuss this now for example
this is an opto g obtaining a video
example this is an operative video from
the marketing team they did so once we
do we wanted to do an awesome
intelligence gathering so we've go on to
youtube search for author g found the
marketing videos that they show how to
upgrade a firmware for end user of
course so in that case this is an actual
screenshot from a video on v-mail
where they download the firmware and
just you know uploading afterwards so we
just pause the video retype the URL got
the firmware and yeah everything was
there once you have the firmware you
have the basically the source code once
you have the source code and it's like
Merry Christmas you know
so now of course the URL is removed now
any vendor every vendor was inform about
the issues not all of them created
patches for it but most of the vendors
created patches and yeah I think
recently like yesterday they just
released an advisory I'm going to show
you this later so we got the firmware
form of the jury like this this is a
simple approach of course we've tried to
read manuals as well we've discovered
default credentials hardcore initials
and that's everything around on the
Internet this is a second example for
Nortec linear where we managed to you
know we got the firmware from a
different research done previously so
we've done just code execution done the
database and we saw that in the database
there are clear text credentials for
connecting to the FTP which is the main
repository for the former's and we were
informing the vendor of course they were
communicating in the beginning but
suddenly they just decided to drop the
communication and it's still unpatched
of course so they were trying to and I
think as I've speak now they're trying
to update a firm as well but we can see
if they try to update the firmware so we
always test the latest firm as well
there inform about it but yeah they're
using the FTP so this is how it looks
like when you just navigate to it with
the credentials provided in the database
as clear text passwords look at a lot of
issues guys I mean there are products
like totally broken we'll see some
examples more for example this is a sea
computrols for building management
systems a simple cvn subversion
repository of the entire firm was
present in the target that we've tested
in the lab so you can just download the
firmware itself directly because it
allowed in the directory indexing and
yeah read the code find backdoors as
well and I'm gonna discuss about
backdoors as well because we've
discovered a couple of backdoors inside
products
IOT and IOT vulnerabilities basically we
found every possible vulnerability in
all of these products or you know
building mannerism and access control
systems that allowed us to just do an
authenticated remote code execution and
just try to open doors or just turn off
the lights I tried to do this before the
you know joining this conference to
start to try this building if it's using
some known building management system if
it's also exposed on the internet so I
could just you know maybe try to shut
down the lights that didn't work
it's not exposed so the main problem was
that a lot of you know interfaces were
exposed to the internet which is a
problem of course and yeah we've
discovered a cross-site scripting so
deviation bypasses signal injections
file directory server source I mean I
can just go on on the list every
possible bit is there and of course
memory corruptions is a buffer overflow
issue in one of the products as an
example this is what we did some
reversing of the binaries that holds
that was the main CGI or gateway
interface for the linear III from Nortec
this is just a simple one one example of
cookie traversal because once you see
the code pseudocode we can see that
there is a path reversal issue with the
open function and before there's a cyst
path issue here and before that we've
discovered that you can upload
unauthenticated you can upload any
firmware not any firm about the firmware
you can upload it without authentication
so we've chained that and use the
directory traversal from the cookie to
authenticate it to be you know to bypass
certification itself so once the bypass
of that occasion occurs because we
uploaded a valid session cookie which we
also reverse and know how the cookie
looks like as a file we just uploaded
that file to any arbitrary location and
from the cookie the cookie just you know
searches for a valid file name and it
just reads it successfully and then we
have a authentication bypass like this
so it's really like a twisted and a
chain of all aridity reactions
also another example so this is a sport
root password in a binary not just one
like several binaries and the root
possible is all over the place so you
just easily I don't know go online and
start opening doors I don't know man
it's a dangerous thing and you can see
it clearly in the firmware the vendor
didn't want to you know understand what
is happening and yeah this is just one
example of all the issues that we've
discovered there are a lot of issues for
example backdoors this is Samuel the
binary or source code revealed to us
that there are backdoors present and not
just real or there's a regular backers
there are smart backdoors with some
logic to you have to overcome to just
you know execute the code itself because
backdoor these burglars allow an
authenticated remote root code execution
and full system access so you just shut
down the building one click this is an
example from the Java backdoor
discovered in one building management
system as you can see that there is a
challenge sorry
so once you click the challenge you get
a response as a timestamp value and that
value has to be sha-1 encoded or you
know hashed and that and then that md5
has to be you know calculated as a sha-1
sorry md5 and after that you can you
have to concatenate those values and
provide it as an answer here and then
you can provide an ID or not Aidid of
command that you want to execute and
basically they had this wide open like
this unauthenticated so you have a web
interface for the backer itself so you
can just type you know if you click the
get here you can get the challenge you
have to calculate it manually aside
because I'm thinking that you use it on
special program for this and once you
calculate it everything together
concatenate it and provide it as an
answer you type in the past the command
that you want to execute and click exec
it's gonna execute as the current
running web user
religious of course they removed it now
they said that's like a you know
forgotten development console but yeah
the back door was really sophisticated
so I don't know if it's a you know so
this is this this is how it looks like
when you try to access using this
backdoor account so just one simple
script it just automates all the things
and just you have route how do I get rid
because I told you previously that
oxygen to Solaris file because they
allowed everything to be executed as
route as that user so I can just sue the
ID this is the outcome system access
also provided for linear III emerge
series just with one click you have the
ID command here as light httpd but when
you echo they style as the user password
the route possible you can execute
commands as route directly some other
examples also there's a file upload
issue as well in just unauthenticated
you can upload any file because it's
using the PHP input wrapper so you just
write anywhere anything just create
yourself a web shell and get the root
access as well also we created a
Metasploit session to be more convenient
of course I'm going to show you a demo
at the end of this presentation to show
you how it's possible to remotely unlock
a door understand that we had at applied
risk the dollhouse if anybody seen that
this is for Lena emerge 50 P and 5,000 P
is a different product different
codebase we've seen a lot of you know
critical critical buildings critical of
famous buildings let's say or access
control of the buildings that we've seen
because you can easily see that without
even you know interacting with the
system just shouldn't and remote route
of course optic proton also had an issue
besides the other issues are not you
know this is just a you know I'm saying
the final issues mentioned but
low-hanging fruits vulnerabilities as
well memory corruptions privilege
escalations directories reversals all
over the place so everything will be
detailed of course in the paper that
we're gonna release but this is just so
you know endgame presenting you to see
how it's possible to execute code on a
building manager system because once you
have access you can just modify
everything you know this is a prima
facie this is a issue with access
control system which they allowed to
download you know predictable name of a
database and they because if you change
this vulnerability with another one that
we discovered that they allow logging
with md5 hashes once you download the
database you can dump the hashes once
you've done the hashes you can log in as
that hash as a system admin for example
and just you know break the control
itself in the place a second ID
volubility also allowed remote code
execution using this google token Google
Facebook social token so social login
feature and yeah you can do this only
three times and then your IP will be
blocked because yeah it's using this as
a you know wrong password but we managed
to get ID this is discovered by a civic
a malama also there's a authenticated
code execution as well so for dedicated
issues a lot of technical issues there's
I'm just mentioning some of them Python
scripts are already developed in execute
code as well in prima systems you can
also upload direct Python scripts on the
controller itself authenticating it and
just execute as route also for sea baths
computrols we did not get remote route
connect you know code execution this one
we just had a remote code execution with
the web user account but yeah we're here
dumping the database credential super
secret and you know the users of the
database string so what are the impacts
remotely lock up lock and unlock doors
gates of course physical access to
restricted areas control a delay access
monitor the human
behavior and movement by reading locks
once you enter an Access Controller or
building mattresses and you can see who
is going to the gym at 2:00 p.m. for
example you can do something about that
intercepting video control video stream
Sylvain you can freeze you can modify
modify electrical overview and billing
information I can change my billing
information to be zero not to pay
electricity in that residential building
or company building or industrial or
monuments and you know so on it's like
never-ending manipulate HVAC of course
disrupt critical operations impact this
is what you get once you log into the
web interface I'm gonna show you a demo
with you know controlling the door from
the command line directly from the
binder itself with the given commands
which we reversed know the logic of it
this is a screenshot also from the optic
ANSI I don't know if you can see clearly
but you can you know disclose some
information because it says here 334
devices connected which means that using
botnet protocol which is the building
automation control network protocol
which you can just use maybe there are
sensors or field devices or any any you
know small things boiler controls this
is just I don't know one of many
screenshots or interfaces that we've
seen that you know that we needed to
know what you can control once you get
access or the you know description of
the given product
Prima's system access control platform
you can see how you can just with one
click you can open unlock or lock
forever a door or unlock it forever or
just have a man and man trap feature you
can lock someone inside camera stream
disclosure as well in an elevator
so you can you know control the stream
disable it you know and this is also an
example from sea bass where you can
control the temperature and the lower
part you just change the value make
everyone you know be cold or extremely
hot and yeah this is also from the
vendors itself as a case study potential
targets it's not like that we've seen
this but potentially because they're
using this software and everything is
patched everything is you know released
everything is in
people know about it they pass it but
you can just you know some universities
or Statue of Liberty I know anything can
happen
so operate octave G new enterprise two
four five has been released crediting
applied risk of course for our research
we've been in collaboration with all the
vendors in step one a school as well of
course and everybody was you know
extremely nice collaborative and they
created patches in timely fashion
discovered released new firmware
versions and inform their customers to
protect their exposed instances of
building management and control systems
this is our upgrade for sea bass where
they just released it yesterday
as a you know public announcement but
this is fixed before that of course
during this research we've discovered
more than one hundred zero days and that
doesn't mean that we have to have as a
CV for all of them because none of the
not all of the products we've tested are
in this presentation or in the paper
itself so it's still let's say ongoing
but so far we have 48 CVS assigned and
yeah a lot of them are not even patched
yet
some of them are not even presented here
so we're moving on forward for to you
know do some other research on building
management systems but yeah in 2019
exposure of when building manager system
on the internet is the dangerous thing
so a lot of people can say yeah we're
using a cloud-based solution centralized
solution password-protected but a lot of
vendors here has default credentials you
can just enter in like with admin admin
similarly that so changing some of the
viruses we discovered allows allowed us
to have an unauthenticated code
execution directly and take full control
of the building or the access control
itself jails as well can open doors guys
recommendation of course secure building
management system so in security be
aware of insecurity of protocols by
design back net is really unstable we've
managed to crash it in some simulation
follow industry
practices guidelines along with vendor
supply chain security testing and secure
software development lifecycle do firmer
analysis on your products do version
control and patch management because one
of the vendors there was a failure in
version control there was a new version
that patched something by coincidence
then in a newer version on the old
vulnerability pops up so there's a this
summer it's a it's a mess I don't know
this is the dollhouse we made for the
challenges we had yesterday and today
for from the batteries to you know try
to hack and open the door or attractive
hang to PLC's and modify the lights of
the house or HMI which is the small
screen top of the right there you can
play with it and yeah let me try now the
demo hopefully it's gonna work let me
see let me see if I think this is the IP
address of the controller downstairs
let me see the stream because I need you
to see the cameras livestream here
yeah so yeah this is live downstairs
imagine that I'm from home here opening
doors in some laughs chemical spills
stuff happening you know you didn't
happen so let me just try to run this
exploit on this thing it's gonna ask me
do I want to jump the credentials like
that yeah you know dunk the credentials
in clear-text are you seeing this
clearly ok so there's a spider sequel
spider cgi door 1m unlocked which is
manual unlock you have three versions or
three modes of unlocking no control of
the door em unlock which is manual
unlocked which is forever unlocked and
locked which is gonna close the door em
unlock was gonna unlock it and lock it
again in three seconds the
all times time so let's see let's see
yeah he's gonna go back so I'm gonna try
to open it forever fighter stick cool
let's see GI door one you can just
select any door and just brute force all
doors and open everything unlocked it
should stay unlocked forever now until
somebody manually close this or I close
it why not
lock lock it yeah and that's it and of
course I'm gonna mention as well again
that yeah this is a video just keep this
this was just in case the demo gods were
not with me you know it's the usual
approach any questions guys thank you
for this amazing talk and yeah so we're
still in the coffee break but so feel
free to make any questions now and I
guess it will be glad to answer to all
of them yes please ask away so any
questions so yeah okay
it's a tough question man
sorry we have official public disclosure
policy on no website we give them like
two months - you know react but this was
going on from since May 2018 so we tried
several times to just explain what's
really happening but this current you
know this specific vendor I think I
don't know what I don't know what
happened really just dropped
communication we had a phone
conversation emails web chat also
contact forms everything every time was
the yeah did you try to contact your
reseller no I'm trying to report
availability please
and some management contacted us we say
yeah we want to report serious critical
vulnerabilities yes we already fixed
them and we've scanned a new firmware
and nothing is discovered anymore so we
are clear said which villages I didn't
support anything I mean didn't submit
anything to you so they just drop
communications I don't know what
happened but the other ones perfect I
mean everything is fixed everything is
good so yeah one weather remains exposed
unfortunately but yeah they were aware
of the disclosure policy they were aware
that we are going to do a research paper
and presentation energy it will be known
and basically two years ago or three
years ago there was a you know research
done on this specific vendor and since
then also those those releases were not
patched okay thanks we have another
question here yes thank you for your
talk did you find a lot of product
sharing the same codebase in this
industry is there one wonder selling
everything to everyone no we've not we
haven't seen any similar or same
codebase of different products no
everything was like different different
OEMs so you know maybe they are but I
don't know yeah any more questions no
more questions thank you that
q Ithaca
you