good morning thank you for coming I also
want to thank the organizers for
inviting me back to speak again it's
always a pleasure to be here so I'm
going to talk a bit about securing
journalists and the work that we do at
the New York Times some of the work that
we've done with other media works or
with nonprofits in the same space the
challenges that we have and sort of why
and the intersection of media and
security so unique and so fun so I'm
just some quick intro originally from
Oslo Norway I now live in New York City
living in a couple of other places in
between my husband and I hacked a sniper
rifle back in 2015 because it was fun
and it was something that you could do
last year I got a certified in sake
figured it would be a nice hobby outside
of InfoSec and I previously worked on
the Tor project and secure drop and I'm
now the senior director of information
security at the New York Times so the
timeline for sort of the type of work
that I've done is back in 2009 I started
working for the Tor project as part of
Google Summer of Code so back then
Google would give nonprofits works or
projects funding to take on summer
interns so initially I worked for toward
doing research and development and I
sort of stayed on and volunteered to
maintain the project that I took on and
a couple of years in the Tor project I
think this was back in 2011 the Tor
project got funding from if I remember
correctly the State Department to train
reporters so I ended up leading that
project back then traveled to Turkey to
Train reporters they are both local and
foreign reporters in Turkey
and it sort of just spiraled from there
back then people weren't really talking
about securing reporters we talked about
securing in the enterprise we talked
about more traditional traditional
security of you oh but I think then
since then in a more recent years maybe
since like 2015 to today ish we've sort
of started talking a bit more about
securing reporters securing cars
securing healthcare and so we sort of
seen this like space develop where we
you have these sort of niche areas of
securing a thing that is very unique
very specific that has challenges that
you don't necessarily see elsewhere and
so from the work that I did with tor I
worked for free freedom of the press
with secure drop which is this
whistleblowing system that allows media
words for a while anyone who sets out
the system to anonymously receive tips
from the public so I think I forget the
number I want to say there's around 30
orgs I'd have that system set up today
and we are one of them so initially I
was then hired to do security just for
the newsroom that was her the scope of
my role then over the past three years
we've sort of had a change in leadership
change in people on the team so my role
has sort of expanded to be not just
security but take the work that I'm
doing there and really expand it to the
rest of the org as well which I think
makes a lot of sense because you now
have you have a number of different
teams that do different but sort of
overlapping work in the context of the
newsroom so you have information
security that does a lot of stuff on the
enterprise side of the company or the
business side of the company but also
something in the newsroom
you have physical security again that
they deal with facilities they deal with
the physical security of executives they
deal with a lot of other sort of groups
of staff but they also work in the
newsroom
so what we're now doing is that we have
cross team collaboration in ways in
which that
three four plus years ago we didn't have
them but I will get back to that in a
bit so yeah I'm gonna talk a bit more
about sort of threat models in the
context of media what is it that we see
that I think is a bit unique to the
space some of the challenges ensuring
the safety of the people that we protect
it's sort of one thing to secure a
twitter account or your G Suites the
deployment then securing the
communication between a reporter and a
source when you are not really in a
position to enforce any security
settings when you can drive the
conversation talked a bit about how to
evaluate the capabilities of your threat
actors so in the context of security and
especially when we talk about reporters
or individuals we also talk about threat
modeling you sort of have to know who's
interested in the data that you have the
reason which that they could get it to
what they would be willing to do so I'll
talk a bit about how we do that as well
and then talk a bit about the sort of
work that we've done over the past three
years to really build a culture of
security and then how we can take
lessons learned at the times to support
and empower media works elsewhere just
make sure I get some water over here
okay cool so if you haven't worked a lot
with a newsroom Saussure a couple of
different things that I always expected
walking into the New York Times that I
never really found
the newsroom is a very dead Ryan
deadline-driven and product-focused
meaning at the end of the day the goal
is to get the story out on time towards
the end of the day around like 4 or 5
o'clock that's when in most cases the
reporters are expected to deliver
whatever story they were they set out to
write that day whether that was a story
they came up with because something
happened on their desk or they were
assigned a story earlier in the day by
their editor like that sort of deadline
time basically and the main goal what
the newsroom really cares about is
getting that story out the door we can't
have a state where we don't have any
stories ready or where tomorrow the
front page of the New York Times is
blank we always have to get something
out we always have to have to get that
story out so the idea that something
like information security should ever
block us getting a story out it's just
not that's just not a discussion it's
not a topic which means that in some
cases we may find ourselves in
discussions where we have to for a short
period of time except less security and
more risk to ensure that the story is
published so there's a sort of some of
the interesting discussions that we have
to have where it's very very clear that
we cannot block the work that happens
now we're journalists file for more than
150 150 countries each year which means
that you have reporters that are
traveling at any point in time you have
reporters that are based in different
countries so I think that if I remember
correctly we have like something like 23
foreign bureaus so we have a bureau in
Moscow Berlin London Hong Kong Paris
Beijing Shanghai and we also have
reporters going in and out of very
high-risk countries we do have someone
currently based in Iran we have people
going in and out of Syria so you have
people that are like remote and also
traveling and traveling in high-risk
countries and somehow you go to find a
way to secure those people as well and
whatever it is that the day are up to
right
we have a newsroom that has to click on
links and open attachments so depending
on who you ask in this community in
information security you will get this
advice that you should never open an
email or click on a link or open an
attachment from someone you don't know
in the newsroom context that doesn't
work because they get their information
from people they don't know they have to
click on these links they have to open
these emails which means that our job is
now how can you empower someone to do so
securely are there tools that you can
deploy that will allow them to do this
is there training that you can roll out
that will help them understand what to
do and what not to throw even what to
look for when they open amo are there
ways in which that you can like empower
them to minimize that risk knowing that
it's still going to be a risk so with
that the solutions that we create have
to be usable and reliable so before I
came to the times I was I was sort of
doing a lot of consulting work workshops
public speaking training of reporters in
the UK and Norway and so one thing that
I was doing as part of that just for
myself was that I would come up with
these sort of scenarios that our
reporter might have and then figure out
how I would secure them or in that case
myself and sort of really just try it
out to see how well it worked or didn't
work so one thing that I did a lot of
back then was travel security so I would
have a travel laptop and I would have a
travel phone and I would really sort of
think about the different types of
advice that we would give reporters or
high-risk folks and just see how well
that advice would work for myself and I
found that you can you can absolutely go
so far on the scale that you are very
secure but it's not very usable so if
you find yourself in a situation where
you have to send an email really quickly
you're going to be out of luck versus
you can go so far on the usable side
that you can send an email very quickly
but it may not be as secure as you would
like and so somewhere on that line there
is a balance
between what is usable what is secure
and what's going to work for you or for
the reporter at that point in time there
are various systems that we certainly
could use in the newsroom lake cubes
which is from a technical perspective
incredibly neat and I would also say
secure but from a usable perspective for
a non-technical user they may not be the
best so maybe that's a system that we
can leverage in a very different context
maybe it's something that we use for a
pointing time project with people that
do have some tech background where we
have dedicated support to ensure that if
they need help they have that quickly
and they don't have to wait for someone
to respond to an email three days later
and things like that so there are ways
in which that we can leverage solutions
that are more secure than usable but at
that point you have to then consider the
level of support the time it's going to
take the requirement that you would have
for the people from the newsroom using
the system and cetera so it's really a
long list but we do try and figure that
out
it's really going back a bit to the
email example if you are trying to
empower someone and to securely I should
say securely open open their email and
click on these links from people that
they don't know there aren't a whole lot
of technical solutions out there that
ensures that they have that they can do
that without taking on any amount of
risk there are some solutions out there
that can check the email that can vet
the link but at that point you're
talking privacy and potentially security
concerns on top of that as well so
there's sort of like some balance
between the technical tools and the
knowledge you want to give the newsroom
and we focus a whole lot on awareness
relationship building and building trust
because ultimately reporters are going
to find themselves in a whole lot of
weird situations whether it's travel
communicating with their source
receiving a document that they've never
seen before
getting a link for
some random source and be to some extent
need to rely on them to do the right
thing and to loop us in at the right
point in time and you're not going to
get that chain without building trust
and doing a lot of awareness-raising in
the newsroom now get back to a bit of
that as well
let's see cool so I touched on some of
this but so in the in the newsroom so
the newsroom of the New York Times is
around 1,500 people today I think it's
gonna be about 1600 by year and I think
1200 of those are reporters and then you
got news admin support staff we got some
dedicated training staff for the
newsroom editors and sort of other
groups of people that will timidly
support the work that the reporters are
doing and from there you have the
concept of desks so international as a
desk Metro which writes about New York
in New York City is a desk science is a
desk and we've got a bunch of different
bureaus now individuals desks and
bureaus are all going to have different
threats and concerns so someone who
works on investigations is going to have
different requirements than someone who
works on obituaries for example the
person working on investigations may
need security communications may need
encrypted email may need a way to speak
outside of the corporate email messaging
setup may need a travel laptop travel
phone know how to vet documents that
they're getting from sources and the
government for example versus obituaries
potentially just need the sort of
baseline security for securing email
accounts with a password manager and
two-factor authentication
and get a reminder to keep their
software up-to-date they may not
necessarily need all of these other
things that investigations needs so it
would be I don't think it would go over
a while if we were to just roll out this
super intensive slightly paranoid
awareness scheme to the entire newsroom
when only a portion of staff actually
need that same with the bureau's Moscow
is going to have very different security
concerns than say la for example and
we're talking not just digital but also
physical security I think there are
considerations that you'd make for a
bureau in say Moscow than you would in
LA but these are sort of the many
different sort of layers that we have to
consider when we think about how we roll
out the different features that that we
want to offer so different individuals
will have different levels of comfort or
knowledge so you have to look very
quickly in a conversation figure out do
they know about passwords two-factor do
they know that they should keep software
up-to-date and sort of figure out where
we can start in the conversation which
is sort of fine if you're one on one if
you're in a big group of people though
that becomes a bit more challenging if
you're trying to tailor your content to
the majority of the audience they all
have different workflows and day to day
schedules I frequently have reporters
canceling last-minute or just no showing
two meetings with me because something
else popped up breaking news some
different story a source sent something
that they thought would be interesting
they were so into writing their story
that they lost track of time that
happens and we just have to accommodate
for that it can be frustrating when
people no-show when you may time out of
your day to meet with them yes but that
is also a part of the work and
finally reporters frequently use a mix
of personal and corporate accounts which
i think is one of the biggest challenges
that we have when it comes to securing a
newsroom and I would say that it's fine
for a reporter this would absolutely
continue to do that we have sources in
some cases that just straight up say I
will not communicate with you on your
corporate email for whatever reason
maybe they don't like Google a lot of
media works use Google these days maybe
they trust another platform maybe they
are familiar with the types of
enterprise controls that you typically
have on email and they just want to
avoid that there could be like a number
of different reasons but the reporter
will always meet the source where their
ad so if the source is saying actually I
want to speak over here I want to use
this app or I want to use this type of
email service or I want to communicate
through letters that we leave in Central
Park at random points in time ultimately
that is what the journalist is going to
do which means that that is something
that we have to be able to support so
again that goes back to the awareness
raising and empowerment and giving them
the tools that they need to secure their
own accounts I can't enforce the
security of someone's personal twitter
account I can teach them how to set it
up I can help them understand why it's
really important but at the end of the
day it is it is on the reporter to take
those steps and to come ask when they're
when they're not sure so that is a lot
of challenges and I would say a lot of
fun that's sort of one of the things
that I that I personally love about the
work that I do is that I see all of this
as just one big puzzle and I love
puzzles I love trying to figure out the
many ways in which that you can solve a
problem the many ways in which that
something can go wrong and really sort
of come up with that perfect balance
between usable and secure so I included
two use cases that I think will just
highlight what I just talked about where
one is
let's say that we're just going to
secure the main account on Twitter so
it's a corporate account we have a team
that's very responsive and work very
closely with us so if we wanted to
secure that account we already start
with considering the ways in which that
the account can be hacked which can be
something like let's say that plain
account no two-factor password is
password guessing that password would be
fairly easy so we can ensure that they
have a strong unique password at which
point you could you can still guess it
not very likely but let's say that
that's possible
you can successfully fish someone with
access to the account okay and we can
add two factor to the account at which
point you'd have to get the past for the
two-factor code and then get into the
account you can get access through a
third-party integration at which point
we can say okay let's just limit the use
of third-party integrations either we
can say let's just not let's agree to
just not use the month at all and let us
know if that has to change or we can say
we trust these three you can add those
if you need to use something else let us
know and we can review which ones you
want to add then you've got the context
of DMS if someone makes it into your
Twitter account you're not going to know
the steps that they take unless you see
it so if they follow unfollow or tweet
you're not going to necessarily see the
actions that they take which means that
if they just read all the DMS that you
have you're not going to know that they
did that so then to limit the exposure I
should say or the risk of someone just
silently reading all the DMS that you
have associated with your account we can
as you can just say that
we limits how and when the account is
used for games if it is used for games
at all so there are some services that
offer DMS for support for example I
recently had to deal with an airline
about my frequent flyer miles and i DM
them for support and they responded
saying here just give us your full name
your date of birth and your address and
I said no thank you I'm gonna call
instead because if I give that
information via DM and their their
Twitter account is hacked someone's
gonna have access to a whole lot of
personal data there's no sitting inside
of their DMS and I want to avoid that
type of scenario for the newsroom
so we'd sort of come up with some
guidelines or rules that make sense for
us and then what we've also done and
Twitter has really ramped up in the last
six months I would say is providing sort
of VIP urgent assistance to larger maybe
high-risk orgs so we now have an
escalation channel - Twitter's or if
something were to happen either with any
of our corporate accounts or with VIP
accounts that we monitor we will get
faster support and faster response than
we perhaps otherwise would get which i
think is super super helpful and I think
that is something that we will need on
other platforms as well and it's sort of
been a hit or miss whether or not the
platforms are prepared to engage with us
on that scale so that's sort of one
example of like securing a corporate
account which fairly easy it does
require that you communicate with the
team they don't see account but
providing that you're not a jerk
building that relationship should not be
a problem so to make it a bit more
complex though let's say that your
commune
caning with a sore so you have a
reporter you are supporting a reporter
who's communicating with a source again
you can sort of consider the ways in
which that either end of the comms can
be compromised in this case which means
that we can talk about in-person
intimidation we can talk about
surveillance we can talk about metadata
we can talk about the compromise of
their accounts if either of them are
traveling we can talk about search and
seizure at the border there are so many
ways in which that that level of
communication can be intercepted and
compromised that things start getting
very complex very quickly and I think
the best thing that you can do is just
provide the reporter with the tools and
with the knowledge that they need
another thing that sort of makes this a
bit challenging is that the reporter and
the source will almost always have
different levels of technology which
means that you can equip a reporter to
use tor and tails and signal and
encrypted email and know how to get
something from secure drop but if the
source only knows how to send a regular
email that's not going to work that is
where the journalist will have to meet
them at initially it's always possible
to to educate a source in how to use
some of these other tools maybe you can
get them on signal maybe you can get
them comfortable with making a whatsapp
phone call for example but that still
requires the reporter to take some time
to get them set up and if that
communication happens by email for
example you are leaving a trace showing
that the reporter was engaging with the
source at that point in time talking
about how to set up secure comms now I
don't know how many saw this from it
came out yesterday the DOJ announced
that it has charged a former
intelligence analyst with providing
classified information to a reporter and
the indictment it's pretty interesting
and it's also fairly short so if you
have time you should dig it up and
read it and I think it's like page five
and six that sort of outlines the many
different times that the source and the
reporter communicated and you see the
source uses a non non secret non
classified computer to research the
reporter then attends the reporter's
book event the day after then he uses a
top-secret computer to search for
classified information about the people
that the reporter specifically indicated
that he was interested in then you have
this like long thread where the source
of the reporter are communicating back
and forth with regular texts and an
email then about six months and the
reporter contacts the source to set up
encrypted cops and so you have this like
metadata trail all throughout this
interaction that shows that they were
communicating and so if at the end of
the day if the source is not familiar
with how to securely communicate with a
reporter you're going to have a
challenge of how do you bootstrap that
how do you set them up for that without
leaving this much metadata just hanging
around which just means that you have to
essentially find that like baseline
could they just meet in person for
example and they're just there's no sort
of like one-size-fits-all it sort of
really depends on the reporter it
depends on the story they're working on
it depends on what we're expecting to
get from the source so we really try and
like engineer a little like toolbox
alike
we can try x and y and z and then with
the reporter come up with the the method
that's going to work the best we also
say that the whatever policy we said in
the newsroom must follow best practice
and it can't be something custom I would
rather have a newsroom that is raising
the bar for making signal and what's up
common and acceptable and accepted same
with tor entails and these other tools
making encrypted comes the default
rather than us trying to roll something
that is unique
possibly faulty and ultimately it's
going to put more people at risk and
over time it may be seen as more
suspicious to use something custom by
the New York Times than it is to make a
what's up call for example so we try to
focus on solutions that are well known
known to be secure have been vetted used
by the general public
and so we do work on educating the
newsroom and through articles that we
write workshops that we do we do try and
also educate future and current sources
even if we don't know who they are so
another sort of challenge that we've
seen is sort of the rise of online
threats and harassment it's not new but
I would say in the past two years maybe
three years we've seen online threats
and harassment escalate in a way that
just sort of feels free different it's
persistent it's it's persistent it's a
higher volume and it sort of feels very
different than what we perhaps saw
before and I would also I would I would
also argue that you have reporters who
maybe because of who they are or what
they write about have just like gotten
used to this like low-level Wiltern just
harassment on social media and they
gotten to the point where that's just
like it's like whatever they got used to
it the bar is a bit higher now for what
will rattle them or upset them or cause
them to report something but now you
also have a lot of new reporters often
younger reporters getting this sort of
firehose on Twitter in a way that is new
for them it is to some extent a bit new
for us to see the escalation and we're
trying to figure out how do we best meet
the needs of the newsroom in this case
can we educate staff on what to do what
not to do how do you handle harassment
or threats who do you report it to other
times what kind of support can the
company provide what would it look like
if you had to report it to law
enforcement and then unfortunately
educate law enforcement to Scylla they
fully understand what it is that you're
dealing with and that it's not just
someone blowing off steam for example
and this is sort of a challenge that we
do share with a lot of other media works
as well as something that we do talk
about we all try to sort of figure out
how do we best support the newsroom
knowing that we're not going to be able
to eliminate online threats and
harassment so how can we focus on
digital physical emotional support for
the newsroom and in that way build a
resilient newsroom now that is a huge
challenge and undertaking and one of the
things that The Times did about a year
and a bit ago was that we created a
cross collaborative teams across team
collaborative team to focus on this
challenge specifically so you had wraps
from InfoSec and physical security and
legal and that topic did get the space
it needed to be discussed so we could
all come up with solutions and then a
month ago now we also hired a VP of
corporate security who is going to focus
a bit more on the physical safety and on
all on threats and harassment of our
staff which i think is a fantastic move
and then finally we also now focus more
on proactive steps prior to research and
publication so last summer two people on
my team Kristin Kaczynski Nena Kapoor
came up with what they call the daxing
workshop where initially it was a
dusting service if you filled out a
Google Form with just like your name and
like some online handles and it's
essentially gave us your permission to
dock see you we would spend about our
air over and I have seeing how much we
could find out about you then we would
sit down in person and show you
everything that we found and then talk
about ways in which that you can lock
down or delete it completely and that
was such a popular service that it's now
turned into a workshop where we will
teach reporters how to docks themselves
for the purpose of ensuring that when
they do publish that next story about
alright for example it's not going to
have a huge blowback on them and the
same way it would as if they're like
home address and phone number and
favorite pad and everything was just
publicly available and that is something
that we continue with today and that has
had a huge impact in the news room and
now we do see editors and reporters
reach out saying I started investigating
this thing I'm planning a profile about
this person at that point they don't
even know when they're going to publish
which means that we have a lot of time
to really get this right and really help
them lock things down a couple of other
fun things that we've done so when I
started back in 2016 there was a
security team but we didn't have a whole
lot of presence in the newsroom so I
figured what is a good way to introduce
yourself to 1,400 people back then and
at the same time bootstrap the team that
you're on so I started sending at
monthly phishing tests started fishing
the newsroom on a monthly basis and at
the end of each test it was I would
summarize it and publish on our internal
site how many people opened the email I
mean if people click the link how many
people enter their usernames and
passwords and then I would note the top
five desks so the you know the Metro and
international and cooking and those
groups top five that that failed or had
the highest number of people
enter their usernames and passwords that
created some competition within the
newsroom which seemed like that was a
popular move and to the point where
people knew that we were sending out the
tests every month so they knew that
something was gonna come and it's like
oh it's June 2nd there has some inner
fishing test something's gonna come at
some point in time so they would all
talk about it and they would sort of
chat with us on the hallway trying to
figure out when are we sending the test
what is it gonna look like what are you
doing with the people who didn't do so
well the month before and it also really
helped them shape who we engage with how
we train them how often we train them
and just how we communicate what fishing
is and how you do to avoid it because
you can give the same message to someone
multiple times but if they DIF that
doesn't land if they don't fully
understand what it is that you're trying
to communicate you're gonna have to
switch it up so that also really helped
us see like who needed more help and who
needed help in a different way that we
hadn't done it before we also so this
has sort of changed slightly but back
then in 2016 17 we would have one full
hour for information security training
with every new hire in the newsroom so
we would do that on a I think it was
bi-weekly business back then since then
our onboarding program has changed and
we now have 30 minutes with all new
hires at the company so and then on top
of that we do some additional training
with certain desks so we have then the
opportunity to provide that basic the
baseline digital security here's what
you absolutely need to know and then we
also do engage with different desks to
talk about here's how you research
securely here's how you research a
company where they're disclosing that
you the New York Times is interested in
looking into this here's what you should
consider for travel we've done brown bag
lunches with legal to talk about border
searches especially in the context of
the US what the law says what's sort of
like gray area and what you shouldn't
shouldn't do what the company can do for
you if you do get detained so talk about
what the law does
and then we can talk about also what you
can do from a security perspective and
what we then our team can do for the
newsroom in that context so you then get
to train people on that very sort of
unique topic challenge specific area in
a way that talking about that in an
onboarding wouldn't necessarily make
sense one because the audience is sort
of too broad but also on morning is like
this crazy I think it's like a three day
if not full week experience and you're
sort of getting this firehose about
anything and everything that you should
know about the company so we try to save
that for a bit later we do a lot of
awareness through newsletters weekly
tips we sent out advisories when things
pop up and we do national cybersecurity
Awareness Month so the first one was
last year we had cake that was really
popular and lock-picking was I think the
most popular workshop that we did last
year to the point where and the
Washington DC bureau wanted lock-picking
as well so we organized that for them so
we do focus a lot on culture as part of
the security program and building
awareness we also do as I mentioned
earlier build a lot of relationships
with vendors and teams because there are
so many different people that will
ultimately engage with the newsroom in
some way shape or form if we can educate
them they can then educate the people
that they talk to and really as a team
of I think we're now ten at an
organization of five thousand you are
going to need to find other people who
can help support your mission so in
terms of supporting in the mission how
can we take the lessons learned at the
times and empower other media works so
one thing that we can do is sort of
share experiences and intelligence and
so the lessons learned so for the past
year we've had a little sort of group of
folks from security teams that media
works that are
getting together on like multi calls
in-person meetups sharing the type of
challenges that they have what they're
thinking about travel comes up a lot
what they're thinking about just digital
security what about data retention
policies for email what about social
media nor talk about some of these
challenges that I may be unique for the
space but certainly not unique to
individual mediaworks talked a bit about
secure supporting users with accounts so
the whole personal corporate accountant
piece is just really really tricky like
you have no way to like enforce security
settings in that space so you do really
rely on ensuring that the end user knows
what to do and what not to do we also
then focus on have reporters can
securely use Twitter and Facebook and
these other platforms instead of saying
no you shouldn't use it it will lead to
much metadata or it's not secure or
Facebook would give out your data in
response to a court order would you try
and just sort of know we try and help
the reporters just be aware of the
challenges be aware of the risks and
then sort of show one how to how to do
it yeah
and two final pieces are not everyone's
got personal or professional contacts I
will I will say that the network that
I've built up over the years with the
people that have had the pleasure of
communicating with are also sort of the
same network that I reach out to now
when someone needs help with their
snapchat account for example in some
cases we're not going to have a
corporate New York Times to whatever
relationship with the other org and so
there are times when we then leverage
more personal contacts to get to the
right contact at the company and get the
assistance that we need it works today
but it's a bit unfortunate that media
works don't have that level of contact
at these companies so we're really
trying to build that out now and ensure
that that is also shared among all the
other media works so that if a reporter
does have an issue there is sort
official ish Channel and place to get
them the help and then finally online
threats and harassment is sort of it's a
topic that everyone's talking about it's
not unique to two media by by any means
but it is now a conversation that is
flowing both within Media works and now
also with I mean we've seen Twitter and
Facebook talk about it for a while but I
think there's a lot of talk and
everyone's now very interested in
finding more solutions to the challenges
that we're seeing so I think that was my
last slide yeah with that I do have
about 15 minutes for Q&A if anyone's got
questions either here or I'll hang
around outside as well I think thank you
thank you very much true enough
any questions from the floor or indeed
questions during coffee break over
coffee thank you again to Runa for
coming back on to the hack in the vox
stage another round of applause please
[Applause]
[Music]
you