okay so let's start with the talk first
of all for those of you who don't know
we which would be most of you I guess
my name is are now I'm from Barcelona
I'm a student of maths and computer
science at the University of Barcelona
I'm also the president of a non-profit
hacking organization in Barcelona I
found it with some friends the faculty
and I'm also a collaborator in the
organization of the r2 cone which is the
Congress about rather - and which is
held every year in Barcelona and
probably most important then who I am is
who am I not I am NOT a professional
reverse engineer and I am NOT an expert
in ruther - and I am NOT a developer in
brother - lista core one this is
important because that goes straight to
the motivation of the talk that is the
very beginning just demystified rather -
there is a lot of myths around it and
being very difficult to learn and do
stuff so we'll try to domestic I it then
of course
following the previous one I am really
interested in trying to give you simple
explanations that came from a non
advanced user which I guess will be
helpful for many of you also there is a
great way to organize and share the
knowledge about rather to to make just
conscious to our back lap and also I
strongly believe that conferences of all
kind of conferences should have
introductory talks to some some topic in
this case rather - and basic reversing
with it and that's my that's my
motivation - for him presented this this
paper this talk and for being here today
first of all quick poll who are you
how many of you are students undergrads
is there any undergrad ok that's cool
I am I'm also undergrad so we are -
right now
maybe masters phd's okay how many of you
are working in InfoSec I guess most of
you how many of you are doing low-level
staff or reverse engineering as you main
work okay
and those of you mostly that the ones
that do a low-level stop reverse
engineering I guess you will know there
are two but how many of you use it like
regularly okay that's cool that's really
cool because I I tend to say that if you
are people that use rather too and are
working in reverse engineering as
professional field I'm I have really but
I have very little things to teach you
because this will be an introduction to
rather to and some basic reversing for
people not not introduced to that but as
I have seen most of you the past
majority don't use it or or don't work
on reverse engineering so I think it
will be pretty interesting to see how it
goes from a my intro interruption
standpoint and this will be at the
outline of the ADI conference and before
i go straight to it if it will take a
minute though the ones that are with
computers if you want to follow the
demos you have those URLs to download
some correctness and one of the other
demos I will be doing I will let you one
minute
copy it and there you will have it
for the first the first link you will
download the whole pack of your lis
kragnes which are scrag means made by
both it's a computer researcher based in
Barcelona currently and it's funny
because he did those crime is to teach
his wife to learn reverse engineering a
long time ago and they are still pretty
useful and very basic for people in
getting introduced to reverse
engineering and I still love them and
use use them every time I can the other
one is just the pack of complete samples
from accompanying a book on reversing it
is secret of reversing by Halen
I guess his name and this is a pretty
cool book on reversing right into
reduction in my opinion and we will be
using some one of his samples to do
couple demos so guess the most of you
will have its yeah sorry thing ok or not
it's really easy to find them just look
for Yoli correctness or a secret of
reversing Geylang samples and you will
find at first search
ok let's go strike with it first of all
I'm gonna I'm gonna cover basically or
rather to and I think this will be
useful because most of you didn't answer
when I when I asked how many of you used
it so let's go to it first of all and in
case you know whether to this free and
opensource reverse engineering framework
that is rewritten in C by pancake it's
name is Sergey Alvarez is a mobile
security researcher researcher currently
based in Barcelona as well and it says
rewritten because initially it was
rather not trailer - it was born as a
forensics tool to care for data among
partitions for his work like more than
10 years ago and then it continued it
evolved as he needed to add some stuff
or cts or his his own needs and then
there was a moment that it was a
completely mess full monolithic project
without any real structure so he decided
to rewrite it entirely as libraries and
so we will see the structure a little
bit later but that's that's why there is
that too because there was a an initial
one it's rather a framework that is
built from scratch from scratch without
third-party dependencies that's that's
kind of interesting because you have the
libraries for example the analysis
libraries the binary information
libraries and you can get them and
include it and use it on your projects
without having to build upon the whole
rather to frame where you just can grab
the library you need and use it as as it
and it doesn't really have any
third-party dependency for example I I
remember that at the very beginning I
guess it was a little dependency on onon
courses and packages we wrote some kind
of pseudo and courses for his nets and
that's it and of course it's really
portable scriptable and extensible
through plugins we will see a lot of
that afterwards and more formally and
the foremost stuff it has a release
timing of six weeks it's based on the
rust release and it's not really fair
that I say that but it has a really
great community and there is the the
Congress held annually in Barcelona
every September so I will invite you to
come to visit it they're really cool
Congress let's go to the capabilities
what can't rather to do first of all of
course it's a reverse engineering
framework so it can disassemble binaries
of several architectures operating
systems it can analyze code and date I
mean that a structural reference is to
function so that come on staff that that
you will just expect from our reverse
engineer
work it can also be used to do low-level
debugging and it has some really cool
stuff to do exploiting I will cover Lee
a bit of this afterwards not that much
but just a brief on how can we go to to
exploit in part with with Radha too and
of course we can do a binary
manipulation patching and all kind of
stuff then we have as well as I said
previously it was born as a forensics
tool so of course it keeps it forensics
capabilities
montt mounting file system in part she
partitions data curbing that that stuff
the point is that it's probably not the
main focus right now developers the the
forensics part of Radha too but still
you have it and it's built in relative
so you can use it without having to
change the other tools we are doing some
kind of reversing involving our analysis
with and you need to mount some file
system or whatever you can do it just
just with it it has also cool methods to
extract matrix from different binaries
and it's quite useful for classification
and it has entropy modules it can't for
example there is a there's a cool option
that lets you made block based hashing
that is I can define I want to compare
different binaries okay you make a hash
of those binaries and you know that they
are different because the hash is done
then concede that you don't know where
it is and if it's a huge binary then
it's it can be a problem a problem so it
has integrated it for example okay I
want to make hashes of every 100 byte
blocks so it compares block by block and
you can you can see where it is changing
exactly and then you have you can do as
well colonel analysis and debugging I
wouldn't go into colonel
today because first of all because I it
won't be enough time to cover it and
second because I'm not really into
karana analysis so I will I can point
you to where to go if you're interested
in doing more kernel staff but it won't
be really extend extensively covered
here and what has rather to support what
has supported so basically all of that I
don't expect you to read it but briefly
it runs everywhere and supports
everything you can any operating system
that you have it can run and it supports
almost any file format and almost in
architecture out there probably more
than those that are written here and if
usually when it comes out some new
architecture some new file format and it
takes very little time to be to support
it and if it happens that you have some
really weird file format or architecture
where you would like to have it
supported and it is not by default first
of all ask on let's tell on channel or I
see videos it's probably supported but
no one updated the document and second
and if not just open an issue or even
better make a pull request but usually
almost everything you might encounter is
supported let go straight to it in case
you don't have it the best way to get
rather to is through the git repository
just clone it go into the directory
create it and use the season style set
script the script is is really nice
because it will build everything for you
you don't have to mess with makes make
files or anything it will install it a
system-wide
by default if you are interested in
installing only per user then you can
run instead of install a sage there is
another batch script called user a sage
in that case it won't ask you for any
permissions but the
the common way if you're on a Windows
machine or a Mac or any other fancy
platform you can check the website for
binaries there the banner the
precompiled binaries for most platforms
and also there are the instructions - if
you want to compile it on your own for
any of your machines okay and yet this
please and it's kind of a meme but it
makes a lot of sense there's a huge
problem with Linux distributions in
particular in particular Debian they are
using a old version of
provisional brother in the repositories
and many times there is people
complaining that this feature doesn't
work this is not supported and it's just
they're using a bill from three years
ago or four years ago so please if you
you will be happy and everyone will be
happy using rather - from get if not you
if you don't want to be updating
everything I just forget to mention that
this the last come on install sh you can
run it every time you want to update
rather - and it will automatically pull
the repository and install it so you
don't have you don't even have to bother
of polling repositories just every time
you want to update it run this command
it will pull it and uninstall it and
there are the releases every six weeks I
said so in case you don't want to be
just updating every day rather tool you
can stick to the releases but their
preferred and recommend the way of using
it is from get okay and what are the
tools included in rather - as I said
it's a the reverse engineering framework
and it has many tools included not only
the main rather tool as it is I have
listed here the tools there are a bunch
of them the first one is rocks - which
is a base converter it's a very basic
base converter to make some operations
binary to hexadecimal it script
all really useful right into it is the
standalone binary for extracting binary
information which is also integrated
into the rather tube shell as well
razvan tool which is the assembler and
disassembler you can specify here the
architecture the bits of the
architecture the engine nests and the
terrain you can assemble on this
assembly with it then there is the
Rajesh - which is the Krypton fashion
utility it has implemented hasn't been
that most known Krypton hashing
algorithms you can check out them also
relative to which is the included binary
different tool in rack 2 which is here
it says it's to compile tiny binaries
which is true but it's the official
description but I would say it's more
like an exploit helper in my opinion
because you can basically grab your own
C code that you want to be the you want
to inject a shellcode basically and it
will create the shellcode for it to
execute it will drop unnecessary stuff
and give you the durability shellcode of
course as it was growing as a
exploitation system let's say the way it
has some other typical things to do and
I will show late it like doing the
bridging patterns and searching for the
offsets under kind of stuff when we are
looking for for the memory position for
228 the code then we have a run to which
is running it let us to run rather to
with different environments what does
this mean it means for example that we
want to open spawn shell oh brother - we
want to work on a file we are reversing
a file but we want to make it like if we
open from that working directory with
that environment variables with these
arguments so we can just grab a little a
very little file with that and we found
- we will pass the binary and with the
environment as well and it will be
loaded as if it was actually running
from the
and define it's quite useful for some of
the tasks then of course there is the
hair to PN which is the package manager
said prior to is really extensible via
plugins there are some of them the most
use that are actually included in the in
the core rather - and you just install
it you will have them but there are
other ones that can be installed through
the package manager it's really really
easy to use her to PM install and the
name of the package and that's it and
you can obviously uninstall and manage
it is a very simple package manager but
really useful to to get track of all
your external plugins and then for sure
we have relative which is the main tool
which is the shared actual shell for for
doing all the staff and it includes the
functionalities of most of the other
tools I mean we have standalone tools
that are using some of the libraries we
said before and as well we have rather -
that is including all those libraries
and using them inside the shell so you
can use it them as standalone programs
or inside the shell it depends on your
needs so let's go for commentary
interaction and let's go straight to it
I hope you have your rather shell just
waiting for the opening so how to spawn
a rather - shell first of all our - is a
same link for our tool you will usually
see you are - when calling card - just a
formalism but just in case to open a
file just are two and path of the file
then this won't open in in right mode
which means that we won't be permitted
to write and the file and to do this we
will have to open it with the right flag
which is the W and if we want to do back
has so we can run the process and attach
to it
we'll discuss a little bit about how
debugging works and afterwards so one
debugging session we have to append we
have to use that - the flag while
opening then there is another
interesting flag for me which is okay I
don't want to load any user settings any
custom settings that that is because we
can custom and crafts mostly everything
from rudder to its options
configurations or a lot of stuff we will
dig into it in a couple points
afterwards but just in case we want to
just open a shell without any custom
custom settings loaded just with -
capital n we will do it and then there
are two other interesting and quite
useful sometimes come on that is okay I
just want to open our arty shell but I
don't really want to open any file I
just want to look through it or maybe
explore the configuration to configure
it or whatever I just don't need to open
a file you have two options first one is
just with a - I will just open with this
macro which is Amit will give us 512
bytes of memory so we can write in it
and and we can can modify it we can
write whatever we want and we can also
save it to a file and there is okay I
don't really want anything to be opened
or memory to be allocated I just want to
look through the the shell and their
options
so with two dashes it will open a shell
but it won't attach to any file so this
is one of the important one of the
important slides here are two comments
per se to be difficult usually because
are not common their syntax is not the
most common lastly but it's not that
difficult it's based on mnemonics
mnemonics means are - comments are
really short comments usually short
where each letter means one thing and
the letters left the leftmost letters
are the comments then we have the
following sub comments so for example we
want to seek to an offset we will
use the s we want to bring the hex time
we'll use px bring hexagon printer
disassembler PD want to write experience
right assembly analyze all info all or
quit and everything worked like that so
sometimes you can even guess what will
be the common and for example I will
make it is here I don't know if you see
it so as I said let's say that I want PD
20 lines of the assembly print the same
with 20 lines and you don't see anything
because it's freaking ok good so now we
want to seek to for example I round this
position so we just seek to this
position
whoops yeah and the pointer changed ok
that error is just because my clipboard
doesn't work well and when it passes
stop it just ok and if you want to for
example you wanted to write something
here we can do it because we have not
opened in write mode so I will open now
something that that I can write but not
being LS of course
[Music]
and if we open with the pride flag now
for you I'll bring the hexadecimal we
see the hexadecimal representation at
the opposite we are located we don't
need to we don't need to print the
default values a default amount of
hexadecimal program we can specify the
number of bytes the default values are
also configurable so view by default
just want to bring the hexadecimal of
three lines you can just configure it
that way and now we will forget out why
I want to write experts who said like a
90 and here you can see 90 90 so that's
it that is that this is quite important
this but probably most important slide
is this one now you have everything you
need rather to is really cool because it
has inline help which means that for
every comment and every sub comment you
can get in line help while in the shell
for all the options are on everything
and I will show you just right now if we
just open our show we just saw a
question mark will have all the options
all the commands available and there the
description for example let's say we
want to go to the analysis comment which
is the a so we hope we go to a and we
append a question mark we will see it
sub comments we want to deal with
analyzing functions okay so you can
analyze functions and a question mark
now we will see all the options for
function analysis we want to list the
functions we here unless the functions
and there is only the entry point why
because we haven't analyzed it yet so we
just analyze the code and now an iced
functions list we will see all the
functions it from this is LS okay
so keep in mind just appending a
question mark its
best way probably to move on is you
don't really need to know every comment
every mnemonic you will get used to most
of them at least they're 15 which are
with those you can make 99% of
regular stuff but if you need to to look
for something just a penny question mark
and you will have all the descriptions
and all the options running for it okay
some handy tricks that I found quite
useful and are interesting when dealing
with para 2 is for example usually when
we throw a comment if we append that J
at the end or J with with that with that
curly brackets it will gives us the
output in JSON format both or contented
or expanded I will show you for example
eyes for information will see the
options okay let's say I'm interested in
the sections of the binary so
information of the sections here the
sections let's say now I want to get it
in JSON okay
this suggestion and I want to read it
like pretty so this is that's it I will
advanced just one slide but I am coming
back in a moment
that's really cool because we can pipe
with the shell comments directly and we
can even run shell comments from it
which means basically that we can do
this and pipe it for example to less
directly we can look for it then
whatever nib and I'm not really sure if
this works right now yep we can drag the
pipe to a file and now we have you can
call it directly so another cool thing
is we can append cube on most of
commands as well and it will give us a
quiet quiet output for example removing
some non non important or not essential
staff this is quite useful for example
in these sections example just appending
a Q so it will give us a way briefly
output that's it and it has implemented
an internal grip that's very interesting
and you would say because I advanced
okay but why don't you just pipe and use
grip there are a couple of reasons first
one is not every systems have grip if
you're running on a Windows you don't
really have grip style or some versions
of busybox that don't have grip and you
can have a brother installed and wanting
toured with that so you have internal
grip that you can use it right right
this for example will is the sections we
can grab for section that contain the
word data and that's it then we can run
native shell commands from the native
geology of the system with the
exclamation mark protects that's that's
quite interesting that it will it will
return to the rod to shell without
losing the session just and finally one
interesting thing is that we don't
really there are some modifiers I want
to go deep with them but one of the most
important or most used is the the
temporary sig is with the @ symbol and
it basically means that perform the
operation you are telling add an offset
but without having to be seeked to it
that you will understand with an example
way better for example if I want to
print the December of 16 bytes at I
don't know
here oops at this at this memory I would
have to seek there as I told you before
and now in the disassembly of 32 lines
but if I am just here which is the entry
point where we arrive just respond
Michelle I can do the do this without
having to be sick to the other place
just with the temporary sick and was
like you will see that it's the same
output but we are still sick where we
want this is quite useful because most
of times we are dealing with main
function and we are working with it but
we want to explore another function but
we don't really want to be seeking from
back and forth to one function I'll just
do a tempura sick and that's salt and
yeah let you go straight to it let's
make a very simple first demo of the
crack me I guess it will be there number
two of the Yoli ones that I put before
just to show you the do you see it well
the screen yeah it's just very simple
fragment is put a password and it says
invalid our goal in this crack me will
be to to make the program accept any
password okay then afterwards we will
see when we talk about emulation why I'm
doing this now and afterwards I will be
doing like extracting the natural
password actually the the challenges if
you read there if you have downloaded
them and look to the readme says that
you have to fight the binaries clock
setting it password so we are being
legal okay we have the the Primus
unloaded but with the
first of all if we want to patch the
binary how do we have to open the file
so we can patch it that is modifying
anyone exactly we need to double your
flag because otherwise we can explore it
that we cannot modify it on disk then I
will show you a cool trick about
modifying the binary on the session but
not on the disk but now we will will be
using that will make just a copy cm2 and
we are opening it with the value flag
first of all what do we want to do
analyzing it there is a there is a meme
in the community that says that just
throw a stew rather to and analyze
everything because as more a 0 deeper is
the analysis so usually with 3 days you
have enough there is some experimental
analysis methods that run with 4s and
some some time ago you just open the
session and just did that and it worked
because starting at 4 s you can put more
but it will do the same but then there
are rod developers are really funny and
I guess it's starting at 7 8
this is this message I'm doing anything
so you can throw a bunch of face but no
more than 7 or D won't do anything ok so
hey if we will have it properly analyzed
by now so we can for example is the
functions analyzes functions list AFL to
lose the functions we are interested in
the main wine in the main one and now
what can we do as as we know we could
seek to the main
which is a this is a flag so we don't
really need to copy the upset we could
just seek to main to the flag we could
as well print this assembly at main
which is printing the disassembly ah at
the offset reference by the main flag
but without singing to it and there is
another option which is PDF which
basically is created this assembly of a
function this is quite interesting
because if you specify that what you're
disassembling is a function it will as
it is as it has been analyzed it will
give the assembly of the whole function
with the boundaries otherwise you will
have to print this assembly 20 lines or
10 or maybe 30 so it as it has detected
and the length of the function is quite
interesting and we can just see two men
because we will be using it you see the
pointer change and then we just run PDF
if we wanted to print the assembly of
another function without seeking to it
just the same temporary sig PDF add
function whatever okay but in this case
we're in the main so we can just print
it as a symbol of the function how many
of you understand assembly okay most of
you that's fine but that's really fine
that some of you don't really understand
it because you'll need it you don't
actually need to understand assembly I'm
not an expert on assembly at all I can't
read it more or less some architecture
but that's it and you will show you will
see because you don't really need to
understand it because it's really easy
in this case these are really easy
crackme so we have the main function we
have some stuff worried about it then we
have here Oh risk you will do it a
little bit can you read it as okay
because Danny here it's less messy and
having all the that zoom so here we have
a reference to a string which we have
here in the comment and then a call to
something that is printf you don't need
to know assembly to to know that what's
happening here okay here there is
another reference to another string
which contains password con space and
our call to printf again you don't need
to know assembly to know what's going on
here then we have something and then a
call to scanf it was asking us for a
password so again you don't really need
to know what's going on to understand
what's happening here and then here we
have an interesting part which is
basically moving some values on memory
making some operations adding and
multiplication so on and then comparing
two values that's it you don't really
need to get to the exact I mean you
don't really need if you are starting
reverse engineering it's quite
recommended that you go through through
that with a pencil and paper and okay
this goes to this memory and then this
one is multiplied by this value here
it's really really useful but to do most
of the things you really need to
understand line by line up the assembly
just go stick to the point so here we
have two printouts of the strings we
have seen then a call to scanf some kind
of operations with somebody's that herb
are being loaded and then a comparison
between the OP D D value that is stored
here and the value register here and we
can see that the one stored the Perseids
which is at the base pointer minus C in
the stack frame is the one that is being
reference here okay we will see
afterwards when we talk about emulation
why this is important at least why we
are interested in it but now but what we
only what we want to do is patch it to
accept any password so here it is a
comparison and
then we have a conditional jump if not
equal here we you have the arrows if
it's not equal it will jump here which
is invalid password Oh a reference
symbolic password and printf it's it's
clear crystal clear and otherwise it
will continue and you say ok the
password is ok and we are done
so anyone has an idea how to patch it so
it always says that the password is ok
yeah exactly
just get rid of this jump if it does a
comparison but it doesn't care about the
result because if we remove this it will
just go straight to loading the password
string and calling the printf how can we
do that so can sick if my clipboard is
working ok this is the line print the
disassembly of one line and we'll write
to experts 90 90 in case you don't know
it an ID is the hexadecimal of the OP
code representation which is not just no
operation ok next 36 so we will write
two knobs here and now we can see for
example the hexadecimal of just this
time we see that this has been written
and if we again read this assembly have
a knob here have knobs and that's it
that's pretty much it now we can do
assembly the main again and you see that
here just before the world in the
password ok we have knobs and we just
wait
oops it's not this one is the copy
password okay whatever so that's it
we'll come back to this example
afterwards to see another demo on
another different approach but that's
basically it
and again let's say I don't really
remember how to write hex decimal and
hexadecimal value so I know that right
is W so W question mark ah all right
okay here we have right hexadecimal okay
so right exercise now do we have any
more options yes we have more options so
we write hex pers and seek at the end
for example we can write hit X first and
then sync to it or I mean this is the
when you have done this a couple times
usually we remember it but if not just a
pen a question mark and and look for it
it's really really quick to do okay
that's it now we will dig a little bit
on the visual modes and navigation yeah
no not necessarily
of course yeah really good question in
this case was really easy because no
piece everyone knows that is not an idea
but no you can just assemble the the
instruction as it is if you have two
ways one is just the same read which is
using the the the assembler and is a
symbol library inside you can do it both
with standalone utility which is resum
to or with inside rar - you have another
another option which is the right
assembly and sub comment and you can
directly write the instruction and other
way is there is some advanced with
advanced some visual mode that you can
just for example usually if you want to
change one jump from not equal to equal
or something like that you can just use
the cursor mode cursor mode that maybe I
will yeah I will use it a little bit at
the end on the last demo that you can
basically place to a specific byte and
just increment decrement and usually
wait for example when you're not jump
instruction just incrementing and
decrementing the bite of the hexadecimal
you just are changing their values but
yeah of course not you don't really need
to know all the hex values but if you if
you would you can make it with the
December yeah so the visual modes
okay the all this shell is cool but we
want more interaction we have more
interaction we have the basic visual
mode which is just with the big comment
we can run into it I will open a file
otherwise it would be just nothing for
example with the beep we have here the
hexadecimal representation here we can
use the scroll I'm scrolling right now
we can just move right yes and with P we
can rotate the print mode that is here
we have in hex representation here we
are in this assembly we have in December
E and if we were debugging or emulating
we we would be seeing the registers
values and so then this is another
representation because its enthalpy and
more representation of strings and come
back this basic piece well note I won't
really waste more time into it because I
mean it's interesting but it's not the
point to seeing all the options of the
visual mode but two interesting things
that you can just throw a question mark
and you have the help the visual mode
help so you can have all the other
things that you can do inside the visual
mode you have Hugh explain so you can
just navigate through it and another
thing is that if you want to run and are
to comment while visual mode you have to
just depend : it's like v we are used to
using V I am NOT but I am used to use
rather so it's small at the same you can
just run ranked on for example if you
want to analyze the functions you're
here want analyze the functions ok and
I'm going to the disassembly for example
and now I want to list the functions
so just colon and then the command and
you will see down there with an with a
return you come back to the visual mode
then there is the graph B which is
really cool for all reverse engineers
and really useful for following the
flaws of the function what's going on in
there what are the branches switches if
else closes loops it's only visual way
to do this for it to work I mean to work
to show something you have to be seeked
to a function or apply it to an offset
function with the temporary sig we have
seen and you can move it with the
old-style AGPL or also with arrows and
you can zoom in and zoom out with plus
and minus has more options of course but
those are the basic ones for navigation
and again you can just append a question
mark and see what are the all the
options so let's see how it looks like
for example let's see cut main and here
we are these are really poor rap because
it's so simple so I will open for
example being a less about 10 LS we
analyze it secant main see the graph
function okay you can follow it for
example you have all these ogod eoa be
there here you can just follow the paths
with those shortcuts you can make it
just smaller bigger whatever you need
you can also rotate mode here it is kind
of cool and of course you got with the
question mark I just pick the question
mark you have all the options with grab
use so you can play with it and then
there is another one which I'm in love
with which is visual panels and they are
extremely useful when doing some kind of
debugging or some parallel things and
they're basically a panel terminal to
the panel terminal with different views
you have this assembly here the stack
here the registers they're usually the
default panels that it's
it's troves are the good ones let's say
that way those are there if you are
debugging it will show one panel is a
building and other stuff it will show
another one slightly different but you
can of course customize the view panels
and add your own and move them around
whatever you like it oops it looks
something like this let's see
yep have the disassembly now you you see
it good because I have a lot of zoom for
you to view but on a regular computer or
addition bigger screen so you have here
you can with tab you can just move it
this is a really decompile the
compilation this which is this like a
toy the compiler this is not anything
fancy it's just getting a quick
translation there afterwards we will
talk about the compilation and so and
you have for example you define terms
listed on the same balls and if you were
for example the debugging for example
you could cut the stack and you have
some panel for a stack telescoping which
is getting the references and the values
and other for the registers that's quite
useful okay so again you can just with
its with V exclamation mark and just a
pen a question mark and you're good to
go
let's go straight to a configuration and
customization of order 2 and that's it
basically use the e comment and it's up
comments to tune rather to the e stands
for the available configuration
variables there are ton of different
valuable variables configuration
variables that can be tuned to your
needs or your preferences to use it
within a brother to if you just throw an
A it will show all the configuration
variables and you will say holy
what the yeah but there are better
ways to look for it and and see what's
going on if we append to question marks
we will see the descriptions of them but
course first thing you know okay we can
grip because we have internal grab for
example let's look for something that
has to do with bite so you have the
options that have to do it by some their
descriptions and these are one of the
ways of looking for that there are more
and I will show you my preferred one
yeah look for them with internal grip we
can list the possible variables with we
just make either configuration variable
equals the question mark if it has a
predefined set of values that it can
take it will gives us those I guess for
example he has an architecture it gives
us which parka texture can be defined
here's variable that's an example and a
lot of them are just binary values to a
fault and we can set a new value just
sin a sig signature what is s it have it
here yeah but I will go now
I will advance it the best way for me to
explore all the configuration is with
the visual mode because if we just if we
just throw ve or if we're in visual mode
and press key we can explore all the
configuration variables structured so
for example we are interested in their I
don't know graph so just throw an arrow
we can see all the values on their
descriptions or we can add it navigate
to it and we can even change them for
example grab line mode we can define any
value and if it's other for example a
boolean value we can change it directly
that's it
these are nice way to explore the
configuration BIOS but I said don't be
overwhelmed with that usually the
configuration variables that you would
need for a particular binary at loaded
by default because the before the binary
format the architecture are out to
detect it and automatically put in the
configuration variables it's more like
okay I want the block size for my
disassembly printing to be off I don't
32 bytes instead of 256 so that kind of
stuff but most of the like hardcore
configuration variables will be detected
by default and you won't have any
problems I'll still there in case you
want to force it because I don't know
polymorph malware or whatever you want
to explore it with viewing with
different architecture or something you
can have it but you won't be messing
with configuration variables most of the
time just very little and what's cool
I'll cool thing that I don't have
mentioned but I guess it's it's
important to mention at least funny with
AC is the colors is all the
configuration or color mapping we have
predefined themes my case I have
selected the doctor but I don't know
whatever and you can just have another
color map and if you press ECR it will
give you a fancy random color map so
which is more interesting is that in
visual mode you don't have to do it
every time you just capital R and that's
it and here if you want to have some
configuration variables loaded by
default on its session for example the
color mapping or I would show you mines
in a moment you just create our two RC
file hidden file in the home folder and
it will be loaded by default I can show
you mine this is just ecommons for
configuration variable that will be
loaded by default I am gonna discuss
them a little bit the first one is just
setting the color scheme and the other
ones I will talk here those are the
probably the useful configuration
variables for almost everyone first one
is CFC CR R EDF put the true that's good
because most of computers I will be
using nowadays support you T
characters and terminals and you will
see the difference you will see why it
is important if I just run it this way
remember the minus capital n flag is 2
don't load any custom setting so it will
it will ignore my my custom settings
file ok this is the the color map is
well it's kind of old school but ok but
look at the arrows please or with grab
videos look at the boxes and the arrows
so just a hearty go and you're good to
go
that's way cooler and it's even cooler
if you enable the curvy corners it's
just a tiny thing but it looks way
better those corners that are really
really strict you can make them Coria
here we go so does that really mean non
functionality related configuration but
at the dark cool to have and your eyes
will would thank you then there are well
one more I will show ok they I will go
to the asmu case that is right there
which is basically showing the
disassembly in upper case if you are
more like all school stuff and you want
to show it is assembly in upper case
it's as easy as that
that's then the show up code description
and enable see the syntax that's really
really really cool especially for people
getting into interest to reverse
engineering or even for reverse
engineers that with experience but they
are faced with a new architecture or a
new system they don't really know how
how it works
the first one is it will just a pen a
comment after each instruction saying
what is this doing it's just the
description we can see this for example
this is their I will have to put it a
little bit smaller titled I won't expect
you to read what it says just to see
what it happens here's described I just
throw the easm described equals true and
now you see all the red things I think I
can make it a little bit
it's just describing what's happening
okay like it's very very basic but if
you are in one instruction set you don't
know it's a cool way to learn some new
assembly instead of getting to the
manuals so of course you have to go to
the my notes for in-depth but for a
quick look and just understanding what's
going on it's quite useful and even if
you don't really like that assembly like
assembly way of doing things you can do
a whole thing let's let me reactivate
that which is a SM pseudo which will
make up pseudo syntax more
human-friendly or high clever friendly
and basically it will show that instead
of assembly look at this with eaves and
variables equals to ax minus three and
is not the composition at all it's just
making one-to-one translation between
the assembly and the on some other
syntax like that people coming from high
hiked languages will appreciate if they
are getting introduced to that okay and
then there is that other trick that I
mentioned you before which is the one of
of the i/o cache we did this lets us to
write into the binary that is loaded
into the memory but with without
modifying the actual file that is in the
hard disk that's quite useful in case we
want to play with some binary with some
crack name with whatever we want to
see okay I want to change that see what
it's happening but you don't want to
store that or modify the the of you just
have been to our session on reversing
something and you missed off it
don't have the day I have I'm not on a
copy of the file I just don't want to do
this again so you can enable i/o cache
and it's basically it makes a cache and
you can overwrite it won't say it will
permit it to you for example write
something on a file that you have not
opened with fright mode it will say you
can right here okay but if you enable
the cache it will act normally it's just
the the filing disk won't be modified
just the fact that is loaded into memory
you can work with it and when you are
out of the session that's it and we will
use it afterwards in a in a daemon
emulation okay seeing that okay I guess
that's it yeah let's go straight to code
emulation this is one I guess the the
longest point on the outline mainly
because two reasons one is I don't know
why people is not using emulation and
particularly not using emulation in
ruther and it's really useful and second
I had to give a talk like ten days ago
about emulation with easel so I just had
to make it anyway so I just get I stole
my own my own content so it's not
stealing and we will go through it and
it's what is emulation basically in case
someone is doesn't really know what
emulation is about is just similarly in
the execution of code of you know CPU of
the same cpu architecture or another CPU
architecture that's that's the point of
emulation that we can simulate executing
code that does not belong to the
architecture of our machine
yes that's basically what you do when
you run games from old or not that all
consoles all that kind of stuff is
basically full emulation
you're running and you're emulating
you're simulating the diffusion of code
that is not meant to be running the
inner architecture but the kind of rptr
emulation we are dealing today is not
the emulation seen as a part of running
games or all software is more a way is
an assistant for code analysis and
reverse engineer in particular we're
interested in it because it lets us to
understand specific snippet of codes of
binary from architecture or another
architecture doesn't matter and it's
quite useful as well because let's say
you are hiding some kind of weird
malware and you don't want to be pawned
so you can do this you can emulate some
parts of the code that is not the whole
binary just I'm interested in that
section that it looks like is some
routine Ford encrypting CUDA code or
it's some routine for whatever so you
can just take that snippet of code and
see what's going on there
and of course you are not running it
because yeah everyone uses butyl
machines all the time and all that kind
of stuff but I won't discover you that
they are exploits for scaping butyl
machines are all that and I mean of
course use virtual machines your son
boxing but if you are truly trading with
something really really delicate before
going to debugging or trying to
executing something unless you have a
dedicated machines then you're good to
go it just up you just don't
everything and install it again that's
fine but if you even if it's not your
case
so emulation is a really good friend for
you then of course it helps on debugging
and on code analysis you see with when
we are doing analysis with four ace and
I guess it with three as well in there
are two it's using some emulation for
branch prediction on functions and to
reconstruct some of the paths it's kind
of
tricky I don't really understand how
it's done but I mean I have not coated
it of course and I'm not into that part
development but it's using some kind of
emulation just for analysis to see okay
what's going on here with that function
that in and which information can we
extract from that just from looking at
particular snippet of code and of course
if you want to explore some non-native
executables we have to do something I
mean if you are if you want to explore
for example up PowerPC or an a RM tiny
binary that is not I am not saying like
very huge applications that you need a
full analysis but just specific things
you can you can explore it with
emulation you can see what's going on
without having to emulate things I debug
things and of course because you cannot
debug an architecture which is not the
computer so one important thing on an
emulation is the concept of intermediate
languages and just I want I won't go
very deep into theory it's just an
abstract machine that helps in analysis
of computer programs just as this name
says is an intermediate language between
the code and the actual code that is
written and the assembly that helps us
in the analysis and it's it comes mainly
from compiling from the compiling
process GCC is using an intermediate and
maybe you will know LLVM which has its
LLVM intermediate representation and
mainly they came out for assisting on
compiling process but are also vital for
the compilation so the idea for example
the IDA micro code for the hex race the
compiler is based on a in or an
intermediate language and we have our
own intermittent written in Row 2 which
is called a shield which means it stands
for available strings intermediate
language and
characteristics are quite simple it's a
very small set of instructions and the
syntax is based on reverse polish
notation which is basically a stack you
will see in a moment an example which
usually means that it is not meant to be
read and understand by a human but more
to be executed quick on a machine okay
and one some of the main properties is
that it has infinite memory and set of
registers like many others intermediate
languages at first there is this so
called
it has native register Alice's which
means for example you are emulating an
AR m AR M code and when you construct a
virtual machine that will emulate the
stuff you want to emulate the register
Alice's will be something like R 1 R 2 R
3 so it constructs the aliases so kind
of put you into the into the mood of the
architecture we are emulating so it's
not like something like okay I need to
now understand some other names from
some other register it they can be
arbitrary but for common architecture
they ultimately give you the Alice's
that you will thank and of course as I
have said it is space-time as most an
instruction but if you need custom
operations to support for some
architecture even the mainstream ones
that have very weird or rarely used
instructions you can just define them
you can quite easily implement a custom
operation based on the simple operations
that has a seal and link it as okay now
this operation will be described as this
set of instructions on in so you can use
that and why ezel ezel first of all we
needed the Malaysian on our to land is
basically they are to environment and
it's really easy to generate to parse
and modify because as I said it is so
most mostly the most important thing
generation and person because it is
based on reverse polish notation which
is basically a stack way of thinking and
also it's quite extensible rather easy I
would say
I mean it's not trivial but once you see
the instruction that you have at what
you want you're complete it's not really
difficult to add your custom operations
or width on top of it and of course why
not one of the problems that have some
of the intermediate languages is that
they are they are built with compiler
with a compiler band and easily build
with that the compilation with the
completion in mind so that's a good a
good way to see it so I would describe
UCL as this I would say the parser
that's running behind this deal if I
need a stack machine on steroids and I
will go straight to describe you what is
a stack machine
this is theory this theoretical computer
science which is super cool and I know I
see your faces that you are really
interested in how to matter stuff and
all kind of stuff I won't go into it
it's just you need to know there is a
stack and there is a abstracting to
input tape that has some input symbols
the current state and a stack symbol and
then from that it generates its
transitions to other states and during
the transition it can manipulate the
stack which means basically pushing a
pop making pushes and pops from the
stack that's the basic idea
yeah sorry I will show it in a moment
and we will have a demo just running it
and yeah here's just the visual
animation what's what is the rest this
is reverse polish notation which is
basically first the operators then the
operation and it is basically how it
work in a stack we put the 3 in the
stack we push the 5 on the stack we do
it okay this is an operation then let's
just pop the operands and get an egg Oh
magic and in Row 2 is quite easy we can
just now for example it will be just not
opening anything r2 with two dashes oops
sorry
and then
ayyyy is for emulation all all the
commands are under a year I will
describe the basic commands afterward
but just for you to know II are the
operation is the shop commands that will
contain the emulation with diesel part
and let's do the same sonic ok very very
basic it just parts of it and gives the
result back so what's the problem with
that again more computer Theory don't
worry about it I don't even understand
all that but the the main idea we are in
a pushdown automata which is what I
describe we have an input tape with
subsamples we transition to state we
have a stack we can manipulate during
the transition and we have to go in to
go more into a Turing machine what does
this mean is we want for example with a
stack machine we cannot access random
positional memory we are limited to the
top of the stack and there are some
things that we cannot do so how can we
do this and the most of use answer is
the correct one with asteroids it's also
known as cheating cheating basically
means ok let's add our randomized
operations and let's control let's add
control operations to easy this is part
1 and part 2 is ok let's add register
axis and let's add an extra tape with
random axis that will be a virtual
memory that will be stacked for a bit
cold memory to work with while emulating
so that the asteroids that are added to
put on machine give the random access
operation control flow operations and
also another tape which is basically as
a section of the memory that will be
used for storing all the data we need to
when emulating and this is another
important slide as I said the adoptions
are under the AE sub Commons which is
the analysis easel and we have for
example the eye a eye for n8 I am for
the memory just point if we na
initialize the memory automatically we
have initialized this tag machine so
usually if we don't want to we don't
need a memory don't use a have a I am
but we need to use it we don't really
need to put first initialize and then
initialize never hits it's already done
then an instruction pointer okay we want
to move the instruction pointer and now
we have kind of familiar instructions if
you're you have debug something which is
barely stepping stepping until an
abscessed stepping over to skipper -
don't enter into a function step skip to
step skipping some of the instruction
and we can also show the registers the
step skip for example I want to mention
with difference between a program step
over just we are in the function we just
arrive to a call to a function a step
over we'll just don't go into that
function and am a little the stop step
skip is for example we are emulating
something and we want to go from the
offset 0 to offset 10 and at offset 7
there is some operation that is doing
something program is computing a highest
value of whatever and it's not really
useful in what we are trying to decode
and it's it doesn't interfere with
anything we we are we are dealing with
so we can just skip it okay we I don't
want to waste three seconds to emulate
that because I won't use it so that's
quite useful a step skip part and what
are the ESL operands so what can we do
with it and I was thinking of putting
here giantest giant table but just look
for the help I will show you you have
the operands on their descriptions and
some examples even some examples so
that's it you don't really need to
unless you're building something up on
SO syntax usually don't care about it
usually you don't care about it but it's
fun to know and how it works and if you
need to perform some custom operations
you
need to use that for example this one
the question mark quarterly is is an if
is the control flow if just as a as an
example and then we have yeah go to go
to some breaks we have also initial
internal variables which are basically
the flags and they're prefixed with the
dollar sign and that read only I will
explain you a bit about the flags and
why they are like the internal flags and
why don't we have just some let's say
register flags like a normal I would say
normal architecture the point is that
those flags the internal flags on easel
are updated every time an attempt you
operation that easel performs but
depending on the architecture we're
emulating not all architecture update
all the flags in the same kind of
operations so for example what is really
really common is we have their flags
this Flags internal flags that are
updated at each operation in ISM but the
operation that that is it's being
emulated into the in the architect we're
emulating by definition it doesn't do
nothing with the flag so we don't do
anything but if it does then we just
create the another register because we
have infinite registers in easel there's
the definition and we just copy the flag
we got from the internal variable to the
register flag we define but the that's a
common way it's kind of weird but it's
really useful because as I said not
architecture update the same flags with
the same operations and these will the
internal bars will be updated and every
operation that they still performs and
in depending on which operation in which
a couturier are dealing if they predator
don't observe or don't at the flags then
we can just move the values into the
register so here we will revisit our
crackme from before and I will say I
will
demonstrate why I won I didn't want to
just go by hand because we are lazy
sometimes and why you can have why we
have to compute things that can be
computed automatically so let's just
compute it automatically and that means
basically emulating and that will be a
very basic demonstration on easy okay
let's find the correct me to again just
see I am lying
and now what we will do is instead of
patching we will see which is the actual
value that they will it will accept as a
valid password we just open it analyze
it we printed this assembly of the
function that is set at main and we see
exactly the same as before and here as I
said before after this can I have the
other two values load it into memory and
then some operations perform and then a
comparison based on the result of those
operations so what we will do basically
I will start my the butyl machine
official here and this upset
it was a ok now let's say I'm gonna
emulate I I'm telling you what I'm gonna
do I'm gonna emulate this snippet of
code which means I will simulate that I
have a program that the only thing that
does is just this part which is the
computation that we are actually
interested in so I will seek here let's
see here the I know you see it here do
you see dwell right in the bottom okay
initialize machine the remember a is was
for emulation commands and then I am you
have the initialization of the machine
okay
we can see the registers let's let's do
a birthing all doing well I want to show
you something okay so now let's see the
registers okay
the instruction pointer points to the
the other we are seeing right now that's
not important both but when we start the
machine then the registers see the stack
pointer and the base pointer they
changed they curated a stack of memory
for us add those offsets so now we have
a stack that can use as a virtual memory
for the basil basil emulation needs and
now here we are it's good here which is
the I guess I will print it the main
function again we have seeked here this
is the beginning of the operations and
we want to emulate until here
so before emulating remember that I told
you that I'm not opening it in write
mode so I cannot write but I'm
interested in seeing what's going on so
now as it will be writing into the that
piece of memory that I reserved to be
built on machine I need write permission
made so I just enable the i/o cache okay
and now it will be able to write it so
if I will now this is just step until
and it will just step until at other
words it will take a couple seconds
I wasn't seeking the right place so
ah I forgot to put instruction pointer
today the opposite I was so of course it
was running just before and II was
trying to emulate all these printers and
scallops
[Music]
oh yes I know but is it working
sorry for the seconds see the register
is either stack pointer and the advance
yeah it was fine
okay yes it was right now what we're
interested in in looking for is what is
the value that it is being compared so
what is the result of the computation
that happened here so this value is on
VAR c 8 we see which is exactly at EBP
the base pointer minus C so we will just
print it PF to print format the data
which format dear as decimal where to
EBP minus C and we have this value so
now we just run the crackme
password okay and any other password
faith that oops
okay times passing by yeah here we go
for another more interesting demo which
is the obfuscated encrypted code using
ezel that's really more interesting that
just are random crack min and in this
case I will be using the sec on this one
in case you have it defender directly
from chapter 11 from this on world let's
see
[Music]
first of all let's print the information
this is an X here which is a 3-2 byte
32-bit Windows executable portal portal
executable file which means there is no
way away
we cannot just natively debug it here
okay but we are trying to do some stuff
with it as well with emulation so first
of all let's analyze it let's list the
functions and now I will skip one boring
part that is looking for its function
what it is doing but I can tell you that
this function has something testing and
we seek to it print this assembly and
get R is string something some stuff we
don't care okay we don't care what
what's going on here but if you see it
here it's doing some moving some memory
and some registers then ignoring some
stuff again showing some step again
exerting some step then same jumping
back coming forward and then we have
let's print the whole function this
little push pop jump to it that in case
you're unfamiliar there usually it's a
quick treat to perform codification so
basically this will be a very simple
cipher to work with so that means that
if we just print this assembly after
this we will see what's going on here 20
lines will be not maybe a little bit
more here
yeah this is just a pushed pop jump but
I shown before just at the end of the
function and afterwards there is this
really weird stuff with even some
invalid operations that it's it really
makes no sense
like for it to be executable so if you
analyze malware encrypted malware or
something similar it's lights screaming
an encrypted code an encrypted code okay
so and we have just in the in the in the
previous function that is just preceding
did that push pop jammed with all the
previously ignoring stuff with moving
memory it's it varies it's screaming
screaming like and the decryption of
this obfuscated code so can we how can
we do decrypt it actually decrypt it
this is a function that is in the
decryption and we will basically emulate
it to we emulate that function that is
making the decryption of this code we
will see that the code will be decrypted
so see if I can do it right yeah here we
have the IO cache activate it because we
will be modifying the code that is just
afterwards it wasn't really necessary in
the previous one I just confessed it the
initialization initialization of the
machine we can see two registers and
then this is we're sick that sick is
just at the very beginning of the
function we see just before and we are
going to the end of the function just
emulating it okay it will take a couple
seconds that's it
and now if we print again 32 lines you
know disassembly add that offset we will
see okay this looks way better this
looks way better so we have basically
emulated their routine in that function
that was decrypting the code that was
flag below and as we have emulated it
and we have enabled we had enabled the
the cache it has been modified on memory
but not on disk brand memory but not on
this so we accept
this file the file will be just as it
was the very beginning so that's kind of
cool and it's now it makes a lot more
sense okay so let's go yeah hi I have
some time no to extensibility and
scripting and I will go really quick
with that as I previously mentioned to
is design design is composed by several
C libraries that are made with no
third-party dependencies and it's
library can be built on your project or
some of them as you prefer one of the
main use case of that and the practical
produce test that does standalone
program that I told you before that
fragging to extract information rights
for the based converters the horizon for
the assembly and disassembly are just
standalone programs using each one of
those libraries or one or more to amour
them depending on the on the knee
capabilities and this is the basic
structure like the axle structure when
you clone and the relative repository is
the liberal Lib our folder where you
have the models with dependencies then
inside it is slave library folder you
have the P folder when you have the
plugins the core plug-in for each module
then have the bean are for the binary
programs and the shirt sh LR which is
code that is read from third party this
code that is used to perform some of the
things for example to mount some
partitions it it's it's code that is has
been is the quantity that is being used
is from the group and the group
bootloader slightly modified but that's
a they can show you really quickly those
are the libraries for example if we go
to the assembly we have here and the P
is all the assembly plugins you can see
the architectures and
those are the programs I told you before
and course yep oops
third party goat is used in some places
that's it and this is really fancy
organizational stuff I'm not really sure
that is updated but is the most updated
version of the graph list of the
libraries that dependency but internal
dependencies on libraries or two at the
top we have our util that consumes it's
consumed by everything and then at the
fire we have the core which is provide
the main API to prime it's just I just
wanted to put a fancy picture but I
don't expect you do just now come
develop that if you are interested just
clone it and looking through the code
just keeping my that basic structure is
but you need plugins for extending as I
said we have plugin for the assembly in
this assembly of different architecture
for file formats for input output and
debugging for example I won't list them
because I don't wanna lose two minutes
more it will do more interesting stuff
at the time but we just comment there
you just list the plugins that you have
for example the input output this is
cool because you can just connect the
session to a socket through somewhere
and just work through that or really
really fancy input and output plugins to
work with and how to manage plugins that
are not in core basically be at the the
package manager my package manager at 2
p.m. we just when we install our 2 p.m.
we need to initialize it first of all
with our 2 p.m. in it and then we just
install a plug-in with our 2 p.m. - I or
just are 2 p.m. install the plugin you
can check manual of our 2 p.m.
although all the standalone tools and
also art work has a manual in case you
want to see all the options for
executing it but it's quite easy just
start
and with you you uninstall it and this
will provide more plugins that are not
in the core of the relative but quite
useful some of them and scripting that's
really cool and for some time rel was
told that it was not really easy to
script it cannot be easier I'm gonna say
in the first thing we have is bindings
for many languages which are
automatically generated with balla bind
which is another tool created by pancake
some some years ago so automatically
there are bindings that are being
generated for Java ago no GS Python and
a ton of more languages and you can use
those but it's I mean it's not being
deprecated but it's not really being
used those native bindings and in favor
of what is the are two pipe api which is
the standard and recommended way of
scripting on top of rather two and is
it's under recommended way because it's
really really really really easy to use
basically you just throw us input are
two commands and you get a lot put our
two output that's it and there is a
really cool thing that you remember that
I told just out of slides before that if
you open that J on some command you
receive the JSON output then there is a
special command you can input are two
commands and you have one of the ever I
will see here in the Python example in
start with Pip and use import are two
pipe and these are the four commands
that we have only open Smitty seemingly
J and quit the Smitty is just inputting
rather two commands and receiving the
output and the J is really really cool
because it performs native JSON
deceleration okay that means that if
basically in Python for example when you
receive a JSON output from the sections
of the out of the binary or analyzing
with you if you are if you have executed
a command with the JSON appended I'm
calling with the see me DJ it will
return a native Python object in this
case a Python
that dictionary to work with
automatically so that's kind of cool and
it works for many other languages with
this JSON the serialization let's see
yeah so I'm just going to show you how
can we script something interesting that
we are racing just the previous demo of
the encrypted code so let's see how to
use our two pipe to do this
automatically and to work with it and
it's not here this is just the Crypt
file I will show to you that's it
importer two pipe r2 is equal to PI po
plan the executable analyze seek to the
function nebulae IO cache initialize the
butyl machine of the SEO set the
instruction pointer to the extra to the
current seek upset and step until the
end of the function that's it what's
really cool you you think okay but what
what do we do with that I mean it's just
script that makes something and what the
the cool thing is that with rather too
we can give initialization script
written in different languages one of
those is Python and there is also native
language like native syntax but we can
just throw this initial script as an
initialization script to order to
session attach to a binary which means
that when it opens the binary it will
perform those operations and then you
your set and that's really cool because
I will just show to you I guess it's hi
script yeah so you just you did the
manual stuff before you put it as a
script and you just pass it as an
initial additional script and now when
you open it the way you already have the
code obfuscated to work with so now we
we just can we can print it this is the
air the code that we do scary before do
you remember this flash pop jump to yet
and then the code that was obfuscated
that's that's pretty cool because we are
dealing with some encrypted malware
sample or whatever we can just work the
do the manhole staff and the crib does
all the things and then put it as a
simple script that does this and then
next time we want to work with that
sample you just initialize with that
script and we have everything decrypted
automatically so that's kind of cool hmm
that's it now but let me show you have
something the thing on Python the
serialization okay
find it I can do it just right there
I'm gonna Python shell okay so if i run
this okay that's it
and now for example the cool things and
to CMB prints assembly twenty lines it
all the colors everything is converted
well but what I told you the sections
for example it's thanks to the section
of the example okay this is the section
this is the section just JSON but we can
consume it as for example if we see me
DJ now sections equal and now we have
sections as a variable which is a list
which contains dictionaries so sections
zero the dictionary of each section so
we are now just as simple as that
dealing with native objects in Python we
can work with that whatever we need okay
let's discuss a little bit and I mean
quite out of time but I guess I will be
able to do my last demo on time so come
on use cases
I won't go really deep into that because
debugging everyone knows what the body
gives but because you don't know it's
just stepping through a process to
seeing
putting break point and seeing what's
going on to find bags or to trace an
error whatever and the debug debugging
options are under the D of the back
common and for you to be able to debug a
program you need of course to open
rather to in a debug session this is the
- the flag at the very beginning and the
interesting there are some interesting
things here they work the commands work
like almost the same does in the
emulation I did in the inverse way
because I was really more interested in
show you the emulation part that is way
less known that just debugging but with
another interface but do you remember
that with emulation with had the AE and
then all the the commands that were the
demolition here we have basically the
same but with D and D as two-step DC to
continually be just a breakpoint all
that kind of stuff and you can just read
for it here the customer then you have
the options okay so just few words about
debugging in rather to it does it start
the debugging session not at the entry
point does it as if we were just
punching spawning a show on a file but
not running but it starts at the dynamic
loader that's kind of interesting
because there is sometimes some cool
tricks from malware or other software
that are between the dynamic loading and
the actual entry point or the one of the
entry points and this is this way we can
we can debug around it before just
before getting to the entry point of the
of the program then of course it's a log
level debugger it's not aiming to
replace a source code debugging or
you're on your favorite IDE it's just
low-level stuff and what's interesting
is that it has the nating debugging over
to but can just debug with many backends
and use gdb are two LLVM which is a
began to use llll p.m. which is quite
useful for debugging any iOS from iOS
related stuff then of course we have our
Frida and some other debugging backends
to use
for exploiting I want to go much deeper
but just pointing some few words that
might be useful we are interested in
exploiting stuff this last comment is -
for searching the stuff the best
fertilizer searching for a string the
second is searching for Rob gadgets
which I'm sure some of you will be
interested and there are some of them
you can also search for gadgets with
regular expressions and crazy stuff it's
just if you just slice on and a question
McGee will see all the possible
searching modes but those two are quite
useful for exploding things then finding
function references essential with
analyze X cross yeah it yeah exactly
excu the cross references and the
opposite of the function and then we can
also find the writable and executable
sections of a binary really simple just
if we just print a section it will give
us right there so here we have every
section and their permissions okay then
oops also we can list the Lipsy imports
which might be interesting maybe you are
doing some kind of lips every turn we
don't up see that kind of stuff it's
just I asked see symbols okay we have to
analyze it first we have to open
something first of course yes for blue
all the same the symbols and we can grab
for the port ones
then I said Rock to as I said before it
can be used for generating the breathing
pattern those are those patterns that
are really used when you are doing some
kind of looking for the memory position
to inject the shellcode because they are
non repeating and when you get the
instruct the instruction pointer when
you get the Christ and you see the value
of deception pointer it will be loaded
with some of those values and you can
get those values and see okay so which
offset is actually of my payload to
encode your shellcode it's quite quite
common on exploiting these things and we
can of course prop the shellcode with
rag2 we set the architecture the bits
and some code in C there is also an
internal syntax for it but just tiny C
programs and it will literally give you
the the shellcode and hexadecimal value
of the anything you are have written
it's quite useful you can do what and at
the impressed view received a random
shellcode on the internet you can make
the inverse process and get what's going
on in there it will it will give you the
assembly if you are more interesting on
exploiting I haven't really that much
time to make and demos on exploiting
visible to consume the whole session but
the first tool posts are very very basic
just some more points of what I said
here and the third one is a walkthrough
tutorial from my friend it I and it's
really cool it goes to bypass and
bypassing ASL air the DP and all the
kind of protections it's kind of
interesting I will give leave the
references as well afterwards let's move
on for the extras very quickly if you
are still afraid of the of the shell
interface you have a graphical user
interface it's the relative official
graphical user interface
and I say official because they were
like more than ten graphical user
interface for rather from yes from
random people doing go is them not
maintaining or not really used by anyone
or even private ones but this one was
initially called di toe by by yoga Tessa
Spanish was a security researcher and
then some other friends guys and people
take oops
to the leaf a bit and rebranded to good
to Pewter and it's a ball being quite
fast it has a good team of maintained
errs and developers that are really
active is developed in C++ and QT and
it's released alongside they are two
releases and if you want to know more
just yet cuter dot are a debugging is
not working yet you can emulate but
naughty back but it's it should be done
soon let's say but it's really cool
that's what it looks like you have all
those panels you can move things do
fancy stuff with mouse and keyboard and
all that stuff okay then the compilation
I will just go deeper into this but
there for you to know what's going on in
the compilation in our tool on first of
all the compilation is difficult is
freaking difficult just theoretically
thinking the the process of the
compilation is something hard really
hard so there are many things that we
are doing in row two there is what the
first of all it's not even mentioned
here if you just throw P DC on a
function you will get a CD compilation
very very very basic it's very basic
it's not doing like anything but maybe
for a first glimpse it will be enough
and it's pretty fast because it's thing
really the thing then there is our two
deck which is an ASM two solution
converter written in the JavaScript it's
way more advanced that the PC but it's
not the compiler
as it I mean it's not what the theorists
would call out the comparator with the
compiling algorithms and reconstruction
stuff is just a toy and a really nice
toy and there is a ton of work behind it
and it works so well but it's not like a
formality compiler let's say that way
and you have it available you can search
for it the kids have it available at 2
p.m. so in the package manager then as I
said the compelling is card so mainly
what what's being doing but we are been
doing is just calling third-party the
compelling stuff there is another
package magnet packets I plug in to use
the grid deck Redakai
I don't know any of you know spread dick
yeah cool it's at the compiler that was
open source by Abbas the antivirus
company they made it open source I guess
a couple years ago or maybe not that
much and there is just the artwork right
egg is just a bridge between our table
200 dick and it stick on piling thread
then this is the the compiler project
for flour to the actual the compiler
with all the compiler staff and all the
fancy stuff and their crazy stuff
but it has very little developers and
it's mainly developed during the desaad
which is the agava summer of code or
maybe there sometimes there are sock
which is the on kind of Summer of Code
bye-bye rather not not sponsored by
Google but it's work in progress it's a
very nice proof of concept you can do
some stuff but it's not really ready yet
okay but it's the it's the good it's in
the good direction is the one into good
direction it has some some fancy
algorithms that are working really
really nice and if you are interested
over to join it just well you have to
get up here and open an issue or contact
the developers and I will be really
awesome then there is one that is is not
here but it's possible and indeed there
is a proof-of-concept done
but it's it's private and it's not
really stable or anything which is
basically using the get ready compiler
the the compiler of Deidre is quite
awesome
for example objective-c it works really
well and there is a there is a new sub
plugin now working progress plugin uh
but I would say a proof of concept right
now just use using data compiled as a
back-end so that's it we can throw it
any the compiler then I guess I have ten
minutes we'll have enough time okay I
will talk just a little bit of a lot to
Frieda which is are we could plug in any
of you knows Frieda here really yeah I
see a lot of places okay so the ones of
you who know you know that it is amazing
and the ones who don't is just binary
instrumentation on asteroids many many
asteroids and it's frigging lis amazing
what it can do but basically dynamic
analysis with binary instrumentation
injecting called monitoring tracing it's
amazing so our to Frieda is basically
front end for Frieda with in rural area
and we can do some cool stuff we we have
to install it through the package
manager and okay if we open our outer
shell with the backslash is we append
about we perfect with the backlash will
be the comments from our to Frieda when
we have install it now we can stop says
yeah because we are not attached to any
section yeah
I will show you know so to open a free
to spawn a free the procession we just
are to and Frieda this is the back to
open our a process an actual process by
name of the process by process ID or
even our stop locale promote anything
and that's it those are links to our to
Frieda the actual tool and the
an official wiki which is being doubled
by you are gonna wear a friend of mine
which is really cool and I will show you
a very quick demo
what can our Tafoya do and that will be
it
here I have a counter that's it that is
this stupid code that's just prints
number hydaburg happy double Hamsterdam
thousand ninety and sleep once I go on
an increment that number
it's keeps printing okay so let's exit
okay
okay that's it okay now we can open
directly just save the process name
again you can look for that process name
but wait ah it's here trust me that sees
the first of the content but anyway you
can open also with the process ID and
let's just yet ah yes I'm okay okay now
I have those are all the options with
freedom and I will show you just to show
the capabilities of it very very basic
[Applause]
here I will list mission and I'm
interested now in the entry point so
let's see where is the entry point of
this process the process is running I
mean we are injecting a running process
okay keep that in mind so here we have
the entry point let's seek here and
let's just see the central see that see
it better okay
Hank you wake up that whole thing so
just without understanding anything we
have move a x0 then a call then moving a
one then another call and then an
addition and then a jump back to him but
to here so basically this is
initialization the real variable then
the slip and this is incrementing that
way okay so as I told you before
okay with visual mode in this assembly
we have one mode the course
mode which is activated with the sea of
course ER and we can just put it in one
bite and for example if we put here this
one is the one that represents the
incrementing value so fight them it
it will work so see the counter now it's
being the code is being injected in
memory so I can just more of that then
say it one and this one I told you it
was the slipping time so if I just
increase it seems it Christ but it's
just that it goes slower and of course
if I put two zero weight finishes so
that's basically it very very basic but
just for you to to see what is possible
and all your ideas can be really
satisfied so I have very little time but
I'm almost done with it I just want to
point you to some documentation and more
resources the first one is it's already
documented in C so yeah I mean it's the
best way if you want understand
everything but it's probably not the
most practical way to to go to it at
least at the very beginning and there is
the official book which is continuously
being developed is indeed books and then
I I would call for the we are we are in
the google Summer of the Google season
of documentation which is some kind of
duo Summer of Code both for documents so
if any of you is interested on is a good
clinical writer and wants to join us to
make the art to book even better so
you're welcome to contribute to make
your proposal we have also some physical
books I have not any unit with me right
now but we did some physical books
really fancy for the past are to
Congress
that of course now are outdated but they
were really good and yeah that's it then
more resources there is that book which
is a little bit outdated but still it
has a ton of good information right
exploration then you can search for
blocks everywhere those are just to to
mention the rod today which is the
official block it's updated very expand
not really often but it has some
articles interesting and then just to
mention one in the Internet I mentioned
the one from megabit because he's my
friend so this is from him and he has
amazing tutorials and walkthroughs on
rubber to then you want more record more
resources we have recorded talks we have
all the talks recorded for the three
editions of our talk on the first ones
are quite low quality because it was a
little bit well I would say improvised
everything but they are the material is
really good and then the for the past
year and the sullens 17 these those are
those with really good quality and out
of a lot of companies being called it
and then there are just tons of talks
over our to just take on YouTube all
your favorite video is certain Jane
there are tons of talks but if you just
go through all the playlists of lark on
you have way about material to see it
and some extra tips those are really
really quick before before living is
just okay we have to pen a question mark
it's just in my advice for everyone it's
just panic question mark and you will be
fine but if you you can use a native Hut
I have not explained because it was not
the case it was not pretty relevant but
this three points basically native HUD
of rather too and we just use that we
are gripping on native card on the
question mark on all the a stop help
they commander this the help of all
comments up comments and this is
basically it is very quickly
[Music]
so here basically we can stop this this
is our search like that on all the help
and just make an alias hard to help
this is just for do a quiet in it and
just run this command and not opening
any file that's it so now basically if
you I think I already have my heart to
help and yeah that's it
show an X whatever yeah
cook it and for support with the IRC
rather add the version of unity and the
telegram channel and both are Bridgette
together with the bot so if you talk
from one or the other
everyone will receive it and that's
that's basically it's the conclusions I
would say is first of all l2 is not that
difficult and I hope that got a little
bit clearer at least you have to keep in
mind that we are using mnemonic comments
that could be different from other
maintenance things but they are not
difficult they are just different it's a
unique mix like shell so if you are
really used to UNIX programs on
unix-like interface it's really familiar
and with less than ten commands I
haven't used more than ten commands we
can do a lot of stuff yes we can add
modifiers and more fancy stuff but for
the basic stuff and many many of the
things we will run every day with eight
nine ten comment we we have not and of
course and then help pending a question
mark then other conclusions is that
there are many ways to contribute to
open source projects like rather two one
is with code of course but also writing
documentation using it and reporting the
issues if no one reports the issues that
they found they are unsolved so if you
find an issue just report it probably
pancake solves it in one minute but
that's another point
and use it and share it on with your
friends on conferences and that's it and
the final just the 30 second spam we
have the Arctic on for 2019 this year
it's community driven and through Ghana
community focused from four to seven of
September Barcelona we have trainings
both basic track so if you are really
interested me but you don't really have
an idea we have two days of full basic
trainings eight hours of Rod two and
then cuter and I guess other one of our
two internals and then we have another
track of headbands ones with code
obfuscation techniques with symbolic
execution and without to freedom and
then two days more of conference talks
technical talks for everyone and that's
it if you're interested just check the
Congress page and tickets are online on
that end of my star of my experiment end
of my talk thank you very much thank you
you