hello-o welcome to our sharing and
sharing is about fuzzy it is not about
that it's quite okay and firstly let me
introduce ourselves
this is me my name is curating and my
twitter account is panic III and I'm a
senior staff engineer from China micro
and I've used this tool to find a lot of
vulnerabilities and got several CVS and
last year I gave presentations in record
you and color blue Tokyo and this is my
chronic ginger era my name is ginger and
I'm a worker at random echo as in the
amount to mobile security researcher and
I have found some fewer three years
thank you okay this is today's agenda in
the first part I will introduce what is
the pending xnu and the second part is
Excel version one to version 3 actually
the version one is about the Cisco fuzzy
which which was the one I have
penetrated industry years record you and
the pending child Excel version two is
actually the al-kidd active fuzzing the
version 3 is it about the possible
fuzzing next part my colleague dream
sugar will introduce the fastening
visualization and at any operation and
as a last part if we have time enough
time I will show you some very simple
case study
ok let me introduce our what is pending
axon you actually it is the axon your
father is it now suppose cisco father
and al qaeda father maybe in the future
we can extend the ability to support
cannot extension and share
and so it is based on Coco's famous
father
syz color you can see this picture this
page was created after - tiara pre head
talk and the owner of this cornered
created this page he mentioned that I
had spotted his collar to support apples
accent as you may know his collar
supports and enjoy Linux and even
windows / italian support Mac OS and it
also just - Cisco falling in this talk I
will share you about the pending
acceleration story which supports xnu
fuzzy include the Cisco fuzzy and al
qaida falling this is the architecture
funding architecture it is almost the
same with as well the corner it has two
components the server side and the
client side step step and any introduce
the workflow step one it will the server
side will starts the kindest crime side
and step two the syntax engine or the
generation engine we on those the API
patents and the corporate EP the it will
generate some Cisco requests and the
steps three mutation engine also can be
rotated some parameters for this API
cause step 4 API as future will receive
this parameters and to the real request
after each Cisco or alkyl car with the
return value at the step 7 it it will
check whether the return value has some
hip memory disk Laura and at step 8 the
APS killer will also update the car
to the covers DB so this this tour is
based on code coverage driven so I must
add a support for the coverage in
current axial kernel you can see these
pictures that I developed several
sanitizers expansion is the code
coverage sanitizer imposed the PSD
subsystem and the al-kidd
subsystem in this talk I think the most
important thing is the coverage support
in our kit ok before we delve into the
later sessions and then me introduce two
terms the first one is patent the next
one is corporis peasant is action is the
API syntax description and as the corpus
focus on the parameters for the API okay
let me introduce pending xnu version 1
this is as mentioned before this is
actually the one I already talked about
and that's the year blackhat EU and you
can simply say you can take it as sis
collar for Apple X nu and I wrote more
than 500 API patterns also as well as
several sanitizers including the code
coverage and I use this tool find more
than 50 as his car crashes including two
for the Pantone Mac OS 10 point 14 I
already talked about the version 1 in
that's the year's parent ation and today
I will give you two more chill at UM's
the first one is about how to add
support for BSD code coverage and the
second one is how to enable kuno
addressed sanitizer let's focus on the
first question how to edit PSD equal
coverage in two
Karin accent your source code i
developed a module named cake cover very
similar to the one in linux and this
module includes two major parts the
first first part is the function
sanitizer covered with specie this
function is used to extract the code
coverage data and the second one is I
register itself as a kernel extension
module to send back the code coverage
data back to to the user mode fuzzing
tour and in order to compare this module
into the current acts in your source
code we need to update some
configuration files for example the
master Ferrell's the first make felt or
template and let's see this is an
example how I register itself as a color
extension module in inside the OSF MK it
is very strange for I implement some
functions next okay come open close read
our control and please pay attention
here I implements this K comma model in
inside OS f MK note the PSD subsystem so
you when your calls devfs make load
don't use make dev macro because it is
different between the OSF MK subsystem
and as a PSD subsystem you can see that
the first parameter I use the hard code
value and you can see the picture here I
already a sucessful successfully is
inject our synthetic country's PC
function into some basic blocks you now
you can use genetic acronym of falling
to do the further fuzzing
smoothly here is
here has a very small problem that if we
want to do some fuzzing visualization it
is not good with such kind
instrumentation because you can see that
there are several blocks without the
Senate other countries PC
instrumentation point our question - how
to enable pizza
you mean the node is a source code of X
nu and compile it
maybe in release mode debug mode and
even kisum mode but if you try that in
case our model you make you can get the
output the kernel being output but if
you try to put it with put your machine
with kiss on Colonel you may find that
it count
it will feel it can't put your machine
the real cost is that during the boot
stage some concerns top functions will
checks the shadow memory but the channel
memory is not initialized at that stage
so the workaround is as Bulow's we can
as the below functions into the case on
black list for Apple Apple Apple
applause such kind then combined again
you can post the case on kuno
successfully okay this is pending
execution - I will kill active fuzzy I
think this part is the most important
part in today's talk and I will describe
it in details it is also it is still
based on this collar and it so it is
coverage children in order to make it
works we must develop a some API
patterns in for for the alkyl module
but a human knows that I'll kill the
modules most of them are closest not
open source so we used reverse
engineering to extract some API patents
okay in order to users is calling for
fuzzing our key modules we must they
have alkyl api patents and we must they
have the out kid APR 14 that we must
have the module code coverage data or if
you don't have the code coveted
higher-order smart right and as as for
the api patterns weak for the open
source alkyl modules you can just
extract to the api patterns directly
from the source code but for those
closest alkyl modules we mainly use the
reverse engineering and other methods
okay now sees the alkyl attack surface
firstly in current xnu
there are several subsystems in this
talk we focus on the alkyl subsystem and
inside the alkyl subsystems there are
total 88 interfaces and in the next
session in the following sections we
only take the I'll connect method as an
example okay how to extract the route
connecting method patents because this
this interface is a very famous
interface and is a very big attack
surface we can extract the API patterns
maybe you can write a script to extract
the pattern from the structural tables
as method and as is patch but for those
and structural code you can only use the
reverse engineering to extract the API
patterns okay now see the result our
current nav
already extract some API patterns from a
lot of our kid modules
for examples a celebrated family the LAV
be family and a charity family and soul
Nastia example the apple of the keystore
this is an example in this module you
can see that there are many just three
men a master as well as the open surface
as well as the core method and syz close
service the most important one is as
well as a co master after reverse
engineering we found the suti once in
actors for this module and you can see
the selector with value 1 it maps to the
function user kind close and we get the
information that all the parameters are
0 all these results are from reverse
engineering and so the reverse
engineering seems were important and the
our father depends on it heavily so if
we have some mistakes in the reverse
engineering the the following generation
or mutation fuzzing is totally wrong so
how to review if our reverse engineering
is right
ok I have several methods first one
don't depend on the reverse engineering
so we have the positive falling took and
combined the passive and is the active
to make it what's that important
important and we can also with the help
of funding visualization to check if the
reverse results is a right the second
one
currently the acuter don't support our
kid so we must add support for the alkyd
commercial for example
I don't change any car in general is his
car API skilled I just resigned they'll
call in as well as they call method and
you can see if there's a fuzzing request
it will cause cure disease called and
since the column is not empty so the
function in inside the column will be
coded directly and the method is
actually the sy the call method I
implement this function in this project
okay let's focus on the most important
thing how to get the code coverage from
those close sauce al-qaida modules there
may be several mess messes for example
TBI SPI or even in her PT but I don't
find any existing solution or projects
for the Mac OS or EPOS tunnel and I
decided to use the SPI function to get
the call coverage for the Epis kernel
especially for those closest alkyl
modules I caused the SPI idea from the
project PB il okay now see what what all
it means this is an example of a pro FD
kiss talk it is now this picture to
describe some instructions before any
SPI you can see that the first
instruction is push RTP is a move a ppsv
and so let's see the result after my SPI
you can see that the first instruction
becomes a jump instruction Chester it
seems that it is patched and it directly
jump to another function so what is the
target of function you can see is
attacked finished
Naxos the target function seems almost
the same with the previous original
function except that as the at each
basic block at the start of each basic
block in a course shell code the the
shell code you can implement so whatever
you want in the shell code in in in this
talk I just use the shell code to
extract the code coverage okay so this
is main idea of our spi and you can see
this picture is an example of our with
one result so what is the difference is
between the before spi and the aft as bi
you can see that before as well it only
has one of texture section but after SPI
it has two texture section segments the
the next one in kenapa wrong is the
original texture segment and is the the
next of the right one in blue is my
clone spi text segment segment okay this
is the differences so let me introduce
other details about how to do the spi
for the kernel Marco Marco fares there
are three paths first one you must
update the text section and the second
one is you must update the relocation
and the third part is that you must
update the macro file structure I think
the first one is is the most important
you must fix all the other target
actions and in our torah we only focus
on the instruction type or memory and
the all new and follow those
instructions we fix the jump table and
fix the Neo champ and fix the operand
value for the second part we master fix
moko and external relocation okay just a
jump to the first apart updates the text
section as mentioned before for the
original function ABC I just patch it to
let it jump to my new SPI function
xxxxxx and the new function is almost
the same they it has the same three
blocks block 1 block 2 and block 3 the
difference is is that it costs the
shellcode why why why why why and the
every start instruction of the three
basic blocks in case this is SPI and
here is the fullness of the instruction
type I guess this list from the ITAR
scripts and we only focus on the memory
type instruction and the new tab
instruction here is an example about how
to fix the new jam and is fixed operand
value for example the left picture is is
the source code of the panel view of
apple of the keystore before spi you can
see the the last instruction JBE short
Norco sleepy 1/8 let's take it as an
example we musta fix the operand t2 to
see for this is because we add so many
instruction points the core shell code
at
each basic blocks so we must fix the
relative jump if not it will jump to the
one wrong address
right so we master fix the operand value
and we we also muster fix the new jump
too far jump this is the cost it it is
the same reason because we add the
instruction instrumentation points so it
may jump other sites the original scope
because the short jump can only jump to
vising FF scope periscope right and this
is an East in our tour that we replace
the other short jumps to the non champs
another question is about the jump table
you may see that in Apple's Mac hole
that you can always see some jump tables
jump table is the data in text it is
very special
during in our SPI we must recognize it
as data instead of text or everything
will run and after recognize it we
master fix it because every entry in the
jump table points to the original text
code branches we must fix it to netted
Gemma to our new SPI texture called
branches okay
how to recognize it I have a workaround
first you can check the first
instruction ali-a is jpt - 3 of 7 this
instruction is of type all all new and
then we can check the tape of the target
address TPT's so f7 it locates in inside
the text section
but it doesn't belong to any basic block
then we check every entries inside this
jump table to see if all of the entries
jumps to the existing basic blocks
if yes with the ticket a jump table okay
how to recognize it and how to fix it
during the SPI it is very simple just
the update is the value of this jump
table entries to make it points to the
new code branch in the SPI text so this
is how we fix it just the update is the
entry entries okay the next part about
the relocation firstly what is in
occasion you can see an example here in
in the at our view we can see there's an
instruction call l3 but if you open the
app of the keystore module with the hex
in hex mode you can see that yes the
avocado is ie8 but the operand value is
so how add our order or the system knows
here is Alfre it's simple because the
relocation tables record here that as
the offset one eight six one
it is the symbol l3 so here comes
another question for us for the spi
since we cloned the original texture
section we must add the relocation
entries or update the original anxious
to Internet the system knows that our
core l3 not call zero right
so just update the entries in sighs
local you know kitchen table and is a
poster local indication table and as the
external indication table to make it
works right or making it works well okay
the final part is updates macro file
structure we need to add the SPI text
section and as be a data section and we
need also need to add the shell code to
do what whatever you want and for the
existing macro header you must update
the watcher address and the watcher yeah
what's your address
for example the no command sim table nor
command data in code and such kind okay
this is an example of what we did for
Marco for our kid Marco I I added tools
segments the first one is a text segment
and the second wise data segment and the
the name of the text segment as you can
see is text zero zero panic or okay as
for adding the shellcode and we must use
assembly code to implement your task so
in in my at you we just use a we must we
we use the assembly color tool to to
just implement as the simple task just
the call called an external function and
you can implement the external function
in stand alone cannot extension driver
so you can use C language to implement
whatever you want
so this is the SBI summary you must fix
or not fix the memory and all new
instructions and the fix in occasions
and the fix of file structure and you
need to add the shell code to recall the
return addresses and add two segments
the SBI text and as be our data here is
another question well to add these two
segments you can see that I add the two
SBI segments before the node command
link added so can we push the two
segments at the end of the node command
at the end of the macro fell after the
Ning added my answer here if you want to
s be against usable demarco fell yes
but if you want to to SBI against the
column of the macro file the answer is
no because if you do so the system count
can't put Nancy why during the
initialization they added another
command can be updated to us smaller
size what does it mean the system system
module loader can do some optimization
for the link added load command because
inside the link added section segment
they in many condense some strings or
cosines for example co.design is it's a
must during the check stage but it is
not a master for the module itself run
inside in the kernel so the kernel will
do some optimization to make it makes
the kernel memory allocated on location
smaller you can see this picture this is
an example if we at the SBA text or the
SBI data and n at the end of this macro
firm after the link added the kernel
when it is noted into the kernel the
kernel will recalculate the virtual size
the memory size for this module the
result is 0 X 4 8 0 0 it is not 0 X
5,000 but the the kernel note no they're
still put our SBI text at offset zero X
3000 so absolutely it'll be a panic
because it exists the allocated memory
that's why we can't put this to SPI
sections after the before sanding added
load come on
ok there's set some small limitations
for the SPI
project it doesn't support of 80 mark oh
but I know it doesn't it is not a big
problem and it doesn't support 32-bit
Marko and the the macro and the master
have free space for two more Lord of
commands as B attacks and SPI data ok
and the jump table identification is not
a perfect museum but it works well let's
see a result for current status of our
SPI you know almost the the almost all
the modules we have the API patterns can
work well now ok
if you use our SBI tour to failure
put your machine don't don't
reinstall your OS just use the following
steps to recover your system okay in the
secure in the secure recovery mode
okay next the final one is pending axial
to Washington's three it is about the
I'll kill a passive fuzzy here's the
passing fuzzy I mean it is not the one
use you see in in common scenarios I
don't use the hooks to I may be the
passive fasten you understand is about
use hooks to mutate the parameters
during normal function call I only use
hooks to tamper the parameters into the
Mexico and the MongoDB and I then I use
I quote this data into the corpus db2
that our to consume directly vanessi and
and other result I I use this tour the
hooks to get a lot of a lot of the
al-qaeda connection open data and also
get a lot of the al-qaeda connection
data and also get a lot of other the
real date has the parent as a data into
the MongoDB and finally we have also
seen the API method parameters that we
need need to convert this data to the
coppers DB and you may know that Cisco
knows concept program to fast instead
instead of single API files program is
actually a sequence of API calls you can
see
this picture as an example it may it
caused the socket and is in use return
value as the first parameter for the
find API so it it has the conserved
program I think the advantage of this
fuzzy mode is that it can solve some
context problem right and I also use
this concept to do the my passive fuzzy
I recall a sequence of API calls for
examples the NASS the one the nihms is
three so I recall the series three API
call and put them together
the first one is p0 the second one is p1
p this the third Y is p2 the value of
this the value is actually the md5 hash
value for each single API call and then
I compare them together to produce the
program's you can see it as the picture
as an example I the program shows that
we firstly used as well as the open
surface to open some our kids service
and then cause as well as committed to
too fast to call some our kid master so
it can partially solve some context
problem all right okay now C is al-qaeda
fast summary we can compare the active
and the passive al-qaeda fast now
because we have the al-qaeda open and
the core syntax description by the
reverse engineering and we have the
possible sequence coverage by hooks and
we also have the courage of closest
alkyl modules now so we can extend the
ability of this corner to support fuzzy
our kids
the combination advantages here I think
the passive Cobras can be used to file
system alone
it doesn't need active API patent
developed by the researchers so it can
make us don't rely on the reverse
engineering so heavily and the passive
corporates can happen reveal if the
active patterns API pattern are correct
and the passive Copperas gives the
chances that even the patterns are wrong
we can still fast in the right direction
based on the genetic algorithm this is
our key the phasing architecture which
is some kind hooks to get the passive
API sequence coppers and we can you also
use the SBI tool to get the code
coverage from the close foster modules
alkyl modules and we we also have the
dashboard to see what happens in
everyday fuzzing so next enemy in what
my colleague ginger to give you an
introduction of the fuzzing
visualization and is that any operation
how we go this is about a fuzzing
visualization and the courage is a
first-class citizen in our facing it is
a passive fuzz which has to cook many
about it too many vaccines is al-qaeda
so it's open and al key to connect home
a solder that's where we have a demo
video
okay this is our dashboard your say we
have 10 system I wanna see where the
manager and ten as well father running
on VMware fusion and the next one is odd
Tilly it's running you can see we have
rung of nearly 6 million programs until
now and this number keeps growing
this is a most exciting part it's also a
machine you can say right it's a produce
about yeah when penny called a and it
keeps users away about everyday way
usually every day we got panic oh yeah
and the next is a it's a passing fad in
from work yeah way justice II mmm you
you say that's it's deep and I'm finding
signals fattening signals is a internal
and representation of our coded courage
exceeded every after restart courage
keeps growing yeah signal numbers
copper's means that we have about nearly
2,000 new programs and this is our
coverage data we will choose module most
complicated
I will accelerate assembly is about
Sadie acceleration is lighthouse
integration actually we have a hidden
map for for every function code coverage
and the way how also let house
integration I will show you another demo
that house is a great tool for courage
with realization without courage data
and it's a lot faster yes senior hit map
and you can click from a you can see
that blue is a Haiti the blog you can
even see in the compound mode that will
be very friendly for karate review
another one is eight different or we
know at other on update for program they
fix all the bugs and you'd introduce
some new features and new API for
security researcher way to some diva so
as we can find older and day and we do
some devtools and a new box and a new
attack surface how you see you can see
is a chance log from high syrup to or
Mac OS modules in kernel it has open the
to his course and one Mac travel and
some new some new routines in subsystems
and most importantly you can see it has
adidas three MIG subsystems and contains
hundreds or routines
so how do they do that way collecting
memories from different origins and way
how roars in homo language and we also
read a script in attitude passing this
binary and roar so that we can produce
different Jason vowels by dipping this
Jason to us we can get was what has been
changed in this different versions
another demo
yeah well choose on module and this is
worth colonel and different nowhere seen
Hazira and module
yeah you see how addisam this is a
simple chasm patch and we can see how
yellow change the way and recurring new
one
oh yeah and it's our death-defying
operation so we are not just that
development is just a to say a lot watch
has and the pictures way I mean the
coverage more called an immoral attack
surface after some reverse engineering
we were Maria modify or HSN text and for
files and around again and we were
adding some text for our fuzzy
environment here is a demo from this
flow charting in Ida us see most of our
code was not in blue which means that
another hate leader at all so where it
has to limitation first in the world
shall check our entitlement and second
it will check our boot arguments and so
there should be some text to make it
wrong yeah first maybe we can add some
entitlements but in fact its environment
is evel's provided so we couldn't and a
second oh we can change the arguments in
fact that's what really works and other
color-block in dark and now they are
hate heat
next is the case study okay next I will
introduce some very quick case study the
fact that the one billet is found by
this - this is four four three five it
is a heap memory disclosure on bility
you can see that as the location one
point a it costs as a share in it and
the inside the shell in it at location
two point eight
it I will locate some instruction memory
without the memo set so that the memory
may contain some garbage memory and at
one location one point Pisa the
structure memory is copied back to the
user mode so what I want to show you is
that the structure is Nexus you can see
that the offset 0 X 2 8 it owning has
lens to pilot hers but but at but in the
source code it is only at offset zero X
2 8 it only the mem set V is 0 with two
fighters are remains the next tool
biters unmodified so the tool next two
batters start and offset 0 X 2 a is
copied back to the user mode so it is it
is not exploitable but it may but it can
show a pattern here that the constructor
memory if it is a lot allocated result
without memset is all Kinnear and not
all fighters are field for example
expressionism heading fighters are not
field then the structure memory is
copied back to the user mode I think it
can be a pattern you can use this kind
of pattern to search the ax in your
source code you can use some search
engines to search it and I found several
cases one of them is next at at location
one point a as a max come here is 17 but
at one point at location one point
the count is 11 the counter can be 11
and as this picture that the Mac hope
all info extension count is 17 so what
happens the structure you can see the
structure that means under some
condition that the reverse is filled
with six count it's not filled and the
memory is copied back to the user mode
then you can get 24 fighters disclosure
right and this case was fixed by fo
internally before my submission so
there's no CVE and that's another
example 8 5 to 9 it is a very simple
oh-oh volatility that you can see that
at location a the RPX is controlled by
the attack it is a very easy
vulnerability ok so that's all for our
presentation and we want to credit the
following people or projects the
scholars and at horse and to my intense
and one my what of my colleague who
helped have to come who help provide the
case on black list okay that's all or if
any in question no hands or questions
then I ask you all to give one more big
round of applause for Joe Bailon and
John see you
[Applause]
you