I am absolutely delighted thrilled
really to be back to help celebrate 10
years of hack in the Box in Amsterdam I
have revered this conference for a
decade and been privileged to
participate in it both in Amsterdam and
Kuala Lumpur what I'm going to address
is after 25 years of working closely
with technologists security
professionals and intelligence
professionals and growing with the
industry I want to take a step back and
and see what has been done to us by
ourselves what we have created and a
little bit on the dark side what we
should take responsibility for both
doing and if there is any way to
ameliorate some of what we have done to
do that we all know that the Arab Spring
turned into a long cold bitter Arab
winter we all know that our president
here in the United States recently
praised Egypt which imprisons thousands
and thousands of political prisoners for
wanting to advocate on behalf of
democracy we all know that the movement
toward authoritarian governments seems
to be gaining in momentum and power and
once people have the tools of
surveillance intrusion technology's
domination and control in their hands as
we have seen implemented so successfully
in China to monitor every detail of a
person's life we seldom get that freedom
back we have no choice however to ask
how we exercise free agency and autonomy
using those tools ourselves in the world
we have created the ethics of our lives
in the world of technology are ambiguous
at best I know how surprised I was when
a hacker professional that I had
esteemed was revealed to have sold those
tools of control to governments that use
them that is the zero days he had
discovered which could be used to track
identify persecute and torture and kill
people who opposed the directions of the
government what side are you on what are
the signs these days how do we determine
what they are how do we determine who we
can trust what are our options given the
panopticon only Big Brother's but dozens
of little brothers I'll be exploring
some of these issues in my keynote and
look forward to seeing my colleagues and
my friends