welcome so what we found is a novel
class of attacks against into a book art
into book arts basically firmware
verification and measurement feature
that into offers to protect against
malicious firmware or other kinds of
hardware attacks on the fare system so I
am beta butch I'm well this is actually
my first security-related research have
done mostly been spending last few years
reverse engineering things when I wants
to figure out more about them and when I
got a new laptop and heard I couldn't
put Corbett on it because of boot guard
I really wanted to know how that worked
and if there was some way to get around
it so that's how I found this and I'll
just have traveling to do some self well
looks like we have some HDMI issues so
I'm sure Martin I've been doing hardware
and firmware security research for the
past few years with on the offensive and
the defensive side of things from the
Thunderstrike work back a few years ago
to the heads in Linux boot firmware
projects and we're very focused on how
can we protect against hardware and
firmware threats and it's not just a
research problem this is an
industry-wide problem folks like Intel
are also very concerned about how to
protect systems from these sorts of
attacks
Vincent Zimmer is the head of the UEFI
project at at Intel and he gave a talk
at the Intel Developer Forum where he
laid out a lot of the attacks on the
platform now from different sort of root
kits and malware in the boot roms to
things
malicious devices and he presented
Intel's a solution to this something
called a boot guard that's a fully
verified boot sequence that moves the
route of trust into hardware and does
policy enforcement through that Hardware
implementation
unfortunately they have not released
anything without NDA's so there's no
real public documentation about how it
works which means the best documentation
right now our presentations like Alex
metrof softs who watches the BIOS
Watchers that lays out how boot guard is
organized what the various structures
are and how the chain of trust works and
chain of trust is an important term that
we're going to be talking a lot about in
this presentation so there's a quick
very simplified overview the boot guard
chain of trust starts inside the intel
management engines boot rom which is
on-die and immutable in the hardware it
has enough smarts to verify a signature
on the AMIA region in the spy flash on
the mainboard which is then able to
start the x86 which runs Intel signed
micro code which is able to invent
validate Intel's signature on the
authenticated code module in the also in
the spy flash and these are all signed
by Intel's private key and verified with
keys that are fixed in the in the
hardware the authenticated coach module
is transferred a set of om keys that are
fused by the manufacturer during
manufacturing time and are then used to
validate the reset vector and the spy
fly actually the reset vector and the
PGI region in the spy flash which then
validates signatures on the the Dixie
region in the spy flash which can then
validate the bootloader which can then
validate the OS kernel and these are all
signed by the independent BIOS vendors
or the OEMs or the legacy operating
system manufacturers and this is
wonderful from a security perspective
because it does ensure that if
implemented correctly
no unauthorized code will run during the
boot process but as Peter mentioned he
wanted to run core boot and other
people in the free software community
have complained about this such as
Matthew Garrett who pointed out that
well this is great for security this is
makes a trade off against user freedom
that it sort of violates the spirit of
free software if we can't put our own
firmware onto our own machines but as he
points out Intel should be congratulated
for building a system that does give us
a hardware board of trust because it
does mean that very complex attacks are
now in scope things like evil made
attacks that used to be considered have
out of scope and too hard to defend
against or attacks that required
physical access to internal hardware to
install Hardware implants or other
devices used to be considered you know
just game over from security but with
boot guard these attacks are supposed to
be protected against and that's actually
a good thing it if we can have some user
freedom to go along with it and the the
key management and the cryptography does
seem to be fairly sound but there have
been some attacks against a blue card
and they're not against the algorithm
itself they're against the
implementation and typically against the
OEM components of that implementation
one of the most glaring problems right
now is a lot of OEMs are not even
turning on boot guard they're leaving
the machines in with the OEM keys of
unset which means that malware could
potentially set those keys and create
root kits that could not be removed by
anyone on the machine Alex earmuff
presented zero Knights where they found
quite a few vendors were not bothering
to enable it other OBM implementations
have have made some poor choices such as
what embed he found which is that the
the boot guard checks were would set a
global variable
and then depended on code in the Dixie
region to check that variable and
enforce policy but you can't enforce
policy from something that is being is
being checked by it because if if the
attacker can remove those checks then
there's no code that actually ensures
the validation is correct there are have
been other sort of bad design decisions
that folks have found such as Alex
Morozov that who realized that when
Windows 10 does its update it has a way
to turn off boot guard which means that
the hardware root of trust is no longer
rooted in hardware that it's a it's only
a software a bit away from being
disabled so this also indicates the
biggest problem with the chain of trust
is it's not defense-in-depth
it means that every link in the chain
has to do the right thing has to
implement security correctly or
everything after that in the chain can
be compromised in an example of where
this can take effect or something like
the positive technologies attack on boot
guard
sorry attack on the Emme that once they
were able to get code execution in the
Emme they're able to pass the their own
om keys up to the to the ACM and pretend
that that they've has signed the other
firmware there have also been some
vendors where parts of the firmware had
not been included in the boot guard
hashes both Lenovo and also Intel made
them has taken some of the reference
code so what I found these two
vulnerabilities it wasn't a complex
analysis of algorithms it literally was
loading the firmware into the the UEFI
tool program which helpfully color codes
the parts that are boot guard protected
by Intel's hashes the parts that are
protected by the OEM he used in this
case the Phoenix hash and then a bunch
of firmware volumes that are just
completely unsigned and unhatched so
any executable code in there basically
gives say ability to bypass blue card
most of these attacks would be detected
by a measured boot mode so where these
these firmware volumes are are hashed
into the TPM and the PCRs would reflect
the actual values that were in the ROM
so even if an attacker were able to
modify them in a code execution they
would not be able to extract say a TPM
sealed secret because the code that is
executed is the same that is measured
into the hash but what if there's some
sleight of hand
where it's possible to change that code
after the validation and the
verification but before the execution
and to talk more about that I'll hand it
back over to Peter yes so yeah until did
actually think about this in a design of
boot guard this time I'll mention for
our attacks really are in there in your
fret level so let's see when you look at
the manual that vendors get for
configuring their bios's there's this
little thing in there that says protect
by his environment and it basically
allows vendors to configure the ACM the
authenticated code module first part of
boot guard to configure the CPU in
what's known as caches Ram mode and put
the entire first part of the firmware
inside last level cache so any attacks
on the hardware can't touch it anymore
no DMA attacks no attacks on the flesh
itself so this shows that they did
actually think about trying to prevent
this so
what actually is Cassius around Cassius
Ram is needed because in modern systems
you don't immediately have your your DDR
memory working when the processor starts
up there's a lot of configuration that
needs to be done in order to get there
and that happens after this station you
want to make sure that the code that
does that is actually verified so you
need a different way of safeguarding
your code and they reuse the cache to do
that by putting any write back mode
writing the stuff in there and then then
you can basically use it as round so
this is basically what we would do if we
wanted to prevent up against the time to
check time of use attack we copy
whatever we need to verify into a safe
area and then we verify it and no one
can touch it so it's safe because
there's no RAM you just caches Ram it
looks something like this where so
separate addresses and so it's safe but
you need to copy it that's slow and then
you need to verify it again so you
basically reading it twice so Intel came
up with a smarter way to do this sky
like CPUs inure have a Novik mode of
cache which means that not just can you
use it as RAM you can actually tell it
never to evict a line even if it's not
dirty so you don't need to copy it
anymore you can just have your wrong
with your initial boot block do your
hash verification on that when you do
that you're reading it so it's cached
because the cache isn't allowed to evict
anything it will stay there and it's
safe whether there's a number of
problems with this approach if your each
should work but it's all implicit so you
don't copy it to a safe area you just
trust the CPU to keep it in its cache so
if if you do this you can think that if
it's implicit putting it in there the
you might also not notice if the cash
all of sudden didn't keep it anymore
so what could go wrong well what if your
bias is larger than your last level
cache so on on skylake CPA my laptop I
think last level cache is about 12
megabytes so this shouldn't happen but
it could flash ship is 60 megabytes so
if Venna were to set it up wrong they
think it was protected but it's not this
is actually what got me on this train is
for pinafore at first because I saw they
were using this way and I thought well
what if it doesn't fit in the cache then
I realized cache large enough but still
wanted to look into it because you could
also have a cache flush instruction or
maybe something turns the caches off and
then the code would keep running because
it's still at the same address it just
not be running from cache anymore
instead it would be will be running
directly from flash ship which of course
is a bad idea
so yeah when I realized this could
happen I decided to hook up a logic
analyzer and this was made possible by
my hacker space because this is a pretty
fast logic analyzer that I wouldn't have
access to otherwise and I am I captured
the trace of ESP I bus and then I had to
write a sig Rock decoder to actually
process it because it's not really just
SPI there's all kinds of optimizations
going on so when that was done running
at 2 o'clock time as well because I
think I captured about 4 gigabytes of
trace data for a single booth of course
it's all still serial form
when I'd process the data I had a nice
log saying which addresses were accessed
in which order I think a good way to
visualize this is just to plot it
against time
so although the blue lines on here blue
dots are the first time an address is
red and everything that's in red is
something that's being read again that
was already read before so those are
potentially for a row so this is the
actual hash of the BIOS being calculated
which also the point it should be loaded
in cache and be safe then at some point
you start seeing these very frequent
three reads from flash and there's
actually a few happening before that but
I really didn't really look into those
because I just wanted to see if I could
easily exploit this and I didn't really
feel like chasing down whether a data
read was possible to use to gain control
of the thing they probably are so this
is the first one that I could find that
would actually directly x-cube code so
it's this one that's in the set core
module so for those of you who aren't
familiar with exactly how you if I works
this module just sets up the system and
isn't really supposed to run very much
later in boot so why is it running here
this is actually this function the PAI
temporary ramdom which is a handler
that's installed by sec or as a callback
to be run after the the actual main
memory is initialized them when it can
clean up what they call temporary RAM
which is cache Ram
so looking at those addresses in my
disassembler I saw these instructions so
this doesn't look too suspect at first
if you're not familiar with the way
Intel's cache setup works
it's just clearing a bit in some Emma's
our little specific register but then
you get out your into architecture
manual you see this is the NTR
enable/disable bit and that when it set
the mtrs work and everything is fine but
when you clear it all of a sudden all of
your memory is considered to be uncashed
memory type so your caches are
effectively disabled which explains why
after this point you start seeing the
firmware running execute in place from
flash which it should never be doing so
just to summarize what the actual flow
is that the system goes through while
booting you've got your ACM running
which is a piece of Intel code that's
I'm a and so you can't change it that
verifies and hash on the ROM that then
starts the SEC or which loads the P I
chord in the next stage and then the P
Ike or lost
Ram and chip setting is initialization
module which then goes on to initialize
DRAM and disables caches Ram before
running the rest of the UEFI modules
from round but this is how it should
work because actually we just saw that
disable caches Ram snap halfway through
would disable caches and execute in
place from flash so when I saw this I
thought well I need to check whether I
can actually use this to run my own code
this area but the reason that would be
useful of course is that at this point
almost none of the Emma's ours have been
locked down
there's no system management mode
running yet so in theory you could load
all kinds of nasty boot kids
lock it down and the rest of the
firmware would really notice so it's
pretty bad to be able to do this so yeah
he set out to try it so I opened up my
laptop and at first I actually was
trying to do this just using clamps but
then I tore off some pads and I decided
I need to do something more safe for my
heart or so I sold it on a header to the
SPI bus up here and actually lifted the
pad for the chips leg thin so that's
running through the header now instead
of directly onto the motherboard which
means that if I bridge that it's working
as normal but I can interrupt it and
have any other device response to the
sort of request being sent by the by
chipset and then I made a quick FPGA
design that would listen for all the
read transactions on the SPI bus and
once it detected an address I could see
in my log would only be accessed after
verification so in this case that was
one of the EFI variables which are not
included in hash I would turn on my
device which would then reroute chip
select to an external ROM now this is a
pretty simple way of doing it and it's
got a lot of flaws because need to
reflash that external ROM every time I
want to try a new payload and it is
pretty difficult to to time it correctly
so so it worked I was able to run my own
code because because there is not really
a lot of input/output devices available
at this point I decided to use the SPI
bus itself to to communicate from my
payload so I just had a big area of
memory where I would
or agreed index based on the data and
just use that as a simple text mode
output and I wrote a small script that
would parse logic analyzer output and
would show me when I painted so just
hello world
later on I didn't do some more
complicated stuff but I could run code
on a machine had boot guard enable very
early during boot so so this is setup
here's the board that has the ROM on
it's actually not on your time I took
this photo but this is the FPGA and also
had the the address lines for the ROM
decoded and sent out to logic analyzer
so I didn't have to do very slow
analysis of the SPI trace it could just
look at a parallel bus that showed Y
apples so this worked but then I wasn't
really sure what to do about it because
of what well it's a harbor attack one
who's gonna be interested in that and
this was late December so I just thought
well let's get back to it later on I
went to chaos communication congress and
went there there was this open source
firmware boof so I walked up there and
asked is there anyone here that knows
more about good guard and they pointed
me to Trammell and when I said to a
family I might have something I didn't
really tell him that much
first thing he does is he opens his
laptop nipples of this so apparently a
couple of months before I was doing this
he'd already traced the access pattern
and realized that there was probably
something fishy going on here but he
didn't really have time to look at it
any further send it to Intel and they
said well you need to have a proof of
concept at first so yeah that's what I
had so he agreed to meet up at at my
hacker space rest base and build a
better proof of concept so this time we
took it from a big setup with multiple
parts to just attaching this FPGA effort
to the model board and yeah we also
switched from having a separate external
Rome to emulating Rome when we're
overriding it in the FPGA and there's
also now a serial output core in the
FPGA that will send you the access
pattern the access pattern as easily
readable text over a USB serial port so
no logic analyzers no expensive tooling
required anymore you just hook this up
and you can you can do your tracing you
can attack it there was also something
else that needed to be demonstrated I
could run code but that wouldn't really
show that it could go undetected so we
needed to get the system to boot
afterwards in order to do that we
improved upon the basic idea of the type
of check confuse by also adding a set
where a second trigger address that once
it's read will disable the entire device
make it invisible again to the system so
at the end of our payload
we then you know read that a verse and
jump back to the original to the
original instruction that was supposed
to be executing after and that way
the system would Buddhist normal and
once it booted up and the PCR so that
the measurement registers in the TPM we
show no sign of tampering so this is
pretty bad then we could run whatever
code we wanted to earlier boot and
system the TPM wouldn't notice
so at this point Tramell contacts some
people at Intel we send them an email
also containing this nice video we made
it's so it's
it's not really that interesting but a
simple payload beeping out my radio call
sign in Morse code just to show that we
can actually run code because one of the
only output devices working mr. speaker
at this point it takes a while and my
laptop's crappy so it will reboot up for
this so it will do it again
and that'll continue booting so that
pretty much proves out we're running
code at the point that we should not be
and we still have a functioning system
so internal respondent I think within a
working day and they said yeah yeah
that's that's not supposed to be
happening and we're going to fix it so
they were really responsive and out and
I do want to really point out and even
for something as difficult to exploit as
a harbor tech intel was very responsive
and they immediately acknowledged that
it was actually a security issue and
they actually assigned a pretty high
severity to it so yeah that was really
nice workings and all that that's she so
this still required modification of the
hardware so to interrupt a chip select
line which means that you need to be
solving on your machine it's actually
pretty small so yeah you'd need a lot
more than than just somebody opening up
a case plugging something in and leaving
again so still not really practical this
is actually what we were doing
interrupting chip select and just
wrenching the other ones out the FPGA
but then we realize that most
motherboards allow just connecting a
programmer in parallel to the to the to
the flash head without removing it and
in order to prevent damaging the chipset
having two drivers on the bus there's
some serious resistors in there on
amongst other things the chip select
line which means that you don't actually
need to interrupt it this will work just
as well you've got a series resistor and
now you can just use an input output pin
on your FPGA and and drive it strong
enough to pull it down and that way
comes a lot more simple so all of a
sudden you don't need to modify it
anymore and because we move everything
to the small cheap fpga board f word you
also don't need a big expensive logic
analyzer so this is actually a trammel
setup and she could see it's just say so
ik clip and a small dev board and there
for debugging purposes there's this is
this oscilloscope but this is I think
what twenty thirty euros worth of
hardware at most so sudden it's
something that everyone can do that
everyone can build you don't need a lab
you don't need to solar anything so yeah
becomes a lot more practical of an
attack all of sudden so let's see and
this isn't just restricted to Intel
systems there's a lot of other devices
which uses SPI flash so using its tool
we just hook it up to any device and see
whether it was doing repeated reads and
try to attack those in fact travel looks
at a board management controller before
which he also discussed in his toe caps
has Communication Congress this year to
see if he could attack that in this way
and that turns out to be possible it's
also possible for a lot of different
systems
you can maybe see on here that there is
this ROM chip sitting out on some kind
of a breakout board this is actually a
stock part of the hardware we were also
able to come up with a design containing
a FPGA and a ROM chip that's small
enough to fit in this form factor to
just be soldered in place of a normal
sewing chips also it's not just so he
will clip onto a motor board but that
you could actually put in there and
during production and have a system that
looks normal that when you were on flash
ROM it will seem fine if the right
results but actually contains malicious
code so it's also something that could
potentially be used as part of a supply
chain attack which is actually what
Trammell Stoker CC was about where he
discovered discussed the feasibility of
what Bloomberg was claiming the whole
small passive component being replaced
by a by an implant actually discovered
up to be not that realistic so now I'll
hand this off to Trammell to discuss the
medication said in those planning
offenses thanks Peter
so as Peter mentioned Intel responded
very promptly to our vulnerability
report it's been 125 days since then and
they are working on getting patches into
the OEM and IBV supply chain as I
pointed out in a lot of my firmware
talks one of the big problems is it
takes a really long time for firmware
patches to make it all the way out to
the end user because typically Intel
fixes it in their reference code the
independent BIOS vendors pick up that
patch and apply it to their eggs to
their new systems and but they may not
back port it to all of their old systems
but it is really encouraging that Intel
is taking these sorts of hardware
vulnerabilities seriously they are
creating high severity bugs for them
and they are actively patching them the
fix that they have proposed to this one
is really quite comprehensive I'm really
pleased with what they've proposed to do
which is that they they are going to
relocate the entire contents of the firm
where volumes from the flash ROM into
RAM and then they're going to fix up any
addresses and relocate any any
executables in that region then they're
going to flag the the ROM regions as
being as being know read know execute so
that they can ensure that there are no
talk towel attacks possible from the spy
flash chip this is a really good way to
deal with the entire class of attacks
and I'm hoping that the all of the
independent BIOS fenders and the OEMs
pick up these patches from Intel and
very quickly get them into their supply
chain so that they can protect their
their systems from these sorts of
attacks the other way I think that we as
a community need to be addressing a lot
of these attacks is by moving to more
open source firmware that we shouldn't
have to be reverse engineering these
things is that Jeffers l pointed out in
her recent 44 con talk you know we need
to be building firmware that we can
inspect that we can audit that's
reproducibly built that we can measure
into trusted devices so that we as
system owners can actually have some
assurance that what is running on the
machine is what we built and flashed on
to it so the coreboot project the Linux
group project and the heads project are
three fairly mature projects that are
addressed this and and just talks about
them in her talk it's worth watching now
Peter and I will also be releasing the
Verilog code for our spy spy device that
will allow other researchers to to
accept
with her own machines as Peter mentioned
pretty much everything every machine
we've looked at so far has had
potentially exploitable talked I'll on
the spy bus so having a you know a 10 or
20 euro device to be able to investigate
this will hopefully get the industry to
move towards fixing these problems we're
currently working with Intel on on the
disclosure timeline for releasing the
source code but hopefully that will be
sometime then in the next month or so so
with that we'd love to take any
questions that you all might have about
about boot guard about spy buses about
talked ow but you know all of these sort
of deep hardware security things and
thank you all for coming out to listen
to our talk
[Applause]
[Music]
yes thank you so much for your
presentation are there any questions yes
hi I have a question is it possible to
use the same technique for example to
hack into a hard drive firmware rather
than room so most of the hard drives are
running arm or risk 5 CPUs many of them
have on on on-die boot flashes however a
lot of the OEM code is not particularly
high quality so I expect it would work
for for many hard disks we've certainly
seen it works against ARM based VMC's so
I expect that we could extend it to many
other arm devices hi thanks for the talk
my question is from a systems owner
perspective is there any way they can
they can detect this at this moment is
there are there any tools to see that
malicious code has been loaded or how
can they go about that well that's yes
and no because in terms of this having
happened to your system at the moment
you can't see it from a software side
because the code hides itself again
after being run and if someone would
have made the device that I described
that would fit inside the footprint of
one of these chips and having flashes as
a chip and installed in your machine at
some point I think nothing short of the
next ray of the machine would really
point that out but on the other hand you
can at least detector system being
vulnerable even if it's already being
exploited by using this device and
looking for your access patterns so you
can just hook it up it'll throw some
numbers at you free to serial port you
plot those and then if there's a lot of
red in there then there's a good chance
that your system is vulnerable
it's actually not simple and if anyone
wants to get together afterwards and we
can pop open your laptop and and give
giving a in-person examination can't
promise we won't leave anything else in
there but you might have to trust us on
that any other questions guys all right
if that's it then
thank you Trammell and Peter
[Applause]
you