without further ado Nick McKenna alright
thank you thank you for evidence
alright so i said i'm going to be
talking about DNS attack
past present and future who am i I'm
Nick McKenna I break thing i'm a student
i'm here to talk about some things that
broken if you want to email me you can
the president I talking about a tool
that I created it will be on that github
will be a link at the end all rights
rogue DNS and that's kind of where this
result start so Road penis
i'm sure many of you know it but if you
don't it is where you intercept the next
request and reply with malicious of
responses so you try to go to google it
responds with some other IP so why is
awesome music is awesome for an attacker
primarily it's it's very quiet and uh
the main reason why is the best type of
interception attack is because it's low
data so where is with most of those
texts data interception you'd have to
handle all of the data which would if
you have lots of let's find Toby you
mean lots of infrastructure left the
band with the nice thing about dns is
its low bandwidth you just have to
intercept a couple bites and send back a
couple bites it's very easy the
alternatives are very loud very
data-intensive so this witness is pretty
great and that's that's what kind of
caught my eye the past in the present
i'm going to be talking about 22 botnets
that did dns Rogan attacks so the first
one dns changer infected i believe four
million people
it did this by diffusing like registry
calls to change the dns server of a
client so kind of rather low tech not
very interesting what they did to
monetize it was replaced as so you would
typically ran their own ad network that
worked by intercepting other ad networks
book in soho and this is this is what
really got me interested in this and
what I find the most interesting so how
it would work is it would send is it
would duty srs against your router so it
would just try 1000 that one and
evanescent we just tried lots and lots
of default password
and it was a little bit more delicious
instead of doing as it would do fishing
on bank accounts bank pages it's spread
via mall vertising so you have a piece
of JavaScript that just sends lots of
iframes heard of this is lots of
requests and it would also sometimes
have iframes pretend to be google
analytics so this is how it basically
works so it spreads via csrs in as just
lots and lots of iframes and as or just
a jumped-up loops so try people
passwords and I piece it would then
become become your dns server via DHCP
so your router it's your router dns
server so by dhcp it will become your
dns server will redirect and then of
course step 5 profit so you might not be
able to use very well but it pretends to
be google analytics that's a lot of
iframes and it would also set a
secondary dns server so that their I
guess they're not being that mean this
is the java version that is it would
just try a bunch of different requests
ok so the process is the former hacking
so this is kind of get into the future
but also some stuff that we've seen
before so in attacks like really it's
kind of exploiting either
vulnerabilities in the firmware or just
bad password so i have to typically work
you'd be compiled the firmware you would
look for vulnerabilities and they were
an exploit you would find a way to
fingerprint this and then scan so yeah
so
here for propagating by 2 and this is
involved back during firmer and I've
seen this attacks in the wild early sort
of it but not very frequently but i
think that it will over time become much
more popular so it's where people use
either authentication bypass exploits or
other exploits to get into routers web
interface and then use that to flash the
firmware and from there you can put
whatever you want in the firm so what do
you do after that
what is an attacker to do after they
become a kind of unit provider and this
is kind of where where it started
getting kind of creative and think about
cool thing to do
so the first kind of a backtrack so when
you think about security and what it
means to look at security you're really
looking at largely the difference
between how you want to technology to
work and how it actually works and for
people like this man the middle attacks
as soon as I've been very leaf very hard
to do and have been done by a
nation-state but that's not really true
um and dick in looking at how lots of
different sites and applications are
built found that most people aren't
really thinking of man the middle text
is something that is done commonly or
something that's people so for that
reason I build something called the nsl
strip and what is its a simple
implementation of SL strip using dns so
it's two parts the dns server and then
it's a web server so ans server is dns
Massachusetts very easy to setup is very
easy to add manual exceptions so it's
very quick very easy to himself if i use
the web server i wrote it and flash the
main reason because it's not PHP
and it's good for doing low level stuff
and you can have a function that is just
when we receive this page we do this
with it so so how it works okay with
them on a minute so I believe that it's
okay so show them on a second but what
it does is it takes it takes the headers
so it takes the Youth Center question
the dns server it will respond with the
up with the idea of the the web server
and then the web server will receive it
will take the the host header and then
it will find its actual IP and simple
adjustment request to it so even if it's
an ssl site and it uses HTS it will
still work against it if you can somehow
get them to send an HTTP request to that
domain so here's a demo that i doing it
against wells fargo but uh surprisingly
it works against every major American
bank or goods unsurprisingly
and it's a little bit happy in this so i
couldn't get or I at the time I did the
demo I broke SL concurrency so instead
of creating new SL session I just send
it to an HTTP site and then intercept it
and then redirect to the at the site
where they would log in again but it
does when it actually works it does do
SL interception so it will create an SL
session with the host and just relayed
back to the client over HTTP ok so right
here it goes to wells fargo com up top
is the flash over at the bottom of the
dns server itself so when I went there
is somebody who has request right here
i'm logging in and then you'll see just
the post request here so typically what
would end up happening is dsl strip
would forward that to wells fargo in an
ssl session so you sending it to the
agency s back login page and then it
would create a session with it and
return the response
there we go we took the password from it
my password one that's kinda do it and
it does work against I said every major
American you think so that's fun
alright
it was happening here and kind of
explaining some but here's some diagram
so the client sends a request to the dns
server dns server send their response
and the response will be the IP of our
flash server so then we send a request
to the flat server class server and this
is the SFL trip aspect of it will send
it back and replace everything this
https with just HTTP so then you're
sending more HTTP request that it can
intercept
ok so then the second part of it is
intercepting SL and having your own
session so you can play it back
so what we do here with art and in doing
this
look something up ok so what we're doing
here is we're sending the request to the
Wells Fargo login page which has it
forces us itself HTS although it doesn't
implement it very well
so after we go to the homepage we
respond and it'll say go to HTTP / their
login page so at that point we can
intercept this then a the flash server f
the actual will Fargo server Kate where
am I going with this and then it goes so
then we'll start your replies back with
the body of the HTML body in its own ssl
efficient than it feeds that to the to
the victim over HTTP so we can continue
messing with their traffic and you can
do it indefinitely so pent head also
known as the future the reason I'm
saying testing out the future is because
I guess this isn't supposed to me to be
me giving criminals ideas so test
so what you can do with these type of
tax or at least what I what I found
interesting that you can give them so in
fact in boxes and i have another demo
but a I didn't have time to included in
this which is exploiting or equipment
vulnerability in app where i had a VLAN
of like ten boxes running semi modern
pretty modern versions of debian and
then I used
recent exploits in the app in app how
assignments packages where you could
just intercept our quest to save the
debian update server and then say this
needs to be passed
here's where you get the past and then
it would include a wooden code malware
in it and it would exploit the
assignment ability so you have an effect
one router and then from that you would
affect everything that gets dns from
that you could conceivably use that in a
setting like a data center and I think
that would be very interesting to see if
you do that in a pen test let me know so
full control of all the traffic if you
and install an ssl cert on the box so
from there you could do a service that
you can do SL signing on the fly
kind of like your own DIY deep packet
inspection and us if you have an ssl
cert on the box you can kind of defeat
this with certain pinions but not not
quite stealing passwords kind of like I
showed recently it's pretty good feeling
password
even if the login page that even if this
is where the passengers are being sent
is FL nhcs RTLS rather you can still
intercept it if we're there if we're
getting the form from is not so masking
the command-and-control servers
I'm not going to try that much but that
is something one could do because you
can just communicate data / dns and if
it's your own dns servers you can just
retrieve the responses so as I mentioned
earlier about using the using dns now
you can meet us you can ask your working
context would be that you've got into a
router somehow and you want to get our
seat and it kind of exploded earlier the
cat-and-mouse of this so kind of what
the attackers can do and what if
defendants to do so if you're starting
with the attackers heaven and external
dns server this is rather you to block
you can just say hey only use these
external dns service and lots of places
will do that however they will not do
that with internal dns service though
where the tiger could go from there
they could just if they're already in a
router they could probably flash some
firmware that would have its own dns
server running on it that they can do
the attack from and then the blue team
from there could conceivably do just
monitoring of dns like that to monitor
local dns or whitelisting bien and then
I'm sure there are lots of reading
people that have much better much more
clever ideas and I do so and fixes as I
said black hole and external an apple
iphone but out whitelisting your dns
monitoring dns and then so the next to
our kind of ideas that I've been
thinking of and I haven't seen them
implemented anywhere but i think that
they would successfully fixes and I
think could also be used for useful for
antivirus and browsers to implement
something like this so if you have a bad
dns server and you have you any requests
to it and send a better responses you
could look at it
cross-reference of a bunch of other DNS
servers and then if none of them give
you the same response you can probably
tell that something's up there and you
could investigate that so i'm working on
making an open a dd-wrt model that does
that
so if you have a bad dns server either
being used by a client or by your router
it can look at these and that it can say
hey this is bad it's good acceptor so SL
everywhere and always so as a tune
earlier if you uh you can only really be
taxed at least you can H to be if you
don't use ssl at some point so if you
use ssl always in all your requests that
kind of fixes that so there are plugins
like SL everywhere that would be useful
for things like this so rock scene so
lots of companies they will press the
other check out from there you can serve
sort through it and look at the DNS
requests and you could do something like
the craft cross-referencing i was
talking about
so then the answer cell trip if you want
to see more about it for see the code
you can go there if you have any
question e-mail be there and that is it
thank you
thank you very much i'll before you go a
thank-you thank-you from b-sides and
Fitbit and thank you from Nick thanks
very much we will have another short
break and i will let you know when the
next speaker is up momentarily