it's going to be my honor to introduce
our next speaker we have robert woods he
runs the security compliance team at
nuna whose Corps directive started
protect the one of the nation's largest
collective healthcare data sets
previously he was a consultant principal
consultant visual where he founded and
led the Red of red team assistant
practice and work with strategic clients
across the united states and advisory
capacity
here we go I was with
I radio computers work alright good
morning everybody let's get to it all
right so let's break so this morning
we're going to talk about the the
age-old battle between regulation and
compliance and security where most of us
likely fall and some of the challenges
that end up coming into those into that
battle when those things are at odds
with one another even though regulation
and compliance was was kind of brought
into being with the best of intentions
so things like mist and iso and all of
these frameworks out there they were
they were introduced to to try to make
us all better and give us some structure
and so I want to share some some
personal stories about how we've handled
you know some of the at odds and
craziness things that that come up
between between juggling security and
best practices around security and some
of those regulatory requirements so
sorry touch on this run the security
compliance teams at nuna where a
healthcare analytics company based on
the road here in soma and we work with
very large employers health plans
government agencies etc to help them
deliver better faster cheaper healthcare
services through a variety of analytics
products and probably the most important
thing down here is I'm a massive Batman
fan my wife called me a fanatic i like
your daughter anyone on my team will
tell you it's probably the latter so
first things first I want to cover what
is the actual problem and what are the
what are some of the symptoms of this of
this bigger compliance vs security issue
and I think it boils down to three main
things the first being that there are a
zillion frameworks out there you know
you've probably all seen the xkcd around
like making 11 framework to rule them
all and just ended and ending up
introducing another framework on top of
you know and number of you just end up
with an n plus one problem and so we're
drowning in this complexity that is
compliance that comes from
government regulations and customers and
maybe you know internal organizational
policy and it's just a lot of stuff to
manage for already overburdened
securities hands and then you know we
probably all heard this story the the
compliance and security theater so when
we see compliance companies end up on
the front page of The Times The Wall
Street Journal after they suffered some
kind of breach and you know we have to
ask ourselves what's what's going on and
why is that
how is that possible and then something
i'll refer to as the the gotta catch em
all Pokemon syndrome and in compliance
for digging into each of these of a
little bit more so to give you a
snapshot so noone is a relatively
smaller newer player in the healthcare
scene but since we are dealing in the
healthcare data space we're all pretty
much automatically subject you to HIPAA
security and privacy rules that you
might imagine but beyond that based on
the customers that we end up engaging
with we've already tracked and kind of
put ourselves in a position where we
have to track over eight different
standards which ends up leading us to
track over 300 plus controls unique
controls across all of these and then on
top of that we end up dealing with
customer specific audits which can come
in anytime but it most happened annually
we end up with the the possibility of
random OCR audits and then we have to of
course conduct our own internal
assessments and audits to satisfy all of
these other requirements which you know
if you're if you're familiar with going
through that process is a lot of
overhead for any any security team and
what ends up happening is I end up
looking like this in the straitjacket
and it's you know it ends up leading
into this tension where you know the
customer shows up for somebody shows up
on site more calls up or send an email
and they're like you know we need we
need you two to go through to jump
through this hoop for us and you know
many security teams will end up just
kind of rushing to the door to you know
to show them these massive spreadsheet
if anyone that if anyone familiar with
dealing with compliance in the
government space that used to track all
of this stuff in these big massive
binders and they would just hand
auditors
you know trapper keepers of compliance
controls and it's if you might imagine
you know you this is why our government
employees resemble this and it's not
pretty
the next thing security her compliance
as security theater so a few reasons why
I think this ends up being the case that
is compliant companies you know consider
like your targets in your home depot's
end up falling victim to breaches so
anytime that you're going through any
kind of assessment or an audit your
course going to put your best foot
forward so teams are gonna you know
maybe kind of spin things in the right
way they're going to really polish
things up they're gonna you know clean
it's like cleaning up before before
company comes over I'm gonna make sure
everything's in its right place
you know your vacuum you put everything
away you don't have your your laundry
laying out everywhere and this is kind
of what's happening with any time that
we go through assessment so that way we
can achieve that that business objective
that you know the company needs to get
compliance to you know not fall victim
to find to enable business development
thanks to that effect and then beyond
that because compliance oftentimes map
directly to some kind of business
objectives IE not getting finder or
enabling business development what I've
seen him in many many cases that budget
only go so far as enabling compliance
you know you're only going to get enough
money to handle or implement the
processes the controls etc that are
covered by whatever frameworks your
subject to whether it's PTI or HIPAA iso
or NIST whatever and and beyond that you
know I'm sure you're all familiar like
control framers don't cover everything
so for instance and all of those
frameworks that were covering the words
fishing or social engineering or
anything pertaining to to social
engineering attacks or human based
attacks isn't mentioned or referenced
anywhere
the only thing that's mentioned or
references that we do an annual
powerpoint 15-minute security awareness
training which you know I'm sure if any
of you guys have gone through those is
not really sufficient thing to guard
against their to enable people in power
people to guard themselves against one
of arguably it's like the most
prevalence attack factors that are
leading to a lot of these breaches today
and so you know why why is that
and then third we're going to talk about
some of the that they gotta catch'em all
syndrome and this is really where people
become so enamored that's why I called
the pokemons syndrome anyone talking
about go players in here so hands or
friends who have a erika friends who
have played pokemon go
so I've I've watched people like walk
into ladders and and do all sorts of
crazy things playing playing their games
and for just being on their phones and
so what this ends up looking like is
people become so enamored tracking these
controls that they forget about
everything else around them they forget
about best practices they forget about
you know making sure that the controls
are implementing this guy doesn't I
don't worry he comes foot so we end up
forgetting about the things that are
right around us are making sure just
making sure that you know that the
controls that we're implementing other
processes were implementing are actually
effective and we'll do one more this is
epic into what i said what i end up with
ended up witnessing and so we end up in
this situation where we don't really
care about are the things we're
implementing effective and that's a big
problem because if something is not
effective if it doesn't cover the entire
scope of what it should be covering but
you just check your box and move on then
you're going to end up in a big issue
and in a big problem down the road and
so this is an issue that that I've run
into a few different times is cases like
this where you end up with regulatory
policy over here and organizational
policy over here and if you guys can
read the text in here these are
summarized or memorize versions of the
controls that were covered and if you
notice in the organizational policy it's
it's kind of gnarliest it's not
something that you would actually want
to do so they're basically saying
network traffic to databases from
applications to applications with
whatever must be unencrypted so that way
we can effectively monitor it
that's not cool enough for anyone who
you know is familiar with the pen
testing landscape or you know just
configuring and you know actually
guarding the assistance we know that
that's not that's not cool that's not
kosher but that is something that an
organization that I've worked with
actually enforced upon the system owners
with across the organization but at the
same time that had all of these other
regulatory policies to to make sure that
they satisfied such as encrypted network
services must be used wherever possible
and then all of these other things and
so we ended up with this ended up
looking like is they ended up shrinking
down the scope or kind of dumbing down
all of these other controls that were
they were arguably best practices are
things that they should be doing in some
form or fashion just so they could
satisfy and catch them all the network
traffic must be unencrypted and there is
a lot of just excuses and it was you
know once you started shaving the jacket
just it never seems to end it was it was
excuse after excuse
and you know exception after exception
and it was really gnarly and so from all
of that you know we have to ask
ourselves you know that's where we are
today or that's where we have been and
how do we start to how do we start to
change that and so some things that have
been effective for for us at nuna is to
first figure out the people or entities
that can help you drive change or those
that actually care about change whether
you know whether they just care about
compliance or whether they care about
you know the bigger picture of security
you know actual security figure out
what's important to them you know are
they worried about business development
are they worried about making sure that
customers trust them are they worried
about marketing image things like that
the more stakeholders you can identify
around your your company that actually
care about you know what some of the
fallouts are one of the fallouts that
might come from any kind of breed shore
in a compliance issue find those people
and figure out what's important to them
figure out what language they speak you
know what you know that way you can use
their kind of jargon when you're when
you're lining and and partnering with
them and then right off the bat start to
make your efforts visible so you know we
we in this industry have a have a gnarly
habit of
no operating in this OP sector you know
behind the Iron Curtain fashion where we
don't want everyone to see how the
sausage is made
but if you can show people how the
sausage is made and what's behind the
curtain then people can start to see
just how much work there is to do and
how little compliance actually ends up
scratching the surface and so one thing
that helped us is to think about you
know actually having this this global
list of things to talk about so you know
in many organizations or you know help
i'll focus just on noona with the
products that we that we manage of those
eight different standards and the sum of
those some of those standards are
requirements come from specific
customers on specific products and so if
we were to start to try to manage this
mapping around you know customer only
customer amb care about standard you
know this standard relative to this
product but customer be carried you know
cares about two different standards
relative to you know two different
products and you know just becomes a
giant mess and so you know that the
cloud security alliance is published
this fantastic mapping that covers a lot
of the things that you're probably
dealing with her will have to deal with
at some point in terms of compliance
standards that you can take that as a
starting point and figure out what are
the industry relevant standards that i
have to adhere to you know is it because
of the space that i'm playing in whether
financial services or health care energy
telecommunications whatever are you
working in the public or private sector
are you planning on building something
that might be sold to the government in
some form or fashion because it's so
that opens you up to a whole new bucket
of a fun and then are you are you
running everything on premise and some
in some way or are you starting to
outsource things to cloud vendors of
some form or fashion because that will
that will kind of dictator or influence
what kinds of things that you start to
look at look at the scope of the control
sets that you have to manage and what I
mean by that is things you may be able
to to cleave off a lot of a lot of
requirements that you have around
availability or you know the way that
virtualization or you know hypervisor
layer controls are managed
just use an example and then within that
within that global framework you can
start to funnel in other things that you
know needs to happen so we did this and
you know we started throw-in you know
other best practices other capabilities
things like threat modeling and things
like static analysis and you know
running manual penetration test instead
of just you know regular Nessus can
things like that into this massive
framework and so that way when we're
being transparent and showing people you
know just how much work there is and you
know how much of it were doing on a
regular basis that can start to
influence budget decisions and budget
discussions and then pass that as I
mentioned we end up getting a lot of
customer requirements as i'm sure some
of you folks in the audience do as well
and you have to start to tease out what
are the specific asks that come from
your customers that can inform the
direction that you want to take your
security program and you have to either
figure out how to map those asks to
something that you're already tracking
or plan to track or you just add that
end as another security control some
examples of things that we ended up
getting from particular customers during
an RFP process or a bidding process were
you need to have some kind of data loss
prevention policy or capability in place
you need to have you know controls to to
restrict the use of USB drives on your
laptop something like that stuff that's
not covered in a normal compliance
framework and then what you end up with
when you have this this funnel of of a
global controls major is you can present
this document when it's pushed together
to a customer you don't have to worry
about going through all of the specific
hoops and you know jumping through all
of those things to to pass the customer
audit if you're dealing in the
enterprise space you're likely to end up
dealing in the enterprise space that is
selling to enterprise customers and b2b
fashion you're going to end up going
through a lot of these things because
they have their own very robust sender
governance programs and the one audit
you and test you make sure that you're
up to their standards and so if you can
see if you can show them the standards
that you're at and then let them deal
with the work battles that will save you
a lot of time and our world-time is
time is everything so the next thing i
want to talk about is reframing the risk
narrative and what I mean by that is we
need to get away from just labeling
things that high medium and low risk and
so the CIA the CIA did a study back in
the nineties and some folks here may
have read it but it was on the
psychology of intelligence analysis and
what they did is they took about 20 to
25 national security relevant events and
they rank them high medium low just that
high medium and low and they varied who
they were delivering these results to
who delivered them the time of day and
the order in which they deliver these
results and what they found through
doing this is that people's
interpretation of what high medium and
low meant very very drastically
depending on the order depending on who
presented them thanks to that effect and
if we think about that in in our world
if you don't have somebody very
compelling you know giving this you know
giving this decision maker the you know
the risk break out the risks landscapes
of if you will within your organization
and telling them what hi actually means
then you're likely to end up with a lot
of different opinions across your
decision makers decision-makers minds
and so you know i would urge you to
start to think about measuring things in
terms of numbers so you don't have to be
perfect
we don't need very very complete data
you don't need to go engage a vendor to
do this who have done you know big data
analytics and machine learning on on
risk numbers to throw up your buzz words
in there you can do it as simply as
saying within the next year this event
has you know this event within a ninety
percent confidence interval could happen
anywhere from 5 times 2 15 times
depending on the threats that we that we
kind of deal with it and expect and from
an impact perspective this thing might
cost us anywhere from a hundred dollars
if it happens to ten thousand dollars
which would be a pretty nominal you know
mishap versus something like a a a
sequel injection issue on your your
flagship app that you know could extract
and expose all of your customer data
that can cost you much much more on that
in the hundreds of thousands to millions
of dollars and so it will help you
prioritize by numbers and this is the
way that a lot of Finance teams do it
because finance teams of course dictator
budget you know how how much risk you're
actually at and they can start to model
these things to think about them in a
little bit more same manner it's much
harder to argue with numbers and it is
high medium and low because everyone's
going to have their own interpretation
of that and then pass that we can start
to align capabilities with strategic
objectives so all of those people that
you found in the beginning of this that
actually care about you know with
compare about compliance care about
security and your organization's start
to build a mental model you know this
does not have to be a big formal mapping
you don't have the script anything but
start to build stories around the
various capabilities that you're
developing and fostering and and and
building and maintaining your
organization so things like incident
response things like disaster recovery
and business continuity and
vulnerability management stuff like that
those big broad categories that all of
these controls roll up into you don't
need a specific breakdown of everything
that everything that funnels up into a
capability but you should have stories
around how these capabilities map to and
help help achieve your help support
those business objectives and what we
found is when we start to have those
kind of discussions are you map it to an
ok our KPIs objective and key result for
a key performance indicator within your
organization executives can start to see
that hey this thing over here this
objective whatever you know measurement
tool or that they use to to guide their
strategic decision-making this thing
that I care about over here is going to
be directly impacted based on the
performance of this particular
capability and so if that's a really big
one for them then maybe that's a maybe
that's the reason to find more resources
into it
I'm so moving into more of an
implementation perspective you know you
first have to figure out or we know one
of the early things you have to figure
out is what are you actually working
with what platforms and tools and you
know cloud service providers are you are
you
building on top of what vendors are you
using and you have to figure out what
your shared responsibility looks like so
think about you know the shared
responsibility model of AWS in terms of
AWS we can handle these things that the
underlying layers and then you're
responsible for everything that happens
on top of it it looks very similar in a
compliance and security perspective you
know you can't end up bringing in a
bunch of vendors to handle and process
and store computer on your sensitive
data are your most valued assets who are
not up to the same standards that you
are i use an example from a vendor that
we recently evaluated or in the process
of evaluating and we have a vendor
governance process so we send out
questionnaires to folks and we ended up
getting in the response in LOL to one
question that we asked like do you do
this particular security thing and they
were their response with LOL price and
so like if an auditor to come in and we
were to give them all of this stuff
their response would more likely be WTF
not LOL like they would not find it as
funny as this particular vendor did so
you know figure out what your shared
responsibility model looks like with
regards to all of the things that you're
building on or using or the people
you're engaging with and that will help
you figure out what controls actually
matter to you and what ones don't and
they all bailed ultimately matter but
once you have to actually track or which
ones you can just say you know we're
using vendor a drop a link into their
compliance stage and say you know we're
done with it you know we trust them to
handle this particular area of our
organization and one idea that we've
been experimenting with lately is this
idea of adopting test-driven development
to test driven compliance and so writing
tests or starting with a condition that
fails on a particular control so is X
encrypted is X resource encrypted is
this networking is this network
connection encrypted things to that
effect and this won't you won't be able
to do this across your entire portfolio
but the more things that you can adopt
and
build automated test for in a similar
fashion that we would any kind of
quality function you know you can start
to you can start to track these things
as part of your CI CD pipeline you can
start to deliver results or bugs to the
developers that are potentially turning
things off for work writing something
new that doesn't conform to the
standards that you're rolling out of
your organization and you can put the
responsibility back on them to fix a bug
and not necessarily deal with compliance
you know it's all about framing this
just as it in the same way that we don't
go to a developer and say or at least
we're not anymore
according to the trends that were on you
know we don't go to a developer and that
you have a number of vulnerabilities to
deal with we send you know you have n
number of bugs to do with its all bugs
you know whether it's a quality bugger a
security bug it's all issues that
negatively impact the performance of the
system that you're working on
so please please address it you know you
can start to work with your your builder
Ops teams to a no-fail builds based on
certain things happening or certain
conditions not being met and this again
feeds into that idea of monitoring and
reporting on the state of your
compliance program and so then we start
to think about you know if we're
tracking all of these things we start to
be able to generate metrics for them
which is great metrics are fantastic and
you know if you're running these things
on a case-by-case basis you know
point-in-time audits then it becomes
very difficult or you're not getting
very timely metrics like doing a a
quarterly assessment as an example
however if you're running a lot of your
control stuff through a cic pipeline and
you can start to track these things how
their other performing over time how
quick are you to remediate a particular
control gone wrong thinks that effect
that provides a much more compelling
story to auditors as well as to the
decision makers within your organization
and you also start to introduce this
concept of transparent reporting and
transparent reporting what we found it
is a very very effective tool for
increasing social pressure on people so
whether it's social pressure on an
executive or social pressure on a
developer if somebody introduced an
issue and everybody knows about that
issue
being in place then they have more
pressure on them to fix it and this
works even interested in executive
circles so if you're doing roll-up
reports to to an executive team or to a
board you know highlighting where all of
these things where all of all of these
things stand from a you know from a
coverage perspective from you-know-where
eighty percent of the way there and
business continuity just after covering
ninety percent on instant response
cetera and you started you start to call
out which director which executive is
responsible for these things nobody
likes to look foolish in front of their
peers and this is not a necessarily a
thing to a tool to make people look
foolish but everyone wants to make sure
that their stuff you know their house is
nice and polished anytime that company
comes over and so this is the way to
start to do that and what I want to what
i want to highlight is this relationship
right here between the strategic the
strategic alignment with capabilities
and the metrics so if you can start to
build the build metrics around the
capabilities that you're tracking and
and want to track and that are important
to the key stakeholders then you can
start to tell really compelling stories
to both auditors and 22 internal exact
for people who are influencing your
controlling budget and so you know
moving into you know how do we actually
fight upstream what do we actually do
when when these things are at odds with
one another so i think there are there
are six main big takeaways
the first is making sure that we reframe
the narrative around around compliance
reframe the narrative around risk and
start to think more about how we can how
we can report towards people's intrinsic
motivation so you know if they're
motivated by you know by again business
development or making sure that their
customers trust them when they walk into
a sales meeting or something to that
effect then talking to them in the in
the language or in the in the narratives
that they have is going to be a much
more powerful story then the next one so
that way you don't end up in the
straitjacket condition of the pokemon
syndrome you need to identify why you
actually need complete need to be
compliant and to what you need to be
compliant to so not everyone needs to be
fed ram
applying for instance only vendors who
are building software to sell to a
government agency of some form or
fashion need to be fed ram compliant and
you know you don't want to be taking on
something as massive and media as
FedRAMP if you don't have to it's not
necessarily impressive if you're FedRAMP
compliant not settling to the government
however if you need to or plan to if
your business wants to go down that road
finding those things that really so that
way you can structure things accordingly
it's gonna be a really really important
thing and then this is where we start to
think about the points 3 and 4 start to
think about the social pressure and the
transparency element so we need to make
our reporting personal to those who
would actually matters so this is you
know very very closely related to the
intrinsic motivations but you know we
need to make sure that we're that were
communicating in the same native tongue
as the people who are you know to who
this matters because compliance enables
us to do business in some way compliance
isn't necessarily bad but it can be it
it's like a necessary evil in the
organizations that we work and then this
was not mentioned mentioned the past but
you know this probably comes to no
surprise but make sure that you have
some element of deadlines and directly
responsible individuals or
accountability when it comes to
remediation of these things you don't
want to be on the hook in your
organization for actually handling all
of the remediation work that might come
from you know any kind of audio for
assessment there's probably going to be
a lot of it and so if you can start to
pinpoint the team's the project managers
the business owners etc we're actually
going to be responsible for for managing
all of these things then it's going to
it's going to benefit you in the long
run you're not going to have to do as
much work to maintain it to do the work
initially etc because you probably got
your own massive bucket of work to
handle on your plate and then of course
if you can start to you know this and
this ties back to the to the risk
narratives you know using numbers to
drive how we talk about risk if you're
not just saying hey mister mister or
missus developer you've got a high-risk
vulnerability you know when nobody
actually know what that knows what that
means and so if you're talking about
if this thing has a you know with a
ninety percent confidence interval has a
chance of happening you know 50 times
this year and it's going to cost us 50
million dollars which we know is going
to put us under because that way out
does our cyber liability insurance and
blah blah blah then you know you can
start to you can start to work with
people and come up with much more sane
deadlines you know maybe you don't have
or maybe you do in your organization's a
a set deadlines based on risk for things
to be remediated in my consulting
experience I've seen that go both very
well and extremely poorly in the sense
that some issues are just way too big to
to remediate in a in a set amount of
time and so you know having these these
hard and fast rules that kind of blanket
everything can sometimes be very
difficult and then of course in the
compliance space and this is one of
those things that that is
counter-intuitive to the most is you
know we need to embrace automation much
like we are in the rest of the security
space so you know compliance is kind of
a subset a sub function of this broader
generalized thing that is information
security organizations and the more that
we can embrace automation to to
implement to maintain to to
course-correct all of these different
controls the better position we're going
to be in and then of course as you're
automating things that allows you to
start taking measurements on things and
if you can measure things you can manage
things and once you want you can start
met managing things you can set your own
objectives that then roll up into the
bigger kpi's or you know again whatever
objective objective tracking tool that
your executive teams are using and so
with that I will stop blabbering for a
little bit and wrap up and does anyone
have any questions and thank you
oh yeah
sure so the question was and correct me
advice if i paraphrased incorrectly was
for new people that are coming into the
organization how do you continually make
sure that that your compliance
initiatives or no control implementation
initiatives are accurately maintained
and things don't go off the rail as you
know time goes on because you know we'll
build something and like you know
controls and compliance and all of that
is like right on top of the business and
everything is aligned perfectly but very
much like when you build a you know
build a network and design everything
appropriately the business and you know
compliance starts to like come out of
sync with the rest of the you know the
original technical vision that alright
so so that's really where i think the
automation comes into play so the more
and more things that you can you can
implement by a by automation it's just
it's just there it becomes a part of
people normal workflows you know the
normal testing frameworks the end up
being used and run against the against
the the codebase that you're that you're
maintaining and you know this of course
gets a little bit more complex of the
more and more products that you have but
you know if you're if you're writing
good test and you you really commit
yourself to writing good test as you
know any good quality function an
organization does then you know it's a
kind of self maintains and then from a
you know from those controls that can't
necessarily be automated one thing that
we found really effective is identifying
the business owners it's a mapping
business owners to a particular
capability and so let's say your
business continuity is agree the great
example so you know that may fall if we
think about business continuity from a
revenue perspective and operations
perspective and a technical operations
perspective you know we may we may
highlight two people maybe one person
and operations one person and
engineering who is responsible for
basically making sure that you know if
things go off the rails you know they're
going to be the ones on the hook and
then we just have you know like ongoing
conversations with those individuals and
we put the pressure back on them to to
maintain these capabilities and so will
do things like like tabletop exercises
too
you we're not measuring the
effectiveness of a bunch of specific
controls or rather will just pick up
scenario out of a hat and go talk to you
know talk to those those individuals who
are responsible set up a tabletop
exercise and you know we'll drop this
scenario on them and you know everyone
in their in their team will make it a
cross-functional thing and you know
we'll make it fun and engaging and all
of that and you know we'll talk through
how they would actually respond to the
scenario so you know like availability
zone goes down or you know somebody
compromises their social media accounts
and start spewing a bunch of crap like
what do you what do you actually do have
you have you thought about all of these
things and if their answers are not very
good or compelling or if they just have
no idea what to do then that shows that
they're not actually you know taking
this taking this thing seriously and
then we can start to you know we can
start to work with them to create
project plans because ultimately if you
make it real for them in the sense that
something that they're responsible for
its going to completely fall over
because they haven't maintained this
this responsibility then you know
they're going to be the ones that look
like fools not you necessarily like HR
is another really good example because
there's so much hr-related controls
aren't we have injected into like NIST
and iso and these other these other
frameworks thanks
any other questions
yeah so the question was just a repeat
was when there's a lot of different
platforms and tools and technologies in
a play how do you manage all of that
under one roof is that ok so so one
thing that we've found that we found
effective is we've got we've got a few
different platforms so to speak across
the business lines that were maintaining
so one way is to try to just you know
push people to consolidate that's not
actually an easy thing to do and it's
probably not actually very likely to
happen but one thing we had to kind of
adapt to and this introduces a little
bit of complexity but is is capturing
somewhat of a scope if you will perk
control and so you know something as
simple as something as simple as
encryption at rest of of of data sources
and you would we extrapolate that to to
a particular product and then owning
team and so we have each of our controls
map to somebody who somebody or a team
who's going to own it and the product
that it relates to and it's it's kind of
an additional an additional mapping and
so a lot of controls if you go through
these these frameworks like stock to iso
or NIST are are more organizationally
focused or at least there's a subset of
controls within them that our
organization focused and those are the
easy wants to handle but with a from a
product to product perspective will
oftentimes just will not really worried
about the technology necessarily from a
from a compliance management perspective
we'll just figure out what team owns the
what product it relates to and then that
you know the specifics around managing
technology and all that is is more of a
nuance that will deal with outside of
this this particular compliance like
tracking because then it just becomes
way to wait too cumbersome this from our
perspective for our experience
so i'll paraphrase and let me know if I
got it right
do you ever look at other guys the
personal information or other high-value
assets how much of it is going into or
out of a particular part of a system and
then how do you prioritize is that ok so
that's where I think the risk like
talking numbers around risk really comes
in handy so you know if we if we just
use the the ordinal risk scale to talk
about you know everything is high medium
and low risk you know it's all very much
relative to the thing that you're
talking about for instance if you engage
a a pen test team and you have them come
in and test like let's say you have some
organizational or regulatory mandates
that says thou shalt have everything in
your application portfolio and tested
manually been tested by third-party
alright great you know that team is
going to look at the the scope of the
thing that they're testing and they're
going to risk crank things and that high
medium and low or no fashion relative to
the thing that they're looking at and so
if you were to just sit back and look at
you know high medium low critical
whatever risk issues across the entire
you know set of reports that you end up
getting you're not really going to get
much useful information because you're
going to have you know high-risk
critical risk issues and a bunch of very
very low-risk applications let's say
you're juggling like you know a hundred
200 300 applications i found this very
frequently when when i was working with
banks and digital and they would have
these like marketing sites or other you
know a temporary like advertising
advertising sites that went through
almost no testing whatsoever and you
know they would just be subject to a
manual tests you know once every two
years or something to that effect and
you know so of course they are littered
with issues but they don't really care
because they're throwaways sites that
aren't really connected to anything and
so that's where I think starting to talk
about numbers when it comes to risk like
if something were to happen relative to
this particular scope it's going to cost
the business this month
and even if it has a really really high
likelihood of happening it might happen
you know to 300 times in a year or
whatever you know kind of time cadence
use you set or use you know if the
impact is so nominal that it doesn't
really matter then you can you can wait
to prioritize those things that make
sense
any other questions
that's good question so the the
particular question was how do you deal
with with issues that lets say something
goes down and that that thing going down
does not itself introduce a business
risk in terms of financial loss or
something to that effect versus
something that you know is directly
impacting the business like you know the
the sequel injection or something that I
heard that you know data loss of some
sort so in that case I probably that's
actually really good question
you could probably change them together
in the sense that you know if this thing
happens you know if you you would
probably marry the two things together
and and like look at them as 11 joint
risk so you know if your intrusion
detection system goes down you're you're
much more likely to to fly blind and if
you don't see if you don't see a risk
then or you know somebody poking around
your network then you know you're you're
in for trouble in some way shape or form
so i probably just write that liver
right that risk out as one thing such as
you're not able to see you know somebody
somebody stealing data or somebody
accessing a particular system and i
would i would probably rank it at the
greatest thing that would be most
impacted and so let's say is you know
somebody accessing some high-value
server and you want to be able to see
that and the ids going down is is what's
going to enable you to do that and if it
out then you're flying blind then i'll
probably I would focus on you're not
able to see somebody accessing or
somebody accesses the high-value server
you know that's X likely to happen
because of because of the fact that this
thing is you know maybe in stable
something to that effect and therefore
could cost you this amount of money so i
probably just rewrite the risk it
doesn't necessarily have to be a mite in
my opinion and everyone else will
probably have their own but it doesn't
have to be a very specific very specific
instance in all cases
any questions
alright well thank you very much
everybody and like reset please drink
your coffee and and have breakfast and
be married so thank you
assembling of weird that we're going to
service
[Music]