thomas i work at zions bank i'm also a
PhD candidate at George Mason University
this talk cyber insurance emperor has no
clothes
I think it's different from all the
other talks for two reasons first of all
it's probably the least technical in the
computer science sense of the term the
focus here is I on how organizations
work and how they make decisions second
difference is i'm not going to try to
fill the whole time with presentation
i'm hoping that people here in the
audience have questions they want to
discuss some things brought up maybe
they even want to present a contrary
point of view and I'm not going to
provide all the information on this
topic right up there you see the URL for
my blog the blog post on this topic is
the first one that you'll see on that
homepage so please go there if you want
to learn more details and understand the
fine points of the argument so to
preliminaries first of all I'm here
presenting a reason argument this is the
initial part of an investigation
I can't say that every point i'm
presenting is fully defendant or
justified but i do believe this whole
topic has not been sufficiently analyzed
now at hackers one of things we do is we
challenge assumptions and we especially
poke our fingers that how things are
supposed to work to see if they work
somewhat differently and my Paul thesis
here is the value of fiber insurance is
not been sufficiently challenge from a
functional and operational standpoint so
the second preliminary is I'm not here
to bash insurance companies or insurance
people quick show of hands
anybody here from the cyber insurance
industry i see at least one very good ok
so whether you're here in person or you
here virtually or you hear about this
talk there may be other domains where
people complain about the insurance
companies this is not one of them
so what I'm really here to talk about is
not the risk transfer function of cyber
insurance perfectly valid function that
has its own business case I'm really
here to talk about the incentive and
risk pricing function of cyber insurance
so where did this notion of insurances
incentives come about anyway so it
actually started out in the early
eighteen hundreds it happens to be the
economist Jeremy Bentham and when they
thought about social good in general
rewards and punishments basically boiled
down to some combination of carrots and
sticks and Bentham and other people came
after and their theory of human behavior
is if you get the right combination of
carrots and sticks people in society
going to do what you want to do where
they're going to do good thing
so this theme has carried forward and if
any of you have been to a cyber
insurance conference you've been talking
to policymakers in the back of their
mind and sometimes in the front of their
mind is this whole notion of well cyber
insurance is potentially good because it
provides positive incentives we don't
have to bring out as many sticks
well there's something problematic about
simplifying it that level and i'm going
to go through a number of objections but
first i'm going to present the point of
view of somebody you may recognize the
character Malcolm Tucker from the
british series that thick of it and he
had his own particular twist on the
carrot-and-stick strategy which is a
package stick approach this account
pick up the fuckin off followed by the
stick full of bodies bigger lot of
challenges
so the point of presenting that is
simply an academic or an idealized
notion of carrots and sticks can be
quite problematic when they're in the
hands of any particular organization or
any particular institution to implement
so where did this idea come from that
insurance would be a good incentive and
information system for risk reduction
well it turns out with the hartford see
boiler company in 1866 this is a picture
of this stock certificate and it shows
various calamities industrial boilers
steamship boilers railroad boilers were
blowing off with high propensity and
hartford steam boiler company was the
first to build a successful insurance
based business model but I've
highlighted here it was the inspection
and insurance company not just the
insurance company so right from the very
start
they had a model of people in knowledge
and expertise and customer engagement
that would make risk reduction central
to the product that they were offering
so one way of characterizing this debate
over cyber insurance is is security
roughly speaking like steam boilers
can't be managed and influence that way
why reasoned argument is no 4 10 reasons
and each of these ten reasons may be
relatively true or not true in any
particular circumstance one of the
things that troubled me about this
believe that cyber insurance is an
unmitigated good and if only if
everybody applied it things will be
better is it only takes a couple of
these 10 reasons to cause the system to
fall apart in any particular company or
in it
anything particular insurance pool so
the the exploring possibility blog goes
into great detail into the following ten
reasons
i'm going to read them off quickly then
I'm going to sort of dive into two of
them before leading into our discussion
ok so first point is cyber insurance is
bought in your firm by the wrong people
and it's sold by the wrong people the
people who are selling cyber insurance
are the same people who sell property
and casualty and errors and omissions
and every other line of insurance they
have no particular knowledge or
expertise in cyber insurance our
cybersecurity likewise the people that
buy it in your organization tend to be
the risk managers the CFO people quite
this distant from security now this one
is a little bit more controversial and a
little bit more technical but we often
believe that insurance companies will be
able to pool all kinds of information
and come up with magical formulas or
actuarial models of risk and then be
able to underwrite insurance based on
that and i think the actual information
basis for doing that is rather weak and
anybody I talk to your presentations
I've seen in the insurance business
tells me that they're struggling in this
arena show of hands how many people have
actually read through the coverage of
your company's cyber insurance program
ok not very many that doesn't surprise
me by the way if you ever get a chance
please try to look through it
metaphorically it's Swiss cheese
it covers some things excludes other
things the whole logic of the contract
is to serve the insurance company not to
serve you and especially not to serve an
improvement program in security number
for the claims process is both too
expensive too uncertain as to whether or
not going to pay off and certainly not
frequent enough to provide feedback
between your company and your insurance
provider
number four the number five the two-way
information flow aside from claims is
woefully inadequate now insurance
companies are expanding somewhat in this
area by contracting with risk rating
firms like this site but it is it is no
way we're close enough to what it needs
to be number six the cycle time between
stimulus meaning something happens in
your organization something changes in
the environment and something changing
in your policy is way too slow and maybe
six months nine months 12 months 18
months 24 months before some change in
the threat environment of the security
environment is reflected in your policy
and that is way too slow to have a
useful influence on security
decision-making so one of the
conventional wisdoms is higher
cybersecurity is hybrid higher cyber
insurance premiums will be a signal that
you're cybersecurity practices need to
improve and conversely if you do good at
that your insurance premiums are going
to fall on the blog post like a numerate
a whole bunch of reasons why this is a
noisy signal and it's not a very
reliable signal to and i'm going to go
into this a little bit in the in the
following discussion now number 8
doesn't get talked about enough i
believe strongly that firms need to
focus on retaining risk to the extent
that they can because firms when they
built best ability to understand what
they are in to mitigate them so even if
risk transfer makes sense from a
corporate finance standpoint it should
be a second or third line of the sense
not a primary one insurance company risk
models fit their needs
not your needs they don't supersede the
opposite need and requirement to develop
risk models internally or conjunction
with your service providers finally this
I've gotten debate on this topic
it really does not fit network
interdependent risk
yes there's something called third
RT risk contracts but when i say network
independent i'm talking about the sort
of modularity between coverage so all of
the players in a supply chain or in a
value chain are in a value Network have
complementary incentive signals rather
than the incentive to put the blame of
the liability of responsibility on on
someone else and I I think we learned
some lessons here it was at the target
breach with the blame was put on their
their third party contractor we see this
happening a lot
ok so i want to look at two of these in
more detail and i'm going to provide
some data from a survey that somewhat
supports and maybe contradict some of
the points I making so I the two
characters in the foreground are the
people who are buying and selling let's
say the red is the insurance company and
the white is is your firm somewhere in
the background is people involved in
infosec whether it's the sea so whether
it's your technical architects
enterprise architects these are not at
the focal point you're not choosing the
company you're not choosing the coverage
you're not dictating the information
flow process so here's data from the
survey they talked to 203 people who
were involved in information security
you notice the deciders here the
executive board the effective management
of the board of directors lots of
influencers but the senior security
management compliance and technical
people are at the bottom of the list in
terms of the people involved in
recommending I've got a couple quotes on
this in a second so i apologize for the
pie charts i did a cup cut-and-paste
here this sort of goes against the data
visualization best practices so yes
the technical people are frequently
involved but quotes from the survey or
very revealing
so the risk managers themselves that are
on point really are not very well
informed and don't feel very knowledge
about cybersecurity so they depend upon
the technical people but the technical
people don't generally involved because
often they don't even see the value in
the exercise and appeared to me from the
survey the technical people get involved
when it comes to filling out the surveys
filling out the audit reports so it's a
one-way flow
it's a check box type task is not
collaborating on the decision-making so
I think that's further supporting the
idea that we don't have the right people
at the table in the buying into selling
decision ever you're not going to end up
with cyber insurance coverage that
drives the improvements in security so
the other thing I want to our problem
area want to focus in on his the
variation in premium so some of you may
know about the publication of virus
bulletin is John haws I believe this is
a 2013 article that he put out in a
naked security he capitalized what many
many people say about cyber insurance
and i'll use the same connection so
connected to auto insurance or home
insurance and they say well if you do
these things your premiums will go down
well let's look at what the survey says
about that
so first of all of the 203 people only
thirty-three percent actually they're
firm engaged in cyber insurance and of
those thirty percent the insurance is
bundled with a whole bunch of other
things
now think about that for a second if
you've got a comprehensive corporate
policy to cover cyber insurance errors
and omissions
property and casualty a whole bunch of
other stuff how big and how important is
the cyber insurance signal in there
about how big your premiums going up and
down so at least one-third of the people
are not getting a very good signal out
of this in the first place and then the
question is well what happens to that
signal at all
well some people will say well in order
to qualify for cyber insurance in the
first place
you've got to bring your cyber security
up to a certain level
well here's a survey of underwriters
happens to be a hundred ninety four of
them and here's all the things that they
say disqualified somebody from cyber
insurance
well this looks like a decent what you
might call hygiene list but I don't know
anybody in this room C so or even a
technical manager who would say if i
only do these things that I'm doing
topknot cybersecurity these that this is
the ante this is the entrance state and
a fiber insurance only gets you to the
ante
we can't really make a claim that it's
taking you to any level of excellence
and here's a similar set of questions
which is to me what's most important
what changes did you make in your
organization because you engage with or
purchase cyber insurance number one is
implemented policies and processes could
be good or could be meaningless
depending upon what those policies and
processes are so the last element i want
to bring up before opening up for
discussion and debate here is this is
just one headline I've seen recently so
british firm CFC under whiting I get one
of their annual meetings presented some
survey results and they say insurance
premiums are rising and we believe it's
the fear of security incidents like the
yahoo breach which is increased demand
and any market where demand increases in
supply
is restrained prices are going to go up
with prices go up not because my firm is
doing worse but because lots of other
people are buying the product
what time is signal does that send to my
firm
ok so there's lots of factors to drive
premium prices up and down there's even
lots of debate in this industry whether
it's going to turn out to be cyclical
like property and casualty or it's going
to be stable but the whole notion that
premium prices or coverages themselves
are going to be a good reliable signal i
think is fallacious so that ends the
core of my talk I'm getting approached
by several publishers here's oh really
maybe we got a book deal in the in the
work and now i want to open up we've got
about 13 minutes for questions comments
encounter of arguments right down in
front i'll try and repeat the question
go ahead set up all the talking so I
tend to agree with your points about the
effects of cyber insurance on the
arrogance has on the corporation as its
buying insurance
what would be your thoughts around the
effect of cyber insurance as driving the
overall quality of security in products
are being purchased in other words out
of the cyber insurer is a more
knowledgeable fire of security so this
reduces information the symmetry a
excellent question so i have two answers
to that first of all I see no
operational on the ground evidence that
cyber insurance firms are building
expertise to the level they need one
piece of evidence is who attend
conferences like this who attend the
workshop on the economics of information
security who presents there it's not the
cyber insurance
company they are following rather than
leading the second thing is let's
consider an alternative cyber insurance
let's say there is industry associations
or even government agencies that simply
pay you four are implementing the Miss
cybersecurity framework or pick any
framework you want
why do we have what is the value social
value of having the insurance the
coverage the claims process is quite a
lot of informational and functional
overhead associated with it without
clear evidence that they're going to
provide the value the driving force that
you just described
now I think alternative insurance type
products that have a completely
different institutional structure could
work but i don't think that the current
model and cyber insurance will do it
ok next question yes please
ok the gentleman brought up to point
first of all he said cyber insurance is
in its infancy it's maybe not fair and
maybe not proper to criticize it and its
current form maybe give it time it's got
to go through its growth spurts the
second point is well maybe pushing
hygiene is sufficiently valid reason
ok on the first point i would like to be
more optimistic in fact i like to put to
believe in the creativity of Mason
industries unfortunately what I see here
so compared to the rest of what's called
FinTech peer-to-peer lending micro
lending this huge energy of creative
entrepreneurship in syntek we do not see
the same in cyber insurance and I wish
there was
and the reason being is this is all
happening within the existing
institutional structure of insurance the
same companies the same legal process
the same regulatory structure the same
human beings with the same skillset and
they're trying to say well cyber
insurance is like all these other lines
and we're going to invest in it and
we're going to grow and by the way
that's why you see some people wanting
to have a government mandate for
insurance to drive adoption right
ok so the second point about hygiene in
other presentations i have had some
negative things to say about aiming for
hygiene because i think it aims to low
on the other hand what's called hygiene
is so obviously bad in so many places a
case could be made that we got it drain
that particular swamp i would argue that
there are better ways and I certainly
wouldn't claim that the major social
value of cyber insurance will be the dr
hygiene because there's a dozen other
ways that will be more economical and
more effective to do it than that
other questions anybody strongly
disagree with any of these ten have
different points of view
ok so his question is what about the pr
aspect you mean the pr aspects of big
planes and breeches or this
so he's asking about the public reaction
to to what
ah ok so he's saying companies tend to
react to negative publicity around
breeches and that's sort of what that
British underwriting firm was arguing
that they're seeing demand for insurance
because these highly publicized breaches
i'm not sure how that relates to the
effectiveness of cyber insurance though
you have anything
ok so he's adding that this head puts a
spotlight on brand damage associated
screeches and things that are might be
covered under insurance policy
whereas otherwise they may not be given
visibility soft costs that's a valid
argument and if the claims process was
more expedition so take for example the
target breach or the sony breach my
knowledge and even the heartland breach
he was 45 years before the insurance
payouts remain maybe it's three years
it's not the same here it's not within
six months so there's a time urgency we
think about the dfi our investigation
the attribution investigation the
corrective action right so the type of
corrective actions got to do in your
your vendor value chain all that has to
happen on a very quick time scale even
personnel changes in the firm right we
have inadequate staffing we have
inadequate leadership in our ensure our
security organization that's going to
happen within a few months it and if the
insurance settlement and payout is years
later it is way too slow to have an
influence on the process in the blog
post i talked about a number of
strategies that corporate executives
could take to minimize the premium costs
in the short run to meet their number
because if they did hell if if you're I
can't see the number raised a finger
okay thank you
I'll be done in just a few minutes if
you are chief financial officer and
you're leading the risk committee and
you're going in front of the board and
let's say the board is going to be
really hard asked about this and they're
going to want to say you as chief
financial officer will not get your
bonus if our cyber insurance premiums go
above X or we encounter increase
section such a size now who here has
seen a performance measurement system
gamed or scams or manipulated i know i
have you read the news that's happened
in public education that happened in
toshiba has happened lots of places I've
seen it happen on of enterprise-wide IT
project so the first place to manipulate
that is in the coverage right who's
going to read 47 pages of coverage and
there's lots of things you can do to
manipulate and control the amount of
premium to your charge which is the
visible thing without actually improving
security and maybe your successor is
going to deal with the consequences of
that so if I'm a CFL to find five years
away from retirement
I'm gambling that within the next five
years either i don't have a breach or if
that we do this insurance settlement is
happen after I'm gone or is the
responsibility is diffused so i guess
the last thing is there any other
questions or comments
yes please
ok this is a superb question thank you
sir
he said it's so fucking broken is there
room for a start-up so i have two
answers to that
yes and it's the road less traveled
meaning you're going to be walking 40
miles or 40 miles through the desert
eating locusts for a long time if you
compare what it would take to do a
start-up in this environment to the
latest in AI for threat intelligence or
any purely technology thing we do not
have including the funding agencies the
venture capital agencies good models for
how to develop this now i believe there
will be entrepreneurial organizations
going after it but it's gonna have to
start small very niche focus and develop
something that works in that classic
disruptor type model right the ignored
part of the marketplace and then get
momentum so that you can start taking
over more than mainstream so thanks
everybody for your attention thanks for
your questions
take a look at the blog follow me on
twitter
Thank You Rocco on behalf of besides and
fit to fit and I think the organizers
deserve yet another round of applause
guys did an awesome job twice as many
attenders last year really appreciate
their work
thank you and that huge thanks to our
sponsors Fitbit Harker one and very
sprite will be back at Fort and thank
you
[Music]