ok
so I
Jim I'm not
pretend games a 10-game rebuildin
awesome hun platform and I were con-
security aspects of it like an officer
in partake of I really all of you to see
some of these guys especially Joe was
our in-house sparkling foot and also the
author of maximum a Christian Sean to
give this particular of the optic nerves
and finally Brad and caffeine from other
traffic and that caffeine for working
tirelessly to travis and giving us
together to work out to work with so
last year I was working on domain
definition you're doing scoring and
stuff and excited for becoming a big
challenge
none of the traditional ways that
features of classifying the winds with
workforce like it so I had sinking
deeper and it came down to this
multistage action despite confuse the
matter that's spreading strike it has
three different cities redirects exploit
and inspect and what's interesting is
that these cities are managed by its not
much watching entities he had three
different confidence at play that are
very loosely coupled so if you look at
any report from a traffic or caffeine
movie something like that leech
redirecting to let you know dropping
lucky and so these are three different
confidence three different players that
are working together to make it happen
on network level it looks like this so
user of this website it may already be
compromised or it may have a man reaches
out that redirects users to a series of
gates now get our life bouncers they
figured out unwanted traffic looks like
it and they are intentionally hosted on
a throwaway domains like dynamic dns you
are charts and stuff like that and so
they get the place where you often once
you get fast the case you end up on our
next slide kidnapping page again the
expected landing page is to it really
often from expected quite often ask a
museum a Nazi sm landing piece over
again
and so once you're on the landing page
the browser gets excited the bad grades
drop and again the binary might change
over time
so what I'm going to highlight here in
this slide is that there's a lot of
dynamism wanting actually a lot of
moving parts
the winds and content get stopped in and
out really frequently so given this
challenge I started looking at what to
Wilson techniques we have at hand to
look at the expression and they broadly
fall into two categories one is to
detonate our URL in our sandbox and then
observe the artifacts from the oil
that's a real photo approached
differently but the challenge is the
cost of your management you're not
starting up a vm saving the street
coming back to it so that if you don't
really gots can literally went on the
other end of the spectrum we have
suicide here feet off you have ravello
we have a lot of JavaScript engines that
lets you walk to the code the office
getting on on the run by a flying
three-point at specific dom manipulation
functions so that's another good
approach understand what happens in the
browser but you have to man me eve of
the code why it's doing this and what's
going on so that giving the idea that
there's a gap between the two approaches
and maybe we can find of Midway could be
find a way to understand what happens in
a browser when unexpected acute and
without having to manually code the code
to enter Heaven brothers many of you
might already know about headless
bowlers these are frameworks that lets
you interact with the browser without
having to load of the GUI fact
imperatives of you know the oldest and
most widely used one it's usually used
for of QA automation stuff like UI
testing and stuff like that and it's
based on a bit on top of the get to my
generation is another one which is being
built on top of firefox has the same
sentence
api so these frameworks have some
interesting if he admitted to what you
want to do the lettuce injection our
trips into a page before the bases
loaded so that gives me an idea in stuff
during break line could be fun with our
function we can apply the hooks to all
the functions that's a very low lets you
make wine Duke and intercept the part in
addition to that the scream of have to
it's like you know a lot even handle set
you intercept HTTP requests and so on
and about it with dropped the modified
explode request and such support and
finally you know even the user agent and
ok tell you the range to look like IE
and stuff like that so that's what the
first idea and I thought alright so i'm
going to do some JavaScript cooking on
all the functions that ravello that you
forgot to show talking to try to you are
and all the traffic that and magic that
was looking it looks like that if you
want you guys I'm not Justin Darcy
programmer this may look at the way it
works of self-efficacy is no replacing
the original function with a rapper that
lobster request responses and optionally
call so it will function and response
back to the product that's that's the
skeleton of it so I'm but this code I
loaded up a particular it's like it and
this is I think student-athletes going
to need to know so first phase predict
there's not much good here of regular
website may have a small i think that if
injected somewhere or a small charge
pipe that runs an injection ice cream
but basically not much obfuscation
really into line treatment of course
it's hidden somewhere so that's easy to
get fast then we enter the series of
gates like in a conventional earlier
today our kids are meant to send your
traffic to exploit kit doesn't want to
target think about it and inflated
infrastructure that you don't want
exposed to any random person any
animation request so they are decently
to make sure it's just redirects that
unwanted traffic out of its likeit's
past the way the gates do this is
firstly the use flying objects there is
going to be proud of in between all the
finger-pointing its kind of four V's
it's going to look for sandbox
environment it's even closer look for
headers process in some cases in
addition to services a landslide chicks
it has some server side chicks there are
exploit kits that are known to target
specific countries there are exploiting
its likeit's that exclude certain set of
countries that they know their they have
risked getting prosecuted i would
imagine a lot of IP ranges are excluded
so you find that if you're running if
it's dry too scared to reach out to
these access problem it abuse you want
to get the real leader so there's not
suicide chicks in today's schedule and
this is where you start seeing a lot of
fortification and encryption let's take
an example so this is again the field of
each code of as you can see there's this
whole span element which is hidden and
has some code that looks really
different from the rest of the book and
then there's this JavaScript that's
highly appreciated
I don't think you can look at our script
until I find out what's going on but one
thing i can highlight here is that it is
it defines a lot of variables and
assigned character value to it you want
to end its not depending where they will
be no particular manner to make up a
string of code and basically evaluated
after two rounds of the Opposition
remember it's called starts to look like
this it's being processed in the pantry
as you would imagine it's going to look
for the user agent and look for IE
soft-top strengthen this but what i want
to highlight here is the first line
which initializes are variable using
windows sidebar and windows chrome
objects now windows sidebar is only
available in firefox and window the
chrome is only in chrome so if any of
these
six are not under find the value is not
here and subsequently the court failed
to decrypt once we get past the brothers
fingerprinting we get to the description
face and this is the Holocaust looks
like the first line has the key
it's second and you can see it is
putting the code from the Spanish meant
the description doing is a very typical
of string manipulation where you have
alternate calls to bring got from calc
road and calico dad and finally once you
get adequate strength it's passed onto a
function constructor function countries
such a fridge our function prototype in
Java is that function constructor that
takes a string argument and returns a
function that he was that quote so
that's that hella cute and that quote
again looks like very similar to this
solid redirect to the expected landing
page
let's look at one more example this is
rigged the area version that came out
after it it's a newer expect get this is
quite get it does something more
it looks for 600 synchronicities and at
heinz probability of about bothering
firefox are chrome or I and then to
attend it calculates whether it's really
i er into the pot and better that it
makes a decision on whether to reject to
the exploit kit are not so our first big
have some drawbacks it would work great
so what have you learnt firstly we need
to replicate I window object really want
to look like I so literally I enumerated
all the properties in IE with objects
and replicate that in Firefox as
exciting as some cold on how to do that
secondly our function hooking could
should should go
sure we should be hooking onto more
functions little equal why not leave it
may make the output more night here but
you catch more stuff so fucking function
for tonight's Don manipulation of sting
migration even handlers just added a lot
of more functional things together
constantly you know thank you for the
food earlier and lastly and we thought
you thought we know that navigator
object that's another subject that I've
seen you heavily to detect browser so
when the Navigator has always Navigator
has like in mind is that I used offered
to see what about it's running speaking
off modifying an object look like
something else
this is how actually hooking looks like
you could define a defined Gator object
function on an object on a particular
attribute and that function gets called
anytime that attribute its axis so this
gives you the hook into a Texas you can
choose to return a different values to
hide it
do whatever you want with those
particular attributes so once we have
this particular code is played the organ
chord run through this JavaScript look
exact a little of their I actually
removed arguments and resolution to make
it fit in a single slide but think about
this in a single second of execution
that some of course you get settled call
stack that you can make sense of you
understand what's happening here
that's the first win some exploit kits
go a step further they use plugins and
activex activists against to look for
this particular code example is from
magnitude I think and it's looking for
kaspersky of activated objects
similarly there is another one ability
in excellent job with the water whenever
the next module 4i even below where you
could load an excellent repast red color
and the massage and look for five hearts
and other the other additional letters
you can find out whether particular fine
particles are not and this will use
heavily to look for drivers to look for
a sandbox environment to look for a visa
architects so with such objects we need
to sort of introspect a little harder
that's where rocky objects come into
picture rocky objects basically the name
suggests arm and a model little rocky to
a particular object you can define
handles that are caused any time of
particular operation is performed on an
object if your application programmer
this is like distance so here's a simple
example of a genetic activity object you
can define gettin my function to look
for actual access and functional parts
but you can take the idea further for
facility for eczema Dom objects and
implement exact interface often activity
object so far
excellent tom i implemented Lord XML
attribute and return a function for the
party for that but if you actually
access and i was able to capture all the
findings that exploit kit towards
looking for
so that gives us the ability ok so
fucking good measure of add image of
human behavior you could insert
regulating set to move the mouth insert
keyboard keyboard events and art events
and and have looked like this and Human
Human there so but all that code and
again this is like I was the final ends
of hockey code you have a call stack of
whatever happens in a browser you have
the attribute exercises
overall this call stack we get to see
what plugins and what activex the
Dodgers will be part if we have to find
any of political accurate program to the
proper interface we see exactly
interaction with its rugged we get
access to the cookies we get access Dom
so we can extract iframes objects you
know except the artifacts objects right
and for all the bands coming and finally
we get access to education requests that
we can go management body found a way
so what can we do with this output at
the least we can write signatures and
these are all over the place the
signatures here are from actual that we
use in this project and literally you
can search the 64 these delicious and
find existing expected but this pretty
with free but lets you take that idea
and fathers you can write signatures on
our arguments to document.write
arguments to functions for like 20 force
description data is available to rent
images on I haven't tried this but I
really want to try writing to me picking
out what decryption keys i use and reuse
of the encryption keys aquatic for kids
but you know signatures are brothers
it's an arms race with my writing
nature's also retain the court so we
could do better than that
so here are some of the features that we
started collecting on the data to be
able to classify their website is
definitely bag or something
issues going on and if it looks
suspicious maybe we should do next two
or ten marks so invisible of the screen
text box with your heart and with the
entropy 20 years is a telltale sign up
intricate code order it cause to think
manipulation functions like these are
heavily for the capture function
contractors means quite fishy activity
object system for AV definitely bad
excellent are looking for five parts
like eczema dog
loading xml let's start with red
wonderful massage differently back and
not be you could look at the JavaScript
code and be able to find out whether
this is officer gated many fights are in
civic our scripts i did a simple program
analysis and was able to classified
really well but if you have your
machining shops of cognition and your
network would do this really well
so what do we have here so this is a new
approach that you can use to build a
fast low interaction honeypot that add
the leaf does everything that a GSR
javascript your facility to understand
what's happening on a browser while and
export code is executing you can prove
your way through a gate you can and you
can extract the exploit artifacts the
flash fires and adobe experts for out of
and scanning from violence and such and
you can have skin look for signatures
for known expected and that
[Applause]
any questions
alright so i haven't yet for the cool
sites on the penis but i will put it up
there are in discussions about the last
quote over there so i'll put it up there
so I bet you know what I'm going to say
next
on behalf of b-sides and fit we'd like
to thank you