welcome to a decepticon and autobot walk
into a bar this is a new python tool for
enhanced opsec
i'm joe gray coming to you from uh
almost on the other side of the world
i'm here in the united states
uh so this is going to be a project that
i
took on to enhance
my own comprehension and understanding
of
both python artificial intelligence to a
degree
machine learning and natural language
processing i wrapped it all up in a way
that uh will allow a positive outcome to
occur so i'm going to go ahead and
kill my camera now uh since i've been
told that i have a
face made for our radio
uh that continuing um about me by day
i'm a senior ocean specialist complex
i have some experience with python
scripting
i'm incredibly interested in uh the data
sciences
uh as i stated previously i do
frequently compete in the trace labs
ocean search party
or missing person ctf whichever you know
it by
my team the password inspection agency
actually just won the
last competition that occurred as part
of defcon
with that uh with a lot of what i do
regarding
ocean uh i i look at the yen to the yang
of ocean which would be opsec
i also have advisory uh volunteer roles
with
both the national child protection task
force and operation safe escape
operation safe escape being in bold
because honestly that's the organization
that benefits most from
decepticon a few things that i'm not
i'm not a programmer or a developer
in nature i'm by far not a mathematician
or a data scientist
nor am i an expert when talking about
things
dealing with trafficking or domestic
violence
it's something that i'm concerned with
that's something that
i definitely have uh interest
in making a positive outcome but i'm by
no stretch of the imagination an expert
so before we get started i have a few
definitions for us to go over
just so that we can level the playing
field with uh everything that will be
talked about in this presentation first
we have oscent open source intelligence
that's basically
information gathered from public sources
in an intelligence context we have opsec
operation security basically that's
taking steps to
obscure hide or masquerade
information about you and what you are
doing
so that adversaries or
other concerned parties will have
trouble finding you
or making any determinations in terms of
the reliability of the data
i'm a huge fan of implementing
disinformation and deception through
that
in fact implementing disinformation and
deception to enhance your opsec
is a term i've been calling that
decepticon for the last couple of years
since the name of the bot
machine learning that's just the study
of math and algorithms
to improve the automation uh
via learning if you will uh
so that it assists us in
developing algorithms uh to be able to
uh learn if you will uh based on the
outcome
of the data we can also do predictions
and decisions based on that
uh with decepticon it's mostly focusing
on
predictions uh data science is an
amalgam of several disciplines
that seeks to study uh the relationship
between
uh data structures
and the processes and algorithms to help
us gain
insight from the data i like to think of
it uh from the perspective of
data science seeks to identify patterns
that are it
not visible to the human eye or the
human mind
we have artificial intelligence yes i
will admit that's a term that
has been kind of ruined by vendors as of
late
but it's the study of intelligence shown
by machines
and programs to
attempt to mimic that natural
intelligence
natural intelligence being the
intelligence shown by humans or
animals and then finally we've got gpu
that's the graphics processing unit it's
a specialized
system on board many computers in fact
any computer that has any sort of
graphics has one
but in this scenario we're using it to
accelerate the processing
of images or video more specifically
it's used within
machine learning to speed up processing
nvidia uh has some really cool toys for
that
so the problem one of the leading ways
that adversaries find their way
into the lives or back into their lives
of their victims
is social media so
what is an adversary that could be a
malicious person
seeking financial gain that could be
someone just seeking to harm someone
else
abusers traffickers political opponents
will do that
uh in the united states uh we've got uh
the possible apocalypse coming up um in
uh on the first tuesday in november with
the election
i really hate to toss the term nation
state out but uh
depending on the person's threat profile
a nation state could legitimately be an
adversary for them
and then they you also have what i call
adversaries of opportunity
and that would be in the case where
someone has really bad opsec
and the adversary's just out there
looking and just happens to come across
that particular person and notices
hey this account is hemorrhaging
information let's exploit it and see
what we can get from it
so when we talk about victims they could
be public figures such as politicians or
executives
obviously there are some companies out
there
whose executives are universally a
target because of what the company does
or who the company does business with
and then we have victims of domestic
abuse and or trafficking
many times they don't have much say so
in the matter whatsoever
and then we also have people with poor
or misguided opsec
for example i was debating with a friend
from when i was in the navy
on facebook a while back uh about
privacy and he's like oh i don't have to
worry about this
i use a vpn and uh i was like oh cool
which one
and he's like oh it's a free one it's
this and i don't recall
what it was exactly but i pointed out
that with
a vpn especially that's one of the
products that you definitely want to pay
for
because you have some expectation of
support
that's not to say that your data won't
get sold
but you have a more legitimate claim
when it comes to that and oftentimes if
you don't pay for the product you are
the product
references for that see facebook and
google
thankfully for many of you you're
subjected to gdpr
so you have a certain level of privacy
and protection that
i only wish i had and uh to be honest
i had coveted not happened and i had
actually traveled to gerdinia for the
conference
i was going to hop on to some wi-fi
connections around the area
and uh use the right to be forgotten
because what i've learned is
many many platforms when you go to opt
out of things they don't do any
validation checking to verify you're a
citizen
of the european union they just look at
the i p address oh well this is coming
from the eu
so um kind of bummed about that but
uh life goes on and there's always next
year
and if not next year the year after and
eventually it will become safe for us to
all travel again
so um after i rebutted
that to my friend he he was like well i
used this dns service as well and
i hadn't heard of it but i looked it up
and it looked pretty solid and i
explained okay well
you still need to implement things like
https
if you're doing certain things you might
want to use tor you may want to do this
you may want to do that
and it turned into a really good private
conversation between my friend and i and
he learned a lot and i i learned quite a
bit myself
so as we dissect some advice from an
opsec perspective
if someone's being harassed or stalked
some of the advice i've seen tossed
around is
well just uh just abandon the account
well that's not always feasible to be
honest
um and with that being said
it could cue the adversary uh that the
account
has been abandoned uh it could
also um lead them to go looking for
alternative accounts
and if someone's using accounts
that doesn't have the person's real name
on it especially with facebook
i don't know if this is something that
you encounter uh in europe
but in the united states if you create a
facebook
account and they don't believe you're
using your real name they will prompt
you for a driver's license
and if you don't want to provide that
they just straight up shut the account
down
so if someone's trying to evade an
adversary and creates an account under a
fake
name a fictitious name
then that person could report the
account if they report it enough
then that account will be prompted for
submitting some form of identification
and when they fail to do so the account
gets burned
let's face it some people have to use
social media for work
me working in the ocean field i have to
use social media for work
that also being said i don't have to use
legitimate accounts
whereas some people have to use
either to interact with customers or to
run a business page
or something to that effect and i mean
i'm just going to be real here
why should a victim live in fear because
someone uh cannot respect their wishes
and their privacy and at the same time
some victims just
are not aware of the adversary until
it's too late
so continuing to dissect this if the
abuser wants to continue trauma
they can create fake accounts of their
own
they may leverage friends or friends of
friends that may have access to see
the victim's posts as i stated before
they may report those alternative
accounts for being fake
there was a case just about a week or
two ago
there was a young man a college student
in india who published a medium article
talking about how he had a crush that
ghosted him 10 years ago and he used
ocean techniques
to find her he made contact with her via
instagram
and there were some cringy things in the
blog post
up to that point but uh
as soon as they finished their
conversation on instagram he immediately
attempted a password reset to get an
email address
and then he continued uh trying to get
stuff with the email address to the
point of
trying to reset the password for the
email address so he could find out what
kind of phone she used
so a lot of uh methods with that and
honestly both of those there are
intelligence
uh attributes to attempting the password
reset stuff
but know that proper osant
typically does not allow leaving a trace
behind or
any opportunity for detection and that's
a little bit more hands-on and active
than what we typically deal with
with ocean at the end of the day
companies can still be
exploited so as an investigator honestly
if i come across someone that i'm
investigating and i don't find any
social media presence i get a lot more
skeptical
over that account uh certain things
playing in such as age location
demographics and things like that
but generally speaking if
you have one or two accounts under your
name i'm a lot less skeptical than if
you don't have any
and as i stated before why not have that
autonomy and agency over what is posted
with
minimal effort so here's links to
the code for decepticon uh
it is uh on github my username is
josephus and it's decepticon underscore
bot
uh i'll share that link again later in
the presentation as well
so the code itself is written in python
i have
two current versions only one is
released at this time
one is leveraging tensorflow and cross
i'm using the nvidia port of tensorflow
version 2.2
the other version is written with pi
torch but i'm not discussing it in this
presentation because i still need to
work out quite a few kinks with it
i use pandas to organize the data and
data frames
it's just an easier way for me to get
the data put across
that and honestly the books that i was
using to
learn about automation uh machine
learning and all that stuff using python
uh they heavily advocated the use of
pandas
so i went along with it for that and i
just it kind of stuck
so within the code uh
keras is used to implement a long short
term memory model
which is used to predict sequences of
the text and
then thus generate the text
so it's a long short term memory model
in short it's a type of recurrent neural
network
more specifically a neural network
too far a recurrent neural network is
something that takes past decisions
into mind and that's going to influence
the outcome with that
they can also remember previous things
learned so in order to do that
if the model is not actively running you
just have to save it to
a specific file so that it can be
reloaded the next time that
the code runs and the model needs to
execute
the reason these are very useful for
things like
text speech and images is that a
recurrent learner
neural network is not of a fixed vector
size
and as we know within natural speech
we don't have fixed vectors for example
if i greet you
you may say hello good morning good
afternoon
how are you get out of my face all those
things have different
lengths different characters different
lengths of words
so we can't say there's a fixed vector
size for that
so a long short term memory model in
that
in that specific vein seeks to learn
order dependencies and do sequence
prediction
so that's very important for generating
text
and honestly it doesn't even care what
language the text is in
so you could i've not tested this but
you could put it
against uh text from any language and it
should be able to do that same
order of dependencies and sequence
prediction
so again because of the prediction and
dependency
analysis that makes lstms very
lucrative for natural language
processing
another way i've not fully researched
this yet either but another way you
could accomplish this may be markov
chains
and me not having that solid math
background i'm still working on bringing
up the rear in terms of
taking some math classes that uh
honestly are at the undergraduate level
i'm basically going to satisfy the
requirements of an undergrad in math
uh before i start two additional
master's programs
so how does the code itself work
basically i use the python
twitter package and the twitter api to
authenticate to twitter and pull the
tweets down for the user
by default the tool only reads the
particular user's tweets but
i have modified the code uh if you look
on the github repo
it is actually under the sock version
uh where you can read anyone's tweets as
long as the
account tied to the api can view them so
if someone's blocked you
or has a protected account you can't see
it you can't you can't read from their
tweets but anybody else you can
so from there we capture the text the
time of the tweet
and we measure lexical diversity
basically that's the ratio of the words
used
uh compared to the length of the text
right now it's not really that important
but in
subsequent versions i've got some
revisions
planned i don't know when i'm going to
get to them because i'm in the process
of rewriting some training that i offer
as the ascension
but i have plans for assessing say time
of day
and other things including also adding
replies retweets and
responding to uh messages
i also have plans to do a fork of it um
called intercepticon that would actually
identify
other bot accounts and then with lexical
diversity that could also be used to
potentially identify
uh if the tweet was written
from someone that's a non-native speaker
of a particular language
especially if they used like say google
translate to convert
russian to english or
mandarin chinese to spanish or something
to that effect
um from there we tokenize it we i
tokenize it by words
i've i've done limited testing with
doing it by sentence
but it just didn't really uh jive at
that time so i need to do some more work
with that
and then we add it to the corpus within
machine learning
and natural language processing a corpus
is basically a fancy word
or not so fancy word for basically a bag
of words this is the input text this is
what we are using to
train it with uh from there we get some
standard stats like standard deviations
and mean and then we also calculate the
post interval
then we move into the generate module
that's where we establish our
vector sizes and sequences since we
don't have a fixed
size and then we also measure the unique
patterns
in the corpus we set up the files
associated with the model
in both json and h5 we define the model
and the associated parameters such as we
are doing an lstm
uh model it's going to be 160 bits
we are setting our sequence at 500 and
we want to run for seven epochs
uh from there we go into the trainer
module that's going to create some
pseudo-random seed to begin the tweet
generation from
and then the next module will execute
the model and assess the predictions
we work through a logic check and
basically what that does
is through my testing if you look on my
c underscore three p
joe account uh back in
um i think june and july you'll see a
bunch of odd tweets
that are nothing but apostrophe comma um
combinations uh repetitively with like
two or three words in them
uh that's because decepticon i was
originally training decepticon against
that account
and it was just picking up on that
and it became problematic so i within
the logic check i filter out
uh any links any mentions
any hashtags uh any known characters
that i saw
that uh would come across and
make it a little bit more glaringly
obvious that
this wasn't written by a person after
all that's done we tweet
and then after that we wait and
that's going to be based on the uh post
interval
now we are coming up on the
demonstration piece
so uh bear with me while i get that
pulled up
let me get it here i
just had it i had it loaded previous
but no big deal
let me swap screens with it
[Music]
can everyone see my video
so at this rate we are just uh kicking
off
the code so it's just running
it'll be just a moment uh this is kind
of a little bit of a long demo but i'm
going to talk through it
uh so there we see it's connected to the
twitter it's receiving the tweets
it's tokenizing it at this point uh we
are able to see
links so these are all the twitter links
we can look at mentions
so these are the accounts that uh the
accounts that were
uh observed mentioned
and then we start the in-depth analysis
of the number of characters
so just doing some more stuff with that
we see here
it has identified the tensorflow device
and the physical gpu
and it started the first epoch
this is just an interval of analysis so
this is going to take just a second this
entire process took
about half an hour total so
there are parts of this where i applied
a filter to make it go a lot faster
so here we've already started that first
interval uh as we can see here
it takes um in the case it takes about
160 seconds
so right at two and a half minutes to do
this so this is going to speed up
at this rate this is just looking at the
analysis of my jetson nano
platform that i'm running this on here
we see the gpu is almost pegged out
um and then as we go through everything
here
uh we can see that this was as it was
initializing the gpu device
it stopped and then as the analysis
started it's kicked back up
take a quick look at some cpu data
so nothing too exciting here and then
this is just looking at the memory
notice i've got 50 gigs of swap
after you've ran the code for a few
times and you're in waiting mode
you're going to need that because you're
going to run out of ram and you need
that swap to be able to drop it over
so i have a 256 gig
micro sd card that the operating
system's running on as well as
um about a one terabyte solid state
drive that i've got an expansion board
connecting with but we'll look at that a
little bit later
here we have some control information
this is where we can control the fan
and then this is just some data here so
um we go back here we're gonna see that
this
speeds up tremendously again
so i did an eight times speed up
on this um and then we're going to
shift over notice the host names george
george jetson
uh so here we see that the gpu is about
to drop off
and then what we will notice is once the
gpu usage drops off tremendously
that that's in that's indicative of it
moving from one epoch
to another
there it just dropped down pretty
tremendously
and then as we shift back over notice
we've started a new epoch
so there that goes i'm just gonna
move this along a bit so number three
number four number five
number six
number six is almost done so we'll go
here
i'm gonna get close to the end of number
seven
okay so it should be good here and then
uh
the uh the timing will realign
since i had that initial technical
difficulty
um just want to make sure so here we see
the random seed has been created and
we're initializing the process to create
a tweet
so right here is what it tweeted so if
we can actually see this on the account
uh which i've already got the query set
up so i'll show you uh basically this
just from one of the six accounts that
it's following this is something
basically saying for vuln disclosure
anti-vaxxers vaccines cause autism me
y'all are idiots trump promises a covet
vaccine before the election
me decepticon how fitting
uh so we've got a sleep interval here uh
it's gonna sleep for 76 seconds
that's for the purpose of demonstration
i actually altered the post enter the
lines of code dealing with post interval
normally this would be uh the post
interval uh
minus um between zero and 480 seconds
just for
a slight pseudo-randomization
and we're going to see here in just a
second the process kicks right back
off tokenizes tweets does everything and
then
creating the model and that's pretty
much how the code runs
um to actually look at the code
um here's the requirements file so this
is everything that we need to install
uh to get it to run this is a file where
we input our twitter api keys
uh obviously i've not saved the file
because i just cut my own keys out
but that's how we go about doing it
and i probably just closed
i did
you reopen
and because there's so many imports i
didn't want to eat up this many lines of
code so i just do an import
uh or i do one single import here
and import everything over here so just
a few things like
random and json here there's pandas
there's numpy
tensorflow several cross things so
sequential lstm uh so that we can get
all that we have the tokenizer here as
well
uh there's h5 uh i've got natural
language toolkit but i don't really use
it right now
aside from the word tokenized thing and
then import the twitter package and
the twitter api keys so here's the code
we do the import we set the encoding
and then we have all those definitions
but here at the bottom
we download stop words that's not used
in this current version
uh because stop words would be things
like and
the or it would make it kind of awkward
so i've not implemented that part yet
but i still download it just for the
sake of having it
we get the current directory we check
for the presence of a subdirectory
called files if not we make it if it
exists we continue
we set the stop words but we don't use
them again there's the physical device
so we look for gpus
if it works great if not we continue uh
here's the
structure to connect to the api so it's
just giving the keys
we're setting tweet mode to extended so
that we get all 280 characters
and if we don't set sleep on rate limit
to true we're going to limit ourselves
to between 24 and 32 tweets depending on
how
fast our system connects so
takes a little bit longer but we can
pull down up to 200 tweets with the free
api
we've set the model to sequential and
then results that's just to get the user
time on with the api information next we
move to login
so we're going to go back all the way to
the top
and from here there's connected
retrieving tweets
when we set the global variable for data
frame
make sure we move into the correct
directory here are the users that the
code as it's running right now
are evaluating i've got consent of all
these users
uh four of them are men who are women
some people live in the same area some
people don't so there's a little bit of
diversity of that obviously it's not an
accurate sample of the population but
i just wanted six accounts to work with
in this case it's creating a
files underscore sock dot csv because
this is kind of operating as if it's a
sock account
we uh create the data frame uh with the
columns of tweets times like school
diversity and the user
the version that just reads from your
account does not have the user column
and then we move into tokenization if we
have
the csv file there then basically what
we're going
to do is we're going to import it and
then move on
lexical diversity there's the
measurement going into tokenization
we have bag of hash bag of
mentions and links so that's going to be
hashtags mentions and links
just capturing all of them here we have
a for loop for each user
we pull everything down we're not
focusing on retweets
or replies right now uh and then from
there
we get the full text we split that i've
got regular expressions to be able to
put things into the appropriate bags
um and then we move into the hopper
from here we replicate a little bit of
that effort
and then we have the tweet time so that
we can create it
put it into epoch time so it's a linear
time from january 1st 1970
that allows us to measure the
distance between tweets and pull that
standard deviation
uh and then from there we're gonna go
into the sorter
which is where we will actually
um iterate and uh
tokenize so here we're using the word
tokenizer
we put everything into a single um list
and then we tokenize it put that into
the bag of words
uh we write it to the csv before we uh
we write everything that's in the data
frame to the csv
before we move on collect our stats
so here we've got our lexical diversity
we get the mean
and the standard deviation for lexical
diversities
as well as times uh post interval
that's nothing more than the standard
deviation of time
so standard deviation in between the
epoch times that's how i
arrive at post interval
next we do our frequency analysis
and then we go into generate at this
rate we convert all the characters to
numbers so that it fits into the lstm
correctly uh
from there we define our x and y
sequence length of 500
that's something that i toyed with in
terms of shorter and longer numbers 500
for this seems to be the sweet spot so
then we just append
things to the xy plots we determine
the number of patterns based on the
length of the x data
and then there we move into pre-model
and training
so pre-modeling this is just checking to
see if we already have a model defined
so there's the h5 and the json
uh we can load um and then
once we see that we take the x and the y
put it in seven epochs batch size of
eight
that's just going to be the size of the
stuff that's put in
if you have it too large it will crash
if you have it too small it'll take
forever
the checkpoint that's what we saw with
all the epochs
we defined the loss model as categorical
cross-entropy
the optimizer is rms prop um to be
honest i'm not 100
sure on that side uh i looked at the
various options and basically ran a b
testing to see what got the most
accuracy
and then from there we move into the
actual modeling
so we define 160 bit model
input shapes return the sequences we
do a few iterations of that uh the
dropout
that's at 60 i could have left this last
value at 60
but i put it at 40 just to see if
anything would change it did increase
accuracy a little bit
um and then from there we compile
there's our checkpoints that's what we
see when it comes up
and then here's where it actually goes
on to the gpu
and what we actually see on the screen
from here once it's done uh we will
convert all the numbers in the lstm back
to characters
uh and then that's where the random seed
is created
uh from there we will
go through and basically do a for loop
and just reassemble everything
uh that's where we're gonna get our
results in terms of
what it's actually saying here's the
logic check and the cleanup pattern
notice all the stuff it's just removing
um and then here's where it goes to
sleep in the repeater
so there's the normal sleeping interval
right now i've got sleeping on intervals
of 40 to 80 seconds
so realistically this could get two
maybe
three tweets out and then it's just
gonna wait
at the end of that time it wakes back up
and it starts the process
all over again so
that's pretty much the process there so
about the project itself it started
around december 2019
i ran into some hurdles shiny objects
delays etc
i had written some things in python like
wikileaker and some other the recon
module recon ng module associated with
it
um but i am by no means a pretty python
coder
um i am not even really
an efficient one to be honest as i
stated before i've been reading about it
and i was trying to implement some
things i was working
with uh safe escape on some stuff and
i wrong so basically
i decided that this would be a good
practical explanation
um as usual the project stalled around
march around
covid season uh and then i
was on a podcast of sorts and someone
was talking about the
jetson platform this might solve my
problem
so i ported the code over started
playing with the tool it worked really
well
uh i was doing it the original
development in a virtual machine
i mean i gave it eight gigs of ram and
three cores it was on a radeon gpu
on my mac and it wasn't efficient
basically each epoch took about 55
minutes
as opposed to under three minutes
so this is the jetson platform on the
left we see
the jetson nano and then we have the usb
3.1 bridge to connect to the t300 board
that's the expansion board that allows
me to run the solid state drive
on the right that's just a regular uh
jetson nano board
they're fairly inexpensive uh i've got
the t300 board in
this particular case i don't have the
antennas or the camera on it
and i have about 250 us dollars wrapped
up in it
but basically it's got 128 cuda core gpu
uh
four gigs of ram and it's running a quad
core arm processor
so nothing to scoff at but
it's by no means a super computer i like
it because it's external to my regular
host so i can continue to do
other things on my computer while
testing this
and i'm able to have that enhanced gpu
as well
i've looked into hosting gpu
processing in the cloud and it is not
cheap
so my lessons learned data science is
not a walk in the park especially if you
lack that heavy math background
honestly pie torch is faster but i've
not been able to replicate the
reliability
and if you've seen the tweets there
that's to be lacking so pi torch is even
worse
uh if you're testing this on your
regular account uh make sure
you've tweeted frequently and something
of substance as of
late uh all i had been tweeting had been
uh announcements for my upcoming
training
and my tweet interval was 12 minutes or
i'm sorry 12 days
so what i ended up having to do to try
to influence it
i broke uh several poems and songs
such as all-star are never going to give
you up as well as the raven
wasteland and we wear the mask into 280
character chunks and tweeted them so
that i could influence
that post interval and have uh
more information but
that worked and it created some
interesting tweets
another thing you should be cognizant of
is if you're testing something like this
on your regular account
people are people are probably going to
start unfollowing you
and they will probably uh be a little
bit angry with you
so i highly recommend testing it on an
account that
uh you don't use as heavily like what
i've done
honestly there was a lot of a b testing
and hypothesizing with this
and just know that around 200 tweets
that only have 280 characters that is a
very small data set for an lstm for
example
the book i was working through was using
the book of genesis uh as
a corpus as well as a few other books
like harry potter
and the chamber of secrets i actually
was the sorcerer's stone but
nevertheless
something a lot larger than you know
a possibility of uh 56 000 characters
that's pretty short
so limitations right now i've only
written the code to make use of the
the gpus and cuda course if you do it on
a vm or a server it's going to be very
time consuming
like i said gpu in the cloud is very
expensive
and the model is dependent upon what
your account has posted if you're
setting this up
for uh some violence and they have never
posted
you're going to want to use the sock
version to have it pull from some other
accounts
if the account was just wiped out it's
going to need to be the same thing
but you're going to need to get some
things posted to have something to work
off of