all right
uh good morning everyone from chicago uh
really happy to uh joining uh good
morning everyone from chicago
uh really happy to uh join you guys via
recorder presentation i'm on the middle
of some paternity leave uh so i wasn't
able to do this live hopefully i'll be
able to
uh join for some question answers
afterwards but really excited to take
you guys on a cyber safari
looking at under examined threat actors
from the global threat landscape
and so typically discussions around
state nexus threat actors focus on
bears from russia pandas from china
colomas from north korea
and kittens from iran
and those are great and they tend to be
high profile but the global threat
landscape includes enough activity from
the cranes of south korea leopards of
pakistan buffalos of vietnam and more
to constitute and be worth the whole
cyber safari of underexamined threat
actors
this subset of adversaries represents
the proliferation of how more and more
governments are using
state nexus actors and increasingly
conducting
targeted intrusions inten on
capitalizing on the asymmetric
advantages offered by those cyber
operations
by examining these actors their activity
their victims
we can see the diversity of their
motivations different methodologies and
capabilities
they use and their targets this allows
for more accurate and complete
understanding of how truly global
the threat landscape is and subsequently
better tailor our threat models
and defensive postures for
the blue teamers that are watching this
hopefully you'll be able to improve
your threat models especially for
regional threats and
for uh your red teamers hopefully um you
see some really interesting campaigns
that you might give
might give you some ideas uh for your
next engagement
uh we won't be covering any of the big
four that we just talked about
um because there's already a ton of
excellent reporting on them we're also
not going to be covering five eyes
because i don't think they actually do
any offensive operations
that i know about at least uh so who i
am
my name is yoshi uh also known i also go
by josh
uh safari guy today i currently work
in healthcare cyber through intelligence
and have a couple certifications
my background's actually in political
science international relations
where i really enjoy the geopolitical
aspect to the threat intelligence
landscape formerly with the fbi before i
joined
healthcare and you can follow me on
twitter if you
so desire so as we get started
there's a lot of different models when
you talk about adversaries
the diamond model is one of the oldest
and in my opinion
one of the better ways to start thinking
about these thread actors
and how to understand and cluster them
so when we
talk about the diamond model the first
thing we usually talk about is
infrastructure
infrastructure just means anything from
the email accounts used for spear
phishing
command control servers or domains maybe
even their ip addresses
really that tangible those tangible
things
next is victim so when we talk about
victim i think victim can be more
diverse than people typically think
it's not just the organization or
company that's targeted but also maybe
what
individual position are they targeting
cfos are they targeting hr departments
um are they targeting research and
development
and then also specific data are they
after payment card data are they after
um different um
research uh for example 19 vaccines
or are they um just after anything and
everything
uh and then also the vertical so are
they targeting
um aerospace engineering are they
targeting healthcare
that's the thing we look at a lot uh in
my current current role
and then next is capability so
capabilities are usually dependent on
technical intelligence like malware
reversing and ties well to a model like
miters attack
i think that really helps put a common
language on what capabilities
are and what actors are doing not it
doesn't cover everything but for the
most part gives a common language for
both red teams and blue teams
and finally it's adversary depending on
who you're talking to
and or working for adversary can range
from the person behind the keyboard
the organization that they work for
whether it's a front company or actual
state military unit or even the customer
who said hey
we have a requirement for this
information and sponsored the campaign
or intrusion
for that information again that varies a
lot based off of who you're working with
so when we talk about that adversary i
think it's also important to talk about
different
aspects of national responsibility so
starting at the bottom here we have
state prohibited
that's where the national government
will help stop the third party attack
good example that is going to be in the
united states you see people that are
arrested extradited or prosecuted for
conducting
cyber operations next is state
prohibited but inadequate
the national government is cooperative
and wants to stop the third parties but
they're
unable to they just don't have the
capability personnel
resources or sometimes even authorities
the next is state ignored so the
national government knows about the
third party attacks but it's unwilling
to take any official action
and one caveat here when i say tax i i
mean cyber operations
in general not limited to just
cna attacks just overall cyber
operations both espionage related
financially motivated
and then also those destructive attacks
next we have state encouraged so third
parties control and conduct the attack
but the national government encourages
them as a model
matter of policy a great example of this
are the iranian hacktivists
who are defacing web pages uh leaving
nationalistic
defacements but aren't operating
strictly on the behalf of the iranian
government
um next would be state shapes so third
parties control and conduct the attack
maybe as part of a front company of some
sort
but the national government does provide
some support to that
front company payment infrastructure
protection that sort of thing
state coordinated uh the national
government coordinates with third party
attacks
by suggesting operational details and
that's really where you get into that
those front companies that are
operating on behalf of the government
so next uh very similar is state ordered
uh the national government directs
third-party proxies to conduct the
attack on its behalf
very similar to state coordinated um
just
suggestion versus direction uh next
would be state road conducted so these
are the out of control
elements of cyber forces on the national
governments conducting the attack
a good example this would be
freelancers for say north korea or china
who conduct intrusions for the
government during the day
and then line their own pocketbooks at
night
for some financially motivated attacks
next is state executed where the
national government is conducting the
attacks
using cyber forces under their direct
control uh uniform military and or
uh intelligence services actually doing
the attacks or operations
and then the the pyramid or the apex if
you will
would be national government attacking
using integrated third party proxies and
government forces
so this is just a quick look our safari
will include looking at the netherlands
france spain turkey israel
united arab emirates uzbekistan pakistan
india south korea
vietnam and some south american sets
so as we get started um
we're going to start off with one of the
more advanced groups that's been
publicly talked about
if you ask most people to talk about
some of the best attackers in the world
most people won't mention the
netherlands but in 2018 a dutch
newspaper
revealed one of the most sophisticated
and successful hacking operations
which is against the apt cozy bear
apt-29
the dutch managed to get a clue into
cozy bear's operations they literally
identified the building they were
sitting in
of course this was pre-coveted so there
was no work from home
and based off their good preparation and
planning they were able to do more than
just pop boxes on the network
but they're able to hack into the
security cameras and record everyone
coming and going from the operation
so not only did they have access to the
network to identify
attacks they also identified individual
hackers and officials coming going from
the building
so this allowed this access allowed the
dutch
according to this newspaper to tip off
the americans once cozy breasts started
attacking
the state department and they gave them
information about russia capabilities
c2 infrastructure their targets etc
additionally because they had those
security cameras they were allowed they
were able to
attribute cozy bear to the svr um based
off the intelligence officers that were
going to and from the building
and this is just one snapshot into what
an advanced actor could do
with the right opportunity preparation
and patience
and a really good attack
so next we have france which is babar or
animal farm originated in 2007
targeting iran syria mali malaysia and
others
it had a pretty diverse set of malware
and was extremely targeted compared to
some other
groups that have more wide range
animal farm was very targeted
one thing to note was that according to
french law french cyber command does
have authority to do offensive hacking
and sometimes will do so
so next we have spain which is known as
the mask of correcto
uh it started in 2007 attributed in 2014
over 380 victims identified 31 countries
targeted
including governments energy research
institutions
activists private equity firms now they
were discovered when they tried to
exploit a patched vulnerability in a
kaspersky product
and they actually shut down their
operations when they were sinkholed when
their
c2 infrastructure was sinkholed
attribution was identified based off of
who information who is information
as well as spanish language remnants in
their malware
and one thing before we go forward or
further i do reference a lot of
different
research from variety of groups uh
kaspersky eset
um crowdstrike a lot of uh good firms so
all of my sources will be cited in the
at the end uh please if you have any
interest in reading the actual reports
please go and read them there's some
excellent reporting
that people have done
so next we're going to talk about turkey
this is actually a lot of turkey
and so when we talk about turkey the
first third actor we're going to talk
about
is strong pity or prometheum
in december of 2016 microsoft released
reporting that indicated prometheum had
been operating since 2012.
they've been targeting both domestic and
international targets
um and microsoft
uh identified that they were targeting
specific individuals within a specific
area in europe
um their 2016 campaign included a zero
day in adobe and was actually delivered
via instant message client
strong pity has also been known to use
phishing links along with strategic web
compromising
or compromises or watering holes as the
initial inspection vector
interestingly enough they do also use
trojanized encrypters
and other apps particularly to target
users in italy and belgium
kaspersky did an excellent job
documenting
trovar cis the malware that was dropped
after the initial infection
by strong pity the malware is often
bundled with legitimate installers and
often include
includes lures in turkish this combined
with the local setting
of most of the victims helped attribute
them to turkey the 2016 campaign
also had multiple similarities with the
odium
a group that likely used finn fisher
malware for espionage purposes
and we'll talk about that a little bit
later
um so another really unique group coming
out of turkey is known as sea turtle
in april of 2019 uh cisco towels
reported on a group they identified as
sea turtle
the group targeted national security
organizations in the middle east and
north africa
and included cyprus greece iraq albania
egypt armenia uae jordan syria and
sweden
that's according to cisco and i think
reuters as well as domain tools put out
some great research on these guys
assuming they are guys let's see
so sea turtle executed what's known as
the first public example
of widespread dns hijacking they were
extremely successful by first targeting
third parties like dns registrars
telecommunication companies and isps
internet service providers once they
gained access to these targets
using mostly known vulnerabilities and
in some instances
phishing they were able to hijack the
dns of their primary targets which were
those national security organizations
by doing this they were able to redirect
legitimate users to active controlled
infrastructure
that allowed them to intercept and
harvest their credentials
according to routers credentials
included email services cloud storage
servers and online networks
redux based their attribution to sources
that cited three things first
victimology like we talked about
similarly similarities to past
campaigns as well as confidential
intelligence
and those are just two thoughts from
turkey that i find pretty interesting
so obviously there is a ton that can be
said about israeli cyber security
um one of the things i'll cover today is
just one example
fourth possibly fifth party collection
or what's known as hacking hackers so
the new york times report on the story
where
the israelis had hacked into kaspersky
to gather intelligence in 2015.
this campaign was identified as doogoo
2.0 by kaspersky
the israelis were allegedly able to
identify russian hackers inside of
kaspersky that were searching for
intelligence on american programs
so you have the israelis that identified
the russian hackers
that identified inside kaspersky
that was looking at american programs
the hacker store store stole passwords
and documents and screenshots
as well as emails related to case versus
apt work uh particularly those related
to the equation group
and region other targets of the
israeli campaign as identified by
kaspersky
uh included hotels uh based in the u.s
that were related to the u.n security
council negotiations on jp
koa which was the iran deal kaspersky
blog is really good
so recommend reading it if you're
interested in dooku 2.0
uh and then when you talk about israeli
cyber security uh it's also important to
talk about private companies in israel
uh and one of the best known is nso
nso is currently embroiled in a lawsuit
against facebook
for using a vulnerability in whatsapp
nso tools like phantom and pegasus
are only supposed to be used by state
ordered organizations for
counterterrorism and other missions
but vice has reported that human rights
dissidents journalists and political
opponents have also been targeted by
those
nso tools one of the reasons i think
it's interesting to bring this up is
that
when we talk about actual real campaigns
this is a great example of what to look
for
um some advice showed that some of the
domains used for lures appear to be
innocent unsubscribe links or other
facebook links
or links masquerading as facebook
the infrastructure was often procured
from cloud providers located in the
united states
so it looks pretty legitimate and it's
definitely something to watch
going forward as more information
informations revealed throughout the
court case
so next we have lebanon and lebanon is
really interesting
dark karakol is the name of the group
there so
the eff and lookout identified dark
karakol um
as in threat actor allegedly supporting
the general directorate of general
security
in lebanon
dark karakol was originally identified
in part because of the infrastructure
reused from operation manuel
uh which we'll briefly discuss later
dark karakol
is considered an apt for a couple
reasons the first being
numerous campaigns in parallel uh
hundreds of gigabytes of data
exfiltrated
and then the typical targets of
government military
utility financial institutions health
care manufacturers
exfiltrated data all that data included
documents call records recordings
contacts photos account information
an interesting thing about this is that
it was primarily mobile malware focused
as a primary attack platform so initial
access included the usual
phishing and social engineering but then
also included physical access to the
target devices which
is definitely something that's useful
for state nexus operations
paulus which is the malware used was a
trojanized and android apps as well
some finn fisher mower
was also used which is the operation
manuel
link other malware use included
banducrat and crossrat
while the infrastructure being used
seemed to be shared with multiple actors
the eff was able to fingerprint some of
it rather uniquely and that's really
where the attribution came from
so once they identified uh
the infrastructure being used by dark
karakol they were able to identify
that some of the logs had actually been
left open and unsecured
so based off those open logs testing and
testing devices were identified and the
wi-fi networks associated with those
devices
were then identified and happened to be
in a
very close vicinity to a building
owned by the general director of general
security
additionally the command control address
was controlled by three ip addresses
that belong to the lebanese
government-owned oguero telecom
so next we have the united arab emirates
and stealth falcon
fruity armor so in 2016 the intercept
published an article detailing dark
matter's recruitment of cyber personnel
from a variety of countries
to conduct offensive operations uh their
report was followed up with reported by
reuters that showed
nsa hackers that were hacking for a
group known as project raven
from a mansion in abu dhabi alleged
targets include human rights activists
journalists and political rivals
the manual used which is called karma
did not require any user interaction and
obtained
photos text and location information
it's hypothesized that it actually used
an imessage zero day
also in 2016 citizen lab published a
report on stealth falcon
the group that conducted a large scale
campaign
against uae government critics the
actors first profiled a user's device
with a redirect link and then later in
the conversation fished them with an
actual malicious document
that eventually returned to custom
powershell uh backdoor
similar to powershell empire so uh
then fast forward to 2019 eset published
a report about a binary that
bears a remarkable similarity to the
powershell backdoor
disclosed in 2016 by citizen lab
they noted targets in the united arab
emirates uh saudi arabia thailand and a
middle eastern diplomatic mission to the
netherlands
the binary also uses one of the same
command and control domains
as this powershell backdoor so that's
where they drew
additional uh context
so really it's interesting to see both
the domestic and foreign targeting again
by the united arab emirates
so when we talk about morocco um
i thought this was kind of interesting
because i wasn't really
expecting to find much on them but in
the security company hires found tax
against a variety
of french industrial firms after
sinkhole in the domain
they researched the register information
and eventually found an email address
that aligned to a dns server for the
malware campaign
in march of 2020 uh brian krebs took
that email address did what he did best
traced it through some forms and doxxed
a moroccan security researcher who was
tied to the forum posts in the email
of course the security researchers
denies being affiliated with the french
malware campaign
uh because his email was quote unquote
hacked and that campaign
did use njrat so we all know that um
krebs is great at tracing emails and
identifying individuals
but at this point we don't know who
directed or sponsored the intrusion
and we may never know who was targeting
those french industrial firms
using the quote-unquote security
researcher from morocco who got hacked
allegedly
so next is uzbekistan so they weren't on
my radar as a player in iphone's
offensive cyber operations prior to this
my research here but
they've been around for a while their
national secret police the sss
first took interest in commercial
hacking tools started in 2011
and came to light by the attacking team
dumps by phineas fisher
then in 2019 brian bartholomew from
kaspersky presented on an apt
they tied to uzbekistan's intelligence
agency
the strong attribution to the sss was
possible
in part due to horrible opsec by the
individual operators
based off of who is they were able to
identify
the actual military unit as well as the
military officer's name
who was behind the behind the domains
behind the unit
or side behind the campaign that's just
the first optic failure
additionally the operators were testing
their software in the zero days they buy
on computers that had conspiracy
antivirus on testing machines
um conspiracy team was able to grab
three other purchase zero days
um from sand cat which then burned them
for
anyone else who had bought them and they
were able to identify other information
for their campaigns before they were
even used
so it shows that the sort of visibility
that some of the vendors
outside of the the
larger vendors is excellent for hunting
these smaller adversaries they're really
those regional vendors
see a lot of really interesting things
and telemetry that some other
companies may not see
so next we have this beautiful picture
from pakistan
so there's there's two groups attributed
to pakistan we're going to talk about
today
the first is interesting it's the gorgon
group because they
have targeted both criminal as well as
targeted espionage
campaigns in february of 2018
unit 42 identified the gorgon group
as targeting governments in the united
kingdom spain russia and the united
states
and those same campaigns use shared
infrastructure with
some financially motivated campaigns
another notable thing from this
campaign is they use url shortening
services to actually download the
payloads
this allowed both the campaign operators
but then also researchers statistical
click counts and visibility when we talk
about the capabilities for the go around
group
i use a variety of rats including nj rat
like we've seen
other groups use as well as info
stealers like loki bot
um in october of 2019 prevailion talked
about another gold ground group campaign
where the alert documents again used url
shortening services to redirect
to blocks blogspot urls hosting
malicious javascript
that javascript ran a
code that was found on pastebin and then
which established persistence
via schedule task and registry keys and
then another pastebrand url was accessed
that infection chain eventually led to a
rat that was either typically revenge
rat or azeroalt
the other apt tied to pakistan is
transparent tribe
also known as mythic library or apt-36
primarily targeting military and
diplomatic targets
primarily indian
in 2016 proof points darin huss
published some research
identifying phishing attacks on indian
military resources
these fish included a weaponized rtf
document that eventually dropped a
portable executable
that eventually led to a rat in addition
to the phishing campaign you
they also saw a strategic web compromise
blog or lure blog
that was set up for indian military
users they included fake articles about
the indian military to entice users to
click on it
and it was a dual pronged approach for
that campaign
which is decently unique um
so and then in 2017 cis info reported
actors that allegedly linked
um a link to transparent tribe targeting
officials in the indian central bureau
of investigation as well as the indian
army
uh this continued their uh transparent
tribes historic targeting of the indian
government officials
and in may of 2018 crowdstrike reported
that mythic leopard continued to use
generic themed excel documents as lures
they paired well with a unique visual
basic script to install a variety of
implants
similar to what proof point identified
crowdstrike identified mythic leopard
c2s that continued
to be reused against comp against
campaigns
um in march malwarebytes reported that
this actor had now begun using
uh covenanting related lures and in
addition to those lures the
apt had also increased their targeting
to include targets in afghanistan
and then just recently uh kaspersky's
put out some uh
new reporting on an android implant that
they tied
to transparent tribe uh that's
definitely worth looking at
as well
a beautiful tiger from india so let me
first start by saying that india is a
mess as far as cyber attribution goes
both state supported and criminal
operations we're going to look at some
interesting campaigns
that have a nexus to india and talk
about different threat groups that have
been reported on
but and nowhere will this be exhaustive
in march of 2018 a chinese security
vendor reported that a large number of
highly targeted spear phishing attacks
targeted sensitive chinese government
agencies in this campaign the alert
document ended up dropping a.net
executable
that related to case rat scheduled tests
and eventually led to x-ray as well
documents were exfiltrated via post to
the command control
veloxity and other security vendor
reported a similar campaign from
the same time frame in their report they
identified campaigns that also directly
attacked us think tanks
in addition to the malware alerts
patchwork which is
who they attribute the campaign to did
something unique by
using an embedded image tag that beating
back to the attacker's domain
that embedded image tag was unique so
attackers could see who had clicked on
their links
successfully again the final payload in
that campaign was case rat
the exploit used was pulled from a
public approval concept post on github
and it was likely not developed
internally and this copy and pasting is
what originally gave this apd
its name of patchwork symmetria saw
a threat actor operating one of their
deception environments in 2016.
they were able to identify blurred
documents on a c2 server
and they all used chinese related alerts
or south china sea related lures
the tools all seem to be open source
tools available on github
so that again using those open source
tooling as part of their campaigns
and although that that was back in 2016
indian-based officers have not gone
anywhere um
earlier this year in may unit 42
released some reporting on hangover or
advisory tiger
uh in this activity uh targeted
government and military organizations
and worked extra hard to blend in as
impersonate legitimate services
include things like self-signed
certificates unique file descriptions
and convincing error messages
within the software the interesting
thing is that instead of using
phishing to directly deliver the
documents the actor actually hosted the
payloads on compromised third-party
websites
within the targeted countries tld
so in some ways even more interesting
than the state-sponsored activity is the
indian hacking for higher activity
two main names come to mind that have
been publicly reported the first is opt
in security
the second broker earlier this year and
is called dark basin by citizen lab
both operations target a variety of
individuals including attorneys
dissidents and journalists
the eff reported that operation manuel
which we talked about
earlier was in use by a variety of
individuals including kazakhstan
and the campaign that led to the
identification
of dark karakol in lebanon dark basin
allegedly has two different types of
campaigns the first seems to be
aggressive and annoying
forcing the user to click the link to
unsubscribe the second was more targeted
and masqueraded as legitimate service
asking for access to photo sharing
and that sort of thing if you're
interested in following indian apts and
and doing some more research
definitely suggest searching for hashtag
sidewinder
on twitter it'll get you a variety of
malware samples to look at from the
community
so next we have south korea the first
uh in november of 2019 a chinese
security company reported a pretty
unique campaign
uh that they identified as um active
since 2016 they called it hayasa
they used north korean related lures to
conduct their campaigns
and fished diplomatic
entities government officials expats and
traders
targets included china north korea japan
nepal
singapore russia switzerland and of
course
poland which is an interesting target
typically you don't necessarily see
poland being targeted
they often have the spear fishing often
happened on important holidays
and gave quote-unquote blessings during
those holidays
a unique thing about these this apt is
that they
weaponize newsletters as soon as four
days after the news happened so it was a
very quick time from uh
something being newsworthy to being in a
campaign
besides the typical trojan there was
also a key logger an outlook account
password stealer from github
and ghost rat as well
attribution came from a couple places
the first being timestamp analysis
which can always be faked but it just
takes some
extra work and then also
remnantsofnover.com
in the documents naver.com is south
korea's biggest search engine
so next we have dark hotel or shadow
crane that's probably one of my favorite
apts
uh in active since 2007 in 2014
kim's that are reported on uh hi
attacking
the hotel wi-fi against high-profile
vips
including us targeting of the defense
industrial base
any sector relating to investments in
economic development
targets include the us north korea japan
india bangladesh
thailand mozambique in germany um
[Music]
and so some actually interesting things
about this group
uh they'll start doing fishing with
monthly reports
um so you may not click on the first
fish in february with that report
but by late may you're used to seeing
those reports and you may click that
because hey if it comes every month
it can't be malicious right
um another interesting thing is that the
group configures their c2 to look like a
normal website if you visit the wrong
page
according to kaspersky they often show
pictures of artisanal ice cream
or comics unrelated to their target
this group has plenty of zero days
including
zero days internet explorer
vulnerabilities
interestingly some of those areas are
actually used against targets that
appear to be located in south korea
and at this time it's unclear whether
they belong to the multinational
companies
who are having to be operating south
korea or
domestic south korean citizens
it would be consistent with south korean
geopolitical aims to solicit information
from companies
that could be considered competitors so
that's the way i personally
lean on that but again some really cool
stuff
they also targeted the world health
organization earlier this year
um in relation to kobe 19.
so next we have some water buffalo from
vietnam
um so apt32 also known as ocean lotus
is a really unique set because with the
right visibility it's easy to see how
their campaigns align with vietnamese
state interests
nick carr formula fire i know with
microsoft has done a great job reporting
what fireeye had seen from this threat
since 2014 they have consistently
targeted foreign corporations
with manufacturing consumer products and
hospitality sectors
they've also targeted vietnamese
diaspora journalists and activists
as well as government agencies
what's interesting is that the targeting
isn't just for straight intellectual
property theft like a lot of intrusions
are
but rather they're serving the law
enforcement audit purpose
the best example of this would be the
automobile industry where
vietnam vietnam excuse me vietnam
implemented strict regulations for
importing cars
following those laws multiple car
manufacturers including toyota and bmw
were attacked in late 2018 by ocean
lotus
and these attacks happened quicker than
the meeting notes sometimes got out from
those new bus
we talked about how ocean lotus conducts
operations against typical targets for
a government-sponsored adversary these
include operations against other
government agencies
most located regionally according to the
eff they've also been known to target
journalists
and activists ocean laws actually
transcripts between the philippine
president duarte
with world leaders both the president
united states and the chinese president
so another uh threat actor with
ties to vietnam and some overlap with
ocean lotus is phantom lance
first publicly reported in spring of
2020 kaspersky estimated they've been
active since around 2016.
they primarily conducted attacks using
mobile malware
the first version that they submit to
the store is clean with no malicious
code
but later updates then contain malicious
code and payload to make it past
the screening this allows them to
successfully enter that
the app store targeting information is
consistent with vietnamese state
interest
in southeast asia majority happen to be
in india
bangladesh vietnam indonesia nepal
myanmar and malaysia
so next we have machete possibly
colombia or venezuela attribution
they've been active since 2010
revamped in 2012 they're
spanish-speaking
apt and they're looking for photos from
webcams geolocation
audio from microphones targeting
includes
venezuela colombia and ecuador along
with russia so you're seeing
both whether whether they're based out
of colombia or venezuela you're seeing
both domestic and foreign targeting
by this group which i think does not get
as much attention
as some of the other ones
all right so what so we've talked a lot
about different adversaries
a lot of content so first off let's talk
trends it's evident that smaller
governments have no problem using these
targeted attacks against dissidents
journalists and sometimes even their own
citizens
if you have employees or friends in
these groups please make sure they're
protected
the google advanced protection program
is now free for everyone get a hardware
token
get to work protecting yourselves as
defenses
if you're a multinational company when
was the last time that you threat
modeled
the local gov governments or the
the governments that may affect your
local subsidiaries uh your businesses do
you conduct work in a place that may
conduct cyber operations against you
a couple suggestions would be have you
read reporting from companies that are
doing work
specifically in those regions a lot of
times their reporting is unique and is
quicker than some of the larger players
i personally am a fan of getting outside
of just the american infosec bubble
and getting intelligence from um
other places because i think that allows
us to a better
fuller picture of what the threat
landscape actually looks like
um and if you've seen have you seen with
unique regional targeting
i think if you have and you're able to
share some ttps and trends that you've
seen
that will help everyone um understand
the
the landscape better and understand the
threat better
red team hopefully you saw some
interesting things to make yourself look
more like actual adversaries and not
just trying to get the latest
exploit to work and again i'll please
share the information that you see i
think it's really great to
to share across the industry
[Music]
so like i mentioned before all images
were from pixabay
citations to the original research are
located on pastebin
or scan the qr code and i'll take it to
you i did cite a ton of public research
um please go read there there's some
great work
and the researchers and journalists did
an amazing job of reporting it and i
want to make sure that they
if you if you have a specific adversary
go
dig deeper and engage with that work
because it's great work
uh so thank you so much again follow me
in chicago cyber
uh appreciate you listening to me i've
uh really enjoyed wish i could have been
in poland
for zfcon but never know maybe next year
if you have any questions i will
hopefully be joining shortly to answer
them
all right thank you so much
you