my name is uh
peter bianchak i work
as a senior uh researcher at
sepolska and
also i'm a phd student at versus
university of technology
you can reach me by email or by
twitter no
so
i've always wanted to begin presentation
with
a card picture
and yeah today i'm doing it
it illustrates the mechanism
which i think applies
to uh to to
work of blue teamers when they try to
hunt
malware using some block lists
or some information about
infrastructure malware infrastructure
so i think a lot of
people will wish to be that
identification via
this block list ip addresses domains was
useful but and effective but
i think it's not
it's not um
ips domains constantly change
and mobile developers introduce some
dedicated mechanism for evasion like dga
fast flux all these things
and yeah and
when these things are
maybe effective when we know the threats
but when we are
when we encounter an unknown threat
then they these lists are useless
so what should be
what could we do if we have maybe some
mechanism to identify
uh something constant in malware
behavior
which also could provide some
[Music]
distinguishability between
malware families i would say that
it's marvel fingerprinting
and malware fingerprinting using network
network traffic which i will talk today
about
um with fingerprinters
it will provide the fingerprinting we
can identify
threads
because they use some rarely changed
elements
and we don't use the ip addresses
but only those things which are
like constant in all the traffic all the
messages
uh fingerprinters make
uh the fingerprints produced unique
that which can give us
a way to identify in some sort smaller
families
but also the fingerprints can provide
good
generalization that means that
if we have for example 100 requests
a good finger printer can provide only
10 fingerprints or
even one fingerprint for all this
traffic one is the same
also fingerprinting provides
uh or should provide an easy way to
share the fingerprints and
thus sharing the intelligence with the
community for example
um i think there are two different
notions of uh
fingerprinting mother fingerprinting uh
one is i would say it's a direct
identification of
our families this
this systems these tools directly
provide
name of the malware and i would say
these are more like multi-class malware
detectors
and more than
the second group which are more generic
i will call them like generic feature
extractors
because they provide a representation of
some
features uh from from the network
traffic from from the messages
and these features
do not er or its fingerprints do not
give
mother family however we can label it
later in this presentation i will focus
on the second group
so let's begin with traffic fingerprints
um majority of tools
extract some payload fields uh
from from for some help from
headers here we can see ipv4 header
or pseudo header and i have a lot of
different
different fields however
the tools should choose only those
fields which are like i said before uh
rarely changed and also which are hard
to change
because if those change too much then um
yeah or they're easy to change then they
can be
evaded um
the fingerprinters present the results
present the features
usually into two forms like full
presenting all the features and concise
like
hash or something like that so
some uh examples of usage
firstly you can use the fingerprinter to
group activities for example you have
like i said before
100 http requests and you want to know
either similar or different
it can provide identification malware
for example we have some
one fingerprint which is distinct and
you can use it as a hash
to search for for other
messages in this format it will it can
be
simply it is similar to like
virustotal
it can fingerprinters can also provide
identification of different operations
single malware
family for example if we
want to identify which request is for
example for
cnc and which is for
information about ip or connectivity
check
fingerprinters can provide that info
also if families
are for example have
one ascendant then
yeah you can you can correlate some
similar behaviors and provide some
information that
these two families are somewhat similar
um now i'll present some popular tools
uh we will begin with jeffrey i think
it's very popular
um it provides means for
fingerprinting to your last uh both
client and servers
it uses the symbol values of some chosen
fields of client hello message
these are a version of tls
the cyphers use used list of extensions
elliptic curves and
curse point formats all these things
are concatenated and this is the
full version of of the
of the fingerprint however it's rather
long so we can
um use a shorter form
which is hard with md5 this
tool is extensively supported
different different
systems like mis like moloch
monitoring with three music all the
things
that's over here to search for the
github
[Music]
the second tool
aj ssh
yeah the name does all
its fingerprints ssh clients servers
uh as before
it extracts some
fields from the
[Music]
one of the first messages when the ssh
connection is
negotiated and decimal values of
fields like public categories
or encryption algorithms mark algorithms
compression all these things are
concatenated and then
cast to provide a shorter phone
also that would have open source so
you can check it
i think that this is also a great tool
fingerprint of the things um
it supports both previous
previous tools jeffrey hs sage
but also it can
fingerprint remote desktop protocol
by using rdfp fingerprinter but also
gquigg
um and http
i had a fingerprinting i will talk
about this later it can
online network pick up files
all these things here and the github
so maybe some other great tools
like it's a classic tool uh
both in the version three it supports
http fingerprinting
cisco mercury
[Music]
a lot of protocols supported
um identification framework
which is called recalc by rapid7
it gives information about not only
about protocol
to fingerprinting but also
services operating system all these
things
so now something more complex that
tools presented before smtp
fingerprinting
smtp used by
to send emails to exchange emails
[Music]
this method it's called smtp dialects
because it checks the implementation of
[Music]
smtp how the the client
talks with server um
it looks which messages are exchanged
um the case also checks
smtp extension imf fields all these
things
it can be used to detect spambots
you can see more about this i think this
one of the first
papers about this academic paper however
very i think we're promising also my
colleagues in the system project
uh worked on this and
yes here is a screen from
from from the season block
and two different bots
uh thunderbird and some spambot
we can see some differences we've
exchanged messages thunderbird is
elo and about
hello here is our ap address and
the bot uses a domain name there is a
difference in mail in the from
the made from message
it's written in some other case also
there is a
space after it there is no white space
here in the thunderbird
the same applies to
the second message recipient to
so and at last the quit uh information
the bot does not send it so
you can see the difference however there
is no open source tool
for for smtp fingerprinting so maybe
someone want to to check it and check
these papers
and write something in the
in the free time so
i will now try to provide some demo
oh already started so okay
i've imported
yeah yeah i should see security on okay
so uh
i've imported uh network traffic because
files from
uh model traffic analysis.com or
you know you know the site and
yeah the the traffic comes from the
the posts from 2020 and i've
i've imported them with so
import pickup from security online
okay i will like play the the
film so uh
i i go to this keyword to check
all the surikata alerts
and firstly i've
checked the time
because i'd like a whole liver
as a time reference because the the
pickups are from different
time from holier
okay so next yeah
you can see some different uh different
uh different different colors
and because there is a lot of malware
this traffic is almost all malware
however some pickups have some
traffic from from windows background
[Music]
so we can check
check the traffic and here we can see
here we can see that there is
some cnc
server of drivers or chipboard
we don't know yet and
there are some alerts for it and
we will check the ip addresses
[Music]
for example here is some address from
russia and yeah we will
now click it and we will
we have this default dashboard with
information about the
ip address however we would like to
use it as a filter
firstly yeah i forgot to
to make time reference of one year
last year okay so making a
filter with ips keyboard
and i've pasted the ip address
save the filter okay so now we are
in the in the default
and the main dashboard and we want to to
go to
uh to some different dashboards but we
want to save the site b
and so i have pinned it
and now i will go to
um to
ssl
and yeah
i think yeah
we can see some counts
uh how many times was it was observed
[Music]
so i've added
here uh it's not default
however i wanted to uh to to
additional dashboards uh
about zeke jeffrey and
because it comes from zeke and jeffrey s
for server
and now i will uh
[Music]
try to prevent some
i wanted to filter the traffic
there was some problem however okay so
yeah i have
i have inputted the qr
joffrey keyboard to my hand this is the
fingerprint for for the client
who connected to to this uh
cnc server which was
malicious at least by surikata
so now i've unpin the ip
and it showed that there is there was 51
messages from with this
fingerprint and yeah i think
it is a lot and there is
also some other jeffrey case here are
some
information about ip addresses of the
clients using it
so we can say that these ip addresses
can
provide some information that they are
they are malicious
okay so next thing
[Music]
sorry uh now i will
uh the the filter is empty
i have refreshed for the whole year to
check information about all the um
all the tls connections and then we have
a lot of
this joffrey keyboards a lot of
fingerprints
so maybe a lot of clients and
so i have we can download it
like a csv file and
we go to
terminal um
let's see how how does it look so there
you have uh
um we have a
fingerprint and the crown so we have to
make it a little more prettier
meanwhile we go to the
abuse ch geoffrey fingerprints
blacklist i have previously downloaded
it
and yeah
we can cut the information about the
fingerprints
from from the zig from from the from the
kibana and
zig and then check whether any of these
fingerprints
is on the blacklist of abuse ch
so we are preparing the data i have the
data we can
write all the information to
the scene jeffrey
dot txt file and then
let's see how does look the blacklist
which are free information of
mother family that's all all we need so
okay we use
advanced tool called grab
we will grab using
using all these fingerprints from
from kibana to check whether any of them
is
on the wch
list so yeah we have found
sorry i cannot but
it's like here mark two thread is uh
so we found gtx then we can pivot all
the things
more okay let me know if you see
another desktop
okay great thanks thanks all right so
okay
the next one because time is running
out so let's play
now i will uh uh
give you information about the fight how
does it work
so some demo so previously i have
restarted and fat
as remember fingerprint all the things
and we will use the http
fingerprinting uh feature
so firstly uh i've downloaded from model
traffic analysis
tripod pickup file
and we will filter out only
the http request
[Music]
http requests so there is
like nine of them and
there are some different but different
ones
this i think this one is like
[Music]
very identifiable
for the trick board if you ever see the
traffic
because the name of the computer
so
there are some different different
requests
and there is a pulse request which i
talked before here
this three uh from what i remember
are these three requests are used to
develop
additional trickbots dll and
okay so let's see what can
what fat can tell
about this yeah we
take the pickup file name
and
okay problem with the argument however
it's like a minus r to read the pickup
file
minus p to print to the
command line and http for for
fingerprint
so and there is a lot of data
and however you can you you have
source ip destination ip protocol
um fingerprint and user agent
and however there is information about
the server
uh server side but i would like to
filter only for for
[Music]
for the client uh so we will
get the info however it still is a lot
of
data so here we cut
only the destination might be with
with information about
about destination port okay so
here we can see there is a one
fingerprint is
in like one two three messages
also there are two other
fingerprints which are the same also the
same are the user agents
and i think uh
fat gives a good uh information about
different uh different requests of this
malware
like um the one i showed
the fingerprint shot was for for the
pulse request another
another fingerprint for this
post request which is kind
different
[Music]
it's like here and this post request is
on
other report but also it uploads some
other information on the other other
requests so yeah
i think it's a good
good tool so um now we will go to
uh to another problem we have uh
emoted pickup uh
a modern tripod and unknown pickup for
someone no malware
so we will check
the traffic there is some
traffic for http https okay
so
we put it in the pickup file to in the
file
and sort four unique
values of fingerprint and user agent to
provide
unique information about
all the requests in the known pickup
with the emoted then we will do the same
thing
okay so now we save it as a voltage
fingerprint txt file okay
then we do the same for the
unknown unknown pickup
we get some information and
let's see what's in there so there's
some
some hunches so some user agents
but let's see whether these two
intersect
so with that uh with that mechanism we
can
we can tell whether those fingerprints
from emoted are seen in the unknown file
if yes then we can say with some
probability
probability that
in the unknown pickup has also emoted
traffic let's see
yes using grab grabbing
through the emoted from
the normal and yeah we have some
free uh three fingerprints with the same
hash and user agent so yeah
we can tell that the the one file is
the one file is the second file it
usually could be a model
now two other uh malwares beta board
and a copter
firstly we will look at the copter
there is harsh beginning with zero
a0f etc then we will
check the beta board
all this has to show
that there is also
the same value for both modular families
so yeah we have a collision here
uh because
uh both modeler the similar
requests the similar headers
however they are different by
url okay so
let's get back to
sorry okay
let's get back to presentation
the problem the problems which we can
see
here is that
there are in some current
this is not only from this observation
from some of my
research current http fingerprinters
have a lot of
collision between families also between
malware and benign software and
currently the analysis of url payload
is limited in them so yeah i've created
each finger
which looks in the url like this
features
length directories file extension header
structure
like request method protocol version
order of the headers
popular headers and values i think most
of these
features for the headset are already
known and also the payload
the length of the pile of entropy and
presence of some non-ascii
characters to check the
information about the battles by the
maid modeler so here we have a
post request uh which
is a dummy post request dummy data
but it provides a fingerprint
with information this is actual
fingerprint from
uh from from the finger and
it provides information about the length
of the
url it's a base 10 logarithm
of of the length uh
also the extension of the file requested
there is no extension here so
it's empty and number of variables uh in
the in
the url here is only one so yeah it's
here
then the structure
name of the request method version of
the protocol
and then a list of uh
there is a list of uh
[Music]
headers some popular headers with with
values encoded
here and lastly uh payload features it's
the length of the payload
of this part uh as before
uh it's a base then
logger of of the length so
it's you you can make as before
uh md5 has from it however uh
the main uh the main thing we would like
to achieve with it
is to give some interpretation for
for analysts to to look into the
request and check what's there by hand
yeah there is some coding
some popular headers are analyzed the
values are
[Music]
encoded for example application json is
called like
ap js however
you can provide your own encoding i
don't know even
with emoji or some smiley faces
it's off for you
the h finger have different support
modes
i've presented before the result of
different features
which are used by
a springer however if you take a lot of
features
there is a lot of fingerprints given
from the
from the tool it's the generalization
it's
it's not very well then so
you have you have to to make this
optimization
between uniqueness of the
fingerprint and the number of
fingerprints produced by the
by the tool so uh you can
choose choose the report mode depending
on your
level the default mode tries to optimize
both
this uniqueness and generalization uh
there's a
more informative mode where you can
have more features presented to you but
it makes also
slightly more fingerprints and all the
features
not full information however it
is full information the fingerprint is
more is the most unique however
uh there is also a lot of fingerprints
done
in the other modes some more info
i think it's already uh
already published at third point
github you can find it there
please know that it's a working
prototype stage
i think there will be some changes i
wish to
the tool is written python uses
discharge for pickup parsing
and http reassembly and
comments issues pr's are all welcomed
you can
write to me by email yeah make issues on
the github
so maybe some demo
let's check it i you should see okay so
yeah there is but there is a problem i
forgot to resize the
size of the icons but
okay so maybe you can
see anything there is a long string it's
not not beauty
[Music]
it's not so beautiful as you would like
to
so we put it into the queue
maybe okay so here i resize it and i
will talk about it so
uh i've put the one of the
collision files the copter pickup which
was uh
interfacing collisions the gate
collisions
uh so uh
when we put it from the gq you can see
some
information about like like before
uh length of the url but also the
headers
and then we will call
the beta board and we can see that even
that
the part about the request version
and the headers is the same however
there is difference
in the part of about the url here's a
length of the url
requested file number of variables so
yeah here is a different uh
difference between those two
fingerprints so lastly
valak
we will analyze it with
each finger firstly there is a lot of
we filter out in t-shark the requests
there is a lot of different requests
here
is some cap file
here are some isp aspx
requests one is on go dot spx other on
rpc there is a lot of dissimilar
uh requests but also
there is some oh maybe i will
can before yeah here you can see
some background traffic from from
windows
it's not i think it's windows update so
yeah mixed traffic
and okay now we'll show it uh
some different requests here is the
request from the
windows update yes
update for funny user agent
crypto api okay so
we check the the file
and it produced a lot of different
requests however we can see that
there is the the fingerprints are pretty
uh the same
so nextly we can
we can check there is like uh five
uh five uh five different
fingerprints
and with this fingerprints we can
both
[Music]
identify this shorter shorter
request but also between these two two
requests which are to some two different
uh different resources
uh let's see is okay so
that's all
so back to the presentation
okay okay i'm late so let's quick
conclusion
uh fingerprints are helpful in hunting
malwares i think
i show i showed you that that but
like you know modeler developers are
also
working and fingerprinters are
good until the the new mechanism of
ours start to evade these fingerprints
and
these tools there is a
all fingerprints including edge finger
there is a problem of this
generalization versus collisions
if you make the fingerprinter more
to give more unique fingerprints then
you have a lot of fingerprints so you
cannot
generalize in a good manner
the the requests sent by by demolar
some popular tools are already called
work
protocols however there are some tools
which can also be
created so call
[Music]
and please give a try to which finger
it was part of the work was sponsored by
european union thank you
and that's all
you