[Music]
thank you
next up from Amber Inferno and staging
emails shouldn't lead to complete
Disaster by November enjoy
[Applause]
all right hello all uh it's a pleasure
being here it's my first time speaking
at balcon
so my name is Nicos I work as an instant
responder for three years now
um I like forensics I like petting dogs
I like memes
I'm one of you
so once I started let's say my career
back then when I was a student I always
said you know what
let's make things interesting
and uh being here makes it really
interesting to be honest
yesterday of course as you can see I
have a very nice mark from drinking too
much right yeah unfortunately
I've been two times in Serbia last time
it ended up with a border patrol uh
searching Micron jewels
and as you can imagine each time I'm
here something happens but it's nice so
what's the agenda for today we're gonna
discuss about an instant that happened
in an organization we will not go let's
say in too much into the details uh of
the of the impact it goes because
because I would like to focus more on
the challenges we face and how we will
approach let's say the investigation I
truly believe that one of the biggest
issues in at this moment is that
everybody can teach forensics but you
cannot teach the investigative mindset
it's something that you either pick it
up during uh with your experience or
unfortunately it's something that you
will need to have talks like that you
have to to become better by yourself
and of course at the end we will discuss
some recommendations on on what to focus
so since the dawn of time we use pigeons
to carry messages then when we moved on
to more electronic ways let's say we use
the post office services and then as you
can imagine right now the digitalization
of all the mailing infrastructure we use
exchange and of course the Outlook you
cannot of course have different
Technologies but you get the concept
right
messaging is an important aspect in uh
in the throughout the human history and
today most of us most of the talk will
focus around
The Exchange compromise and exchange the
incident and think about it that
although all these Services come
together that are interconnected and
something bad happens to one of them
like in the case of Greece where it got
hacked
though that it's a lot of the post one
of the the services actually got post
and said some pretty nice let's say
message about the prime minister
okay
so what about Microsoft chains the thing
is it is very very targeted at this
point since uh the last three years we
had 69
CVS and actually 10 of them were so so
big they had critical score so you can
imagine it was a mess for everybody
working uh in the security industry it
wasn't quite the year that we would hope
for and it involved a lot of incidents
imagine that when proxy Laguna came out
in March 2018 it wasn't it wasn't much I
believe
we had so many incidents
in only one week more than four so you
can imagine no sleep at all
but exchange has a very nice feature
it involves parcel that you can have in
order to do massive operations you can
do stuff in bulk you can do things to
automate rather than going behind the
console the web page and uh
and do it manually of course that
creates an extra problem for us for us
in the security business let's say
because at this point we had one problem
right you had to Monitor and secure the
device but the server and the
application but right now with the
remote options that you have with power
exchange partial you see how many
Technologies they are available there
and it's not so easy because
there is one huge problem with security
at this point we tend to to limit the
usability of our products to enhance
let's say the security aspect of the
organization and that that these
Administration tasks are really
important for one organization
of course for attackers this is
Christmas right
excellent
so let's uh discuss about uh the
incident pretty much it involved the
typical scoping let's say with the
client they pick we pick up the phone
and they give us the first let's say
details about it the the users inside
the organization received
a fishing email it was an email that
prompted them to download the uh one
malicious file and they didn't record
they did some basic let's say sets for
the headers in the email and they
identified
that the user IP is suspicious because
it was not part of the organization so
at first you see okay this is a typical
business email compromise no biggie
right
but here's the thing we received a
second call in the next 30 minutes
saying you know what we'll have a second
incident
so we had two of them
at least this is what I thought
so you can imagine it was a very bad day
it involved in one week
of an incident so you can imagine there
was no slip at all
but
the devil is not black as he is painted
because we have tools
we can detect it we can respond
and we will discuss during the
challenges how tough it is actually
of course when we start the
investigation we pick up the the web
cells you know at least three of them
into different service into different
servers
and as you can see it already had the
privileged uh systemic privilege so it
was pretty bad from the start
because at this point you said that your
organization your mailing infrastructure
is completely compromised and that could
State the tax for the next uh to enter
the other systems as well it's one thing
having a website but it's another to
have admin running it with
administrative privileges
because we were saying okay the initial
access is on the server how could they
uh did the attackers just Collide
further what could they do wouldn't have
this kind of visibility and imagine that
in most organizations right now they
don't properly they don't monitor
properly not the devices not the systems
they don't know what they have this is a
big big issue when it comes to scoping
the incident because most of the times
we enter blind you don't know where to
go where to look and you have to pick up
let's say some needles inside the whole
haystack
so once investigating the ISS logs we
could find indeed that these web cells
were plotting for uh some queries back
to the C2 Channel
and these are very important keep them
in mind uh this is where you should be
looking once you have a
compromise like that not necessarily
from a change because IIs might have
different uh applications running on it
as well so the assets logs are very
important for us always keep them
safe and if you if you can have a good
retainment of at least one month before
and let's save the list because it
should be the bare minimum most
organizations don't have this type of uh
of logging capacities most of the times
we have the question okay what could be
a good retainment and most of the times
it it involves the cost of the
organization because
logging and storing it costs so a good
idea is to have at least three to six
months of of retention
as you can see in the website in one of
them we were uh the the attackers were
changing the local seeds and it was It
was a base64.
um string so let's keep in mind that
okay you see something that you might
not recognize at first but always look
at patterns
and then we focused on The Exchange
Server again
as your as you can see
we found out in GitHub with that same
simple sets that it was not even let's
say uh a very very difficult attack to
identify at first it was just a public
POC that was out there and was run by
Script kidding imagine that when a proxy
shell happened when it came out it was I
think August and that this incident was
in November so the organization should
have already been prepared for that but
they didn't
and this goes to show that no one cares
about the patches that even the most
simplistic attacks can be done and I'm
simplistic because public POC that has
already been picked up by the antivirus
by the Arts by by whatever may be able
to stop it
and most of the times RC organizations
think okay we need to invest more in EDR
we need to invest more in the detection
capability the thing is that all these
products will be bypassed at some point
right so no matter how you invest on the
detection side you should always invest
on the response as well
we should it's something that I always
say that there are three things in my
life anymore that are inevitable it's
death taxes and cyber incidents and we
will never be able to avoid them at this
point unless nuclear disaster happens
and we're out of uh electricity and then
we will not have the systems but always
always
keep in mind when you're looking at the
at your logs you might be able to find
unique identifiable uh observables as we
call them in this case it was
uh it was this is a user agent because
once I was starting investigating I said
okay
we have two instance right now we have
the one with the business email
compromise and we're having one that
change do they have some sort of
collaboration between them the attackers
did they know something uh did is it
part of the same attack is it something
new
to balance with you it was my most
difficult incident because it took me at
least three days to try and pick up what
actually happened
and imagine that it's not always easy
when you have an investigation because
it's not always linear right you pick up
some traces you pick some some
some evidence you investigate as you go
and then you have to do the analysis but
at the same time you'd run out of time
because most of times the organization
circuit you know what you do a very good
job with a forensics but I need to go
back in business yes but how can you go
back to business if you don't know where
the incident happened what happened what
caused what was the root cause of that
what would you do to stop it from
happening again uh most of the the times
that will be seen in last four cases
everybody proceeds to recover but do you
know the entry point and if your backups
are already compromised if you install
the systems from scratch again
what would happen nobody actually
thinks about that during recovery times
and this is something that we should
strive as an industry to see what we
will be looking we would be doing
because at some point
we see that most of the times the
response companies that they called they
only do basic investigation let's say
and they proceed to according to the
client needs and because you do what
your client pays you to do it's okay I
will stop my investigation I have
already built you and I will continue
with uh with the restoration of your
services
the good thing with forensic forensics
is that it's a very well established
science we do have uh this this
Principle as we call it it's the local
principle every it means that auto times
when and a crime happens traces will be
left behind and this is true to cyber
instance as well
no matter what something will be there
remember when I told you that it was so
difficult to try and understand if these
incidents were linked together well in
fact they were and I was
amazed at the end of it like wow I I
couldn't be able to understand it but
again as you investigate
you get all the peace together
so one of the conclusions that I got out
of it is never never us to to judging
the situation mentally
so these are three things let's say on
the exchange technology how it works
because it's one thing to receive the
email in the
in the server and it's another to have
it uh you know in your system right so
you have the message tracking you have
the swap requests the shop messages we
call it and have the Authentication
as you understand the authentication
means identity it means user it means an
account
and uh as we talk about ntlm you can
figure out that uh if you can have a
compromise and if
you're able to hit the exchange
initially this is a very good starting
point because as we saw the website
we're running on system so you would
have a escalated privilege already and
getting a house would be very very good
to actually propagate inside the
organization
so just to have a graphical picture this
is from the Microsoft website uh you
will be able to to understand it's a
little bit better we mostly thought it
flickers a bit anyway but as you can see
on the auto Discovery service it is the
one the first that got hit and then it
uh escalated
ews service
so what was the anatomy behind the
attack
discover service is abused to leak uh
the the distinguished name of a known
user in this case it was administrator
and keep in mind that it is a very nice
recommendation to change the name of
your local administrator or disable it
one of those two things because even
script kidding even someone that has low
uh let's check up capacity
and doesn't know your organization they
will always try the first ad or admin
administrator something like that and
for them it was the case as well
so the attacker knows the most
well-known uh distinguished name
and then they can afford the their
access to the AWS so
uh with the attacker being able to
successfully impersonate the target user
with this valid access they can perform
the old vws operations they want
so the proxy cell to continue the
operation they will uh have let's say
the shop request we're discussing so one
of them was a create item so it allows
the create the remote creation of
females and then they can impersonate
the user
uh imagine
that this was the missing key
because
we were looking at the websites we were
looking at the emails we found that in
the in the mailbox we analyzed the the
headers and who analyzed I find out
actually that the client IP address
the one that sent email was the one that
had performed the swap request
the softbox on the create item so this
was the missing the missing link that we
require to let's say link the attacks
together when proxy happened I'm like oh
my God finally I'm looking at an ATP
find out my proper responder but it was
not the case I harassed to to judge I
asked to judge and this was a mistakes
from my side because you go to the
client say you know what you're being
targeted by the Chinese and uh they look
at them oh my why and this causes an
unnecessary escalation let's say so
that's why I say I have to be more
careful next time but I'm happy because
I learned from my mistakes and this was
a key because it took me like three days
only to find this IP address and I found
out from the the create item to be
honest with you I didn't have much
experience back then with uh with
exchange but as I told you you learn as
you go you can learn all the things
right and this is a very uh big
statement when it comes to to most
response companies and all the response
Consultants out there if you don't have
the capacity you don't have the
knowledge inside your organization you
will probably Outsource it so you cannot
expect everybody let's say to have the
Techno the knowledge and all
Technologies uh technology evolved so
much right now imagine that in Cloud
especially in Azure things change it
it's uh six months so it's you either uh
have to keep up or you will have let's
say this sort of uh slacking and this
liking can be a little bit dangerous
imagine that with a forensic tools as
well we do not don't have the latest
kernels inside them because first you
wait for the the OS to come out for
example in volatility uh we didn't have
the latest version to analyze the
windows 11 systems that were out there
so you can imagine that this can create
a problem as well
so this would be the bigger picture
let's say this would be how we link
together over
uh all these incidents together it was
not so incident actually as you can see
yeah we have the proxy exploitation the
proxial exploitation and then the
attacker created the show up the swap
action this is how you know we're able
to transmit the message this is how uh
the the the attacker would spawn later
the attack it was if I remember
correctly it was the the squirrel
bathroom uh payload and it didn't cause
that much trouble inside the
organization the good thing is because
they detected the uh The Exchange
compromise they will show
agitated by that so they were behind the
screens all the time saying okay what
happens now what happens now and they
were asking questions to the users and
this is a bad thing because when you
don't have Consolidated logs you only
require on the users themselves to
verify if they clicked or not
and we will discuss about it in uh in a
few seconds
so additional investigation always
evolves around the processes right it's
really really important to understand
what uh process have been run all the
volatile information out there so this
is why you should never ever shut down a
system it's better to touch just
disconnect the blood the
ethernet cable or disconnect from Wi-Fi
because all the volatile data would be
lost imagine that we are seeing power
commands
from w3wp
and we would be able to see the from
Telemetry we would be able to see the
malicious commands from uh from the
attackers this is how you should you
properly do the scoping because imagine
you can see that the command get mailbox
for example it means that right now the
attackers has knowledge of the emails
that you have sent right now they know
more people inside the organization and
they can stage more attacks I believe
that with all the evidence around you
would be able to have better mitigation
action let's say because it's one thing
changing the password it's one thing
let's say reissuing Kerberos tickets and
even certificates so once you finish the
investigation then you would be able to
say
the bigger the impact
remember this there is no one size fits
all uh solution to that and this is why
we shouldn't just rely on password
changing
and what I loved about the latest
technology right now that Microsoft
offers it's by no means there's no sales
talk but the I as far as I know they are
the only uh detection action at this
point the 365 Defender that you can have
Telemetry especially for clicks so with
this uh query in the in kql you can
actually find the list of all the users
that they have clicked the suspicious
links let's say and as you can
understand it's very good for us because
at this previously we had to go to its
computer that we assumed it was braced
and then we had to perform forensics and
do all the actions there imagine that
there is a specific in registry where
you have to investigate to find the if a
user has opened an Outlook attachment
and uh and Outlook link but right now
with Telemetry we are more able to stop
let's say the incident before they cause
too much trouble because indeed a
business email compromise shouldn't lead
to a complete disaster
this is the time where you actually take
your your phones to it
to take photos I've Consolidated over
the things we did for for the
investigation so always processes it's
very very important to say for uh cell
commands
it is also very very important to have
all the volatile data I'm saying process
because most of these times
in at least in the in the investigation
we have with the the whole incident
around evolved around the compromise
websites
from the compromise server so keep in
mind also that you might have web cells
mostly these parts are indicative
most of the times they might actually
change but these are the two uh paths
that are actually writable
but keep in mind that it might that's
why I put the asterisk on top of that
they might be
somewhere else
of course you use the application logs
as well so it's really really important
not only to gather the logs from the
system but from the applications as well
and this is a general recommendation not
just for exchange server not just for
ISS logs Call It Whatever You Like We
had an instant last week where it was uh
an unauthorized access into a server and
their client goes and says okay can you
please tell us if we are compromised and
we go okay of course but do you have
application logs to to tell you who
itself which accounts actually logged in
and said we don't have that kind of
visibility so
because all the other external facing
applications on your organization will
be targeted let's face it it you might
have let's say a lot of false positives
you will be seeing scanners you will be
seeing script kiddies stuff like that so
we we typically say in the in the
business the words maturity but what
does it actually mean it's only it's a
big buzzword right we only care let's
see how much someone will invest
and without proper investing that's true
without proper investing in firewalls in
the office the proper detection
techniques it is very hard to respond
very hard to respond
so let's discuss some of the caveats
some of the problems that uh
that we face
the one thing at most of the times we do
as a response uh as a response
consultant and call it whatever like
blue teams defense teams whatever we
link everything to meter attack that's
good meter has already provided a good
Consolidated list you have a very good
picture let's say of what can be
categorized as a tactic as a technique
as a procedure of the attacker but it's
uh and it's no Silver Bullet
so this is why defend is being created
at this point because all these uh all
these tactics all these techniques would
produce artifacts and as you can
understand
you have multiple artists tactics
and procedure that map two specific logs
keep in mind that first you have the
system then you have the attack right
someone has to happen so we need to know
our operating systems better we need to
know applications better and I believe
that this is what defense strives for
if you do know if you don't know it give
it a look I believe the combination of
both Frameworks is really important uh
to to shape the future of cyber security
because things evolve and we cannot rely
not only on a single framework we need a
combination of them and the combination
of different uh skill sets I don't like
putting Hudson gray hat black hat
Whitehead or even saying blue team
already team security is one right so we
should be able to collaborate better and
Frameworks like them that enhance the
collaboration I believe this is what
would be striving for
and these are some of the challenges of
course that that we face like I told you
you have to know your logs you have to
uh
it's something so this is why I laugh
it's something that most organizations
don't put focus on
and not having logs is essential you
cannot expect not to have an incident at
some point you need to realize that your
digital footprint is out there and you
have to do something about it you may
not you may not have let's say the
biggest Investments when it comes to
detection capabilities but you need to
be able to respond and respond fast
is never linear you pick some Trails
crumbly stuff like that and then you
start connecting the Dodge
like I told you jump too early on my
conclusions I will I try not to do that
anymore you learn as you go some that is
very important as well is that you don't
understand the pressure that uh a
response team faces actually because
you've had your normal eight hours let's
say and then you you get a call on your
Friday night and say okay you know what
screw your your weekend you have to
respond you have to go to an organizer
and this creates an extra pressure and
especially during copy times this is
something that uh create a lot of stress
during uh not only for responders but
most I believe most of us in most of us
of course sharing is caring right this
is why we need to have conference like
that open conferences we need to have
open resources for digital forensics as
well and what I don't like particularly
in this industry in the fir is that
there are no uh not known let's say many
resources out there and you have to
either pay for them uh or most of the
times as they say okay you can blame cpf
stuff like that I don't really believe
that CTF approach is better for uh for
forensics because imagine no one teaches
you how to search the needle in the
haystack but when you're playing a CTF
and you're hunting for the flag you're
focused on only one Mission finding the
flag you know it's there sometimes when
we get called to respond to incidents
there are not even incidents so imagine
you have to image the whole computer
just to find out in the end of the day
that nothing happened but you have to be
able to prove it and that's why I say
forensic science hiking is an art
and you have to properly have a
structure behind that and just by
playing uh you cannot be able to get
let's say the bigger picture in the
future
and that concludes my talk
I don't know if you have any questions
yes
hi thanks for your presentation uh I was
wondering you said that you matched your
malicious shop API request from the with
the IP address of the sender of the
email
but if I'm not mistaken the IP address
of the sender is usually the smdp
address the servers and the others so
did you manage to find VIP from an
administrative console of the user that
sent the actual send email here's the
thing this investigation specific to
this point you have to do it in Outlook
this is why I was talking about the
headers we found the client IP address
this is the one that matches in the
headers and then you find the the IP
address in the logs imagine in the logs
for the system of uh it was the AWS we
can go there
so
when you're the the IP address from the
client is uh in the middle we found that
in the in artwork in uh in with the
email analysis right and then we jumped
on the on the server and we're going
through all the logs there are so many
logs out there and at some point I
started the investigating the user agent
that we saw uh previously from the from
the attack
and uh all of the time it appeared that
all the other requests were done with
this agent the because in uh
yeah we had two infrastructure set up by
the attacker but they mailed was were
sent by this one so this is how I was
able to pinpoint let's say that these
incidents are actually together they're
linked together
the IP address and the user agent
together for this incident it sounds
funny because it's so simple right
because you look at uh and uh a user
rate and say okay these things much but
initially because we didn't have the
visibility that we wanted to we were not
we didn't know what was happening inside
the organization so that's why you
thought it was two different incidents
and these two things actually probably
was one and the mitigation actions
behind that are completely different as
you can imagine business compromise from
a whole domain recovery
okay I think
did you sleep during the incidence
response
no unfortunately no I didn't sleep last
night as well so you can imagine my
whole life
you should sleep more
I can sleep when I die that's what I say
to myself I almost died yesterday but
that's a different story
yeah I believe that concludes oh I have
one last question what is in your
opinion the best size for incident
response team for investigation
for the investigation
I won't say
about how many people you need I would
say how which roles you need you
definitely need someone to speak to the
client an engagement manager call him
whatever you like and then you need to
have at least one or two responders you
will be amazed how much overhead well it
is created once you investigate because
the clients ask questions all the time
what are you doing what's your status
what's your progress stuff like that so
you need to have someone in the between
that match the client expectations it's
really important as well that is
important as well but I would ideally it
would be let's say three to four minimum
and of course that depends on the size
of the organization
other rules yeah you have the responders
yeah the roles I mean you have someone
who's going to be speaking and the ones
that are gonna be like on the technical
side what should they because they the
logic size that's why I say three
persons at least because then you put
extra costs with the utilization aspect
all that stuff you need definitely
someone to be in the meeting between the
client but once you say that you have
three extra person let's say you need to
have different skill sets not all of
them should know for example Windows
someone has to know how to imagine the
Dual in forensics someone has to know
how to do Cloud investigation and this
is how actually this is like the concept
of very team right or very teamers the
attackers no one knows everything there
so why not have the same concept in uh
in forensics everybody expects you to
know everything in this field
unfortunately and that's not the case
that's why we need to collaborate more
yep that concludes the talk thank you
very much
[Applause]
[Music]