[Music]
thank you
thank you thank you guys
um so hello everyone good afternoon
um
first of all I want just to say thank
you to the organization to Delena to
Milos just to allow me to stay here it's
a great great pleasure I'm super happy
to stay here it's my first time in
balcon and in Serbia
so I hope you will enjoy my talk
so I'm going just to start in the
Country Way
that talk used to start
I have a question to you
um how many of you are from the 80s
okay
how many of you have read The
NeverEnding Story
cool
and what's the movie
really nice
so I was so so fond of The Neverending
Story so probably you already know the
the history behind
but I see the many of incidents and apts
like they never end in a story you can
just finish the history just giving
another name
um from Fantasia
to the APT so we are talking about
traductors and we are going just to talk
about iocs the timeline for sure so
let's start just a little bit
brief introduction about me
uh Sandra Bardon thank you for the
presentation
um currently I'm working for a United
Nations International Computing Center
[Applause]
exercises it can be today one topic
exercises red teaming exercises purple
teaming exercises
and
helping as well into the Fantastic
because my my core my main expertise is
just in that wheel and as well in
exploitation I used to to teach at the
University different universities as
well
but I had a conversation yesterday quite
nice that I started my work as a blue
teamer
during some years at the Spanish joins
cyber command it was so nice doing some
forensics Central hunting but I decided
I mean there's a person gave me an
opportunity just to to join the the red
team
uh uh and I yes
just go directly to to the open side
site to the dark side I will say to the
red team
[Music]
in Spain many many years and after that
I just moved to the to Estonia so I know
the cold cold winter
I mean more harder than here I guess
um doing some research related to band
testing on ICS industrial control
systems and as well service station
electrical substances and power plants
and so on doing some research in related
to pen test that kind of systems
teaching courses as well and
participating in different kind of
exercises all of them in in the red team
or leading the the red team
so
um
I'm going to have to stop talking about
me
first of all languages to give you a
really small introduction about what is
unicc that is the place that I import to
uh I'm not going just to sell you
anything I promise it will be really
really small and after that we just go
directly to tissue some technical
details about the incident that we
suffer inside United Nations one of the
incidents I will say
and next steps for sure
so
um United Nations International computer
center it's an organization Under the
Umbrella of UN
we have 50 years
of experience just giving some digital
Solutions some different agencies or
organization Under the
Umbrella of a un right now we are
supporting and helping more than 85 I
think it's right now it's not 70 clients
it's like more than 82 at least
so we are providing some digital
Solutions like at the very very
beginning like hosting
but some from some years ago we are
providing as well some cyber security
services so
um
what are the agencies or the
organization that we help or we support
uh for sure United Nations they work as
a Organization
for example the World Bank
um
uh immigration for example
[Music]
um
the U.N volunteers U.N government I mean
many many many of different kind of
organizations I started yes you I joined
at the beginning of this year
and I'm not used just to know all of the
all of the name of the different
organization it's a little bit
complicated to to be just to remember
all of them just to show you
um
very brief a map where our customers or
our the audiences or organization that
we help are around the world we
represent most of the of the countries
and we are physically in Geneva
Switzerland Valencia Spain Rome and
rudisi in Italy and New York USA
so there's some really small highlights
about where what exactly we are doing in
cyber security just to help this kind of
organization that we have seen two
slides before so we have the the common
secure service
that mainly we are providing threat
intelligence for the the overall
audiences well not the overall some of
the some of the audiences
we have a shock 24 7 monitoring and
providing some information as well to
all of this kind of um organizations
and we adapt to the technologies that
they that our partner or our customer
just need to deal with it
uh for sure it's a common sock so most
of us probably we are using the same
technology in the in the system but we
can adapt just new technologies as well
to the Technologies of the every client
and there is a
really gross integration between the
people working from the shock
and the incident response team that is
composed by the fears as well for some
good reversal we have one of the
reversal from Malwarebytes uh we have
some sun instructor so we have really
really good people technical people just
there just to analyze the different
incidents like this one the languages
you talk about
and as well we have an offensive unit
uh that's my my power that I'm I'm happy
to work
um we just do some red teaming and Pen
testing property teaming
um in different kind of infrastructure
with different Technologies uh Network
like inside a web
um so we can just adapt if it's remote
if it can be I mean the paint is
completely on site if it's a Blackberry
white box so it depends on the
requirements of every project mainly but
we have like a 360
um vision
well this is like a commercial sentence
but I mean everything is completely
joined
we have like different units but all of
us I don't care if they are part of the
blue team or we are part of the red team
we need just reward together if not I
mean we are in the same direction at the
end so I I see the work like like that
so but let's go for just you to dig a
little bit into the incident related one
of the incidents because we have a lot
as probably most of you in in the
organization but I I would love to
assume to ask you first
another question
how many of you have been involved
in an incident of your I mean solving an
incident in your organization company
now or in the past
well
probably most of you
who can tell me that you are completely
sure
that you have all the details and you
have remediate
and you have mitigate
everything on all servers and all hosts
on
connected devices
yeah
okay probably I have a contract to you
see you on uh
[Music]
okay okay I mean it's it's quite
difficult right
yeah
correct so you never know
if the traductor is still on your
systems
or you have all the evidences from the
past
um just to identify all of the iocs and
all the activity that it's running on
the different servers and so on right
so always it's quite quite complicated
so just for that reason
uh I call this presentation The
Neverending Story because it's a like an
infinite Loop
so let's rock
well
um one year ago almost
on 20 October 2021
um
an organization just was notified that
four servers were compromised and just
the day after
uh we were activated our incident
response team were activated just to
help support analyze everything related
to this incident well at the very
beginning is yes okay just four servers
but exactly which ones you know
I need to assume give like a warning
about this talk
because unfortunately I cannot talk
about any threat actor I will say
attackers cyber criminals I will say
traductor in general
but
in United Nations we representing most
of the countries around the world
so we cannot say that okay this country
it's attacking this country
for obvious reasons I said you probably
know if you know how to read between
lines
so
um I'm really sorry but I will call
thread actor in general okay or
attackers or whoever
so the day after uh we were activated
and we face this incident at the very
beginning
um into different phases but at the same
time simultaneously
first one the backward investigation
phase just to identify uh all of the
ttps the tactics techniques and
procedures related to the to the
incident that's that makes sense right
just to create the the threat
intelligence related to this incident
and if it has any
um relation or any join with any
incident in the past
and as well at the same time they
contain maintenance response phase just
to monitor everything that was happening
just to correlate probably with future
events
or just you to identify more potential
attacks related or involved the Korean
incident
[Music]
so
um just identifying uh analyzing this
ttp's different tdps
we just realized that it wasn't just
four servers
it was related to 24 horse compromises
at the very beginning who knows later
so
um
the the window of the attacks on 2021
was just one week
from uh 18th of October to 25 of October
as a red teamer
I see that come on it's a really really
small window or time you know usually
the the attacks
are not related to to apts
we are talking about
not only one week probably a lot of
weeks months or
years who knows
um but during the the investigation we
realize
that the same traductor started to
attack and to Target our systems
one year a half before from 28th of
April and 2020.
and we see some connections and some the
same kind of actions over the the
systems so but we don't know exactly if
it's completely link it
the attacks that were done
on 2020
and on 2021 and who knows right now
so the three doctor in the past in 2020
they try to
explore open collect
a lot of files
that contains sensible data
when we say sensible data it's quite
important because if you remember I'm
not I'm not saying that this is the case
of the refugees for example I'm just
giving just an example stupid example
but just to let you know the the
importance of the information that it's
contained in some files for example just
try to imagine that this agency or this
organization is related to refugees and
it's uh
um for example for a for a mission in a
specific Zone some people were deployed
just there and they need just to
reconnect it and they just need to
receive instructions what happened in
some of these documents are completely
changed just giving a different
um instructions so can you imagine what
can happen
if an attack on our service uh
uh are completely related to emission of
refugees or something like that I mean
it can be crucial right
[Music]
but on 2020 one
um the traductor just went directly to
the file server so that's one of the
points that I see come on they they were
just there before because just go
directly to the file server just just
with that clue we just step back back
back and we realized that they were
there from 2020.
they tried just to collect some files
from the um
10 days ago until now I mean in 2021
but
they try just you to open and yes you
see the information contain it in that
in those kind of file but it was
encrypted with a really strong password
so they couldn't see anything
cool
[Music]
um
so
remarks just at the very beginning about
this it's like the question that I that
I asked you
before it's like okay we have some Clues
we have a lot of evidences because
we were recollecting
one gigabyte of data per day and in some
cases up to 20 Gigabytes per day
so it's really greasy I mean the the
amount of um of data that we we had to
to analyze during this incident
but
um
you never know
if you are missing something and if you
have missed something like uh the the
previous or the the the first attack
Vector you know
I hate meetings sorry I hate doing
reports sorry as well I'm more focused
on the technical part I know that they
are so important but at this point
they were I mean they were crucial the
meetings a daily briefing we don't need
to talk about ours
we just need just to go directly to the
information just to have the key people
in that kind of meetings
um just you to
to explain
what is the point that we are
and as well just giving some
explanation about the the the
analysis that we have done the day
before and where exactly that we are
going to do during today
so um
really really brief daily briefings but
they are quite important
so let's go uh to the timeline
uh timeline if there is any forensic
here
recently
forensic analyze it here
no well the timeline is
um is the key in the resolution of an
incident you know
so just to establish what happened when
where
so if we established from the very
beginning of on 18th sorry yes on 18th
of October we realized that for another
remote system they just try to access
the domain controller come on just the
the the first attack Victory is just you
try to to get the the main controller
it's really crazy right because yes they
were just there on the network from
before
so they just write here just to use well
they try no they use the TGT so the
ticket granted ticket
um that it's probably you already know
but it's um
and a user authentication token that is
requested to the to the ticket granting
service in order just to get access and
to join the domain so they try it from
the very beginning from that remote host
just to join the domain one of our
domains right so they just went to the
to the game
um just after that they just use some
Powershell scripts just to do some
lateral movements through uh win on a
win RM
and just after that they try just to set
up command and control
of cobalty strike but the that's very
funny
but the the antivirus because just
detect it and it wasn't allowed how many
of you know what is Cobalt
cool I mean I see more people just
around there
um just for those
um who doesn't know what is Koval
I really love it
a spread simmer
um Koval it's a framework common and
controller that can be used in the
create team activities it's quietly used
in governments and in some countries
uh in the offensive bar
and it's quite quite nice because yes
you can just set up like different
servers just to do many different things
and you can just customize everything
with your own scripts with Cortana
scripts so you can just join as well uh
different Frameworks different common
controls and just to create your own
binary sophisticated blah blah blah uh
setup listener in in Koval and you can
just start using the different Bitcoins
you know
um it's quite quite nice I recommend you
just you use at least the trial just you
test it and see what kind I mean how
powerful it can be I really love Cobalt
and I knew Rafi the developer of this
tool of this framework and he's a very
nice guy that he's working a lot every
day just to improve uh that will
um time by time I have to tell you that
it's not free tool
it costs a lot if I remember well 350
500 dollars American dollars
per server sober license
uh you can just look for that on the
dark web or whatever
all of them came with a surprise so good
luck
always trust me
but anyway we we can just continue with
the incident
just some minutes after
the trade actor just creates
a binary
unexecute title I don't know how many of
you know what is chaiso
cool
so it's a it contains a socks proxy a
four and five
um
forward
some packets from one chord to the other
and this is used commonly used in the
red team or inoffensive operations uh
just to set up a pivot to do lateral
movements or people to another part of
the network right
[Music]
the following actions are related yes
you set up that pivot
um I mean the the end report the exit
Port
um and yes you configure as as follows
so from the DC that they were I mean
that they compromise
they wanted just to go and just to do
some lateral movements uh inside the
network so they went directly to the
Usos W
shoes that it's a quite common I mean
it's already known for both of you right
it's just to update all of the servers
and hosts related to Windows
so they just do lateral movement throw
or 135 and they use yesu as well 138 35
139 and 445
just to do some recognition through the
network so just thinking about that
attacker
you need to be completely stealthy
if you get one server and you need just
to do the reconnect sense uh phase just
you see
how many servers or holes or in general
are in that segment right so it's not
just you use a map with the top 100
reports or all the ports that's I mean
it's foreign
ERS kill you
so this case is exactly the same
I can't recognize exactly the same
ways just to do everything you need to
be always stealthy so at this time they
just do their recording scenes through
main mainly three ports
and just with that they could do a throw
a power cell while liner just your pivot
and just to do the lateral movements to
the to the Usos
um and as well from from that server
they download some common and controls
they just execute some malicious Powers
all scripts uh
um that it was a store in the in the
databases in the database sorry
and from the versus they just went back
to the domain controller uh why just you
set up for first time one of the common
uh common and controls that they are
going just to use
so whenever the the common control Wars
install it completely on the system on
the DC and on the buses it was
throw we are going just to analyze later
I did both more in detail
uh program data that Ln key and for sure
that it's pointing to a scheduled task
that it called Windows updates
how many of you I mean how many of you
have been involved in any offensive
operations
okay
do you use yes you call services or
schedule tasks like
this is malware not right just tell me
one name
I used to use Windows updates come on
in The Blue Team Jesse Windows update no
no no this is not fake this is quite
real right we need just to maintain
because come on we need to patch so
that's a really tricky trick
that it's commonly used and as well in
real incidents as you can just see here
so
um
and again we can just solve different
kind of pivots not only our
throwing winner M but as well to thieves
and as well
throw a RDP come on RDP it's quite
common it's quite easy yes you get it
right
but I'm I was so so curious because uh
some of the connections were the
duration I mean of the connection were
more than 40 minutes
probably it's because the monitoring
power they didn't do uh well like in the
best way or who knows we are going to
see more in detail
for sure if you see uh the the time
I have been talking about just one hour
and I told you before that the window
attack
was due in one week so this is just an
example just the the starting point but
the the report of this incident it's
well many hundreds of pages so you can
just try to to imagine the rest of them
I don't have any enough time just to
talk about all of the the timeline and
about all of the iocs
but the butter it's always the same
or quite similar I will say
so this is just a small piece
this this is not the whole diagram about
the lateral movements so I don't know
yeah
this was the starting point the remote
host like that try to get access and and
got access to the domain controller
and just after that go to the a w source
and from then I mean yes mainly when
they if you have the domain controller
you have everything right if you have a
golden ticket
as well
so you can just go through the the
overall Network and here it's a small
representation of the of the overall
diagram of lateral movements
so
talking about and remembering I mean you
probably remember that I told you that
24 hosts were completely compromised
um from a routine perspective
what will you do first after get some
foothold into a system
just answer me please I mean it's it's
more than seven there are lots of people
drinking rakia outside and I'm really
happy that you are here but just try to
collaborate between us
yeah yeah it will be nice as well
any idea
yeah that's but for what reason
correct yeah probably I mean
that's my weight he has to act
first get a photo probably to get
persistence or
do some privileged escalation and after
that what is the most important part
persistency
I mean if they reboot the system you are
off you're over
so they install malicious persistency uh
in all over the the servers and horse
that were compromised
um but one tricky part
that we be they know how they how they
did it is that they were using some
domain accounts
but the legit domain accounts
yeah that's that's really scary
and they create a new local admin
accounts just to use some Services I've
used some Services yes you get
persistence or just to install some rods
on remote access tools
I just use send and receive some some
commands like aorus and W and DW agents
as well just to set up the scheduled
tasks of a Windows update and so on so
let's go just to to see
some of the iocs
let me drink a little bit
well I'm not going to tell you always
did probably it's a local
train here
so
um first of all the binary the
executable MSI hub.x
that at the end
[Music]
um
well creates a channel
to download the the command and control
and how can this Winery can just get the
the configuration because all of the
binaries as you created the common
control needs to have some some
configuration just with something that
it was a store in the registry
with the style name this binary just get
the the configuration of the of the
binary and as well
um gets some information related to I
mean from install process into the the
registry uh just to to have some cells
using
um
Power Cell Scripts
the Windows update as well I mean and
again
that's uh just with that you can just
get the program data that Ellen key and
from the program data that lnt that it's
a binary encoded uh just from that
binary you can just decode it
and and they offer skates the script and
you can just get
the the desktop that anywhere in as you
see more in detail and the desktopini is
mainly the the common and control that
they use yes you send and receive some
some commands and some files right
something more
ssa.x some of you know what is SSA
no
cool
it's quite similar to title right
but this case is over TLS
so it's
um
it's a secure socket funneling instead
of tunneling but at the end it's a socks
proxy
uh completely Cipher over TLS Just For
What in
um
uh some data from a portal to the other
one right
but at this time
um they just use a power cell script
that install that binary the executable
into the system
but as you probably know on Windows did
you install a binary without a
certificate you are over right
so they were quite smart because they
just installed some certificates related
to the certification Authority so just
without the binary it's
just you to be used into the system so
that's that's really nice
from the faces a perspective for sure
uh and as well we just could identify
some of the rats the remote that has
tools that were used like aorus or
wagen.x
and as well on the last part you can
just see main.exe
that's probably at the very beginning is
just like quite common but it was
detected by the the antivirus that that
they had like
um like chisel so you already know
thistle right
sorry
who
um
well they delete some of the files
during the the attack campaign yeah just
to try to
avoid giving us some evidences just to
identify them
right
so our related to the Windows update
schedule task
um mainly it's um executes a power cell
script and just with that you can just
get a uh the program data that's
with the obfuscation and the execution
of the file you can just get the desktop
that ini so mainly is yes respond a
powerful
script as system as you can just see
here
so with this kind of schedule task
probably they just do this kind of
actions just to do some privileged
escalation right just to get system
on every server on any horse that they
were compromise
so they they program data that that Ela
sorry Ln key
um
this kind of file was observed in
different parts of a of the rest of the
horse so it's it's like not kind of
randomly but it was like in
um many many many different parts on
every server on any host that we just
analyze so that's pretty good
the script just the open skates uh the
second power power cell that it say the
file desktop that any
and what it does contain well mainly
it's a common control that just send and
receive some command and some files
throw or 443 that's all mainly
the multimedia reports here is scheduled
us it's a skeletal test mostly well it
has some differences from the previous
one but it's quite quite similar so just
execute the powerful script uh after
that
um get the configuration from the from
the registry and they offer skate and
execute another binary that it's.com
so again is just your to get system over
the over the different services and host
and it just spawn a power cell process
um running the script
into the into the registry of the of the
service right
so the register key that is they say the
security health score just the
obfuscates the script
and points to the binary that it's.com
and at the end
um
well
at the end mainly they share they were
restored in different locations but they
serve they exactly the same Global key
and exactly the same user alien and as
you can just see they are just quite
common I mean Mozilla
um Chrome Safari Apple weapit so they
are just targeting
um most of the the common
um web browsers that they are using in
Windows right or in any platform at the
end
and this is uh quite nice the service
that is Ms
hub.x just get the configuration from
the register key
uh mainly it's a portable executive
execution sorry executable it's because
I was just seeing the the guy behind you
that I have 10 minutes more only
um of 32 bytes
that mainly implemented the service just
to get persistence over the over the the
old horse compromise so as you can just
see the.net a classes are https my
service program and sell
so you can just try to imagine what this
this executable is doing over the system
something quite important that I would
love just to remark is that the default
Beacon interval is set up to one hour
and a half
that's quite nice because you need to be
a stealthy you don't need just to
receive the Callback of a beacon just
you receive some commands or whatever
like every minute that's a very
iterative interactive mode
each one I just have one hour and 30
minutes but at this point
as a red teamer I used to use guitar
you know just you try to randomize a
little bit it's not like one hour and 30
minutes always it can be 1 hour and 20
one hour and 35 something like that just
try to avoid the detection by default I
will say in the case of the the blue
teamers right
and the ssf
so probably you already know I explained
before
um at the end it's a Powers script that
just tried to unzip the zip file
containing all of that you can just see
at the at the screen and it's exactly
the same that I explained before so just
the executable
um that is synced by the certification
Authority certificate and that's all
it's it's done just without they can
just use and just to set up some socks
proxy over a socks four and five
well I'm
probably I mean how many of you knows
Mitri attack
cool almost all of you
um I had a pleasure just to collaborate
with Mitre some years ago
um as a red teamer because they really
need yes you try to impersonate or just
you replay some apts we just did
assembly exactly the same
attack vectors as a apt-29 during an
exercise and it was quite not just to
collaborate with them in all the years
you facilitate
this framework for the blue teamers
right so at this incident
we can just see that they
we can just identify tactics like the
initials initial access the execution
persistence privilege escalation defense
evasion they don't have a lot of
defensive engine so they
they didn't need just to use a lot of
techniques just to avoid edrs and so on
right
um credential access just at the very
beginning they use DC sync who knows
what is this is Inc
cool
easiest a technique just try to
impersonate the domain controller with
mimikats for example
uh just without the next step or is
golden ticket right again
yeah
so they they they they use it
the discovery that we have been talking
about and as well lateral movement
collection but the building is filtrate
any file any data
and at the end we couldn't identify as
well the impact
I mean the the technique related to the
impact
because all the servers were up and
running
I mean they I guess they try just to
exfiltrate
or just to do something more but
thanks to to our incident Response Team
probably they just were killed and over
in the overall
um
segment of a well different segments of
the network
so at the end we had to stop the
investigation for many different reasons
that I'm not going just to talk about
but we just gave some recommendations
in the short term a billion term a
long-term and classified by uh if it's
quite important quite risky median or
low
but just talking in general
please yes you do at an asset inventory
how many of you can tell me and can
guarantee
that you have a complete asset inventory
in your organization
nobody right I mean it's almost
completely impossible
but we need just to reinforce this idea
as well
uh inventory of the gpos just try to
identify all of the the gpos on all
servers on all the main controllers just
to erase all of them that I really don't
need it or just to create new ones
um some of the ideas were deployed but
we'd recommend just to deploy
edrs on all connected devices just to
Monitor and response in a
um in a good time right
and as well
um we monitor with a Renault 1cm this
this agency after this incident for sure
related to user and groups into the
domain yes we need just to have an
inventory of different users just to
give the correct privileges
Implement as well the local
Administration administrator a password
service that's mainly a store the
password of the local administrator into
the domain controller and it's only
accessible in some specific
circumstances right
for sure I'll review the network
segmentation for SMB version three I
mean the last one and blah blah blah
much much much more but
do you miss anything
yeah please
probably it was from 2020
but we didn't know we didn't have enough
evidences just to say okay this is the
entry point right
but we are talking always about
technology right
right correct
what about people
uh in the red team exercises we used to
test not only the defenses
as well the Defenders
so this is a
really nice video
I really love it a really good friend
just send it to me some months ago and I
say come on I have to to saw it and just
to see with you so just enjoy because
this is like the common offensive
operations are done and it's quite quite
similar to most of the incidents right
so that's it
foreign
[Laughter]
[Applause]
thank you
foreign
[Laughter]
[Applause]
thank you
quite funny right
[Applause]
so just after the incident was solved
and blah blah blah blah blah what's next
what do you think that we can just do
after doing some consultancy just try to
help you know yes you put some
recommendation blah blah blah
yeah probably
come on do pen test
every year
an external pen test every two years
that's my recommendation always
great team in
yes you test as well people from The
Blue Team Vibes or just to collaborate
between all of us purple teaming
or
what's more this is quite important and
it's always miss it you know the Seesaw
attack
come on we are always talking between us
technical people we are really weak we
really a geek
but what about people that they don't
really understand the technology they
are using the same infrastructure right
so what happened with them
well from the offensive unit
um we are just doing pen testing for
teaming proper teaming I mean I guess I
talked about it before it is and also
simulating some reductors
but this is quite important
the table top exercises this is just to
train key people the sea level the
decision makers
just to train them in case of a real
incident
it's quite quite important as well as
appendix or our red team that's more
funny probably
but this is quite important as well so
if you have any question I'm more than
happy just you answered you or we can
just talk later with rakia beers so
whatever that you that you need
yep
just wait for the mic please
I gotta hurt you sorry
yeah my question is regarding uh
monitoring because okay incidents happen
nobody noticed and the attacker was in
the network and doing whatever he's
doing I didn't see the signs that
sellers were hardened and that is really
important because if these servers were
hardened really good a lot of actions
will not be possible to be done and also
monitoring where you got a few new
created local accounts and nobody is
watching in CM or checking these reports
it's really strange
yeah you're completely right I mean I
will say exactly
do you answer your own question
um if they implement
really good monitoring tools just to be
connected to the CM to this to the sock
mainly
if they just go Implement edrs if they
just Implement Guru gpos
if they just do really good hardening of
the whole service and as well for sure
to the domain controller
I cannot say that it's completely
impossible just to have these incidents
but it will be more difficult probably
yeah they are completely right
just for that reason after this incident
just happened
I mean this is just the NeverEnding
Story
people just react come on prevent
you know always the same story
so thank you for your answer just for
your question sorry so
didn't you have like a big red alarm
when when like the local admin accounts
were created because it's like the big
alarm in the CM or in a in a soccer team
well thank you for your question as well
because I heard it a lot of times that
in some networks local admins were
created or admin accounts and like there
is no monitoring or they are sleeping or
there's like nothing that they don't
detect it because of a big alarm if you
get the admin account created
well
we just uh we just were activated
in 2021
Park we just saw the the attack the
entry point was on one year a half
before
and we didn't have enough evidence is
just to know how they create
local admin accounts so that's a true
key part but I mean I cannot say 100
percent sure that that was the the way
that they were able just to create that
kind of accounts it's really tricky that
far but sometimes you have some Shadows
you know in the investigations
for sure right now they are completely
being monitored by our CM by our sock
uh they deploy some edrs and with many
of I mean following some of our
recommendations they are completely more
safe than before
so that's quite nice but I cannot
guarantee as well that they are not
being attacked right now by the same
three adapter so who knows
thank you
uh you said uh 20 or so assets were
compromised and had persistency
mechanisms installed which
percentage of these persistencies would
be stopped by implementing Labs because
Labs will wipe local admins on the next
update
well
um
that's a tricky question because I
cannot tell you exactly I don't remember
I didn't do the maths I mean the most
the most persistence is or some
persistence the most persistencies yes I
cannot tell you a number exactly but
it's the most yes the most right thank
you
is all done
so okay
the first question is how much did the
incident response process last
sorry how for how long did the incident
response process last from your side how
long have you been working on that case
much more time
I mean the report they ask you to tell
you a number
it's more than 300 pages
so you can just imagine then I mean just
telling you that we receive one giga one
gigabyte of data daily to analyze and in
some cases up to 20. I mean it was
really crazy
okay and you mentioned that you
effectively stopped the attack but did
you link the attackers to a specific
organization or apt group or to other
active attacks or past attacks
yeah that's uh that's a good question
um
this is the spoiler
uh sorry
I cannot tell you anything about the
trade actor
just with the two faces that I commented
from the very beginning
we just create the tcbs just try to
identify if it was just before on the
systems and just to use it as well for
probably next uh incident
so but at the very beginning we didn't
know anything about the this reductor
it's clear it's cool
any more questions
okay
hi uh you said that edr's helped is
there any preference on choosing the ADR
or do you think that any ADR would help
well there
are quite quite good I'm again just to
sell you a specific technology
[Music]
um mostly all of them are quite good
okay thank you thank you
anymore
[Music]
we're hungry of questions right did you
just got like Windows machines
compromised or have also some Linux
servers that you're around it got
compromised mainly windows
only or mainly windows
so thank you everybody it has been a
pleasure yes you'll be here
[Applause]
[Music]