[Music]
thank you
welcome back everyone our next topic is
on Hardware hacking please welcome
vladani College
thank you hi everyone
so let us start so this is going to be a
talk about Hardware hacking some
interesting stuff I hope
so let me first start
a little bit about me so I'm not going
into details more about me but I just
want to say that that Balkan actually
ticks all the box of my interests
so it's perfect conference to be here so
and always glad to be in in beautiful
city of novice nuts I hope you are
enjoying your time here these days after
two years of being far far away from
here
so I hope this will be interesting so we
are going to discuss a little bit about
problems with current problems with the
Hardware security and how and what we
can do to address this situation and and
how to actually start doing Hardware
testing
so first thing that I want to make sure
that we all understand is difference
between hardware and software so I I
know we all know what are harder
Hardware
uh strong things made of stuff and
software is something imaginary that can
run or that stuff or in the cloud
recently but when we are discussing
harder here we are talking about devices
which do not run any explicit user code
so they come already with programs on
them if they need any programs so
everything is embedded in that package
and we can just use this device for
every any purpose that we might need to
use that device on the other side when
we speak about software we speak about
user space software so something that is
created or loaded onto device by the
user itself so something that is under
our control generally at least the hope
so it is under our control
uh and of course operating system itself
is is part of that problem right now is
that this distinguish between hardware
and software is getting a little bit
more hazy so it is no longer clearly
said because for example you have modern
TVs which would be embedded device by
definition but you still can run your
own code on it because you can download
stuff from Google market or any market
and run your user space software so this
is becoming more and more interesting
distinguished but it is not so easy
anymore but we for the purpose of this
talk we are going to keep this strict
separation between those and we are not
going to address that fun stuff
we will leave that for some other balcon
few years in the future I hope
so let me start first but we all work
with software daily and we accept the
software is not secure
because it is controlled by user itself
user can put any kind of software and
can modify this software and make it
make it unsafe but this is not something
new this is the situation that started
long long time ago since the first time
we had any software practically running
on anything so
as soon as we have connected computers
we had the first real malware it was
called creeper it was developed in 1971
and ran on arpanet which was like 30
computers connected around the world so
Within These 30 computers there was one
guy who decided oh I want to make
something fun and he created a creeper
software which was
simple so if idea is did this piece of
code will just move between different
PDP 10 computers and just print message
that I'm showing here
and after that he would migrate itself
to another node in the network
so and the time when we get first virus
we get first antivirus so another guy
who was sick of this game created two
called Reaper and that was first
antivirus
so we started implementing software
controls and the sole purpose of Reaper
is to search for creeper or nodes into
this extinguish it
uh that was a long time ago but we still
can see this code because
there is a game called core War so it is
no longer so important but when I was
young my sole dream was to participate
in Cold War games so core war is
practically a sandbox with some
imaginary Assembly Language and you have
two pieces of code which try to kill
each other
so there are a lot of algorithms that
they are using but the idea is one
program must kill all threads from
another program
so it is still available I believe so we
had one competition this year so if you
are interested in that you can search it
out
so we are aware that software is not
safe not secure but we usually assume
that our Hardware
might actually be secure
I'm not sure if that is true
but for the purpose of this call we will
consider that t t 800 is still far away
in the future and that he will not
attack us immediately
so I at least I hope so
so let us see actually what is the
current situation and do we have
something to fear
let's address simple Hardware tool and
let's try to analyze
threat model for for this Hardware tool
so it is very simple and very very old
piece of Hardware it fulfills definition
of how that cannot run any user software
on it and it was developed for one
single purpose
to paint male fingernails in Black
during the time we discovered that it
can be useful for other things so we
were hacking our tool already so we
discovered that we can hit things with
it either there are nails
and we started using it
but thread model on this device is
fairly simple so it can be misused by us
or somebody can steal it and try to
paint our toenails on black in black
so protection of such device is fairly
simple so you need just to rely on
physical security
so lock your tools
and you are safe to go
but this is really simple model let us
try something also old but a little bit
more complex than a simple Hammer so
let's speak about my one of my favorite
computers as I already mentioned I like
retro computers and to be honest I spend
too much time with jarco in in Retro
Room this year so don't don't hate me
for that
this is a bigger computer Amiga 500 and
it is not so old I think some of you
might be as old as I am and might have
opportunity to play with this computer
and security model of this computer is
actually also quite simple
this computer was rarely connected and
most of the problems that we had this
computer security related is when we
exchanged backups of versions of backup
versions of software in order to test
them for our friends
and that is the time when we could
caught some malicious virus which the
the worst one was actually destroying
floppy device so it would just start
hitting heads until they fall off
but still that is just vandalism there
is no real threat you can lose your
floppy drive and that's it so there was
no personal data there was nothing that
can endanger endanger you in in using
this computer
and hacking
with this platform it was usually meant
we are going to find a way to employ
so we have developed a lot of expansions
for this computer to make it work
something that it is not supposed to
work so now we have connectivity we can
connect Amigas to internet we can have
more powerful processor although it is
not supposed to have more powerful
processor so we have developed a lot of
harder hacks in order to enhance and
make this platform uh useful even to
this day
okay
so what actually went wrong since that
time
so first thing is future creep
so it is very common in harder forums if
you post something that you have done in
Hardware that you will get smashed
whatever you did if you could create
blinking lights by using nf555 there
will be somebody who asked oh but five
you use Danny 555 you can use
microcontroller it's much more versatile
that then you go and implement it in
microcontroller and still you have your
blinking lights
and you post again proud of yourself
that you upgraded put it and then why
did you spend so much time programming
microcontroller already can be done by
simple na55 which is I think 50 years
old already
so this uh
make a lot of problems because right now
microprocessors are really cheap so I
have here one example this is paduk PMS
150 it costs like three cents when
bought in China
and it is full featured microcontroller
so it is much cheaper than a formation
nf555 so when designers make decision
about which kind of Hardware they will
put
in their device that they are right now
developing they are no longer bound by
oh let's go with chip
because everything is cheap of course
when you find it right now we have
problem with a lot of harder devices but
generally microcontrollers become really
cheap and omnipresent so even in a
simple greeting card that you see the
thing you have small microprocessor
inside
so devices are becoming much more
powerful and much clever much more
functional than they were before so they
can run a lot of software and hardware
and sometimes we are not even aware of
what is possible to accomplish by using
simple device
of course then we came to another great
idea and that is let's connect those
dumb devices and create Internet of
Things
so we have decided to integrate our
smart devices because why not not
imprinting us so we have a lot more fun
we can control each other devices and
they can speak with themselves they can
serve and make our life better is it the
truth we'll see might be but as one of
the consequences of this is that they
are integrated in our daily life so we
have these devices everywhere everywhere
around us
and we sometimes are not even aware of
those and
if you recall few months ago there was a
big pile of news that some Google
programmers started by yelling oh we
have sent the entire AI
so is it true that I don't think so but
I that would be not not the first time
that I'm not right
so if I don't believe it it doesn't mean
it's not true so there is a big chance
that if you don't already have sentient
AI that soon we will help
and I think we had a many many many
movies
which told us that sentient I is not
really good idea
but that didn't prevent us
so we are pretty destructive species so
we have
one idea that drives our progress and
that is our
wish to destroy as much of our species
as possible in a very simple way so we
decided okay we have Smart devices we
have maybe Essentials so let's let's
give it the guns
again I cannot stop thinking about
Terminator films all the time whenever
I'm watching stuff like this
so what is going to control and and
prevent these devices to make their own
decisions which might not be aligned
with what we actually want
so right now we still believe that
humans are in control so the guy behind
I think this is remote control I really
hope so
or at least big powerful kill switch
because if this this
what is it like dogs start running at me
I'm
I don't know what they're going to do
but I will not run far away for sure
so there is nothing preventing this
device to be confused what is Real Enemy
and what is just bystander so
so I'm not sure how much of of of good
idea is to to to give guns to autonomous
machines but hey somebody thought it is
great idea so let's do it
uh but okay let's let's uh move from
those uh scary things let's
start analyzing something that is a
little bit more close to us so as I
mentioned uh these devices are
everywhere so first one that I actually
encountered many many years ago over
smart bulbs
I had friend who had great idea he
bought a bulb connected into his home
and connected it to his Facebook account
because why not it's feature that is
supported and in all its wisdom idea was
okay when somebody tagged you on a
picture your bulb will change a color to
the predominant color of the picture
so we have a lot of fun and we decided
okay we'll put
fully black pictures
and tag him
so okay this was just a joke on his side
but uh problem is if it can be also
dangerous because if somebody decides to
rob you it is nice to to leave you out
off site
so if you are in dark you cannot see
what is happening around you and you
might be in not so good position
so this this kind of Integrations are
everywhere and they are
uh pretty tricky because sometimes even
manufacturers are not aware of
consequences of such features even if
they know that they implemented these
features
so how my favorite topic so I had many
many presentations about this topic and
this is about connected cars and not
just connected cars so car should have
only one purpose to drive us from point
A to point B safely and securely
but again we decided we want to program
our cars
so like any computer so it becomes
practically robot on Wheel
so it can be autonomous so we see that
there are many Teslas with self
navigation features that will drive
drive themselves while you gently sleeps
and then we also have one question what
will happen when this car encounters our
Serbian roads
that would be real test to see what will
happen and what will happen if if
there must be decision by the car is it
going to kill one person that drives the
car or one person that is in front of
the car
so that is ethical dilemma that
computers are not good at solving
so people will try to find another
solution but computers are limited and
they do only what is programmed and
their ultimate programming is to prevent
uh driver to be harmed
and even if it is not self-driving or
autonomous autonomous car in in modern
carbs there is about 200 different
programmable pieces of hardware
so most of us think about there is one
big computer that that is in charge of
our car but that is far from the road so
if we first have one that controls our
comfort
so it is inside cabin and control stuff
like AC there is another one who
controls our airbags there is another
one who controls motor rail uh who
controls transmission units there is
this device which controls transmission
unit control device
so there are many many of them so uh
there is I think I'm not going to write
I think seven million lines of code goes
into programming a single car
it's huge amount of code and
car should not be able to do anything
else except drive you from 0.8 from
point B but
but right now you can connect your phone
to it you can connect to internet
your Telemetry your personal data is
regularly uploaded into the cloud
and now manufacturers are also switching
to one more step of control so we are
not going to buy our cars but we're
going to lease
and all features inside car will be
released so you buy a car okay excellent
so you pay like three or five hundred
bucks to play to start it then you pay
monthly subscription
and then this bundle this is extremely
cool oh do you want heated seats yes or
no
so you know you are no longer in control
of your own car
so it depends on Safety and Security
that is implemented in Cloud
and this cloud is not implemented by
some I.T expert but by Automotive
companies
not again
I said many many bad ideas are piling up
so far
so and we did a lot of testing of this
kind of devices and I can tell you my
car doesn't have buttons
my car has OBD Port clipped
and I suggest be careful with a lot of
buttons
and next and probably most important
topic that you already touch are Smart
Homes
so right now
it is possible to automate everything in
your home so when you go and buy a
heater for a water if you go to buy uh
AC device or you go to buy your
refrigerator there is a big chance that
there will be Wi-Fi connectivity
it will be connected to Cloud because
yeah we live in Iraq of connected
devices why so we can see and set up our
AC device when we are outside of home
using application around very secure
phone
to make it okay cool to 25 degrees
because it's so difficult when you are
in the house to click the button
and we allow our devices to speak to the
internet
and these devices can do interesting
stuff so there was
less than a year ago there was a big
problem because one of the manufacturer
manufacturers try to update the firmware
on microwave ovens and they all stopped
working
my first question why would microwave
ovens up be updating firmware so do they
have new develop new feature for it
because it's microwave oven
but they did it so it needed to be
connected to Internet obviously so your
microwave is connected to Internet for
one reason maybe it's tweeting right now
while you're sitting here
and it's updating its favor and by some
mistake of somebody we don't know who
was it it was it's just somebody who was
tired or it was sentient AI
so they applied wrong updates for
another device so our microwave started
having identity identity crisis and it's
not it's team oven
excellent
and this is just one example
so a lot of devices are connected and
smart so our TVs
also
and our TVs are really powerful devices
because they sometimes have even cameras
microphone and they can do a lot more
than just show you a picture of the
program that is currently being sent
also we had recently problem with garage
doors
so there was manufacturer who decided oh
we are no longer supporting our old
garage doors
and people lost all ability to open
their garage doors because everything
depends on cloud and this manufacturer
disabled cloud services
so I did also recently I have done some
research with my good friend who is very
commonly here with me but this year he
skipped and I was really hoping that he
will show that research also so we have
done some research on a baby camera he
got maybe a few months ago and he bought
some cameras to monitor his baby and we
did a lot of checking of these devices
and we found a real interesting thing
but I will keep that for our next
balcony so we'll go into more details
together
and the problem is who has control of
our device
it's not us it's cloud provider
it's whoever controls connectivity
services for our device being smart home
being cars ACS we are not solely in
control
so we we even have those smart
assistants Alexa or or
or Google or whatever
and we want to give them voice commands
and we allow these services to connect
to other services so they can control
them
so as I said a lot of fun and problems
are every everywhere and to be honest
it's not so easy to solve these problems
so what is the root cause of most
security issues in Hardware
it doesn't just impact these simple
devices but this spans over more
critical infrastructure so this funds
were energy manufacturing energy
distribution water treatment so
everything that lived in isolation for
so many years
we had I.T world and we had world of
devices and they were two separate roles
so to implement Security in devices it
was enough to make sure that nobody can
enter your building
but but lately as I showed we started to
implement connectivity and features and
we started to collide those two words
and all the worlds are colliding people
are not following so we still have it
experts who are not electrical engineers
so most of the Security Experts comes
from computer science
and in computer science you don't need
to have even basic of electoral
techniques
and on the other side you have engineers
and their manufacturing mindset which is
not always aligned with best security
practices
and it's very common that they do not
even speak the same language although
all technical features but they cannot
understand each other because they have
completely different View
in one engineer is focused on design on
operation not on security
while security doesn't concern always
about functionality but we need to have
controls
and those two rules are now colliding
and we need to start developing skills
in in both fields so it's not always
easy it but it's always fun
so
why it is fun
I always say to my guys you cannot learn
to hack
no way but you have to learn
so you will need to start doing stuff in
order to learn how they operate to
understand them we need to make mistakes
we need to destroy stuff in order to get
how they actually functioning and what
they actually can do
so I will show you a few things just to
entice your imagination and I hope this
will inspire you to actually try to get
your hands dirty and to start opening
your devices
and to see what you can do to make them
more secure and different so I will I
will show you uh this is ongoing project
that I'm doing right now so I started
recently so I didn't go very far with it
but I think it will be good as a
beginner
uh uh beginner demo so what you need to
do in order to start so
first thing that you need to start is to
open device
so and to do visual inspection of it
try to find easy targets are there any
flash cards SD cards inside it are there
memory chips which are isolated flash
chips something that you can connect and
maybe access the data
uh also try to find interesting points
on PCB that you can do something with
good source of information is FCC number
so if if device has any kind of Wireless
connectivity and if it is sold on U.S
market it must have FCC number and it is
already in database when you can search
it and discover a lot of design
information about device itself
so that's extremely good source of
information to start with and of course
your eyes so you open device you'll you
thoroughly look it so both sides of the
board and try to find interesting points
what are interesting point that you can
connect and extract data we need data
so here I have identified many many
ports which are not populated mostly
but when I check the traces I found that
this port these two rows are actually
connected to nearby components here and
I think here if I see correctly
and they are not dead
so of course I didn't check only those
two I have done a lot of tracks so it
sounded to be easy five minute draw but
it's not so you need to search every
single possible Trace to see every every
point and to try to identify what this
is connected to and how you can use it
or misuse it and good thing
he's a lot of stuff you can do without
powering on device but in the end you
need to power device on
so in order to power device you need
first to to have proper connectors so
you can connect
to device if you only don't have power
connector in the in this case I didn't
have it because it was not available on
this device but it was very helpful that
on the front bezel of device I had
that it is 12 volt DC so the only thing
remaining was to discover what is the
polarity of the power connector here and
it is simple just checking continuity
between pins and known ground you can
discover where is the ground pin and by
definition the other one is a plus so
that gives you ability to power a device
and actually I have succeeded so I get
green light and it was also red light
because device could not connect
whatever it was searching to connect
and after powering device we do
measurement so we need to do a lot of
measurements to to try to see if there
are any Live Connections so live traces
where something is happening and then we
need to analyze what is happening and if
that is of any use for us
so on that Port that I mentioned
originally I have identified the two
connections are ground but one of those
connections for showing interesting
signal and it was only when it was power
done
so not all the time but on power on I
would see activity on that PIN
and when I connected later to that pin I
I got this
login Pro
so this is excellent results so we
finally have a way to interact with
harder which is not available to normal
user but it requires login
and this is where I had to stop because
I had to come to Balkan
but it doesn't prevent people to tell
you what are my next steps for this
so first is I I want to tamper with boot
process so during the if I'm corrected
in time and I can see boot process I can
see that there is a loader which
actually do some stuff and in some cases
it's possible to interact with that you
can redirect it for example that not
load the image from the flash memory in
device but to use tftp or I can do if
there is a Linux I can put put it in in
it one maybe or some other way to gain
control of booting process because that
will give might give me access to
console which I can use to to go further
to the device another thing is to try
brute forcing root login so by using
device like this called TTL to USB so I
could it is serial port on your machine
when it's connected and you can use
Simple Python scripts in order to
automate brute forcing of logins
and the third thing that can be done in
this case is time analysis so whenever
you
put
strings in something and they are
verified there must be some mathematical
operations and if this process is not
done perfectly
it is possible that you can see timing
differences so if I start typing wrong
passwords and it matches only first for
example only lengths is checked first it
will exit much sooner if it is wrong
length of the string then it's right
then if I finally discovered what is the
right length and I put first letter
properly it will be
quicker or slower depending on the
situation so you can do a lot of time
analysis by putting uh new uh repeat
repeating the same inputs and then
Gathering like average of response and
then you will see okay when I put first
letter A I get response of 80
microseconds if I put letter Z it gives
me 200 microseconds and all of them are
under 100 so Z is something special so
it might be our first letter or not
why because when it compared string it
it used some more primitive process and
it compare one letter by one letter and
he decided the first letter then it is
matching and start processing another
letter so it took additional time
if it is wrong letter it discovers that
it is wrong on first letter and falls
through immediately
so timing attacks are also interesting
it's not always possible of course so it
depends on implementation but luckily
developers are really really really
smart richers and they want to invent
their own algorithms instead of using
what is industry standards and that
gives us opportunity for different
attacks
also there are other options so trying
to get to the firmware any other way by
finding update or by glitching so fault
injection
or something new who might know we might
invent something so I had a colleague of
mine who found a way in some specific
series of microcontrollers to dump the
firmware by misusing uh USB stack so by
just connecting to USB port of device he
was able to find a way
and to finish to to
dump the filter very soon and quickly
so
I think this is all that I wanted to
show
thank you all and if there are any
questions
wait please wait for
when you do timing attacks do you do
them on a computer or do you implement
them on embedded Hardware too just to
have more control over timings yes I use
fpga usually to create my own thing okay
what does the device do initially I mean
what the
what it should do Based On A lender I
cannot disclose that okay
foreign
so sometimes Communications within the
devices are usually the encrypted or
have some maybe some sort of encryption
usually sucks but sometimes it happens
not just like how would you deal like
when you have you either extract a
firmware that is encrypted or the data
in transit that you can capture is
encrypted how can you find out how is it
and how to break it yeah not so easy so
first we try to find unencrypted
Communications there are a lot of ports
that you can use like SPI which is
usually not encrypted so you try to find
something that is not encrypted other
options try to attack memories itself
because in memory it is usually not
encrypted but if everything else fails
and you need to deal with cryptography
you have few ways one is to do uh
the power analysis to try to guess what
device is doing but that's really not
easy other ways to try what we call
unknown protocol analysis so and also
that FCC documentation that I mentioned
can be really useful into deducing what
device actually use for encryption if it
is communication Channel and that can
help
now
here
hi I have a more philosophical question
in the first half you said that cloud
providers or cloud is controlling our
devices
since we all know that human are the
weakest link do we and we are rapidly
going towards the idiocracy style of
gamification of everything
can we expect from a common ordinary Joe
to know how to control its own device
that's never happened they're going to
happen so when you know there was a long
process of creating idiot-proof devices
and whenever they manage to do it
somebody else managed to enhance idiot
so it's not joke so like 50 years ago
your car came with manual would say how
to tune your vowels exactly now it's
written to not drink your acid from
bakuma later
so we are not getting smarter for sure
and as soon as we have that AI gain
control of those guns that we saw you
will be removed as we are we're told
sister we are toasted we are worthless
part we just consume energy and we
contribute nothing just stupidity
maybe we should provide it
yeah thanks for the talk it was
interesting uh I wanted to ask have you
ever tried uh reversing uh some
extracted firmware and have you ever
tried replacing uh firmware on a device
many times
yeah uh cool and uh
how complicated was that I mean
was it something like uh replacing a
firmware like on a router or it was less
complicated it depends so it depends of
the device sometimes you have om version
of device so there are many of the same
they just have some specifics for
specific manufacturer in that case we
might be able to use pyramid from
another manufacturer which might not
have all the Safety and Security
implemented so it will give us something
or we can use older version of firmware
which have known issues and that will
give us access uh for some devices if
they're running something like Android
we might be even try to compile Android
open source project in order to make
device work but that of course is not so
simple because sometimes you need to
bypass a bootloader signatures and stuff
like that so there are some features
that we need to bypass but it is not
impossible
thank you
thank you thank you for the talk
interesting topic really and it reminded
me uh some some time ago that I heard
another talk at the topic of
undocumented Hardware
um
uh harder commands regarding CPUs and
that that may be used for back during
the the device that software doesn't
recognize uh were you in your career
being able to find such undocumented
commands that were not in the
specification many times so that is not
so uncommon this is why we actually do
if you recall that I mentioned that we
need to read
manufacturer documentation about actual
chips implemented because when they are
implemented you will get just user
manual for it but manufacturer will give
much more detailed description of the
chip itself and then you can discover a
lot about keeper actual capabilities not
what is advertised but what is actually
under the hood and also it is always
good to to perform these checks of the
PCB because you can discover stuff like
this uart which was not mentioned
anywhere in user documentation it should
not be a this thing and also we saw that
manufacturers do really bad things when
such vulnerabilities are reported so we
were once doing some some engagement and
we reported that we have found debug
port on the board did you say yes sure
no problem we will sell it out and what
they did they just removed the port the
soldered it but they still had PCB
traces for the love of God
it's just three minutes to get back to
it
what are your thoughts about open
sourcing Hardware
uh that is actually really good because
uh hope you know we are all open for
open source so it gives much more
chances for everybody else to contribute
and to check security of devices they
are using are everybody able to do that
I'm not I would not bet on it but at
least there will be much more people
than now so who is now checking source
code of manufacturers
nobody so at least you will have chance
to to do something on under your own
terms are you good or not good that is
to be seen but you will have a chance
now you don't have any chance
yeah thank you
hi uh so you mentioned uh bypassing uh a
bootloader's signature protection uh
could you go into a bit more detail
about that
how do you I'm assuming it has a hash
that is calculated uh the image that it
loads so you need to match that hash
right okay so what you use like nice
cache or some other service that then
how do you add what is net necessary to
produce such cache yeah so it's really
complicated matter and it would take at
least two terms of of presentation like
this but in in a nutshell uh we in
theory it works perfectly in practice
there is always something that is not
implemented as it should
so something is missing somewhere
so you you need to have trusted bootload
it must start from the first
step so you need to have some secure
element inside your uh CPU in order to
be able to pull initial secret that you
will use for the later steps and that is
something that is sometimes not
implemented properly or not implemented
at all so they just trust one of the
steps blindly and then continue so we
attack weakest link so to be honest I
will not attack cryptography by default
it's waste of time usually if it's done
properly but I said developers are
really smart people and like challenge
to develop something new and better and
they fail 100 of the time
so
uh so this is all the time we have for
questions uh we need to get moving so if
anyone has any more questions please
feel welcome to approach uh well then
after the presentation thank you
[Applause]
[Music]
thank you