[Music]
hello everyone this is a broken chain
discovering opc-ua at tax office and
exploiting the supply chain
my name is eran jacob i'm a security
research team leader at otorio
otorio is an industrial cyber security
solutions and services provider and
along with me on this project worked
roman volkin and alonzini on the fasting
part
let's do a quick overview of what we are
going to talk about first we are going
to start with some intro
on opcway and why we decided to research
it
we will continue to discover the attack
surface of different implementations
and afterwards we will exploit some of
the implementations we found
at the end we will cover some fuzzing
work we have done
so let's start
automation protocols are used in many
cyber physical systems we can find them
in factories critical infrastructures
and even in your company's building
along the years many automation vendors
have created their own proprietary
protocols for these purposes
which caused some issues in
interoperability between devices of
different vendors
along with movement well towards more
connected environments in industrial
environments
there were some issues in security in
these protocols that were not originally
designed for this kind of security
the companies have decided to create the
opc foundation which is a consortium
that is responsible for open and secure
communication for industrial
needs the foundation first created the
opc classic which is a protocol that is
made of multiple specifications
providing open and secure communication
for different needs of the industry
and while it was widely adopted
there were some issues in this protocol
first of all it is based on the
microsoft decom
which is a proprietary and close
protocol of microsoft making the opc
classic not that open
another issue was the use of dynamic
ports
which made firewall configurations very
hard for this protocol
along with some other issues and
security concerns the foundation have
decided to create a new protocol
the new protocol is opc ua
opc unified architecture is basically
everything we could ask for
it is security-minded
cross-vendor platform independent very
maintained and very flexible and of
course supporting the industry 4.0 and
smart manufacturing
opc ua can be used across the whole
industrial ecosystem
starting from field devices in the ot
network all the way to the itn cloud
for example opc ua can be used between
controllers
hmis
f2 scada mes and erp in the it network
opecua is also supporting cloud
communication
and if needed it can be used for field
level communication and with tsn it is
real time
as you see opcwa provides us with great
power
but with great power comes great
responsibility
and any compromise of this protocol
may compromise the whole industrial
ecosystem
that is leading us to the motivation for
our research
well basically opcua is the next thing
in industrial communication
we can see it is highly adopted by many
vendors and many of our clients
and if compromised it has some
significant potential impact
mainly because it is used to connect
very sensitive internal ot networks with
more external and more exposed it and
cloud environments
now we can start discovering the attack
surface of different implementations
and we are going to start with the
specifications
the opc foundation provides full and
open specifications for opc ua
they publish the online and along with
them we can find multiple open source
implementations that were published by
the foundation
most of these implementations are now
legacy
but the dotted standard that is based on
the dotnet legacy is still maintained
there are multiple other open
communication stacks and commercial sdks
available
and if we look on the opc foundation
website we can find listed many products
that are using opcwa
now we wanted to check
what implementation is used in
common products
and
we checked some of these products in our
lab and found out that
softing and unifi automation sdks along
with the opc foundation
communication stocks
are being widely used
and we found two main variations of them
one is a native version and the other is
dot net
focusing a bit on the
native version of the sdks and
communication stacks
we can see that the ua stack dll
of the foundation
is the same name for the unified
automation sdk
but this was not the same library
well this was not such a surprise for us
since kaspersky also mentioned this
subject in a report they have done in
mentioning there are some third-party
applications that are using modified
versions of the ua stack
we checked it truly and found out that
both softing and unifi automation sdks
are based on the foundation original
stack
which is now legacy
looking at the dotnet version of these
sdks we found the same thing
now if we go back to our attack surface
we can see that there are some popular
commercial sdks that are based on
the foundations
most of them legacy now communication
communication stocks
along with some other open communication
stocks and sdks
we don't have the full details on all
the products that are using opc ua but
from what we've been able to see and
according to some statements of the opc
foundation
we understand that most of the products
are using commercial sdks
or
the communication stack made by the
foundation
now if we focus on the upper part in
this attack surface we can see a clear
chain of dependency
starting from the foundations
original communication stocks through
commercial sdks all the way to
products made by large vendors
but before we start exploiting this
chain of dependency
let's first
cover some previous work done in this
area
first we have the opc foundation
security working group which is actively
working on securing these important
protocols and we even have the chance to
meet with them
but there are some independent
researches that have been done such as
the research from the bsi
that covered threats specifications and
the rtc implementation
and they were also able to find memory
leak in the foundation stack
kaspersky have done another research in
covering applications using the
foundation stack
and were able to find issues in
third-party products and products made
by the foundations themselves
in 2020 they published another paper on
ncc fuzzing
claudia have published another paper
recently that is discussing opc and
opcua vulnerabilities
they found some issues in products that
are not part of our supply chain
along the years many academic papers
have been published and if you are
looking for securing your own opc server
or client i recommend you reading one of
these
well it is about time for us to start
exploiting our supply chain
and we of course going to begin with the
specifications
looking at specifications we can find
there is a standard opcwa connection
starting from a low arc
followed by a secure channel initiation
the secure channel provides us with
confidentiality integrity and
application authentication
after the secure channel is initiated we
have the session layer which provides
another layer of security in the form of
user authentication and authorization
after the two of these we can send our
messages in a secure way such as read
write and call
reading the reference we looked mainly
for areas
that may be more
risky for implementations
there are many of them but we focus on
three of them
first we have the complex data types
some data types in opc ua are very
flexible
and we decided we can try and use them
for exploiting different parts of it
another area is the flexible encoding
opc ui message can contain different
coding and even binary and xml together
and the third subject is press security
messages
some opc ua messages does not require
any security
and for example we have the messages
that are used to create the secure
channel or messages that are part of the
discovery service
if we are taking these three areas in
the opc ua
we can try and check if the dotnet
starter con standard communication stack
by the opc foundation is vulnerable to
any issues in this area
we decided to focus on the dotted
standard mainly because it's the only
one that is still maintained and we
found it being used by many
vendors and large products
looking at the.net stock we knew that
memory corruption issues are
not much a thing in dot net
but dotnet still doesn't like the
function calls
2d precursion in dotnet
may cause the
application to crash
and
here it is very interesting because
in the opc ua we have objects that are
so flexible they can call and contain
the same object underneath
making them nested objects
the reference alert of such risk when
describing nested data types
and a related issue was already found in
the past
in extension object decoding
looking at the foundations.net stack
we can find the source code many
limitations of the nesting level
but we felt this is not very systematic
and decided to check it truly
well we have a few nested data types in
opc ua
first we have the variant
which is basically a union and can
contain any built-in data types
or array
and matrix
extension object is also an interesting
data type it is a structured container
it can contain any opc use structure
in xml or binary this is very
interesting because opcwa structures can
contain different data types including
extension object itself
diagnostic info is much simpler and it's
basically just able to contain an
optional diagnostic info object
and the data value is able to call
variant that can contain another data
value
looking at these data types
we were able to find
issue in the variant decoding
in the xml decoder of the ocua
here on the left
you can see the read variant function
calling read matrix that is able to call
read variant directly without any
limitation allowing us to perform
unlimited nesting
this is placed in the xml decoder for
the opc ua and all we need to crash the
sdk using this is to create a large
enough xml something like this but
much larger
and
we need to find a way to get it into
the xml decoder
we have done this using the extension
objects
which are able to contain xml decoded
structures
and using the extension objects we are
able to pivot our way into vulnerable
parts of the stack
and
using them before channel session
security we are able to crash the sdk
before
any security is initiated
here we can see an example for
exploitation of this issue in secure
channel initiation
we have an extension object in the
message header and
we just have to change the encoding for
the extension object and append our
payload
and we get a crush
but that was not enough for most
application
because we had to find a way to send
much larger xml payload
and most of the applications were
limiting us by the buffer size
so we used chunks
opcua allows us to send messages in
chunks
and reaching message size up to 4 to 16
megabytes in the configuration we
checked
but chunks are not supported in the open
requests
so this time we used a pre-security
message find servers which is part of
the discovery service
that is by design not requiring a
security
sending this message with our vulnerable
xml
we were able to crash any dotnet
application we've checked
this six years old zero day can be found
in the opc foundation's legacy standard
and
softing and unified automation sdks
if we try to demonstrate how this can be
exploited here we have a main site and
two remote sites connected to it
and in the middle we have the scada that
is communicating with two of the remote
sites
an attacker on the main site may be able
to send a malicious packet to the opcwa
servers making them crash
and cause a lot of visibility and
control
this action may cause a total shutdown
for many factories
and can be performed also from a remote
site
in this scenario we have an attacker
that has access to one of the opc ua
servers
or main the middle in its network
the attacker can response the opca
client of the scada with a malicious
response and get the same result
now let's try and cover another area
again around the xml but this time with
the xml processing library
we know that xml processing in dotnet
may be a bit tricky on some versions
and
we noticed there were multiple
vulnerabilities in these areas before
but it was a great chance for us to
check the commercial sdks
looking for the modified versions
we found in unified automation
this piece of code and if you look here
we have an unsafe xml document loading
this allows an attacker that is able to
load xml into this function
to perform http requests into the
internal subnet
and leak files from the attack device
code refactoring reintroduced this
vulnerability after it was fixed in the
dotnet standard
and we can exploit it in the same way of
an extension object
a scenario for this kind of attack is
pretty simple we have an attacker in the
it network and we have an
internal ot network that is accessible
to it
the attacker
can send a malicious packet to the opc
ua server
retrieve sensitive files
and send malicious requests into the
internal network
let's continue with another type of
commercial sdk this time we are going to
focus on an sdk that is based on the ncc
legacy stack
we chose softing cpp sdk which is used
by many vendors
and is supporting multiple platforms
the software cvp can run on vxworks
windows and linux and is made of
multiple libraries
on the bottom here we can see the tv5
stack
which is basically an extended version
for the opc foundation nc stack
above it we have the tb5ot
that is in charge on stack sdk level
processing
and on the top we have tb5 cpp
that is the interface for integrating
applications with the sdk
here we focused on the integration
between the extended version of the ncc
stack and the tb5 ot library
an interesting fact is while the
foundation is using
c structures for representing decoded
opc ua objects
the tv5 ot is using
a cpp object made by softing for the
same
purpose
and if we try to walk through the
process from binary message into cvp
objects
we can hear
see that a binary message is first
processed by the tb5 stack
validated
and if everything is okay we get some c
structures
the t5 ot using these c structures for
its own purposes or if interesting it
saves them into cpp objects
our focus is here we looked for issues
in the transfer from c structures to cpp
objects
but finding issues in the cpp object
setters is not that easy because
any input for these functions is first
validated both by the tb5 stack and the
ot
so we had to find a c structure that is
flexible enough
to introduce unexpected input
to the cvp object
for that purpose
we have the foundations extension object
this is how the foundation see structure
of the extension object is looking this
is not how an extension object is passed
through communication but how it is
saved in memory
the extension object structure is made
of three main parts
the first part is the id of the
contained structure
after that we have the encoding of the
internal structure
and in the end we have a union that
representing the contained structure
if we zoom into the body of the
contained structure we can see it can
contain three types of
structures
first way is representing the structure
in a binary format this is used for
structures that are not supported by the
stack
another option
is saving it as an xml element
and because the ncc stack is not
supporting xml decoding it is basically
the same
the third one is an actual decoded
structure in
ncc structure that is containing the
internal
object
and we basically have here two options
for
encoded body
it's muscle we must understand that this
both
parts of the structure must be validated
before any access to the body union is
done otherwise we may access in 32
instead of a pointer
looking at the sdk object setters we
could find some setters that are
accepting extension objects
but
most of them were validating both the
type id and the encoding
after looking a bit deeper we found a
few that missed validation on the
encoding part
meaning that
if we have any option for making the
body not a decoded object but a byte
string for example
we may be able to crush the sdk
but we must remember that type ids that
are known by the tb5 stacks
are automatically decoded and all of the
types we found were supported by the tb5
stack
we have two options for bypassing it
one of them is pretty simple is just
using xml decoding for the internal
structure which is not supported by the
ncc stack and it will be saved as a
by-string
another option we have
is using the type id
the id of the internal structure can be
represented in different ways
and the ncc stack is supporting only
numeric version of it
so if we send and by string identifier
in a specific length it would be enough
to bypass the checks of the sdk
and provide us with an undecoded object
now that we have a c structure that is
received by the sdk
and
is valid on the type id field but
contains a byte string in its body all
we need to do is to find a way to get it
through the object setter function
unfortunately
this was not working for any of the
extension objects you used for so far
and all of them were used internally in
the tb5 ot without being set into an
object
well
this was kind of an opportunity for us
we wanted to check another area of the
opc ua
the pub sub extension
pub sub is a new extension
for the opc ua protocol
and
we decide we are going to find a message
that is part of pub sub that will be set
into a cpp object setup which allow will
allow us to crush
pub sub
applications
a word about pub sub
pub sub is a publish subscribe model for
the opc ua it is using udp packets and
it is slightly different
there are two main
usages
for pub sub one of them is
through a relay broker
that is publishing the messages to many
subscribers this is mainly used in the
cloud
and there are some
secure multicast options that is used
for field level communication for
example essential publishing information
to multiple subscribers
looking for an exploitable message we
found
one message that contained variant
and was set into an object setter
using the variant we can add any object
we want under this variant including our
malicious extension object
and if we try to demo the use of this
message
we can see here
that there is our publisher on the right
communicating with multiple subscribers
on the left through a multicast network
these subscribers are constantly keep
getting messages from this publisher
and on the right top we have our
attacker
which
is also connected to the multicast
network
and if he will send our malicious pocket
we will see the subscriber crashing one
after the other
we were able to find
seven object setters that were not
protected against this attack
and we assumed that this issue is not
only exist in softing
looking at the opc foundation code again
we found the same issue in the sample
server of the ncc stack
and we managed to crash it
with the same methods we presented
this is about time for us to continue to
the last part in our chain
the products
we know products
that are integrating ocua are facing
different risks
one of them are
configurations related
which means that
because of the configuration of opcua is
so complex there is high possibility
for different applications to miss some
important parts
and
end up with an unsecured client or
server
but since they have been done a lot of
work in this area and there are many
tools for
providing these tests
we decided to focus on the integration
of the
products with the opcwa sdk or
communication stack
here we have an image of unified
automation sdk
and we can see in the bottom our system
vendor
system
we can see in the bottom the vendor
system that is integrated with the sdk
through multiple interfaces
unified automations are defining
multiple required interfaces and
optional interfaces for the integration
process
and we checked i o manager interface and
could see that some products are
actually implementing it
but this time
we understood that this issue must be
tested in a more generic way
so we used our own made
father
our father is a network-based father
that is using
structured mutations on the internal
parameters and on the packets or message
flow
the io manager
we implemented
was read write and monitor items packets
and we focused on fighting the objects
that are being passed to the underlying
device
we yet haven't found any significant
issues but we are still working on
expanding the mutations to be more opi
specific and covering more products
to sum up
opc ua is a very powerful protocol
but if compromised
it can be used by attackers targeting
cyber physical systems
and
if we look at the supply chain we
discovered
any impact
to the first part in our chain may
impact many products
we used specific parts in the op-ua for
demonstrating exploitations of the
supply chain
for example complex objects dynamic
encoding
and unsecured messages
but it's still important to remember
that opc-ua is one of the most secure
industrial protocols right now
and we only recommend users
to use additional security measures and
of course make sure the configuration is
proper
i want to thank matandu brushing for the
mentoring in this project and of course
roman volkin and alonzini for the
fuzzing part
i am iran jacob and feel free to contact
me if you have any comments
or questions
thank you