[Music]
hello and welcome to our talk breaking
network segregation using esoteric
commander control channels
a quick introduction my name is james
coote i'm a senior consultant at
f-secure here in the uk and likewise i'm
matthew champion and i too am a senior
consultant
we've got quite a packed agenda for you
today so we're going to jump into the
technical details quite quickly first
we're going to quickly talk about
why care about esoteric commander
control i'm going to be talking about
this from both the perspective of a blue
team and a red team i'm going to
introduce you to the lab environment
we've created to contextualize these
techniques and also introduce you to c3
which is f-secure's command control
framework
and then we'll be going through four
channels today vmware using vmware tools
printers or specifically print jobs rdp
map drives and then ldap attributes all
to transfer archery data between two
hosts we'll be looking at both the
operational considerations so as a red
team what we're going to be doing and
then blue team as well um kind of things
we might be able to detect upon
in terms of why we care about this blue
team perspective ultimately what we're
trying to do here today is challenge
some of those assumptions around network
boundaries where we think there are um
some really tightly segregated networks
that maybe there are shared services or
boundary systems um that could be used
to pivot through those networks and
achieve as we'll see here peer-to-peer
and c2 communication and for a red team
obviously we want to keep our tradecraft
up to date we're going to bypass this
network segregation and ultimately
achieve our objective whilst evading
detection
so very briefly then the lab environment
we've got a single forest mwr.com and a
single child within that forest
uk.mwl.com
we've got two workstations within that
domain workstation one workstation two
and
these are virtualized assets on an esxi
server that's managed by vcenter and
this is joined to this the
uk.underwear.com domain and relies on
that for authentication and
authorization to make this a bit more
realistic we're going to be using c3s
slack external c2 channel um so we're
going to have a foothold on workstation
one it's going to be talking via slack
back to the c3 infrastructure hosted on
aws and connected to c3 is going to be a
cobalt strike team server so using
cobalt strikes external t2
and then from a detection standpoint
we're going to be using a few things so
firstly sysmon
and that's going to be using the swift
on security configuration in the link at
the bottom
and we're also going to be using uh
ruben boone and silk etw to uh to get
some additional telemetry from our
endpoints and then all of that is going
to make its way into helk roberto
rodriguez the elastic and cabana
instance there so we can look through
and query the data that we're collecting
there
so very briefly then c3 is f-secure's
command-control framework
it supports integration with kerbal
strike beacons and covenant grunts and
allows you to stage those respectively
through
your
the relays
so c3 operates on some arbitrary sort of
c2 medium so this externally could be
slack it could be dropbox etcetera
internally it could be any of the
channels that we're going to describe
today
in c3 land you have this concept of
relays so these are the payloads
essentially and this is what
communicates from the target to the c2
medium
right to pack it to this this medium
c3 will then pick that up interpret it
write a response back to the medium
where the relay will then pick it up
in the scenario where you've commanded
your relay to stage a beacon you'll then
get the beacon appear in your
cobblestrike team server from the target
machine
we'll quickly grasp as we go through
these techniques and what we've
experienced like operationally when we
when we've been doing our red teams
etcetera
if you can read write and delete to an
arbitrary service the chances are you
can leverage it for command and control
there's a few operational considerations
like api rate limiting etc but largely
read write and delete that's enough for
commander control
so let's dive into our first technique
so this is vmware so this is how we're
using vcenter's api to upload download
files and execute arbitrary commands
inside a virtual machine managed by
vcenter when we have no network
connectivity that target machine or
indeed that target machine doesn't even
necessarily need to have any network
connectivity at all or even a network
adapter
so the scenarios workstation one has no
direct
network connectivity to workstation two
however we've been able to compromise
legitimate credentials to the vcenter
server where workstation two
is a virtualized it's a virtual machine
managed by that vcenter
there's a couple of limitations before
we jump into um you know how to actually
use this in practice you need to have
valid credentials and a certain number
of guest operations privileges within
vcenter to interact with the guest os
you also need to have valid credentials
unfortunately for the target vm so they
don't necessarily need to be an
administrator but any account no if
you're sitting physically in front of
that machine
you could you could log in so this can
be local or domain credentials and the
tiger vm also needs vmware tools because
this is how the upload and downloaded
files and the arbitrary code execution
actually happens
the data flow relies not just for the
vmware for actually most of the channels
we're going to talk about on c3's unc
share file channel so at its core this
involves writing files to a shared
network drive so both workstation 1
workstation 2 uses the same arbitrary
network share to read and write c3
packets
we're going to be using in a slightly
unintended scenario
where workstation one workstation two
will be reading and writing these c3
files to its own local directory so
we're choosing cuse as public but it
could be any arbitrary file on that file
system any directory rather where you've
got read and write privileges
and we're going to use a tool that i've
written called sharpsphere to sit in the
middle and manually transfer c3 packets
from workstation 1 to workstation 2 and
vice versa
so in practice what this looks like
you execute your relay and workstation 2
that's going to write a packet to its
own c users public sharp 2 is going to
grab that move it across the workstation
1 where it's going to get interpreted by
c3 response generated and written to
workstation 1. see use the public
sharpshow is then going to take that
file move it across to workstation 2
where it's going to be interpreted on
workstation 2. so the rough workflow is
you find a vcenter great channel to see
through and download and relay for that
channel
upload it to target so this is
workstation 2. so you need sharp sphere
for this
execute the relay again you need sharp
sphere to execute the arbitrary commands
within workstation 2 and then lastly you
use sharp sphere's c2 functionality to
establish that command control channel
just a quick note to find the vcenter
you can obviously use any internal wiki
pages sharepoint asset lists all of that
in our experience we've also had some
success with ldap crews so if they're
using vcenter appliance operating system
service pack would be unknown so you can
use that to filter results and also the
name can be vcenter virtual center vcsa
variations on the above so you know we
have some success with that
the first thing you want to do is create
a channel i appreciate this is probably
the first time many of you have seen c3
which is on the right hand side so this
is what the c3 web ui looks like and
this is what's hosted in your attacker
controlled infrastructure and you'll see
our existing slack relay with an
associated cobble strike beacon hanging
off the the side of that relay
so what we're going to do is create this
unc share file and we're going to tell
it so this is workstation one this is
what executed on workstation one so
we're going to tell it to use c uses
public as its
uh
arbitrary directory to read and write
data from make sure you take a note of
the input and output ideas you'll need
that for a later step
what we then want to do is use
the
sharp sphere aggressor script to list
the virtual machines
so the vcenter api so you know you found
your vcenter you're going to use the
vcenter url
to query the api to retrieve a list of
all of the virtual machines that that
vcenter manages so we're hoping in these
responses to see workstation 2 as a
managed virtual asset you'll see here as
well i've just done a quick check-in
because of the way c3 works and the way
the beacon receives its output sometimes
you just need to do a quick check-in to
get the full results
so you'll see there workstation two so
just make a note of this ip address
because this is the machine that we're
actually going to target for subsequent
steps
so once you've got your relay you've
generated your relay executable we we
now need to upload that to the target
host so again you're going to use
sharpsphere and and sharps is just using
the vsphere apis the legitimate
functionality within the api to upload
this file so source file upload
destination
pretty self-explanatory the guest
username password so these are
credentials that have legitimate access
to
workstation 2. so these are the local or
domain credentials
the source file is respective to
workstation 1 and the destination file
is where you want to place that on
workstation 2. so for simplicity's sake
we just put it all
um
in c user public
um so that we know where to reference it
from later
and so all being well you'll see
sharpsville telling you this uploaded
the file to a certain destination so
just worth making a note of where it's
uploaded to so that in this next step
where we execute the relay you know what
you're trying to execute so using the
aggressive script again
fill in all the relevant details and the
command
is the relay executable that you just
uploaded this is going to start the
relay on workstation 2 and this relay is
going to be continually polling sea uses
public
for
files associated with c3
what's worth pointing out is
that's not going to get anywhere at the
moment because it's just referencing its
local directory and nothing else can
talk to it so we need something in the
middle we need sharp sphere to actually
transfer those files across
so just to note in the beacon output
you'll see that the process has started
and has returned you the period of the
running process so you're reasonably
confident that relay is now running on
workstation two
the last step then is to establish the
commander control so again with sharp
sphere you want to do c2
fill in the relevant details put in the
input id and the output id that you made
a note of before the local file
directory and the remote the guest file
directory is see uses public so this is
what c3 is using on workstation one and
workstation two respectively as its
uh
local directory to read and write c3
packets too
all being well that sharps will just
stay in the background as a as a running
process to
transfer those files manually and you'll
see that it's now checked in within c3
so at this point commander controls
established
from an operator's perspective you know
it's probably not as usable as it could
be at this point so we're just going to
stage a beacon through the relay that's
running on workstation 2.
sharpshooter is still running in the
background so workstation 1 is going to
put its files in to see you as a public
sharksville is going to copy that across
workstations who's going to receive it
it's going to keep doing that and you
can see the beacon is now checked in
so from an operator's perspective this
is quite a seamless experience
and you can use the
the beacon
as you would normally
so from a prevention perspective before
we move on detection
restricted network access to vcenter to
your known admin host so if you've got
privileged access workstations limit
access to any of those machines
vcenter supports quite granular
permission levels so implement the
principle of least privilege
there's been some research in the link
below about disabling specific api
methods you know if you still need
access to the api legitimately perhaps
just disable the ones that you don't
need
and also when you come to install vmware
tools uh perhaps remove the
non-essential parts of vmware tools
that would allow this sort of
functionality to take place
awesome thanks so detection then how can
we see this it's quite a convoluted
channel i think end-to-end so let's take
a look at how we might see this taking
place there's a few different areas we
can look at
as we go through this not just this one
but the other channels as well we're
going to be looking at both a tool
specific detection and then more broadly
around the technique as well to kind of
give a bit of a balance there so tooling
wise we're looking at obviously.net post
exploitation tooling sharpsphere running
in memory has to run continuously to
shuttle those files and kind of
synchronize the two directions as we saw
and we can use a yara rule such as that
on the right hand side and the strings
that are present within short sphere to
identify it running within memory
we can also make use of etw there so you
can see the microsoft
runtime provider and then quite clearly
we can see run dll32 quite anonymously
um loading the shout out program into
memory there and there's just a snippet
um to use with silk utw as i mentioned
um to facilitate this etw logging
c3 usage there's a couple of things here
both as a binary and in memory firstly
the the lower um yara rule you can see
there for identifying c3 binaries
including the dlls that kind of make the
magic happen as it were and on the right
hand side we can see another yara rule
that detects the specific strings that
are part of the reflected dll loading
that c3 uses for its shell code so you
can also detect that in memory as well
network connections are probably one of
the most anomalous features here aside
from the vcenter apis so here we can see
our
net
sharp sphere here is loaded within run
dll32 and that is making a series of
network connections to the known ip
address of a vcenter server
on 443 so we can see that as well
obviously with the beacon running within
our relay that is spawning our what is
called a spawn two process within cobalt
strike and that is run dll and that's
making those connections
process creations then for the execution
step there so whenever we execute a
command through sharpsphere like our
relay or any other command
we're using a very specific command line
argument and it's all spawning from vm
tools d so you can see within the code
there at the bottom um we've got a
hard-coded path to see users public and
a randomized file name so we end up with
something along the lines of as you can
see there cmd c the command we're
running so who am i and then it will be
put into public and then cleared up
afterwards kind of similar to something
like impact it's wmi exec if you're
familiar with that
where we have no um output required so
example when james is running his relay
um we can see the exact same thing here
the cmd slash c and then the command
itself but then we won't have any file
rights as a result of that but still any
anomalous and child processes of vmtools
d dot actually is gonna be worth
investigating
and then the api usage logs if we turn
our attention to the actual code for
sharpsville we can see
the execution of commands is achieved
through starting a program on the host
listing process ids until the process id
is is is removed i.e the process has
finished executing
we download the output file we put in to
see users public and then we delete the
file to clean up afterwards
looking within the at the api logs on
the vcenter server so this is vpxd.log
you can see quite clearly the initial
login
and we can find our vm by ip as we saw
james do
and we authenticate to our guest and
start our program but be that relay or
who am i or otherwise and then we list
our processes repeatedly until that that
we've seen what we need in our process
is terminated and then obviously we
initiate the file transfer to retrieve
the output and then delete it afterwards
what you'll notice is there's no
indication here of who is performing
this activity nor from where
what we can do is take the gui there
that's provided if you look through each
line of that api
log you'll see the same guide present
for all of them that's essentially a
session id and if we look into another
log on the vcenter server with vpxt
profiler.log you can see that that
corresponds um to the administrator
account there the local administrator
account and it's coming from the dot 200
address which is our workstation one
c2 very similar stories a different set
of ips here so you can see the initial
login find ip but then list files is the
api call that's effectively our
beaconing functionality that sharpsphere
reaching out to the vcenter api to say
what's in this directory is there
anything i need to start shuttling back
and forth um to facilitate c2
and then the file rights themselves that
are the unc share file in action so we
can see firstly our workstation one is
writing files to a given location i'm
using downloads folder here but
obviously public is just as relevant
workstation 2 we see vm tools is the one
that's actually producing those files on
the workstation 2 endpoint
we can then see our other relay on
workstation 2 is writing in response to
those files and then we can see on
workstation one
our run dll32 which of course is is
sharp sphere in memory and is then
producing files as well
back from the workstation two back to
the originating source
and then finally windows event logs
obviously
this api is performing a series of calls
to facilitate c2 and there's no stateful
connection here so every time we make an
api call
we're logging in again essentially we're
authenticating authenticating again to
the workstation so here you can see over
a period of um kind of maybe a second
there's four or five different instances
of authentication so our four six two
fours and our four six five ratios we
connect with a batch logon type
interestingly at the bottom if you don't
have the ability to log on with a batch
log on type you will also see a 4625 as
it tries to do that initial connection
so worth bearing in mind the volume of
log on events that you're going to
produce
now onto printers great thank you so
that's the biggest one biggest channel
out the way
we're now going to move on to number two
of four and this is using arbitrary
network printers for command control so
a lot simpler conceptually as well
similar scenario workstation one no
network connectivity to workstation 2
but it does however both have
network connectivity to a shared printer
so mx470
in this case and we can use print jobs
to transfer
data between the two
a couple of limitations on this one as
well
both sides need network access to the
same print server so smb
also ideally they both be executing
under the context of the same user
account on both sides or at least one of
them needs to be an administrator this
is so that it can delete print jobs that
were started by another user
you'll see in the ui unlimited print
jobs are supported operationally for us
this has been slightly less stable so
i'd suggest limiting print jobs to one
slightly less throughput but much more
stable
each print job as well because we're
storing the the data in the print job
name uh can support a transfer size of
one megabyte so it's not huge but
operationally it's still enough to
to perform what you need to do unless
massive data excel is necessary
so the workflow is is pretty basic
workstation one has direct network
connectivity to mx470 and it's going to
read and write
packets via print jobs and workstation 2
is going to be doing the same thing
first of all we need to find a
target printer so you can use ldap here
you can also use powershell to query a
remote machine or if you want to find a
princess for
the machine for instance workstation one
you can use wmic as well to to list the
the local printers already mapped to
that machine once you've found that
printer the next step is to create the
channel within c3 so there's a
particular channel type called channel
print
you can leave everything default except
printer address which is the printer
that you identified in the previous step
and the outbound job limit print number
of print jobs to create so default zero
i'd suggest setting it to one
just for stability
you then need to execute that relay so
we're assuming for this scenario that
you've got some out of band execution
path and for us we've got remote desktop
up in the top right hand side
so this is the workstation two so we can
execute the reload and workstation two
and you'll see in the bottom left hand
side the print queue so you'll see jobs
being created in a pause state and then
deleted as they're processed
and you'll see this continue happen as
workstation 1 and workstation 2 transfer
data and then you'll see your relay
check in so at this point command and
control has been established despite
workstation 1 and workstation 2 having
no direct network connectivity with each
other
we can then stage a beacon through this
and because a beacon is typically larger
than one megabyte you'll see
in the print queue in the bottom
left-hand side
multiple print jobs being created so
print job we create in a pause state be
interpreted then deleted and then
another one will be created as well
and you'll see actually what this looks
like in practice because we're storing
in the document name the way c3
transfers its data is it will encrypt
the packet and then base64 encode it and
that's what you're seeing in the
document name
and there you can see the beacon
checking in and we can begin to use that
operationally as we would normally with
any other beacon type
awesome thank you
so detection opportunities so there's a
little bit a little bit different here
so there's less of that obviously the
net and post exploitation totally needed
for this obviously we're just using our
relays directly to talk to the printer
but we still have a series of things
that we can look at here first thing to
bear in mind actually is quite an
interesting one is the endpoint ui the
way you're interacting with it so if
you're running in the context of a
user's session and you interact with a
printer that has low ink low paper
there's a jam the printer's offline
something like that
typically those areas will be presented
to the user as a balloon notification as
you can see there
so if they're not doing any print jobs
it might be something that raises
suspicion that could potentially burn
the whole operation there you can
disable those notifications with some of
the registry entries there as i've
listed but just worth bearing in mind of
course the the operational
considerations that they could have as
well
i think the best place to see this
taking place as a defender to alert upon
it is using our print server event log
so here you can see on the left hand
side we can enable um the job name being
present in the event log and on the
right hand side and just zoom in a bit
you can see
that very long base64 encoded file name
which is of course the data itself and
we can see that in a series of 308 which
is queuing the job and the 310 which is
the job being deleted in quick
succession as that file transfer or the
data transfer takes place
similarly module loads here so to
facilitate the interaction with the
printers as a series of dlls we're using
most notably every time we're queuing
adding a job um the print workflow proxy
dll and the print folder dll are both
being loaded each time
one thing to note actually on the top
right you can see me attempting to print
through microsoft word interactively
with the ui and the dialog boxes that
come up
when you're using this programmatically
there's no ui it's all done through the
relay and its apis you won't see that
print ui dlr coming up so it's probably
worth investigating other instances of
that programmatic printing taking place
network connections as we've already
seen there has to be some kind of
beaconing taking place to facilitate
this connection how do i know when
there's jobs for me and read them and
then subsequently obviously reply as a
response and this smb connection here to
the spool service name pipe using the
open printer x
api call is what achieves that and that
is our beaconing behavior again and
again over time and to check if there's
any jobs destined for our relay
you go off the deep end and start
looking at rpc and there's a couple of
rpc methods here the enum jobs and the
ad job which is optin on 4 and 24
respectively and if we start logging
this
we do get some as you might expect well
high volume telemetry and also some
really good granularity here which
allows us to see the process id so which
process is actually initiating these
jobs and we can see them interacting
with the print service there using the
the interface uid and then lastly we can
see the op number to say it's this
process that's interacting with the ms
rprn interface and to add print jobs
and delete and obviously list as well
cool rdp
great so on to our third of four
channels so this is using remote desktop
map drives for commander control so
conceptually this is even even simpler
than the previous two
workstation one has only inbound three
three at nine so remote desktop access
to workstation two there's no other
network connectivity so we need to use
some functionality of remote desktop in
order for command control to take place
a couple of limitations here
you obviously need map drives to be
enabled so by default it is but we have
worked on some restrictive environments
where it's explicitly disabled by group
policy so worth checking that
and also for this
example in the scenario and most likely
operationally you'll be using sharp rdp
to do everything through a beacon if you
are using sharp rdp it's got a couple of
limitations so the target's keyboard
must be set to us english and also there
can't be any special characters in the
command you're executing so the the
default relay name has underscores so
you just need to change your relay name
if you're doing this hands-on keyboard
like manually through a remote desktop
session these restrictions don't apply
but it's worth bearing in mind as
chances are you will be using sharp idp
the data flow is quite simple so
workstation one will be using uh c users
public so it's again it's using the unc
share file channel that we talked about
before so it's going to be reading and
writing packets to see users public
workstation 2 is also going to be
reading writing to see users public
except from the perspective of
workstation 2 the network path is
slightly different so it's the terminal
of services client backslash c backslash
users access to public
so it's reading right in the same
directory but just bear in mind that the
the target directory
is slightly different when you're
generating the relay
so first thing to do is create the
channel so you can see here we're using
the book standard unc share file and
we're specifying c users public so
workstation one is going to use that
directory we'll need to download the
relay and we can keep everything the
same except the target directory so from
the perspective of workstation 2 this is
again the the ts client see users public
so it's going to use the map drive that
sharp idp is going to create
to to expose see users public on
workstation one two workstation two
so to execute the relay we can also make
use of sharp idp we don't actually need
to upload the the payload to workstation
2 we can put it in the map drive and we
can execute command there with two
really important flags so
connect drive equal true
so this is going to connect the map
drive and allow you to access that
payload and ultimately access cs public
to transfer the files
and x equals force so this tells sharp
rdp that once you've successfully
executed this relay keep the session
alive don't exit so this is going to
keep that map drive exposed to
workstation 2. so once we've done that
you can see that it's already checked in
in c3 on the right hand side so we can
now stage a beacon as we've done before
through this
and
this is going to be
writing its files to c users public
which is already exposed because sharp
idp is still running in the beacon
and you can see
hopefully the
b can check in c3 on the right hand side
and also in the team server on the left
nice cool so from a detection angle then
so of course we've got our relay process
in the the workstation one
and that's going to be using.net tooling
just as we saw from saw from sharpsphere
in this case sharp rdp ox13's post
exploitation tooling is now running in
our spawn to process run dlr32
that's making network connections over
onto our workstation two where we have
our new relay running and then both of
those relays are then communicating back
effectively to see users public on
workstation one so what can we look for
here well a series of different things
really let's take a look
firstly dot net tooling we've seen this
kind of principle before using ecw we
can see our assembly loads within run
dl32 so we can see quite clearly sharp
rdp is running and we can also see some
of the dlls that actually facilitate
this as well
so using our effectively headless rdp
session we're making use of the dll
mstscax.dll which is the activex client
rdp dll
using etw or you can see in process
hacker for example we can see that that
dll has been loaded obviously as james
says that needs to be running to
initiate the connection
and then map the drive and allow that to
stay open so that's what we're seeing
there we can see that the the module
load taking place
and then of course just as we saw before
i run dll32 our spawn two process is
making a very anomalous connection to
our second workstation on 3389 to
actually establish our rdp session
um
also here just as a note and when we're
doing that beacon staging we're going to
see a burst of package with a larger
size there those udp packets that are
actually going to enable us to transfer
that data over and achieve
the beacon running within workstation
2's relay
and finally elder brilliant so the last
channel we're going to talk about is
ldap so this is using ldap attributes to
transmit data between workstation 1 and
workstation 2 ultimately for command
control scenario workstation 1 has again
no network connectivity to workstation
2. however they can both talk ldap to
the same domain controller and so we can
use these ldap attributes to transfer
data between the two
there's a couple of limitations and i
would highly encourage you to check out
the references listed below because all
of this channel is entirely built on the
research from from these two in
particular uh
so
please please check them out um you know
kudos to them this wouldn't have
happened without the research they put
out
so both sides need to communicate with
the same domain controller ideally
otherwise it becomes operationally um
very restrictive because you have to
wait for the attributes to sync across
the main controllers
both sides need to be able to modify the
same user's attributes
and you're also limited by the the
target attribute that you choose so the
size of data type and again in those
references there's some research which
data which attributes are appropriate to
use uh and we've simply used that use
that research already
so from a data flow perspective it's
very similar to before
except there's a difference but there's
a lock attribute and a data attribute so
these are the two different ldap
attributes that you are you are reading
and writing to so
workstation one is going to use the lock
attribute to set
the destination id that the data
attribute should be read by so
workstation one is gonna write to the
lock attribute
that
the
information in the data attribute is
destined for workstation 2 right so it's
going to write to the lock attribute
first and it's going to write the actual
data to the data attribute you've
specified
workstation 2 is going to check what's
in the lock attribute and say is it
destined for me great it is
so it's going to take that and it's
going to clear both attributes ready to
be used again by another relay
so we're going to create a channel and
there's a channel ldap in c3 just to
drive a bit deeper into what each one of
these means
the data attribute so this is where the
bulk of the data is stored
we use msmq science certificates there
are others available if you check out
that research that we linked before
but msmq science certificates mean you
can
any domain users can modify their own
attribute here
and it can also support one makeup data
so it gets the best throughput block
attribute is less important that's just
where you're storing the
where the data attribute is actually
destined for
maximum packet size
if you're not changing it don't need to
worry about it if you are check out the
research because not all of them support
this much data
username and password that's for an
account that has the ability to or the
permissions to modify the target
attributes if you're running under the
context of the user here
who owns the attribute then you don't
need to worry about this but if you need
to operate it under a different user's
context you'll need to specify the
username and password explicitly
so
in practice
on workstation 2 you've got your
outbound connection you can execute your
relay
this is going to start writing data to
the data and the lock attributes
and
all being well you should see uh in your
c3 on the right hand side your relay
should check in
as it uses those attributes for for
transfer
there we go you can see that the relay
is checked in so commando control via
those attributes has been established
and again we can add a peripheral beacon
as before
nice thanks
so last one then detection opportunities
here well
there's there's several here again
obviously the old app queries network
connections and the windows event logs
that are servicing from our domain
controllers as well so let's take a look
firstly network connections just as we
saw there needs to be some kind of
constructive beaconing taking place here
and as we can see in our in this case
plain text ldap implementation we can
see this continuous polling against the
isdn number um attribute which is our
lock attribute to see if there's
anything there that's destined for us
and our relay
if we like take a little bit of a dive
into the code here we can see how the
receiving
logic looks firstly we check the lock
attribute is it destined for us is this
stuff that we should care about if not
no further action
if it's us writing to the channel we
check the lock attribute again but this
time just to make sure it's clear we're
not going to be overwriting some other
packets and start interrupting other
communications
and then when we're happy there we've
written to that we can then write to our
data attribute with the data that's then
going to be passed on to our destination
again using etw for the ldap queries
here there's a little snippet there for
the config
we can take a look at that and quite
clearly we can see our two relays making
these queries to the primary
international sdn number and to the
scientific attribute as well
interestingly we can use um directory
service change events so 5136 and this
is surface through the use of a sacl or
a sacko against those attributes as well
so every time they're changed we will
see um
the surface of 5.36 and here you can see
on the very right hand side
that unique attribute value being set
and then further down you can see
another attribute and the the same
attribute set with a different value
another another value there and if we
take a look in c3 and kind of compare
them side by side we can see that these
values actually match up with the output
id and the input id for their respective
relay so just as james described what
we're doing here is writing to this and
say this is destined for this relay and
this is destined in response to that as
well
and then as well as that we can also see
the sign certificates actually being
changed as well with bike content which
is of course is the contents of our data
that's being sent
then we can also use access events
directory service access event so this
is 4662
this is a little bit different and
obviously by design more noisy basically
and because rather than just the change
events we're looking at every time a
user accesses this attribute as well um
if we look at the object properties
there you can see these guides and using
the microsoft documentation we can relay
that back um to the relevant attributes
so the science certificates attributes
um and the primary international isdn
number as well there and quite usefully
we can see the access mask as well there
so you can see read property and right
property are being used there so we can
kind of infer what's happening where
we're writing and reading from those as
we need to to achieve um c2 so finally
conclusions
brilliant thank you so if you made it
this far then well done uh if there was
three things i want you to walk away
from this talk with right it's the
importance of reviewing the trust
boundaries between critical networks you
know confirm that are they really as
air-gapped as you think
look for possible data flows that could
be exploited in this sort of fashion and
then also look at how they could be
mitigated so can i completely be
eliminated or can you include the the
prevention and detection controls that
we've
discussed here to
prevent an attacker abusing these
channels and more broadly can you
preemptively reduce your attack surface
by looking at the internal external
services that could be used and abused
for c2 and preemptively blocking them
yeah absolutely and then just one last
thing to say the link in the bottom
there is to the c3
tooling on github it's open source
openly available so please do check it
out
and then also we're we're very active on
bloodhound slack as well in the c3
channel so if you want to talk to us uh
or indeed the developers that maintain
c3 um then please join there and we can
we can have a chat but otherwise thank
you and thanks for joining thanks
everyone