[Music]
hello everybody and welcome to my talk
bypassing windows hello for business and
pleasure
my name is ahmad salfati i'm a security
researcher at cyber clubs
i'm 24 years old and i'm for six years
in the security industry
and for those of you who play call of
duty i'm a vehicle of duty fan so feel
free to contact me and we'll play
together
so what will we have today
we'll talk a little bit about
passwordless what is passwordless why
should we use passwordless uh instead of
or
of existing authentication methods
now then we'll speak about windows hello
which is a relatively new microsoft
password resolution
and then we will talk about the main
part of this research that we did
and on how we managed to bypass uh
windows low fashion recognition at the
end we'll talk about what could be done
even further more in the research and
for any of you that would like to
continue this research is more than
welcome to
look at this part um
very closely
anyway by the end of this talk you will
should know by 85 percent what windows
low is and some of its features by 50
about usb and ufc by 10 you should be a
little bit confused and you should have
a lot a lot of fun
right
let's go let's start uh let's talk about
passwordless um so what is passwordless
uh so passwordless it's kind of
all right so before we're talking about
passwordless let's talk why we should
use passwordless uh i mean we have
existing authentication methods we have
passwords we're using those four years
and we why we should replace them so
underneath passwords there is a lot of
problems inherent uh i mean we are human
and we
tend to use weak passwords because we
want to to choose password that is
really easy to remember
um there is there are data breaches so
once we are giving vendor or server or
password it should save it somewhere in
database or something like this in some
cases it saves it's saved as a version
of our password and in some other
less good
cases it saves as plain text and once
accurate so attackers bridging in and
and steal those passwords you might um
they might get our password so it's
really bad and the third thing it's
phishing attacks so phishing attacks um
it's a major problem because we are
human and we tend to to fall to them we
tend to give our passwords
on our will to attackers and hackers and
and so this is another big problem
and
as i mentioned before we are human and
we we don't want to remember a lot of
things so we will use passwords and
actually do this so we reuse our
passwords for many vendors and if one of
them got bridged we
actually lose all of our all of our
accounts
so now we understand that passwords are
kind of not that good as we thought uh
so
let's use password less so what is
passwordless uh so how you should do
passwordless so passwordless is any
authentication method that doesn't
really
require you to
send a password
so like fingerprint scanning or facial
recognition security key or otp all of
those are variants of passwordless
solutions
about otp so otp it's kind of one-time
passwords and it might
not be
it might not sound as a possible
resolution but because it's one-time
password and you can only use it one
time it's considered as possible the
solution
so
now we we understand that passwords are
bad and what is passwordless how
passwordless solution implemented in in
in different ways so let's talk about
one of the uh most common implementation
of passwordless which is windows hello
uh as i mentioned before windows hello
it's microsoft a
relatively new password resolution
so say hello to windows hello
right so windows low and
it's for everyone everyone can use it
either if you're enterprise or home
consumer the main difference between
those those fit
those implementation it's their main
purpose so for enterprise solutions um
it's it will give you the ability to um
to authenticate uh via domain or azure
assets and for home consumer it's
actually
kind of
replacing your passwords it's it's not
actually what happening in the
background because your
your password hash is still remain on
your device but your pin code will let
you access it the system will access it
and then you can still use it
right so let's talk about windows hello
features so windows hello has three main
features
face recognition which relying on ir
sensor and advanced analysis of the
frames that coming from the io sensor
pin code which is a kind of replacing
your password with another password
local password and fingerprint
authentication
which we all know for years
right so
we we
wanted to do a research on windows allow
because it's passwords it's cool and um
we thought which which feature should we
do research on
so
we we we did a little a little overview
on all the
uh all the solutions on all the
different features
and we try to consider what would be the
best option to do a research on
um
fingerprint so the to collect the data
the fingerprint
scanning of images itself will be really
hard besides that there is a lot of
previous art on
on this um area i mean i think there in
2006 in blackhead there was a research
on this there there there was a top on
this and the protocol is kind of uh how
to implement and there is not a lot of a
public implementation for this
pin code
so pin code as anti-brute force
mechanism so we couldn't really do a
brute force on this and we we thought it
will be the same challenge as trying to
break your regular passwords for the
computer
so we we didn't want to
choose this as well
and then so
the third feature that we did the
overview on which is the last one is
face face recognition so facial
condition also has an anti-brutal
mechanism
it is more easy to to start doing a
research on this because
nxp which is a major vendor in the
electronic industry implemented a basic
usb device which you could use as a
reference and
your face at the end of the day it's
kind of a public data i mean
we can capture this
relatively easily so
we choose to do a research on this
and and then we we try to figure out how
we should do the research i mean we
should first understand how um how
parametric authentication in windows
actually happens in the kind of an
overview
so
we are starting from application or or
credential provider that want to do
authentication and
biometric authentication then it uses
win biodll that advertion will
communicate with the windows biometric
service
to do this biometric authentication the
magnetic authentication is divided into
three parts i mean the facial
recognition
is divided into three parts the storage
adapter engine adapter and sensor
adapter
the storage adapter
will get the information that the
biometric templates that are saved on
your device from uh from the windows
biometric database
which is a folder in system 32 and
which contains many different database
for different and
different
authentications and face recognition as
its own database there uh and
there is another adapter sensor adapter
that is actually responsible for
communicating with the external uh
camera io sensor and there is the engine
adapter the engine adapter is
is the one that
responsible for um for deciding either
to log you in or not
uh right
uh so after we created this graph we
look at it and we thought what would be
the best uh place to
to to do a research on i mean we don't
have any kind of
um code execution on the device so most
of the parts are not relevant and the
only only part that we kind of can
control is the sensor
so
we we consider the following things so
at first we thought that it would be
cool to run a
code on the sensor itself but actually
it will be a standalone research for
itself and we didn't want to go there
and the other way is to beat a sensor so
we we implemented a kind of a inform
ir camera uh out of nothing uh we we
um we used an xp evaluation board for
this and um we will talk later why we
use this and one of the main reasons you
actually use this is because as i
mentioned before there is an example
project which we could use as a
reference
so it will be much more convenient for
us to
to actually use nxp
right so we talk about
windows hello about password less about
what we want to do in the research so
let's talk about the research
uh
so part three exploiting show me the
money
so the research vector is divided into
four parts the first one will be analyze
and before we try to implement a usb
device we first want to
implement to understand what usb and usb
and uvc is
then after this we will mimic the usb
device um which actually we will create
kind of a low camera a
usb
video camera that
is compatible with windows low and can
function as a regular windows hello
camera then we will capture the person
that we uh put his target
for us to log into his account and
bypass windows authentication and we
will bypass windows hello
all right so let's talk about uh the
first uh the first part the analyze so
that that section is divided to two main
parts at first we need to understand the
usb specs and then we will need to
capture the traffic and
so
capturing traffic will be used we will
do it via wireshark uh with the plug-in
a usb pickup and the usb specs
the way that we chose to do the research
to understand the usb spec is to read
the usb spec and we read it we read we
read we read a lot
too much and we we we went to offsite i
mean it's it's too many um
and
and i thought what would be the best way
to
to explain to you guys for those of you
who are not familiar with usb and uvc uh
the usb specs
at least the the
usb framework
so we choose to do it in a kind of story
so
this is usb
usb it's it's a nice guy
and it's
usb first day at school so you went to
school and then
he met
austin
and austin it's a bully
and our usb is a nice guy
and austin
came to
to usb and asked him who the hell are
you and they used to be told them
i would say everything everything that
you want to know uh let me do it um
in a great detail so
because he was afraid of fasting that he
will beat him up uh he won't consider
what would be the best day to do this so
the best day for him to do this was via
descriptors
so he started to describe himself at
first he started with device scripto and
where he's coming from
everybody and
every descriptor has a lot of fields and
most of them are not really interesting
but the most interesting um fields are
the bcd usb which is the version of the
usb device and those three
those three
fields which is i defend or id product
and bcd device at the event though it's
the id of the
of the vendor id product the idea of the
product and the bcd device is the
version
of the device
right so
besides that
mr nice guy wants to tell about his
abilities and features to ask him
because again he's really terrified uh
that uh austin will beat him up and he
started to do it via configuration
script
so he sent a configuration descriptor to
to austin
and uh
and austin because
nothing needs to allocate enough memory
for the descriptor and because every usb
device is a bit different from one
another um
the the configuration the full
configuration device which describes all
the abilities and features of the usb
device it's a bit different so therefore
the length of the configuration
descripto will be
will be either longer or shorter
um
and the endos and austin should know um
how much memory to allocate so at first
we are sending an intro intro includes
the the total length of the
configuration
and uh usb device sending to austin and
austin now want to know
what is the full abilities of the usb
device usb device
send it to austin
right so i hope you understood
what a configuration descriptor and
devices
and
this is was our story about a usb
mr nice guy
and
all right so
after we we we captured all this
information uh we saved it for later
years because if because we want to
mimic the usb device and we want to send
all this metadata to this
to the host as we were the uh original
camera device
all right so for any of you that want
even to
to learn more about usb the best the
best way to do this is either by reading
the usb specs uh which you can find
those in the usb if uh
website
uh or either you uh read it in um
and beyond in beyond logic website there
is a good article called usb in a
nutshell so you totally should take a
look on this
right so now we finish the first part
which is analyze usb ubc and now let's
go to the mimic part so also this part
will be divided into two
the first one will be uh implement
implementing the usb camera
with our um
evaluation board device
using the reference that nxp
implemented and the second part will be
make the usb device that we just created
compatible with windows hello
right so
this process will look like this at
first we'll download the nxp ide which
called mcu expresso and then we'll
import the sdk example
which called their video
virtual camera vm
and then we'll need to
uh configure it configure the
the example project uh to match the
descriptor that we extracted uh add
another support for a second camera as
the windows hello requires every
compatible camera to have
to have
regular camera and infrared camera and
um
we did all of this so we actually should
have should have
should have a working and functional
windows hello compatible camera but once
we connected it to the computer we got
this
beautiful error message that says our
usb device could not be recognized and
you should go and figure it figure why
because it's not
that easy to understand as it's kind of
a generic error message
um
so we we we were clueless at this point
we we didn't know why why it happened
because
during the development of the of the
video camera the
the evaluation board the all the changes
we do we did on the evaluation board we
didn't
have any kind of these error messages
and
this error message only came up when uh
when
we changed one thing one field
which was the
usb version we changed it from
2.0 to 2.1 which for matching the usb
version that their original camera the
compatible windows hello camera is using
and then we we didn't know why what does
why
does it happen
and we we wanted to understand so after
a lot of
uh trial and error we
find out that we are missing a
descriptor
so which descriptor
are we missing
the bos descriptor of course
apparently
every usb device that reports a bcd usb
which is over 2.0 or
0x 200 and we'll be required to provide
a bos descripto
so
the operation system will ask for the
bos descripto and if the request fails
it means that we are not sending the bos
descriptor there a driver stack will
fail enumeration of our device and it's
kind of bad
so
we went through the um the documentation
of um of usb and we found out uh what
are the field that the boss descriptor
need to be there and we extracted the
pos descripto
that
the original camera using uh is using
and
and we we still remain
with the same question
why
did we not see
the
vos descripto in the washock traffic
captured
i mean
we we
we capture it should show all the
information all the all the traffic but
it missing the voice script though so we
we thought white white is happening so
the main reason for this is because we
didn't use linux
and
we we didn't understand why why there is
those differences between linux and and
windows in capturing usb devices
uh um because we didn't uh really
do any kind of a research or a further
investigation on this
but
we we
it was really strange to find out that
this is the main reason anyway uh after
this uh we we had after we added the os
descriptor to the
usb device and we added implementation
for this we connected the usb device and
then we got this
so now we have a fully working usb video
camera that is compatible with windows
hello and we can control all the
information it's sending to the computer
so what are we missing we're missing the
information that we need to send so
let's capture it um
all right so
as i mentioned before windows low
require you to
have a
ir sensor which will transmit infrared
frames and camera sense and the color
camera sensor that will transmit regular
camera a irregular a color phrase
uh so we need to capture both of those
and a funny style note about that uh a
side note about that doesn't really
pay attention to anything that you are
sending in the color frames because
the the analysis analysis mechanism it's
only relying on the infrared frames
so you actually can send whatever you
want there
we chose by the way to send a
frame of spongebob and
believe it or not it worked uh
diaphragms were um real by the way
uh so like if we want to capture the the
data let's talk about how the the frames
are transferred to the computer so
we see now we see the the
the
the urb packets usb ulb packets which
kind of reminding how udp works as it's
sending chunks of data kind of streaming
the video
to the computer and the computer needs
to extract the information from this
um
all right
so how does the computer know
what is the start of the frame what is
the end of the frame
what you should do with the frame so
each frame starting with an adder
with the header so
this header is um has a lot of fields
and we are not really
want to go all over them but two fields
are really important for us the frame
identifier and the end of frame so the
frame identifier um
tells us when a frame
is started and the end of frame
as it sounds
indicates us when a frame is ended so
with this information we could go over a
use a usb traffic of the video stream
look for the urb packets
and extract all the frames
um
but because we know where the frame
started and when where it's ended
but to validate it our frames are valid
at the end of the day this is what we
want to do
we need to we need to know in which
format they are being sent
so
we looked at the configuration skip
though
because it's mentioned there and we look
at the color image and we we saw that
this is kind of um
m jpeg frames the stream of m jpegs and
the left one which is the ir sensor is
the strength grid
so we didn't know what this trend could
mean and so after a lot a lot of
googling we found out that this is a ks
data format subtype l8ir which is a
which is a format that
microsoft uses
which is at the end of the day it's a
luma 8-bit plane frames
by the way we could
save a lot of time
of googling if you look just straight in
the msdn documentation documentation
because it's written they're
pretty much straightforward
so
by now we we covered usb and usb specs
we we know how to capture usb traffic we
managed to implement a fully working
video
usb device
and also
we know how to
extract the
video frames then
so
we have all the information that we need
with all the tools that we need to
bypass the authentication
right so
so
what i thought that
it would be really great to go with pie
shark
uh which is a library in python for um
manipulating and
loading a washout traffic
capture so
go with bioshock on the capture
save the relevant frames with the
previous knowledge that we have and save
it into the evaluation board send it to
the computer pretending to be a real
usb
windows hello camera and bypass the
login
the facial recognition
but it didn't work and we
so the reason it didn't work it's quite
interesting apparently
the
regular camera sending a lot of
information and a lot of frames that are
um not valid which was very strange but
apparently microsoft knows how to uh to
get rid of those frames and uh
we didn't want to understand how to do
this to do this as microsoft did it
already so we used a microsoft media
framework to capture the relevant
infrared image frames of the uh our
target person saved it into the um
to the evaluation board and it worked
this time there was a lot of yay in the
in the crowd and it was really really
fun right so we talked a lot let's see
the demo
um
so it's demo time
right so here we we see windows hello
user
this is the evaluation board that we
used it's a custom usb camera that
stores the recorded iframes of me of
course
we connected it to the
to the computer
of course
and shortly windows will recognize the
usb device and we'll use it as it was a
regular video camera
windows log compatible by the way
so the custom usb camera sends the
recorded frame to the target
of the target to the computer
so this actually tricks windows a lot to
think the target person is in front of
it of the computer
and proof
um
all right
so let's discuss what we just saw
right so at first the attacker captures
or create and infrared
frames of the victim
then it stores the they infrared then
he needs to create a custom usb device
that in person at a usb a video camera
that is compatible of course with
windows alert
the attacker saves the relevant
information it captured the first step
to the
to the usb device then connect the usb
device to john's computer
the usb device transmitted the capture
infrared
the paramedical system accept the
environment the biomedical cardentile
and logs the user in and attacker gets a
lot of information and sensitive data
that he shouldn't have access to
right
so
all right here we come to the final part
this is the four fourth part
what's what we should uh
what
we should do in um richard in research
even more
um
right
so um
we so what i recommend you to do if you
want to continue this research is to
find a way to convert color in for an
image to infrared
um
so if you will do a google on this you
you if you will find out a couple
threads in some forms that will say it's
impossible
um but we actually did the sim
uh quite briefly research on this and we
found out
that from our research it might be
possible because we managed to
convert one color image of
of me to infrared one but it wasn't that
extensive research and we we do
recommend you to to do a better research
on this another really interesting thing
is to manipulate the biometric uh
database in windows
at the end of the day if an attack you
want to create um
really really smart backdoor that nobody
will look after
he should look at this i mean
it is considered to be a place that you
save a credential in and if somebody is
able to manipulate this it will be great
and it will kind of can create uh
it can create a passwordless i mean a
backdoor to the user account
um the the database at least the one
that windows law uses is
it's protected by uh
by the system passwords but it i think
that if the user if the attacker has
already um high privileges in the
victim computer you can manipulate this
another cool thing will be fuzzing so if
an attacker could extract this database
and decrypt this with a system password
and take all the information there to a
local machine
and start to use the windows hello
framework
in order to
kind of
fuzz in the database to find out what
will be the relevant information you
will be able to send to
to a real device to unlock
the device target it will be really
interesting
we started also to do a small project on
this and it's a walk-in progress so if
anything will
come out from this we'll let you know
guys
and that's for what is next um
so let's cover what we saw today so at
the first section we talked about
usb
then we went about password less and
then
what is password less why it's
considered to be more secure than a
password regular traditional
authentication
mechanism methods or in the other way
other way to say passwords
and
so
we talked about windows low
and how we managed to bypass windows
hello
what considered to be the weak point the
the weakest point in the windows law and
mechanism um and the fourth thing that i
hoped you had it's a lot a lot of fun
so regarding recommendations um so this
is that verto is not
it's not even about windows or law
specific it's about authentication
mechanism that rely on public data
public factor for authentication
so please don't base your authentication
on public factors
um
about mitigations um
so we walked alongside microsoft to
mitigate this attacking vector and we're
still working with them on this and
microsoft told us that they should uh
publish
uh publish um advisory to mitigate this
attack vector so by the time you should
you will see the by the time you're
seeing this video
this talk
there should be advisory in the in the
micros in the mslc website so go and
check this
and
besides that we also by the time you're
seeing this um this video we also
published um two blog posts about this
research and what we did in the research
even more extensive than this talk so
feel free to
visit our website or threat research
blog
so thank you very much guys uh i'm
mohamed sawfati i had a great time being
here today uh and feel free to contact
me via twitter if you have any questions
uh besides i'm waiting for your question
in the live q a
thank you very much guys