[Music]
hello everyone i am ali davanian a
fourth year phd candidate joining me is
ahmad we are very thrilled to
present our work cnc hunter
iot malware is on the rise and you
probably all
already know about this
the question is how can we defend
against iot malware
and a
key piece of the puzzle here
is the command and control server or the
cnc
uh if we knew where the command and
control servers are located
then the defense would be easy we can
easily take down the botnet or we can
blacklist them at our network perimeter
and our iot devices within the network
would be safe and this is essentially
important for iot devices because of
their limited computing resource we
cannot afford more expensive solutions
like antivirus on the device
uh so our goal in this work is finding
all the live cnc servers i want you to
picture this for a second right imagine
that we knew we're only live cnc servers
are located right this is very exciting
i've been thinking about this uh gets me
excited
uh if we had this information then
taking down a botnet
or defending against them would be easy
so what do we have to start with as
independent security researchers we have
malware binaries we have access to some
ip blacklist and we have partial
information about malware communication
protocols
what we don't have is access to the
network traffic and also access to
antivirus companies sensors right
given that let's review the previous
approaches
so one method to identify cnc server is
to statically analyze the binary and
find the ip addresses that it might
contact
the limitation with this approach is
when the binary is obfuscated right so
it sometimes wouldn't work
the second approach is to execute and
activate the binary let it generate
traffic and then watch
what eyepiece it tries to contact again
the limitation with this approach is
that the ip address might not be live
the third approach is to infer the
network protocol right the protocol that
the iot malware tries to use
and then scan the internet you look for
finger prints based on the protocol
inference and then find the cnc servers
the limitation with this approach is
that iot malware proto communication
protocols are too complex these days
uh and you cannot have a generic
solution and uh encryption also adds to
the problem
finally we could passively monitor the
internet look at the malware traffic
and then
find the uh cnc addresses that the
malware might contact the limitation
with this approach again is the size of
the traffic and the diversity in the
number of iot malware communication
protocols
so what do we propose we propose cnc
hunter
and our solution is a novel solution
that allows you to probe do the probing
and cnc discovery using the real malware
right so for the probing we don't want
to understand the communication protocol
but we want to use the real malware to
uh communicate with the
uh potential addresses that we might
think uh are hosting cnc servers right
uh as far as we know we are the first
open source tool
uh and we are specifically designing
this tool for finding iot malware cncs
uh the way we do this is by activating
the iot malware meaning that we actually
execute the malware we let it
communicate with the outside world
and uh we use many-in-the-middle
techniques to
redirect the cnc traffic to some uh
candidate addresses these addresses are
inputs we suspect that they might host
uh cnc servers
right
uh with that uh this is the overview of
the talk we are gonna cover some basics
and then we are going to spend the rest
of the talk
uh
discussing cnc hunter design and
implementation okay so let's start with
iot communication
protocols now i don't want you to read
over the text and learn every bit of uh
detail about the iot
malware communication protocols what i
want you to see though is that the
communication protocols are kind of
diverse here right so we have custom
application layer protocols that are
binary based some are text-based we have
sometimes encryption
and this really makes generic probing
very hard right if we were dealing with
only one application layer protocol then
probably we could design a probing
technique and scandinavia right and
scanning and you know actively probing
is very important here
uh if you look at the communication
protocols
then uh within a single family what we
find is that they barely change right so
what i'm going to show you in this slide
is
a generic irc say server communication
with a gasket malware sample
uh
this is not the cnc server for the
sample right
but uh we made the sample talk to this
generic irc server and it actually
successfully communicated with it right
the reason we chose gaffit is because
it's textbit so it's easier for you to
follow
so the communication starts with the tcp
handshake and after the tcp handshake
the malware sends
the irc nic command right the server
responds and after that the malware
sends a mode request right this is again
an irc command the server responds and
again uh the malware communicates it at
this time it sends a join command says i
want to join this irc channel the server
again responds and then the malware
finishes
with a who request right to which again
the server responds now here's the
interesting fact using the same irc uh
server
it's a it's a generic server again it's
not a cnc server we could communicate
with
99.5 percent of the gasket samples right
and this is very exciting because this
provides an opportunity for us right
only with one gasket sample possibly old
right uh
years uh four years old malware samples
we can search go and search for the cnc
servers that are live right for the
entire family
and we need to do this because uh
probably we are not aware of most of the
cnc servers
that are live and we didn't know they
exist so what we did we manually
analyzed 100 iot samples and we found
their cnc servers right we started with
the samples that were four years old
and what we found is that only 3.5 of
the samples have a live cnc server right
so we reduce the age of the malware
and this time we analyzed samples that
were
142 days old in this case uh none of the
samples had a live cnc server
we continued we again reduced the age of
the malware by
one order of magnitude and this times
this time we analyze samples that
were two weeks old and in this case 14
of the samples had a live cnc server the
the best we could do or you could do is
analyzing samples that are one day old
and in this case uh roughly half of the
samples
had a live cnc server what this means is
that half of the other samples have a
cnc seller that already moved to a new
location right
uh so these samples are hidden and we
need to
actually actively probe the internet and
find them and with this i'm going to
give the floor to my friend ahmad turkey
thank you ali
so in this part we're going to look into
what are the
active research or whatever has been
done previously in identifying live cnc
servers so there is this concept of
active probing you send out certain
traffic to the internet and doing
scanning and then when there is a
successful connection or there's a
successful uh communication in general
you deem uh the endpoint as a potential
cnc server
now we're gonna look into this from an
iot uh malware perspective we're gonna
look into mirai malware mirai had been
uh notoriously famous for their uh the
volumetric uh ddos attack that they
carried out in both september 2016 on
kryptonsecurity.com
and october 2016 when they carried out
the biggest ddos attack on dying dns and
resulted in disrupting github twitter
and some of the major uh you know
services like spotify shopify and all of
those and the source code was released
and that led to a lot more
malware samples coming from this malware
family that you can see it in any
malware repositories that
the malware family with the highest
number of samples is something like
exactly mirai
so we're going to look into how does the
communication look like when a malware
like mirai infects a an iot device and
how does an active probing would look
like so for an active probing say an
infection has happened and
malware will send out
after initiating a scene the tcp
connection with the cnc server it will
send out a byte pattern uh for in this
example it's it could be
zero zero zeros and the one at the end
and then the server acts the whatever
packet it receives and then uh it uh the
bot would proceed with authenticating
itself sort of like sending certain
patterns so that the cnc server would
know this is a button
um
a botnet instance and then uh it will
continue the connection and they will uh
maintain the connection like going back
and forth like something like a ping
pong and after that when there is a
successful uh recruitment of the butt
the cnc will command the uh bob to for
instance start doing a dos attack or or
something like that on crimson security
for instance on certain port
so this is how the active probing would
look like on the other hand we do things
a little bit differently we look into
actually using a malware
malwarebinder and sets of ip address uh
and then port numbers
to do the probing for us
and the way we are doing it we pro uh we
look into the malware using some static
analysis uh information to create an
effective emulation mechanism so that we
can have the malware start executing
properly and then we do the recording on
this traffic and we uh identify what is
what is the cnc server is trying to
communicate with and then we redirect
that to the input ip addresses that uh
we have
so
going a little bit into details of how
the sandbox and the profile module would
look like so in this project we're using
kmu
kmu enables
emulating
some of the not common cpu architectures
like mips power pc or mips cell
so this is something that we chose to go
with
um and then we are
uh we are attaching kernel to it so that
we will have the kenya running and then
we will also attach file system to it
this will allow us to have
some sort of a recording
and snapshotting of whatever uh the
malware is doing in the recording it's
you know a system called traces um and
so on and so forth
we also attach a tap device to
the
2k mute so that we can redirect the
traffic to
the proxy that
later we will get into and tap device
would also allow us to
do a recording of network traffic
and later we will what we call it up
implanting the malware into the uh
emulation so that uh so that we can uh
realistically execute the malware
collected
and then recorded system called traces
and have everything uh collected like
execution uh is entirely collected via
the profiler which will later on will be
fed into other
parts of the cnc hunter
with that i will yield back to ali
please ali take it away
thank you ahmed uh so
for the rest of the talk i'm gonna uh
discuss the details of the mitm
component and already covered the
sandbox component of cnc hunter
uh the goal of uh demanding the middle
component mitm component is to redirect
the cnc traffic to candidate addresses
as we mentioned a few times these
candidate addresses are inputs right we
suspect that they are hosting cnc uh
servers the man in the middle
is
ip based here
and uh we are gonna tap the traffic and
also provide internet from the sammers
right uh so we are actually men in the
middling the real traffic that goes to
internet all right so let's start with
uh the design alternatives that we have
uh
for placing the mitm module right where
should we place this mitm module we have
the sandbox module right the maverick
executes there you also have the network
perimeter and that uh as i said proxies
the traffic to the internet right
zooming in uh the sandbox component
there are different parts there is the
qmu component that runs the an operating
system with the malware that malware
executes in the user space and for every
network request it sends the request to
the network driver which resides in the
os kernel and this network driver driver
closely communicates with the sandbox
driver handler right
three of the design alternatives that we
have
uh would be placing the
mitm module
uh
at this sandbox component different
parts of the sandbox component they
suffer all from the same problem and the
problem is that if we
wanted to
go for a solution like this we had to
provide an implementation for every
different
you know implementation that there is
for the layer for instance different
operating systems
uh on the other hand we can you know
place the mi atm module
at the network perimeter and this is our
choice it doesn't have the previous
problems
right so
uh we would place the mitm module at the
network perimeter and
our goal is to replace the original cnc
address that the malware tries to
communicate with with the candidate
address right and this candidate address
is an input
so if we were to write the rule for ip
tables it would look like this right we
would simply tell iptables to
replace the uh original rp address with
the input ip address that we want right
however this wouldn't work
right
uh we spent quite some time trying to
figure out how we can you know make
iptel
ip tables work and do this by default ip
tables wouldn't allow this so we are
stuck right what should we do
and uh
after you know some time and kind of
banging our head we
came up with a creative solution the
solution is to move the iep tables from
the network perimeter to the sandbox and
if we do so then we can change the rule
to
from the post routing chain to the
output chain and then this works right
this allows us to
uh replace the ip address with something
that we want great now we have the man
in the middle functionality we can
redirect the traffic but how about the
dns based cnc addresses right as i said
iptables is ip based we don't know
anything about dns in iep tables how can
we handle dns based cnc addresses and
the answer is we need to manipulate the
local dns resolution process we actually
need to resolve the cnc dns address the
original uh address dns address that the
malware tries to communicate with
uh with the candidate address right that
we provide
uh how do we do that so it turns out
there's a uh
we tried different things the clean and
easy solution is to change the
uh host file
uh on the guest operating system and add
a line that says in the host file that
says translate resolve this dns address
to the candidate ip address again the
candidate address is suspected to host
the cnc server
great okay so we have the mitm function
already the next question is what
traffic should be redirected right
uh probably you know it by now only the
traffic to the cnc but is it the only
traffic that the malware generates the
answer is no right so there are other
types of traffic that the matter would
generate there's the traffic for
scanning the malware goes and scan
different ports to find vulnerable hosts
and you know infect them as well there's
the background traffic that comes from
the virtual machine and every now and
then the malware some malware uh
generated random traffic to for instance
google or other addresses so fun finding
the traffic is to the cnc is actually
not trivial
uh here you can see a snapshot of the
new
uh traffic you know this is just a
portion of the traffic that mirai
generates there is the cnc address in
this traffic
and what we are going to do we are going
to start uh from some observations right
something some observations that we have
about the cnc traffic cnc address
uh so the
logic here is that the cnc address is
going to be contacted quite uh
frequently by the malware
and the port that the
cnc address has right the cnc server has
is kind of unique now if you take all
the ports that the malware tries to
communicate with the one that belongs to
the cnc server is kind of unique there
are the details i'm not going to cover
them now
but let's go to the you know the main
part that is
the frequency of the connection to the
cnc address and the port
so what we are going to use is the
parshark for the traffic analysis
and we would have an algorithm that
helps us identify the cnc address so
what we are going to do we are going to
assign a score to each iv address in the
malware traffic and the s core is based
on the observations that i just
mentioned right we know that this score
is proportionally related to the
connection frequency and it's inversely
proportional to the port frequency right
so we can uh write this simple formula
that the score uh is
a connection frequency over port
frequency times a coefficient right and
the
cnc address is the one that has the
highest score
right great so now we have this formula
how do we calculate connection frequency
and port frequency
we have two data structures uh we store
the connection frequency and port
frequency in these data structures so
the first data structure stores the data
about the connection frequency uh we
would have the ip port cards and also
the dns addresses that the malware tries
to communicate with for each of these
addresses we keep track of the number of
times that the rst flag the syn flag and
the act flag were on and also the number
of times that the dns address could not
be
found right this gives us the connection
frequency for the port frequency we have
another
uh hash table
it maps port numbers to the number of
times that they were seen
in the malware traffic right
using these two
uh parameters we can calculate the score
for each address and you know find the
one that has the highest score that one
is the cnc there are other details based
on other observations that i mentioned
i'm not covering them here
but our source code is uh open source so
you can go check it out you have the
port filtering and the reputation
filtering functionalities
okay great so now cnc hunter can
redirect the cnc traffic to some
candidate addresses right
but which of these candidate addresses
is a cnc
right again this is not a trivial
uh problem uh
because not only the cnc server uh would
communicate back right would respond to
our request as a matter of fact every
address that is live every ip address
that is live listens to our target port
and is not filtered
will respond right
so which one is the cnc server
the criteria that i just mentioned could
be uh simply filtered based on the you
know tcp communication the tcp layer if
there is a response of course we can see
that the ip address is live uh listens
we can check whether the tcp handshake
is successful and for
being not filtered we can check the rc
flag but rd is enough
uh no
right uh for instance in this example we
have two addresses that listen on port
443 right the first one is a cnc server
but the second one uh happens to
randomly you know listen
on the port that you're interested in
443 and in this case probably it's a
https web server but anyway it would
respond
it would respond to our requests right
so how can we distinguish the first one
from the second one we are on we are
only interested in the first address
right
what we found what we observed is that
the cnc's respond with significantly
lower uh number of times that the sim
flag is set right and in order to
understand this think about the human
communication right if two individuals
are chatting and they don't understand
each other what would they do right they
restart they repeat themselves and the
way that this pattern appears in network
communication is by resetting the syn
flag right uh setting it again and
sending the packet uh out
uh so we are finding the uh
communications with lower number of uh
times that the sim flag is on the way we
do that is by doing outlier detection
based on a standard deviation it's a
very simple formula we just calculate
the standard deviation and we find those
that you know are on the lower back okay
we evaluated cnc hunter
on a set of 100 samples we evaluated the
cnc finding functionality
we could activate 90 of the samples that
be analyzed and out of this uh we could
achieve a precision of 92 percent right
this is pretty much very accurate right
uh and i'm glad to say that
of the live cnc servers that we found
were exclusively found by us right the
other 82 percent also via solo reports
as malicious but uh these
18 percent were only found by us if you
check them on virustotal uh
they are not reported malicious
okay great so uh
i'm gonna start the demos now
we are gonna have two demos the first
demo uh is for finding the cnc server of
the sample right so we provide an iot
malware binary we know nothing about
this malware binder right we don't know
the architecture we don't know the
malware family we don't know anything
about the traffic that it generates you
know the ports that it tries to scan and
then exploit nothing
and uh we don't provide any
configuration for cnc hunter we just run
this script and it reports the cnc
server
uh for the second demo we go one step
further and what we do is
provide uh
some ip addresses that that we suspect
are hosting a cnc server
and we are using old samples you are
using four years old gasket samples we
expect these gasket samples to
communicate with the addresses that are
hosting a cnc server right and this is
very exciting right the they they have a
dead cnc server they would not
communicate generate any traffic but we
met in the middle and we want to see
whether they can successfully
communicate these addresses if they do
these addresses are hosting cnc server
okay so let's start from the uh
first demo so here i'm placing the
binary in the malware malware folder
this is a mirai sample i'm telling you
that it's memorized samples so you know
but i'm not providing this information
to cnc hunter uh the command is just
running this script around that py i'm
using the p option this is for filtering
the
ports that we are not interested in
right
i'm just showing you that we have this
option but even without providing these
options since your hunter is able to
find the cnc address for you right so
what cnc hunter does is analyzing the
executing the matter and analyzing the
traffic that it generates
so let's take a look at the traffic that
is
generated uh
i'm gonna fire
wireshark and take a look at the p-cap
traffic that is generated this is the
traffic that the mirai malware generates
right and as you can see by yourself
there are lots of ip addresses right
these are the scanning activities that
the malware has
there is the cnc communication
uh the analysis is going to take time by
default uh by default we spent five
minutes but here i'm gonna fast forward
boom we found the cnc address and here
in this case it's a dns based address
it's a live cnc server because the
malware was recent
and we are going to check the dns
address in virustotal and the virustotal
reports that it's not malicious right we
are aware that this is not like the
ultimate
uh oracle but we are just saying that uh
this is what we see on virustotal
all right uh the address is also
reported in the in a csv format this is
very useful if you have you know
uh a bunch of binaries not only one you
can see the report at the end in the
cnc's that csv file we also have an
analysis folder
under the result uh directory with the
name of the malware and there you have
the pcap traffic and also the system
call trace for the malware execution
uh
i'm gonna move to the second demo now
and in this demo as i mentioned we are
using the uh man in the middle
functionality right so in addition to
the malware that we provide these are
the matter that we use for the mitm
attack these are two
four years old gasket samples and we are
also uh providing an ip atlas in
practice it would be a wrench but since
you know we don't have enough time i'm
going to just show you
uh the communication with the you know
candidate address that is hosting the
cnc cnc server
again the analysis starts by uh finding
the cnc address of these two samples
it's going to take time but here we are
going to fast forward
uh
boom we found the cnc address of the
uh these samples
now in the next step what we are gonna
do we are gonna redirect the uh cnc
traffic right it would go to these
addresses by default but we are gonna
redirect this traffic man in the middle
and send the traffic to
uh the candidate address right if you
provide a range in each iteration one of
these addresses would be tried but here
it's only a single address
uh
so the malware tries to communicate with
this hyper atlas and you're gonna
analyze their traffic again it's gonna
take time but you're gonna hear fast
forward
uh
great
perfect we found the successful
communication
it still gives me goosebumps this is
really exciting right so we found a live
cnc server
right by using a four years old gasket
sample
right the malware would have talked to a
different cnc server it would have been
that but here no we used it to find a
real cnc server and now i'm gonna show
you the traffic if you see the traffic
since it's text based you would find by
yourself that it's actually a successful
communication
so let's take a look at the pcap traffic
this is the traffic that is generated
the malware starts by doing the tcp
handshake
and uh after the tcp handshake uh
there's this command that the malware
sends sorry for the language builddonk
and
the server responds with an act says i
got it
and then here's the interesting part the
server sends the pin command right to
the malware and the malware response
with the punch
great so this shows the successful
exploitation of the malware and the mitm
attack
and with that we actually found a live
cnc server using four years old gasket
samples it's very exciting
uh
okay so this is the demo that we had
we would be really happy to collaborate
if you're interested in
if you have an active honeypot uh or
have you know iot devices file systems
for different architectures if you have
intelligence on iot malware cnc is we
would really appreciate it we could use
that in for for evaluating our system or
if you just use our tool and you have
feedback for us
we would be very happy to talk to you
and if you have insight also on iot
madwear antivirus evasion
that's something that we want to you
know support in future please talk to us
uh
a shout out to martina lindelofer she's
collaborating with us
uh also to virustotal for providing us
the samples
i am ali davanian i will be in the job
market in six months if you're looking
for additions to your team please talk
to me
and with that i'm gonna conclude the uh
presentation
uh so in short we need to proactively
scan the internet and find the cnc
servers and that's because cnc servers
are very short-lived they are hidden
from us just by analyzing the samples we
cannot find all of them and since iot
communication protocols are diverse and
complex we need to use their real
malware right to have a generic solution
and that's what cnc hunter does for you
right we do cnc discovery using the man
in the middling and i i'm happy to tell
you that cnc hunter is fully automated
as i showed you you don't need to
provide any configuration just the
malware and your ip address branch and
it's open source
uh please use it use it and give us
feedback thank you very much and with
that we are gonna
take the questions