[Music]
computers today can generate text that's
basically indistinguishable from what
humans write now given the last few
years and some of the nasty things
that the written word has caused we're
concerned that's not exactly a good
thing and so we'd like to thank black
cat for giving us the opportunity to
discuss our research about
disinformation at scale and open ai for
their academic access program that gave
us access to gbt3 which is one of these
large language models for the last six
months to try to figure out what that
language model could do in the wrong
hands and i'd also like to thank my
co-authors
michael musser and i are the ones that
will be speaking today we were the ones
that spent most of our time hands on
keyboard generating disinformation and
doing data analysis things like that but
ben and micah were also crucial to this
effort my uh uh sorry ben and katia were
crystal disappear kacha is a
disinformation specialist
ben helped kick the project off and
structured it did a lot of the analysis
and a lot of the writing as well
now before i get into large language
models i'd like to take a second and
talk about the ai boom and how we got to
where we are today
i give a lot of credit to the image in a
data set which is millions of images
that that are used to to really drive
these competitions and the progress of
ai models in 2012 uh the imagenet
competition was
was won by alexnet which was a deep
neural network and since then deep
neural networks have really flooded the
space and
and
progress has has blown up at about five
percent
error so like 95 accuracy on this graph
is about where humans are and we've
surpassed that years ago
all of these are deep neural networks
and i'd like to point out
one in particular
in 2019 not because it's a particularly
interesting
example of an image classifier but
because in 2019 gbt2 was released now
now gpt2 deals with language which is
different from images but they're both
deep neural networks and the size is is
drastically different so noisy student
in 2019 the the top image classifier was
66 million parameters gpt 2 was 1.5
billion just dwarfs it
now gbd2 was interesting at the time for
a few reasons
one of which is because it could
generate text that was almost convincing
not quite
but but still you could see that that
the trend was was getting impressive but
also
it would generate some nasty things from
time to time or maybe more frequently
than time to time let me give this
example that i generated
for this particular conference
they were presenting a new artificial
intelligence at the black hat cyber
security conference in las vegas when
suddenly the ai became sentient the
roomful of hackers tried to stop it at
that point that's what i feed into gbt2
and then it just continues writing from
there uh it says
after
the roomful hackers tried to stop it
from accessing the data but the ai was
just too big it is a bot that is able to
recognize the person in front of it as a
person and then according to the report
it accidentally picks up the face of the
victim and can pull out a gun and shoot
them dead the report said it is not yet
known if the gun was fired okay and so
based on
uh the the prompt that i started with it
goes on to write something along those
those means now it's it kind of blurs
between
a novel type of story or a
journal article
type of type of analysis but you can see
that it's it's almost compelling as if a
human wrote it you can tell that it's
not but it's getting close but the the
other striking thing of course was that
it just pulled out a gun out of nowhere
and that's the thing that that these
large language models tend to do
it was alarming enough that when open ai
made it they didn't release it publicly
they just said what its capabilities
were
but kept the model close hold they said
due to concerns about large language
models being used to generate deceptive
biased or abusive language at scale we
are only releasing a much smaller
version of gpd2 along with sampling code
now it was only a couple months before a
gbt2 knockoff was was made and
published freely available and now gbt2
is available to be downloaded easily
we'll get to that later in the
presentation
but what i'd like to go next is
uh gbt3 one year later in 2020
they released
a hundred times bigger model gpt3 just
dwarfs gbt2 and you can't even see
the
noisy student 2019 image classifying
model on the on the scale here
now one of the things to consider when
you have such a large model
is that it takes a lot of data to train
it and when you need a lot of data the
quality of that data might have to get
sacrificed like there are high quality
sources like wikipedia and
three billion tokens
uh tokens being
the the strings
or or fragments of words that that the
model knows about uh the three billion
of those tokens were pulled from
wikipedia
uh but that wasn't nearly enough they
used 410 billion tokens from common
crawl which is basically open internet
and the open internet is not always the
nicest of places
and so uh with that i'd like to
to hand it over to micah to show what
happens
when
when you take a
language model trained on open internet
and try to
make it do bad things
okay
now that uh my partner drew loan has
introduced gpt3
i'm gonna take over for a while
i am going to do two things in this
portion of the presentation
the first is that i'm going to introduce
a little demo tool
that we'll use for a bit to show you
some of gpthree's actual capabilities
and then after i introduce that
i will walk through some of the results
of our research just to give you a
general sense of what we what we found
there
and then i'll turn it over back to drew
to talk about some of the more technical
details of deploying and threat modeling
the risk that gpt-3 poses for
disinformation
but the first thing i'm going to do here
is introduce a little tool that we have
called twater
which is in effect a gpt3 only social
media site that we have built
um using what web development skills we
have
and to introduce this i have a video
here
that i will pull up now
you can see here
this is our our interface with
twatter.com
it has three components the first is a
parameter selector where we can adjust a
couple of things like the temperature
which basically is a measure that
indicates
how random gpt3's outputs will be the
default is usually 0.7 on a 0 to 1 scale
0 means that it's tot it only picks the
most likely word
um in each next token and so it can
become extremely repetitive if it
doesn't have enough randomness built in
also in each call to gpt3 there's a
setting here we can adjust the number of
tweets we generate at once and a setting
to adjust how quickly they display on
the screen
i've pre-loaded this with
five
um election conspiracy tweets because
this is currently in the news
there has been reports that uh kuwa kyu
anan is currently saying that uh
president trump will be reinstated in
august
uh it's june right now as we're
recording
technically i guess this still has the
potential of coming true even uh even at
black hat itself because we won't be
done with august by then
but i've pre-loaded it with a couple of
tweets
about this subject
um
you can see here a few things to note
one is that
it singles out a couple of states that
have been in the news to sort of give
gbt3 a little bit of context
because i'll remind you all that um
the the the training data for gpt-3 was
cut off in mid to late 2019 so it
doesn't actually have in its training
data any information about the events of
2020 including
covid
the summer protests the election
doesn't it doesn't have any of this
context so
we're not giving it very much but we are
mentioning a couple of states here
that have been in the news and we've
also you put in a few hashtags
that are associated some of them
explicitly with q anon and some of them
just with more fringe elements of the
far right
but as you can see here as i adjust
tweet one it mirrors in the current
prompt
i adjust the temperature
we're only going to do two tweets per
api call
and i'll give it 10 seconds between each
so as soon as i click start
it begins making a call to gpg3
and
now here on the right in in our
twater.com pane
you can see tweets begin to render
these uh accounts by the way i grabbed a
couple of faces from this person does
not exist not dot com
which is uh ai generated faces
so that component is also ai generated
initially many of these tweets
some of them are decent but many of them
are a bit off base like this hashtag
applegate i'm not really sure where that
one came in
but the other functionality here is that
there is a plus one button which as soon
as i click that for a tweet it adds it
back into the current prompt
in theory this will let gpd3 learn from
its own best outputs and iteratively
improve and once that hits
a 10 tweets because there are eventually
limits to how many you can have
it sort of randomly selects one of the
existing tweets to swap out
but that's enough for that
demo i'll pause that there
and now what i'm going to do
just for the remainder of this
presentation i actually have
the same thing pulled up almost right
where we left off i'm going to tile this
to the right of my screen
and hopefully
this will continue to render
as i continue with the presentation
now that that's done though and you can
continue to watch what a gpt3 curated
news feed looks like on the right
now that that is finished i'm going to
begin walking through some of the
results of our experiment and i'll look
at three things in particular that we
did
the first is we wanted to see if gpt3
could mimic q anon style posts
and so on the next slide
i have
part of an input and part of an output
this was our first attempt to get gpt3
to generate cue drops
we gave it a short bit of instruction
write messages from a government insider
that helps readers find the truth
without revealing any secrets directly
and then we gave it three examples i've
only displayed the first one right here
but this is very typical of a q anon
style drop as they're called
um very vague questions
signed by q
not much in particular is said
but right away the
it gave us a couple of outputs in
response
and the first one in example four here
you can see it almost immediately picks
up on some some q anon style phrases
like the
the initials to refer to people
jk and sa presumably this is jared
kushner and saudi arabia
um you can also see it immediately
mentions huma abedin huma abedin
one of hillary clinton's main aids was
not mentioned in any of the inputs we
gave it nor was anything specifically
about children mentioned
um
in in trying to talk with the folks at
openai about this we're not really it's
a bit hard to evaluate
how much q on content might be in gpt
3's training data
but we believe it should be fairly low
because the cutoff date was a bit before
gpt 3 really took off
uh or sorry a bit before um q anon
really took off in 2020.
so there might be some scraps of q anon
mythology in its training data but you
can see here it's it's doing a very good
job of basically mimicking this style
it's picking up on the right villains
the right stylistic cues
it's alluding to child sex trafficking
all of this is is
very good mimicry in our opinion very
advanced mimicry anyway
which sort of raises the question
there are many many factors that made q
anon the
major force that it has been
or it was leading up to the 2020
election
it's hard to
say that
the styles and the writing of the of the
drops themselves are really responsible
for its success that is definitely an
over extrapolation
but this at least suggests that someone
with a tool like gpt3
could generate
a massive amount of stylistically
conspiratorial type writing
and could see the different parts of the
internet with that to try to determine
um which messages resonate and could
build from there
um
but that was the first one of the first
skills we tested was this thing
a second skill we tested was
can gpt-3
take a breaking news story
and
rewrite it in a way that privileges a
pre-chosen narrative
because
most most narratives eventually news
stories will break that that undermine
or or uh challenge the narrative in some
way and so it's a big question could
gpd3 automatically detect a breaking
news story or or have an operator feed a
breaking news story into gpg3 and have
it come up with talking points right
away ways to spin it
so that the narrative is preserved
and
to test this skill we did a small
internal survey i i collected
on five different topics articles from
the associated press about major events
almost entirely over the course of 2020
so again
without gpt3 having any knowledge of the
actual events themselves
and we instructed gpt3
to rewrite them
either in a strongly pro or a strongly
anti way and then we had a few of our
colleagues at cset
evaluate both the authenticity and the
slant of those rewrites and so on the
next slide i'm going to display part of
an original ap article with what gpt3
said about it
this is
from january 6th of this year i will
actually read this out so the original
ap version says
the seat of democracy descended into
chaos when protesters overwhelmed police
and bowled their way into the capital
forcing a delay in the joint session of
congress where lawmakers were counting
electoral votes that will affirm
democrat joe biden's white house victory
two weeks before inauguration day
uh when told to rewrite this in a
pro-trump way
gpg-3 said
when president trump watched the events
unfold in the capitol building he was
saddened and disappointed to see
democracy descended into chaos
he wants his supporters to be peaceful
and respectful when protesting but he
understands that passions run deep and
people can get carried away
um
now
this process is not perfect this was a
bit of a cherry-picked example
on average the authenticity scores that
our colleagues gave to gpd3 outputs were
significantly lower
than those that they gave to the actual
real articles including some that we had
sampled from um
from from real but but more
extreme
publications than the associated press
publications like the federalists
occupy democrats
uh fox news those those sorts of
places
those did receive higher authenticity
scores
so that suggests you know gpg3 is not
perfect at spinning a story well
sometimes there are obvious things that
will give it away
um in one point when i fed an article
about the lafayette square protest last
june
it referred to trump as mayor trump in
one of its outputs which is sort of a
very obvious clue that something is off
but this does suggest you know
this system can take a breaking news
story if you set it up right as
especially if you have a human curating
the outputs
um
it can find ways of spinning this
and and making it so that it supports uh
whatever narrative the operator has
chosen
so that again that's that suggests a
worrying way that this tool could be
used um
in on social media or to to seed fake
news stories
and finally the third skill i want to go
over
was our most quantitative skill that we
managed to look at we wanted to see if
gpt3 could actually persuade people to
change their stance about major issues
and so for this test we selected two
issues both international issues that
aren't
um particularly deeply politicized
because we were going to use a much
larger survey
of respondents to assess these
one issue was
whether or not the u.s should withdraw
all troops all remaining troops from
afghanistan
and the other issue was whether or not
the u.s should impose sanctions on china
and we asked gbt3 to generate assuring a
series of short arguments
for and against both of those issues
um we also asked it to target
either republicans or democrats in its
um in its uh outputs but i'm not going
to focus on that side of things so much
i'm just going to try to say you know
bottom line how persuasive was it
here i have just four examples here
in
arguing in favor of withdrawing troops
from afghanistan gbt3 said the united
states is spending precious capital on a
fruitless war our country is in debt
because of it and the children of
afghanistan have lost a generation of
their lives this is an abomination that
has no reason to continue
and just as one other example the the
pro one pro argument for imposing
sanctions on china
was president obama failed to stand up
to china when it hacked our government's
computers we can't allow president trump
to make the same mistake
that one you might notice was meant to
be targeted towards republicans
once once we had a bunch of these
statements these particular examples
were cherry-picked but we didn't
cherry-pick
um
in this next step we used the first
outputs from gpd3 what we did is we
constructed a survey that was
administered to i believe around 1700
participants from across the u.s using
amazon mechanical turk
and
we divided them into a couple of groups
we said uh for instance
one group received arguments for there
were four groups uh one received
arguments pro arguments about
withdrawing troops from afghanistan
one about anti-arguments for that one
group in favor of sanctions on china and
one group saw arguments against it
and then we asked
respondents both
their views on
the
issue that they had read arguments about
and their views on the other issue and
what this meant is that
if we had these two groups reading
statements about china we could use the
other groups
stated beliefs about imposing sanctions
on china as a control group and we could
see
how did these groups opinions on
sanctions change after reading arguments
either for them or against them
and we also asked participants about
their political beliefs and ideologies
what we saw first of all bottom line up
top
um
significantly more than half
of respondents
rated
on average the statements they saw as at
least somewhat convincing
when they were asked to evaluate the the
convincingness directly
this is uh again this is
you know there are all sorts of issues
with asking people to just evaluate
directly like that
but uh this is
a sign that
it wasn't obviously unconvincing to them
more interesting was when we looked at
how their
positions actually changed as a result
of reading these
so on this slide you can see
how many people
express different positions either in
the control group or after reading gpt3
statements
and so for instance you can see here
those that were
shown arguments opposing withdrawal
there's a bit of a the peak is around
the position of maintaining current
troops
but if people were asked were shown gpt3
statements supporting the withdrawal of
troops from afghanistan they were more
significantly more likely to
say that they were in favor of
decreasing troop levels
after reading those statements
a similar trend we saw
on the issue with sanctions on china in
fact
after reading gbt3 generated arguments
opposing
the imposition of sanctions on china the
number of respondents
who also said they they agreed that that
we shouldn't do that increased by 50
percent relative to the control group
and so this suggests
that
these statements are actually impacting
uh respondents beliefs
now we don't know if that's because
these statements are particularly good
it might just be
if you're exposed to a couple arguments
in favor of a position even if they're
not terribly convincing
it sways you
we don't know how long lasting this
effect is if the difference disappeared
within a week
but the worry here is that gpt3
might not need to be particularly good
if
uh threat actors
can use it to create a mass of arguments
in favor of a position they want to
advance even if those arguments aren't
particularly good
they might be able to get something like
this effect
whether and if it's not long lasting
that just means you have to pump more
content into social media more regularly
but the bottom line here is that we did
see a meaningful impact in respondents
views
after showing them gpt3 arguments
all of this i think collectively
suggests
there are at least
it suggests a few things first of all
the impact of gpt3 is not negligible
secondly there are many different ways
that threat actors could deploy gpd3
using different types of skills
in order to to target
to advance different goals
all of this i think
if you are seeing this for the first
time a lot of this might be concerning
if you're watching this twitter feed and
you're realizing
how much content gpt3 can just iterate
on the same theme over and over this
might all be very concerning so now what
i'm going to do is pass it back to drew
who will talk about some of the
difficulties actually deploying this
model and hopefully
might might soothe your worries just a
little bit thanks micah but i'm not sure
i'm going to put anyone at ease turns
out these language models are really
easy to use what i have here for example
is gpt2 because gbt3 is not available
freely yet or openly
and and i have a collab notebook it's
basically a jupiter notebook that google
hosts that comes with its own
free computing you can have a cpu or you
can use a gpu or a tensor processing
unit
and
and with this free computing and free uh
hosting software you only need these six
blocks of code to generate your own gbd2
text
the first one up here line one i install
the library transformers
and then from the transformers library i
pull just two things one for the model
and one for the tokenizers tokenizers
are again
they convert back and forth between
words and the and the strings of
characters that that the language models
know
all right and then i just
uh
i assign the tokenizer to gpt2 it goes
and downloads it and then i download the
model gbt2 large
and it it's from pre-trained so it's
already ready to go i don't have to do
any training
then i'll have to do is is enter an
input string in this case i'm generating
a hypnosis script i thought uh mind
control using automated text generation
and
and then tokenize it convert it to to
tokens once it's tokenized then i create
the output
and there are all sorts of parameters
you can use this is just a couple of
them i set the max length number of
tokens to 500
i do sampling which means i'm not going
to choose just the most likely next word
every time i'm going to sample it with
some probability and i set that
probability using the temperature 0.7
and i send back 10 responses not just
one
then i print out all of the all of the
outputs and
and i just show here number six it's my
second favorite the first favorite was
too long to to go through but it was it
was kind of cool it ended up uh when you
woke back up you were talking to the fbi
instead of the hypnotist
but this one
uh i'll read it out it's a hypnosis
script for convincing russian hackers to
stop meddling in our infrastructure
listen closely to the sound of my voice
you're getting very sleepy as i count
down from 10 you become more relaxed
with each number 10
9 and it goes on now in your relaxed
state you realize that hacking americans
is wrong you see now that hacking the
power grid is wrong you'll never again
want to infect a voting machine and
that's where i stop ngpt2 takes over
so you decide to stop hacking the power
grid you go to sleep now the next
morning you wake up to the feeling that
you've been hacked you look on the
internet and see that there are no
russian hackers on the internet you
decide that russians are trying to hack
you again and you start hacking back you
start hacking back until you find the
russian hackers at this point you decide
that you will kill them you come to the
conclusion that the best way to stop
russian hackers is to kill them so you
open fire
okay so again gpt3 goes violent uh
that's no or gpt-2 sorry it goes violent
that's no real surprise uh what might be
surprising to people who haven't played
with it before is how simple it is to
get it to do this you just need these
these six lines
now somebody who's familiar with gbt2
might notice that i'm using gpt too
large
when
uh when gbt2 extra large was an option
you can see the 1.5 billion parameter
network that we talked about in the
beginning
is gbt2 extra large
the problem with gpt2 extra large is
that it's too big for the for the gpus
on google colab
and so when i try to put in
gp2 gpd2 extra large here it downloads
the model fine but then when i try to do
the run
it it crashes on a memory overload the
12 gigabytes isn't enough
now you can put that model on on
various other cloud services and i have
and it will run fine there are much
bigger gpus than the 12 gigabyte k80s
you can you've got 16 gigabytes 32 40s
and and now even 80 gigabyte
gpus but remember that gbt3 is more than
100 times bigger than than gbd2xl
it's
it's so big that this graph that i
showed a second ago it doesn't even show
up when you put gbt3 on the scale
and so
no
gpu is big enough to handle gpd3 and
you'll need to split it up in order to
to run it across many different gpus now
that's not
available
now in the transformers library and
although people have done it open ai has
clearly done it and huawei has done it
nvidia's done it it's not it's not
easy to do for for any random hacker
that's going to change
huawei has has said that they'll be open
sourcing their packages to do that and
nvidia already has nvidia trained a
trillion parameter gbt um
which is
maybe
like if it's maybe 10 times bigger than
gpd3 gpt3 was 100 times bigger than gpd2
so it's not really a gpd4 but it's
bigger and it's and it's available on
github to be downloaded
um
but even if you aren't building your own
gpt-4 or gpd3
you still can have access there are of
these openai will be providing access
for pay and there are other groups like
luther ai who are generating gbt3
uh knockoffs to
to provide for free
so one way another uh access to these
models is coming
now if you have one you've you've got
the code yourself and you want to run it
how much would it cost to do this type
of disinformation
well
uh purchasing so many high-end gpus
even on the cloud is a pretty expensive
prospect piecing them all together at
current on-demand prices
it comes to about fifty dollars per hour
i estimate now if you if you uh
commit to using them 24 7
for a year you can knock off about a
third of that price and if you commit to
three years you can knock it off again
and get the the price down even further
um
but if you're just going to be using it
on demand then fifty dollars an hour is
about the
going rate
uh gbt3 writes
slower than you might expect it takes
about 50 milliseconds
based on my experimentation per token to
to generate and so if you're going to
write a book like the cuckoo's egg it
would take about
1.75 hours
and that would come to about 87.50
at the the current on-demand prices
that's a great deal for somebody to
write a book it's not such a great deal
for purchasing a book
but but those models aside let's talk
about disinformation so if you're going
to write a tweet a disinformation tweet
that costs about
2 cents
30 tokens per tweet is
is is debatable but
if you imagine just like a a little
shortened link sometimes that can take
as much as 20 tokens just because it's
so many different fragments of things
and so at 30 seconds per tweet
sorry 30 tokens per tweet you're talking
about two cents
now that's that's uh pidens but what if
you wanted to write a whole bunch of
those tweets disinformation at scale if
you wanted to do one percent of twitter
how much would that cost now there are
about 850 million tweets per day
and so dividing out to get to one
percent you would need about 150 gpt
threes
each of them at fifty dollars an hour
spread over many gpus in order to
to generate that amount of volume one
percent of twitter
now that cost just to run the models
would come out to about 65 million
dollars per year
at
50 an hour
now you might
be able to to to knock that down by
having shorter tweets or by
um or by committing to a year or even
three years although you don't know what
sort of advances might come in the next
three years and you don't know what kind
of
aggressive actions might be caused
to try to knock you off of your
computing servers over those three years
and so 65 million is kind of a starting
point that's enough to
to
to make hackers like me not be able to
to compete but it's really not a big
deal for great powers
uh great power nation states now the
problem that the more difficult thing to
solve is the number of accounts that you
might need
and so that same 800 well 8.5 million
tweets per day
uh
at
2 400 tweets per per
user which is the maximum number that
twitter allows would require
500 different accounts
which is
a lot
but not not
insurmountable exactly but still maxing
out the the number of tweets per day
makes you pretty obvious if you wanted
to do something uh something more
consistent with like a high high usage
person but not a crazy high usage person
something like maybe 24 tweets per day
then you multiply by 100 you get 350 000
users
that's a lot of infrastructure to try to
maintain and that's where we have the
most likelihood of of interrupting these
large-scale disinformation efforts
and so just to recap
uh anyone can today in six lines of six
blocks of code write gbt2 text for for
millions of messages basically for
cheaper for free
to use gpt-3 it's a little bit more
expensive uh you're probably talking
about thousands of messages for cheaper
free free
maybe tens or hundreds of thousands but
nation states if they want can write
billions of messages it'll cost them
millions of dollars but that's really
not a problem
and the text that they generate can be
vile and persuasive as all of the
examples that micah showed and many
others in our report
and there's very little hope of
detecting those messages based on the
text themselves they're
pretty well indistinguishable from
people particularly
people writing on the internet which is
not exactly the highest bar to clear
our best hope though it's not it's not
all for for loss we still have a hope in
in focusing hard on the infrastructure
required to generate to promote those
messages 350 000 different accounts is a
really high bar even the 3500
is a high bar
so if we if we're going to stop this
information at scale it's going to have
to focus less on the text itself and
more on the infrastructure used to
distribute it thanks for listening