[Music]
hi everyone welcome i'm going to talk
about ios security today the title is
everything has changed in ios 14 but
jailbreak is ethanol
my name is sandorji a security
researcher from art security chen chung
lab i mainly focus on mac os ios
security i attended black hat asia
2021 as a speaker i'm glad i could
attend the black hat again
on february 10th modern toner released
the secular versa it is the first
workable ios 14 kernel exploit open a
door to ios 14 jailbreak after that i
published a stable kernel thread
primitive firstly
based on the exploit today i will
complete a project dq preview break show
how to run or authorize the code on ios
14. this talk is about my ios 14
learning journey
first let's compare the security between
ios 14 and ios 13. in ios 13 there are
many vulnerabilities in its lifecycle
for example
ob timestamp in ios 13.3
taking on in ios
13.5
and ob wins in ios 13.7
so jailbreak is almost always available
on ios 13
but things changed in ios 14
since the first warning of ios 14
we go to the first kernel exploit after
more than five months this is really a
long period of time
now ios 15 beta is testing maybe ios 14
will come to the end of its life cycle
this is still there is still only one
public workforce chrono exploit so ios
14 is really a tough way
why is ios 14 so hard to be pruned
well ios 14 introduced lots of new
mitigations such as the kernel heap
hardening data pack user speeds pack
academy tlp harmony ipc key message
harmony and etc
some works on the vulnerabilities did
some works on the exploit stage make ios
more secure than before
first i want to talk about the kernel
heap translation
with the key key translation you can't
overlap the free the object with a
different object
avoid that have confusion
that's a good way to stop uef
vulnerabilities
it's not new but has been hardened
massively in ios 14. in ios 14 key
analog heap is split into four subtypes
now allocations made by kernel extension
are moved to key fib pxt
kernel objects and the key ext objects
can't see each other
there is a heap named data buffers
let's see the definition of it
this set of zooms should contain pure
bands of bytes with no pointers or of
size so
uaf in this clip has few harmful side
effects
that's not a serious problem and there
is a special heap to store temporary
data
when writing kernel exploit we often use
os data to build a fixed
or uaf object but now os data and os
screen contains a model into data heap
it is nearly impossible to build a fake
object with os data what's more ampl has
moved more and more key objects into
delicate zooms
now the heap in ios 14 is fine green
with few common errors
which significantly reduces the living
space or uef vulnerabilities
data pack
newly introduced in ios 14. you can mark
a pointer using macro ptios signed pdr
then the compiler will add
extra instructions automatically to
protect this pointer the disassembly
code is shown below one full story
impact pointer and a landfill fetching
the signing strategy is encrypting the
pointer with a unique discriminator plus
its memory address
so if you count
so you can't touch any base of the
packed pointer and since the memory
address is also involved in the
encryption
you can't use the packet pointer in
other memory address different from code
pack data pack is used for data
integrity ensure that the data is not
modified by others
now most of the data pointers then apple
consider considered critical which are
commonly used in exploit are protected
by pac
such as ukraine ipc port
furthermore data pointer is
not the only scenario where pack can be
applied sorry my bad complained about a
webkit commit ago
i'm not familiar with the webkit exploit
i guess field m offset of struct
assembler label is an important employed
primitive
in this commit ample expander am offset
to 64 bits so it can be signed by pack
using the extra 32 bits
and what's more with the da cas
you can sign arbitrary blob
kernel exports and api to do this
the thread state in kernel is also
protected by ga case
in ios 14 you can find data pack in
kernel here and there but it's not easy
to get rid of the
in rs13 all the user speeds processes
share a sim ak so attackers can afford a
key protected function pointers in other
process
this is
this is a serious flaw then
i was 14 ample decides to change this
situation
now iak becomes process dependent
different processes use different ii
keys a name that is user speed pack
hardening
this is detailed in kernel document pack
dot md
this change is effective to resist cross
process attack
but geopreg also need to control other
process i.e am fid this mitigation
brings trouble fortunately with kernel
rewrite
it is possible to bypass it i will talk
about
this later
in the past hackers use the task for pid
0 trick to access the kernel task port
it is the most convenient way to achieve
criminal rewrite
almost every kernel exploit tries to
build a tlp zero but that is not
that is not the case now apple has had
another kernel task
you can't resolve the kernel task now
and if you try to access the kernel map
you will trigger a panic
both pre-trial and e-12 plus devices are
seen
we must find alternatives to trp 0 to
achieve kernel rewrite
there i want to talk about a special
kernel object ipc key message it is an
exploit friendly object
you can frequently see it in heaps pre
but
i must say key message is more powerful
than that
with key message you can directly
convert a toolbar clip overflow
which happens in key analog large area
24 is export
the key idea is modifying field ikm set
to free more memory and you can look
itself with link pointer
but key message was hardened in ios 14.2
all key message objects went to zoom now
data path is separated from key message
header and moved into key keep data
so now you can't overflow a key message
now i think this is the apple's smart
idea without the essential exploiter
primitives you cannot
exploit a bug easily
this really matters to me
i had an ios kernel back but the exploit
code relies on key message without a key
message i'm not able to exploit it now
so it only works on ios 14.1
i can't find an alternative to key
message yet
all right so it's very hard to pull ios
14 it is not impossible
now let's talk about the first public
ios 14 chrono exploit
cve 2021 1782
it is a risk condition bug in module fc
water we can convert it back to a useful
uef it was fixed in rs 14.4 on january
2021 after two weeks snack tea published
the
uh blog post detailing how this
vulnerability works they also released a
workable poc to demonstrate the
vulnerability on ios 14 by making the
kernel crash
and then this in the same day odin puna
published the exploit named
secuta versa for this vulnerability in
the exploit code kernel read write
primitives are included that's amazing
be aware that writing an ios 14 export
is not that easy due to the new
mutations
i really admire the techniques more than
pruners shown in their code today i will
focus on how to execute our authorized
binary on iphone by utilizing modern
toner's exploit
and how to solve the problems i met
which was newly introduced
by ios 14.
okay now let's see the kernel regret
primitives provided by secutar versa
it converts the original original risk
condition bug to an uef of packing
options
there is a pointer in packing options
pointed to a pancreas info structure you
can overwrite this pointer by freeing
and reallocating this object in user
space
then through get and set
circuit option you can read and write
the packet info structure by the user
speeds control the pointer
that's the
arbitrary kernel redirect primitives
provided by secure towers
we noticed that secure towers are you
utilize the circuit operation to lay out
the kernel heap
but in the past we usually use os data
or key message to operate the kernel
heap so using salt it is a little weird
that is due to kernel heap resolution
now they are in different hips
in this vulnerability we must look up
suitable objects in keyhip default the
bad thing is the circuit option object
is nearly the only solution
actually
there is a limitation on the kernel read
write
every time we perform a kernel read or
write operation we need to free the old
object then we allocate a new object
to modify the read write address
but if we are not lucky there is a
chance that the memory call is occupied
by others then we lost control of reader
life address
kernel will panic so this way is not
very stable
when i debug the code of a security
versa and notice that that they write 20
primitive fields sometimes i don't know
why then i checked the implementation of
rating it is based on
set packet info the code is in ip6
output the data we write to kernel is
actually a packet info structure the
first
16 bytes is an ip address the last four
bytes is a interface index
but there is a check about the the
interface index
it must be less than a rf indexed value
the value is the net interface count
the system has
i don't know what the exact
the exact value it is but it must be a
small integer
likely one two all three so it's now
clear that the 20 bytes we passed into
kernel must end with a small integer and
i think 0 is the best value
then we know that red 20 is not an
arbitrary right there is a limitation we
can only read 6 16 byte arbitrary data
plus 4 by 0s of course we can still use
this red kernel data
but it will smash the kernel object
sometimes
leading to chrono panic
so there is limitations the right
attention is still very very very useful
it gives us a very good starting point
we must build a new
and stable kernel regret primitives
using read 20 and red 20 we already have
before we had tlp0 it is the most
perfect way to achieve kernel rewrite
but now due to the tlp-0 hardening it is
nearly impossible to access kernel tasks
from user space
we can to find an alternative to tlp 0.
we really need a currently right ability
in post-export state but how
and the key idea is that we can find out
our kernel objects that can be accessed
from user space easily and has specific
interaction with the user speeds
like transferring data to and from
kernel
then we can use the right attendee to
overwrite the objects control the read
write address
transform it to a new kernel read writer
primitive
but the question is which kernel object
is the suitable one
well i have reader people exploiting io
surface 0 by chance the author is kenyan
inspired by this paper it seems that the
key object io surface is a good
candidate if you are familiar with ios
kernel exploits you must be familiar
with io service
researchers often use io surface to do
kernel heap spree
leakage kernel memory info or ford
kernel objects
then reliance on the flexible gate set
value
external methods of io surface
in addition to this our surface has lots
of other external methods as we expected
we can really build a new kernel
redirect primitives on top of these
external methods
before discussing that
let's take a quick look at how io
service works
in user space we use api's exported by
io surface diy life to interact with io
surface
and use surface id to specify which io
surface we want to operate
but in kernel it is a bit complicated
this figure tries to show how the io
surface looks like in kernel memory
the surface root user client
use the surface id as an index to find
the correct io surface
but kernel don't operate our surface
directly it uses an io service client as
an agent
every request from user sends to service
client first then will be redirected to
our service object
actually these are not
important
i just want to explain that
if we can control any about structures
in this team we can directly influence
the behavior of io surface operations
now let's see some special surface
external methods
the first one is the set indexed
timestamp this is the
field code from ide pro
through this method we can write a
timestamp to the address specified by a
field in the io surface object this
field is
is stored and offset of hex
360. so
can control field 360 of io surface we
get a 8
8 byte light
of course we can use the red 20
primitives to override this field to
obtain a new kernel right primitive
and what's more in the question we do
not touch any other class field so there
is no side effect with the extra 4 byte
zeros right but actually i didn't try
this way i will talk about it later
and there is another surface external
method
get
ycbcr matrix
we can use this method to read the field
before our i o surface from the from
kernel
this time if we can control surface
pointer we get a 4 byte read and there
is no side effect too
now with the two external methods
exported by our surface we obtain both
new red and new read primitive
but we can't build these new primitives
based on our
unstable relativity
all the new ones will be unstable too
we must use another way to modify the
class field or kernel memory
to modify
to modify kernel memory i think the most
convenient way is the shared memory
this time i choose pack
so pipe is not a real shared memory it
works like a real shared memory
when you write data in to pipe the data
will be cached into a block of kernel
memory name the pipe buffer as if you
read something to kernel directly
so if i can move io surface
related objects into pipe buffer i could
modify them freely
actually it is easy to achieve this
after after all we already have a
residential primitive
just over red surface client re-pointer
in root user client
force is pointing to memory in pipe
buffer then you can fold surface objects
as you want
and now you can read write arbitrary
kernel memory using a thick surface
pointer and the figure field 360.
besides pipe there is other batteries to
create a shared memory with the kernel
but i'm lazy i've just simply reused the
code learning from brandon users
watchers line
the implementation of new kernel rewrite
primitive is simple
using read 20 to find out the memory
address or pack buffer
then assign the address to service
clients re using red 20 after that we
can specify read write address by a path
right
then call the gate and set external
methods of io surface to achieve
arbitrary kernel result
this is stable and they will never panic
the kernel
now we have a good alternative to tfp 0
and we could share the primitive with
other process with the daemon
since we already have the ability to do
kernel rewrite
it's time to do something useful
that is the jailbreak thing
my goal is simple i want i just want to
execute arbitrary unauthorized binary it
is somehow equivalent to take full
control of my iphone that's enough
it is better to
stand on the shoulders of a giants to do
something
so i just pulled the code of free the
sandbox to secure versa
next i will discuss the troubles i met
in the protein progress and how to solve
them
to execute a binary we need the fork erc
cisco combined nation
but it is disallowed by sandbox so the
first thing is to
disable sandbox
it can be done by nullifying the process
sandbox slot in mac label but starting
from ios 14
there is a pack mark on the pointer as
we said earlier we can't touch any bit
of a packed
pack protected pointer so can we modify
the sandbox slot
to
now pointer the answer is yes actually
there is a flow in data pack
let's see the disassembly code function
not clickable get
there is a cbz instruction if it is an
out pointer the function just return now
the packed pointer will
not be verified at all if the pointer is
now
for performance considerations now
pointers are handled especially in pack
we usually use memory set 0 to
initialize
objects and the impact to every now
pointer will bring loss over overhead
so in most cases we can nullify a data
pointer safely
now we are out of sandbox but the emi
will stop us to execute unsigned code
we have two choices inject cd hash to
each
cluster cache or bypass amf id check
but injecting hashes into trust catch
needs kernel code execution
it is somewhat difficult ams id is an
user space demon it is easier to
take control our user space process then
kernel code exclusion
so i will try to force amf id to be
happy as the free sandbox starts
suppose we want to run
signed but unauthorized the binary name
that it out
a request will be sent to amf id
emf id demon realize this is not a legal
program then we'll stop it running
now that we have currently right we can
try to turn our our own process into a
privileged process
get the task port of amf id and the set
exec exception port for it
that is a debugger for emf id
then we are able to control the behavior
of amf id
after that we can intercept the request
and hijack a worried cd hash for it out
force amf id to believe it out is a
legal program
finally our goal running on authorized
binary is achieved
to get the task port of amf id
we can use api task for pid
but kernel states that
only process assigned with the
entitlement tasker for pid allow
can cross this api
increase the sandbox code
the entitled self in the following way
find out a process which has the
entitlement we need and then deal is
your credit and
assign the credit to self-process then
our process has the same intelligence
and we are able to call task for prd on
af
on amf id now
but in ios 14 there is a different
situation
almost everything is protected
by pack
we can't steal your cred from other
process and we can't still see our label
or anything else
i had no choice but to look at the low
level data structure
finally i found that intelligence are
stored in the in os dictionary i'm lucky
that the dictator increase is not packed
so i had a chance to replace the key
value pairs in the dictionary
and the essential intelligence to make
kernel believe that i'm a good process
but this time i don't want steel or
borrow entitlements from others
using set value interface we can attach
properties to an io surface
they are stored in a dictionary
associated with the surface
as we know
processing elements are stored in a
dictionary too so we can put all the
inherents we need into the our surface
values in advance that is we build an
intelligence library for ourselves
when i need a new entitlement i just
take it directly from here
i'm not sure if anyone has used this
method before maybe this way is a small
innovation
so i didn't actually defeat
this pack in fact i just found a way to
avoid it
moreover i'd like to mention one more
thing our surface is really a trailer
it has already helped us to implement
hips free fake object building kernel
read right and now it helps us again
with the entitlement hack
io service is really a powerful helper
for exploit development
ok
we successfully go to the task port of
amf id
next let's do the real amf id bypass
and there are three weapons we can use
task set exception port we am red and
the thread set stick
we can bypass amif id with the following
steps
note that mis validator signature and
copy info is the executable file
validation procedure we
redirect it to involved address
if a mfi request comes that's function
will through an exception
we can't the exception hijack the will
be simpler process
calculate the writer cd hash for the
executable file put the result to amf id
memory to satisfy amfa
check
the last step use the thread set state
to set the pc register
on the original return address
furthermore we are talking pack device
so we need to sign the address first
finally resume amif id this am fid
bypass strategy works fine on ios 13 but
fails on ios 14.
well this is the sad let's look into it
with the crash log we can confirm that
amf id stops and wear the address
so the problem is here
setting pc register doesn't work as
expected
let's check the kernel code to see what
a thread set state does
i found that thread state is signed in
user space but in kernel it is stored in
raw format so thread sets data will use
target threads
iak to decode the pc register is
specified
from the code we know that gopid is the
so-called pack iak
then i read the emf id's gop pid back to
user space and compared it
with our own wpid
they are different
and remember that we said ios 14
introduces user speeds pack hardly
one process cannot hold function
pointers in others process
this is the principle of it
different process assigns a different
gop pid
so sign an oauth a packed pointer with
different iap
that's why thread said street field amf
id got involved pc register to make it
works on ios 14 we must assign the pc
register with emif ids iac
but how
there is another function
thread gate state contrary to set speed
it reads thread speed from kernel stack
before returning the state to user space
thread get state or sign pc register
with target threads gop pid
so there are two functions about thread
state
one for earth one for sign
they make up a functional loop of course
we can both use and sign pc register of
our own thread but the amif id by pass
needs a return address correctly signed
by amf ids iip
now that we found a graphics signing
method
if we can steal emf ids iac override our
threads iaek visit we may achieve this
goal
i create a dummy thread and suspend it
so i can manipulate freely
target pc is the address that we want
emf id running to we strip it to a row
pointer sign it with iap and then set it
to the dummy thread thread
this is our own thread so there is no
problem with this operation
next i
copy the dopp id from ams id thread to
our thread now we call thread get state
the pc will be signed with the new jlp
id
finally we get a correctly signed pc
register and we can set this value to
amf id this time
the amf id will return a successful
validation result as we want the emf id
bypass is done
when i was studying thread state i found
a microcore by accident
thread convert thread state
is code as shown below
if we specify the parameter direction to
from self it will help us convert our
own thread state to target thread user
representation
this is exactly what we want
this is the second way that can be used
to bypass user space pack harmony
and what's more in this way no kernel
read write required
if you can get targets thread port
it's a it's a perfect bypass
the code is simple just assign target pc
with our own iek then convert it to am
fid's signed pc by the thread state
converting api
about this api i think it is useless
except one scenario
when you intend to debug a process that
doesn't belong to you
but it
is really helpful to bypass user speeds
pack handling i guess maybe ample will
delete it someday for security
now we have two ways to sign a pointer
with other process iak it's time to
complete the emf id bypass
let's repair the last
step
put the correctly signed the return
address into amf id as we expected a
mfid bypass on ios 14 is working we are
able to execute
on authorize the binary
okay
let me summarize ulta and i have talked
today with this image
it gives an overview of how to execute
or authorize the code in ios 14 by
exploiting a risk condition bar
the red part is the outstanding exploit
written by
modern poner the green part is my ios 14
learning journey
maybe the stable kernel rewrite
primitive built by ios by io surface
hack is the most helpful one
you can find the full exploit code you
might be tough the link is given in the
bottom
actually the code is the better way to
express my
to express my thought
last i think ios 14 is the most secular
ios ever
everything has changed
among the new mitigations
key keep isolation and the data pack are
the outstanding lens
one kills most vulnerabilities well
clear the most exploited primitives
with high quality bugs like cve 2021
we are still able to prune ios kernel
jailbreak is unstoppable but it is
indeed harder and harder than before
i learned everything from the community
security gives me the opportunity to
contribute to iowa's hack community so i
make a tqu pre-jailbreak fully open
source now
hope this will give some inspiration to
researchers
okay thank you for watching that's all
on my talk today i hope you enjoyed it
you can find the source code on my
github
and if you have questions you can
contact me by this email
thank you