[Music]
hello everyone so thank you for being
here uh welcome to this virtual talk
about graybox program synthesis
um
[Music]
so just few words about me i'm robin
david i'm a software security engineer
at quarks lab a french cyber security
company
and i'm working on obfuscation and
especially the obfuscations
and many ways to automate bug discovery
okay so what is the agenda of today i'm
first going to get some definitions
about obfuscation and synthesis
then i'm going to describe our gray box
synthesis algorithms that we use for the
obfuscations
and then i'm going to
describe the implementations and
the use cases on which we applied
this approach
okay let's jump straight to obfuscation
what is obfuscation
we usually refer it to the the means of
transforming a program into a
semantically equivalent program but
which is meant to be harder to
understand
why we do that
mostly to protect intellectual property
so we do find a presentation also in
malware but
most of the time uh we find it in
mobile applications softwares
from completely legitimate companies and
so on so
we less often see it in malware
so how we do that
so the idea is to within the program you
want to protect the valuable assets
and what are the valuable assets in the
program
usually it's the program logics or the
algorithms
or the data the data can be strings
constant although all these kind of
things
so we usually
uh separate
obfuscation into three categories the
first one is the control flow
observations
where the goal is to hide the logic the
logic of the flow of execution so
at the bottom you see a small cfg of
functions and on the right the
obfuscated versions of the exact same
functions
so there's plenty of applications for
doing so like virtualization flattening
or pack predicates and so on
and otherwise you have
the second category which is data flow
applications which aims at adding
constant strings keys and so on
and for that there is also plenty of
different obfuscation techniques like
data encoding
mba that we are going to discuss white
boxes
encoding and so on
so in this talk we are going to focus on
data obfuscations and more especially on
mba which is mixed boolean arithmetic
what is mixed boolean arithmetic is the
mean of
scrambling expressions using
so bitwise operators like xor and r and
so on and arithmetic operators like plus
minus
and so on
so here is the so we have a small a plus
b expression
uh
and on sophisticated we transform it
with a semantically equivalent
expressions but that is more difficult
to understand
so the questions from a reverse
engineering point of view is how do we
get back the original expressions
and that is the difficult questions
because unlike
control flow obfuscations the the answer
is not
boolean
uh
with control flow observations you
sometimes want to negate branches make
sure uh
check that some of them are dead or so
on but here you really want to recover
the original expression and that is
difficult
so
obfuscations yields two distinct
research problem
the first one is
locating the data that you want to
deficit
and that's highly dependent on the
targets that you are looking at
what you are looking for into the
programs what you want to attack or
retrieve so this is mostly manual and
this is also distinct for each target
and the second problems when you're the
obfuscating programs it's the the deal
fiscation itself so you
it's um once you've found found uh the
data that you want to diffuse get so how
do you deal with this kit do you have to
skate it
and synthesis in a only address this
second issue so
you first have to find
the data register or memory that you
want to duplicate
so i wanted to highlight these two
different issues
in the obfuscation
now i'm going to describe what is
synthesis so synthesis is the mean of
deriving
creating a program given high level
specifications and some additional
constraints
over it
for combination it can be faster program
for the authentication it could be
smaller or more readable program
so
for program synthesis so you usually
have a programming input and that
program is the specifications it encodes
the semantic the behavior that you want
to preserve throughout the synthesis
so you give it a synthesizer that
optimizes some constraints like
speed size or whatever
and then you obtain the new program
which satisfy your
specifications so semantic and the
constraints
so there is two
main use cases for program synthesis the
first one is optimizations
and people doing opinion optimization
with synthesis you usually call it
superior optimization
and there's two nice works for that i
recommend the super
work made by john reger and some folks
at google
and also stock
and but we are going to focus on the
observation in this talk
but but as one might notice this is
basically the same issue at the core
level you have a program and you want to
make it more
more small more efficient
so the you're basically solving the same
issues
um with both optimization and the
obfuscation
okay so for the obfuscation
through synthesis there is multiple
approaches existing
templates stochastic
search based enumerative and so on
i'll give you a small uh overview of the
work that has been done in the past
so the first works i've found about this
is the work performed by royal frauds um
in 2014
is truly a pioneer in this field
then there is the works by nino eros
which was at crosslab at that time
about spam so spam is not truly
synthesis it's more like patterns and
rewriting rules
but yeah that's
one of the first works targeting
um
mbas and giving some implementations for
for it
then in 2017 you have the work of
cynthia that has been published at
usenix and they use the stochastic
approach using monte carlo search tree
i'm not going to describe that approach
but
it does it's really interesting approach
lately in 2020 we did published some
academic results in an academic venue
about our approach that we called q
synth
which is based on the name enumerative
search
and lately this year
there is
some
interest for mbas and synthesis so there
is more works that have been published
in xintia
msint which is basically the
implementations
and implementation of kucints using
miasma
by the same people of cynthia
and loki which is more
oriented than
making obfuscation more resilient to
synthesis
okay so what is gray box synthesis i'm
going to describe the algorithm
so our approach um
use two components uh a symbolic
executions and a synthesizer so the
basic workflow is that you have a
program you execute it symbolically
then you obtain some expressions that
you want to simplify you give it to the
synthesizer and hopefully you obtain
some synthesized expressions
so we only use symbolic execution as a
mean to obtain some data from
expressions if you're able to
retrieve uh expressions that comes from
with a different approach that's
perfectly fine for us
because this is not the main of the
algorithms we just want to have
expressions that we want to simplify
in practice we can we do our symbolic
execution statically or dynamically on
the trace
that works
the same
and so to give you a little overview of
how it works so
here is a small mba
at assembly level
if you execute it with a symbolic
executor it will lift it to an
intermediate representation
encoding the semantic
and let's say that you want to have the
area x5 at the end here
what you are going to obtain is an
abstract syntax tree
of
representing the area x5
value
at that location
so
our graybox synthesizer takes
asts of expression as input that's
really the input of the synthesizer we
want you we have a huge st and we want
to obtain something which is smaller
and it's based on two components the
input output oracle
which is our main contributions in terms
of synthesis so that's the black box
components i'm going to describe it
and we also have the ast simplification
algorithms which is the white box
component
and so the id is the following
you have your expressions you try to
synthesize from the root node
if you do not does not succeed you're
just going to iterate through the
subnodes
trying to simplify opportunistically
sub sub expressions
and that's why you are going to have in
and outs between the black box oracle
and the ast simplification algorithm
um so the black box purely black box
approach when we say black box it's um
usually referring at the comparing the
input and output behavior of the program
so you're not considering the semantics
so
that's a good thing when you're dealing
with obfuscations
but you have a huge search space to to
look for and the boolean is uh
the result is boolean because um
either you synthesize it all at once or
it does not synthesis it at
all
and on the other hand when we refer to
the white white box aspects it works for
symbolic execution fading and things
like this
white box is manipulating
the semantic of the expressions through
its syntactic representation which is
usually the ir
and in our context it means that you are
going to manipulate
the ast itself and the expressions the
operators that are have been are being
used and so on so
the good point is that you consider the
exact semantic
of the expressions
but as we are dealing with obfuscation
we are hindered by the syntactic
complexity of the expressions
so balancing between the two is really
um
a good choice from our point of view
so now i'm going to describe a bit the
input output synthesis oracle so let's
consider here that you have
a plus b an expression that is known and
a black box for which you want to know
what is
his behavior
what you are going to do is to
generate some uh
input vectors that give some valuation
for a and b and you're going to
give them to the expressions you're
going to evaluate the expressions with
those inputs
and then you obtain
an output vector
and if at some point
the values are all the same
what you can deduce is that um
the black box here is indeed doing an a
plus b operation so that's the basic
idea behind black box input output
synthesis
and what we do
to perform some such
computations
and this is the three-inch strength of
our approach is that
we are going to pre-compute
uh all the possible expressions if you
can say so we take a grammar
with some operators and variables and
what we are going to generate all the
possible expressions up to a given bound
of view obviously
and we are going to evaluate those
expressions on the the input vector to
obtain the output vector
and that gives us this mapping of output
vector to the associated expressions
and so when you want to evaluate to
perform the synthesis of a given black
box here for instance you're going to
evaluate it
you obtain the output vector
and if you find it in our in your table
you know which expression it's encoding
and so the strength here is that you
generate this table only once
offline
and then you're going to use it when you
are go you are synthesizing
the perf the the output vector this
approach is basically unsound because
if the vector is too small you might
miss some behaviors
but you can also check the equivalence
to make sure that you're synthesizing
something
equivalent
but the question here is
what happens if
you cannot synthesize the root node and
that this is where
the white box ast search is going to
come into place
and the idea of iterating through the
sub nodes is to be able to
synthesize
obtain a partial synthesis of the
expression
and here is the the original strategy
that we've implemented so you we were in
iterating the the st and
replacing things that we've been able to
synthesize and at the end we substitute
all of them
and we obtained the resulting
[Music]
de-obfuscated expressions
some of you might have noticed here that
we have some complexity issues because
we are restarting from the root node at
each iterations to iterate through the
whole ast
so on huge
ast that might be kind of complicated
we also experimented a few other
strategies that was fixing those
complexity issues so the first one was
a top-down approach
where we ether it through the ast only
once so it's like a divide and conquer
and as we go we simplify the nodes that
we are able to to synthesize
it's not the optimal um algorithm but
this is the fastest
and then we had the top down and bottom
up approach which was also replacing
with placeholder variables so v1 was the
placeholders and you do it recursively
so the algorithm is more
efficient and you obtain something which
is more
smaller than the
simple divide and conquer algorithm
so we experimented with all these
strategies there's probably others to
to implement
and the questions that we we had in mind
is how much how many
sub expressions
we were able to synthesize on the whole
big ast and so we made a small
visualization of the algorithms to to
look at it
and as you can see even though you're
not we are not able to synthesize the
whole ast at least we are able to
synthesize
many many uh
sub expressions within this big asd
and that this is where the gray box
combinations
helps
synthesizing expressions
we have some other examples here
here are the top left you have like uh
ns ast which is uh something like uh
hundred thousands of nodes big
and as you can see we are able to
synthesize many
at many locations and we reduce its size
like
significantly
and here is the result as a graphics
okay so
now i'd just like to discuss the table
generation process which is also a
critical part of our
uh algorithm
so when you do generate all those tables
you have to evaluate millions of
expressions
in order to create this mapping from
outputs to expressions
so what we did is
two
[Music]
interesting thing is memorizations of
the intermediate values so
for instance a plus b will be only
evaluated once
and then the result will be recombined
with all the other operators and
expressions
to
to improve it but we kept keep it in
memory
and we're also using jiting to evaluate
the expressions at native speed
because our implementation is in python
but all the evaluation is made in c
so what we have been able to reach is
like 25 000 expressions per seconds in
terms of throughput
and we now have tables of
375 million entries which is
kind of satisfying
um where does we store them
at the beginning we were using pickle
files uh
one year ago but
it's only works for like one million
entries
um
because it takes time to to deserialize
a pickle object
so it was not sufficient
then we tried like a relational model
of database but
we either have the insertions or the
lookup to be linear in the number of
entries so when you have millions and
millions of entries it does not work
so we ended up using leveldb which is a
key value database made by google and
that's working like a charm
and that ensures um
logarithmic lookup and that's really
that was a constraint that we wanted to
make sure
to have
and
we have so the lookup in db here is like
um in average like
122 microseconds and
if you realize that's really the
the synthesis time the
the input the so you compute the output
vector and the synthesis time is only
like 100 microseconds
um
then you make we made some experiments
to try improving the
[Music]
representativity of tables that we were
generating and as
mixing variables with operators is
really done in a
combinatorial way
sometimes expressions generated and are
not optimal and so here you can see
the kind of
operation expressions that we do
generate
and we tried using simpy to perform some
linearizations of equation of
expressions and what we obtain is the
things on the right
so that's really great to
further
improve the size of expressions but
it completely kills the generation
performances and it has some other
issues that makes it very difficult to
use it in practice so
in practice we don't use it
unfortunately
but that was a good trial
the second thing that we do
is expression learning
and that was based on some weird uh
observations that we made during our
experiment
sometimes we were giving the synthesizer
and expressions on what was coming out
is an expressions which was bigger than
the input one so we were like what the
what the is going on
so
when we looked at uh
at these expressions it was actually
expressions involving
things that were not in our tables so
mostly constant
so
this was our inputs and this was our
outputs
so what we can do with that is basically
we can
update the table with the new expression
that we have just learned
so we have not been able to synthesize
the expressions but at least we have
improved our table that improve constant
uh
and did mean that over time tables can
theoretically
become better and better
so that's great
and by the way it's for like generic
constant like one and so on we now
introduce them in our table generation
process but
um we cannot animate all the constants
so
we we still can learn the new expression
let's talk about benchmarks so these
were these were are the benchmark that
we did
um
for academic publications we
targeted the binaries sophisticated with
tigress and we did compared against ctf
against which we had like really good
result
and since then
we kept improving our
algorithm and implementations
so
we still use the four data sets which
are available online um
we used so ea is encode arithmetic so
it's basically mbas we also mixed
virtualizations and mbas
and on mbas and encode data which are
all uh tigress transformations
and so we have four benchmarks
the first line is the paper results and
as you can see we kept improving things
over time
and now we really have
good even better if you can say results
for instance on the last data sets
we obtained like 90 percent improvements
in terms of
exp synthesized expression size
and in terms of speed
for some of them we have like up to 67
persons improvements i think it's the
second one here
we we turn to two minutes 49 seconds to
55 seconds
so that's great and here we are talking
about like 500 obfuscated expressions to
the of skate
implementations we implemented that into
the q synthesis utility which is our own
implementations that we
are releasing for
this talk
q synthesis is based on multiple order
frameworks um
the most significant one is triton which
is doing the symbolic executions for us
we also integrated it into trace which
uh which is our own time travel debugger
that we use internally at quarks lab
um which is unfortunately not open
source at the moment
and as i already mentioned we use dragon
ffe which is also developed at quartzlab
for the editing of expressions we use
leveldb for the storage
we also integrated q synthesis to ida
pro
we use fastappy to serve the tables to
be able to perform some lookups as
with a rest api
and i did not mentioned it explicitly
but what we wanted to have is
once you have the obfuscated expression
you want to have like
to
re-obtained uh
the final code executable code
and for that we use arribo which is also
developed quarks lab which is open
source
and that takes inputs triton expressions
translate them to llvm and through lvm
lite we are able to recompile the the
obfuscated expressions
and then
i'm going to show you the integrations
into ida that we've performed so it will
give you a great overview of how all
that works
so here we have a small functions which
is basically
a mba that we want to simplify
we are going to load launch queue
synthesis
and we are going to has to synthesize
from here
uh to the end of the basic block we ask
here to synthesize the register array x
we are going to load the
tables that we want to use
then we just run triton the symbolic
execution to obtain the expressions so
here the expression is 124 nodes
big and contains three different inputs
like rdi rcx and rdx
we can highlight the dependencies
to and we can see here that all the
instructions are involved in the
computations of the array x value at the
end
we can look at the ast that we obtained
which is not that big actually
and then we just have to run the
synthesis and that's almost instant here
you can see that this is the resulting
expressions uh we reduce this size by 92
percent
and we can visualize the asd
which is kind of small
and so what we want to do here is
basically we want to
[Music]
to reassemble the expericated
expressions back to assembly
and this is exactly what we are going to
do here
so we are going to call arribo which is
going to call llvm lite which is a
binding for llvm so we recompile the
expressions and we obtain
compiled code
so here we are going to patch the
function bytes shrink the functions
because it's only in a single basic
block and we can do it
and there it is we just
patched back the instructions only the
instructions that are involved in the
computation so we keep
the
prologue and ep log and here you can see
the expressions with the xor add and
we charge the difficulty the expression
so that was for the demo
um
showing you how how do we do use it
and now we are going to discuss
the use cases on which we are we tried
uh our implementation
so we first tried on yanzo llvm which is
an obfuscator llvm derivatives that was
published last year and that is actually
really
a decent obfuscator the obfuscations are
kind of great
there's multiple of them and but we are
going to focus on the
vm and the obfuscate constants
so the vm is basically going to replace
um arithmetic operations and bitwise
operations with calls to functions that
are going to do them so you can see here
the
the handler for the ad
and for synthesis is like almost instant
in this case we can just synthesize it
and what we obtained in our case is the
functions which is basically
uh
le rex rci plus rdi and red
so yeah that's pretty straightforward
for the synthesizer
they use multiple mbas and they also use
mbas to obfuscate constant
and
so i would like to give some precisions
on constant
so there is two two two cases uh either
you have expressions that are using
constant like a and that beef
uh we cannot synthesize such expressions
unless you have
this ex this constant in your in your
tables
but as you cannot enumerate all the
possible constants you probably don't
have this constant and you're not going
to be able to synthesize
the expressions once it's diversified
but
what we can do is that we can synthesize
constants themselves
so opaque constant is going to take a
constant and to
introduce some spurious variables and
perform some mbas and to compute the the
constant
but that we can synthesize it
and this is a small example that we
have
generated through yarns or lvm
and the idea from a synthesis point of
view is that
you take the expression if you evaluate
it on all the inputs and you always
obtain the same output it means that the
inputs
does not
performs any
modifications on the resulting value
and that means that
they are not used and that you are
basically encoding a constant
so
in during the synthesis process if the
output happens to be always the same for
all the inputs we know that we are on a
constant and we can just evaluate it to
obtain the associated constant
in this case it's just zero
and the second use case that we've
looked at is uh
the windows kernel
and especially some patchwork functions
so
these those functions in the kernel are
known to be obfuscated with a framework
called warbird
so i've not looked into details into
into that but
it's a colleague pinpointing me that
does this function and i'm i've looked
at the code on it
it's true that it seems to contain like
uh weird
arithmetic operations
that
could probably be
simplified i don't know whether it's mba
or or not but
but
we can do a few things about this
and here is a small example of the
result
in the ida
plugin
so we executed some this basic block for
instance
which was yielding this ast and we were
able to synthesize it to something
smaller
which the resulting assembly is the
following
so
i've not looked that much into details
but um i recommend you to
to look at the two links that are on the
slide if you want to know more about
this obfuscator
and then the last use case that we've
looked at is some messaging application
that are being used by
youngsters mostly to send ephemeral
messages
and it does contain the lots of mbas
and that's good for us and we can try to
rejuvenate them
and actually so here is a small example
for arm 64
where it generates like a huge ast with
5000 nodes
with one inputs and it's actually
encoding a constant like 0x 0x7 b2
so we are kind of happy with that
we've been able to synthesize multiple
of them
um but yeah once again it would require
like a more in-depth uh research to to
know what
these mbas were used for
okay uh quick conclusions so our grey
box algorithms it's like a good balance
between the black box and white box
aspect because we can opportunistically
synthesize sub-expressions while pure
black box cannot
we still have issues that most
approaches have like to target the
expressions using constant
but we do have ideas on how to
to address them
um
and as takeaways so breaking
notification is still crucial it's still
the first step
that you have to do before
doing further reversing
um synthesis only address a certain part
of the division process mean meaning
that
it's able to synthesize to simplify
expressions once you've located them
into the program so you first have to
solve the first issue which is
finding what you want to diffuse within
the program and that's always the most
difficult part
we also use it to
synthesis to assess our horn of the
skeleton which is called quarksep shield
and that allows us to continuously
improve it to make sure it's the
obfuscation we generate is resilient
and of the like like usual uh what makes
a notification post potent is
carefully mixing it with
other transformations
an mba taken alone can usually be broken
and last i would just want to do some
acknowledgement to luigi coniglio
kickstarted that approach in our dynamic
tracing framework
and jonathan sarwan then with whom we
tweaked
to to make it more efficient on this
kind of use cases
and that's all for me
if you have any questions does not
hesitate to to ask
feel free to ping me i would be happy to
answer any of your questions so thank
you very much