[Music]
hi everyone welcome to our talk how are
you jason digitalization zero day to
steal money on the blockchain i'm
rolling and my co-speaker uzokai will be
present at part two we are from tencent
security shin lab our resource fields
include android web iot browser
blockchain etc and our xeon lab offers
many outstanding achievements that are
bad channel
here is outline of our talk
first of all i will introduce first
jason briefly
for jason is a widely used open source
json password with 23 thousand hundred
thousand
stars on github it's known for faster
passing speed
there are
3600 artifacts using
subjection on the movement as a basic
model of countless jail web service it
serves hundreds of millions of users
in this part i will detail the
digitalization process and security
check in the frustration and the
vulnerability to bypass this hike
first of all
there is a demo for json serializer and
deserializer
first of all there is a demo for json
serialize and deserialize using first
json at the left side there is a java
being named user with a stream field
name name
and the getter and center for name on
the right new user object and set name
to
using method json.jstring
with flag serializer
feature dot red class name to serialize
the user object to json stream and you
can see the output json
the key ad type has value user that is
the class name of the object and the
following is the field name
and then
use method set auto types file to enable
our type feature
then using
json.pass method to
deserialize this json string to a user
object with name 4.
take note of this line of code of code
password config set auto type spot auto
tab is a very important feature of
fascism digitalization
it's the flag about whether physician
can destroy any
non-principled
non-presupposed
classes automatically without
other configuration
it's false if default
if you don't enable auto type message
json path will also adjust an exception
about auto type ignore support where
you'll pass to json with x type user
class
next i will detail the visualization
process inside the first json
when the scanner catches the token key i
type
the serialized
process will be started
first the target class name
will be checked by the method check auto
type if the check is passed
method get digitalizer will written the
digitalization constructor the
digitalizer will be selected by the
target type and finally use the method
create instance of the object
digitalizer to get object from json
fields
next let's focus on the default method
check auto type and how to bypass it to
visualize archery classes
the message check auto tab has three
perma parameters parameter type name is
the target class you want to
decentralize
the you can
you can specify it
explicitly in the json for example i'll
type user
the parameter expect class is the super
class or interface of the tagged class
and again it can be none
and the last parameter feature in the
serialized flag it always defaults
before we start detailing the check
process inside the check auto type we
need to know how to input a parameter of
type class as the
second parameter expect class
as we said the express class means
inheritance
there are two forms of inheritance in
the first json the first one is is
is
explicit inheritance
you can start adjusting object string
with two edge type key the first attack
value is the express class and the
second one following is the subclass
which inherits from the express class
and the third following are the
properties of the
subclass
another form is implicit inheritance
there is a demo class user had a field
id with interface 4
and the class 4 import implements the
interface form so you can set the id to
adjust an object with tab
tab 4 import
that will trigger the implicit
inheritance the interface 4 is the
expect class and the full import in the
subclass
go back to the check auto type
this section i will detail the control
flow of the method check auto tab and
show you how to bypass it
the first layer is the function
prototype first if the target class is
in the waitlist or in the digitalizer
cache
all has the
json annotation json type
it will be it will pass the check the
target class will be returned and saved
to the digitalizer cache next if not if
the target class is in the blacklist or
inherit from
json circle rule site data source or
class loader
the method will also error and
exit
if not if the incoming in parameter
expect class is not now and it's not
those tabs object uh serializable clones
ball
uh a clone ball closeable
event listener collection and the target
class is assembled from expect class
it will pass the check return and cache
if not finally it can't pass the check
unless the global flag auto type support
is true but is always false in the
default configuration
to intuitively
observe the kisses passed auto type
check
i list them as follows
first enable the auto type support flag
is a rare situation next classes with an
analytician just in type
those classes in non-universal we can't
use them anywhere
next classes in the waitlist what is
initialized as a final static hashcode
list
with about 60 classes which are mainly
related to java abstract window toolkit
and spring
framework
those classes in weightless and at high
level
which are not easy to be
exceeding
to be extended
so the first three cases are not our
first choice for bypass
next classes in the visualization
in the digitalizer cache
the last one the second parameter of
check auto type expect class and the
subclass of
it
especially note that the expect class is
a parameter with tab class instead of
type of string that means the expat
class has already passed the autotype
check is converted from string type name
to a target class so the source the
source of express class are the classes
in the
workplace and the digitalizer cache
so we focus on the distributor cache the
cache is named tab utils mappings
it's initialized in the method type
utils and base class mappings for
preloading the digitalizer of basic tabs
at the right it's a part of source code
you can see the class byte into boolean
early class object and interface clone
ball are added to the cache mappings
although there are many low level class
and database in the cache
the tabs have their own specified
visualizer for example
class is exception and the class error
will handle by syllable digitalizer a
class hash map and hash table will be
handled by map digitalizer
but
except the two types
java util bitsight and java long auto
cloudable
but json will create a default java
industrializer for them so
any classes extend beside our auto cloud
board can
bypass the auto type check and create an
instance friendly
so we can inherit from those classes to
bypass the autotype check and auto
cloudball is a very low level interface
says jdk7
it's the super interface of the most of
stream classes channel classes and the
connection classes etc the picture at
the bottom is the sub interfaces and
implementing classes listed in the jdk
document
those classes provide us with a broad
search space
to derive our guidance chain so finally
we bypass the auto tape check by java
long auto close evo
this is a port for the bug adjacent
string with two f keys the first one is
the expect class auto type
auto close ball and the second one is
the target class
java io reader because reader is higher
from auto close ball so it will pass the
check
in the previous section i detailed how
to bypass the security check by auto
crossbow in the next section i will
detail how to find some interesting
guides to achievement
to achieve remote code
executed
execute and more
now we need to find out which classes we
can derive and what we can do about
those classes the second question can be
described as
which method
can be called during visualization
we call those methods magic magic method
the method create java being
deteriorated in the main process of
visualization and inside it
the main method of creating digitalizer
is java being infobuilt
the parameter is the target class and
type
first in this method it will select the
contracture by the two method get
default constructor and the get creator
constructor the order of choosing
constructor is as following
after constructor publishation will
iterate and call all the central
messages of the target class and next
there are some gator methods will be
called automatically during
initialization depends on the return
type
now we can answer the first question
about derivation
except directly inherit from the
interface autocrossboard there are four
cases that classes will be added to the
cache during the digitalization
first the class itself second the tabs
of the
selected constructors parameters
next the types of the parameters of the
center message including the types of
public fields and the last a part of
written types of getters
there is a very flexible feature named
json pass in the first json you can use
it as an object query language and
what's even more amazing is that you can
use it in the digitalization by the
token key dollar reference following is
a demo json the key username has a value
with key reference which is dollar dot
user object dot name the dollar means
the root element is the in intelligence
object itself so your user object is the
first key and the name is
the field name in the use object it will
call the get method get name to get the
value from the used object
so jsonpath
not only allows us to get actually
getters
to call actually getters but also allows
us to cross-reference and access their
properties on multiple generate
instances when dura
when contracting objects during json
passing
this feature greatly
expands our magic method space
there are some conditions for
gadget classes
first
it must be derived it must be
derived from autoclausable second it
must have default constructor or
constructor with symbols otherwise it
can't be in
extension it clicked correctly
and third it must not in the blacklist
in addition to the necessary conditions
we also have some quality requirements
for gadgets the gate instrument called
rce
actually fail
read and write or other high risk
effects
and the dependence of goddess should be
in native jdk or in the widely used
third party libraries
there are almost hundreds of
third-party packages used
widely used in the java ee and we need
to search get it in nearly a million
classes it's impossible to peel
to pure manual search so i write a
tool based on the reflection to search
the
derivation of classic space
i rewrite the fabrication digitalization
process to check the derivation
conditions and create a graph about
derivation relations between classes
it's helpful when you reverse the chart
from the sync class
and in addition the tool can search
available
guidance classes in the jdk and the
specified set of jazz and i crawl and i
crawl common third party libraries
from women
from
[Music]
as input
there is a video shows how it gen
generates almost five thousand classes
from the interface autoclave at the
beginning the yellow node is the
interface autoclavable and the green
node is class jdk natural url reader
the oral and lan means derivation
relation and you can see the url reader
inherit from auto global
and then start searching
there are many colors of nodes
different colors
represent different types the green node
is class the blue node is interface the
peak node is
abstract class the proper node is member
class
here are some high-risk gadgets we found
in the third party in packages by the
tool
such as use
the circle connector to rce
use a patch comp io to read and write
files you'll get jetty to ssri etc
i will detail the gadget's comments i o
read and write files in the next section
about exploited the block channels
there are some fertilizing pillows to
your json connector to rce
due to the difference between versions
and the limitation of blacklist you need
to use different gadgets of our
different method conversions
now we can control many important
websites and affect millions of users by
the json vulnerability let's make more
let's let's make leg makes things more
interesting we found that
this fascism vulnerability affect a
public child with multi-billion dollar
market value and we are detailed i see
on the sovereign nodes of blockchain
tron is next
torn is a public blockchain with a
little crypto
currency known as trx the max value of
trx is 5 billion dollars and it have 14
million holders besides
1400 of the apps are on the troll
network with a daily transaction
over
volume of over 12 million dollars
and the java trend is the java
implementation of the public blockchain
protocol launched by tron it analyzes
all the decentralized applications in
the torrent ecosystem
it's an open source java application
with two services that's on github
java torrent can enable html service on
the torrent nodes to allow users and
developers to interact with the
blockchain
we will detail the java troll in the
next section in this section we just
need to know
its http service using facilitation to
pass json post data
now we have a vulnerability can see or
read and write any file on the
on some conditions but those conditions
are not always made first of all there
is no remote jdbc driver in the java
toronto
so we can't use the gadget's message
connector and there are some problems
need to be sold for exploited by read
and write file
gadgets the javascript is an independent
spring boot factor
so we can't write a web shell directly
we should think about what to write
and the jar can run with actual uh
upfront user with
network permission so we should think
about where are readable paths
and the java turn using fast json to
decode the post in the http api request
however there is no direct response by
http but broadcast on p2p network the
http response just only shows the state
of
the state of
api request so
if we read
read files
from server node how to get contents
written
furthermore the blockchain is
decentralized is decentralized
it is decentralized
that means you take over
models you get more control of the
blockchain so our exploit should rely on
as few preconditions as possible
there are some common uh there are some
common ways to get shell on the spring
foot put faster
when you can read fill a red file
for example
you can override system leaves or write
class
file in the gvm class path
such as a
charset gel
but as i said above
root formation is not required those
fill those files can only be already
or written by root
the operating system or jvm lab is
dangerous without the exact version
there is a feature of gni in the
java package
the binary library files
this should be released to the file
system before it can be loaded
this operation is usually in the static
block triggered when the class is loaded
for the first time
and the binary library is always
released to the directory uh
specified by the system property
java io type directory and the java
method system load will load the gi iso
file by function dr open so or writing
the gene iso file will be the first
choice
java trolling
used level db as the local storage
driver for blockchain data
ldb is the first key value storage
library and is used by bitcoin therefore
it's inherited by many public chain
level dbc with a block chain metadata
with which needed to
pull in frequently for reading and
writing
so javatron use the gi driver
other side jfile needs to extract
to extract gene elaborate level dbgi
extracts the iso library in the method
library extract and load and it drags
the gene iso file to with a random
suffix
to the
temp directory
so
if we want to override the jni iso at
runtime we need to get random
file name extracted by the java
the motor directory of the most direct
way is to list the temp directory but we
don't want those information to be
broadcast on the p2p network
and the last problem is that we need to
write binary bytes instead of
a string with coding there are two
things called can called coding
confusion the input json is read as a
string with encoding instead of byte and
the output stream and the fill writer
should use base
we finally solved those problems by the
gadgets of patch commons io this gadget
chain can be combined with other classes
to not only write but also read file
let's start with red file get this red
file gadget is more clear
look at the left side the class comes i
will input boom input stream inherit
from autoclavable so it can bypass the
autotype check it has three parameters
in the constructor input stream delegate
boolean input include and a wearable
parameters of class
type order mark
booms
there is a getter method for field boom
in the
bomb input stream get bomb will call the
delegate read
we can set the field delegate to the
class commons io input
t input stream
the method read of t input stream will
write the input bytes to the field
branch the field branch can be set to an
output stream in the constructor
so using the class com i o input
commands i o boom input stream we can
choose proper input and output stream
classes to achieve red
red file for writing
encoding string we can follow those
gadgets just in the comments arrow
package
set the source input stream field input
to
charging
chart synchronous input stream and set
the field cs to the input stream which
you want to write to fail
and set the output stream failed
field branch to
[Music]
output stream with class
failure with encoding
as for writing binary bytes besides a
patch com io we need to use two other
packages in the geotron
set the field input of in t input stream
to call to apache commons codec binary
uh
basically a base 6 for input stream
which input of red in string and output
advice
and set the third branch of boom input
stream to eclipse internal
low-cost.file upstream which is from
expect joy
next this is how to use a patch combs i
o to read files
the
entry of guided is also the class boom
input stream and it's getting messed up
getting boom
it costs
it cause methyl matches in the gut bone
the methodic matches will iterate the
filled bones and compare every bone with
the
bite
with the base read from the
input stream delegate if there is one
boom is same as the best read from
delegate it will return the symbol
otherwise it will it's none
so that
so that will let us get the
read content according to the different
written states
it's a way of blend read
there is a pillow for reading the temp
directory to get random file name first
look at the number one at the right side
we use the class jdk natural url reader
as the input stream the parameter url a
support file
scheme for a folder and listing
directory the number three
the field boom is set to multiple bias
blocks to be compared with reader output
and the number four you just pass
reference dollar dot abc dot boom to
call the gather message get bomb of the
object abc
which is the first field
in the json with the class bomb input
stream as number five let this reference
reference value be the field address and
send this json post data to the java
training api wallet
while data address and if the address is
known it will read nothing if the
address is bad format it will return
well it is a failed message
so we can use apache comsio to read the
temp directory by byte and finally get
the random file name of gn library
now we can all read
the gni library at runtime
the last question is how to hijack
pointer
the gel channel will register a timer
task for level db red right on
initialization
the message dbright will call the gene
and method
little buffer gene and malloc
so we can inject shellcode to the
outside address of gmaillog when the
timer test winder when the timer task is
a executed pun
this is the fun process of
exploit and the last step is recovering
the program contest to
prevent the crash and for the sixth step
in post
penetration for real money
return to michael speaker with a kai
next i will introduce a post-penetration
exploit method that affects the security
of blockchain user size
after we successfully rce on toronto's
http node we need to test whether it
will cut losses to the user's size
for the blockchain the first approach we
think of is a 51 percent tag
a 51 percent tag is attack or blockchain
by a group of minors who control more
than fifty percent of the network's many
hashtags
attackers with with majority control of
the network can interrupt the recording
of new blocks by preventing other
manners from completing blocks
and joint use the super representative
mechanism
any account can apply to become a super
representative candidate
every account can vote for super
representative candidates
the top 27 candidates with the most
awards are super representative
super representatives generate blocks
package transactions and get blocked and
voting rewards
therefore we need to rce and at least
one half of the super representative
nodes to cover 51 percent tag
but actual rotation is somewhat
unexpected
not all nodes have a http service
enabled in other words we can't attack
owners of tron
this picture shows the location ip of
all the nodes of the troll network this
date is provided by the
trussgun.org website
as shown by choicegun.org
trolling has
1332 nodes in total
with guns of ips and found that only a
quarter of the nodes can be accessed
through the http service
therefore
there is no guarantee that more than
half of the super representatives have
enabled http service
unfortunately we can't use this
vulnerability to cost of 51 percent tag
of the troll network
we need to find another way
now let's focus on the h2on http node
itself a study with those http node
placed in the short network
the trolling http node has a variety of
api cards to allow users to interact
with the blockchain
some of the api cards serve as
standalone requests to getting wider
pieces of information
the most important thing is that there
are also many api cards which modify the
user trs wallet resulting a need to sign
and broadcast transaction
remaining we mainly focus on the second
type of
of api
this apis will be used on user trade of
blockchain
the user wants to send some trx tokens
to other users in the tool network
three steps are required
first of all the user needs to make a
transaction
and conquer the wallet create
transaction api to compare the website
the http node will return a low
transaction in json format
the fixed step is to find the
transaction the user can call the wallet
get transaction sign api
the ap the http node will use the
private key provided by the user to find
the raw transaction
the last step is to broadcast the
transaction the user can call the wallet
broadcast transaction api
the http node will broadcast the defined
transaction to the blockchain
therefore
after we are the http node
if the user use http node to make a
transaction
we can return a folder transaction
which will be execute executed after the
user science and broadcast calculate
if the user use the http node to find
the transaction
we can steal the user's private key
if user only use http nodes to broadcast
the transaction
it seems that we can only prevent
transactions from being broadcast to
cast us
obviously stealing private keys is more
harmful than photo transactions and
further transactions are more helpful
than dof
in the short network
almost all users use wallet programs for
transactions
channelling is firstly launched as
choice official website and backed by
foundation
it is the
wallet with most users
channeling has three versions including
chrome voltage extension ls and android
among them cumulative extension alone
has more than 300 000 users
after testing the three versions of
troll link wallet
we found that all three
wallets use http nodes to broadcast the
transactions
in addition current knowledge extension
also used http nodes to make traffic
actions and directly find and broadcast
the transaction without checking the
return to draw transaction
so we can try to attack the wallet by
return link for the transactions
when the wireless sender requests to
make a transaction to the http node
control
we return our further transaction
then the validator finds the transaction
locally and finally broadcasters send
the transaction to the blockchain
we recorded a video to demonstrate it
with my active attack method
first selection shift normally and are
less than 100 urs tokens to bob
after that the attacker actually
exploits program
and successfully rc is http node
and run some leisure's program of the
port
select him with transaction okay
and the attacker returned the first row
transaction
finally the tiger received qrx tokens
instead of bob
the tag is not over yet let's think
about it why can't wallet extension have
different behavior from ls and android
after analyzing the source code of
chromolytic extension we found that it
used the tone wipe library
tone wipe is to deliver a unified
seamless development experience in
experience influenced by ethereum's web
three implementation
turn live use the troll live
trans transaction builders builder those
center x method to make transactions
which will request http nodes
as you can see in the source code when
calling this method the wallet
transaction api of the http node will be
requested to make a transaction
we realized that the total web library
would be a key point
so we investigated a very variety of
tolerance related applications and made
some new discoveries
we found that in addition to channeling
chrome volatility extension some
multi-currency voltage and
index also use the tone wipe library
and we also didn't check the raw
transaction returned by the http node
multi-currency wallet is a wallet that
supports multiple crypto currency
transactions
m token is a multi multi-currency wallet
that supports a choice
m token has 12 million users and is your
search on web library
after testing we found that when i'm
token knowledge generates choice related
perfections it does request the
http node as you can see in the picture
we've carefully first returned
transaction replacing to a drive with
another address and then find and
broadcast the photo transaction
that is a computer application that runs
on a distributed computing system like
blockchain
as of december 17 2020 1400
steps have been created on strong
network with a daily transaction volume
of over 12 million dollars
for developer depth is a combination of
front end smart contrast
john pro has 12 wires for front-end
developer
take a poll next step as an example
winterized token absent in this
step
it will request hdp notes to make a
transaction
we also successfully for the return
transaction replacing two address with
another address and then signed and
broadcasted for the transaction
in summary the trolling link chrome
wallet extension with more than 300
thousand users
the total the trolling part of the mem
token multi-currency knowledge with 12
million users
and the death with a daily transaction
volume of over 12 million
will all be affected
finally we make conclusion
also distributed and decentralized
structure improves the gravity
credibility and fault tolerance of the
system
blockchain is notable bullet proof to
securely vulnerability
and we hope our work
our work can notify blockchain
developers and users to more careful
about security
our research on the future of blockchain
security will include
traditional web security cloud and age
computing and the poster penetration
exploit
here is a vulnerability timeline
special thanks to songkai told you your
women in the uil
thanks