[Music]
welcome to next gen dfir mass exploits
and supplier compromises criminals have
started targeting suppliers and also
leveraging zero-day vulnerabilities in
order to break into systems worldwide
and this is not an isolated incident
this has become the new norm as
criminals realize that they can maximize
their return on investment and by
hacking into a relatively small number
of systems they can spread malware and
gain unauthorized access on a wide scale
so today we're going to talk about how
incident response needs to change and we
all need to adapt to this new norm
my name is sherry davidoff i'm the ceo
of lmg security you may also know me as
alien from the book breaking and
entering i have a degree in electrical
engineering and computer science from
mit and i'm a gcfa and g pin and my name
is matt durin i am the ir team lead for
lmg security a senior security
consultant certified forensics examiner
and head of r d
together with our colleague karen
springer we have a new book coming out
on ransomware and cyber extortion so
check it out should be out by the end of
this year
today we're going to start off by
talking about why we need to adapt our
incident response processes and how the
attackers tactics are changing we'll use
solarwinds as an example and step
through that to discuss our new
checklist and things that you need to
include in your incident response
processes then we're going to flip over
to a zero day exploit and analyze the
microsoft exchange zero day
vulnerability that was announced in
early 2020 and finally we're going to
dig into the cassaya attacks and apply
our new checklist to this recent hack
along the way we're going to talk about
how incident response needs to evolve
and we'll leave you at the end with that
checklist that you can use
so of course recently we saw uh in the
news that casseya was hacked kasey of
course is remote management and
monitoring software that's used by
enterprises and also managed service
providers to gain remote access to
networks around the world multiple
zero-day exploits were discovered back
in april and hackers were able to
exploit those in july
the rival ransomware gang and an
affiliate of that deployed ransomware to
at least 1500 organizations that we know
of this is the largest ransomware attack
on record
so again this is just another of the
recent mass zero days and supply chain
exploitations that we've seen from solar
winds to blackbaud to microsoft exchange
to excellian and many many more and even
though these are slightly different
types of incidents our response will
have many similarities so there's some
debate over whether something like the
cassaya rmm exploit counts as a supply
chain attack so we like to summarize it
in this way supply chain attacks are
where the vector is through a
third-party technology vendor whereas a
mass zero day exploit is when the
exploitation occurs after the software
is already deployed in the victim
environment and again the response is
surprisingly similar as we'll see
let's take solar winds as our first
example we're going to dissect this so
fireeye announced that they had suffered
a supply chain malware infection in
december of 2020. so they had been
hatched some of their offensive tools
were leaked and they notified the public
now they were able to trace this back to
a back door in the solar winds platform
their orion network monitoring software
is widely used by organizations around
the world and the unfortunate thing is
that this meant that criminals had
installed a back door to approximately
18 000 customer networks
now solar winds have been hacked since
2019 september of 2019 and this was a
little bit shocking because again the
first time that this was publicized in
this was in december of 2020 so think
about how does your response team find
out about a supply chain attack in the
case of solar winds the criminals went
went hands-on to the solarwinds network
and did some test deployment of code
starting in the fall of 2019. by march
they had actually rolled out that back
door into the platform and customers
started to install it the code was
properly signed by solarwinds and so
there was really nothing to indicate
that there was a problem
shortly thereafter the criminals started
actually reaching out into customer
networks and interacting with customer
networks getting hands-on access to
their enterprises as well
again it was still many months before
any customer that we know of detected
this and publicly reported it and
fireeye one of their customers was
actually the first to announce it not
the vendor themselves which has some
implications for our threat intelligence
you may be looking for notifications
from their vendor from your vendors when
really the notifications may come from a
different third party and you also have
to think about how how much can you
trust those notifications so we need to
be monitoring threat intelligence
platforms so identify your key software
products and suppliers what do you need
to be monitoring what announcements you
need do you need to be watching for and
then set up your threat intelligence
sources so think about receiving vendor
alerts uh getting you know following
your vendors on twitter things like that
it's actually very effective even though
it's low low tech
also you can subscribe to various threat
intelligence platforms there's
commercial options you can also you can
also follow security vendors critical
stack crowdstrike and others
academic organizations and security
training companies like sans are very
good at announcing these also government
agencies
tend to circulate this type of news this
is the carbon black threat research
center which is a community driven
threat research repository offered by
the vmware carbon black company we use
them a lot when we're when we're
responding to incidents and uh it's a
it's a great place to find updates and
indicators of compromise for new and out
or kind of upcoming cyber attacks before
they really hit any of the mainstream
media feeds also think about whether
your suppliers are also monitoring for
threat intelligence what software do
they rely on that is then deployed to
you or that affects your risk
the next thing you do you need to do
once you hear about an alert involving a
vendor that relates to you is you need
to evaluate your risk so in the case of
solarwinds we knew where we found out
early on what versions of their software
were affected but it still wasn't
trivial to figure out exactly who was
impacted
some organizations were running that
version of the software others had never
patched or never upgraded and in fact we
found
organizations that had been very slow
and didn't keep their software up to
date weren't impacted by this issue so
they kind of dodged a bullet but i'm not
sure we really need an incentive to not
apply patches yeah again we don't want
to we don't want to recommend uh
skipping security patches on your on
your systems but in this case it did
save a few people yeah
in some cases you also need to think
about
the window of compromise so
were you running an affected version
during that period of compromise you
might need to look at your change
management logs now what do you do if
you're not sure again often in these
early phase phases you may not be
certain if you're impacted and we need
to take quick action with very little
information so talk ahead of time about
whether or not you should take down
software that might be impacted and what
the balance is between taking action
versus keeping things online you also
want to coordinate with your suppliers
if there's a supplier running software
on your behalf ask them ahead of time
how will you react um when will you get
notified will they be
changing your software on the fly or
coordinating with you
one new tool that we have in our arsenal
is a software bill of materials s-bomb
so recently there was an executive order
from the white house and one of the
things that was required was a software
bill of materials for any suppliers that
do business with the government and we
do anticipate that this will trickle
down to the public sooner or later so
that means that any software you rely on
or suppliers may have to produce a list
of software that they rely on now this
is going to become in part of our
incident response processes over the
next few years because you will have the
if if this comes to pass you may have
the ability to review those s-bombs when
there's an announcement to determine
what your risk is of
downstream compromise because of
software that your vendors are relying
on so stay tuned
we do expect to see incident response
practices evolving and taking into
account increased availability of
software bills of materials
all right so let's get back to solar
winds so in the case of solar winds we
want to evaluate our risk and what is
the risk of a potential data breach or
widespread attack or a lurking piece of
malware within our network well
unfortunately it was very high once the
solarwinds
adversary had access to customer
networks they could really do whatever
they wanted so they could steal files
they could install new software they
could gather information about your
network disable security tools we saw a
lot of evasive behavior
they were deliberately trying to avoid
detection and that's why they were so
successful so there was a very high risk
of a breach the good thing is that in
the government advisory the csi advisory
they specifically said hey you're going
to want to forensically image system
memory and or host operating systems if
you have that capability
so remember when there's a risk of a
breach you probably want to pull in your
cyber insurer your breach coach your
forensics team and really think about
preserving that evidence in a lot of
these cases especially with a zero day
or a supplier compromise we have to act
quickly with very very little
information about what is actually
happening with the system advisories and
early information can help but it's
usually largely incomplete data so we go
with standard options uh you know if
we're going for the nuclear option we
can yank the power cable we can yank the
network cable uh and then it's kind of a
general step we want to do system-wide
password resets but there are impacts
that we need to be concerned with are
there going to be operational impacts to
the organization if we take this service
offline are there going to be help desk
calls is is the help desk department
going to be overwhelmed by tech support
now pulling a plug on solarwinds
unfortunately might not have saved
people who were impacted directly by
this by this vulnerability solarwinds
was a multi-component attack the back
door the original backdoor was in the
solarwind software but the attackers
rarely stayed within that system uh they
would move laterally into other systems
and in most cases we saw them deploying
things like cobalt strike beacons these
were used for both lateral movement and
for persistence inside of the network so
taking the the solar one server offline
was great but if they had a if they had
a beacon or some other means of
accessing the network it was a little
too late at that point to really rely on
that uh and cobalt strike is something
we're seeing in a lot of new uh new
adversary attacks i mean it's become a
very very common occurrence especially
in ransomware and system compromise uh
to see these legitimate tools being uh
being used by malicious actors yeah
that's a recurring theme
so that that brings up our very
important next point uh threat hunting
needs to be included in everyone's ir
plans this needs to be standard
operating procedure for any kind of
malicious or remediation activities that
are taking place uh we tend to use
carbon black when we do our incident
response and here's an example of that
this is an example of us finding a a
cobalt strike beacon dropper being
executed on the network and that's
executing using powershell and a base64
encoded command this is something that
is kind of a hallmark for a lot of
malicious activity we'll see when we
talk about exchange as well
but
knowing this ahead of time means that uh
we we need to be careful there are other
pieces of the network that may use the
exact same tactics and procedures that
uh the malicious adversaries are using
that may or may not be malicious at all
a good example of that is well ansible
so in a couple of the networks we were
working with we're actively looking for
these these cobalt straight beacon
payloads and again that's a powershell
command running a base64 encoded string
that then acts to install the beacon
ansible functions in a very very similar
way for network automation so if we're
taking steps to block encoded powershell
usage we could also be breaking a
critical component of the system at the
same time again not a not a new tactic
but something that especially with these
these newer kinds of attacks and the
sophistication of networks that we're
working with we need to be very very
cognizant of as we move forward with
response so i think this really gets to
the point you need to be prepared to do
threat hunting so have the tools in
place that you're going to want to use
and understand what you're going to be
looking for to avoid these false
positives or be prepared to pull in a
third party if necessary that's that's
totally right
so the next thing we want to think about
since we are going to be doing threat
hunting is how do we do that effectively
in one of these new these new types of
cyber attacks something that we know
very little about uh first we need to
obtain the indicators of compromise that
we have available for us when these
first break out now in the case of
solarwinds we had indicators of
compromise provided by both fireeye and
microsoft very very early in the
outbreak they were two of the more
highly impacted organizations that were
public about it anyway and those were
pretty reliable indicators of compromise
so we were lucky in that respect exactly
we could trust the data we were getting
from them we also had some good
indicators of compromise provided by the
u.s government from sisa they offered
things like hash values specific pieces
of behavioral activity to look for it
was very good
other times you can look for the vendor
the vendor may release these uh these
assistant guides to help you hunt for
these these malicious infections inside
your network uh next security firms and
researchers are are usually a pretty
good resource although we do have to vet
those a little bit more carefully
because really anyone can put up a blog
post
and then thread hunting and intelligence
software so things like carbon black
what you see on the screen here is a
list out of the watch list they're
available through the carbon black edr
tool kit
and they are subscription feeds that are
regularly updated that we can use to
assist in these threat homes so things
like us cybercom amc uh built-in miter
attack framework notifications are
really helpful here there's also open
source threat intelligent projects like
misp misc is a
you know a very good source of community
driven information that can be used and
directly integrated into a lot of ids
systems so definitely something to watch
out for
and then also structured formats for
these are really good to be familiar
with so if you're not familiar with yara
or styx
take a little bit of time get familiar
with it they can be incredibly useful
for quickly identifying indicators of
compromise on your network without
having to sift through a lot of
superfluous data now if you want to have
an effective response you're not going
to be able to assemble these on the fly
in the heat of the moment and have a
really effective thread hunting campaign
so again you want to understand ahead of
time where you're going to get your
indicators of compromise and make sure
that they're sources you can trust
so in this case
one of the challenges was that this was
a nation-state attack so
there are there are sources of evidence
that indicate this was nobelium which is
a russian state-sponsored hacker
microsoft believes that over a thousand
developers contributed to that solar
winds attack um 44
of the organizations impacted by this
were themselves information technology
companies and i find that particularly
scary because it means that the
criminals uh the adversary could have
gotten into not just solar winds and
their customers but then customers of
those customers so we anticipate that
there will be ripple effects from this
creating risk throughout the entire
technology ecosystem for years to come
now one of the things that made solar
runs particularly difficult to uh to
analyze especially at first was how
difficult it was to actually obtain
indicators of compromise from networks
that were not actively experiencing an
infection from the the sunburst malware
at the time sunburst malware was
specifically designed to evade detection
and analysis so they employed things
like a 12 to 14 day sleep timer
verifications of very very specific
solarwinds dll names before the software
would execute random delays and
execution which made sandboxing
incredibly difficult multiple domain
checks and then security analysis and
software checks again they designed this
to not be analyzed and it made it very
very difficult at first
for individuals to obtain these
indicators of compromise unless they
have direct access to this running in
the wild again this is our new norm so
responders should expect those iocs to
be updated throughout your response the
initial iocs that you receive are
probably just going to be a small subset
of the ones that exist in the long term
so you want to constantly get updates
and be checking regularly 12 to 14 days
is a pretty long period of time we're
also seeing things like heavy decoy
traffic being used in in pretty much
every new piece of malware we're seeing
banking trojans uh specifically are
really bad about this
basically what this means is the malware
is going to generate its own malicious
outbound traffic that it's sending it
out or sending out to its own c2 servers
but at the same time it's going to
generate almost identical traffic that
it's going to send out to a bunch of
legitimate sources things like jquery
google g static one tech company
facebook yahoo uh the list is very very
long here but again it obscures that
outbound traffic and makes it very
difficult to find unless you're
specifically looking for it okay so our
next step after you hunt for threats or
while you're hunting for threats is you
need to consider applying emergency
patches and software updates so when you
have a supplier like solarwinds
that has an issue with their software
they issued multiple patches to deal
with it and again there wasn't even a
patch for this when it was first
announced so you can see that the first
patch was released december 23rd of 2020
and there were three patches released on
that day another one was released in
late january and two more were released
in february so as responders you need to
be aware of the fact that there will be
emergency patches but they may not exist
right away and so you need to have
workarounds if they do exist they may
not fully solve the problem they may be
just a partial solution so you still
need to take some other steps to reduce
your risk and deal with it sometimes new
patches can break things and that's a
real balancing act
we do need patches matt
plan for elevated risks longer term this
goes for you as well as any suppliers
that may have been impacted so again
solarwinds has now been hacked we know
that and organizations that were
leveraging their software many of them
have been hacked as well the result of
this is that hackers may have extensive
data that they can leverage to launch
future attacks that could include
employee emails internal sensitive
information passwords keys and more so
this affects the risk of our entire
software ecosystem that relies on that
one supplier we've also seen the
installation of advanced persistent
threats and additional malware as matt
alluded to
criminals may also have obtained
software source code and vulnerability
details and that's something fairly
common and then they can leverage that
in future attacks if an msp is hacked
you might see customer lists that get
stolen or software providers as well and
then again the criminals can go after
them so remember this doesn't just apply
to suppliers that are in the news in
many cases suppliers may have been
hacked and not detected it or may have
been hacked and not reported it because
there weren't any laws or contractual
obligations in place at the time that
required that level of of reporting
so here's our checklist when we analyze
the solar winds attack
here are seven things that we need to
think about integrating into modern
incident response processes so number
one we need to be proactively monitoring
threat intelligence for the tools that
we rely on
you also need to have someone assigned
to capture this information and evaluate
the risk
when a new risk is announced you need to
consider preserving forensic evidence
even before you step up to contain the
damage and then threat hunting needs to
be included in all of our response
processes it just needs to be part of
our new norm also expect emergency
patches and emergency updates and have
those conversations in advance about
whether or not you want to apply them
and finally plan for elevated risks that
pertain to either your organization or
your supplier
all right now that we've analyzed a
supply chain attack let's talk about how
these same tactics apply to a mass
zero-day vulnerability and a great
example of this is the microsoft
exchange vulnerability that was
announced in the first quarter of 2020.
so of course microsoft announced on
march 2nd sorry 2021
microsoft announced on march 2nd
that there were zero-day vulnerabilities
in the microsoft exchange software that
many organizations around the world used
to host email and they released those
security updates but even before they
released them organizations around the
world had been hacked now the adversary
behind this was linked to chinese
state-sponsored hackers the hafnium
group so again we saw some very advanced
tactics deployed by march 5th we knew
that at least 30 000 organizations were
already hacked and when your email gets
hacked you may have a major data breach
on your hands or other fallout as a
result of that email is very sensitive
so what could the hackers do in this
case well by exploiting these
vulnerabilities they could gain full
administrative control over this server
they could steal your email they could
steal credentials they could install
more malware and pivot into your
organization's network and infect other
computers so this was a very high risk
situation
now how do we as responders find out
about it well this is an interesting
case to analyze we know that researchers
discovered the vulnerabilities on
january 5th 2021 and alerted microsoft
microsoft actually responded fairly
quickly compared to many suppliers they
clearly jumped on this and worked hard
to create patches but unfortunately the
release did not happen quickly enough
for many of their customers
on february 23rd microsoft shared
information about the attack with some
of their partners and on february 26
three days later attackers started to
exploit it now the public was not yet
aware of this so literally before most
people even found out about it many
exchange servers were already hacked
most people found out on march 2nd when
microsoft released patches but it was
already too late by then and the next
day
tens of thousands of exchange surveys
were already compromised so unless you
were right on top of that and installed
the patches right away chances are
pretty good that you were already
compromised in some form or fashion and
even then it might have been too late
so it's interesting to think about how
that exploit actually got leaked out
into the uh you know the hackers sphere
uh devcor the uh the pen testing group
that actually discovered the
vulnerability kept things pretty
tight-lipped but one of their testers
who went by the name orange tsai noticed
that the code that was being used by the
by the adversaries in this case looked
very very similar to the code he had
submitted to actually report the exploit
to microsoft up to and including the
fact that the web shell password orange
that he had hard coded into his exploit
was being used by hackers in the wild so
it got out somehow we're just not quite
sure how
yeah so one of the things um that people
been wondering out about is was this
leaked through microsoft active's
protection program so this is a method
where microsoft partners key partners
get a heads up about upcoming patches
and vulnerabilities so that they can
prepare and support their customers
unfortunately you know a small number of
people may be able to keep a secret but
can 82 possibly not
now microsoft warns that if a map
partner was the source of the leak they
would face consequences unfortunately
think about the um the attack surface
here if any one of those partners had an
email hack or some kind of compromise
criminals might be able to steal
information about these upcoming
exploits and patches so and this is
something that hackers are really
targeting
so that's something to consider is how
that information gets distributed
we know that historically hackers are
actually very interested in bug
information and source codes so that
they can find vulnerabilities and
exploit
known issues
for example and we also know that we
don't necessarily get a heads up about
these so for example microsoft's bug
tracking database was hacked in 2013
but the public didn't find out about
that for four years four years later in
2017 this finally hit the news and
chances are pretty good that many other
technology vendors have had similar
issues where their networks have been
hacked maybe their source code has been
accessed or their bug tracking database
has been accessed and either they
haven't detected that or they haven't
reported it because there's no legal or
contractual obligation at that time for
that particular firm researchers may
also be targeted and many of these are
not many many researchers are not
deploying
security technologies or staff that
could rival nation-state attacks
so again we have to think about the fact
that bugs vulnerabilities all of this
information may fall into the wrong
hands before customers or the public
have a chance to
respond all right so with exchange how
did he know if you were affected by the
by the exchange zero day attack well
unfortunately if you were running
microsoft exchange in an on-premise
server and it connected out to the
public internet there's a really good
chance that you were affected by this in
one form or another this means that all
the email data on the server and user
data on the server is potentially a risk
now the vulnerable code that was
exploited in this uh this particular
outbreak had been in place for over 10
years in the the exchange code base for
those who are counting that means it's
been out since at least 2011 and this
affected uh virgins 2010 2013 2016 2019
the entire fleet of exchange products
now once these exploits become or became
public
what we saw was a mass seeding event
this meant that every hacker on the
planet who now wanted to exploit these
probably did
this was going out to tens if not
hundreds of thousands of active servers
all across the country we were seeing
organizations being or at least
attempting to be compromised by multiple
threat actors at the same time
and really all you had to do was go on
to something like showdown and look for
exchange servers and that would give you
your attack list and it was a reasonably
simple exploit to execute everything was
pre-scripted so these these adversaries
became very very aggressive with their
tactics and how to break into these
servers
so again in response we had to start
with forensics preservation and this
this needs to be one of the very first
things that we think about it's often a
time consuming process nobody wants to
stop and do it but it's incredibly
important so first we need to
forensically image all of our exchange
servers uh we need to obtain the
volatile memory too because we want to
know active network connections and
active programs that were running on the
computer when this actually happened
and we want to preserve our network and
iis logs this is really important
because it's a potential business email
compromise and business email
compromises are serious business there
is a lot of sensitive information in
email there's a lot of recon information
these are future target lists it's
potential financial information medical
information personal information
a lot of stuff in there that we don't
want getting out
we then needed to go through and do a
check for unauthorized access so we
needed to see if the server was affected
and if so how deep that access went and
then we could determine the risk of both
email access and acquisition and network
compromise according to the fbi business
email compromise cases were the route of
1.8 billion dollars in cash losses last
year so the dollar amount is high and
the risk of a breach is high as well
which is why we saw customers microsoft
customers like the european banking
authority announcing breaches um and
there was a lot of fallout to this yeah
there's there certainly was uh next just
like solar winds we need to contain the
damage so we need to act well yesterday
on these things literally we cannot
leave these servers online if they're if
they're that one time everybody yeah
exactly uh so sisa and microsoft
released guidance for the proxy logon
remediation which was very helpful at
first to to get things offline uh but
again we we didn't know a ton about how
exactly this was happening when it
happened so we have our standard options
you know yank the power cable and yank
the network connection of your company's
exchange server so let's keep that one
in mind uh and then in this case because
we knew a couple of the uh the ttps that
were being used by the adversaries in
this case uh we we knew that domain wide
password reset was likely one of the
very very first things we wanted to do
we could see them using proctom to
capture passwords and and harvest
credentials uh but again there are some
major impacts that we need to consider
before any actions are taken this is
your exchange server so your email might
be down how does that affect your
organization again help desk calls
evidence destruction and operational
impact all need to be factored into how
we respond for these things
now this brings into threat hunting one
more time our our you know primary new
goal when we start into incident
response is to start threat hunting
microsoft and sisa published a great
list of indicators of compromise right
away remember microsoft actually had a
little bit of time to get these things
out the door before this really became
huge
and we had an example of a financial
services firm that we we worked with we
dropped carbon black onto their network
so we could look at their local computer
systems and their local network
infrastructure and then we did a very
targeted analysis of the iis logs from
their exchange servers to look for any
email system specific activities that
might indicate that the company had been
actually compromised and we did this uh
using some known happening behavioral
characteristics and when we were looking
we actually identified literally
hundreds of attempts to exploit the
vulnerable server and these were coming
from all across the world likely from
multiple different adversary groups some
were successful others were not i think
it all depended on the skill level of
the adversary that was going after the
server at that point in time but again
it was really eye-opening as to how
pervasive this threat actually was
so these are some of the indicators of
compromise that we were looking for with
the with the exchange vulnerability we
were looking for eight character aspx
files in the inet pub folders uh this
was an indication that with some
specific naming conventions and of
course the the time the uh shells were
installed that the exploit had actually
been successfully used and that there
was now a web webshell present on the
server we also again were looking for
encoded powershell activity uh and there
was there was a lot of that the problem
that we had here was so many people were
jumping in to do these investigations on
exchange servers that we had an
overwhelming amount of community
indicators of compromise being provided
and in a lot of cases those turned out
to be false positives it was people
seeing malicious activity where there
wasn't any because they were in such a
heightened state of alert so again we
need to vet those things it really
seemed like everybody and their mom was
releasing iocs even chile's bank
regulator
and another problem was that the iocs
kept changing so and that was partly
because the adversary's tactics kept
changing as well so many different
attackers were involved um ransomware
operators started taking advantage of
the exchange vulnerabilities many many
others we even saw law enforcement which
we'll get to in a moment um but again
those iocs kept evolving and responders
had to keep on top of that we did here's
a good example of another one of the
iocs that we we pulled from one of our
cases so this is an encoded powershell
that we saw or encoded powershell
command we saw running in the iis server
they're they're invoking a web shell
which is the support with a zero instead
of an o file uh and then executing what
uh what was later revealed to be a recon
attempt to get process information back
from the host and we saw multiple
different iterations of these exact
types of commands but they were things
that we could key into uh to determine
if the attack was successful and if it
was still happening which was really
important to know
we also wanted to look at post exploit
behavior uh and the thing i really want
to point out here is not just the list
of things they were doing but how they
were doing it so so we can see the
adversary using things like 7-zip we can
see them using the ps exec toolkit the
system turns tool kit from microsoft and
this is another one of those trends that
we're really starting to run into in ir
is that a lot of
adversaries once they reach into a
network are not using custom designed
malware to infect and recover data from
your network they're using commercial
tool kits and a lot of times they're
tool kits that the actual environment
that they're breaking into uses
regularly so again that blends into the
background it makes it really difficult
to tell when something is malicious and
when it's not if it's not clearly
defined like happening at 2am when the
office closes at 5 or something like
that so again something you really need
to watch out for
now microsoft was very helpful in the
exchange
in the exchange zero day attack and
released some very nice scripting that
we could use to one tell if the server
was uh was vulnerable to the compromise
if it had been compromised and then if
we chose to we could utilize a uh an
on-premise mitigation tool to identify
and remove the web shells from the
environment and kind of cut off that
initial point of access again this was
automated remediation but we had to be
really careful because this does delete
things from the system and if we're
deleting things we're potentially
deleting evidence from response again we
need to make sure that we're
we're preserving these things to the
best of our ability for that follow-on
investigation because we may need to
report a data breach because of it again
we need to we needed to apply emergency
patches and updates and the good thing
was that microsoft was prepared before
this was publicly announced the bad
thing was that the patches were not
available before many organizations got
hacked and after they announced it not
everybody was ready to immediately patch
their exchange server if you didn't
patch immediately you were likely hacked
so you want to have these conversations
ahead of time and decide are you going
to immediately deploy patches to
critical systems when an issue like this
occurs or are you going to be a later
adopter
in this case we also saw law enforcement
intervention so the fbi received a
secret court order to hack into i mean
there's no better word for it to hack
into organizations using these same
exploits and then remove the web shells
they then attempted to provide notice
they made their best effort so they're
pros and cons to this right matt oh yeah
of course i mean one i'm sure they had
the best intentions you know we're from
the government and here to help you uh
but uh
when when you have somebody coming into
your into your server and removing these
things a responder doesn't know if this
is the fbi or an adversary doing this so
it becomes kind of confusing for him at
that point also there's the potential
for evidence destruction and then we
look down the road i mean is something
like this going to happen again and what
are the future implications of this type
of this type of activity i think this
poses unique challenges for
investigators as well because
when you're analyzing access logs it's
hard to tell if something is if access
is initiated by a government agency or
by an adversary and you may only find
out about it days or weeks or months
down the road yeah exactly
so plan for elevated risks long term
again like in the solar winds attack
email theft can be very impactful you
may see financial fraud or targeted
follow-on attacks and this could impact
your vendor or your organization
okay so now that we've gone through our
checklist with solarwinds the supply
chain attack and with microsoft exchange
a mass zero day vulnerability let's get
back to our recent cassaya ransomware
attacks first of all this was announced
on the 4th of july weekend that this
remote monitoring and management
software was
had a major vulnerability
uh this happened fourth of july weekend
was this a coincidence probably not
probably not at lng we call friday's
forensics friday because so many hackers
are deploying ransomware after business
hours on a friday according to fireeye
76 of the time ransomware is executed
outside normal work hours so 27 of the
time on the weekends and 49 of the time
after hours on weekdays so think about
who is on call for your organization
who's going to be monitoring over 4th of
july weekend and what kind of decisions
are they empowered to make also talk
with your key suppliers that you rely on
are your msps monitoring threat
intelligence how quickly are they going
to notify you and are they going to take
action msp communication is absolutely
key
as a supplier can a software vendor's
communication
now in this case we had some interesting
impacts uh surrounding disclosure as we
often do so the timeline of the
vulnerability detection and notification
is as shown here so the vulnerabilities
were detected by the dutch institute for
vulnerability disclosure in early april
of 2021 and at that time they discovered
at least seven vulnerabilities they
pulled a list and discovered at least 2
200 vulnerable vulnerable systems and
they provided all this information to
the software vendor cassaya so that
that's nice that they were there to
support cassaya and cassaya worked very
collaboratively with the researchers
according to the research team now the
researchers gave them a 90-day timeline
on the disclosure and on april 10th and
may 8th cassaya released patches for
four of those vulnerabilities but the
remaining three were not slated for
actual uh correction until july they
were working diligently on them
according to the researchers but and
they were just about to be released when
the attackers struck and took advantage
of those so uh the timing on that
honestly is a little bit suspicious and
it should really make us think about
again who has access to information
about those vulnerabilities because
hackers are always looking to take
advantage before a patch is released
whenever
often we have some challenges in
communication with suppliers so you
really need to think about what to
expect
in terms of your communication matt do
you want to share an earlier case
involving rival and a managed service
provider yeah of course in 2019 uh rival
took over an msp that serviced dental
facilities specifically this is an msp
out of colorado uh they demanded seven
hundred thousand dollars for a master
decrypter from the msp uh who initially
refused payment uh odds are good they
probably paid a little bit farther down
the road but they were very tight-lipped
about the entire thing and didn't want
to share info so as a responder we had a
really hard time getting any indicators
of compromise or any assistance from the
msp at that point so again it brings up
a very important point do you know what
your supplier is going to do do you know
how they're going to behave in the case
that something like this happens and if
not it probably should be something that
you have a discussion with them about
yup exactly
also think about where you get your
information from immediately after the
cassaya attacks criminals started
pretending that they were your partners
so um cassaya came out with a warning
and said watch out spammers baby may be
making phone calls claiming to be a
cassaya partner reaching out to help
they're also using news about the
cassette incident to send out fake email
notifications that appear to be caseah
updates and you can see one of those in
the screenshot here where there's an
adversary sending out spam pretending
it's a microsoft update to protect
against ransomware and it fixes a
vulnerability in cassaya so never mind
that this makes no sense people do fall
for these or at least click on the link
and if they do it's a cobalt strike
installer yeah
so how do you contain the damage again
this is a standard part of our checklist
unfortunately um in this case really the
main way to contain it right off the bat
was to immediately shut down your vsa
server and cassaya announced this and
said it's critical that you do this
immediately because one of the first
things the attacker does is shut off
administrative access to the vsa yeah so
you got to proactively do it yourself of
course that is not so easy
to shut off your remote management
software when you're trying to remotely
manage your network so again a lot of
challenges
we also saw them
hoping to roll out a patch unlike the
microsoft case the patch was not ready
when news of the cassette vulnerability
emerged because
criminals had taken advantage of it and
it was a ransomware deployment and when
they were attempting to release the
patches they ran into multiple
unforeseen delays so that time frame
kept changing and as we've seen in
previous cases even if the patches do
get rolled out there's no guarantee that
they will fully remediate the issue
there could potentially be other
vulnerabilities and you need to
understand what is your organization's
policy what's your msps policy regarding
applying those patches
do you want to be the guinea pig or not
okay so this will happen again hackers
want the most return on their investment
and they figured out that if they target
widely used software or they target
service providers they can have a
widespread impact and get the most bang
for for their buck we've also seen that
breaches lead to more breaches so the
information and access that the
attackers have gained from previous
hacks can help them to launch more
effective attacks in the future
so be careful
um sorry for the image matt you now owe
me a bottle of whiskey
we had a little bet that i couldn't use
that image in this presentation
all right adapt your dfir processes how
do we do that number one make sure that
you're monitoring threat intelligence as
we talked about evaluate your risk um
first responders need to be doing this
when a new alert comes out you want to
think about conducting forensic
preservation it may not necessarily be
important in all cases but in many cases
it is you have to contain the damage
before you have extensive information
about the problem which again is its own
challenge threat hunting needs to be a
regular part of our incident response in
these types of cases also emergency
patches and updates are become going to
become the norm in supply chain
compromises and these mass zero day
vulnerabilities and finally plan for
those elevated risks this is the new
norm my name is sherry davidoff and i am
matt durin we are from lmg security
check out our upcoming book ransomware
and cyber extortion and our podcast
breaking breeches and drop us a line on
linkedin if you have any questions