[Music]
hello all this is nicholas jolly i will
be co-presenting this talk with sarah
moore we both work at the microsoft
security response center vmsrc i'm based
in the uk in cheltenham and tsar is in
israel we are very happy to be talking
about cherry today
so why are we here and why cherry well
the short answer to this question is
that we are haunted by memory safety
issues as you can see on this graph
which represents the number of msrt
cases for memory safety issues that we
had over the past five years the trend
isn't really going down memory safety
issues is something that we are going to
see
in the years to come
why is that because enforcing memory
safety this is a non-trivial problem
there are solutions to this such as safe
languages like rust or net but the
problem with this is that this hardly
scales it's
very difficult and obviously very costly
to rewrite everything in the safe
language so what else can we do well we
can push for more mitigations but the
problem with mitigations is that at the
end of the day they only make
the attacker's life a bit harder those
mitigations they are rarely a silver
bullet and each year there are events or
competitions like for example pontoon
that remind us that we are losing the
battle we make the attacker's life a bit
harder but
in the end it's still possible to
exploit memory safety issues so what
else can we consider well there are
hardware solutions
something like cherry for example and
that's why we're here today
so in the following slides i will be
assuming that you've never heard about
cherry so we'll be giving a very short
introduction
and then we'll be talking about some
vulnerabilities and attacks that we've
tried against cherry
and finally we'll be talking about some
work in progress and we'll be giving a
few words
in conclusion regarding our research
all right
let's go
so what is cherry a cherry has been
developed by folks from the cambridge
university and sri international with
special safety in mind from the very
beginning it extends a traditional isas
such as arm mips or wrist five
with new instructions to provide special
safety
so in this research in our research
i should mention that we've only looking
we've only looked at the mips and arm
implementations the army implementation
will be referred as morale in the next
slides
so this new model introduces a new data
type called capability so this is a very
central point uh and we're going to talk
about capability uh
for in in the center presentation so pay
attention to this
so capability you can see this as an
extended pointer a pointer with extra
information
and such capability
takes exactly 16 bytes
in memory plus one bit for a tag so in
total this is 129 bits so the tag is
very important this is the bit that
protects the capability the capability
cannot be forged it is unforgeable so if
you try to dereference a capability that
doesn't take set
you will trigger a fault
if you try to overwrite a capability
you will instantly clear the tag
so this tag is super important
so obviously cherry is a bit more than
that and if you're curious or if you
want to know more i encourage you to
have a look at the cherry documentation
provided by the commerce university it's
super interesting
so coming back to those capabilities
what can we find in them well we can
find of course the virtual address so
this is the pointer that we commonly see
every day when we're dealing with c
we can find a few other fields such as
the permissions so this is the
permissions to
to the object pointed by the address is
it readable is it writeable is it
executable i remember there is another
field called type so this represents
whether the capability is sealed or not
sealed means that the capability some
capabilities can be made immutable or
non-dereferenceable for example so you
can find this by reading the o type
field
and the last field that you can find in
your capability is a length
so this length is represented using
compressed bounds
and because of the compression for large
allocations uh just slightly more memory
can be sometimes allocated and this in
this very specific case it's still
possible to get some out of bounds
access but those accesses will never
lead to some memory safety issues that's
because just a bit more memory has been
allocated for capability this is just a
note but it's important to
to have that in mind the next slide is
going to show you what's a capability uh
you when you're debugging a program so
on the left side you can see uh
traditional registers and on the right
side you can see a bunch of capabilities
so for example this one is c3 which
points to some memory that is read and
writeable
so where are we using capabilities well
the answer to that is pretty much
everywhere
when you're programming and when you are
allocating some objects for example
whether those are in the stack or in the
hip you'll be dealing with a capability
if you're defining some function
pointers your will be you will be
dealing with a capability again
and what about and also good stuff
well you will be dealing also with a
capability so say that you're you're
doing uh stuff
in the stack for example then you will
be dealing with a capability say that
you are
doing some c prospers programming and
you are dealing with some zippers press
objects that have some v table
here again you'll be dealing with some
capabilities
so when you're programming
the compiler will under most of the
capabilities that the program will be
using
and for under the hood staff this will
be the responsibility of the loader to
create those capabilities so obviously
this model
suggests that the programmer is aware of
specific changes
changes like for example casts
casting a pointer to an integer is
something allowed in cherry however the
contrary is a bit more difficult you
cannot for example cast from hint to
pointer this is not possible what you
can do is you can cast from in pointer t
to pointer that's a load
and something also that uh we need to
have in mind is that mem copy or memo
operations are tag preserving which
means that if you try to copy a bunch of
capabilities from one place to another
then the tag bit will be preserved
it's very important to have this concept
when you think about exploitation
so this is a short slide to show you
what's a capability in
in the compiler after
the program has been compiled so those
three lines of of c code
shows a buffer overflow so here we have
a stack buffer of exactly 10 bytes that
has been defined
and you can see that a special
instruction here is setting the length
of the capability to 16 bytes and if you
try to
write out of the bounds of these
capabilities then you'll get a thought a
secret if you were trying to read out of
bounds of this capability you get again
a secret
so this is almost the same example but
this time with the hip so here we
haven't shown
the location where the length of the
capability is set but this is basically
the responsibility of the allocator here
in this example of malloc malloc will
set the length of the capability and
then the program will use it and here
since we are trying to write out amount
of capabilities will be triggering a
secret
so if you've followed so far and if you
like to write exploit now is a good time
to be to start worry about sharing
why well cherry has two main impacts the
first impact obviously is for special
safety
out-of-bound vulnerabilities those are
no longer a security concern they are
deterministically mitigated which means
no buffer overflows no stack overflows
no things like that
and the other consequence is that one
cannot manufacture a pointer so think
about attacks like rope where
the attacker is trying to craft some
arbitrary pointers those are no longer
possible
so in in summary cherry is a game
changer for the attacker
trying to exploit a memory safety issues
is something that is much much much
harder for the attacker to do let's see
a quick example some quick example so if
you have a primitive where you can
corrupt a few bits or perhaps the
entirety of a monitor then cherry is
going to raise a tag bit violation
so this violation won't happen on the
moment that you grab the pointer it will
happen on the moment you're already
referencing it
if you try to uh write out of bounds
read or write out of bounds of a
of a buffer you will get this time a
length violation the only corner case
where it would still be possible to get
some buffer overflow is when you're
trying uh to uh overflow from some intra
objects so typically some c struct where
you'd be using a buffer followed by an
integer or a pointer or something like
that in that case
it would require a special compiler flag
to get rid of the issues
so what else well there is isn't only
special safety um the problem uh is that
there are other issues such as such as a
temporal safety issues like double
freeze uh use after freeze etc those are
still theoretically exploitable with
sharing
there are other things also such as type
confusions or uninitialized
memory vulnerabilities and actually sar
in the next slide is going to give you
a very interesting example of this
and so now i'm going to leave you with
sar who will be talking about those
vulnerabilities one last word uh
cherry is very good at mitigating
exploits it makes x it makes writing
exploits
tasks much much much harder than what it
was before
all right sar it's up to you now
thank you so much nico for this great
introduction now
so let's discuss some of the attacks
that are still possible on cherries
about the platforms so as sure i say it
does not mitigate type confusions at the
architectural level we can still create
type confusion scenarios between
different simple space objects and this
of course is the very powerful
expectation primitive of calling
arbitrarily existing methods of
different objects v tables and from this
we can of course scroll up some
important metadata to escalate
privileges and to trigger some
information disclosures all of that
actually reminds me the famous park
bypass that was found in objective c and
relied on the fact that the isa pointer
was not protected by pak
this is from the amazing talks and
sailor head at 36 c3 and as you can see
and before the pack era we could just
corrupt the ici printer and fake the
entire class descriptor with all of the
vtables function pointers and basically
everything and this just gave us the
primitive of gaining full control over
the pc register and jump to an arbitrary
address now given park this is no longer
possible of course because all of the
function pointers and all of the
references to code are signed by pac
that being said the ic printer itself
was not sunway pack at the beginning it
is today by the way and because it was
attacked pointer and therefore we could
still corrupt the isa pointer and make
it point to a fake class descriptor that
contains valid legitimate v tables and
and this of course give us the
explanation primitive of calling
arbitrary existing methods in different
objective-c objects this kind of type of
confusions attack are very powerful and
they are still possible on cherry
okay now let's discuss exploitation of
cherry isa from in high level point of
view
so we all know how this classic circle
of life works right we find some of them
zero day we shape some memory layout we
trigger the vulnerability we do
corruption of some target structure and
from this point we gain
arbitrary or relative read write
primitives and from this point it's a
game over it's a clear win now given
cherry this phase of gaining relative
arbitrary right primitive is actually
kind of broken in the sense that if you
want to gain a truly generic arbitrary
read writes you need to gain a
capability with a link that spans then
the entire virtual outdoor space and
there is no good reason the allocator
will generate you such a capability
please note that this makes the
allocator to be in the sense some
of the part of the tcp of the trusted
components because the allocator
actually uses dedicated instructions to
change and edit and modify existing
capabilities so we really need to make
sure that the allocator cannot be
compromised and that it checks the
integrity of its own metadata before it
uses it okay great so cherry introduces
a new restriction right we cannot craft
painters and we cannot fake pointers in
any way this of course applies to
everything function pointers v tables um
return addresses structures buffers
literally everything we can even know
and longer though and partial corruption
which is a very elegant and convenient
trick and for instance if you want to
deal with slr and you don't want to lick
the entropy bits so you can just corrupt
the lsb part of a pointer and you can
move it backward or forward in memory
such attacks are not possible on cherry
at all because even if you flip one bits
in a capability you clear the tag and
you will just trigger a cherry exception
when you will try to dereference this
capability okay so what we can still do
is we can move an existing capability
from one place to another and this of
course opens a pretty wide range of
opportunities for us and for instance if
we want to exploit and use after free
bug
does not mitigate temporal safety at the
architectural level as well
so we can just replace a structure a
with a structure b in memory and we can
choose our structures such that the v
tables or some other pointers will be at
the same offsets and we can treat these
pointers differently this kind of type
confusions attack are very powerful and
they can be converted into a very
exploitation
primitives
okay now let's talk about slr this is
really fun slr means nothing on cherry
and because we cannot corrupt or fake
pointers in any way there is zero value
for us to know the layout of the virtual
address space right we really don't care
where the star keep and leaps are
located because we cannot even use this
information in our exploits to begin
with and and this is of course by design
when people build the model of cherry
they try to create a threat model where
we can assume that we can give the
attackers the entire layout of all of
the virtual address space and it
shouldn't help them at all
i really do want to make a very
important distinction here
between bypassing slr and generic
information disclosures because while we
really don't care about people leaking
capabilities and know the layout of the
virtual address space we really do carry
and we don't want attackers to be able
to leak secret or confidential data
across different security domains we
even have some models such as the home
sandbox for windows that rely on the
fact that you cannot leak secrets in the
homes and box for windows for example if
you lick the port names from outside the
sandbox you can escape the sandbox by
design so we really do care about that
okay now let's go to the exploitation
so we have a
port of jsc over pure capability cherry
this is very convenient uh we use that
in our first offensive research on
cherry mips and we still use that in our
research on morelo which is cherry on
arm javascript engines are just a great
place to export vulnerabilities in right
we have a script in language which is
highly convenient for exploitation and
ever since morello we have jeets which
is fantastic because jit compilers are
have been proven to be a very rich place
for bugs and for security issues so it
just looks like the right place to start
from and i want to start with an amazing
bar an uninitialized
stock in jsc full credit goes to bruno
and then to lucatodesco the one and only
who did an amazing job exploiting this
vulnerability and all of this
understanding of the root cause is based
on their work so let's see what's going
on here so as we all know registers is a
limited resource right
and
in many cases we need to free up some
registers when we have no ones available
and in order to do so we need to
implement
some kind of a context switch
we need to take all of the values that
are currently stored in the registers
and just
store them to some piece of memory start
hip or whatever and then later on when
we want to continue the execution we
need to restore all of these values from
memory into the corresponding registers
and then keep going
and in many cases these values are being
written to the stack
okay great now the jsc register
allocator makes this very interesting
assumption that allocations happen
unconditionally and this is interesting
because if we have some flow in jsc that
has a conditional branch and then does a
register allocation
it means that we can skip this register
allocation and therefore we may skip all
of these rights into the stack and this
is very problematic because if there
will be some flow later on uh that will
try to use a value that is corresponding
to a supposedly spilled register from
before we just created here a scenario
of using of uninitialized value from the
stack
and this gets super interesting because
we can use the jit compiler to compile
some javascript functions that fetch a
pointer or in our case a capability on
cherry a pointer from the stack that
points to some js object of a certain
type and you can use our bug in order to
make the stack address to contain an
uninitialized value
and therefore we can shape this stack
and upfront to drop their capability a
valid capability that points to a
different js object of a different type
and this is how we can convert in a very
elegant way this uninitialized use from
the stack into a type confusion
okay great so let's see some code so
this function com compile string slice
is the function
that contains the bug and as you can see
we have our conditional branch and then
we have some register allocation and of
course this register allocation may need
to write some data into the stack and
but if we will take the conditional
branch we just keep the register
allocation and all of this area on the
stack will just remain uninitialized
okay great now we said that we can
control then initialize and shape the
stack right so let's see how we can do
it this is actually super simple if you
want to write some data to the stack
let's just call a function which
allocate it on stack frame and then have
this function to write some data into
its own local stack frame and then when
this function returns all of the data
that we just wrote to the stack simply
remains there until something else will
come and override it
so in our case we can simply implement
two different javascript functions of
one and opt that are basically identical
and we just use them with different kind
of objects we just pass them as
arguments capabilities that points to
two different js objects and so in this
case for example let's call opt one with
capability that points to a js object of
type a and then we will call opt with a
type b and then because of the bug opt
will fetch from the stack a capability
that it believes that points to type b
because we use the jit compiler and we
train this function to be compiled with
type b but
opt one actually wrote something to this
and to this uninitialized value on the
stack and this something is a capability
that points to type a and this is how we
can con create this type confusion
okay now let's see the plc and actually
we can do
more in this plc we can convert the type
confusion to be out of bound read in a
very simple way and great vlog and great
curse to luca for this exploit again
so what we have is just a lot of useless
accesses to the stock to make sure that
we have the stack frame that we want and
then we need to do a type proof this is
very important we need to fetch for some
field in the object because this will
tell the data flow graph that it can
emit some structure checks and this is
super important because we have a type
confusion and these structural checks
may break
the exploits and it could cache us and
then we do the bug trigger we call slice
on a string which calls compile string
slice the function that contains the bug
and this creates the uninitialized on
the stack and then we call get by offset
but this get by offsets with big
it will be called on an arbitrarily type
red from the stack instead of on a
proven type
okay
so this is super simple let's see how we
can complete this out of one grid so we
just need a
to define some
some objects and we just create an
object with five fields and then another
object with four fields and then we need
to repeat this second object because we
have an out of bound read here so we
want two continuous allocations on the
heap
and
different types on jsc are actually
allocated in different areas and then
we'll just try to fetch to read a field
a from obj2
but because of the type confusion we
actually use the offset of a in obj1
which is clearly clearly an out of bound
for obj2 okay great fantastic um
now let's talk for a minute
and talk about this that it's pretty
well that we're standing here and
talking about out of bound on sharing
because we said the cherry i say does
mitigate special safety in the
architectural level so yes it does
through and cherry does a wonderful job
in deterministically mitigate special
safety at the
architectural level but if you want to
get all of these guarantees from the
architecture you need to use it right
for instance you absolutely need to make
sure that your allocators for star keep
in global set the accurate bounds in all
of the couple in all of the capabilities
they return
and as it turns out in the prototype
that we were
working on the cherry bsd over morelo
all of the allocators for start keeping
global did a fantastic job
but the allocator for the jsl heap did
not and it just sets 16k for bands for
all of the allocations that it's
um that it's like returns and this is
why this technique works on morelo just
as it works on ubuntu x64 or like ios or
any other platform and now this actually
was fixed in a
dev branch of webkit over cherry so we
can actually see the difference on the
left hand side you can see the main
branch
with the bug and you can see that all of
the capabilities have a 16k for bounce
and on the right hand side you can
simply see that all of the capabilities
have accurate bounds
okay great and this is the commit a
fantastic
job by brett from the university of
cambridge okay now we have a very stable
out of boundary right so let's see what
we can do with it we already agreed that
asl is out of the picture it's
absolutely not interesting and this is a
good time to talk about structure ids
every type in jsc has a unique structure
id a tilted
bits that are stored as the first deload
of every object
and attackers supposedly need to know a
valid structure id in order to fake
objects in memory because there are many
structure checks that make sure that
every time that we are about to operate
on some objects
we need to make sure that this object is
of the type that we are expecting from
it to be
uh
and
back in the day it was actually very
easy to guess and predict these
structure ideas you could just spray a
lot of like different types and objects
and then you could guess that for
instance structured thousands is of a
certain type and it works fantastic and
everybody did it and because everybody
did it apple added a randomization that
called structure radio randomization
that does exactly what its name suggests
it just randomizes all of the structure
ideas and this is a very good example
for mitigation that it would be very
interesting for us to bypass on cherry
because even though there are many
mitigations that we might remove given
cherry such as acelav
and some others this is a very good
example of a mitigation that we still
want to keep around
because it make a faking structures more
difficult
okay so
let's try to leak some structure id and
this is actually something that you can
see in many webkit exploits today most
of the exploits just opened with
a licking a valid
saxophone structure ready okay and this
is the commits that added the
randomization of the structure ideas so
this is the the part of uh likable plc
that
did compile the javascript functions as
in and and as you can see we have the
definitions for all of the objects and
we set a pattern here in objects to an
victim so we could identify them in
memory and this is on morelo and you can
simply see that obj2 and victim are
allocated continuously on the hip and
the first deal in both of these objects
is the 32-bit structure ids and clearly
we can understand it if we'll just
trigger the art of madrid
from obj2
to victim we'll just fetch and read the
structure id
of victim and this is exactly what
happens and and now we will go back to
nico which will show us the second
vulnerability and the second exploit
thank you
thank you sir that was super interesting
so we first
had a look at cherry in summer 2020 and
we looked particularly at jsc on cherry
bsd on actually cherry mips
the question that we had was that we
knew that sherry was very good at
mitigating special safety issue but we
knew that there was still a concern with
temporal safety so our question was
provided with special safety would we
still be able to exploit a temporal
safety issue
so to try to solve this question we
looked we looked at jc and we wanted to
have a look at some cvs and see if we
could still exploit those
problem that we faced is that
well one of one of the problem with
with jsc on mips is that jit the jit is
unsupported
and there were something else like the
gc garbage collection that wasn't really
working so we couldn't really trigger
some use after three issues so instead
we went for the easy way and we
introduced a stack user factor free
stack uaf
so why this kind of issue the reason is
a few years ago we had a bunch of test
cases in chakra and the scenario here
was that in some cases it was possible
with the jit to allocate an object in
the stack and because of the bug in
chakra it would be possible for an
attacker later to uh
to use that reference and so this would
give him the ability to read and write
stuff in the stack so this was a super
powerful primitive so we were a bit
curious about those issues and we wanted
to see how far cherry
would be able to mitigate those
so to do that we decided to introduce a
bug
in the era buffer so something very
simple so here we just chant a couple of
lines and so instead of dealing with the
hip the array buffer would now be
dealing with the stack
so a trigger would be super simple so we
would just allocate a normal array
buffer and then we would slice it and
that would give a view to the stack
to the attacker so what can we do with
that well if you know sar
you know that once you've got your read
and write permittee well it's game over
so we want to get to the same state but
here we have cherry to deal with
so first what can what
where do we want to go first we want to
see if we can copy a capability from one
place to another without losing the tag
the tag bits
so at first i thought that this would be
easy i would just have to use
some known types in javascript that
would be using 128 bits
the problem with the gic at least on
mips is that there is no
such objects that uh that exists at my
at most
float takes
64 bits and so if you try to copy two
floats then obviously you will lose the
the tag bit
so this proved to be a bit more
difficult than expected
so by looking for move online copy the
source code we noticed two methods typed
our reset and slice
and it turns out that when
the destination and source have the same
type it's possible to enter this
particular
piece of code and here as you can see
there is a main move
so which means that
if we are
using set uh typed reset with two array
buffers that have the same type then
we'll be uh able to copy a capability
from
one array buffer located in the stack to
another array buffer in the heap so
that's already a good step
now can we read from anywhere well not
exactly anywhere you cannot read from
4141.41 for example this is not possible
with cherry you have to read from a
valid capability
so what can we do for example we can
read
capabilities in the stack but can we
really read from those capabilities well
it turns out that with re-entrancy
applied on the length argument
we could for example trigger again the
same issue and this time alter will
change the sorcery capability
so we would be
triggering twice the issue once to get
into
the set function
then we would trigger around 20 and then
we would trigger again the same issue to
overwrite the source array and
in that state we will be able to read
from anywhere and i mean from any valid
capability so this is already a good
step
now can we write
anything anywhere
well the answer to that is likely i'm
saying likely because i didn't already
explore
this possibility it turns out that the
bug that we introduced was already quite
powerful we were able to write things in
the stack so we were able to correct
pointers no need to be able to write
something anywhere but if you look at
set or slides it's
likely that you'd be able to do exactly
the same thing
so now that we have that in mind where
are we going so ideally we would want to
reach a function that would
that would allow the attacker to execute
an arbitrary command something like
system for example where can we find a
system libsy.system it turns out that
there is one place where we can find it
it's a cherry capability table and it
also turns out that the cherry cabbage
table is used everywhere by the compiler
you're going to see tons of references
to it in the stack
so this makes it super convenient for
the attacker you cannot
you can just read a pointer to a cherry
capability table and then traverse that
pointer up to finding a pointer to
system
so this is what we are going to do we
are going to traverse enough capability
up to reading system and then we'll find
a way to get rc
so how to get rc so one could for
example just try to overwrite a return
address
with a capability to system but the
problem with that is that because of the
current convention uh system would use
its first argument in a register and so
if you try to overwrite a return address
then you'd also have to make sure that
this particular register would be set to
uh your uh
your your own value
and because of that it makes things uh
really hard
to to implement it might be possible but
definitely harder so what we did instead
is that we targeted a saved c plus plus
object
in the stack so an object with a v table
and here it would be super easy actually
to fake a v table you can with cherry
you just see you can as i said in the
beginning of the table is just again a
capability a capability to some other
capabilities so something that is easy
to to achieve with uh with an array
buffer so we would just create an array
buffer and then add some offset in this
array buffer copy the capabilities
to system and that would be rv table
something really easy in the end
and so in the end we just need to
overwrite two pointers two capabilities
in the stack one for dc plus plus object
and one for
for the argument
and then we'll just wait for the stack
to and win to execute or payload
and so this is a result i agree with you
that this isn't very impressive but at
least it works you can see a ping to uh
some some websites executed just from
loaded uh a script with jsc
and now i'm going to hand over again to
sar who will be talking about some work
in progress and we'll be concluding
thank you thank you so much nico this
was super interesting okay so now let's
talk about how we can present some
hardening of cherry so as we saw cherry
isa
gives us known for non-foldable
references to virtual memory and bounce
and permission check at the
architectural level which is amazing
and
if we just use cherry aware compiler and
runtime we could actually achieve um
deterministic mitigation for all of the
special safety variants and it's
fantastic and this means that we just
left with temple safety type safety
allocator safety and probably some other
stuff that we need to care about
and we just want to mention here that
there are some fantastic and really
impressive work in progress projects
they try to present software solutions
for these backlashes a very good example
is cornucopia which is capability
revocation it's an extension
for the virtual
memory subsystem in cherry bcd and it's
um
it's simply
represents a
deterministic mitigation
for c and c plus plus heap temporal
safety issues mostly focused on heap use
after freeze and we don't have time to
talk about all of the details but there
is a great paper that you can check out
and there is actually the code in a
dedicated branch of cherry bsd that
implements capability
revocation so please check it out
another very important example is jit
jit is always a very sensitive and very
very dangerous place and for instance we
do want to make sure that we can enforce
right so x right we don't want to have
one physical page that is both writable
and executable at the same time so
instead of just having two different
virtual mappings that the first one is
read right and the second one is it
executes we can just have two different
capabilities the first one is read right
and the other one is executed and it's
very elegant and this is very good
example for the fact that cherry isa
is also provide us very
very like unique set of abilities in
hardware that we can take advantage on
from software in order to implement a
more elegant and stable software
solutions
and and this is for instance a
commit from brett from the
university of cambridge that implements
this idea of just like having and
capabilities that are only
recreatable or executable in the
executable allocator okay so some
takeaways cherry isa
mitigates a very wide range of
backlashes at the architectural level
fantastic and cherry i say significantly
like raises the uh the the bar for
exploitation uh
in a very elegant in a very unique way
and it's very important to keep in mind
that cherry offers a lot of abilities in
hardware just like we said that you can
take advantage on from software
and it's very important to keep in mind
that it's only the beginning there is so
much to innovate research and to develop
in
in this area so we absolutely hope that
all of you will like jump by and we'll
try to help to make cherry and um better
and
stronger and now it's time for shout
outs and this project could not have
been done without an amazing force for
many different teams and organizations
msrc msr cambridge and like many other
partners we cannot mention all of you
but thank you so much
it was super fun to work together and to
collaborate on this project here are
some references that you can follow on
cherry and thank you