[Music]
welcome to securing open source software
end to end at massive scale together my
name is jennifer furnik and i'm joined
by my colleague christopher robinson
in this presentation we'll be speaking
about securing the open source ecosystem
so to begin we'll share a little bit
about ourselves myself from the
perspective of a security researcher and
as someone who in a past life
design and ran cryptographic systems
that protect tens of billions of dollars
in daily transactions and crop from the
perspective of someone who helped
coordinate some of the most impactful
vulnerability disclosures in our
industry over the last seven to eight
years we'll also share lessons learned
from these experiences in coordinating
vulnerability disclosure we'll talk
about why securing the open source
ecosystem matters will share several
challenges to securing open source
software at scale and we'll offer a
threat model of the open source
ecosystem because securing open source
software is way more than preventing
malicious commits we'll also talk about
why we believe that the insecurity of
the open source ecosystem is
accelerating based on things like the
speed at which new vulnerabilities are
exploited in the wild
the increased use of supply chain
attacks and advances in computer science
that make exploitation
faster and easier than ever finally
we'll discuss techniques for reducing
vulnerabilities at scale
the status quo for coordinated work to
improve the security of the open source
ecosystem and share how the open source
security foundation is scaling the
efforts of security researchers as well
as share a bit about some of the
resources and opportunities to get
involved with us
um so my name is jennifer fernick as
mentioned i'm the global head of
research at the security research and
consulting firm ncc group i'm also one
of the co-founding board and technical
advisory committee members of the open
source security foundation
in a past life i was a cryptographer and
a quantum computer scientist and
previously was the security architect
and later
led a large security team at a global
bank and my background academically is
in quantum computing systems engineering
and artificial intelligence
thanks jennifer i'm krobe i've had the
great privilege to work within open
source and security for a great many
years
i've had the
honor of working on a lot of high
profile critical coordinations within
the community and within
the larger technology industry
i've worked with red hat product
security for six years before i came
here to the intel corporation
i currently am the working group leader
for the vulnerability disclosure working
group and the developer best practices
working group part of open sss and i've
you know done some stuff i've seen some
things
crazy crazy and we're going to share
some of that insight today
the open ssf is a assembly of
very prestigious and very humble folks
great and small organizations big and
small we've all come together focused on
the mission of securing open source
software for the larger community
benefit
we're going to start off today where i'd
like you to imagine a world
imagine a world where there's a security
researcher they find what they feel is a
critical bug in an open source
cryptographic library and they want to
see it get fixed they feel
greatly that they need to participate in
a process called coordinated
vulnerability disclosure
so they search around the internet
looking to try to find the developer or
the maintainer and there is it's not
very easy there's no website there's not
any centralized place where this
development team
hangs out eventually the researcher
finds out that there's a github repo
that unfortunately hasn't been updated
in about three years
not deterred
uh they continue searching and they find
on a mailing server a mailing list that
another project is using that same
cryptographic library's name in some of
their posts so they reach out to those
developers and they find out yes indeed
this team forked that original project
they found a lot of good value in it
unfortunately these folks they aren't
security people
they know some people that do security
but they're not security people
themselves so they ask can we include
some extra people they reach out in irc
in their mailing list to try to find
additional people to kind of help out
figure out this problem
now on that mailing list happens to be a
group called
megacorporation megacorporation sells a
commercial security package that uses
this library and they're very excited
that the reporter found this issue and
they want to work with them on you know
vetting out the proof of concept kind of
triaging what the impact is
they will get issue a cve for this it's
going to be great
so they say give us a little bit of time
we'll get back to you
the researcher waits and waits and waits
and
they reach back out and eventually
megacorp says yeah you know
this is an issue we acknowledge it's
pretty bad but unfortunately we have a
new product release coming up within the
next six months we can't issue the
release today can we wait until uh that
product's release kind of coordinated
around then
researcher isn't super happy about that
but uh you know they agree and then mega
corp also mentions that there are
several other major vendors they're
aware of the uses library that they want
to include in kind of the eventual
remediation
at the same time around this time that
fork developer that original development
team they had some free time and a lot
of coffee and they said hey you know
we've figured out the fix we've posted
it upstream everything's great kind of
ruining the not ruining but you know
stepping over the kind of agreed-upon
disclosure timeline and this is where
things start to spiral out of control
the internet starts reporting that there
are exploits of several major vendors
that use this a couple of them actually
seem to pick it up in a major container
platform and that image was downloaded
thousands of times in the last month and
you know a domestic telecommunications
company picked that up and now they are
being reported as vulnerable
a huge internet
uh
magazine
puts out a headline cracked crypto
creatively crumbled by boffins for mega
headaches the internet's on fire
it seems to gotten pretty bad pretty
quick
or
another scenario is
that researcher never was able to find
anyone to report that flaw to
they try they eventually post the their
exploit into their get repository they
write a blog about it and you know they
get a prime talking spot at a major
security conference let's call it
hat black for example because at the end
of the day no one was able to help them
and you know that's where we're here to
talk about today
while this was all kind of based in
a thought experiment it really
a lot of this stuff happens more
frequently than you think
back in 2018 there was a
developer of uh open source library and
essentially you know they
didn't see a lot
of value in continuing to maintain it
and some
random stranger on the internet said hey
you know i'd like to help out i'll
pick up maintaining this and the
developer said you know what this guy
mailed me i don't get anything for
maintaining this module and i don't even
use it anymore have him for years so he
let this complete stranger
start to maintain it and at first
everything seemed fine but over a series
of commits
this
maintained this new maintainer was found
out that they were secretly baking in a
back door to do bitcoin mining as for
users of this module
so this incidence these types of things
can happen a lot more than you think
let's reflect back to the granddaddy of
them all heartbleed it was a very
popular open source library
and
still to this day is and it's basically
it helps with cryptography on the
internet
uh
you know at the time this
researcher found this problem and there
were something like half a million
servers on the internet that were
potentially vulnerable so the public
disclosure happened on april 7 2014
and just a couple months later in june
there only were 300 and there's still
300 and 900 000 of these devices that
were potentially vulnerable
flash forward three years after that
that number dropped to 144 000
and even just a few years ago in july of
2019 over 91 000 devices were still
vulnerable to this
very public
very severe
problem and kind of thinking about the
issue
at the time
about half a million of these secure
servers that ran internet banking online
commerce
were potentially vulnerable to having
their servers private keys or session
cookies or passwords taken
and to think about it the root cause of
the issue was you had two incredibly
skilled open source developers that
worked kind of full time on this project
and that was it and you had thousands
upon thousands of downstream consumers
that were leveraging this work
but these you had two folks that were
basically responsible to develop
maintain test and review about half a
million lines of code more work than is
feasible for a team of two that really
they
weren't paid to do it and that is the
kind of the crux of a lot of our
problems here
the security of open source our theory
here is the security of open source is
the security of everything
a lot of research has happened over the
last several years to show that free and
open source software
has a substantial impact on
the global technology landscape anywhere
between 80 and 90 percent of modern
software uses
open source
looking at those things
a report recently found about 84 percent
of these code bases had at least one
vulnerability with the average being
about 158 depending on those larger code
bases
and thinking about it the average age of
some of these libraries in between when
they were they had updates was over two
and a half years
looking at the
cve population over a period of 10 years
it quadrupled in volume in just 10 years
that's the amount of issues that were
found and hopefully fixed in that time
frame
and looking at when you think about the
problem with open source a lot of times
you have an issue with indirect
dependencies
and you know when you report an issue to
the project sometimes these issues can
go for
over 218 weeks one study found
and once it's reported to that
development team it can take four weeks
to resolve if it's ever resolved
a lot a lot of stuff going on there
so what are the challenges of securing
open source software at scale
what makes open source development
models so impactful is also what makes
them so difficult to secure
so we can think about you know the
various things where open source differs
from other types of software development
models so to begin we have this the
obfuscated public-facing source code
which is reducing the barrier to entry
and that attackers need not reverse
engineer the binaries
there's also this distributed community
driven development model where
contributions can come from many sources
and at times even from unknown third
parties
um at times as well i think that
security and privacy folks are sometimes
we give in to this tragedy of the
commons where we have thought that just
because someone has looked at the code
that they necessarily have looked at the
code but in practice this may very well
not be the case
so we start to see this lack of
consistently deployed security standards
reviews and tooling across open source
resulting in weaknesses at various
points in the secure software
development life cycle even where easy
wins for security could have actually
happened
so this is somewhat related to this idea
that people may not have always looked
at the code
and we extend upon this by thinking
about the fact that in many cases open
source projects have a decreased
capacity for vulnerability remediation
so writing the patches and even worse
for incident response particularly for
smaller projects and those without a
mature security program but as we've
seen historically and up to the present
day
even this is true for many of the larger
projects as well
on top of this and we'll talk about this
a bit more later there are entirely
different economic incentives for open
source developers and maintainers
compared to enterprise developers and
maintainers
compared to the attackers
both security researchers and
threat actors
so we have all of these different
competing factors that are
bringing together this challenge in
securing open source and in spite of all
of this we have these incredibly high
value targets that are foundational to
many of the technologies that power our
world and the internet itself
so let's think a little bit about threat
modeling
open source security is about way more
than just vulnerabilities and source
code and there's also a breadth of ways
we can think about how these
vulnerabilities could get introduced so
we have this broad attack surface that
begins before any code is written it
extends to every individual developer's
local machine and network and all of the
way through this broader project
infrastructure out to even the package
management ecosystem and beyond so in
the ideation phase or the concept phase
we have to think about the risks of the
entire tech stack we also have to focus
especially on areas of enhanced risk
like cryptography and secrets management
operating system kernels anything around
container orchestration um when we think
about the actual development environment
we have to think about the maintainers
machine and interest that an attacker
may have in making malicious commits to
a repo or to preview forthcoming changes
or otherwise exfiltrate sensitive
information so we've seen for example
malware which sought to exfiltrated
developers and pm access tokens or the
xcode ghost supply chain attack dating
back to 2015 in which malicious versions
of apple's xcode development environment
were distributed
so we can move beyond
not just thinking about the developers
local environment which could be
compromised in many ways beyond the
couple of examples that i've given but
let's extend this to think about the
infrastructure or the project itself so
there can just be mistakes in code that
a developer didn't mean to introduce but
happen to be there
this could be
resulting from copy pasting insecure
code from stack overflow or just in
general using insecure software
development practices just by mistake
it could involve committing secrets or
to source code or to packages and it
could also involve leaving debug
functionality open such that it can be
abused as a backdoor by a threat actor
we can also think about external
contributions so contributors who may
introduce malicious code either
independently themselves or through the
compromise of a legitimate developer's
contributions so this can have to do
with identity and access management of
developers it can relate to insecure ci
cd pipelines and in which a range of
attacks can occur it can be compromises
to build systems um even though there's
been some great work over the last
several years around build pipelines
and verification especially things like
reproducible builds and binary
transparency which can solve some but
certainly not all of the problems here
these problems are amplified by a lack
of pipeline security tooling static
analysis fuzzing
as well as in instances where there's a
lack of platform security or operating
system level protections or runtime
protections it's really this defense in
depth together that can help make things
more secure
if we go beyond this there's also also
the package ecosystem itself so
individuals may typo squat to insert
malicious packages there may be a direct
compromise of legitimate packages and
they may also introduce things like
malicious dependencies there's much more
beyond this but even if we want to think
about these particular problems and
extend it to vulnerability disclosure
there can be inaccurate security contact
information a project may go
unmaintained the maintainer may not see
the bug as a vulnerability to security
or be unable to write the patch
there also may be insecure
communications methods including
projects that would like you to report
security vulnerabilities as public
issues and patching in public mail out
for the reverse engineering in advance
of forthcoming patches to infer not yet
public vulnerabilities so there's much
more we could talk about but probably in
the interest of time today i would
direct the interested listener to the
threats risk and mitigations in the open
source ecosystem paper published by
michael scoveta of microsoft and several
collaborators from openssf
so let's talk about vulnerabilities in
the open source ecosystem
ultimately open source security keeps
getting worse on average it's taking
years to detect a typical vulnerability
in open source software for example
data from github last year said that the
average vulnerability on github goes
undetected for four years and even
critical vulnerabilities take more than
two and a half years to get disclosed
what's more exploitation of
vulnerabilities in the wild is happening
faster than ever before this is true for
both open source and proprietary
software a number of reports have stated
that the number of days has dropped from
weeks down to just on average about
three days between a vulnerability being
publicly disclosed and exploitation
being observed in the wild
and this has happened over just the last
few years and this is true for both
proprietary and open source software
ultimately threat actors don't really
care what licenses our software uses
however reporting from rand corporation
has even further
demonstrated this point by stating that
it was found that exploitation of
vulnerabilities of open source in the
wild do not actually die off faster than
those for proprietary software
now why is this happening part of it is
developers seem not to be getting any
better at writing secure code
github used their tool codeql to study
several thousand popular github
libraries
and the rate of vulnerabilities being
introduced to them between the years of
2016 and 2020
ultimately the results were not very
promising and i quote
a line of code written in 2020 is just
as likely to introduce a security
vulnerability as a line of code written
in 2016. so things are not getting
better and on top of this applications
are growing in complexity
so software complexity can derive in
part from
both direct and transitive dependencies
which compounds the risks of these
dependencies the more and more
dependencies there are in the dependency
chain so let's go a little deeper about
what that means
okay so transitive dependency risk even
if your code is in the rare instance uh
free of vulnerabilities your code itself
probably depends on something which
itself is full of voles so we can
imagine it phones on phones on phones
all the way down
and what is the data that really backs
this up we know from recent reports that
open source projects have an average of
180 package dependencies some of them
have even up to a thousand we also know
that the 50 open source projects with
the most projects depending upon them
had an average of 3.6 million downstream
dependents
we we further know to really amplify why
this matters that vulnerabilities in
open source software have been central
to major breaches
so if we think about the equifax breach
of 2017 it was based upon a
vulnerability in apache struts an open
source framework
and we also know that they are often not
found until decades after their creation
at times
so every year we write more and more
lines of source code than ever before in
2020 60 million new repositories were
created on github with around 1.9
billion contributions
we also know that vulnerabilities seem
to scale proportionately with lines of
code even if you don't want to measure
the size of software or the complexity
of software based on lines of code
you'll see similar patterns around the
scaling of the introduction of
vulnerabilities
we also see that the number of reported
vulnerabilities in open source code
bases is growing each year and
furthermore we have reasons to believe
that um the number of volumes being
reported is radically lower than the
total actual number of exploitable
vulnerabilities in the wild
so we might ask ourselves if we stay on
our current trajectory will the security
of open source software get better or
worse
and without serious and coordinated
intervention i think it will get worse
the number of vulnerabilities in the
wild outpaces the speed at which the
security community can patch or even
identify those vulnerabilities and each
day the world gets more lines of source
code than it ever has before
as a consequence the generally
inadvertent create creation of
potentially exploitable vulnerabilities
increasingly outpaces the rate at which
we can search for and remediate them and
this problem is only getting worse with
time so ultimately we have this problem
that the security the security as it is
practiced now does not scale at the rate
needed to keep up with things um to make
them at least as secure just as they
were yesterday and what's worse than
that is that we have compelling reasons
to expect this to get even worse for
defenders
so in this slide i'm going to introduce
two points
the first of these points is that the
economics of exploitation for threat
actors offer them a considerable
advantage compared to the economics of
patching for defenders and this is
especially true for open source software
so threat actors don't generally have to
care about things like policy or law or
cfaa
unlike patching exploiting open source
software bones does not actually require
multi-stakeholder coordination
on top of that if we think just about
incentives threat actors are
incentivized to successfully exploit
vulnerabilities but in contrast security
researchers are not generally
incentivized to write patches and
neither are open source maintainers so
threat actor's number one priority is to
exploit volumes but in contrast open
source maintainers number one priority
is the core functionality of their
project not writing or applying patches
or making sure that they're ready for
enterprise consumers or people that are
working with different threat models
in addition to this the economics of
open source compared to closed source
software differ while with enterprise
kind of proprietary software we have
certain expectations of software
maintenance and security open source is
at your own risk with the understanding
that the developers of these code bases
may not have the same goals threat model
or priorities that you do as a result of
all of these interrelated factors we see
a decreasing length of time between
vulnerability discovery and exploitation
as well as between vulnerability
patching and exploitation
so the second point that i want to make
is that we have yet to see the true
potential for of techniques for finding
vulnerabilities at scale
what's simultaneously exciting and
terrifying to me is that the
technologies that can be used to hunt
vulnerabilities at scale are dual use in
nature they can be used by the defenders
or they can be used by our adversaries
and as the cliche goes within our fields
it is our adversaries um only have to
get it right once so the uncomfortable
truth is that scalable finding helps our
adversaries too
so what are the different ways that we
can think about these scalable bug
hunting methods
these certainly include you know
large-scale fuzzing projects
vulnerability discovery query languages
like codeql
various flavors of innovations in
program analysis
sometimes applications of machine
learning to identifying particular
examples of bug classes
and all methods by which attackers will
be able to scale their findings as
quickly as we will
i think that this is compounded however
by recent work over the last five to
eight years i would say in automated
exploit generation where we're seeing
that even for small poorly incentivized
academic studies that there has been
considerable progress in automating the
chaining of exploits or the chaining of
an ultimate attack so i mean even if you
don't buy into the idea that computer
science will eventually have a
sufficiently advanced
scalable automated exploit generation in
the near term even with the most
restrained version of our hypothesis
namely that there are at least some
level of efficiency gains possible for
vulnerability exploitation this is
nevertheless concerning
furthermore we have reasons to believe
that large language models like gpt-3
which have shown themselves to be very
good at learning um not just from a
corpus of internet text
that they've been able to be generative
so even when asking these models to
generate novel things be they images or
stories with particular natural language
descriptors we've seen that they're
capable of generating novel code as well
so
how do we reduce vulnerabilities at
scale to solve this problem i think we
need to just not have security research
but security research at internet scale
traditional vulnerability research and
the ongoing whack-a-mole defined cves
can only take us so far and ultimately
it makes its highest impact when we
prioritize for the criticality of the
target system either because it is
inherently foundational to the internet
or to enterprise software or because it
is an upstream dependency to those core
pieces of infrastructure or because it
presents subtleties of implementation
that make it particularly hard to secure
so we might see this in cryptographic
libraries or things with like low-level
machine code
else maybe because it puts a targeted
population ecosystem or other single
point of failure in the internet
infrastructure at risk
so this is thus the motivation for this
entire talk particularly here at black
hat among security researchers of a
broader range
set of technical subspecialties and
particularly within the community track
because we believe that it is only
through coordinated and strategic effort
that security researchers can attempt to
outpace the in the wild exploitation of
vulnerabilities in open source so how do
we reduce vulnerabilities at scale
right jennifer now so our challenge is
how do we reduce these vulnerabilities
at scale
that there are a traditional kind of
cyber security framework find
prevent prevent find and detect is a way
to handle this but we need to figure out
ways to eliminate whole classes of bugs
doing individual vulnerability
whack-a-mole onesie 2z one at a time
does not work will not get us to the
space we need to be in we need to be
able to eliminate whole classes of
problems like sql injection or
cross-site scripting or remote code
execution be able to eliminate these
things whole swaths of you know hundreds
of vulnerabilities at once
we need to understand and take a look at
the threat model of open source is
most modern software today isn't a
monolithic code base it's a composed app
where you're borrowing little bits and
pieces of software here and there and a
lot of it trends towards microservices
where things are hosted randomly all
over the globe and that threat model and
that attack service needs to be analyzed
and understood by the end
uh consumers and implementers of this
software
and we need you know as a group like
openssf we need to concentrate our
resources on critical libraries critical
components and projects to help provide
the most bang for the buck
there are a lot of different tools
available and we'll talk a little bit
about some of the things the
foundation's doing about that but
static analysis fuzzing peer code review
these kind of traditional
software engineering practices need to
be you know more fully adopted within
the community
and we need to perform kind of enhanced
testing that's where that that manual
code review and that's we have a project
we're partnering with an organization
called ostiff where we're going to go
through and do code reviews of specific
high critical projects
and then you know kind of thinking
forward we need to participate more in
things like coordinated vulnerability
disclosure the
open source ecosystem is broad and
diverse but
we can provide some simple rules some
simple guidelines and templates that
people can refer to and use and help
educate the value of coordinated
vulnerability disclosure to reduce the
end risk for those end consumers and
things like software bill of materials
helps you describe what's inside that
piece of software you're just
downloading that container you're using
that you know that
pull request you just made kind of
what's in there and there's also
improvements we're making with the
larger cve community to help improve the
speed and ease of use of you know
getting these vulnerabilities identified
and communicated out
but at the end of the day the tldr of it
is what actually helps open source
be more secure
i'm going to give you a groundbreaking
idea give you a minute i'm going to blow
your mind
if you use
software for a project
maybe on some level you can contribute
back to that project to help them
help them
improve the quality of their software
help them perform
improve the speed of their delivery the
quality of their overall product i know
it just
blew your mind it's an amazing novel
concept
so
kind of what we can do i mentioned i
touched on it very briefly threat
modeling understanding kind of where and
how a project can be compromised both at
a software level you know these
engineering perspective this is how this
coding mistake is why that's there and
how to eliminate it but also thinking
about how that project works where is
their repository how do they what's
their ci cd pipeline look like think
about how that can be compromised by a
bad actor you know we need to help work
to identify the most critical open
source projects and invest time and
resources to help them
do better to help improve the overall
ecosystem for everybody
and again things like preventing
vulnerabilities in the first place using
tools like depend-abot to help as you're
checking in code or downloading code
you're able to see kind of what the
dependencies are or doing automated
vulnerability scanning before even using
something and implementing sdlc like
practices across the board whether for
big projects and small projects
it all kind of boils down to there's
a lot of potential inherited security
debt here when you are using software
that you didn't write yourself
from unknown sources you know that
there's
an aspect of risk that you need to think
through and understand how can you help
protect yourself how can you help
protect that project tools like the cii
best practices badge help give you a
list these are these are projects that
have been vetted and meet expected
criteria on
varying levels
you know there are investments that we
made in tooling to help bug hunting you
know scale up more and help remediation
happen more it's great to find a lot of
problems your boggle is you don't have
you have more people finding problems
than you have people fixing the problem
so how can we help fix the problems
we need to invest in things like
security reviews we need to have
coordinated patching and incident
response if one project fix something
somewhere and there are other related
projects that don't get the fix that's
still a failing there's a gap there in
that model we need to figure out how we
can help make sure everyone gets aware
that there's a vulnerability and there's
something that needs done and those that
can contribute have that ability
we need to have that more
thorough more consistent vulnerability
disclosure process when a user of open
source software is using a project they
need to understand how that project
works how they handle vulnerability
intake how they fix stuff who else they
might include
and again i think where we can have
coordinated and impact prioritized
funding for these improvements audits
and further research and how we can help
model going forward
thinking back there has you know this is
not the first time in history people
have invented you know come together to
help solve the open source problem
thinking back
uh
to
you know the the dawn of time you know
back in 1988 we had the morris software
worm that kind of got people to realize
hey there's a problem on the internet
and all these things are connected and
bad stuff can happen in the early 90s
you know linux was created yay
you know around the year 2000 there was
a little problem called y2k that the
whole world was going to end in december
31st 1999
spoiler it didn't but that was again
there's another area where people
realize there was a problem with
computer software they got together and
helped to try to fix it
our friends over at owasp got together
in 2001 and started initially focusing
on web application security but over the
years they've branched out to be broader
just application security
remember i mentioned back in 2014 we had
heartbleed that kind of woke a lot of
open source people up and later that
month there was a project created called
the core infrastructure initiative that
started to fund
people and resources and tooling to help
assist projects like openssl but then
again we were reinforced you know kind
of the ubiquity of open source in that
september when we had shell shock which
was a bash vulnerability
uh
our friends over at owasp created a
great
uh kind of a testing tool zap 2015
uh folks over at google started a
project called oss fuzz in 2016. uh we
have dependable that came out in 2017.
the open source security foundation came
together in 2020 and we're partnering
with organizations like ostif and others
to help improve the overall quality of
open source ecosystem and who knows
where we're going to go in the future
when we're all wearing silver spacesuits
and flying around our cars it's going to
be awesome
so you know how can we help
you can help today by participating
there's
great ways you know there's many
different groups that you can join in
you can contribute your knowledge with
by writing software by providing
comments helping with documentation it's
you have to remember we're all in this
together it's an ecosystem sharing is
caring we all use the software let's all
try to find ways we can help to improve
it
thinking about how the open ssf
specifically is working on this problem
we have six different working groups
today we have identifying security
threats securing critical projects
digital identity attestation security
tooling my favorite working group the
developer best practices working group
and then my favorite working group the
vulnerability disclosures working group
and we have a lot of different projects
we're working on these are things these
are tangible items that people can
participate in active development that's
going on so for example we have uh
projects like uh
the metrics or the badges or things like
skf or cre that we the the or oss fuzz
that you know the foundation is working
on we have members working on we do some
academic stuff like we have a listing of
personas and persona pain points we have
white papers
we also work with industry groups you
know there are several things that are
affiliated things like in the developer
identity
space like you have key lime and toto
and sig store that aren't part of the
foundation but are affiliated and
they're working towards enhancing a
pedigree and providence of open source
software so people that use open source
software have assurance that you know
some of the it's coming from the right
place and wasn't changed
um and then you know we were working
towards creating best practices
for the ecosystem on you know here's
tooling that is great options for open
source project to use if you use these
languages here's secure coding guides we
can help you refer to so that you can
write better quality software and that
whole all-important cvd here's what cbd
is here's how you can do it and how you
can participate resources that are
available to you to get vulnerabilities
documented and if you need help doing it
we can help provide you resources to
help find out how to do that
and then thinking about the larger
ecosystem we partner with organizations
like cert cc there's a vulnerability
reporting platform called vince we're
working with them on to open source and
then they'll think about the larger
efforts like the ntia's s-bomb software
build materials effort the foundation is
involved in a lot of these different
things and you know there's always room
for improvement but there's also always
room for your participation your
feedback and your collaboration
and i'm gonna
pass it over to jennifer
to take us home here
we currently have six working groups
that are working on things like building
scalable tooling for open source
software in general including the
development of scorecards to help users
better understand the security
properties of a given repo or package
improving coordinated disclosure for
open source software developing security
guidelines for open source developers
combined with tooling like the cii best
practices badge to encourage projects to
reach a certain minimum level of
security standard and perhaps most
interestingly our securing critical
projects group which seeks to define the
most critical projects on the internet
for the targeted investment of time and
other resources for things like research
development of tooling partial rewrites
of code in safer programming languages
and third-party security audits
thank you for listening
please join us by visiting
openssf.org get involved and we will now
share further details about our work and
take any questions