[Music]
hello and thanks for joining this
session um i'm brian and today i'll be
talking about intel's houdini binary
translator
before that quickly above myself um i
studied electrical engineering at the
cooper union and currently working as a
security consultant at with the ncc
group
i like to build random bits of hardware
and also like to reverse engineer
things other people built both hardware
and software
lately i've been doing a lot of android
testing and sometimes mandatory android
malware analysis
so let's get right to android
you guys probably know android is one of
the largest operating systems for mobile
devices
and
you can write android apps in java and
kotlin officially
and you could also write
components of those apps in c and c plus
plus using the native development kit
uh android was originally built around
arm platforms armed devices
and
later google has added support official
support for x86 devices as well
just to mention there there has been uh
out of
out of tree support for android and x86
prior to that as well such as the
android x86 project
so there are two main types of android
devices
that's on x86 now
those are x86 chromebooks and x86 hosts
running commercial android emulators
however there is a general lack of
support for x86 and apps
and that's because again like i
mentioned andrew was originally built
around arm so most of the devices are
still armed
and if you are app developer and if you
have native code they don't actually
require the only only thing they require
is the arm builds and no other
architectures are required
so
yeah only a few developers end up
shipping x86 binaries for the apks
but many of the apps actually contain
native code
so how do these x86 android devices
support running these arm native
applications
the inter answer is the intel's
proprietary
houdini binary translator
it was co-designed by google to work
with android
and this is the key piece that enables
arm native applications to run on x86
devices
it's a it's a little black box shattered
mystery there's
barely any mention of it on their
websites and there's no public
documentation
and it seems like several vendors
vendors may be obfuscating trying to use
their
try to hide their usage of
houdini
and we notice there are three variants
that are
around
so houdini is used in on x86 mobile
phones phones which aren't really around
anymore
and also x86 chromebooks and this is
actually how we got it specifically the
32-bit x86
implementing the
32-bit arm
houdini is also found in commercial
android emulators both bluestacks and
knox
use or at least have the option to
enable
lipodini
and android x86
has it as well
interestingly um from a
talk from defcon 26 a few years ago
bluestacks you renamed the library from
le poudini to
like something like lib3b trans.so for
some unknown reason
i believe knox does something similar as
well
so houdini is basically an interpreter
for arm instructions
and it's essentially a while loop around
a switch
and it also keeps track of the
the emulator arm processor
it reads um
note that it does not do just-in-time
compilation um as there's no x86
constructions output to be run at a time
and houdini is mainly two components
the first is houdini it's it's used to
run executable binaries and the second
is lipodeny which is used to load shared
objects and other libraries
so
yeah so houdini can run arm executable
binaries both static and dynamic
for dynamic
executables it actually has its own set
of pre-compiled libraries for arm and
android that it uses from those pads
so you can see in the screenshot below
the um the system i'm running on is x86
the file i'm trying to run is arm
and it ran just fine
now you might be wondering how where how
does houdini come in i've never invoked
it and this is actually a feature of the
linux kernel called bin format misc
and if you aren't familiar here's a
quick
intro whatever um
so bin format mist is a capability of
the linux kernel or feature
and it basically lets you
register customer interpreters for
custom binary format it's very similar
to how a shebang works for bash or
python scripts
so you can see the uh
the
see that houdini has
registered interpreters for itself
and so what this basically does is if i
type in
hello and i call try to execute kernel
will see that and try to compare the
magic bytes and if it matches it will
convert it into system bin houdini
hello
so the second component lipodynia so
is a shared object itself built for x86
but it can be used to load arm objects
shared objects
and it was mainly designed to use
android native bridge to run arm native
code
so let's talk about android native
bridge um
it is the main interface that android
uses to talk to librodini
and it's part of the android runtime and
it's it's primary feature is to
support running native code in different
architectures
so as it's part of android runtime it's
initialized on boot and it reads that
system property to see what file has to
load if it's set to zero it's disabled
um
actually android x86 project uses their
own version of uh called lib
own implementation called libmb.so but
when you look at the source it's it's
actually just a thin wrapper around le
perdini um
also interestingly they if you go
through the source trees um
throughout different tags they seem to
have moved around the link and the code
to download lippoudini and uses some dot
cn link shorteners and
yeah
so this means that
so native bridge is actually not
specific to arm it just defines an
interface for a translation layer
that also means
if you implement a native bridge
you could
write your own custom binary translation
layer for different architectures such
as mips on x86 and whatnot
and nativebridge defines interfaces with
these callbacks that i'll be talking
about but before that i want to talk to
you about uh
java native interface so java native
interface is basically interconnect that
connects the java side of our code with
our native code
um
and the struct shown on the right is the
jni m
struct which mostly consists
of it's a bag of function pointers
and whenever the java side calls any
native code this the pointer to the
struct is passed as the first argument
so that when our native code written in
c wants to call interact with the java
world it could use these functions such
as like find class alloc or call object
methods
and it would it's equivalent to a low
level reflection api for java
in c
so going back to the callbacks the first
them which is the native bridge runtime
callbacks
as far as this talk is concerned this is
not that important and it's
these callbacks are provided from the
native bridge to the houdini so liberty
could interact with native bridge
native functions
the more interesting callbacks are the
native bridge callbacks
and
this is how
our native bridge from the android side
enter can call code into our houdini
so
i
cut out
some of the functions on on the right
but some of the interesting ones are
initialize probably guess what that does
uh load library which acts similarly to
a dl open
and get trampoline which acts similar to
dlcent but we'll talk about why that's
interesting later
and this struct is actually
an exported symbol on liboudini.so via
the name nativebridge itf and you can
see that here
so
and that's the uh the picture is
actually the
[Music]
data the structure
in the binary and you can see all the
function pointers right there except for
the last one
i guess that's unsupported
so to kind of put this all together this
is how it works on on a normal arm on
arm
app
system
so your
android code runs and android app runs
and it wants to load a library
and then
so the android runtime will call dl open
on your native code libnative.so
and when you want to call a function the
android runtime does a dlcim which
returns a function pointer to our native
function
and then you could jump to it
and our native code could also interact
with the java world using the jnim
function pointers that i mentioned
before
so this is pretty simple under normal
circumstances
now when you have a cross architecture
app or
not a cross architecture app but a
arm native code running on x86 android
with native brits and lipodini loaded it
looks something like this
so
before anything happens before your app
is loaded on boot native bridge is
initialized and it reads that system
property from a few slides back and then
dl opens the houdini.so
and
liberating that iso is actually so you
could just use dl open and dlc it gets
the callbacks via the native bridge itf
symbol
and then it calls initialize which isn't
shown in the diagram
so this before the app happens when you
launch the app and the app requests
a
native library with something like
system.load library
um the native bridge does not do a dl
open because it's native bridge is
enabled so instead does a load library
library on the libradini binary through
the callbacks
and that loads our arm native code
and then when our
app code wants to call a function it
calls get trampoline
so we can't actually use dlcm directly
because
one dl open would not open it because
it's a different architecture and two
dlc will give you the
pointer directly to the native code and
we can't call that from our android
runtime because our native code is armed
and our android runtime is running on
x86 processor
so the function pointer that's returned
by get trampoline and actually a stub
into the interpreter
and when you call it
the interpreter starts working
and it starts reading the native code
and starts emulating these instructions
so i mentioned previously that um
whenever you call native code the
java side
gives the
pointer to the jni instruct function
pointers
as the first argument
uh similar to how why we can't call dl
sim on our native library we can pass
our jni instruct directly from native
bridge into our native
code
because the function pointers you would
get are
pointing to functions written in x86
so to handle this
um lee houdini creates its own jni
instruct and it's filter function
pointers that
it's for the function filter function
pointers
that lead to uh trap instructions
and when our native code wants to call a
function in jnim it loads looks at that
and
executes those trap instructions and our
interpreter knows which trap
instructions those are and it uses the
jni and
struck cached when it was called and
then
that's the blue line turning into red
so
basically our native code runs that trap
instruction and interpreter sees that
and does the jnam call and returns back
to native code and when native code is
done it turns back to the interpreter
which turns back to wherever you called
um the function pointer
initially from our java
that was a
mouthful
so now that we have a good uh somewhat
understanding of how
liberdini and native bridge gets loaded
together
we could start delving
deeper into
how it works internally
starting starting with memory um
lipidini seems to load uh leave houdini
loads all of the libraries in the same
address space both arm and x86
and it also doesn't have any like
special magic translation between arm
memory addresses and x86 addresses which
means they're all
accessible with each other
um
and there but there is a separate
allocation for arm stack and you can see
it here this is a snippet from
the process memory map using self pid
map
and you can see our native library and
lipuidine loaded
um these are the arm libraries that are
loaded and the ones on the bottom are
x86
so they are in this in fact in the same
address space
um and lift c is loaded for both the arm
version and x86 version and we could
also see
some anonymous memory mapped and our
stack is somewhere in there
so let's go to the next part which is
how the houdini actually executes the
instructions
so i mentioned previously it's basically
a switch inside a while loop plus a
state machine to keep track of the
register states processor states and
this portion shows the
kind of like the fetch decode and
dispatch portion of it
and
i'm going to describe the
the comments in the next slide
so what it does is it
basically reads the instruction from
memory
it checks in uh
checks the first four bits which in arm
is the condition code field and if it's
your x0e
which means always it continues and if
it's not it jumps somewhere to what to
see whether they should continue running
the instruction
um
so when we get to that point it
concatenates the bits 20 to 27
with bits four to seven
and then uses that as an index into the
instruction table
which is shown on the right
and
you can see it's just filled with
function pointers addresses
so for example our move r0r1 instruction
and arm looks like that and when you do
the math you get an index of 0x181
and after you're doing some more
calculation you find that the
instruction handler for the move
instruction is at 4bc004
and just to show you what it looks like
at 4bc04
we have the function pointer to
instruction move 1 and on the right side
is giga's
decompiled function
um
yeah so somewhere in there there is uh
there's some code that moves register
values around around like line 22 and 27
but you also notice that
each instruction handler takes two
parameters the first is the instruction
itself so it could decode the rest of
the fields from it
and the second
argument is the processor state
struct
and
so yeah that's where all the register
values are stored so let's talk about
that
the processor state struct stores the
arm registers as well as other important
processor states
so
that was what i was able to reverse from
look looking at the labrudini binary but
you could see like the first 64 bytes
are used to store the 16 registers of
arm
there is also a field that tells it
whether it's in thomas mode or not
and there's some other things that i
don't
really know what they do
so
since this keeps track of the process
state
if we
know where it is we would be able to
read and write to it and which means we
could change register values or for
example if we change r15 which is a
program counter for arm
and if you change the value it would
switch execution to a different location
so syscalls are up next um how does sys
calls work
um it works just like any other uh
instruction decoding so just like
previously it sees a syscall instruction
it will go to the instruction table and
jump to the right handler and this is
actually where the system handlers begin
and they also follow the same
form function
prototype so it takes the instruction
the
itself
and the pointer to the processor state
but you might notice that it actually
does not issue a x86 test call here
directly
it only sets the svc number field with
the syscall number
and the actual syscall is made further
along the uh execution
in the
the while loop
um
yeah
so
while most of the syscalls are simple
enough and they're just wrapped and
re-performed in x86
we
thought
one specific syscall was of interest and
that is the clones this call
and i also wrote a fork because nowadays
you use fork it goes to lip c1 with
lipsy fork
which
does a clone syscall instead
so we want to see how that worked
and as i mentioned like
uh arm syscalls are intercepted and
handled by lipoutini in x86
so for clone it clones the process in
x86 and then
each the child and the parent handles
the
logic to convert it you know back into
how the arm would see it
and clone actually takes an argument
called child stack so you could give it
a memory buffer
memory pointer
and tell the kernel to use this as a
child stack
and this is actually not passed to
kernel directly
because
um the top of the dot child stack is the
return address so if you if we if
lipoedini gave the memory that arm
provided directly to the x86 kernel
it would return
to an arm address which it won't be able
to run
so instead liputini creates an rwx page
and passes that as a child stack
so now we have an insight somewhat
inside of how the emulator works
internally
we could try to do some fun things with
it for example if we we could try to see
if whether our code is running under the
houdini or not um and try to check that
we could check for the host processor
right because we'll be running in our
arm
code but if we want to see if it's
running under houdini you could check
the host processor architecture and you
could do it from java using like
osr to get property or by reading the
prox cpu info
but this will actually not work because
houdini hides this
and
i'll albeit not very well and you
actually might be able to tell because
if you look carefully the os arch
properties has rnv7l
which is not what the cpu info says
which says it's rnv8 processor rev1
arc64 with the hardware serial number of
or hardware version of placeholder
um
great um
[Music]
so another thing we could do is also uh
check the memory maps
one to check if lipodenia is loaded and
two to see if there's both arm and x86
binaries going on in there
however we think the best
way to do this is quietly because all
the methods we mentioned above required
use of some syscall like opening these
files or doing some
memory mapping related assist calls
so
the best implementation is one that's
quiet and
hard to detect
and we came up with one way
um and because i i mentioned previously
um
lipodini provides a fake arm jni vamp
pointer
which has trap instructions
we could try to read that instruction
and see if it's a valid arm instruction
or
also valid but it's a trap instruction
another fun thing we could do with
houdini is we could try to escape to x86
because it is a
fake virtual
emulator right so
their now
container break out is pretty popular so
we could try to see if we could break
out of x86
and we could do it a few ways and one
way would be
calling and protect and overriding code
so we have an executable
memory
however this is not subtle again because
we're using a syscall and
i mean if you're doing analysis on these
apps some some process calls and protect
and you might be suspicious of it
so without doing that we could also do
x86 stack manipulations um we could try
to find the stack and clobber with raw
payloads
um we could try to overwrite the return
address function pointer
but the hard part would be to
you know getting the raw payload finding
the drop chains or finding our
executable page to run in
this is not an issue because the houdini
provides
if you notice
if you were
if you look carefully in the previous
slide there were also there were
actually multiple read write execute
pages
um which means you could write code to
it and just jump to it
um in x86 you would uh
yeah just to show what some of these
other pages are being used for um this
memory region contains our fake
arm jnim
arm jni instruct
and this address is used for arm stack
so going back to the read write execute
pages um
we could write code too and jump to it
and if you're in x86 you still have to
figure out how to get our program
counter or instruction pointer to go to
the actual address
but since we have executable pages
but on arm we we're running arm code so
we could just jump to it
um the harder problem might be trying to
find the red drive execute pages
this is also not an issue because
apparently houdini does not care about
the execute
this makes sense as an interpreter
because
libridini's interpreter
and
it treats the instructions as the or to
it
instructions are to the host just data
so as an interpreter if you can read the
data it will read the instructions it
will run them
so
therefore the arm libraries themselves
are not loaded with the execute bit set
on their pages
so as you can imagine this is pretty
trivial to abuse i just write code
anywhere and jump to it
and here is my proof concept for running
it on a the
executable version of houdini
so in main i allocate some memory um
actually the first version of this code
i wrote it was not on stack it was on
the um
and uninternalized is that on
the heap or
it was in an
an uninitialized data section
and i write some instructions to it and
this specifically adds
r0 1 to r0 and then returns
and then i cast it to function pointers
and then call it
so under on real armed devices
this would cause a set fall because you
should not be able to execute from the
stack
or the heap
given that their proper protection is in
place
but if you run it through the houdini
you can see on the bottom they ran just
fine
and i for the lid houdini version
i have some demos including some of the
things i talked about earlier
so
this is on the chromebook
and i built an app that's houdini tools
for both arm and x86 versions on it
they're built off of the same code
um it just i
set it so that it builds them separately
for different architectures
so on the top is our x86 build and on
the bottom is our arm build and on x86
we see the cpu info um
the screen we saw or it reports normally
right we have our gender and intel and
the top it says i-686 from system get
property
now on the bottom
we saw basically what we saw earlier
osrt says armv7 and when we read prox
cpu info it says rv8 which is not rv7
and hardware placeholder
so the second tab demonstrates the uh
detection method we could use one
possible detection method we could use
by using the jni m function pointers
so when i click fetch all it would
actually from the native side return the
addresses of n
and m
get version function pointer and the
bottom tool will
dereference that function pointer as
double words
so we see that on x86
um when we dereference the function
point nerd it looks like there are
some push instructions
as you would often see in the beginning
of a function
but when we try this on
yeah when we try this on the arm version
we actually get
we also get value instructions under get
version and get call static and method
but they're not they they're they are
the system system called trap
instructions uh denoted by ef and the
number follows it is the actual syscall
number
oops
and the third tab is just a tool um
utility that's useful and it reads
uh proc self maps to see what's loaded
in there so x86 there is no like the
predini
loaded this is filtered because there's
way too much stuff in there but there's
no lip houdini loaded on and in if you
read the maps
you could see there's
lee houdini loaded in there as well as
um
a bunch of arm libraries
uh
i'm having a little trouble finding it
here uh
right there's the arm library and then
i'm like where's lippidini
and then i find it here right there
right
so
the last
tab is our font tab
so
i built this little layout um
where the left side will be the
instruction i want to run and the right
side will be the
uh the result when you run the code and
all it does is it it
it pushes the bytes on the left side
onto the stack or actually in in in on
the heap on the native side and then
jumps to it so
and i i didn't want to remember all the
op codes so it's i put some buttons in
there to fill it in
um
so this would obviously not work because
this does not have lip houdini loaded
and it it's at and
x86
so it crashed
and that is what would happen on real
arm devices as well because it's going
to try to execute from the heap
but when you have a system
running
on x86
that's running arm native code with lip
houdini
this
works and when i click run
um it incremented the five
um
so yeah i you can see the actual bytes
here e2 8 blah blah one which is arm for
add r0 or zero one so that increments
one and returns which is why i named the
increment
the second um and yeah i could change
the the value i call the function with
with r0 r1r2 and the second one adds the
two integers numbers together seven and
two i get nine the second one is
the third
tab third program is multiply so it
multiplies r1 and r2 and adds it to r0
so in this case would be 20 90 97 right
and the last program i prepared is the
get sp which would just return the stack
pointer from the arm side
and takes no parameters so it doesn't
really matter and that is the stack
address of the arm
processor
now just to show that this is actually
you know um
being sent into the native code and
written to the to memory and being
executed you could just change it i i
wrote it so that you you could actually
type in real bytes and it would pass it
and write to memory and jump to it so if
i change it to f which should be the r15
which is the program counter for arm it
would give me where the function
itself is located where it's executing
so yeah it is changing around a little
bit because
this is not on the stack this is
actually on the heap so malloc and free
so it's going to change around a little
bit
but you can see that when i change the
code it actually returns something i can
show that here instead of incrementing
one i increment two and just happen to
know that's the correct bit to change
um
it the r0 is seven and incremented by
two um and if i want to compare the
incremented by three i could change the
instruction to incremented three and we
get ten
um you could do this multiple times as
well
just to really show that this is the
dynamic code execution
that was a demo
so
what can we do with these fun features
of luputini well
we know that uh
apps are often analyzed by security
researchers and app stores and they
mostly do it in three ways when they run
in sandbox environments
they could do it in real arm devices or
fully virtualized
device environment like chemu or x86
android emulators kind of like vms
so real arm devices will be the best
because it will give you actual
real behavior of how it would work
uh the thing is sometimes it's hard to
instrument and it's it's hard to do at a
larger scale
and the second best option would be
fully virtualize our environments like
chemu but this has a significant
performance hit because you're emulating
the entire stack
the
hardware
the third option would be using
commercial android emulators or like
the
android sdks android emulators which run
on x86
and these
are these also have a performance hit
but not as much as a fully virtualized
one and if you use liphoudini you could
also analyze
arm native code on this while
the android part is x86
so
also note if
if an app expresses different behavior
depending on which one of these
environments it's running on that would
obviously one harder to detect and two
it'd be hard to analyze because you have
inconsistent behavior
so using this what if we could key in
this
method so
what if a malware were to detect whether
it's running on the lipoutini or not and
say if there's no leproudini it comes to
conclusion that it's not under analysis
and starts doing malicious behaviors
and when there is lipidini it thinks
that there is analysis and does not do
any malicious behaviors
so
another example is if you know for a
fact that a certain analysis or a
certain
app store or whatever is using one of
these methods
to analyze the apps you can use that as
fingerprinting
conversely
on a malware could be
could be running malicious
behaviors when it detects leboudini so
that it could use
abuse the lebrodini to further obfuscate
itself using the fun features that i
demonstrated um so for example we don't
know what the play store uses nowadays
but it does not seem like they're using
um
it's it does not seem like it doesn't
seem like they're uh
running the arm apks on x836 devices
lip houdini so
this would be a use case for something
like that
yeah
so with all these issues
we have some recommendations to
vendors and platforms
first of all drop the unnecessary rwx
pages
because that would not itself give
give it access to run code but it would
make it easier once you figure out how
so
if it's really necessary
perform a finer page permission control
implement an efficient
nx
slash userline page table implementation
and
we understand checking the page table
every time an instruction is loaded
would incur a significant overhead so
instead what we recommend is you keep
track of the page mappings in process in
a data structure and perform checks only
if the instruction currently running
is in a different page than the
instruction that ran previously
and lastly if you're going to go through
all this you might as well use
virtualization which has all the
pretty efficient
implementation of the nx bit and the
page table implementation
so we'll actually discuss how actually
we could actually implement the
user land page table and the annex bit
implementation
this could be done a couple ways one we
only trust the executable section on
load
um
fairly obvious
two
we
whenever we load a new page we check
from uh or execute from a new page we
check proc self maps and then
add that into the data structure for
caching
and three we could um
in libradini we could for example
you could have functionality in map and
protect to track the syst permissions
um so when a program calls map with
execute permission um it does the map
but also keeps adds it to this data
structure where it's
set as execute or not execute
but the ideal solution combines
the number two and number three
with the number two checked performed as
a catch-all kind of and this also has
extra benefits which is it now it can
now support dynamic straight object
loading via dl open
um
because dl open would do that and deal
open would run and it would do all the
sys calls and though it's
basically you've implemented a page
table in user space and
uh
yeah
the second thing is
because it also works normally now with
proper protection you could also
you could now
support legitimate just-in-time
compilation and obviously after
it's done running the
output code you should create and clear
it and so you can't to prevent page
views attacks
uh so the data structure we're talking
about that keeps track of the pages
is basically our useland page table and
that and should be heavily heavily
heavily protected
such as it should only be writable when
being updated
it could be surrounded by guard pages or
and it should definitely not be
accessible to arm processor
um
so for if anyone's doing
analysis of these android application
um for dynamic glasses it's highly
recommended to also run it under
libertini environments to see if it does
any uh
it shows any uh different behaviors and
if you're running static analysis
um
you should be looking for any access and
weird red memory accesses to
the houdini pages
and attempting to execute from
non-executable pages
and
scanning the jni function pointers
because that's what i would be doing
and that brings us to the conclusion uh
houdini introduces a number of security
weaknesses into
things that use it and
those impact the both the emulated
section emulated arm
processor and the host x86 code
and these issues overall undermine
coordinative code hardening
so
we could have
it's possible
that
these issues could have been caught
earlier had houdini been more public and
more easily accessible which would mean
more people would have looked at it
that's just what we think
um and
that's the only presentation but i want
to give a big special thanks to jeff for
mentoring this research
and come developing the methodology
uh jennifer for great support with all
the research and
feedback great feedback and effie for
basically bootstrapping this research
including the chromebook i was doing the
testing on
and
and thanks everyone for joining the
session and we'll have q a