[Music]
hello everyone welcome to our talk my
name is jin long from 360 alpha lab
today my colleague joe pong and i are
going to share and support chain to
remotely root modern android devices
with only two vulnerabilities
this work is also contributed by han
hong li and monsanto we are all security
researchers at 360 alpha lab
our team mainly focuses on mobile
security including trust zone kernel
applications like browser and so on we
have reported more than 400
vulnerabilities to top vendors and won
the highest reward of the asr program in
and google apr in 2019
we also successfully planned many
targets in poncho on and tm4 contests
this talk many consists of four parts
a brief review of the remote attack
surface of android devices followed by
the overview of our exploit chain
then we will detail the root cause of
this vulnerabilities and share the
export strategy
at last we will present a demo of
remotely rooting a pixel 4.
so let's get started
for mobile device there are usually two
types of entry points for known for
non-physical attacks
technologies such as bluetooth nfc and
baseband allow mobile for remote
communications
so attackers can send malicious traffic
to the connected device
this kind of tech often doesn't need
user interaction but is more limited in
range as compared to the attack over the
internet
technologies such as mailing instant
messaging and web browsers can be
targeted over the internet
and have a larger test service on their
own
as they often must deal with executing
applications logic rendering of web
pages and other online protocols
a typical remote solution is to use the
browser as the entry point to obtain
code execution capabilities in the
render process
since this process is highly sandboxed
attackers need to change other box for
escaping the sandbox
and elevating privileged to system user
or root
since the last time our team discovered
the tv zone explorer chain to achieve
one click remote route on pixel 3
we once again said afterwards this goal
targeting new pixel devices with latest
updates
we named the new explorer chain man code
and reported to google in july 2020
so why mangkhut
in september 2018 a typhon named
mangkhut formed on the pacific ocean
at about the same time a powerful
vulnerability was introduced into the
angel kernel which we used in this
exploit chain to escalate from the
highly sandbox process to root
while the typhoon monkeys caused
extensive damage in the real world
the vulnerability may show its
destructive power in cyberspace
the exploit chain only consists of two
bugs a type confusion bug in chrome
and a kernel box which can be leveraged
to ask
to escalate from the highly sandbox
process to root
this chain affects a wide range of
devices running multiple versions of
android system
and it is the first reported exploit
chain to remotely rooting pixel 4
and
acknowledge it in google vrp annual
report
so here is the first step
rce in chrome render process
this bug exists in the promised or
settled building function of chrome's vh
javascript engine
let's take a look at the function first
it accepts an iterable object as
parameter in which each member is a
promise
the function returns a promise
immediately and the output promise is
fulfilled with the jazz array only after
all the giving promises have settled the
array contains objects that each
describes the outcome of each input
promise
here is an example
the input contains two promises
one is fulfilled with value one and the
other is rejected with arrow two
promise all settled returns a new
promise as its output
and we call the then method on it
since all input promises have settled we
get the result array in a callback
the result array contains two objects
adding the stereo and index one
describing the output of input vertices
from the perspective of code
implementation
way h needs to manage a result.js array
and analog some space for storing the
outcome for example when the first
moment is fulfilled v8 stores the result
in the fixed array adding that zero
more importantly user could get the
adjust array only after all the giving
promises have settled which means if
there is any promise stays in pending
state where it would not return the jazz
great to user
so how does v8 know all promises are
settled this requires a cross-context
variable named remaining nms count
it is initialized with the number of
input promises and is decreased by 1
when the promise is settled
when it becomes 0 v8 would return the
resultant rate
according to the specification a promise
is said to be settled if it is either
fulfilled or rejected
so either resolve animate function or
reject element function will get call
depending on the promise is fulfilled or
rejected
and both of them were eventually called
promise or resolve elements closure
function
this is way well where it stores the
promise outcome to a resultant rate and
counts down the number of remaining
pending promises
this function is implemented using
torque language
whose syntax looks like
typescript
we can see that it reads remaining ms
count from the function context slot
first
and subtract 1 and save it back to the
context
when remaining anim's count becomes to 0
the function will return an array of
objects as a result
normally add the resolve element
function where reject animate function
should only be called once at most
which means turning a pending promise
into a full field or rejected state
but what if we could call them both
the remaining enemies count would be
decreased by 2
and it would become to 0 when only half
of input promises are settled
as a result user will get the result
array at an earlier time
here is a profile concept about how to
get these two functions we call the
promise or settled function on our
custom divide class
where it would call the resolve method
to get next promise
and try to call the dam method defined
on the next premise we can see that
resolve anime function and reject enemy
function are
passed as parameters
that's how we get these two functions
and we can call any of them whenever we
want
so this may result in type confusion if
the attacker gets the dot array and
there are actually still something
performances needs to process
vas believes that the backing store is
always a fixed array while we can change
it to a number dictionary
suppose the first promise is settled
then v8 tries to write the result to a
fixed array at index 0.
actually grew up the metadata field of a
number dictionary
the approach to achieve out-of-bounds
right seems very straightforward at
first bounce
when it stores a value to the result
array it first checks whether the index
is in bounds of the array
if the index is smaller than the array
length way it just stores the value is
back in store
with type confusion even though the
array length could be a large number
which can be which can bypass the inbox
check
the size of number dictionary may be
small
thus and other bonds right could be
triggered at line eight
unfortunately this would only crash the
process because there is another
outbound check when torque compiler
generates code like that
so we want to figure out another way
another constraint is that we cannot
control the content of data to be
writing precisely it is always an
address of a js object which describes
the outcome of the settled promise
since the output points white is not
working so what else is valuable to
overwrite inside the number dictionary
the capacity field indicates the maximum
number of entries the dictionary can
have which seems to be a good target
by overwriting these fields with the
address of a js object which is usually
a relatively large number
we can trigger out of bounds axis
through the victim array
however this
offset of autobahn out of bounds axis is
not
predictable because of the way of way to
read or write a dictionary
after more research we choose to corrupt
a max number key field
which converts the type confusion block
to another out of bounds read problem
max number key indicates the maximum
valid index of number dictionary and
more importantly its least significant
bit indicates whether there is special
elements in the array such as accessors
for example if we define a gather at
index 0 the array is treated as a
special array because it will trigger
user-defined codes while accessing the
element
if the bit is set to 1 it means the
number dictionary has no special element
but by exploring the type confusion bug
we can corrupt these fields with the
address of a js object
and the least significant bit of any hip
object addressed in v8
is exactly one
so taken together we can make the
special array not that special
so the next step is to find a place
where we can use our special array to
gain more powerful ability
in this case the array prototype concat
api would do the trick
in iterate animate function it calls has
only simple elements to check whether
there is there are accessors on the
receiver's elements
as described before our special array
could bypass the chip this check so that
get element would be called in the first
pass however there are in fact accessors
defined on it
which we can call back to our
user-defined javascript codes
and out of pawns read would be triggered
if the array length has been changed to
a smaller value while the iteration
continues
so we have successfully converted the
type confusion bar to another out of
bounds read
block and the rest of work is not hard
to achieve code execution from this oob
read condition so i'm going to give a
brief introduction here
first we can link the address of a
revolver's back in store and second fake
a double jazz array in this red buffer
then trigger the out of bounds read
again to review the reference of the
vague array in javascript holes
first use the fake array to modify a
victim a revolver's memory layout for
object for actually read and write
and next step is to write shellcode to a
web assembly called arl
and finally calls the webassembly
function to execute shellcode
now we can compromise the current render
process and i'll hand it over to joepong
to show you how to escape the sandbox to
root privilege
thanks jerome next i will share with you
how to escape from sandballs to root
with the bender bark with font
first i will introduce why bender was
choosing as a research target and seeing
the cost of debug
after we finally bark in order to verify
the usability we first exploit it in a
trusted app environment
this part will be introduced in the
third part
after proving the utility of the bark
we further complete
the privileged escalation in the
sandboxing environment
this part is also one of the most
interesting
things today
finally i will show you a demonstration
in the team in zong exploration we used
three vulnerabilities
two of which were used to elevate
permissions from sandbox to route this
year we set out again and try to use
only one bug
to achieve this
an android system vendor is one few
drivers and it can be accessed inside
the sandbox
so
its vulnerability can be directly used
for sandbox escape
this time
we look to the vulnerability mining
target on bender
in fact the bender mulch has always been
a hot topic for security researchers
since the water job vulnerability has
found
multiple parks
have been found in band driver for
example project zero team fund one in
2019 and the blue first stack team found
one in 2020
statistics shows that
there is a barg for every 1000 and to my
son and 500 lines of code
and it's been the same file to those
less than 6000 lines of code
so we have to think about one question
is there still such serious security
park
of course the answer is yes
and that's why we're here today
the band rules is like a new canadian
warhead and the brothers are saying
you'd like a launch pad
the compilation of these two
will become an incontinental nuclear
power
next
i will introduce in detail how to use a
band of vulnerability to achieve stable
kernel archery read and write and
finally get rooted in the sandbox
a complete vendor communication process
has a total of four steps first the
clients send the bc transaction to the
kernel and the kernel forward the
request to a server
using the server reply bc reply to the
kernel after processing
and
forward it
to the client and after process
one point we want to pay attention to is
that
uh when sending the band object
a better load object in the kernel will
be created
the better work it contains well insert
into the strategy linkedin list
and the reference to abandon note will
also be inserted into the proper waves
by node tree of target process
normally clinic can process bandwidth
load time work by spending threaded raid
function
however
there is another way to process bandwork
which is by sending vendors throughout
the data command to trigger the battery
network
but this function has a risk problem
after w is removed from machine
there is a low load protection anymore
so there is a risk window before
accessing download type
if the bandwagon finished between this
window
it will cause uaf problem
then
we take a look at when brand work as
afraid before
then radius work
from this picture
we can see after the server receives and
processes the banner object it will send
bc buffer free
command to the kernel
after receiving this command the kernel
will find the corresponding better load
according to a banner wave
and decrease the reference counter
if it is down to zero
the banner load will be reduced
if the rate succeeds
a well-caused standard load to be
reduced before accessing w time
so
how can we exploit this uaf
vulnerability
the key point of the uam vulnerability
is used in the band radius function
there are two branches that can
configure the keyboard operation
so
this uaf problem can be converted into
the
double free problem if
we can control the w type
what we can do with adobe 3 which high
check frame is to allocate a specific
memory and write any content into it
that's interesting
we can use it to modify the swapper to
achieve qsma attack
next i will introduce the details about
this process
there are four steps to complete this
thing
for a uef
problem the first step of course is
using step unit hipsters to modify the
content of a freight buffer
because we want to launch customer
attack
kernel-based adjustment is needed also
and then we'll talk about how to hijack
brain boost and achieve customer attack
it's not easy to do heavy spray as shown
in the december code
from unlocked to use there are only a
few instructions to execute
so the wrist windows
was very narrow thus it's very difficult
to change w type by doing hand spray
this is a
similar problem we have encountered when
exploiting water job
vulnerability
similarly
there are only a few instructions
between unload and use
the race window is also very short
so what increase the success rate of
risk
throw analysis
we found that the wake up q function is
used in the mutax unlock operation
let's have a look at this function
we can see wake up q eventually course
try to wake up to wake up other threat
which means the mutex unlock operation
will actively give up the cpu
therefore we can bind buildable strat
into one cpu
and then use
um mutex lock to wake up other
race threat
by this method you get nearly 100
success rate
but same method can be uh cannot be used
here because spin knock is used in van
der rien at queen workhead
and when spin-off is reduced it will not
wake up other spread that is to say
it will not actively give up cpu
actually there are two main ways to
improve the success rate of history
the first one in old school method just
spend a cpu and increase number of half
spring thread
under preference scheduling
you can always spend a chance in a race
window
a second one is special
increase the number of band objects can
also increase possibility
because better radius work unsealed in
loop assessment work
more band objects means more chance to
create wristing
and another advantage is that spray
figure will enter default branch and it
won't result in any system of luminances
as for the heav spray method we use send
the message
and once the history is completed
a key free operation with an offset
of 8 will be triggered
and if we release the slab or copied by
send message we can build a double phase
scene
after solving these three problems
our next target is to need kernel
address
let's take a look at the method of
converting the double phase first
when double type is tempered with
transaction completed by h3
operation of k3w will be triggered
and
the offset of bandwagon invented load is
8. so a double free with a certain
offset will be formed
this page shows the whole process of
converting the uaf bar into the double
free product
the first step is to use send the
message to do the hip spray
if it raises
succeed
a plus eight will be treated as a heap
and radius
first after calling received message
they will be released therefore a and a
plus h
exceeds uh unfriend news at the same
time
and there is overlap
on memory area
name let's have a look at the second
file structure
sigfi is a common structure type of
virtual file system in linux
multiple files in product directory is
managed as sacrifice
for some spanish software like product
cpu info
op field is a global structure address
which can be used to nix kernel-based
address
so
how to detect the how to mix the op
pointer
there are many five steps
the first step of course is to trigger
the mark and name we need to concoct a
plus eight with banner load
and then we call
the same message to reduce aid
now we can occupy a with signifier
and core band thread rate to rate pdr
out which is the op field of
the circuit file
the following content is relatively
simple
similar to the unique
kernel address
british hijacking can be roughly divided
into six steps
first step
is to spray withstand message after the
bug is triggered a plus 8 will be
released and then we call receiving
message to range a
currently both a and a plus 8 is only
finished
the next steps are very interesting
they will reallocate
a back by sending message and red x into
it
now francis freddie's head is a plus 8
then we call the master gate
and get a plus 8 back now fringe the
head x is x
send a message again
we can write any content into the
address x
now the next step is to
launch customer attack
there are first things we need to pay
attention to
kernel code segment physical start
address is
a20840 and ksma attack's basic map
inside is one gigabyte so fake page
table yields address 870 and
offset 840 is needed when raid will
write kernel code
after each round of attempts it is
necessary to check whether the page
table has been successfully modified
constantly writing explored in c we use
that zhang and long jump to process
exception
if an exception is triggered any means
swapper has been hasn't been modified
yet
according to the previously shared
gamma
we successfully completed the local
privilege escalation
as proven usability of this
vulnerability
they tried to complete the probability
escalation sandbox to take further use
of this power of this vulnerability
there is no doubt that there are many
restriction restrictions in the sandbox
the first one is limited syscore which
means we can't ban cpu anymore
also
buy any devices access is strictly
restricted
not to mention writing files
any chrome sandbox enables its own vpnf
rules
the number one is that chrome is 32 bits
and by kernel in 64 bits
it has two effect the first is that it
will cause its qualcomm patch ability
problem
a second is that ksma attack is not work
therefore when we try to pull the local
scale material sandbox
we encounter two silver challenges
the first one is load bending cpu
so
triggering the bark will be very
difficult
the second one is no ksma
it means we have to find a total new
solution which no one has used before
but luckily send message still can be
used to do hip spray
these two limitations forces us to find
a new solution
which is very challenging
but interesting
we decided to solve the first problem
first
corresponding to hype feng shui we want
to introduce a new concept called cpu
functioning
i think there are two factors that
determine the success rate of race
the first one is time slice
it's a lot harder to understand
that reducing time slice
can increase the possibility to
switch cpu in the risk window
otherwise
increase with schedule time can increase
the possibility to let code block in
different threads execute in a specific
sequence
based on these two factors
we found some key method of cpu
functionality
the first one is creating multiple
padding straps to increase
cpu node
penny thread does nothing but makes cpu
very busy
the second one is to adjust
thread priority
to influence surround time slice and
with schedule time
the last trick is to get currently long
cpu is radiant from prostate file rather
than the gas cpu
this is also helpful for us to do heavy
functioning
after solving the first challenge
we start to solve the second one
before looking for a new solution we
decided to we decided
uh take a new look at historical exploit
examples that
have stable auction reading and writing
and
looking for some inspiration
from these two methods we found
something interesting
that is controlling the pointer to get
after read
and write
let's keep going
the common elements of this two message
is memory issue
but that's why in one testing
it has two elements we just mentioned
through the analysis of these cases we
found two interesting basic elements
the first one is memory share which
means to use the shared data to achieve
arbitrary read and write for example if
structure a and structure b overlapped
and we can use
pointer instruct b to read or write then
we can control pdr
the pointer through structure
to get after read or write
different from the first element
the second element does not focus on
how to control the pointer
but to combine the code logic to achieve
stable object rate in write
this dominates two elements
we found several structures
after they cooperated with each other it
would like the filtering of chemical
reaction bursting out here's power
immediately
first
let's have a let us have a look at a
h-map interface
this structure is saved as a pointer to
file private data
again their functioning of the astronaut
interface can raise a section of memory
from a kernel
if a private port
if the private data pointer can be
tampered with
it can read content from any kernel
address
similarly
you can use the set product mask
function to modify the content
of specified address
but due to the limitation of code itself
the most practical usage is to write
zero
and
with the help of set name function
after write after writing can also
achieve to some extent
now let's take a look at simplify
the first element of six fire and
structure is the box pointer
the data can be rated from box pointer
to the user mode by calling the second
rate of operation
once the buff pointer is temporary it
means we can reading data from any
address
writing the more interesting because the
confirm is only circle bar with
controllable content
and is not subject to permission control
the way to modify its content is to
modify the threading
corresponding operations in the kernel
is divided into two
steps the first is to save thread name
to the task com
when a user tries to read content from
com the kernel will call the construct
function to write content of
column into the memory 25 second firebox
throw circuit print
if the buff pointer can be temporary at
this time
the actual address right is achieved
if item cannot achieve up to rate or
write but it can be used to repeatedly
write up three eight byte data to the
kernel fixed memory
which is
very useful
i have already introduced three
structures and the related functions
that can be used to achieve
actually read and write so how to
achieve this target at first
what we think of is to use ashman
and the powerpoint shows we first need
to modify predator 1
and which makes us be able to modify the
private data too
then we can use
fire to to raise or write tattoo memory
however
the conditions that need to be met are
two nicks and one right
it's difficult to meet right
so
is there a better solution
combining the characteristics of this
solution of this vulnerability
we finally found in a most perfect
solution
first of all
size of these two structures is exactly
so
it can be allocated on the same page
because there is an eighth part of that
when a vulnerability is triggered
if you can make this two structures a
digestion
when you allocate them
you can make data field of import item
overlap with above field of circuit fire
once setup is completed
stable arbitrary read and write can
can be completed without any leak or
right condition
it's either of the plan is determined
only a few steps are needed first step
is to prepare some holes before
circumference will behave functionally
the same step is to fill this holes with
bender load but
here is a little trouble
aopa structure is allocated before
sacrifice and it cannot be deallocated
separately
the solution is to control the
allocation order
through continuous testing we found that
eventually can help us
accomplish this task will
it has several characteristics
first it can be accessed by in the
sandbox
and closing event d will immediately be
allocated to this lab
control a controlling closing sequence
of umd so that slab allocation can be
carried out in a specific order
as shown in powerpoint
we firstly close the event of d3 and the
enclosed event event of d1
and then the order of the hit blocks in
the freighters will be invented fd1
then event of d3
in fact this corresponds to the
allocation order
now after the preparations
we go to create the exec bar and the
structure corresponding to the op field
can separate from the second file
at this point
just close event of d2 again to leave
the hole
before circuit bar
now we can fill the holes with bender
loads
next step is trigger k3 say plus 8 and
allocate the save class 8 back for the
import item
now we have the ability to rate and
write at any address
but we still need to
make the kernel address before we can
continue
however
it is very interesting that we only need
to replace the input item with vendor
load
it's not difficult to find that
the last failed
event load is doubly linked list
which points itself
when initialized
so
when we overwrite the buff pointer with
the pre-pointer content after the banner
load can be leaked
you already
the last step is to close the sdnix and
set the uiid to zero but it's not enough
yet
when writing exploit
we failed to reverse a shell after
closing scenarios and there is no way to
bypass bpf directly
so when we disable ppf
so we have to disable the ppf
setting filter to long won't work
we have to set in the filter
uh to the financing
element to turn off the ppf
finally
i would like to point out some
shortcomings of this
schema
difficult for
the size of sucfar band and load ipo
item structures
are exactly 128
but these structures may differ in
different system versions
the size and of the structure change the
current plane may fail
the second point is that we still need
to adapt this
as linux enforcing
so
could it be done automatically with the
ability of
after read and write
i'd like to do this question for you
finally let me show you a demonstration
we have recorded
at first
we will check the
chrome and the
android version
after check is done we will use the
chrome browser to access
an attacker
and attack
page
as you can see we reversed a shell
and this is a root show
now we use this shirt to install an app
and start it
first we need to download from internet
and
call a pm installed to install the app
and use the am command to start the
activity
let's take us a few
seconds
as you can see app is installed and
started
okay thank you any questions