[Music]
greetings everyone the work we're
presenting today is a summary of the
last three to four years uh researching
industrial robots my name is victor and
i come from india's robotics a robot
cyber security startup together with me
today is federico machi from trent micro
research the fun part about today's
presentation is that it's being given by
two researchers we went out of their way
i myself am a roboticist with about a
decade of experience building robots who
has for the last few years been
researching robot cyber security
federico is a cyber security guy who has
been exploring robotics in the same way
we'll be presenting on behalf of all of
our co-authors our work on reverse
engineering industrial robots
and the findings we encountered in the
process
let's dive into small wonder
so robots
ep
robotics is the art of system
integration
building a robot requires one to
carefully select components that
exchange information across networks
while meeting timing deadlines security
in robotics is really nothing new if
you've done
stuff in it and ot it's a combination of
both a weird combination let's say
there are a few aspects to consider
though uh one relevant when compared to
security is the fact that we in robotics
make a strong distinction between real
time and real fast we use real time as
in traditional control theory that is
real time means deterministic on time
opposed to this we have real fast which
means fast accelerated or simply just
low latency we often found that real
time in some security domains refers to
real fast so mixing them up which is
confusing
and this is important because in a way a
robot is a network of networks one that
comprises sensors to perceive the word
actuators to produce a physical change
on it and then computational resources
to process it all and coherently
responds in time on real time
of course and according to its
application
in the slide on the right side of the
slide you can see a thread model for a
robot manipulator the one you can see
also uh in the screen now this robot you
can see has multiple sensors multiple
actuators and they are all exchanging
information through different networks
each one of these networks needs to be
deterministic so that the overall
control of the robot makes sense and the
robot what does what we expect
this control concept and determinism are
critical and lead us to realize that
security and safety are very very
connected in robotics safety cares about
a robot not harming the environment or
humans whereas security deals with the
opposite deals with ensuring that the
environment does not conflict with the
robot's pre-programmed behavior i think
i speak on behalf of both to say that
federico and i are very very pleased
today to be presenting to an audience
that understands the difference but this
is not what we've been finding over the
last few years in the automation world
robots have their own networks they have
their own technologies safety
requirements and business priorities and
all of these must be uniquely addressed
simply put we can secure robots the same
way we secure it or ot environments
because existing industrial solutions
for monitoring networking traffic often
do not include robotics protocols they
do not include the specific technologies
and robots are typically left beyond the
area of protection assumed as air gap
and even in some cases as some new
solutions in cyber security are
advertising the so-called lockdown
approach this is
far from the security we need in
robotics
from a very technical angle we demand
robots demand their own specialized
measures
that take into account these safety
characteristics these safety aspects so
that robots can behave
safely only if they are secure and this
is the exact topic
we bring up in this slide as well it's
not just ourselves claiming this or many
others out there probably many of you as
well
norms themselves are saying so if we
take a look at the meta standard for
functional safety iec 61508
will observe will appreciate how there
are several paragraphs that literally
account for this and mention that if as
part of the risks that should be
assessed one identifies that security
hazards could lead to safety ones then
one needs to conduct the proper
assessments pen testing thread modeling
things we've been doing in alias
robotics for many years now in robotics
now something very interesting is that
this leads to the fact that safety
requirements spawn from security
research and this is huge for all of us
this is very important this means that
the cbe ids you may get today in those
robots in your kitchen in your streets
in airports wherever they are those cv
ids will need to be accounted for in the
safety subsystems of all of those robots
now we started looking at the industrial
robot as i said about four years ago
approximately
and and we put our target on these
robots which typically range from tens
of thousands of us dollars up to a few
hundreds of thousands so sometimes very
expensive
uh we cooperated with multiple vendors
some of the biggest ones we can say as
of today and one sub-cathetery that
caught our attention are the so-called
collaborative robots these robots are
claimed to be designed to augment human
capabilities by closely and that means
physically cooperating without causing
any harm now
the reality though is that past security
research showed that there are
vulnerabilities affecting this robot
that even as of now 2021 still remain
unpatched we refer to the work of
ioactiv with cesar ferrulo and a few
other folks back in 2017 where they
reported few vulnerabilities affecting
these robots and even as of today they
haven't been passed so this definitely
caught our attention and we'd highlight
that one of the biggest groups uh
particularly it seems following the
strength of not caring as much as they
should about security is teradyne
trading is a big u.s company who has
purchased acquired different robotic
companies including universal robots and
mobile industrial robots we'll be
speaking about this because these are
collaborative robots
that need to be essentially improved
from a security angle
now besides cobots besides collaborative
robots we also uh paid lots of attention
to uh what seemed to be the first uh
instances of obsolescence we observed in
robotics and and the reality
is that uh it's not uncommon for a robot
to fail or to break down
because again a robot is is built out of
many systems and system of systems and
that means that one of these subsystems
may fail over time often leading to the
complete system malfunction given its
interconnection with the rest of of the
overall behavior right so um
we we got scared at the point where we
realized that uh these very expensive
industrial robots um were not easily
repairable and this is what i guess most
of you as well as i did
would expect because uh repairing these
machines often is just about just
replacing one component or even a part
of the robot i just want to grab the
mechanics and just bring them up to
speed with a new controller and that
saved me hundreds of thousands for
example well contrary to to my
expectations and probably to some of
yours uh the reality is not this one and
similar to ford in the 1920s with cars
most robot manufacturers oppose to this
they employ plant obsolescence practices
organizing dealers and system
integrators into private networks
providing repair parts only to certified
companies and discouraging repairs
reversal as well as evading competition
we fought this actively we interfaced
with some of these vendors and we've
reported uh responsively vulnerabilities
and after being ignored repeatedly we
decided we had to take a different
approach so we decided to empower the
end users with the knowledge to protect
themselves
and for that we launched two weeks of
robot packs we launched these exercises
in cooperation with other universities
who contributed as well and in total we
managed to publish more than 100
vulnerabilities altogether
it was a pretty successful exercise
where we learned a lot particularly we
learned a lot about how to interface
with some of these
manufacturers
we'd like to share three main uh
conclusions the first one out of these
exercises was that we definitely
encourage security researchers to adopt
disclosure deadlines of some form we
reckon that vulnerability disclosure is
a two-way street where both vendors and
researchers must act responsively but
the reality in robotics is that the
safety hazards as are such when
connected to security that we definitely
must pressure vendors to reduce
the windows of opportunities that they
give attackers by not mitigating all
these flaws a security first approaching
robotics is a must if we want to ensure
safe robotic operations
the second bit or the second lesson we
learned uh the hard way was that
communication is extremely important and
hard with robot manufacturers many of
these manufacturers are entrained in
security and don't have uh yet the right
uh i guess groups and and qualifications
and as my old boss at open robotics used
to say morgan quickly human apis are the
hardest we experience this uh first
um so that's the second bit be aware and
careful when you interface with robot
manufacturers and the third one which
helps with the second one at least it
helped us with with other manufacturers
is that uh essentially mediators help uh
early in the conversations uh they
helped us very much down the road with
the interfacing with more and more
manufacturers and they definitely uh
will help you as well now
so uh let me share with you uh some of
the actual experiences we've had over
this uh last few years real quick uh the
first one the first quote comes from ole
storm ole is a very funny guy from
mobile industrial robots uh it was he
was the r d manager at the time and only
essentially to our concerns and reports
said that well their business model was
uh just selling these robots to
distributors and and literally they
didn't have control of these robots and
we had to go to distributors if we
wanted these robots to be mitigated and
more secure we were shocked by this
because he was literally telling us that
these robots were not under control and
worse than that they were shifting
responsibility to their supply chains to
their distributors uh so what we did
obviously was we went ahead and we spoke
with the distributors and and again we
got shocked because uh these groups have
had no idea about essentially the
liabilities they were assuming about the
fact that they were in church of
essentially applying mitigations
actually even worse many of these groups
didn't even have the right training or
security know-how to do so so very
concerning as and as you can see these
robots are not especially uh cheap uh we
kept digging kept digging and eventually
uh we spoke with fernando fandinho the
sales director of mir and fernando
finally told us after asking many
uncomfortable questions that essentially
we were not entitled to have access to
the release notes so even if we were to
receive
updates and or upgrades which we never
did
we essentially were not entitled to
receive the release notes which means
literally uh we didn't know what updates
were being applied uh which says a lot
about the transparency of this company
now take a look at the white robot
because that's the one that's being used
here to build
other robots that the so-called
downstream manufacturers or robots and
this robot is the most popular robot
used to fight copyrights these last few
years from uvb uh robots
we spoke with uvd quite a few uh months
ago more than a year ago certainly and
we told them about our concerns we told
them and showed them how we could
remotely take control of one of these
robots we could navigate it around the
hospital and we could even activate the
ultraviolet lights essentially causing
potential
concerns
uh to these concerns to these thoughts
simon told us that well the robot wasn't
connected to the internet so so he
didn't see how it could be externally
hacked
something unfortunately we are hearing
more and more um last but not least is
lars lars is the founder and ceo of
enable robotics and lars just told us he
was aware of the security issues but
that's about it
so obviously we had to uh dive deeper we
had to take a step farther and we did it
by uh taking a step into teardown
in robotics our motivations were
threefold first we wanted to dissect and
analyze
these products to understand better the
safety and security issues they were
facing second we wanted to have a way to
do competitive benchmarking in robotics
this is really hard even as of today in
robotics teardown gives you that
capability and third we wanted to give
to to gain sorry the engineering
experience that is required to serve
customers and help them improve their
robot architectures better federico is
going to tell you more about the whys
and how
thank you very much victor
um the reason that while we're here at
blackit is because we want to give you a
loud message to both roboticists and
cybersecurity folks we would like you to
start
applying these techniques these tear
down systematic teardown approaches
to targets with the same passion and i'm
talking to the security community here
with the same passion that we put for
example to reverse engineer a pure
software artifact because there are so
many targets so many vendors so many
models and different variants that we
really need uh systematic reverse
engineering jobs to be uh published and
documented
um but you know we're fully aware
and
that these targets might not be super
easy to tackle i still remember the way
i felt when i first looked at and this
is only one component of a robot i was
like okay this is full of interesting
things but where do i get started there
are safety relays there's a real-time os
in there with a computer with a
dedicated cpu there are uh there's a
teach pendant out there so it's really
difficult to
for a pure software security person to
even get started
because at the end of the day what you
really want is to get more and more cds
and hopefully inspire
more fixes and have the blue teams
develop good detection signatures
um but
yeah if you're used to
software reverse engineering this is
completely different i think that the
most striking difference is that
well
here you don't have any control z right
so if you look at this machine and you
develop an exploit then you really have
to think for a long long time before you
actually deploy it because you know one
missing check one wrong um
sign in an integer can really change the
the direction of the arm and could
really happen that
for example the hot the arm
hits the the the container and then you
have to i don't know uh send the robot
to maintenance for a few weeks and
that's a lot of time to wait for a
security assessment
let's now dig a little bit into the
methodology
at the beginning i think the good thing
is that the scope of the
teardown exercise is well contained into
these cases which are the robot
controllers you can see two examples on
the left hand side and in the middle
from universal robots which are pretty
much the size of a suitcase
and on the right hand side you see an
older generation of controllers for
larger robots by abb those which work
inside a cage
about tooling i don't want to spend too
much time i just want to make you aware
that well the manufacturers will not
like probably what you're doing so
they're going to make your job a little
harder make sure that you have all the
all the tools that you need including
very exotic screwdrivers for all sorts
of screw heads and of course yes you're
going to break the warranty um make sure
very importantly that you have enough
space but just not just enough space for
a single you know one shot
engagement make sure that you have space
that you can leave all the parts there
for days or weeks depends on how long
you're going to take to find
vulnerability so make sure that you have
a clean space for all the parts to be
laid down
and then we go into the supply chain
mapping step which from my experience is
the most fun part because i mean you get
to learn all the parts used by different
manufacturers for example here we learn
that universal robot like to use power
supply units from artisan and on the
right hand side we learned that well
understandably uh abb likes to use their
own relays for the safety system because
they of course they produce also relays
and so on so it takes lots of pictures
to identify all the parts
and finally if the engagement authorizes
it or if you are the owner of the robot
you can actually do the disassembling
and here one note
you would like to
take lots of pictures as well as
short video clips because you would like
to bring the robot back into
the same you know assemble state because
you want to check your exploits if they
work fine unless of course you have a
mirror unit
about info gathering you need three main
things
manuals which are i mean i'm talking
about technical manuals uh which are
relatively easy to find even if you
don't own a robot you might also start
now right now to uh use your you know
favorite google doors or have a look at
that list of forums that i posted posted
on the right hand side of the slide to
start finding technical documentation
even if you i mean normally vendors do
not make it easy to find but
there are plenty of material around
uh second part you're gonna need
so-called olp or simulation software um
and that's your control z because of
course here it's all simulated so you
have uh all the you know peace of mind
to try all your exploits and then test
the robot get familiar with the
programming language and if you're
curious you can check my la my blanket
talk from last year where we guide you
through all the ecosystems of the main
manufacturers
and finally of course you want the
operating system image but i work i warn
you sorry this is not going to be easy
to find
unless you have a target at hand
right now now let's take a look at the
three main case studies that have been
performed on three different targets um
here you see uh in a larger image the
controller of a universal robot and on
the left hand side the teach pendant
which is also another interesting target
it's usually a tablet a rug tablet so to
speak with its own operating system
the fact that
we don't find the key i mean in this
case there is the key right there but if
we don't find the key to open the cage i
think it's a good sign because it means
that uh whoever deployed that robot has
given some thoughts about physical
attacks which are as victor will show
you later a very easy but also very
effective way to target these machines
then we open the cage and we find out
about the safety system and if we look
carefully we can identify the mcu
so it means that the safety system here
is running in software so engaging and
disengaging the safety relays is a
software decision it's not something
that is only electrically driven
and then we can identify the mcu and we
can take a look at the documentation
from the from the manufacturer of the
cpu sorry of the mcu and we find out
that well at the first glance it looks
like it's a good choice because it's
usable it's useful and
meant for industrial automation but if
we dig carefully in in the
data sheet we find out that the
manufacturer of the chip and xp
semiconductors
warrants against the use of this in
safety or life critical conditions life
critical systems but unfortunately this
is the safety system not just the you
know the the led driver or anything else
of a robot is a safety system of a robot
which decides whether or not um
a collaborative robot in this case uh
must stop or must stop the motors or not
because there is an endangering
condition
in the second generation of the same
series uh we have uh found out that the
manufacturer have made a step forward in
the right direction we believe because
instead of using
an mcu with a firmware they have used a
an fpga which gives you near hardware
performance in terms of
you know engaging and disengaging relays
when it's needed so we think it's a step
forward
uh what we think it's actually a step
backward is the fact that as viktor
anticipated even though the two
the two components the controller and
the robot of the two different
generations are completely compatible
from an electrical and mechanical point
of view and you can see that they're
almost overlapping they have changed the
shape of the connector so if you own an
older generation controller and a newer
generation arm and you want to use them
together you cannot unless you build a
proper adapter so we think it's a step
backward into you know somehow trying to
break the macro compatibility
um
a third case i would just want to
highlight very briefly another
interesting target for
security researchers which you might not
think of that
a simple component such as a motor
driver contains a firmware itself
and if we if we look at once again at
the safety disclaimer put there by the
vendor we learned that dangerous
uncontrolled model runaway conditions
can occur for a number of reasons of
course including faulty firmware and if
you're curious you can download the
firmware from the vendor's website which
i think it's an interesting thing to
put your hands on
and now i want to hand it back to victor
which will show you how
this works in in concrete and what is
the outcome of
see this approach applies systematically
over several years victor the floor is
yours
thank you very good that was that was
awesome so um
as he pointed out let's now take a look
at the results we obtained
the previous case studies federico
highlighted essentially show how robot
teardown is is relevant for quality and
safety inspection as well as cyber
security
research overall
throughout these four years we found
more than 100 security flaws
and 17 out of these were assigned new
cbe ids
unfortunately
those 17 still remain on zero days today
all this data is actually uh publicly
available and disclosed we pushed it to
uh the robot vulnerability database rvd
which is a project that's partially
funded by the european union you've got
a link over there and we encourage you
to check it out to support to help to
help maintain it
and to use it as a resource to also do
your own research
now let us dive now into some of the
examples that uh we poc
for illustrating this findings we had
the first one on the left side of the
slide shows how
essentially we managed to by exploiting
one of these vulnerabilities compromise
the robot and particularly compromise
its safety subsystem by disabling it we
can see how the robot instead of
stopping when it detects an obstacle it
collides directly against it now imagine
this same reality the same situation in
a hospital with a robot carrying
relevant pillows such as blood or
utensils for surgery whatever this is
happening and unfortunately these robots
are vulnerable
the one on the right side shows a bit of
a more complicated
attack in here we are using different
vulnerabilities and
the attacker
would need to have certain
knowledge of the robotic system because
it requires the attacker to essentially
mess up with the computational graph the
computational graph in the robot is the
brain in simple terms and and this graph
essentially uh is in charge of the
behavior overall of the robot um messing
up with the graph means you can really
make the robot do whatever you want this
of course includes also extract or
exfiltrate the information you want
that's exactly what we are showing in
here after pivoting through different
subsystems we reach the main computer we
access the computational graph and
particularly we extract the information
that comes out of the localization
modules we extract the map that's being
constructed and we can see that
realistically of course we could also
access camera images and other
information that's being perceived by
the robot
this third example shows you an instance
of uh ransomware in a collaborative
robot the robots from universal robots
also owned by tedei in this case we're
using a physical attack vector to
illustrate how easy it is to compromise
such a robot uh literally encrypting the
file system disabling the safety
mechanisms
and of course asking uh for a ransom now
we are demonstrating it here with a
physical attack vector but the same
exact thing can be done via network
attacks we can do it through local
networks or even adjacent networks and
many of these robots are unfortunately
connected directly to the internet uh so
definitely concerning and definitely
something we need to work
against which led us to share with you
um our thoughts on this uh which point
towards the direction that we should
really be very careful about which
robots we place our trust and and we
should take security uh very very
seriously immediately
as federico pointed out we uh appreciate
uh appreciated sorry certain uh changes
in the electronics of these
collaborative robots across different
versions across older and nowhere
versions but we found no real reason why
backwards compatibility uh
should be an issue between these robotic
arms
this would mean essentially that
customers with another version of the
robotic arm could repair or reuse the
mechanics and bring it up to speed with
the new controller which may or may not
add new capabilities without being
forced to pay a premium price and we are
speaking about tens of thousands of us
dollars and so in some cases much much
more than that
unsurprisingly uh we observed that the
manufacturer introduced subtle changes
meant to make this particular intent
harder which we can only justify as what
appears to be attempts to exercise
obsolescence practices
a number of such actions includes the
obscurity we observed around the changes
introduced with newer versions of the
robots particularly these changes can be
summarized as adding
an extra sensor a six axis four start
sensor at the tip of the robot to gain
additional sensing capabilities
uh for smaller behaviors and new uh
behaviors overall now the exact same
thing can be done in the uh older
version of the robot and the lack of
transparency once again uh will impact
end users and and will make them uh or
force many of them to buy complete new
sets against spending many many many
resources in a very uh much unneeded
manner
so of course we uh we dived deeper we
wanted to uh at least poc ah a way to
bypass these obsolescence practices and
we developed two prototypes the first
one which we named controller adapter
allowed us to electrically interoperate
older and newer versions exchanging
controllers with mechanics and so on the
other way around as well
this took us
essentially just
just some crafty mechanical component
with electrical matching uh connectors
for a total bill of materials of under
20 us dollars so pretty pretty simple
fix uh and pretty useful we believe the
second prototype we made was called arm
adapter and we used a raspberry pi to
interface to interface with the
communication signals at the tip of the
robot giving us the capability to drive
the robot around without the need of an
actual controller of course we
discouraged the use of such an approach
in production because we removed
completely many of the safety uh
considerations however with this we
demonstrated how teardown empowered
research to extend the robot
capabilities
and bypass some of the obsolescence
practices and limitations we have
observed
now we don't have time to uh go through
uh all of these quotes unfortunately
which we observed while cooperating with
many manufacturers these last few years
but i'd like to at least stress the last
one which really kind of like got into
our hearts because we once heard uh from
a pretty big manufacturer that they they
literally thought that robot cyber
security was up to the end user of
course we opposed to this statement but
the reality is even worse it's not just
that this is not true it is that cyber
security today is up to the hacker
robots are so insecure that it's really
up to any attacker
uh to to come up with the right exploit
which is very very easy most of the
times and disrupt industrial operations
so
three last sound bites to try to
encourage more proactive research and
mitigations the first one please
note that robots are only safe if secure
second one tear downs are very much
needed for security research in robotics
and we should all together put pressure
on manufacturers to reduce how much time
they take to provide mitigations
third and last but not least we
definitely need a right for repair in
robotics
one that allows us to fight actively
this plant obsolescence practices and
one that allows us to design and come up
with better robotic architectures
we hope you enjoyed our small wonder
journey we certainly did
we'd like to thank
our co-authors all of them it was
awesome to work with you and thank you
so much for all of your afford thanks
also to university of clagenfort and to
those of you who want to learn more
there is a white paper we are publishing
which you can go ahead and read if you'd
like to learn more
and other than that we're open for
questions thank you so much for your
time