[Music]
hello everyone thanks so much for
joining in to this talk uh here at black
cat 2021 i am absolutely honored to be
invited to speak here
my story and my history within our
community is
exciting to me and hopefully it is to
you we'll move into uh into talking
about it but uh my title of my talk is
whoops i accidentally helped start the
hacking branch of a foreign intelligence
service
it uh it was uh really it was a a mix up
on my part not really understanding or
identifying the threat landscape of what
i was walking into and uh just like to
share that story with you i've shared it
a couple of times over the last couple
years uh at different b sides and wild
west hackfest and again thank you so
much for the blackhat community you
allow for me to share my story here
let's get started my name is david
evanden my handle is jedi mammoth and
i'm a hacker a linguist author founder
owner i'm continuously a finder and
always a noob
um new to the community as we all are um
this right here what we're going to talk
about is um of course within the uh the
history of um the project raven program
that was overseas in the united arab
emirates and um
has been talked about by chris being and
been um on the jack um
rice adder show dark knight diaries
again thank you so much for jack for
having me on as well
um so within episode 47 i kind of walk
through a lot of this discussion but uh
but again in this
there's a few other things i'd like to
show and like to share
i'm actually going to share everything
within the capacity of this things that
i did share at b-sides nova that i was
not able to take pictures of or share
very specifically but because this is
black hat we want to be as granular as
we possibly can to the entire community
i'm just going to share everything
um so my story starts off within me
transitioning out of a linguistics
capacity into a hacker for the nsa when
i rotated out of that role
i was offered an opportunity to go
overseas with my wife
to help coalition forces hunt and fight
isis and al-qaeda operatives in the
middle east it was a fascinating job and
we did a really awesome great job for
the first couple of months until we
rotated into a different area of
jurisdiction hunting and finding money
as you can see just in case you don't
really know where the uae is it's just
between saudi and oman and just north of
yemen
so the role that i was offered was as a
targeting or threat hunting analyst
within cyberpoint international
the role was
provided to me by a headhunter within
the dc area
that everything seemed
pretty you know legitimate and even the
people on the ground that i was
interviewing with of course all felt the
same exact thing
the role and opportunities that we were
providing to the area of jurisdiction
was all above board and we all felt very
confident in what we were doing
so um kind of mapped this out again
different things that we've talked about
over there was while we were got on site
we moved into that space
and
we
go to this off-site and
i would say a black site location where
is the villa and the villa is broken up
into different capacities where
management um security you know analysis
and research targeting and so on and so
forth where they might sit and where
they might operate so so this is a good
description right here of what the
different levels of the bill look like
and where we operated that and the teams
that we worked in conjunction with
so when we first step into the the space
initially uh our team or our leadership
on the ground gave us two different
briefings one again the isis and
al-qaeda um
attack leadership that we were i'm sorry
the uh the isis and uh al-qaeda
operatives and the hunt threat hunting
of those
personnel within that that region
and then we turn around giving a
completely different one so again it's
important to understand here that the
state department approval for
prior intelligence professionals within
the united states have very limited
authorities to operate in different
capacities for commercial organizations
so the state department might have given
approval to help for us to help train in
a specific capacity but not actually
performing offensive operations and then
when you get on the ground in the event
that you are performing offensive
operations the local
country might provide their or might put
their own classification on what it is
that you're doing
and that was what was happening here so
uh so personnel will assist with the
development and defense measures of that
um you know that jurisdiction or that
area of authority that that theater if
you will and then um again switching
over there for project dread
really doing offensive operations um in
conjunction with nisa which is the uae's
nsa
basically similar to the nsa
all technical offensive operations and
technical and sigic collection happens
through nissa
so uh this sort of steps into um
starting this process of what we were
doing to track and hunt isis what we're
going to do is walk through
this particular conversation and then
how it moved into
a significantly more
dreadful operation that multiple
analysts on the ground decided to step
back away from and we'll get there
so again in one year the seven wars of
the muslim countries kind of looking at
what the isis and al-qaeda and taliban
leadership and operations within the
area of jurisdiction what they were
doing and how they were operating in
different areas at that particular time
our main focus was the operations that
were happening in iraq and uh and as op
as operatives moved out of iraq into
different countries and
took over different
fobs for operating bases in that region
and allowing for us to provide
intelligence back to different
leadership that might be able to provide
assistance
overcoming those different attack
vectors
so
most of the tracking that was taking
place because of the nature of the way
isis
communicated was from
their feeds at the time again this is
2014 2015 2016
and how they communicated over twitter
twitter handles of different utilization
of keywords keywords that would initiate
or drive different operations in the
region
and while we were doing a lot of this
work the same work and research was
being performed by ran back in the
united states so we use different
twitter applications
and collectively utilized uh twitter api
to pull information and perform holistic
analysis
against the
different keywords different handles
usernames the way the usernames were
designed and where different handles
were created and initiated from
so
again uh chatter cross correlations if
you see different keywords used in
different areas of operation if you see
them used over and over again and then
computational deltas so if you do see
different types of patterns performed
over series of time and then those drop
then you see very similar types of
patterns associated with
maybe
like keywords keywords that are similar
to other keywords
you can begin to see different types of
pattern used within chatter online and
then computational deltas of those
chatters over periods of time
and so um
again moving back to like keyword
analytics being able to perform um
i would you know really it's it's not
you're not moving into artificial
intelligence i would even say you're not
even moving into uh machine learning at
that time it's really just data science
against what is the data that's being
pulled down from different handles and
different keywords across um
uh associated personnel for known
associate personnel at the time we were
operating under the uh ovsc 1203
collection of
uh known targets and that would be two
persons away from a known active target
so if you know somebody's an active
target and you can collect on people
that that they communicate with and then
you can also collect on people that
those first hops communicate with but
not necessarily being able to
communicate collect on the associates of
that third level but you can collect on
the activity that they're doing just not
on the activity of
outside boundaries because we're not
performing in that capacity the
offensive operation of collecting on
that we're able to pull down information
that might just be um on twitter over
the web but in the event that you gain
access to that infrastructure you're
pulling information down you can't do
that outside the two those two lanes and
then um i think at that time
2014 1516 barack obama changed that
regulation from three persons um a three
person circle to a two person circle and
so that was a significant change in the
ability to collect on known targets
again different types of activity that
was going over a period of time this
right here really is
between
2012 and 2013 moving into 2015 for
north sniper conviction that happened on
may 18th but
as you can kind of see like different
types of
people and different handles
within the jurisdiction of duae and
where they might be and correlations
between them and other people that are
known targets
and so as we kind of move into this
space some of the other questions we're
starting to get are
personnel that are raising significant
awareness
to activities that might be happening in
the unite i'm sorry in the uae
and um and rory donahue was one of those
people uh
and
he's actually a journalist out of the uk
but uh the way that it was painted as a
picture for us on the ground was that he
was um a an activist that was a national
security threat in the uae uh and it was
painted a very specific picture that he
might be funneling different types of
information to different organizations
that might
provide a security threat
associated with isis in that in that
region of course after a long period of
time and different research and
multiple other stories including chris
being and other people it just became
clear that this was just absolutely made
up um but as you can see
the stealth falcon which is what was
known within that capacity eventually
turned over to project raven but uh fake
personas that were used in order to
target rory and then those particular
targets and how they were pushed out and
um and how they were perceived to him
in order to deliver different types of
content that would take over his machine
and collect information in reality at
the end of the time what we ended up
learning was that rory's main focus
was a human rights activist to talk
about the injustices that were happening
in the uae so it's very important to
understand that
intelligence professionals coming out of
different regions going to help other
foreign intelligence countries
might be manipulated to perform
different offensive operations against
somebody that that other country
perceived as a threat for a different
purpose other than why those
intelligence professionals and offensive
security professionals or offensive
intelligence professionals might be
there to perform actions again so we
were there for actions against isis and
nakata operatives and then other tasking
came down against people who don't fit
into that
category
so just it's an important um sort of
lesson to keep your eyes open that
things might be spun differently to uh
to force you or allow for you to move
into an area of jurisdiction that you
don't have one the authority to be there
but one uh but two
you wouldn't want to be there in the
first place anyways if you have you know
that level of um understanding that
that's not somebody that really deserves
to be targeted just because they're
raising awareness to human rights um
injustices within a region you know let
them write about it the targeting of
journalists for the sake
of quieting them is something that uh
has been
you know it's it's been frowned upon
it's it's it's against the law in a lot
of countries and it is something that
needs to be protected um across
different you know different capacities
and different uh justice groups
so this is an example of one of the
emails that might have been sent to rory
um i pulled this off of a website i kind
of outlined that from the stealth falcon
and i have a list of uh references at
the bottom of this uh slide deck so you
can pull the different references and do
some mobile research and pause it there
and pull that information if you want to
so um again just kind of talking about
and and and forming into
uh discussing here the human rights of
the middle east so after this sort of
got pushed out became aware that that
was really what his goal was and that um
entire concept or subject matter was
used against him to get him to open
something or click on something that
would then um
download something within his uh his
computer
so you can see
you just make up something that looks
like it's a it's a macro protected
document and all you have to do is just
tell them you have to go enable macros
once you enable those macros as
downloads and we all know that process
download something and uh and you get a
call back from that machine
his particular machine was a was a mac
os so the uh the the different exploit
that was targeted against him to be able
to run that that exploit and gain
persistence on that machine of course
was very specifically crafted and
purchased from
you know different exploit brokers and
and targeted against rory so again um
fight for the right to fight uh so again
using different concepts and subject
matters very specifically to his um
uh i would say his uh his desires to
produce
you know
spoken
rather to speak specifically to the
injustices happening in that region
so after we kind of started to move in
this space and started asking a little
bit of other questions we began also to
get different
questions about following the money now
this is very normal this is a very
normal question hey isis and al-qaeda
how are they operating is the mother
muslim brotherhood
funneling the money if so how is that
happening and can you prove it so we
were um we were asked can you prove that
this is actually happening we said well
do you have a a key or do you have an
idea of what might be happening and of
course they came back to us and said
well we feel like that it might be the
country of qatar can you gain access to
the country of qatar and identify a way
um whether or not they're funneling
money to the muslim brotherhood
so again it was brought back to us qatar
saudi iran and yemen there was different
um you know whether or not be the the
houthi
the houthis or the um you know isis
al-qaeda mujahideen whatever it might
have been but terrorist organization
within that region was the main focus of
identifying how that money was being
funneled to them
they all became targets and uh and then
we we sent a request back and said you
know we need to we need permission from
the state department in order to perform
these actions can we do this and so as
we went from there we got that
permission back and then we move forward
in that conversation in order to say
let's let's begin a target um katada was
our first one and for the first time i'm
actually going to walk through the
exploitation life cycle of how the
country of the uae gained access to the
country of qatar
so what initially happened was it was a
full wall and scan and within hho we
identified a a vpn
infrastructure for hho that gave us
access to that infrastructure within the
infrastructure misa had stood up a
manage engine service desk plus platform
that had a a default administrator
administrator login so we were tunneling
through our hso
access into a private ip address that
had shared infrastructure between hho
and misa just for scanning
we
gain access to that manage engine
services plus machine
routed through that platform dumped the
database on there and then used the
javascript code that was used to encrypt
the passwords in that database reverse
that process and then decrypt the um the
passwords in that database in order to
print them out and play text what we
ended up finding was that not only was
this
managed engine plus machine designed as
a testbed to scan this infrastructure
was also
designed to scan a bunch of other
different machines or different networks
within
the authorities of misa as it pertained
to them being a
state-sponsored msp
and so we from there we were able to
tunnel through misa gain a bunch of
other infrastructure gain access to
amiri flight gain access to manae
mofa uh
qatari foundation and moi so
it was a pretty significant um
access that that it obtained and allowed
for us to gain access to
pretty much every military and
government entity within the country of
qatar
there was different area of jurisdiction
within different countries they wanted
access to this they wanted access to
that and the whole entire goal was to
in that capacity was to gain access to
moi so it was assumed that the ministry
of interior if there was money being
funneled out of the country was
happening through there
and then in other countries
you know it might have been like nuclear
research that might have been happening
against you know within the country of
iran so targeting different
university researchers and so on and so
forth was our main area of jurisdiction
uh so
intel requests at that point in the
country guitar started deviating from
our mission plan and they wanted flight
patterns for
the uh qatari rural family and so on and
so forth and those became you know kind
of suspicious so um as we started asking
more and more questions that's when the
initial deviation started between or
when when the um
when the exit strategy began to get put
into play for moving away from um
cyberpoint as a a contracting agent and
then moved into dark matter
and so dark matter you go to their
website take a look
they are state-sponsored organization
for the country of the uae to perform
actions against um foreign intelligence
organizations apart from the uae
they are just an offensive intelligence
shop whether or not it be intelligence
gathering intelligence collection
offensive operations
research exploitation development so on
and so forth um it's been a while since
i've done my own research against this
organization
but from what i understand they're not
the primary organization doing this has
been broken up into a bunch of different
groups now so if you still are
interested in doing that research
there's a bunch of different people that
you can talk to even within about the
united states that are continuing to do
that research you might be able to ask
them different questions
but for instance you go to the site and
you take a look at it
there's no links if they're a commercial
organization uh you would expect to see
some type of way to
hire them for their business a way to
perform different actions but there's
nothing on their website to be able to
reach out to them
so um
uh that was a that's a pretty
significant indicator that an
organization may not be legitimate
so
um again dark matter and departure when
raven was created in 2009 i would www a
little cyber expertise
and over the course of five to ten years
mri intelligence officers
were skilled enough to take over
documents um shown and in 2013
uh the uae really went into and hired
cyberpoint in order to bring them over
to the uae in order from those
operations in late 2015 the power
dynamic of the villa shifted as uae grew
more uncomfortable with the core
national security program being
controlled by foreigners so we kept
telling them no we can't do that if you
see an isis or a kind of personnel move
into the country the united states we
can't track them we can't follow them if
they use a piece of infrastructure that
is within the boundaries of the united
states we don't have permission to gain
access to that so it was it was some of
this stuff was really slowed down and
that was one of the main um
one of the main uh i would say driving
forces to move away from using
uh u.s sponsored personnel and um
contracting organizations
so
we were really told either you're
joining here or you're leaving obviously
people who are loyal to the united
states are not going to do that we're
going to so we we jumped ship and came
back to the u.s
so some of the lessons learned in my
capacity would be if it's too good to be
true if you're giving too much money if
you're going to different spot
everything seems to be wonderful and
perfect
it's too good to be true
vet your leadership that was one of the
main things that i learned out of this i
did some leadersh some research on the
leadership on the ground there
and they came back and said yes they're
known they're aware of them
i should have dug more deeper into that
because after i left i asked even more
questions into that and of course there
were stories that came out of that that
i should have been
aware of or cognizant to
if you move to a foreign country and
they take your passport for any period
of time other than 24 hours that should
be pretty significant and pretty it
should worry you a lot
always ask for printed and signed
documentation of your authorities to
perform operations for in especially if
those authorities are signed by the
state department so you can vet to make
sure that that you actually have
permissions to be doing that documents
i'm sorry to be doing that work
um as in you're doing construction work
you're building something out you
measure twice you cut once i've really
learned ask twice hack once make sure
that you're hacking the right targets
make sure you have permission to be
doing that remember your training that's
that's really important too if you get
those hairs standing up on your arms you
start to feel really uncomfortable um
you need to step back and say my spidey
sense is going off here i need to i need
to to
to change what i'm doing have an exit
strategy if you move overseas to work
overseas and you don't have an exit
strategy you don't have a plan to get
out of there that's that's pretty
important part of this process
whether or not your organization that
you're working with provide you an exit
strategy you also need one yourself
it's always important family is your
most important asset if you move over
somewhere else by yourself and is your
intent to live there long term
awesome that's great if you move over
somewhere else with a family make sure
that you know what to expect when you
get there what's going to happen the
first two weeks is 60 days
and and if you're going to have enough
food if you're going to have enough
money and if you don't have enough money
what is your backup plan in the event
that you don't um
it is uh it's really important it's a it
was a really good
lesson to learn for our family
again here's our citations
and uh if you have any questions and
you're in person here that's great i'm
happy to answer any questions come up
and meet me and talk to me
if you're online my handle is jedi
mammoth as you can see here feel free to
reach out to me on twitter
thank you so much and again to blackhat
community thank you for listening to
this story hopefully it's helpful
hopefully you learned a few things in
the event that you rotate out of the
intelligence community united states or
anywhere else any other country
and you want to go work somewhere and
you're wondering about whether or not
it's a good idea take some take some
lessons from me and take notes
know that where you're going to go work
what jobs you're going to be doing who's
your leadership on the ground and are
they a vetted resource thank you so much
again
bye