hi everyone thanks for coming to my talk
it's my pleasure to present this work on
the automated analysis of TLS 1.3 so
costs and I did this work at the
University of Oxford
I was his PhD student there and
currently I met MPI for software systems
in Germany and Simon Tyla work at or our
PhD students at the Royal Royal Holloway
University of London and they did part
of their this work there as well as at
Mozilla for their internship so let me
situate our work for you first
so TLS as you might know has a long
history of being broken and fixed and
our contribution to this field came
about in the Year 2015
so the the best part of it was spent to
analyze TLS 1.3 and in October the cool
stuff started to emerge so what we do
our formal methods in particular the
symbolic verification of security
protocols and we consider our work to be
complementary to the provable security
work that's being done and here are four
great papers cited so the difference
between our work and theirs is that they
do a deeper analysis in a way but we do
a broader one we recover all the
different modes of TLS 1.3 and their
complicated interactions with each other
and with the old protocol modes so this
new version of TLS TLS 1.3 is designed
to be more efficient than TLS 1.2 with
the three new modes so the zero
round-trip time handshake mode basically
allows clients to encrypt some
application data for servers when they
meet again or when they resume a session
on a different connection so this this
encrypted the message can be put in the
client hello message
and so it's sent immediately on a return
visit the pre shared key or PSK mode is
a way for both clients and servers to
use preciate keys that can be
established either out of bound or by
running the TLS 1.3 protocol and they're
used as building blocks to compute
session keys more efficiently so less
computation is needed
lastly the delayed client authentication
mechanism is a way for servers to only
authenticate clients when they really
have to so for example you can imagine a
client browsing through a public portion
of a website and then they try to access
some secure or sensitive resource or
login to a secret part of the website or
private part and only then do the server
does the server need to authenticate
them so our goal was to improve the
security of TLS 1.3 by analyzing its
specification by using state-of-the-art
formula analysis methods and tools and
what we focus on our interaction attacks
so we assume that cryptography is
perfect or blackbox so basically that it
works as it should so either you have a
key and can encrypt decrypt and sign
messages with it or you don't
so you can't possibly do it and we
assume that the attacker is a dollar
Viau style attacker which means that he
can position himself in the middle of a
connection and then eavesdrop on a
tamper with and inject messages as well
as corrupt the or compromised the long
term secret keys of the protocol
participants that aren't directly
involved in the session that is under
attack so the interaction attacks by
this I mean inadvertently added
vulnerabilities that are exploited due
to some sort of you know composition of
these different handshake modes so when
we were building a model for what we
first did was infer a client and this
server state machine from the
specification and as you can see here if
you start at the initial state for the
client this is the client state machine
what the client can do is either start a
new session by doing the c1 transition
he can on the on a repeated visit to a
server he can try to initialize a
pre-shared key mode which then branches
out into two different modes one is the
difficult man ephemeral mode where a
difficult man ephemeral secret is used
for forward secrecy and the pure PSK
mode is used if forward secrecy is not
an issue and it actually features even
less computation than the PS KDHE hand
check and lastly there's the known
configuration mode which is basically
the zero round-trip time mode so on the
repeated visit to a server a client can
use this server configuration message
that he got from from the server with
which he can he can use a part of it to
encrypt the application data immediately
for the server without going through the
ordeal of setting up a new TLS session
keys and then there's the question of
client authentication so it's nice and
uniform this is why it narrows this
state machine narrows there so the
server may ask the client to
authenticate it then they may or may not
do so and the rest is not relevant for
this talk so as you can see it's it's a
complex beast and there can be any
number of clients and servers engaging
in you know any number of sessions so we
really need it unbounded verification
here unbounded in terms of both breadth
and depth when I say breadth I mean the
number of concurrent sessions or parties
and unbounded the depth I mean the
number of repeated handshakes and
retries due to parameter mismatches
so we needed a tool of course so we
encoded our model for use in the timer
improver which is a state-of-the-art
tool for automated protocol analysis
that's built at ETH Zurich in
Switzerland and it supports loops which
is important for the repeated handshakes
and retries it supports branches which
is very important for all this these
modes of the protocol that need to be
verified and it's also has state of the
art difficult math of symbolic difficult
mode support which allows us to actually
consider the core security in the TLS
protocol which is based on the difficult
man exchanges
however this tool requires considerable
user interaction for such a complex
model however we use tamarin to verify
the core properties of TLS 1.3 revision
10 as an authenticated key exchange
protocol which means that we prove that
the session keys are secret with the
forward secrecy included so for experts
we don't allow our adversary to to
compromise the semi static difficult man
exponent of the server so this is why
this is a full kind of perfect forward
secrecy here then we have the
authentication properties so servers
always properly authenticate to clients
and clients if required and they want to
properly authenticate to service and the
handshake messages cannot be tampered
with without at least one honest
participant noticing this the last thing
that we wanted to check is whether it
was safe to include the delayed client
authentication mechanism in revision 10
and for this particular version of it
which is the initial proposal which came
about at IETF 93 which is this
unrestricted variant tamarin says no so
we managed to use stammering to find an
attack on this unrestricted version of
the deal
client authentication mechanism so this
unrestricted version works as follows so
basically a server can after any
handshake require a client to
authenticate okay and if a client
decides to do so then there you have the
C oath read transition so the attack the
attack that Tamron finds goes something
like this imagine Alice who's a client
of a bank and she wants to connect to
her bank okay so she wants to access her
bank account
unfortunately Charlie at evil.com sent
her a phishing email and you know it
looks nice it's Alice who falls for it
and then she actually decides to connect
to him and establish a PSK by using TLS
1.3 revision 10 with the unrestricted
delayed client authentication mechanism
so there's the that they establish this
PS k1 appreciate key and Charlie let's
say knows Alice's Bank my bank comm
which Bob is running and he would
ideally like to access her bank account
and then transfer all of her money to
him so what he does is connect to my
bank calm and establishes PS k2 with Bob
okay so far so good these two keys are
different these two sessions are
different so and a completely legitimate
there's been no funny business yet but
let's look at the second stage so
imagine that Charlie now cuts the
connection to Alice and then Alice comes
back trying to resume it on a different
connection and she sends her client
random value and see in her client hello
she generated a fresh valuing see
Charlie then reuses he's a client in
this other session right the PS k2
session he decides to resume the session
with Bob by reusing this NC value and
bob says okay sure let's resume the
session
and he generates a server random value
of NS for his server hello
and Charlie constructs his server hello
again by reusing this NS value this time
so you might have noticed that the
session hash values in the bottom there
that are filling up so the the session
hash is basically a hash of a partial
transcript in a session so in this
particular case it has NC and NS however
these have been made the same on in both
sessions and this is actually enough to
make the session hashes in both sessions
the same this is a very unfortunate
trait of revision ten all right I forgot
to say the client finished messages also
go through no problem because Charlie
knows PS k1 and PS k 2 so he can build
these confirmation messages so in the
second part again there hasn't yet been
anything terribly illegitimate but the
the session hash has been made the same
by Charlie in both sessions and this is
what Charlie will now leverage to steal
Alice's money so now he tries to log in
at my bank comm as Alice which prompts
Bob who has no idea who he's talking to
apart from the fact that that person is
claiming to be Alice Bob now requests
authentication from whoever is on the
other side and it's it's Charlie of
course Charlie now needs some sort of
excuse to ask Alice for her
authentication let's say that she
clicked on something at evil comm or
maybe she tried to log in to her account
of course that's a bogus form that
Charlie made and Alice says sure I mean
I should probably authenticate now if if
Charlie says so so she sends him his her
certificate public key certificate as
well as a signature over the session
hash and a certificate and now the
problem so Charlie couldn't possibly
Forge this message himself because he
doesn't have the secret key of Alice he
couldn't forge the signature but he
could reuse it entirely and relay it to
Bob as an authentication package because
the session hashes are the same and
these are the only things that bind are
supposed to bind the signatures to their
respective session which obviously
didn't work here so when Charlie says
give Charlie all my money to Bob then
Bob will say sure thing Alice so we
posted our analysis results and this
attack to the TLS mailing list at the
end of October 2015 and their responses
we got were quite positive let me read a
few for you nice analysis I think that
the composition of different mechanisms
in the protocol is likely to be where
many subtle issues lie and analyses like
this one support that concern thanks for
posting this it's great to see people
doing real formal analysis of the TLS
1.3 draft this is really helpful in
guiding the design this result motivates
and confirms the need to modify the
handshake hashes to contain the server
finished when we add post handshake
authentication so the thing here is that
the session hashes would already have
been the same if they contained the
server certificate so if you remember on
the one side we had the server charlie
and on the other we had the server Bob
and there are certificates of course
differ so if already the server
certificate was in the client signature
then this attack would have been
prevented however what the TLS working
group actually suggested was to add the
full finished message which contains
which is basically a confirmation of the
full crown
not a partial transcript a full
transcript into the client signatures
because I mean into the session hashes
which would transitively also include
them in the client signature and this
would help of course bind the client
signature to a session as the name
session hash actually implies of course
so our attack shows that the initial
proposal for delayed client
authentication is incomplete it also
shows that it's strictly necessary to
bind client signatures to server
certificates and as I said the working
group proposed to include the full
transcript in the form of the finished
message to the signature to binder the
signature to the the client signature to
sessions and this proposal was actually
merged in revision 11 which prevents our
attack to sum up this was the first and
to the best of our knowledge only
comprehensive analysis of the new TLS
1.3 modes and their interactions and
this story actually has a happy ending
because we managed to successfully
verify revision 10 by using tamarin and
we also use stammering to find an
interaction attack on the delayed client
authentication mechanism and our the
proposed fix was verified and also
included in revision 11 for our future
work we would like to update our model
and two to revision 13 and then verify
that perhaps with respect to a stronger
adversary model and with some new
properties that we have in mind and let
me just say that we believe that our
work is just one piece of the puzzle
just like Felix said actually and we
would like to continue being part of
this larger concerted effort of
different approaches to hardening TLS
1.2 1.3 that we believe all of them are
valuable thank you
Christian's right so it's a pretty
fascinating what you can find with tools
like tamarind the attack you've
described at least in the slide seems
somewhat complicated and using and uses
phishing and the kind of things you can
do with phishing or sort of by
themselves are quite complicated and
powerful so I'm curious if there's a way
to abuse this kind of weakness that you
found without fishing well as long as
you have a reason for Alice to connect
to a malicious entity that's you I mean
she she doesn't know of course that the
entity is malicious if there's anything
other than fishing that you can use then
yes okay so I'm C Tremezzo from Terrence
consumption so cooter Miller why so you
choose at a Marine tutor to dis analysis
sorry could you tell me the reason why
you choose at hammering at the to hoe so
so the reason is it had everything we
need it right so it had the inductive
reasoning so we could deal with loops it
had non monotonic state which is one of
the reasons it was built in the first
place so we could deal with branches in
the in all these modes right and the I
guess the third reason I brought up was
the symbolic difficult and support which
is actually the second of the two most
important reasons that it was built
thank you
is it correct to say you can actually do
it without fishing because I think
actually if Alice just visits any
arbitrary website the attack will still
work so as long as the website is
malicious sure that's true