as if box in as if browser books weren't
bad enough I'm here to present an attack
which the explosive browser without
requiring requiring and the box it in
the browser so I'm going to abuse
deduplication inside a channel which
together with row hammer which is a
hardware bug and together they allow us
to exploit a modern browser Microsoft
edge without the use of any additional
books in the browser itself from
JavaScript so in short how are we going
to do this we will use the deduplication
side channel attack to leak information
so leak a hip pointer to date that we
control and then combine this with code
pointer appointed to the process
javascript library and these two secrets
allow us to create a fake object and
this fact objects will yeah we will use
row hammer to flip up a bit in a pointer
to make to make yeah to get a reference
to this fake object and this fake object
will allow us to have an arbitrary
readwrite primitive and own the browser
so how does this deduplication side as a
side channel attack work well say an
attacker has control for some memory and
a victim as its own memory and the
attacker wants to know whether a certain
picture is inside outer space of the
victim so in this case it is what the
attacker does is recreate the pages that
it wants to probe for
in its own address space and then it
waits for the operating system or a
hypervisor so for example Windows 8.1
and higher have this feature as well as
some virtualization hyper some
hypervisors they will scan memory and
identify pages which are similar and
will point the all the memory to the
same place and this saves memory but the
problem is and that yeah so the kernel
or the hypervisor will mark this memory
copy-on-write so why is this a problem
well if you do a normal right to a
memory page which is not marked
copy-on-write
it will go very fast and then but the
deduplicated page has to be as to be
copied first before the rice can happen
and this takes longer and this take yeah
this takes longer and you can measure
this from JavaScript so this is all nice
if you want to leak the content of
entire page but can we generalize this
to leaking a small bit of information
like the randomization in the pointer or
password so turns out we can but there
are some challenges that we have to
overcome so first of all the small
secret it does not span an entire page
so we need to turn this secret into a
page so we need to find a way to get a
secret together in the page with all
known data so that we can protect we can
we can predict what the whole page looks
like another problem that we can have is
that the secret is just just too many
much entropy and if we wanted to scan
for every possible value of this
secret we exhaust our memory so to solve
this we have in the paper we have to
well
three primitives which will help us with
redo with finding out the secret
nonetheless one is we control alignment
of the secret where we only have part of
the secret in a page such that we have
we can leak the information in two or
more steps and this allows us to this
allows us to reduce the entropy and leak
the information we have a second
primitive which where if you cannot
control the linemen but possibly
overwrite parts of the secrets in memory
we can we can reduce the entropy that
way so for our browser attack we use the
first method of controlling the
alignment to make use of the jet
function in the compiled jet function
epilogue in Microsoft edge and because
we control the function we can create
functions which are just slightly larger
than one page so that the function
epilogue is on the border of a page and
then some some of the functions will
have the code address which is in the
function epilogue actually we come to we
know all in from the hole all
information in the epilogue except for
the code address so that's what we want
to leak so if we create a jet function
with the code address just on the
boundary we can leak this code address
in multiple steps and every step we can
fill in the parts that we already know
so then there is a final possibility
that we cannot
/ right part of the secret or align this
something are we then lost this is not
always the case so in the case of
finding our heat pointer in our browser
exploit we couldn't find an alignment or
yeah a way to control the alignment or
to override a part of it but then but
then there is another solution so this
we can still lick a hip pointer making
use of an observation called the
birthday problem which tells you that
the surprisingly small they are given
this surprisingly small group of people
the chances of two of them having the
same birthday gets really high
relatively soon and the underlying
iteration about this is that you're not
doing not doing a comparison one
comparison of someone's birthday with
some others birthday but you are doing
all comparisons at the same time and if
you think of it
memory deduplication does this as well
so we abuse this functionality in this
case we were leaking pointer so we
generate lots of pointers any of them
will be the pointers to objects that we
control and if them will be okay for us
at the same time way we probe for lots
of pointers and we only have to have one
match and this match will be done by the
deduplication mechanism which justice I
need to any comparison so in memory
looks like this you have we have
pointers to real objects and then we
have we guess pointers to fake objects
and then we just create some of them and
after not that many
well we don't have to create that many
to get a hit
so the duplication mechanism make sure
that both pages point to the same
physical page and then we can do our
deduplication tests by writing to it and
get memory so now we have leaked the
code pointer and the hip pointer so we
can create a fake object which allows us
to do readwrite but we still need a
reference to it and the JavaScript
engine for good reasons doesn't allow us
to do this so what we do is we create
this object inside an X extend data
structure a JavaScript array and then we
have another one right next to it and
now we need to pivot a reference to the
one the second array onto the the first
int onto our fake object and we do this
by inducing a bit flip using a row
hammer so row hammer is the hardware
vulnerability where where the
observation is that if you access a
certain row in memory very quickly a
quick succession the the neighboring
rows experience interference and some of
the neighboring rows bits can flip so in
our case we we used a bit flip to so we
are we find bit flip a memory that's
that you can flip and then we insert the
right pointer in this memory location we
hammer the point pointer flips and we
get a pointer to our object
and then we can have arbitrary read
rights
so in short memory deduplication is way
more powerful cycle than previously
thought in our paper we also have an
example of leaking information from a
different process and yeah it's possible
to do reliable browser exploitation in
JavaScript that's it
any question hey thanks so how long do
each of these two parts of the attack
take so how often is the OS or the
hypervisor doing this deduplication
because you have to guess the lot of
values in Windows ok and windows it's
every 15 minutes as we tested every 15
minutes yes but don't you have to like
gas to the yes 8 if not 16 so we haven't
studied the exact mechanism with which
it is being done in Windows in in Linux
it's it's or it's being done right every
once in a while yeah just just they
merged several small pages just ink they
just kinda memory I'm allergic pages row
hammer flips a random bit and then you
have to check did was i lucky no try
again how so how long does this whole
attack take it depends on the the
deduplication
attack it takes about 30 minutes we need
two sweeps for the code for three so and
then the the row hammer attack really
depends on how vulnerable here
memory is Touro hammer right okay my
question is more related to the RO
hammer how did you reliably find that if
if the f1 bed I flipped this bit it's
going to convert into a pointer to the
other location so you need deikun
instance so there in the description in
paper but what the justice that we in
edge you can have pointers and double
values in the same location in the same
type so we put a double value there and
that we can completely agree we can read
so we do ro hammer and then see if the
double value changed and then see which
bit changed that's kind of interesting
if you do ro hammer it's usually the
same bit that flips again and again and
it's directional yeah so so so we have
doubles in an array and then when we
know which bit flips we we put a pointer
there a reference to an object and then
so in h4 this this you can put it in the
same location but the details are in the
paper so my complimentary question to
that is the same physical page was being
used when you are doing the attack so
first time you do the you do the rec on
that okay this bit is flipping and once
you know the knowledge that this bit is
flipping after you have after that you
have to reuse that physical page you
have to force the system to use reuse
the physical page for the same data
object so what behavior you saw there
was it was edge using the same physical
page I said the roham I said yes said so
actually for row hammer we make sure
that Windows doesn't de doop the pages
where ro hammering otherwise it will
screw up the
the yeah the the voices will screw up
the whole well the measure so the
measurements will both the robot will
not work anymore but so so it's always
the same page that so if you find the
bit flip using so you hammer one one
location or it's actually two but and
then it's the and then the neighboring
rows will get bit flips