so before I get started I want to talk a
little bit what i mean by when I say
residual trust it's a very simple
concept it's simply the historical
reputation of a domain that's implicitly
transferred with a change in ownership
and this residual trust can be either
positive or negative depending on
whether the historical reputation of
that domain was good or bad and this has
a number it's kind of a number of
different security concerns that result
because of this so let's look at a
couple examples of those I'll start out
with an example of an expired name
server domain so in this case there was
an educational institution called
benedictine university they were using a
third-party domain for one of their
secondary name servers at some point
this domain was actually allowed to
expire so what's the big deal here well
that domain was subsequently
reregistered by an SEO company that
wild-card the MX record so this meant
that all the email at all the emails
that were sent to addresses that that
domain were getting sent to this SEO
company and this is particularly
problematic given that some of these
email addresses were for students and
for students are protected by certain
privacy laws like FERPA an even more
challenging aspect of this was this was
a particularly difficult problem to
diagnose because of the secondary name
server so this meant that the emails
were only getting forwarded to this SEO
company intermittently it wasn't
constantly happening so clearly that's
not a good thing but it actually gets
worse so we also see a case where we
looked at the email addresses used as
the point of contact information for
regional internet registries and these
email addresses were actually being used
as trust anchors and what I mean by that
is they were being used to verify that
you were who you were so you could login
to the login portal and administer the
siders that you had control of so we
actually found that there were hundreds
of these email addresses that were under
expired domain names and these were
available for immediate reregistration
so what this meant was that anyone could
go and buy one of these domains say it
stand up their own mail server go to the
login portal and request a password
reset this meant you could log into the
the portal with your new credentials and
now you could make unauthorized changes
to IP allocations clearly this isn't
something
you want happening on the internet but
that's not all we also evaluated another
case where we looked at approximately
forty one thousand plugins from the
Mozilla store and when we analyzed these
plugins we saw that they they reached
out to about 3,000 unique domains for
all of these different plugins and about
five percent of those domains were
actually expired so again we have
another problem here where the we had a
problem where anyone could go and
reregister one of these domains and some
of these plugins had tens of thousands
of installs and after registering this
they could use that domain to request a
password reset on a developer account
and now push down their own updates to
end-user browsers so in essence you kind
of got a browser botnet for the price of
a domain but that's it doesn't just
affect user level software we've seen
the case where it affects actually
repositories used by operating systems
for updates so there was a popular
third-party repository called Debbie and
multimedia org that was used for
obtaining multimedia applications that
were outside the license that Debian
wanted to offer and / the requests the
Debian maintainers they wanted more
separation between so it didn't look
like they were endorsing this this
third-party repository so the acid that
changed the name so they registered a
new domain called Deb multi-beam org and
let the old domain expire well that old
domain was subsequently there was
unknown to the Debian community so again
what's the problem here well the
purchaser could have used that domain
and stood up their own repository to
push down update for system packages
including the kernel or even base system
software and while it's true that there
are protections in place like key
signing to protect against unauthorized
repositories from pushing updates to the
system it's still possible for that new
owner of the domain to go to the
internet archive stand up the old page
exactly as it was and update the keys so
any about any new users going from
how-to tutorials or other references on
the wet to that website would just use
this new malicious repository so we've
looked at a couple examples of some of
the different types of problems that
this residual trust can cause when it's
abused oh but one other question that
remains is you know how big of a problem
actually is
so we performed a long-term study over
six years where we tried to analyze just
that and we use three different data
sets the first is a data set of expired
domains this was collected since 2008
all the way up through 2015 and it
contained approximately 180 million
expired domain names over that period of
time so the next data set we use we used
a malware domain data set and this had a
number of domains that were being used
by malware at some point in time and
this was collected since early two
thousand nine through July 2015 and we
saw about 6.1 unique 6.1 million unique
domained in this data set and these were
domains that were likely being abused
and the last data set is a more human
curated list of domains that are likely
being abused and this is a blacklist of
main data set and we collected this
since 2009 up through mid-2015 and this
contained approximately 320 thousand
unique domains so this is the table that
shows the relationship between these
different data sets and we discussed
this these relationships more in the
paper so i'm not going to go into all
the details of this table but what i
will look at is i want to call attention
to a couple different numbers in this
table the first is this we this is the
intersection between the expired domains
and the Mauer domains so these are
domains that could likely be considered
candidates for residual trust of use and
there when we saw that there were about
300,000 of these domains in our data set
here this was about five percent of all
mauer domains were expired at some point
in time additionally when we looked at
the intersection between the black lists
and the expired domain list we saw that
there were about a hundred thousand
unique expired domains in this data set
and that this was about almost a third
of all public blacklist domains had
expired at some point in time so some of
you might be asking or saying well this
raises another question when did the
abuse happen did it happen before or
after the expiration if they were abused
before the expiration this likely wasn't
a case where they were abusing any trust
in the domain but if they were abused
after expiration this means that there
was some residual trust associated with
that domain name that they were likely
abusing and what we saw was that
there were about two hundred sixty three
thousand unique total abusive domains
for blacklist and the the Mauer data set
and this meant that almost ninety
percent of the domains that were being
contacted by malware that it expired
were only contacted after the domain
expired so these were likely candidates
to of residual trusted views similarly
about ten percent of the blacklist
domain expired were abuse only after
expiration so again these are other
likely candidate for that residual trust
abuse so another question is is this a
we saw that there were a fair number of
domains that were being abused but it's
just a growing problem so I want to
highlight one thing about this this a
particular figure and that's that this
only shows domains that were abused
after expiration so any domains here
were abused only after expert and that's
why they're above the diagonal on the
left hand side here I want to highlight
that this is showing domains that were
contacted by Mauer only after expiration
that had higher Alexa ranks so what we
observed is that there appear to be
domains that are even fairly popular
that expire and that subsequently might
be registered by Mauer and being
contacted for abuse and on the left hand
side these are the domains with lower
lower Alexa ranks that were contacted by
malware after expiration for abuse and
what you'll notice here is that as you
move up towards the top right you'll
notice that the the plot is getting a
little bit denser and when this happens
what we're seeing here is that there
there are more expirations there are
more domains being abused after
expiration in more recent memory so this
is a trend that seemed to be growing in
fact to highlight this in numbers we saw
that between 2009 and 2012 there were
only about 6,000 domains that were
abused after expiration but this doubled
in 2013 alone to 12,000 so you might be
saying well okay this is mauer these are
this is am our data set Mauer doesn't
always contact a malicious domain some
of these might be denied domains that
mauers contacting and that's what we're
seeing here so we actually looked at
this same graph but for the public
blacklist domain and remember the public
blacklist are human curated list so
these are less
like you to have the benign domains that
are seen in the the Mauer data set and
what you'll notice is you see a same the
same kind of trend here we see this
growth and again in numbers between 2009
at 2012 we saw 800 expired domains in
the blacklist that we're then used for
abuse that number jumped to 9,000 in
2014 alone large increase this seems to
be a problem that people are
increasingly exploiting so how do we
even go about finding some of these
changes well we can look for expiration
but that's not the only way that a
domain can change ownership so we
actually put the lightweight algorithm
call the limbic and this light week
algorithm is helps identify potential
ownership changes using only DNS and one
of the one thing to keep a note about
this algorithm is it's not a fully
automated detector so it helps locate
these events but it's not a a classifier
or anything of that nature and again I
want to highlight it only relies on DNS
components to compute a change of
ownership score which is how we rank
likely ownership change events and it
does not rely at all on who is
information so some of you might ask
well why not why not who is who's used
to is here who's tried to collect who is
at scale who hates your life because you
tried to collect who is it scale exactly
yeah so who is is an awful thing to try
to collect a scale different registrar's
have different policies about how many
queries you can collect at any given
time who is can lie and it can lie in
unexpected ways and you know once you've
collected it it can be challenging to
parse so we avoid all that with Olympic
so how does Olympic work well we have we
use a window and within that window we
compute several different components one
is we look for infrastructure changes
around a given point in time so we
measure the changes in the host that a
domain points to between the within this
temporal window so if we see big changes
in infrastructure this it could indicate
they move to a different hosts or it
could that indicate that there was an
ownership change here but this isn't
that by itself this isn't a good enough
indicator for a change of ownership but
that's why we use also look for things
like a look at
volume distribution changes which might
indicate that the service that is
associated with that domain has changed
over time or you know something has
changed about the domain may be
indicating an ownership change and then
lastly we look at start of authority
records and these are particularly
interesting because these are records
that don't often change so when you see
a change to a start of authority record
this often is a very good strong
indicator that a change of ownership has
actually occurred so so how effective is
our Olympic algorithm well one of the
challenges that we faced was the
sparsity of passive DNS data so due to
this we didn't always have an
observation immediately near an
ownership change event so one of the
questions you might ask so this so
you'll notice here is that we see that
about 75% of the main field within 10
days so this means that if if we have if
we flag domain as likely being a
candidate for ownership within 10 days
of when it actually expired our
algorithm was doing pretty good give
them the sparsity of Pasadena's data so
what is what is our algorithm generate
well what we see here on the right-hand
side is that below the red line these
are these are cases where we indicated
that a domain was likely a light had
likely changed ownership given a higher
score indicating a likely ownership
change and will notice that the majority
of the lighter blue dots are below the
this red line which is exactly what we
expect to see we also see here that as
the window size increases we get better
at making these these identifying these
likely ownership changes and so this is
really good and this is a really
lightweight algorithm so using our
algorithm we actually made a number of
different discoveries so some of the
stuff that we found were just simple
domains where they were abusing the
positive residual trust so these were
just whitewashed domains they were
previously benign domains that
subsequently registered by malware and
now we're being abused and we verified
these manually but another interesting
cases we've talked a lot about abusing
positive residual trust but the other
case that we mentioned earlier on was
that there's also negative residual
trust so one of the domains that our
algorithm turned up was a an expired apt
domain so this is particularly
interesting because these can be hard to
find but this domain particular domain
was available for immediate registration
so we actually registered it and started
selecting traffic from this domain and
we started immediately getting requests
from a Taiwanese research Taiwanese
research facility so what we saw here
was that for the low price of a domain
registration you could buy your own apt
pretty cool so just want to summarize
kind of what we've talked about briefly
here first is that we identified this
idea of residual trust and we saw that
it causes a number of different problems
that sometimes seem like they might be
caused by different things but it's the
underlying causes of residual trust next
was we looked at a long-term study of
expired domain abuse dating back to two
thousand eight and we observed not only
that this residual trust abuse does
actually occur but that it actually
seems to be on the rise and then last we
proposed a lightweight algorithm to help
us identify these potential ownership
changes using only DNS this meant we got
to avoid using who is which we said can
lie and has a number of difficulties and
the results are actually fairly good and
the last thing that these results kind
of indicate is that there might be we
might need better policies to help
address this problem at the you know
registrar registry level and maybe there
are other considerations beyond just
technical solutions that we should be
aware of and so with that I'll open up
for questions
hi John spring new seal so I know you're
not going to tell us what blacklist you
use but I know from our other work that
there are a bunch more domains on black
lists than 300,000 so I assume you a
couple how do we know that the
increasing trend isn't the people who
curated your blacklist getting good at
detecting something that's correlated
with trust abuse rather than trust abuse
actually increasing so i think it's i
think one of the indicators there is
that we're not just seeing this with the
blacklist right we had two different
cases we had malware and we had black
lists so either they're both happening
by chance and seem to be growing or
there seems to be this this concerted
effort by you know people trying to deal
with boost to take this residual trust
and abuse it and one of the reasons why
that seems attractive is that if you
look at you know how reputation systems
might work on a domain unless that
domain is retired from the reputation
system or something changes then you
know to picking up one of these old
domains has the benefit that you might
evade existing whitelist or blacklist
solutions until they remove that off we
actually had an interesting case where
the we talked to people at facebook and
they mentioned that they've had cases
where they have things on black or on
one of their spam lists and their spam
lists only get updated so often but
they're not great at retiring things off
the spam lists so they have cases where
people will complain that they're being
censored when really they just bought a
domain that was previously used for spam
and the spam list hasn't been updated
the same would apply for you know
blacklist and other things like or you
know for Mauer domain so if they haven't
removed from like a whitelist then you
know if I bought one I'm going to skirt
detection just because they look for it
on the whitelist alright cool thanks to
dimitra's from the University of
Maryland very interesting work I'm just
curious when you say to the Malheur
contacted these domains what was the
purpose was it a CNC was it a drop
malware what what what was he doing I
mean it could have been any of those
types of purposes right so we had we
collected these domains from dynamic Ram
our dynamic execution traces so we don't
essentially
so many domains it's hard to know
exactly what all of them are used for so
but what we were what's interesting here
is when we looked at the intersection we
saw that a number of them were actually
just making queries to expire domain so
they were doing something there and you
know since them since it is malware
there's potential for abuse there so why
are so many malware samples contacting
domains that are expired and I think
that's kind of the interesting thing
there and we saw and I think that you
know alone that's that's something but
with the blacklist that kind of helps
indicate that you know these are
hand-cured into indications of abuse so
it seems like there's something there
cool thank you all right we have time
for some more question is there any
other questions okay that's nice if we
have done so I was also curious how easy
do you think your Olympic algorithm
would be to evade so big so that that's
a good question so one of the things
that's nice about the Olympic algorithm
right now is we're using infrastructure
properties of you know on the internet
so these are things that unless you make
a concerted effort to change this it in
some cases it might even be hard you
know given the infrastructure we see
that now are often uses similar
infrastructure so some of these like
that if the infrastructure changes in
the SOA records these are things that
aren't frequently changed so if they if
they mess with that you could possibly
evade it but we've it's since it's
something that's infrastructure-related
it's it's probably more challenging