so this work is part of a bigger project
called me TLS on building a verified
open-source TLS implementation of TLS 13
but also older versions and it's even
its immediate as itself as part of an
even bigger project depicted here ask
you in the end what what is is so why
downward is just a small piece of the
parcel it's a it's a very important
piece because as more downward slip can
make you lose a lot of security
potentially all the security so I want
to introduce a downgrade on everyday
experience so you get downgraded when an
attacker can make you fall back on
weaker security solutions when stronger
ones are able and I claim that we are
very used to doing that so downloads can
happen at the user level and the
application level but also at the
protocol level and this is the topic of
my talk so by now you've heard about dls
13 and why it is important so for the
purpose of my talk want to emphasize the
TLS is not the single protocol it's a
suit of protocols that have and
negotiation mechanism that is widely
used to negotiate multiple versions and
many more ciphers use this happens in
the in the hello message of TLS in which
the client first sends all the stuff
that he supports the server chooses and
sent back his own and the sense back
that his decision what to use in his
hello message TLS also supports a gooda
mentary down with protection mechanism
is part of the key confirmation
techniques that were discussing in the
second talk during the first talk
so the configurable configurability of
TLS allows it to adopt new cryptographic
algorithms by still supporting backward
compatibility so you've seen a similar
slide before but this is split up into
different types of attacks and this that
allows a quick or HIV action to new
cryptographic weaknesses so you can turn
off old crypto and turn on New Krypton
so for particularly people think that
this is important to be prepared for
quantum computers and quantum attacks
however it also enables down with
attacks in which an attacker can exploit
this negotiation to make client and
servers use which cryptography and the
highlighted ataxia use some form of
negotiation and bound wait so we believe
that the increased number of attacks is
due to increased scrutiny after the
Snowden leaks but also that we need
interest in pls because of the new
version TLS 13 and the two are linked so
in our opinion it's it's high time to
get things right but the fact that most
of these attacks are outside existing
security models and just some of the
previous works we're trying to kind of
get to capture some of those attacks it
shows that we are still somehow in a
wild west of TLS attacks where typical
security graphic security poof's do not
tell us much about real-world tags so i
will single out via tax kind of my
Western heroes and I will call them the
good the bad and the ugly and I will use
them to illustrate the challenges of
obtaining down great security so
summarizing our main contributions so we
have two general contributions for
making kind of the Wild West of
real-world protocols a bit more orderly
one are downgrade definitions and the
other is a modular poop strategy for
proving down wit
so in addition we have protocol specific
contributions in terms of attacks and
also security proves in our new model so
a goal here was to be dispatch our first
two contributions to see how they can
deal with with different protocols being
thrown at them so our focus throughout
on TLS and in particular on TLS 1.34 our
positive results so at two main the two
main contributions that I will talk
about in this talk are the downward
secured definitions that capture down
with aspects of the previous attacks and
that's the first contribution and the
second contribution is a modular proof
of the downbeat fixes to TLS once we
that have been developed together with
the core design teen of of TLS 13 and
that are included in the new I think
drafts or teen of of the standard so
setting the stage for the definition I
kind of want to give some some notation
for negotiation so negotiation starts
from client and server configurations
that describe what versions and
algorithms cipher suit cipher Suites and
modes client and servers I'm principal
willing to support then there is a
multivalent negotiation in which part is
sent messages to each other and the
outcomes of that is a mode which
contains the negotiated version in
cipher suite so we model the ideal
outcome of negotiation using a
preference function nagel that maps to
configurations to the mode that parties
would like to get typically this is what
they would get if there is no active
attacker present so let me explain using
that terminology by existing security
definitions do not capture downgrade so
I take authentication as an example and
typically authentication says that if my
negotiated mode uses strong algorithms
then my partner and I agree on the keys
the identities the mode and the
potentially the whole the whole
transcript but even that is not secured
to guarantee downgrade protection
because authentication does not
guarantee negotiation of a strong load
that's basically where it starts off of
so if an only has such security
guarantees available what is required to
center section of all modes must must be
strong in the section of the client and
the server configurations would only
support strong modes but what if the
client and server configurations support
legacy algorithms for backward
compatibility and what are the minimum
requirements on the configurations to
achieve downgrade so these three bullets
match up nicely with the three attacks
that I will refer to in in my talk so
let us assume for a moment that we have
an an accidental as handshake that uses
strong algorithms as proven secure x
cubed ographers for example take those
of the previous talks so the first
motivating attack poodle exploits
weaknesses in the record algorithm of
old TLS versions and it's negotiation is
prevented by modern handshake that
authenticate the negotiation using the
finished messages so as the whole
handshake is assumed to be secure it
falls within the scope of traditional
poor security results and indeed the
closest prior work by dowling and
Stabler show this so this is somewhat
the good case this is what we could do
before our paper but what if the what
about the following attack that is
reminiscent of luck charm so the server
proposes so the client proposes his
preferred group a strong group but also
a big poop the active manual attacker
makes the server fall back to them to
the week group and now they do
standard scientific element in which the
server signs the key shares at this
point the parties can compute the keys
and I mean actually all parties because
by breaking discrete logarithm for the
smaller group then the man in the middle
attacker can also compute the key key k
and then Forge the finish message so
this is a break of key confirmation and
breaks down with security of TLS 12 so
there's some hope of achieving a
stronger property namely one could sign
the whole ones transcript here as in
fearless once we but this is not
captured by by existing models which
assume that the whole handshake has a
strong mode so this kind of the security
against lock em like attacks cannot be
modeled in existing security proofs what
we would like instead is a stronger
attacker model in which almost all of
the hand she can be broken and to rely
on security only of a few down with
critical algorithms but predict
matically the signature scheme and I
think that was what the one of the
speakers refer to when they said that
they want to look into stronger attacker
models in the tamarind setting so we are
we are talking so we still need some
good cryptography so that's kind of the
ugly attack so if you have a downgrade
attack on the actual signature scheme
poisons a very old hash function and
this attack was published at ndss just
the beginning of this year then there's
really nothing no way we can we can help
your spotter call designers so these
attacks would be really carefully
watched and old hash functions and
signature schemes should be eliminated
so they are support some wild west-style
so more formally to capture the stronger
attacker model we formally define a down
with predicate DP the toads when a
client and server conservation jointly
provides down with security to the first
party so here the client to can swap
things are bound to define down with
security for the server it for TLS i
give this primarily for example the
details can vary the predicate requires
that the client demands good public keys
and signature algorithms and that the
server expresses a preference for down
with secure version in its protocol so
we will get back to this requirement
when we analyze TLS 13 the goal of the
negotiation is backward compatibility so
clients and servers can still
interoperate with everyone so in
particular decline can interact with
servers that support only old versions
and the server can interact even with
clients that do not support a strong
signature scheme and moreover both
clients and servers can support big
groups so this is a quick primer in two
keys change models adapted to this more
general attacker model so we have a
man-in-the-middle that creates long-term
keys and protocol instances and when
initializing particle instances he
provides them with their configuration
so the attacker can adaptively choose
what these parties are willing to
negotiate then he drives the protocol by
using a cent Oracle in which he provides
messages and receives messages acting as
a man in the middle and as the sessions
progress in the execution of the
particle they assign variables which
will be used to model security so that
the configurations there are some unique
identifiers typically typically a
concatenation of nonsense of two
sessions and the mode that is negotiated
and there can be more such variables for
other protocols I think in the key
confirmation talk there was also very
similar way of formulating security
properties so the goal of the attacker
is to make instances reach a bad state
where the attacker wins so a winning
state I will indicate those states in
wet so using that phone work here's our
definition of down with acuity so the
winning state for the attacker and this
is the probability that we want to bound
a is when there are two instances that
have the same unique identifier but and
for which the down with predicates on
their configuration holds but the
instances or the first instance the
client instance here assigns a mode that
is not the outcome of the ideal
negotiation so that would constitute a
downgrade quake and then tackle that can
get into this state with non-negligible
probability 0 is high probability is a
successful down with the tackle so
there's caveats to this definition
namely what if the attacker can make can
impersonate the server so there is no
server instance that has the same unique
identifier in that case our definition
says says nothing it doesn't guarantee
anything good about the mode so in our
paper however we show that we give a
separate security definition partnering
security for which exactly this is the
winning state of the attacker and
typical and we show that for typical
Keys change protocols whenever they're
at the dead that that a downbeat secure
have also also made this partner
executive property so this is all I can
say here about downgrade definitions so
please refer to our paper in particular
there we give much more details on how
down with the down in security relates
to standard security properties such as
authentication and key secrecy so when
discussing our modular poof strategy I
will gain focus on TLS once we please
have a look at our paper for results on
many other real world protocols so as
everyone working on TLS knows the
standard is very complex
and usually the first step in writing a
paper doing some analysis of TLS is to
simplify the protocol so a second
contribution is to show how this can be
done in the sound manner so we don't
claim much novelty here but we hope that
these techniques will be picked up more
because it's really kind of this
soundness issue of looking at partial
protocols that Miss attacks is really a
big problem and there's a very nice work
also that that exposes a nice exposition
of this by walk away and stiga already
in 2008 so it's really no excuse for for
for not showing these simulations so how
does this work so that is the complex
protocol which you get from the standard
and then you extract from that protocol
a sub protocol that can be extended to
the complex protocol using a simulator
and the simulator helps to translate
every attack on the on the complex
particle and the food protocol into an
attack on the subcortical so if you
manage to prove the support the code
secure then you also proved the pool
Protocol secure and we did that for TLS
13 so here's down with subcortical it
starts off by the client sending its
negotiation proposal the server can
reject proposals if it doesn't support
any of the groups in that proposal and
then decline sends a new proposal after
that the server chooses its mode and
signs the whole transcript until then to
the stew the client so the down security
should come from the signature on on all
of those messages whoever TLS once we
missed the be twice so that the session
has did not this started after the
device is one of the pixies that we
proposed and there's another fix that
does something fancy to the to the
server nonce
get back to in a bit so the good news is
that for dispatched downgrade protocol
we can show we can prove security and
the the proof relies on the the
uniqueness of nonces and the security of
the signature scheme as well as the
server signing all the net work input to
the Nega function and the result but
what about version downgrade so we can
show that downgraded TLS 13 so can be
down with TLS 132 TLS 12 and we mount
lock charm so unfortunately there is
nothing in the TLS once we standard that
could prevent such language because the
the version is never signed so the
question is how to patch one sweet
prevent downwards the finished messages
don't help so here's something ugly
those that had a pure mind had should
should have looked away so we put the
server version into the server nuns and
and we do that for all past versions of
TLS to obtain backward compatibility so
while this is a bit ugly the good news
is it works and so we can prove
downgrade security for servicing clients
and support all versions including pls
once we as long as the implement is
countermeasure and as long as they don't
support our is a key transport in which
case they are just no signatures do to
help so this is all I had to say for now
so if Anderson correctly you still need
to have one primitive that is that
remains secure in your case a signature
so could we imagine something in which
for example the security can be one of
two primitives yes I think that that it
definitely could be the signature scheme
and the psk and if you if your signature
scheme by bulking and you had a good psk
it could succeed you could still have
security so TLS ones we may even in
certain modes after property