to speak about inferring user routes and
locations using zero permission mobile
sensors the leakage of location
information is considered as a major
privacy concern mobile operating systems
like Android and iOS have tried to
address this concern by implementing
permissions though these permissions are
successful in mitigating some privacy
leakage there are still apps like the
brightest flashlight app that deceive
users so this app was sued actually some
time back for selling location
information without telling the users
about that they sell their your
information a bigger problem however is
protecting the leakage of location
information from site channels such as
sensors the reason is that these sensors
are not protected by any kind of
permissions nor do they show any
notifications to the user about their
access so our goal was to demonstrate
the feasibility of using these sensors
to infer user outs with a high
probability so this is the outline of
our presentation first I'll discuss the
high level graph theoretical approach of
our attack followed by the graph
construction from the map data then I
will discuss the sensors that we use for
inference the challenges with those
sensors and the route construction
method from the sensor data after that I
will discuss the search algorithm on a
high level and report on the evaluation
results for both simulation as well as
real experiments so we model this
problem as a graph theoretical approach
and we developed some efficient
algorithms for search so basically over
here an adversary downloads the road
network for a large number of areas and
converts them to graph where the roads
are
the vertices and the intersections are
the edges the adversary also creates and
distributes an app that detects when I
user sets in the car and recalls the
sensor data of the user driving this
sensor data is then processed and
converted to a sub graph which can then
be searched in the created previously
created graph for the maximum likelihood
route so in order to construct our graph
we downloaded the map data from open
street maps which is open source map
resource containing the road networks of
the major cities the only place where
open street maps are really lacks is
that the speed limit information is
incomplete so we are for that purpose we
use nokia here platform so to construct
the graph the first thing we do is that
we decompose each road into a one-way
atomic sections where a section is the
part of the road between two
intersections so in the example road
network shown those red dots signify the
intersections and the section would be
the part of the roads between these
intersections please note that these
sections do not contain any turns or any
sharp curves however they do contain a
slight curvature and additional
information such as the heading
direction and the minimum time so once
we have these atomic sections we
reconstruct them we connect them
together to form longer segments which
are basically either straight or curving
roads so if there are sections are that
are connected to each other however they
make an angle of more than 30 degrees
then we label that intersection as a
turn and these sections actually become
part of different long segments so in
the example road network over there or
s1 is an example of a long segment s2
north
is again a connected long segment and
the figure on the right is the graph
that gets generated for our example road
network the sensor data that we use for
inference is the gyroscope for
extracting turn information and
curvature information the accelerometer
for calculating the idle time and the
magnetometer for estimating the heading
direction of the car these sensors on
smartphones are generally low cost and
they are extremely prone to noise so the
figure here shows a real experiment
route that we can conducted and the
corresponding gyroscope and
accelerometer drift for that expert
accelerometer trace for that
experimental drought so if you look at
the gyroscope figure those sharp
deviations are actually the turns
recorded by the gyroscope however if you
see that the y-axis seems to be drifting
away from the ZeroAccess this is a big
problem in gyroscopes also the
accelerometer are not suitable for speed
estimation because they are very
sensitive to the road noises such as
potholes and speed bumps and like those
induced large accelerations which are
very difficult to remove the
magnetometers also are extremely
sensitive to the magnets inside the car
and they add a lot of difficulty in
estimating the heading direction of the
car so in order to construct the route
from the sensor data we first reduce the
gyroscopes drift and then align the
sensor data to a horizontal reference
frame that is in the reference frame of
the car so what this does is it helps
put all the turn information in the z
axis so that it is easier to extract the
turn information and the curvature
information from one axis itself
so from this z axis it is easy to now
detect turns as large deviations in the
z axis and extracts segments as the
trees between two such turns so for the
figure shown below those red dots
signify turn starts or are edges and
those arrows are two examples of
segments or the vertices to each of
these segments we also add additional
information such as like we add the idle
time we remove the idle time information
from the accelerometer and we add a
compass heading or to each segment if
they satisfy certain criteria so once we
have the graph and the sub graph our
objective of the search algorithm is to
find the sequence of turns and graph
that maximize the probability of
matching the observed gyroscope turn
angles so if the gyroscope turn angles
are approximate to a zero mean Gaussian
distribution then maximizing this
probability is actually equally when
equivalent to minimizing the l2 norm of
the errors so our search algorithm is
similar to the trellis code decoding
technique though it has more
complications because the start segment
is not known we also get improved
results because we filter unlikely or
impossible routes at every stage so we
define two metrics for the search
algorithm for evaluation the individual
rank is the rank of the actual exact
route in the search results while the
cluster rank is the rank of a group of
similar routes the map that match our
actual route so basically clustering
helps and adversary gain more confidence
in an area and target
all US attacks in the future on that
particular area so this is how the
algorithm actually works first we assume
that every segment or every vertex of a
graph is a potential starting point we I
to read through all for every
intersection we iterate through every
potential path and get the list of all
forward connections out of these forward
connections the ones that are unlikely
or impossible to happen are filtered out
and the remaining connections are scored
and added to the previous parts course
so basically now we have these new
potential paths with a new score at the
end of every iteration we just pick the
top scoring paths so basically this top
scoring selection is a is a trade-off
between speed and inference rate so if
you want better speed then you can just
select a fewer number of paths if you
want more infant then select more number
of paths we filter out unlikely
connections using very flexible
thresholds so for example if the
difference between the reported turn
angle and the connection turn angle is
less than a certain flexible threshold
then only that path is connection is
selected otherwise it is rejected
similarly for time if there is a
particular in text section that is
impossible to reach in a given time then
it is rejected so our scoring is based
on a weighted turn angles curvature and
travel time so basically we assign a
higher way to curvature and travel time
because they are output from the
gyroscope which is a more accurate
sensor we assign a lower way to time
because at any time of the day the
traffic patterns may be unpredictable
the curvature scoring happens by
splitting the segment into an equal
number of parts as the gyroscope segment
that we
want to match against we assume constant
velocity for this purpose however we see
that even with constant velocity there
is a very large increase in the attack
performance once we have an equal number
of segments for the graph segment graph
vertex as well as the gyroscope vertex
we calculate the curve score as the
normalized distance between the segment
and the curve for each part we do L 2
norm is theoretically optimal for
Gaussian distributions we preferred the
l1 norm over the l2 not because the l1
norm is much more efficient than the l2
norm and we observed better results with
the l1 norm so the final score is
basically the weighted sum of the term
travel time and curvatures code for all
the intersections so we evaluated the
gyroscope are using error distributions
for real driving experiments so the
figure shows the error distributions for
for smartphones and as you can see these
are distributions approximate to a
Gaussian distributions which was our
original as I'm send assumption for
choosing the l2 norm we also observed
that ninety-five percent of the errors
were less than 10 degrees which is quite
ideal for inference so before I report
the simulation results to you we chose
11 cities for simulation and they are
shown in the table below so the cities
that have a high number of vertices and
edges signify the larger cities or with
a lower potential for inference then in
the figure the bottom cities a Rome and
Concord you can see that they have a
higher distribution of turns which
signifies that they have a high
inference for high potential for
inference then there are cities such as
Sunnyvale or in the top left which has
mostly 90 degree turns and that
signifies that the
inference potential for Sunnyvale may be
low so we create a simulation routes by
connecting together connected segments
of the graph starting at a random start
segment to simulate real driving
scenarios we injected variable noise to
every turn curve and time of our
simulation route so there were four
noise scenarios that we tested against
one was the idle noise scenario which is
the noise free scenario and basically
serves as the upper bound for
performance for our simulation
experiments the typical noise scenario
was created using values from real
driving experiments and assume moderate
traffic the high noise scenario assumed
heavy traffic on the road and less
accurate census while the future
scenario as you moderate traffic and
more accurate census like we think that
as MEMS technology progresses or the
errors will be less as the sensors will
be higher quality so for simulation
routes we ran we created two thousand
unique routes for each city and tested
them against all the four noise
scenarios these are the results for six
of those cities and this is basically a
CDF of the results so we found good
inference for eight cities where the for
the typical scenario of we had about
fifty percent of routes in the top ten
results for even for the high noise
scenario almost thirty five percent of
the routes appeared in the top ten
results for clusters we basically got
five to ten percent better than the
individual ranks we also also observe
low inference for grid like cities such
as Manhattan another observation that we
made was that turn and curvature combine
had the largest impact so if you look at
the figures London and
room have an equal turn distributions
like Boston Madrid and Paris however
London and Rome have a better inference
score because they have more curving
roads as compared to Boston Madrid and
Paris which have more straighter roads
also the size of the city doesn't impact
inference because London and Rome are
the largest cities that we chose for
simulations and they have the best
results we also perform some real
driving experiments in Boston and Walton
so basically we collected 70 routes each
or and our drivers were instructed to be
places to restrictions on the drivers
one was to have the position of the
phone fixed while they were driving
while they were collecting the
experiment and do not reverse during
experiment collection so the d4 they
were free to keep the phone anywhere
inside the car I mean there were some
experiments which had the phone kept on
the coffee holder there were some with
the amount which whether the phones were
placed on the amount the key results
here were that for Boston thirty percent
of the routes were found in the top five
search results wife evolved him almost
fifty percent were in the top five
thirteen percent in Boston ranked one
while about thirty-eight percent in
Waltham actually ranked one another
observation that we made was that the
Boston results lean more towards the
high noise scenario of simulations while
volcom results lean more towards a
typical noise scenario this is because
of the traffic profile so basically
Boston has much more congestion than
Walton as and time has a larger impact
in Boston so to summarize we
demonstrated that apps of with no
permissions that use these sensors can
infer routes with high probability we
model this problem as a graph
theoretical model or to identify the
maximum likelihood route or to evaluate
our system we collect
140 driving experiments for Boston and
Walton and found that thirty percent of
them in Boston were in the top five
while for Waltham almost fifty percent
were in the top five we also performed
simulations for eleven cities and found
good inference for eight cities with
more than fifty percent of routes in top
10 so basically this suggests that this
threat is real and should be mitigated
in the future Thank You Ryan Rosenberg
from Qualcomm so navigation solutions
have a thing called dead reckoning where
they're supposed to be able to estimate
the path even the absence of a GPS
signal did you compare did you derive
your kind of segment processing from
actual dead reckoning algorithms or did
you investigate oh no we chose a graph
theoretical approach for our so
basically the problem with dead
reckoning is it assumes relatively
straighter roads and it assumes that the
accelerometer is actually quite good I
mean because it depends on speed
estimation in our case we found that for
roads which have speed bumps and
potholes the dead reckoning method
doesn't actually work very well and
that's the reason we went for this graph
theoretical approach where we model
everything as a graph and then search on
it thanks Ellie canal see me was very
interesting talk just on that note so
have you had much experience / tease
excuse me success with using signature
based methods to extract all the noise
from the accelerometer you know you can
good jolt would be kind of very impulse
driven we're as a normal turn would look
very different so we tried filtering on
the accelerometer however we were not
very successful with that because not
only are these potholes or speed bumps
an issue even if there are slow
oops in the road that induce
accelerations in the accelerometer and
without the help of other sensors it is
very difficult to remove so basically if
your car is going down like this it will
actually show up in the accelerometer
and without the help of other sensors
you cannot figure out whether it's is
the user that actually accelerated the
car or whether it's a road slope not to
follow up with you on that afterwards
and a second comment more is that taking
into account the fact that you're
working off the user's phone it seems
very the potential that you could use
check-ins and Twitter or other
location-based areas and then do that as
a sanity check to see whether you're
actually on the point where the user
claims to be I'd be an interesting way
to extend the work very nice thank you
have to limit it to one more question
thanks I've rob Cunningham from MIT
Lincoln lab I just had a question about
your initial conditions how did you know
which city you started in and can you
use some of your techniques to give you
a sense of which city you might be in ok
so we perform some tests based on IP
address so if like when the sensor data
gets uploaded to a server you have the
IP address over there so using the IP
address you can get a good estimate of a
particular area a user is in so in our
work we actually chose cities but you
can extract graphs for larger areas and
run the algorithms on those ok I hope
that answers your question let's thank
the speaker