so as you already will have guessed from
the session and the paper title this
talk is about key exchange the key
exchange is this neat concept that
allows to remote parties to establish a
shared symmetric key of an insecure
network usually you bootstrap this from
knowing public keys or certificates of
each other and you will run a protocol
the key exchange protocol which in the
end supposed to output a shared key the
same key on both sides of the protocol
participants security wise formalization
go back to the seminal paper of balerion
rug away from 1993 and there are two
main security goals that are usually
consider here the first and probably
most intuitive one is key secrecy the
key secrecy is basically telling that an
outsider and outer adversary eve to that
communication given some capabilities
formalized should not learn anything
about the key so basically the key
should be as good as fallen randomly
from the sky being perfectly random on
both sides and if not knowing anything
about it the other property is
authentication and it's often formalized
in an implicit way by giving for example
LS the guarantee that only Bob can
potentially hold the key and no one else
however Ellis is not guaranteed well
actually Bob indeed holds the key or not
just told that they don't if only then
Bob can be the one that holds it this is
where key confirmation comes into the
game the topic of this talk and to start
with an informal definition let's quote
from the handbook of applied
cryptography it says key confirmation is
the property where by one party is
assured that a second possibly
unidentified party actually has
possession of a particular secret key in
other words it's basically aiming at
saying that you're insured Ellis is
ensured that Bob actually holds the key
that she has so while this property
confirmation is often mentioned in
scientific papers on key exchange
interestingly there was no formalization
no explicit formal treatment of this
notion so far
so you may wonder whether key
confirmation at all matters where it's
important to look into it and if you ask
cryptographers one answer you might get
is well actually it's not so interesting
after all because if you have a key no
one else has and you encrypt something
under their key well no one can decrypt
it but that's all the security problem
so why should you care about it you
might also think well it's somewhat
clear when you get key confirmation you
just use the key you encrypt something
and by that you prove that you hold the
key and the other side will know that
you have it however one needs to be
cautious here because if you do this in
a careless way you might actually lose
the main goal security goal of session
key secrecy that you wanted to actually
aim for in your protocol so
cryptographers usually go and say okay
well you just derive some separate key
which is independent and then you send
some message authentication code over a
transcript to confirm that you are
sharing the same communication if you
look into standards it's interesting
that in the discussions around till has
1.3 the upcoming next version of TLS
there was some discussion where the key
confirmation is actually something that
should be explicitly aimed for until at
one point three settle for it Sookie
confirmation is a goal for Taylor's 1.3
and it's also mentioned as an explicit
goal in various miss standards for
example so there's some good reason to
look into key confirmation and what we
do in this work is we do three things
the first one we provide a formal model
formalization of what key confirmation
means in order to provide a ground where
you can have well-founded discussions
upon second we look into this full glory
transform refreshing with a new key
sending a mac and analyze what kind of
key confirmation properties you get
there and third we look into one of the
latest draft of TLS 1.3 and check what
key confirmation properties are
established there so let me start with
the former model of course in a more
high-level way here and there will be as
you will see in a second they're
actually two notions that we formalize
there
I'll explain in a bit why well start
with what we call full key conformation
which is supposed to formalize the
intuition that by now maybe you already
have which means that once I if one side
one session accepts a key and there
should be already another session which
holds the same key so consider a
protocol where errors begin sends the
first message which allows pop to derive
a key and then Bob responds with its
message and then Ellis concludes by
deriving the key as well so now folky
confirmation is formalized through the
following establishing the following
predicate or ensuring the following
predicate which I'll translate in in
high level so you're guaranteed that for
any session in a particular set s and
here you might think of as being the set
of all client sessions in the protocol
when touch session accepts there exists
another session as prime in another set
s prime for example a server session
that ensures satisfies three properties
it accepted already it shares its the
communication partner it's like having
the same communication transcript for
example or here formalized as holding
some identifiers value for this session
and most importantly third it holds the
same key it's actually some technical
restriction that we need to add here we
can only talk about key confirmation
when you talk when you are communicating
with someone that you know in particular
which is not the adversary because
formally you cannot reason about whether
an adversary derives the key or not
let's now formalizing this intuition
that when you accept there is already
someone that accepted with the same key
so you know you're not using the key for
nothing and interestingly this
formalization now exposes a nice duality
to the classical notion of
authentication so remember that implicit
authentication tells you that there
exists at most one session that holds
the key you're talking about while now
full key confirmation says that there
exists at least one session that holds
the key this means that these two
notions modular acquire modular and
combined nicely you can
prove them separately and in a combined
fashion you will then get that there
exists exactly one session namely one of
the partner you wanted to talk to which
holds the key that you are holding
sometimes called explicit authentication
so why a second notion well this is
because you inherently cannot have this
notion of full key confirmation on both
sides of the protocol one why is this
let's look at an example so let's say
there's some communication already going
on and then at some point Ellis accepts
the key she sends a last message in the
protocol which makes also Bob accept the
key now in any reasonably strong model
an adversary is always allowed to drop
this last message to infer with the
communication dropped this message
preventing Bob from deriving this key so
in particular Ellis cannot get this
guarantee that when she accepts there is
already someone that holds the same key
in any particular whenever you're in the
center of the last message you can only
get some wicked guarantees and this is
what we formalize under the notion of
almost full kiko information which aims
at the following intuition the guarantee
for that for a session is when this
session accepts then there exists
already another session that might not
have accepted yet but if it accepts it
will you're guaranteed array that it
will do so with the same key and for
this we introduce a technical helper
tool which we call key confirmation
identifiers and which work as follows
let's look at this example let's say
Ellis sends a message and then this
provides some agreement already which
allows Bob to send a key confirmation
identifying I will show you in a second
how this then works out in the
formalization then Bob response which
makes Ellis also set this helper to key
confirmation NT fire as well as accept
the session key and then if Bob receives
Ellis last message will also accept with
a key so now the formalization again
translated in more high-level way saying
that for all such session like
is now on the left side when it accepts
you're guaranteed the following there
exists another session already which
shares some agreement namely it has set
the same key confirmation identifying it
doesn't have the same key yet it might
not have accepted yet but it holds the
same key confirmation in the fire and in
particular when this session accepts you
already guaranteed that it will do so
will only do so with the same key so you
cannot make this other session accept
any more with another key so of course
there's a lot more things to formalize
and I refer you to for that to the paper
one thing I want to mention is that
these two notions are indeed comparable
in a sense of that full key confirmation
is stronger that is implies almost full
key confirmation so now that let's look
how these notions can be applied to
protocols I want to first look into this
protocol transform just supposed to add
key confirmation to an app to some
arbitrary protocol so we start from a
key exchange protocol which is complete
in its sense it outputs a key and some
session identifier which is basically
like a notion that makes you formally
link these two sites together as talking
in the same communication you might
think of it being for example the
transcript of all messages exchanged now
we want to build around this a transform
transform protocol which ensures key
confirmation and we do so by first of
all having this session identifier
agreement of the initial protocol being
our key confirmation identifiers our
preliminary agreement and then from the
session key that we derived in the main
protocol we arrived three independent
Keys a green one an orange one and the
purple one and the letter to we use to
exchange message authentication codes
over the transcript of the session
identifiers that establish the linking
in the original protocol and if these
verify with an output the third the
green key as our actual session key
which will be independent of all the
other keys involved so now in the work
we show that first of all this
transformation doesn't break anything so
it preserves in
they're the key secrecy and the
authentication properties of the
original protocol and moreover it
provides you with the strongest t
confirmation you can hope for namely
full key confirmation for the receiver
and almost full key confirmation for the
sender of the final of the last message
alright so now let's look into what key
confirmation will became about say about
key confirmation until as 1.3 more
specifically we looked into draft n this
was a version out there around October
follow following October last year and
we look into the main handshake which is
in diff ahem and based handshake so key
exchange protocol in Phyllis you don't
have to lower understand all the details
of the protocol the main ideas of this
handshake is as follows so the client
and the server start off by the client
beginning server responding with a hello
and the kisha message where the hello
message is basically a random nonce
Reynolds number value and the shiki
share being a defilement share and then
for authentication the server will send
its certificate in particular including
its public key and a signature over the
transcripts of the messages exchanged
will then also send a finished message a
Mac value over this transcript and then
to complete the handshake the client for
authentication also sends its
certificate and a signature and Mac
value over the transcript well we can
show now is that this basically achieves
the strongest eco information you can
hope for in the setting namely that for
clients which sent the last message you
get almost full key confirmation so you
don't know whether the server actually
will get your message it might be
dropped but if it gets the server will
accept with the same key that you're
having already on the other side the
server gets full key confirmation so
he's already sure that there is a client
out there which holds the same key
interestingly now we show this based on
the signatures of them in the protocol
not based on the Mac values send to the
finished messages which are somewhat
resembling the
generic transform which might be a bit
surprising because often finished
messages are thought of the mean of
getting key confirmation but we can
actually show that even without key
confirmation the same properties hold we
wear now this does not mean that we
advocate removing finish messages hell
no it just says okay you get this from
some other part of the protocol already
in particular the finished messages are
quite important for other modes and for
other aspects of security in this
protocol but for key confirmation you
can actually rely on the signatures and
finally in the paper we also look into
the unilateral authentication case so
the case where only the server
authenticates and we show that get some
similar somewhat similar results there
refer you to the paper for this okay so
to summarize well we formalize key
confirmation and are the first ones to
do so in a game based setting providing
some formal ground for discussion of
this property where there was long
before and we establish two notions
separate two notions full key
confirmation for the receiver of the
last message and some weaker notion
almost full kiko information for the
sender of the last message we then
exercise this formalism on this generic
transformation and show that it's indeed
generically at ski confirmation to some
key con to some key exchange protocol
and finally we're looking to till as 1.3
and we show that it provides key
confirmation interestingly even without
using the finished messages within this
proof right this concludes my talk thank
you very much
questions so I have one question and so
you see the TRS apprised key
confirmation over the finish messages
does that mean that I complete I can
completely remove these messages and the
protocol is still secure you use nothing
or you lose something else so again I
want to stress that one has to be
careful here so for key confirmation in
this main hench Tag Mode you don't need
to finish messages and we show that you
could even remove them however this does
not this does not say anything about
what kind of other properties key
secrecy authentication etc you get we
don't look into this for this specific
purpose and in particular we do not
advocate to remove them but especially
because they serve important purposes in
other modes of the protocol so for key
confirmation in the main mode you don't
need them but please don't remove them
okay I have a question so you mentioned
that some jealous modes don't use
signatures did you look at confirmation
property for let's say pre-shared key in
TLS 13 no we just looked into the main
mode using signatures for the pre-shared
key mode you're right there no no
signatures involved this would be in
particular case where well a you get
secrecy only through the finished
messages so you crucially need them and
I would expect that you also get key
confirmation only through these messages
thank you
okay last year's best paper was the
barouche paper on TLS on the previous
version and they pointed out that the
implementations were deeply flawed I
applaud what you're doing and starting
to get the formal analysis of the
protocol but ultimately I think there
are a lot of properties that the
barouche paper showed should not exist
and these are the tough ones to get at
so I just wondered if you had any
thoughts about where this is going and
what you might do in the future and this
question sort of bears on some of the
subsequent papers in this session as
well but I'm not going to get up and ask
at each time so well I guess the others
can just repeat the question without
being asked for my boy guess I fully
agree of course this is just one piece
in a large puzzle there are lot of
things to look into both from the Siri
perspective as well as from
implementations and yes the the paper
last year did a particularly great job
there in finding some aspects and we're
definitely not done I think it's it's
worthwhile and and rewarding to first
look into the theory aspects and to
transfer them then into further models
which are closer to implementations man
getting from cisco systems I'm trying to
remember way back but if I remember
correctly the bell arion Rogo a model is
actually broken by key confirmation the
adversary can use the that tributed key
confirmation to distinguish a key from a
random key so as curious if you could
comment on your security model and
whether or not you looked at how key
confirmation actually affects that model
I'm not sure I got the question right I
understood as saying that in the belly
rub away more low-key confirmation you
inherently cannot have because it breaks
the key secrecy aspect um basically I
don't know if it's necessarily an
important like like the adversary can
recover the key but it actually does
provide a way if the adversary
to distinguish from random which is
essentially their their security problem
yeah okay so so this notion is
compatible in a sense of well the main
point is you or you should you cannot do
key confirmation with your main key like
sending a Mac under your main key this
breaks the the key indistinguishability
in a sense of below so what you have to
do and this is what it's done for
example in this transform you derive a
separate key with this one you Dookie
confirmation and the other one that you
are kept indistinguishable not used
before at this point you output as your
main session key and then you still get
like the freshness the good property in
a sense of ll go away cool thank you
welcome final question yes interesting
work I was wondering have you come
across protocols that are used in
practice or being standardized that do
not meet your definitions of key
confirmation well in particular if you
look into tears 1.2 there was quite some
trouble into in analyzing kills 1.2 in a
formal way because it did not fit this
concept of having a fresh key at the end
of the handshake so you needed more
tailored more specific ways of analyzing
it because it broke this idea of not
using the session key before you
finalize the handshake and that's not
the only example of course but it's one
of the prominent ones it's not clear if
the protocols and not necessarily meet
your definition but this work helps you
sort of organize discussed about it well
it's we didn't look into whether T at
one point two meets this kind of key
confirmation notion but it's an example
where using the key in a way that
whether key was used in a way that
breaks this main idea of key secrecy
idea of key secrecy idea of key secrecy
idea