thank you for the introduction I'm Lucas
I'm just finishing my PhD at the federal
university of pernambuco which is held
in brazil this work is a result from an
internship at Microsoft Research
mentored by Ben David and Margo's so I
would like to start just saying that
something should happen okay gestures
are everywhere
so right now as an example let me show
you just remind you some numbers about
connect so on the two versions of the
connect we had more than 44 million
units sold on early 2616 this is a
gesture sensor which is capable of
recognizing the user body joints on real
time it also provides and Colour
information about the scene deaf
information about the scene and this is
how this gesture sensors looks in VR so
here the user is interacting with Victor
content using hand gestures and we also
have it apply to augmented reality
scenarios so here while using the
hololens the user can see our method
content on the scene and interactive it
also with hand gestures so these kind of
platforms they are growing they are
appearing now we have tons of gesture
sensors of all sorts and sizes they are
getting cheaper and getting everywhere
and they also probably will be come with
application stores so for example the
Xbox one and the Microsoft 10 Windows 10
has an app store and these will become
the platform for applications while
using gestures so there are some
problems to this scenario the first one
that would like to talk to you about is
the privacy so once the applications
want to interaction with gestures on
their flows they
need to have access to some data from
the sensors and these today is given by
providing the application some left
frames some skeleton frames and it
raises some privacy concern this is
sensitive data another problem that we
want to tackle is safety so the judge
recognizer they can ask you to perform a
gesture that may be not safe for you and
also you have conflicts so the gesture
recognizer may ask you to perform a
gesture which is also performant we also
required by the assistance so let's say
on connect you have this attention
gesture which is required by the system
and it should not be overridden by an
application you also have conflicts
between two gestures on the same
application or different applications so
we would like to avoid this kind of
issues then we look around some ways of
performing gesture recognition so this
is the naive approach this code is
presented on white paper of microsoft
visual gesture builder this is what you
you do early on the development process
to develop our recognizer so we just
build boolean expressions one and you
try to fit these expressions on a
particular body posture or gesture but
these have some issues this may present
conflicts as we told before so we can
write two gestures that are triggered at
the same time if it's kind of code you
can also have safety issues you can ask
the user from impossible postures with
this and also this code grows bigger
it's hard to analyze so what developers
usually do they run to machine learning
approaches so here for example have the
wave gesture on machine learning what
you do you record variations of this
gesture so you ask users to perform the
same gesture maybe we want variations
about the Illuminations conditions or
the sense orientation and for this you
usually need some machine learning
knowledge it's also required and minimal
data sets I
for depending on their working and the
recording in tagging this data is almost
always expensive on the development
development process editing the gesture
is almost impossible machine learning
approach so let's say I just have a good
recognizer for the wave gesture now I
want to recognize the goodbye - which is
up here I have to do the whole process
again
I can't reuse the software that or they
recognize that they already have on the
previous gesture the recognition time is
not always on real time so there are
some issues still on some machine
learning algorithms and they usually
don't give you detailed feedback what I
mean by this is that the machine
learning approaches they usually give
you the output once you finish it the
gesture they don't give out you output
continuously while you are performing
the gesture and we wanted to do this on
our approach so we wanted to tell the
application in which part of the gesture
the user is now so it doesn't handles
conflicts as a preferred approach also
does not so there are some work bridges
work on this about privacy particularly
what they try to do is to limit access
to the applications so the applications
do not have the whole content about the
sensor the color frame is for example
can be converted on edgy images so you
can use some edge filter and just
provide fewer information for the
application and you can also just cut
off the color frame and send only the -
frame for the application but then on
the death frame you have information
about the environment because you can
understand shape so you can understand
what kind of furniture the person has at
home what kind of objects it they have
sorry for that so the other two issues
are about the silhouette so you have
also the information about the user
clothing and wait for example once you
have the silhouette and the skeletons
but even if you give all the skeletons
you are giving process information for
the applications so they can
automatically infer some properties of
the user just by analyzing the data so
what we wanted to do is this we wanted
to give a trace boundary between the
applications and the sensing data from
the user so here we have the proposed
concept which is our solution
you have the user on your left and then
you have the sense of sensitive user it
sends the skeleton data to our runtime
and what you do is that you have the
applications on the other side and they
don't have access to the skeleton itself
they just request information about the
interaction of the user so they ask if
the user is perform a particular motion
or postural behavior or a gesture itself
and we return the gesture events so this
requests where people's code so we built
a domain-specific language to formally
describe gestures which can be later
statically analyze it by XIII which is a
constraint solver by MSR and here we
just translate the code of people's into
v3 expressions which can be analyzing
and then you have our first boundary so
how we came up with this we watch it a
lot of applications gesture based
applications so here for example have a
therapy physiotherapy application which
tells the user to raise your left leg to
the side and return so this is a textual
description of the gesture and you also
have the number of repetitions that the
user should do that and they also have
the feedback in red telling what the
user is doing wrong
so the insight here is that they
describe the gesture by text and we
thought on our hypothesis that these may
be enough for a machine to recognize the
gesture and it's also on HCI point your
point of view it's also very good for a
developer to write gestures on this kind
of language which is a natural English
language so
we did that we let's break down the
phrase of raise your left leg to the
side there is an action and then you
have the body part relative to the
action and also a direction to that
action so what we didn't propose is that
we build our language and so you can
write a phrase like this rotate your
left elbow weight degrees to your left
so here we also have an action we also
have a body part and we have the angle
and the direction of the rotation what
happens in one time is this we build a
function a function called rotate
actually these functions right now they
are very hard coded but it they can be
increased that they can be embedded one
function inside another so we can grow
on this and we grab the information
about the left elbow from the data
provided by the connected sensor and
provide the arguments needed for the
function so you have 20 20 degrees in
the left direction as argument for
rotate so this is an action we have some
actions built in proposed and by using
that those axis we compute gestures so
let's say the action is a primitive but
we can build poses other factions in
gesture out of poses so here for example
have a ballet gesture and on this
gesture we have two poses will pose
Italian to use how to place the legs and
the feet and the other pose telling the
user how to place the arms and to finish
the gesture on propose you have to say
how it should be executed so here for
example the codes say that you should
first perform the cross legs one behind
the other pose and then perform the
second pose so what about safety what we
did is that we call it constraints on v3
that should be safety constraints for
the user so we have a spine constraint
that tells that the applications not
allowed to ask the user to bend his
spine we have a elbow constraint that
tells that the application is not
allowed to ask the user to rotate his
elbow on the opposite way so these are
generic constraints but you also can
have specific constraints depending on
the age of the user or if they use a -
physical disabilities you can add
another constraints for safety which you
tell which kind of gestures they use a
can perform or keynote to the
application and how it shake it is like
this we have the current state of the
user body with the positions and you
assume that it is safe right now at the
moment that is captured then we go
through each step of the Joshua and sd-3
if it's still safe after the execution
of the step and then we go through this
if the josh is not safe
where you can tell the developer which
part of the gesture which particular
action of the josh is not safe about
conflicts we have a similar approach so
we just send the three the two coded
gestures with the poses in s3 if they
have conflicts that means they can be
triggered at the same time or no so we
can detect conflicts between the system
gestures and the application gestures
between two gestures on the same
application or just using different
applications so the major concerns about
evaluation where is proposed expressive
enough to describe gestures and is it
fast enough to run real-time for
applications so these concerns were
evaluated so we built gestures on
treedome occasions which were
physiotherapy ballet and tyshee we have
an average of nine lines of code for
each pose and regarding performance yes
proposes fashion up it turns out 30
frames per second which is the top frame
rate for the sensor the Kinect sensor
and the matching time is really fast is
about 3 milliseconds and the post
transition it takes 91 milliseconds
regarding the submission so once you
write the proposed code you want to know
if it's safe enough or if it has
conflicts so you don't you not need to
do that in real time but you can do it
once you write a code and submit to the
App Store or let's say you just compile
the code and propose so to check for
safety we took less than one second into
check for conflicts we took less than a
minute okay so as conclusion I just show
you the proposed which is a language to
express gestures and it's also a runtime
so you can try out and see if to
recognize the gestures that you wrote it
supports privacy because it's at rest
boundary between the application and the
censored data it's also able to check
for safety and conflict using the three
so we added submission of the
application you can see if you your
gesture is safe and if has conflicts and
if not you can know why it's not safe or
where is the conflict so as I told you
I'm just finishing my PhD and but I
still pursue in this direction I want to
get further it on it so as future work
I would intend to add new actions and
primitives to improve the expressiveness
of propose so right now you can say the
second point some Direction can rotate
the arm to some direction can put a
joint in front on top of another online
joint spot we want to increase that so
you can closer to the actual textual
description that you have on real world
we also want to add time constraints
like say you want the user to perform at
Joshua slowly or fast Li we want to
support that on the all language we want
to build reusable gestures and provide
it as assets on stars so you can just
grab one gesture that I start let's say
the wave or point to jump gesture that
you have may start you can also edit it
unlikely unlike you can do on machine
learning approach and develop some X
example applications so developers can
go right to start with at last we want
to add sensor so as I told you in the
beginning you had a lot of hand gestures
on nowadays VR and they are we want to
add leap motion with quite
people the structure is all already
there I've just to add the sensor we
promotional the intel realsense and
others so we also developed a proposed
Explorer so you can write proposed code
on this application that we did here you
have the syntax highlighting and all and
you can try it out just play pressing
the play button so we can test it right
out and on below you can see the
progress bar so as I told you before we
show in which part of the Joshu the user
is and also they on the top on the
bottom right corner you can see the
number of completed times that the user
completed the gesture so that's it I
think that the beauty of proposed is
that it aggregates HCI and privacy and
security and you also can download it
it's available on github and we take
poor repress also thank you for your
time and I'm open to questions yes
questions yes to a very interesting work
ing on Microsoft Research
so you evaluated the expressiveness of
proposed with those three applications
but I think that maybe ultimate kind of
challenge is to evaluate yours against
like dense central like there's a lots
of dance move might be hard to express
with your limited vocabulary so what do
you think about that that's a good
question and also that's a great case
study that we could do so right now you
can write each position of the body we
propose it supports our current states
of the bird it may be too rigid so we
also implemented like restrictions that
relate to joints so it can instead of
saying do twenty degrees to that
reaction case I just put the hand on top
of the other so we think that it's
expressive enough that's why I called in
Tai Chi poses we saw something
some postures likewise tents and also in
balla balla is quite rigid but entities
more like a flow and flow gesture so I
think it is quite good for that case
yeah okay
good morning Peter Norman here I missed
my Tai Chi this morning I had a question
as to whether there's any synergy
between your work and the Purdue work on
interpreting American Sign Language
whether your approach might be useful to
them or whether their approach might be
useful to you yeah that's a great
question
so usually when do they do interpret
sign language they use machine learning
and they got a lot of data because the
signs they are already there I mean they
they don't create gestures the gestures
are already they don't create much at
least the judges are already there so I
think there's a slight difference but
once you have hand tracking on proposed
yes you sure could could that you could
introduce restrictions in and
transformations on the hand skeleton and
understand which gestures are being held
and the descriptions maybe maybe I be
good enough for for tracking this this
kind of gestures yes hello this is fish
from from UC Santa Barbara this is a
piece of awesome work thank you
I have a look so I noticed that you use
d3 for constraint solving we all know
that z3 is a good tool but sometimes
like when you have a large concern set
it may take a piece or amount of time
and you have your really don't know how
long it's going to take is it okay your
use case yeah I mean as I showed you we
did run the the check for conflicts in
safety it was really fun once you do it
offline on the o-line part it's really
fast
have three milliseconds for matching on
suits the transition between my post and
also I was doing a judgment
transit between Jew poses it takes 91
milliseconds so I think it's fine we can
discuss the details later if you want I
mean there are some tricky parts
optimization you need to have yeah we
can talk about it I think I've run out
of time so we can talk about that right
thank you