thank you for giving me the opportunity
to speak to you guys today I'm really
excited to talk to you about some work
that we've been doing at UC Santa
Barbara with my colleagues listed over
there
there's quite a few of us it's a big
project and I want to draw your
attention to two blue names over there
they were both high schoolers when this
project started so I don't know how
often high schoolers get published in
top-tier venues but this is one of them
so this work is not this work is about
two things
it's about binaries and it is about
offensive techniques on binaries so
attacking these binaries we want to find
vulnerabilities in the binaries and we
want to exploit those vulnerabilities
and we really want to understand how the
current state of the art lends itself
toward these approaches and our
motivations are twofold one is we're
really interested in the current state
of the art we're interested in what are
the limitations of current offensive
binary analysis techniques where they
can be improved and this is very
relevant because right now we're
experiencing an explosion of binary code
of course high-level languages have
always compiled down to binary and you
have to you know run binary on your CPU
at some point but now we're having this
IOT Renaissance where everything is a
smart device and these smart devices
often run binary firmware and often run
multiple different binary firmware
images on different sub devices so we
have a lot of binary code that can now
be attacked and means to understand how
current techniques are at identifying
and exploiting these vulnerabilities and
DARPA has recognized this need and
created the DARPA cyber grant challenge
it's a competition for an automated
binary analysis framework and by an
expectation framework they put a lot of
money on the table
which of course is also a good moderate
motivator
this is their statement that this is
important right and so we approached the
idea of analyzing binary offensive
binary techniques from our standard
scientific perspective well in science
we look at existing work in the field I
use it to get some idea of how to
improve it and output some new work back
to the community and we did the same
thing we looked at existing binary
analysis techniques and then we kind of
hit a interesting problem in that these
existing binary analysis techniques the
ones that publish source code so that
you can build off of them and the ones
that you know publish enough of an idea
that you can build off of it the release
tools have some problems right and so
there's a set of these problems one is
that you know sometimes even if the tool
is published it's not open sourced so
it's very hard to build off of it even
when it is open source sometimes it's
basically not open source so if you
write your tool in a language that is
extremely hard to use and extend
like sometimes happens in our field I
it's very hard to build it something off
of it even when they are open stores are
often very inflexible or they lack
support for multiple architectures so a
very architecture dependent and if
you're interested in analyzing firmware
x86 doesn't cut it even x86 and arm
alone doesn't about it you need a very
wide support of architectures and these
tools are not composable they're also
probably not compostable either but
they're definitely not composable in a
very very easy way because you know if
they're not really made to build off of
each other and extend each other it's
hard to combine them so you have
symbolic execution and you have some
static analysis and combining these
different tools from different papers is
non-trivial and sometimes impossible and
this is a problem for two things for two
reasons one is that it is hard to
understand what the real impact of the
work was right how much did the work
really improve over
the previous state of the art versus how
much it you know that's just a different
implementation and happens to get
different results so it's hard to
compare these things on an equal footing
because all the tools are implemented
very differently and it's very hard to
build off of because if you want to
combine multiple approaches to create
the next generation of binary analysis
it's a tricky if you don't have a solid
footing that can support all of your
what you want to do so we had the idea
of making a binary analysis framework
that solves these problems that allows
us to explore in a very system ties the
way how different analyses fit together
how symbolic execution can assist static
analysis how fuzzing can get looped into
the whole thing and what effects this
has right so we're really trying to
systematize the field of minor analysis
so that we can have a standard base on
which we can create approaches compare
them and see what happens at how well
they work so this binary analysis
framework we released and made is called
anger and this is the framework on which
we did this study this survey that's a
body analysis techniques and anger is
extremely modular it's made to become
possible and probably compostable as
well and it's made out of modules that
fit together and are very configurable
you can take these modules you can split
them apart mix them together and really
build different types of analyses so you
might combine different modules to
create dynamic symbolic execution engine
that uses value set analysis to resolve
bounds on symbolic variables you might
have a static analysis system that also
uses can call it tracing to try to prove
that the detections are not false
positives you could have a can call a
tracing engine and integrated with
another tool because the ogre is very
flexible it
meant to be used as a buy as a library
so you can integrate for example a
fuzzer
to understand how symbolically assisted
fuzzing compares to just normal symbolic
execution and all of this is on a single
base so it's really comparable so I want
to really stress this because if you
have different implementations of
different techniques it's very hard to
tell if the improvement was from the
implementation or from the technique
with anger with this work you can really
look at it on a single implementation
say okay that theoretical advance really
did this to the results and so I
mentioned anger has a couple of
different modules it has a bunch and I
don't have time to go into all of them
here but I'll go into overview of
modules that are also useful outside of
anger as kind of a general toolkit in
binary analysis so we created a binary
loader which allows an an analyst to
look at a binary and get a view of how
it would look in memory if it's loaded
it's a non-trivial process and our
binary loader supports elf binaries
Windows binaries cyber Grand Challenge
binaries and all sorts of binaries that
either supports because it can use ID as
a back-end to load them as well this is
very useful we see a lot of people using
this outside of anger we also created a
Python wrapper for Lib Bex we used VAX
as the new immediate language in anger
allowing us to use to support many
different architectures we see this
being used in the community as well a
lot in research actually over the last
couple of years and we created a really
useful module that abstracts data model
domains right so you have symbolic
variables in symbolic execution and you
have value sets and strided intervals in
value set analysis and we have a module
that allows us to abstract these into a
common representation basically an
intermediate representation for data
domains which really allows us to
compose these different analyses because
we can switch from some
execution - value sin analysis on the
fly as needed so we have all of these
cool things so what did we do with them
well we did many things one of them is
this study on how well current binary
analysis techniques an offensive binary
analysis techniques work on the cyber
grant challenge right so if you had a
research lab like ours and you want to
participate in the CGC could you use
existing techniques to basically really
apply them in kind of this real world
like setting and to participate in the
CGC you need to do two things you need
to analyze binaries I need to exploit
these binaries you also need to patch
binaries but here we are focusing on the
offensive techniques so we did a survey
of the existing works the existing work
that we wanted to systematize in this
project and we picked out these kind of
core papers they cover everything from
binary analysis for vulnerability
discovery to automatic exploit
generation to automatic exploit
hardening against software mitigation
techniques software vulnerability
mitigation techniques and there's
actually a bunch more papers of course
that we draw on these are kind of the
core ones and we implemented a lot of
different analyses to evaluate write
everything from kind of these base
analyses like a control flow graph
recovery through symbolic execution with
various different optimizations that we
can combine and compare and contrast on
a similar implementation base we
implemented a lot of static analysis
leicester's value set analysis and we
tested how well it interacts with
fuzzing if you have a assisted
symbolically assisted fuzzer
we looked into crash replaying a lot of
this sort of stuff and we invite you to
read in the paper
how we designed and implemented this on
a common base in anger so of course we
evaluated all of these analyses and
compared how they fare against each
other and our dataset was a hundred and
thirty one binaries that DARPA released
as the qualification event for the cyber
Grand Challenge and these binaries are
really interesting from a research
perspective because they're very diverse
they have different authors their sizes
are everything from a couple kilobytes
to ten megabytes ten megabytes is
roughly the size of Q EMU
I believe so that's a fairly beefy
binary they have a lot of different
types of vulnerabilities everything from
null pointer dereferences to function
pointer overrides B table trickery all
sorts of really subtle vulnerabilities
and some obvious vulnerabilities and
they provide a ground truth so we can
really say hey this detection we found
you know how how many false positives
did this you know to create so what the
detection of false positive or did we
find all of the bugs and of course we'd
never find all of the bugs but we can
try and the binaries are simple in a way
that allows us to save on implementation
time in the way that they interact with
a very simplified environment model of
the operating system so we implemented
all of these techniques on and ran them
on all these binaries and we found some
interesting results so for one thing we
found that in our data set our fuzzer
that we kind of used as a control check
of offensive binary analysis found
almost three times as many
vulnerabilities as basically any other
single technique and it found more than
the union of the rest of them combined
right so this is very interesting
we used AFL as our fuzzer
and AFL it turns out is extremely good
so it would be interesting to further
look into why our results differ from
labas results in this sense but we
looked into why on our binaries fuzzing
was king and it turns out that this is
because in the CTC binaries at least
most of the crashing conditions occurred
about 10,000 basic blocks into 100,000
basic blocks into the execution of the
application right and fuzzing found
those and so Mollica execution before
reaching those tends to suffer a state
explosion so symbolic execution like Tim
said earlier suffers from this inability
to penetrate very deep into an
application but on these binaries we
didn't see fuzzing having the same
problem fuzzing actually got fairly deep
this is also actually symbolically
assisted fuzzing so that might also
explain why it was able to penetrate
deeper but fuzzing alone also did pretty
comparably so we did this study we
implemented this tool upon which the
next generation of binary analysis can
be built and so we open sourced it so
now we hope to provide a base for future
binary analysis research the code is on
github you can grab it right now
actually the there's a docker image that
you can just run with your scripts and
it'll execute them in anger there's
documentation there's an IRC channel so
we really want to push this as a tool in
the toolbox of security researchers I
feel free to ask us for help we were
very responsive and really excited for
the next generation of binary analysis
anger was built by a very large team
this is all of us from UCSB that have
worked on anger in some capacity
and there's more people that are
external collaborators and it's really a
you know fairly serious project that we
were pushing forward and with that I
would like to open it up for any
questions you guys might have all right
any questions so we're waiting I think
one of the benefits of having this
extensive study on the same platform
there's a quite a good plus so the
question would be when you implement in
all these different approaches in the
same single platform did you do any
additional testing to prove that the
algorithm that was presented by
so-and-so is indeed and reflected
correctly on my Testament it's a it's a
tough problem because a lot of these a
lot of a lot of these papers have very
targeted evaluations yes that's the
reason yeah so for example there are
papers that target the state explosion
problem right and they have a motivating
example and then they show that they
work on the motivating example and we
work on the motivating example has that
it's hard to you know analyze it further
right we feel we implemented this
correctly it works like it says in the
paper but does it really work the same
as the original implementation for open
source ones you can check but a lot of
these things aren't open source and or
the tools are just not available so for
those you can't really check we've done
a lot of applications of anger see oh no
am i good so we've done a lot of
applications on anger in terms of you
know of course research on what we feel
should be solvable with these techniques
but also in the CDC and
in capture-the-flag competitions last
actually last weekend at DEFCON anger
got first blood on the top reversing
challenge at DEFCON so that's you know
against human hackers but and we feel
that from our results it makes sense you
know when we see that hey there's a path
explosion here we look into it okay that
makes sense when there are some things
endure a crash we look into the binary
and see okay well from a theoretical
perspective this would over want this
analysis and that would overwhelm that
analysis but kind of we do what we can
with the openness that is available yeah
I totally understand thank you for the
detailed answer