my name's Matt Tischer and today we are
going to talk about attacking people
using flash drives so the anecdote we're
looking at here is actually one that
hopefully lots of people in this room
have seen before it is one where it's
relatively simple to actually attack an
organization just by taking a bunch of
commodity USB flash drives putting
something bad on them going to the
parking lot scattering them somewhere
and waiting until participants pick up
the drives plug them in to their
computers and you've successfully
compromised everyone without breaking a
sweat
the quote shown on this slide actually
typifies what we see in these sort of
anecdotes everything is effective 15 out
of the 20 drivers were actually picked
up and it's not hard to make the attack
work they didn't even need to break a
sweat in fact this particular anecdote
has gotten popular enough that it's
actually made its way on to TV in the
case of the show mr. robot now when we
wanted to investigate this particular
anecdote we had a couple questions we
wanted to answer first of all we wanted
to see whether this attack actually did
work do users really plug in USB drives
that they find and if they do what is
that percentage is it 5% 50% more we
also wanted to see if we could make the
attack more effective by modifying the
appearance of the drives where they were
placed or when they were placed if we
write interesting things on the drive
well that convinced people to plug them
in is dropping things in the cafeteria
just as good as the parking lot is there
a good time to do this
finally we're interested in getting
inside people's minds and figuring out
why they actually pick up these drives
and open files are there particular
demographics who fall for this attack
more our people actually
bad at security are these the people who
don't understand it well why do they
even want to do this so in order to test
all of this we devised and executed the
following experiment
we dropped photographed in geo-located
297 flash drives at the University of
Illinois drives were dropped over three
days with the majority of the drives
being dropped during the Monday and
Tuesday of the week before finals we
dropped in 30 different locations
dropped five different kinds of drives
and during two times of day morning from
6:00 to 10:00 a.m. in order to attack
participants as they came to work or
school and 1:00 to 5:00 p.m. afternoon
to attack participants as they left
school or work we also periodically
revisited these locations after we
dropped drives to informally see whether
participants were picking up these
drives in moving them we were recorded
when users opened files on the flash
drives what files the opened and when
they opened finally when users double
clicked on these files we presented them
with a survey to allow them to express
information about themselves and why
they fell for the attack in the first
place naturally this particular
experiment earns a slide for ethics on
its own as it happens dropping a bunch
of flash drives on a university campus
to convince participants that they are
something innocuous was something that
we got approved by our institutional
review board we worked with various
stakeholders including campus police
legal counsel and Technology Services at
Illinois we incorporated their feedback
as we went and in terms of the technical
setup of the experiment we made sure
that we never actually executed code on
users systems unless they double clicked
on what ultimately was an HTML file on
the flash drive as a result we are not
able to track when
users plug in the flash drives which is
a way to compromise them but we did want
to ensure that the only way we would
load our remote image tag from our
server was one where users had
explicitly made a choice so now we will
address whether users actually do this
first we dropped 297 flash drives on the
ground among those 290 were taken from
the ground by the Friday of that week
and finally in terms of the events we
detected on our own servers 135 drives
reported that files were opened as a
result if we conservatively estimate
that users who opened files on the
drives of their own volition
would have been compromised we can lower
bound the effectiveness of this attack
at 45 percent as mentioned before we did
not track flash drives that could have
been plugged into computers without file
opens as a result the true effectiveness
of this attack is most likely somewhere
between 45 and 98 percent there's also
an interesting note here about speed
this attack works quickly the graph
shown here demonstrates the cumulative
distribution function of the times
between when we drop drives and when
drives were plugged in and files were
opened we notice that drives in
afternoon were picked up and plugged in
more frequently but for the group as a
whole the median time between drop and
file open was 6.9 hours we also noticed
online via monitoring social media that
people did begin to discuss this on
reddit during Tuesday afternoon when we
were dropping the large majority
of the last of our drives now we ask can
we increase the effectiveness of this
attack in any particular way we use five
types of drives to provide a variety for
users to pick from drives in the upper
left corner were unlabeled as a control
some drives were labeled confidential or
final exam solutions to attempt to
appeal to participants self-interest
some drives had keys or return labels
attached in order to attempt to appeal
to participants motivation
oh that's somebody's apartment keys I'd
better plug it in and see if I can
return it to them we also make another
timing note in the sense that these
drives were once again dropped the week
before finals so we did happen to
observe making at least one student very
happy and likely later very sad now we
chose realistic contents for these
drives as well what you see here are the
contents we used for unlabeled return
label and keys drives as you can tell
there's a set of documents including a
resume some math notes and some winter
break pictures we dropped in 30
locations across the Illinois campus
divided into five different kinds of
categories academic rooms like
classrooms or libraries common rooms
like cafeterias or halls in dorms
hallways outside pathways walkways and
benches and parking lots now we ask well
can we actually increase the
effectiveness that this attack at all
interestingly enough the answer is no we
can't actually increase the
effectiveness of the attack by changing
how the drive looks like where we
dropped it or what time of day it was
however we can actually decrease the
effectiveness of this attack by
attaching a return label to the drive so
the net take away from this may in fact
be if you don't want people snooping
through your flash drives provide them
an alternate way of contacting you now
we asked the third question why are
people doing this
well hop back to our previously
mentioned attack funnel and we'll
consider the sixty-two survey responses
we received from participants who
plugged in drives and double clicked on
files we find a couple interesting
things now this survey was comprised of
a couple different components first we
included the domain-specific risk taking
scale which describes participants
willingness to preserve risky activities
across five different domains such as
financial or recreational are you
willing to go skydiving or are you
willing to make an investment that's ten
percent of your income if it's risky we
also included the security behavior
intention scale which measures
participants frequency of various
positive or negative security behaviors
our participants likely to frequently
install updates are they likely to
frequently change their passwords we
also want to know who are these people
who are falling for this attack so we
asked various demographic questions such
as their age gender and affiliation with
the University of Illinois our
undergraduates more likely to fall for
this than graduate students our
professors and most likely of all we
also asked various questions about the
flash drive itself did you notice
anything special about it were you
interested in it for any particular
reason why did you plug it in did you
have any concerns about the entire thing
we find a few interesting findings the
vast majority of participants claimed
they wanted to return that drive to its
proper owner now this makes sense and is
in line with the data we have that say
returned label drives are open less
often but there's a caveat to this
remember how we said we tracked which
files were opened when participants
plugged in drives it turns out that many
of them actually chose to look at winter
break photos first and we argue that
while a resume for example may contain
contact information of the owner and
while one person in the survey made the
defense they were looking for the owner
on Facebook we find that most likely
participants are also driven by
curiosity the vast majority of
participants also did not describe
taking precautions and while some of
them in fact did do very well opening
the HTML file in a text editor on a
virtual machine without network access
other participants were less good at
this for example when one participant
was asked were you concerned about what
could be on the flash drive they said
yes I was so I sacrificed the university
computer
this slide was very popular with our IT
department we also find that there
actually isn't really any particular
type of participant when we compare to
the University of Illinois population
they're demographically similar in terms
of gender affiliation and age and when
we look at their security behavior
intentions for the majority of items
they're actually similar to the general
University of Illinois population to
summarize we find that users do in fact
plug in USB flash drives that they find
on the ground from forty five to ninety
eight percent is a rough estimate of our
success rate you can't really make the
attack much better by changing the
appearance of the drive where you drop
it or when you drop it but if you don't
want people snooping through your stuff
it's probably not a bad idea to attach a
return label and finally participants do
claim that they pickup drives to return
them and there is a lot of evidence that
suggests this but there is also some
suggestion that curiosity plays a
significant role in their interest that
concludes this talk thank you very much
for your time and now any questions
hi really interesting talk I guess it's
a fairly common practice to use
predominantly undergraduate populations
as a as a proxy for actual adults the
the thing that you know I'm I'm curious
in in this case you know the the the
scenarios the environments where like
social engineering attacks via USB
actually worried us are you know
enterprises and government facilities
where we have security training and
security interventions and at this point
you know people talk about social
engineering and what those attacks might
look like so I was curious do you have a
sense you know with these findings is
there anything that we can take from
these results and apply to them to some
of these environments that we care about
the most in this regard sure I think one
of one of the more interesting results
that comes out of this is we did in fact
in terms of you know the context of the
study itself we did actually see
graduate students and staff picking up
these drives as well so in the somewhat
limited context of the university kind
of as a quote-unquote corporated
environment we do actually still see a
little bit of compromise in addition I'd
also say I think it's it's interesting
to note that motivation for people on
this does not really appear to be you
know pegged anything particular so I
think it it's still useful to
potentially educate people and say you
know any of this is potentially
dangerous but otherwise I guess the main
takeaway is probably just to you know
consider it a threat in the first place
yeah le Canal software engineering
Institute very interesting talk
so to think of this I'm trying to think
of this more from a behavioral economics
standpoint if you have a collar on the
floor most people will pick it up
because they won't assume the dollar is
coated with you know Ebola virus or
something like that so to that
standpoint you know it seems that most
people would pick up a u.s. because they
simply
to them yeah I may get to see something
cool and the downside is I'm wasting
five minutes they don't realize that I
may be ruining my life
so do you ask questions about what their
background is what what kind of risks
they associate with putting a USB Drive
in their in their computer we we didn't
really go down that road too much one of
the interesting things we actually did
find along those directions though was
that a decent chunk of participants
actually double clicked on the files
because they saw they were HTML files so
the the fact that the drive looked a
little bit suspicious was actually
something interesting that they were
looking for so good thank you so was the
fact that you didn't go to Walmart say
you put out drives saying store number
size of such layoffs or outside Apple
and say put other draw it drives there
because the IRB or because or what so
yeah I think it it was something we were
a little hesitant to go into in part
because we wanted to make sure we
engaged with all of our stakeholders
appropriately and when you go to Walmart
you know it's not strictly speaking just
that Walmart it's potentially someone
higher up the chain as well and in in
terms of risk keeping things relatively
isolated to the University was something
that sort of allowed us to easily make
sure that proper stakeholders were being
contacted and everything was coordinated
as best as possible
do you think there'll be serious issues
about trying to do a study on a
industrial campus or I don't think there
are serious issues in terms of things
ethically speaking I think it may take a
while unless you know there are the
proper contacts in place to make sure
the right people are aware of things so
there might be red tape I would expect
but I wouldn't expect it to be
ultimately insurmountable
hi good afternoon
I have a question regarding your survey
that you got with the files
did you get information about whether
they were using their personal computers
or university computers I know the one
joke came up about the IT staff but when
you come in to say a corporate work
environment if they would pick up the
USB Drive and say plug it into a work
computer versus their home computer we
did not do any significant tracking we
actually chose not to retain IP
addresses for example because we
consider them identifiable information
so essentially our information in terms
of where people plug things in is
limited to what they supplied to us
themselves when we asked them about it
and on a related note so you said that
somewhere between 45 and 95 98 percent
of the drives were may be used for your
more tech-savvy folk who may not have
plugged it into an Internet connected
device whereas there anything in there
that allowed them to communicate to you
that they found it and didn't plug it
into a computer that would be
compromised yes and actually I think one
or two participants since it was an HTML
file we included the debriefing page in
HTML and we included a contact email
information for us for the entire study
and what we did find actually with a
couple of the very tech savvy people is
they emailed us to say is this actually
a legitimate survey or somebody putting
your name on their own attack so okay
cool that was the those all I have thank
you sorry that we're actually conduct
annual security training for faculty
staff and students I forget exactly the
protocols in place but I believe there
is some regular security component