hi everyone we are at the hardware CDF
at Malkin I've got Phillip Ingram with
me and they're going to tell us what
they are up to
hello I'm Phillip and we organized here
Hardware oriented CTF so CTF views are
probably a few other CTF at närcon which
are more traditional with software
challenges hacking challenges here the
particularities that each challenge
requires some hardware but of course we
don't expect people to come with their
toolbox here so we provide the tools to
solve the hardware to solve the
challenge as well as the challenge
themselves and we have different kind of
them you can go around later and see
what happens there is some for example
RFID challenge where there is an
airy-fairy reader that you can find on
the door and you have to open the door
given some information and some material
that allows you to fake or to clone
RFIDs
you have some other also RFID where you
can sniff what happens between the phone
and the card and then you can recover
the flag with some micro sundering
challenges and some other which are wide
tapping on the boosts like a CRC or SPI
boosts but when you do that on real
device usually you to find your way find
the burst on the PCB so that's why we
have this microwave soldering challenge
that goes together where people can
really stretch the tracks on the PCB to
solder their wires and be able to sniff
what's going on that verse we also the
challenge is more rated to automotive
and radio yeah they will let Guillaume
explain which is so we have a simulation
of a car with the canvas and the guys
have to snip the communication on the
canvas and recover information and
replace some information for example to
open the door of the car and sing things
like that okay yeah I will present
so a workshop about hacking this
afternoon against is something else but
we wanted people to come and try
during the hardware CTF they want to try
hacking and discover things and have fun
with that
this is the microcell during challenge
for this challenge we have designed a
few boards which are here and those
boards are used to sneak the
communication in there we like hacking
you know because the traffic is going
from one side to the other side and
would like the contestants to sniff this
traffic by soldering micro wires from
the tracks here to here to create the
connector you know and this is the the
ball that we that are made and this is
an example board in which you can see a
very thin wire and those wires are a
thin as a human hair so very small and
that's the challenge in fact to be able
to solder them so you see here on the
screen the contestants here is using a
microscope to do his soldering and you
can see here on the screen there is a
wire going from here to attract so he's
doing this challenge pretty well and you
can see
he paints to uncover the tracks and now
he's soldering directly on the tracks I
think it's amazing to have people doing
that here I'm sorry
[Music]