and the topic for this panel discussion
is lateral thinking staying ahead of the
curve items on the CXO checklist that
can help them serve the wave I would
like to invite on the stage mr. sho-me
Ron Das Gupta founder for the net
Montessori a big round of applause for
him I would also like to invite the
panelists mr. Hari Prasad je t'ai
national bank of 0pj
SCC so from National Bank of 2-0 PJ I
see a big round of applause and mr. K or
this I see so from Acer porcine shipping
and mr. Subramanyam Kumaraswamy see so
visa incorporation thanks for give me
the promotion I am NOT a seriously it
simple me as well well thank you so much
for being here
afternoon session thanks to my panelists
to be here and help me host make makes
the job easier so I'm the one who's
going to ask the questions and you know
and point the finger at my friends here
by the way we will have open format
please feel free to raise your hand
disagree with us if you agree with us
you can just listen to what's going on
right all right so the idea of this
session is about you know figuring out
what's going on right how how are we
thinking in our day jobs and how are we
basically trying to bring our capability
of detection and you know being able to
safeguard our our infrastructure on a
day to day basis right so we've got
three absolute luminaries of the
industry what we want to know from them
is how they have taken this industry
standard right everybody knows there's
the industry standard the industry
standard for everything right so how do
you take that industry standard
and actually make it work because we
know industry standards never work when
you actually take it down to to office
right how do you react how do you
actually make it work how do you tweak
the system and best practices from from
such organizations to figure out you
know key things that that were important
in in taking you know implementing major
decisions so we're we're pretty much a
technical audience right so we will make
that journey from 30,000 feet to 300
feet and and backwards up and down so
you know be with us hope hope you have a
good time right so so first set of
questions I'm sorry I I'm not a
millennial but I'll still use the phone
so first question the first set of
questions that I've got three questions
for each of them and before that I'd
like you to introduce yourselves so that
you can you know talk about talk about
yourselves your passion your areas of
interest in cybersecurity two minutes
each okay
my name is Hari Prasad everybody knows
Harry Potter you can call me hurry
that's that's I hope you remember my
name now my name is Hari
I work as a CEO from past 13 years from
different national banks we have
multiple national banks in UAE okay so
my main passion is to change the culture
of security in the organizations I was
there from the organization's where
there is no security to the organization
which is matured up to the CMM level
five and how I have to fit out there
that is one and my passion is what I
learned from past 17 years how I had to
give it to the community so I have
started everybody knows the moral signs
in your education right I don't know
whether anybody heard about cyber moral
signs I work with the psychologists and
the kids to teach the cyber moral signs
for the kids from the age of four
onwards to the ten
okay that is my one and the second thing
what I concentrate on is that is what I
learned from the sales team is how to be
an effective seller in the bank or in
the Indian institution in order to
implement your security if you're not a
Salesman please don't join as a security
C so that's my passion
and the third one is I work for a forum
called for the special needs kids they
don't know how to communicate okay when
I talk you people let's say at least not
I know that when you people are
listening but they don't even understand
and I'm are working with a couple of
technical especially with the Samsung
and Apple to understand how to use this
technologies for effective communication
with the people who doesn't even
understand anything
thank you yeah yeah good afternoon
everyone my name is ko Desai I work for
SR I play a couple of roles in my
organization one of my role is I work as
a CIO for SF ports and shipping business
group where I own the end-to-end
IT lifecycle for the for the for this
for this business groups and my second
role is I had the information security
network and the oral unified
communications part for us our group
that includes the steel business support
shipping as a power generation plants as
a construction cooperate I grow etcetera
so the list goes on we also have a
service on that's the IT services on
that's called ADC networks so we're my
role is more about right from star right
from understanding the business risks
understanding the business workflows
business risk evaluate the right
solutions and then evaluate volumes work
with various different partners and kind
of identify and implement the right
solution and then maintain it so we have
a separate knock and we also have taken
the managed sock services from our
internal IT services on that's HTC
networks so that's that's that's what my
role plays around I just wanted to share
my passion I mean my passion is
bit bit different from from the
technology so in fact I so I I'm a
typical music lover so I play a
harmonica so I'm a part of various
different harmonica so I'm a part of the
all in your harmonica players group
whenever we meet once in a month when
and even we have those harmonica clubs
within Mumbai as well so where we kind
of meet once in month we do jamming and
and I and I and I perform into those
live or live programs in that way so
that's just just an off track first
happy Holi in the spirit of holy
hopefully we can make this colorful
discussion right so my name is super
Kumar Swami I lead the secretary texture
for visa how many of you have visa cards
in your pocket either in a mobile or you
know so we know we are a big big payment
player and obviously we you know
security is the paramount for the entire
company we always say the number one
priority in the company security right
so nothing else number one I've really
pretty comes number two everything we do
in the company starts with security
first and foremost so my so my I've been
in industry for the last 25 years and
start as a developer so you know I so I
know the sins of developers right so I
come to this site to make sure that we
can out-educate the developers so they
can write good code right so making sure
that we can have products who the least
number of defects right going out so
it's you know I don't know if you heard
this term called shift left right you
know how do you shift left to the you
know beginning of the cycle starting
with developers starting an architect so
we start thinking about security very
early in the life cycle not something an
afterthought right there's a saying that
the cost of response is hundred times
the cost of prevention right so it's
very very important focus on pension
first before you think about you know
direction oh they're all important part
of difference in depth strategy but my
passion is to make sure that we prevent
things to start with prevent meaning
built sick built in security versus
bolt-on security right and you know my
favorite
quote is that heads in the head in the
cloud feet on the ground right always
look look forward look forward to the
next gen or what's coming up but don't
lose it don't lose sight of the basics
make sure that you're in a very good
baseline good hygiene the second code I
you know really enjoy it I think about
is you know folks know who st. bolt
right it was involved you know there so
he has a very good saying is that you
know I don't worry about things right I
I train every day and you know and when
it comes to the day I had a go perform
it's it's you know I'm performing so you
know it's very important for all of us
in the room to think about what we do
every day today it's not about being
reactive so we do we train for the
worst-case scenario right we train to
make sure that if there's a breach you
know we can respond quickly and I
remember Kevin mandiant who was the CEO
of fire I and Mandy in cooperation he
had a CR saying that the difference
between a player and yes player is not
the a player is extremely secure is that
a player can identify a breach in a very
short duration right versus EF players
will you know take six months or eight
months before yeah you know they
understand the company's been preached
so anyway so those so my you know again
like I said my fundamental approach to
security is to understand how do we
prevent things in the first place
and then build security around it so
this what we do this session is base
this around the big surface areas of the
breach right so the four we identify
usually if I am the user of the system
and I myself is you know I am the
insider attack right and I am I am my
intent is bad and I want to steal second
is if my credentials are stolen right so
somebody impersonates me and bunches
deals into the system everybody thinks
it's me here's my endpoint is stolen
broken into people throw deals through
the endpoint and four is the application
I'm punching these deals into right and
if that that is broken so we are going
to try and attack as many of these
attack surfaces because the reason I've
chosen this theme is that all three of
them are from absolutely different
spaces and are managing enormous ly
large infrastructure right so the first
one we are going to talk about hurry is
talked about is what is the how do you
you know manage to identify insider
threat right and how do you how to deal
with it from tactical to practical so we
will go that whole distance from
strategic to you know help us understand
how you do it in alright I'll try to
convince the people in the next two
minutes raise your hand if you don't
agree all right
first and foremost thing is there is no
solution for the collusion in any
organization okay there is no collision
there is no solution for a coalition
just keep in mind okay the second thing
is as I told in the beginning as he so
has to be a good sales guy that means he
need to understand his environment on
his business very well if he's not able
to sell security to his people the best
of the best technology can't allow him
to drive his program well the second
thing third thing is you need to
understand I'll tell my experience you
need to understand what is the context
of your organization where which part of
the this small example I will give you
is lot of let's assume that if you are
in a phase of implementation of the
basic security controls in your EIN if
you are trying to be a part of a
security and try to dictate IT people to
implement those controls it never going
to work because nobody wants because
everybody have an emotional quotient
nobody wants to say that you are wrong
please implement this right if a
pinpoint somebody do they like it right
so you need to check it out in your
organ
which part you are so at that time there
is nothing wrong though the best of the
standards say that one the security has
to be independent from the IT and all
the stuff but if your organization is in
the implementation for phase of the
basic security controls there is nothing
wrong in having a security team under IT
ok that is the first thing which I
learned and I was able to achieve the
objectives very well and sell to the
management first thing and the second
thing is as you when you are trying to
do that one
you never boast about yourself let the
business talk about you that's what I'm
saying that when keep on saying that one
you when you try to implement some
solution ensure that some business
people go and talk to the another
business people so you need to be
ensured that one who is that influencers
in your organization that can influence
your program across and to the senior
management you need to identify those
people once you identify them you need
to end you need to get them under your
shoes I mean I usually see his use means
he has to feel that when what is the
pain that you're feeling it and what
you're doing it unless you do that you
will not be able to execute that one
this is the governance part what you
call in the technical terms of standard
parts be it a governance or the
organizational structure if you follow
these principles you will be able to
achieve to implement your information
security program coming to the tactical
things in security every day I heard
about lot of new terminologies right
there are so many terminologies but I am
there in in this industry from 2000
onwards in the information security this
means 18 years the basics not changed
confidentiality integrity availability
non reputation and triple-a right
authentication authorization and
auditing anything else I don't think so
you tell me any weakness I can map with
this
any weakness you talk about any
technology anything what are the
advanced technology talking about please
ensure that one these basics are right
at wherever the program you are in okay
if you are able to do this then you talk
about the advanced technologies about
the detection and all those things map
it to this let's take on my side beat
from the from the governance perspective
I told you from the technology
perspective ensure that from these
basics are taken care you know
respectfully disagree on one thing right
collision so we talked up me know
Snowden there's not an problem right
where you have access privilege so
obviously you know there are certain
things can be solved by technology these
cannot but having said that right you
don't want to make sure there is a clear
you know separation between roles right
especially if privileges and access
control so is own and kind of understand
from your perspective when you say
collusion are you referring to the
collision you know on the business side
or your so when I talk about the
collision like between the technology
part people if the collision happens
this is the risk is much lower if you're
talking about the business the best of
the technology you might implement let's
assume that you have an authorizer who
is having instead a let's say let's take
about many of the people know this web
deal let's take the swift tails if there
is a three level or two four level of
authorizations we can have it right the
ultimate person will be having a let's
assume that he is having an
authorization of a hundred million
dollar just a collision between layer
two too late for is possible it is
definitely possible and we are already
given authorization parameter for the
level four guys a hundred million dollar
it depends upon out of hundred million
dollar how much percentage he gets this
layers that's it
you put the technology of let's assume
that you put a machine learning
technology and whatever the technology
you try to put it you try to take out
the fraud saying that when it is going
to the same destination and all those
things but my author is it is one
hundred million dollar is one one and
then I
what's the money moves out he might get
caught but money never get back
you take about any of the incidents now
again collusion how do you being able to
detect it so you're going to get breed
strike
how will you detect it fast right what
are what are those controls that you
need to put in place to identify a
breach quickly so that you can respond
and you know limit one thing I can say
from the I'm sure that ERISA is having a
volume speaks about the volumes this is
where even still I yet to get a solution
what I was thinking is if there before a
collision there is if there should be a
pattern the pattern may not be the
transactions within your organization
that pattern can be outside maybe a
social networks his family is trying to
move out from these these things there
should be some pattern you've there if
there is a pattern external an internal
map we should be able to come out with a
some correlation and try to identify
early err that is what I can view it I
mean if any other panelists value to it
if I can add right so we saw we collect
over eight billion emails a day right
yeah I mean we don't have problem data
collection you know we collect data from
every single aspect from your laptop
from your your ideas IPS firewall you
name it right I mean we are collecting
data out of the BOSU so the problem is
the signal-to-noise ratio right how are
you able to find the needle in a needle
stack so we've been you know over the
last couple of years we've been applying
a quite a bit of machine learning you
know machine learning as you know the
lot of buzz word artificial intelligence
are the buzzword right so there is
definitely a lot of hype around machine
learning but having said that right it
is you have to start experimenting right
do you have to understand you know what
hari was saying is that you know what is
a normal pattern right so just for folks
right in the room you probably
understand that most of the use cases in
cybersecurity is unsupervised learning
right that means like there's every data
that you collect has no
Abel you don't know what is good what is
bad right like spam right you know spam
the spam filters are very talented they
trained right the trained understand
what looks like a normal email versus a
spam same issue right we collect 8
billion evens a day but we don't know
what those events alright so they're one
of the things we've been doing is we
have what we're calling is closed loop
effect where as data is coming in we
apply the the models machine learning we
distill down like a funnel right if we
distill down to actionable maybe like 30
or 40 evens a day and from there we
validate so they're human beings come in
right sock the security analysts come in
they look at the events they understand
hey this looks like that laptop is
compromised there's a malware right and
then we take that data and then we start
labeling automatically every single even
that comes along right then then it
begins supervised learning so then you
have an intelligent model that can catch
right and without going to details we
have caught many instances because we
looked at some other patterns and say
hey this looks like a data exfil right
and we're able to you know identify and
it doesn't mean that they're perfect but
you know the there are ways to do it
using more of a prayer what it called
deterministic rules but the problem with
deterministic there - right the two
aspects one is a deterministic which is
very declarative versus predictive right
can you predict something that is
happening so a lot of the rules based
technology like firewall is the rules
based right you know that it's allow or
deny right nothing else but in machine
learning is fuzzy so you have to start
continuously you learn continuously
train the models and be able to say does
this data that is moving from this
machine to other machine looks like a
normal data is it a sequel server
administrator doing it dump or is it
insider taking a dump and walking out I
want to take this to KO and ask him what
do you do with endpoints right I mean
you have so cute has multiple
organizations that he represents and
large number of endpoints that are
uncontrolled right so I mean how do you
work with endpoints and make sure
the sanity prevails at the end of the
day yeah so before I quickly respond to
that I mean I just like to add one more
to the last points of repose while I
mean this is based on experience that we
had as a part of our song journey also
while nothing comes I mean like you all
know nothing comes out the typical use
cases as out of the box use cases right
so for each and every business verticals
we actually set with our business teams
to ensure that what are those what are
those deviations as as the as the
business team should should should
Proclaimers so business team say if we
are performing so in so activities all
right sir the counts team the finance
team the the production team so each
team have their own versions of the
deviations now these deviations then we
go back and map it with our sock team
saying that if if anything deviates from
this we should get an alert in there so
so that actually helped us a lot I mean
still it's a journey as I said I mean
it's it's still we have kind of a long
way to go this is this is very relevant
I mean baselining outlier detection is
extremely important for identifying
inside so some things that you know you
did a million-dollar transaction last
three months no and you're doing a
million million dollar transaction right
now it's it's a clear outlier in that
needs more validation yeah sure yeah
yeah yeah sure I think if once you
identified incident then the first place
you go to to look for further
information is the logs right correct so
just coming to the whole insider threat
pattern um my questions more about or
employee privacy so as CEOs who collect
our data clearly as you mentioned is
that something that you even think about
while doing this or is employed price
here still a consideration or yeah they
keep that quick because that's going to
be a less pull us them in some other
reasonable to say that employees should
not have any expectation privacy I'll
take that one I deal with logs every day
I have a mic yes I think employee
privacy if you are if you are using
the office internet for Facebook yeah
you're going to be watching
unfortunately so because there are
higher priorities in in in the corporate
environment there and the corporate has
to deal with far larger boxes of Pandora
right so unfortunately yes
if you're it will you will have a
privilege so I think it certainly just
to our right it's also a
country-specific right you know European
countries are much more sensitive right
so there's certain things so we do have
to take them consideration in terms of
what it can capture data so yeah
certainly but you know but by and large
when you sign a deal when you sign the
contract to the company you're giving up
the rights all right see that is where
again the we need to ensure that money
okay baseline baseline as for our
organization requirement okay
I might be having what technology based
on my technology what services will work
or not based on that we need to
customize that there is no single silver
bullet to solve all these solutions we
need to ensure that what is customized
for not much I can say about state your
number of false positives will reduce of
course yeah all of us have to walk our
journey in our own organization I can't
get get a model that puts me to work for
any other organization it has to relearn
so 90% of the effort goes on the data
engineering right the tenth person is
the you know because we have to make
sure that garbage in garbage out right
if you're not able to collect that data
or normalize it and ingest the data you
know whether you're using Hadoop our
elastic sir
or Splunk right it's very important to
make sure that the data that you're
capturing right attributes because in
machine learning there's something
called feature extraction so you have to
extract the features like IP address or
port or a size of the the packet right
all those are very important to
eventually define understand what a
baseline is okay super so I'm next
question to you know K or again endpoint
compromise you want to just do the
tactical part or the practical part how
do you deal with that like so so I'm
sure we'll all agree will have n number
of agents sitting across the endpoints
nowadays we have what is doing the
legacy the endpoint security one in
monitoring the assets one one agent
sitting and kind of again doing the ML
any I partner all that I can I deal with
parties so now while we have n number of
agents I mean while this this story goes
on what we kind of have one heard in our
in our organizations while so as I said
I mean while we have a typical
diversified type of business where we
have steel manufacturing planning in in
the remote part of the country where
sometimes poori is hard to find we an
even by four o'clock in the evening you
were kind of leave those leave the you
you don't have work at the place because
of I mean the X number of reasons now
staying in those areas or other working
in those areas those endpoints are still
a part of the network right the
endpoints are still part of the network
so what we're doing is so we've kind of
gone ahead with the solution I will not
name the solution we just started
rolling out it's almost 50% of halfway
in the journey now the solution is
simple again it's an endpoint which sits
on the top of the endpoint security I
mean it's it kind of compliments the
endpoint security and so it and it's a
typical signature list solution where it
works it actually scrambles
so while all our application web browser
OS they actually work in the memory
space so this particular application
kind of scrambles the process part the
memory process part for each and every
unique unique unique activity now let's
say if there's an militia
attack happening on that on that
particular machine so this agent also
kind of keeps at dummy kids the keeps
the original memory allocation structure
as a power in tight and actually it it
kind of scrambles it and notifies the
application saying that the new new
memory allocation is is is is different
now let's see if attack happens the
attacker still will kind of its it will
kind of still get confusing that which
is right and memory allocation but and
as soon as it hits the original order
dummy memory allocation part it gets
trapped so now as a part of that
solution we actually could actually now
roll it out to all our remote locations
all our plant locations where we help
those power generation plants which are
in remote part of the different states
within India we are also now targeting
all our remote locations which are kind
of outside India and so I just to just
to name few which are kind of connected
through broadband which I connected to
IPSec tunnels so all the endpoints are
now kind of connected now as a part of
our next story and we have kind of put
this as one of the one of the criteria
saying that if this endpoint is not
there in the machine for whatever 50
percent we rolled out that machine will
be quarantined in that way so I mean
there are a number of ways we actually
found this we kind of and let's ooh just
to mention so we'll be the first
organization within India who will be
kind of implementing this this
particular solution so maybe in another
month or maybe you know the couple of
months it will be out in public public
media okay so how many of you are
interested in analytics in cyber
security three four five six seven okay
so next question to you so you have seen
you know you you see a mountain of data
every day how do you deal with how do
you use analytics sure yeah you know
they're saying that what you don't
measure what you don't make sure you can
manage right and you yeah and you know
and you know the same thing goes for
security you know we have to understand
the line of sight so from analytic
standpoint will be a very very pedantic
when it comes to
we measure everything for example
patching right at any given time any
user application owner within visa can
login to a portal and get a snapshot of
what systems are patched what time right
so our goal is hundred percent
compliance right hundred person can't
miss patching I mean unfortunately it's
a lot of pain a lot of tax on the
operations on the business side right
but so you know the reason why we do
this is really did a research and we
found the three ways companies get
compromised right number one malware on
laptop right in like no Kara was saying
you know then why endpoints agreed
matters so if you are constantly getting
fished you know we see all sorts of
phishing attacks right and they spear
phishing mal was getting dropped you
know through macros what-have-you right
number two insider threat right we
talked about that inside threat is you
know that's another reason why you know
you see their data exfiltration or in a
compromise is happening through back
doors number three is is really like
said patching balance putting management
is a key part of the strategy that every
company should think about so we have to
collect it so they'll be going back the
question is that you know sylvania need
to understand you know what is the
posture for the endpoint so are any
given time I should know what controls
are running on the laptop and I know
that we know that a lot of the
developers they have admin privilege
right they need to do some testing on
their you know Xcode or visual studio or
eclipse right they're running constantly
running against Apache and nginx and all
that at the same point right when you
know when we know that some folks have
admin privilege we also need to
understand what controls are you know in
place so if they try to disable a
control we should be able to go back and
say the system is you know violating a
policy and we'll quarantine it right so
we have you know as we could as we
collect data we always ask why we need
to collect the data right unless you
have you know you got to start with a
question first why is this very
important for you to take an action
whether it is for you know putting a
rule in a firewall or putting a rule on
ideas or four
are you know understanding the secretary
control f UK efficacy right so we start
with that first you know what are the
basics that we need to think about for
example DDoS right so you know week if
you see constant attacks in DDoS and we
understand we like know what are the
targets know what's the what are the
services are getting targeted and we
collect data through Akamai is example
and we collect or other you know other
defenses that we have internally so
these this provides the feed back into
the you know application architecture
right I can actually build in now rate
limiting if I know that you know this my
API is are the target for the hackers
because that's there's something
valuable there right because we expose
quite a bit of api's and these are
payment api's and very easy to commit
fraud right for example architecture
also change well I mean we do the ideal
scenario right where you want is you
want dynamic very dynamic way of
introducing controls right but today you
know if you know almost 80% of traffic
on the Internet is or within the
enterprise is encrypted right you have
Kahless so you need to make sure that
you know be able to get visibility into
the traffic to understand what is going
on right so what we are saying is that
can we introduce some controls on the
fly if I see an attack coming in can I
route the traffic or route the traffic
to it let's say there's ideas ideas
laughs right
but I know that this particular attack
is relevant to application attack so I
can I say route the traffic to an
application control like a bath versus
subjecting every single traffic to the
same controls right so basically
currently what we have is a very static
model one size fits all where you want
to go into smaller dynamic controls
where I can introduce controls on the
fly all right that's the vision so that
we can actually you know improve the
user experience first and also make sure
that we only apply the right control so
the right-hand thread level see
traditionally what we try to do is if at
all in any attack happen first
what we try to do I mean any answers if
any attack you've observed in your
organization what is the first thing we
try to do to unplug the network okay
unplug the network and all the stuff
yeah you need to be very fast legs then
just imagine how many of us are actually
keeping this unplug off the network in
mind when you're designing an
architecture okay so did we take it the
business into consideration is it okay
for them to shut down the service when
we unplug that particular thing when I
incident happen I take an example
because the traditional architecture is
if it is my hive Allah if my primary is
not there I'll shut down the primary and
make it high available one and make it
available to the customer and if the
secondary is not available make the DRA
available and make it down so the
concept need to be changed that's what
we are doing some research within the
organization like a submarine principal
if the submarine one gate is closed its
you close the second gate so that at
least your crown jewels are protected so
are we trying to look into that
particular angle are we educating our
business guys saying that one what is
the current of critical services that we
need try to protect like a fail-safe
method and then maintain it okay I mean
so everybody who's dealt with any kind
of incident response friends know that
yeah we build it once in our lifetime
and then it remains there for that so
it's a piece in the showcase right to be
frank it is the toughest question now to
be frank
because maintaining an incident response
is like actually I will just map it to
the previous thing how you how you
ensure that your team is active I went
and interviewed couple of this Hawk and
list and tell them the hurry how to sit
for eight hours I'm doing the same
boring job how many of you feel it any
any so can list feel that one I have to
analyze of the multiple customers and
feeling the same work so what is that
that eager to ensure that when these
shocking lists are active what is that
you're giving to them okay not always
monetary is not the only thing how you
make them active what is that okay that
is one of the key in incentivize again
depends upon the organization depends
upon the role of a see so up to what
level he has if the she shoulder will
have that opportunity to take it for
himself I don't know what is a capable I
think that is where we need to
revolutionize this particular thing it's
if you see this one the data scientists
are the very highly paid if you see the
dot Gartner's Magic Quadrant or
something start of things they're
average salaries more than 250 thousand
dollars per year and the data scientist
do you know what is the information
security analyst
package it starts from sixty thousand
dollars okay so that's the difference so
that is where we need to check it out
what is the added value we're giving to
the business and actually the data
enlist is doing the same thing what you
are doing to be frank he is just giving
a business value to the right to the
customers if we are able to as
information security people if we are
able to show that business value then we
can make it okay coming to they're
coming back to the my things how you
make it activist it is a continuous
process there is nothing called a single
process you set and sleep over it you
need to continuously evaluate and then
the techni knows that when the
technology is changing every three
months know every quarter right every
quarter you have to do a change so is
your business is into that kind of
change of technology or your business is
not adapting that kind of change in the
technology that is the first thing we
need to keep in mind if you are into the
financial institution and if you are
majorly into the retail banking because
I mean formal institution telling if you
are not adopting their technology you
are not into the retail banking business
with the next five years straightforward
so you need to innovate yourself and
I'm seeing a trend where the information
security people are becoming an
innovation team because the analytic
capability of all of us is much more
than actually businesspeople okay so
that is where we need to try to
understand the business our analysts not
only please don't get into only
technology wherever industry you are
there try to understand the business
when you're looking into from is fraud
or a security perspective try to look
from a business value perspective and
give that to the management that's okay
so now I'm going to move to threat
intelligence everybody you know in the
room working with threat Intel nobody
slowly are you are you working with you
have some specific questions I'm going
to frame my question you can yeah you
can you can improve it so how do you
identify right you've got so many threat
Intel vendor saying hey I'll give you
some CT I am going to give you some
field how do you choose one vendor
number one how do you our number two is
yeah I mean super you can follow up with
this one how do you make sure that you
are actually gaining value from that
that particular vendor on a continuous
basis right there are there are
possibilities of somebody hitting a home
run in the first three months but based
on that are you going to be able to keep
keep that value quotient up for the next
year or not here's my question so yeah
quickly so first of all like your low or
threatened alleles I mean for all the
for any and every organization it's an
it's an expensive affair
that's one so before we so before we
start even evaluating the requirement
the need for the threat Intel I will
need to really understand that before we
before we kind of start evaluating and I
mean we need to do some of our homework
saying that do we need how do we have
the right skill set to kind off and show
that while we once we have those the the
feeds coming in are you kind of geared
up
show that we kind of make the meaning
full get the make the most out of it
that's one second is are we aware about
our business requirements as you rightly
said show me line is our one Nia so so
we need to kind of ensure that all the
business workflows all the business
process and all the business data which
are which are the most critical for the
business should be aware let's let's
phone number two and point number three
so once we started kind of working with
the thread into the partners of the
service part is there are as you're at
least eight I mean there are I mean
there are the whole list of ESPYs and in
that case so we need to map it with the
sole so there is no one thumb rule for
that I mean we need to kind of map it
based on our requirements that that's
one so - our requirement is we need to
ensure that once we have the feeds
coming in water will be the incent
intensity I mean will we be getting the
alerts on a on a real-time basis or will
be getting the alerts or the reports
maybe once in a day once in a week maybe
and also the support the support on the
service product in case of those crisis
situation maybe the 24/7 support to
their t3 engineers in the times of
crisis now this are some fundamental
pointers which before even we start
thinking about will it when show that we
we take care of all this all these
factors and then we end of start start
our discussion with the with the
partners yeah so you know we have a very
sophisticated platform called threat
Intel fusion platform P ILP right we
built it over the last three years right
here version three right now so a lot of
that is really how do we be getting
Intel from government from private
sources right and all other indicator of
compromise I was sees as they come in so
we take those and we normalize it right
because a lot of them are duplicates so
if you don't want to be you know okay
now creating orden over the same I was
easy so we actually you know pull that
we normalize it and then we have an
orchestration platform right the
orchestration platform can actually push
all those signatures
let's say you know to the wife as an
example right you see a sequel injection
attack coming in for a particular
application so we look at that we
normalize it and then say this has to be
eventually you know pushed into the the
runtime systems so it's really a
discipline you need to create a
discipline around how do you want to you
know ingest and be able to baseline what
is relevant to you
and there are quite a bit of IOC is come
you know that are relevant to endpoint
compromises so they're in again we are
constantly you know we're exporting the
you know mal verse in the labs
understanding you know what those are
your bound relationships as well so
we're using manifest in your environment
we share it with banks we do now you
have a Cu geo group yes we so we do it
in a very controlled way right so we
have certain customers big customers who
at banks right we share Intel with them
and vice versa right and we get Intel
from them so certainly they mean there's
value when you have you know a
crowdsourcing where you can get you know
I don't know you know a furor is if
somebody else is the same financial
vertical is seeing the same issue you
know it's better to share that share
them and be able to get more value out
of it so that's something that we have
benefiting a lot right but I think the
before I would say you know how a threat
Intel strategy understand how are you
going to consume it I understand how
you're gonna act on it right and then
you can say you know are you gonna put
your foot behind it exactly so the
efficacy of you know the threat Intel
will only you know I mean so we don't I
don't believe in auto I for security
right so we don't ask that question is
you know is that ROI being you know
because right there you know you're
flawed right because for us it only
takes one breach right so yeah so we do
evaluate different sources and you know
then we also understand you know if you
prevented certain things can you measure
against that right so we had and some of
it is is doing analytical exercise
looking back and every time with about
time we do that is when we come for
annual renewal right they say you know
hey we need to spend a half a million
dollars on this vendor
let's go up and see you know what you
got right talk to insurance right I mean
that's when you answer via threat
intelligence it's it all started for in
my experience is when the Saudi Aramco
incident happened where 65,000 servers
are wiped off overnight
just imagine what happens to us what we
do that is what the my CEO has asked me
a question what I have to do so I told
that I don't know what is actually
happening there to be frank wiping off
is ok but actually how it happened so
that's where so we categorized this into
the two one is it has to be contextual
based it has to be which industry you
are in which job graphical location you
are in maybe I'm from Middle East the
the threat intelligence that is
happening in India may not be valuable
to me that is happening in Middle East
and vice versa the same thing that we
need to be very careful depend upon
which where you are our organization or
their context is very important and the
third thing is your peer relationship
that means I'm a CEO of a bank do I have
a peer contacts with the other CE source
of the banks that is the best thing that
has saved me multiple times you need to
ensure that one you have a contact with
other peers well there the two things if
you want an official threat intelligence
from them
trust me the regulator's the the
diplomacy and all those things never
allow you to get what you want and there
is another relationship depends upon how
you want a relationship whether they
will be able to remember it maybe a
whatsapp relationship you get it so be
practical to be frank this is my
practical experience and telling it how
both kind of relationship one is to show
to the regulators that we have a threat
intelligence one to practically come out
from your situation okay I'm conducting
these people many people you have the
have a relationship with all the subject
matter expert across the globe
whether you deal with them or not deal
with them that helps you when real
incident happens that is what the threat
intelligence we are talking about
thanks to the workshop group that will
help us so this is the second or third
one written by James and the fourth one
is very simple
everybody can implement their own
institution is reward the people who
report maximum phishing males in your
organization if you see the 90% of the
attacks that happen in your organization
or any of the attack you've seen in the
globally started with the phishing
attempt okay try to try to reward your
employees whoever actually report
phishing to that one and collect those
IPS and that will give a real threat
intelligence for you guys use it this
time for a couple of questions any
questions for our panelists can we get
the mic Anoop here the moderator
actually asked this question right I
mean in the cyber analytics horizonal
yeah what are the different verticals it
it it is going to touch in this in the
cyber arena we talked about threat
intelligence we talked about shock is
there any other verticals where
analytics can play role in cyber so good
question man so you know one of the
things we are doing is we are not
constraining the in fact that Intel used
to be very confidential you know sent to
only ten people company right we said
why I mean we want everybody to
understand what the threats are so they
open it up right so he said we have a
mailing list anybody who wants a sign
for threat Intel sign up right I mean we
have DLP if someone's trying to forward
those and stuff like that right so so we
can we've since then right we have seen
other areas in the company especially
and the business side the you know the
application owners who run their apps
they need to understand you know what
this how the thirteen rule can be
monetized for them so we are collecting
so going back to you know the
right so if you look at lanes we have
this all clean which is in our feet in
the ground in a completely looking at
data you know every day we also have the
the application side if you're looking
at collecting data for SS DLC you know
which applications are seeing the same a
little bitty one over again right well
so log log is another Lane so we do
that's a very good point so logging is
something that we have to do at every
layer Network layer a player at the you
know middleware layer right so that that
is very very helpful ultimately it's
about correlation and be able to connect
the dots so you know the more you can
connect the dots and understand you know
is this an attack happening specific an
application or is it something is
happening horizontal right it's not
liking every single operating system
network so yes the app sec area itself
can benefit a lot when you start mining
data and be able to provide more insight
as to you know what kind of attacks
we're seeing on those apps I can take
offline too yeah hi this is Thomas here
I'm a pen tester so I have a quick
question on what he said about 65,000
servers getting wiped out and about
compliance and patching so my question
is very simple I mean for example there
is a vulnerability that comes out for
example meltdown or Spectre or a flash
vulnerability and maybe Google or
Microsoft which other vendor is it takes
time to get out a patch out out of this
so that is a time when when an attacker
would definitely know you know what what
has to be hacked or where where the
attack is performed so if that time a
particular thing is compromised or a
network architecture is compromised how
is it that you know you deal into it I
mean it's a question that because that
is where the ideas or the IPS or the
other things would not have the
signature or the pattern that is learn
is in the patch out before the
all right so it might be happen for one
particular technology right so it's we
all think about the layered defense that
we're talking about we are talking of
let's assume that whatever you're the
vulnerability you're talking about it
impacted the Intel chips in the Windows
environment let's say but you have the
layered technology controls that you
implement it never depend on a single
technology and then always that's where
I was talking about a principle called
failsafe if really that kind of thing
happened can I switch off all these
things and put only my critical services
we're buying core services are running
that is where we need to worry about
it's because we can't keep 100% and
behind always the hackers or the other
part of the wall is much collaborative
than us and they always work um we need
to have a layer different strategy with
us want to say I mean if you're talking
about zero day right zero you know then
you pretty much host right I mean you
know we don't know what zero day is
right because but what we can do is if
you see this is my detection technology
has come into picture right the data a
collecting if I see a pattern that
doesn't happen before then I can start
investigating right understand what is
the reason what is the root cause for
this kind of pattern let me lead into
the actual way the system would
compromise right so that's where you
know the a players come into play right
well how fast can you actually find out
that this particular anomalies happened
and it has to be investigated and that
leads to the zero day compromise or
other ways so detection technology has a
big role to play but you also had to
have the operational discipline to look
at data very cool you know understand
you know is this something a baseline
behavior or something outlier anomaly
all right last question okay we give you
a chance okay that one offline sorry
talking about pretty much the the
typical security challenges within an
organization I think you've gotten a
very interesting topic that is the
outlier aspect I mean if you ask me
sincerely
they are the outliers that many
organizations should be really worried
about and not the script kiddies or
probably a pen testing exercise or
probably a meta spoiled you know module
that's been run and trying to reach some
data so what would be the strategy when
you're actually trying to really solve
this problem of one person of the elite
hackers so how does your organization's
thought processes I'm not actually
looking for what your strategy is but
more the thought processes okay so do
you want to ask so anyone who can start
right so yeah without getting too much
data right so one thing we do is we have
the Red Team Blue Team concept right in
the company and the red team so we do
employ when we have you know when we
have a new model we let the red team
attack right we understand you know are
we seeing other ways that this can be
compromised and that provides signals to
say hey these are the base that and I'll
give you an example well if you already
know the exploit right it's all
signature based right so I think the
question is more about if you are going
to identify outliers right how are you
going to do that without having equal
data right so you have you don't have
current knowledge right I think the
answer is that you study your past and
builder based language does that and
then identify outliers so that that
might be a false positive learn from
that feed-forward learn from their
feed-forward eventually you build a
model which have which has strong enough
classifiers which be able to you know
give you fairly accurate so the reason
how we did are in my experience is the
correlation of the this one is
did the correlation based upon the
identity-based we know exactly each user
what kind of things they will be able to
communicate what they are trying to do
on a daily pattern okay and if there is
any abnormal thing happening but using
that particular user okay that is an
outlier for us I will be knowing I mean
let's assume that Harry is accessing a
swift server daily between 10:00 to
12:00 and suddenly he is accessing in
some other time okay this is an outlier
and hary accessing as an admin so
definitely identity based because every
event we map it to the identities and
from there we are trying to do the
outliers of course still when even if
you try to do up to that level what
you're talking from a zero-day
perspective okay none of these things
will give it only the traffic will move
that is the only outlier as of now I am
coming to if there is any solution so
also please do let me know parking that
already I okay you are right you are
absolutely right when I try to do that
one I will ensure that one what is the
status of my organization based upon the
known vulnerabilities at that point of
time I'm agree with that particular time
if somebody is targeting me from past
ten years and wanted to ignite after
five years I can't help I totally agreed
I I can do from the based upon the
expertise what the organization has are
only from the external people I do the
current state assessment from that time
only I will be able to do it but from
that time if there is a zero day which
is not known I've suddenly wanted to
target me then I will look into my
business I might be that so much
concentrated somebody want to invest ten
years on me
that is the question mark I will be
having on my own do we try all right
thank you so much thank you so much for
being here thanks thank you
thank you thank you sir thank you so
much
[Applause]