we did jointly with several other
collaborators looking at about twenty
seven million malware samples collected
over the last half decade and sharing
some of the evolution and insights that
we got from those from that analysis and
so one of the first thing I would start
talking about is why we why we leaving
what about doing this so you'll notice
you'll see that malware analysis at the
forefront a lot of fights against
internet threats and that dynamic
malware analysis is used both by the
operational and academic security
communities and in particular a lot of
times we take the network information
derived from the ceramic analysis and we
use this for a threat detection instant
response or for other indicators of
compromised and so this raises an
interesting question which is how
effective is this Network signal and you
know what are the ways that we can
actually reliably use this and so give
you a hint into some of our findings
everything is fine it's not all burning
down but there are some cautionary tales
to be that we've learned from the
insights that we got here which I'll get
to later in this talk well but the first
thing I want to highlight is some of the
data sets that we used I'm going to call
attention to a few of these real quickly
the rest were explained in more detail
in our paper but we we looked at roughly
27 million malware samples collected
from multiple different feeds over about
a five year period and in this data set
there were about seven million unique
effective second-level domains that we
collected that we saw from the second
our analysis
additionally we had another large
passive DNS data set collected from a
major US ISP and in there we had about
2.9 million effective second-level
domains that we saw that were associated
with malware so one of the challenges
with dealing with this much data is
actually filtering out a lot of the
noise so one of the things that we spent
a considerable amount of time on in this
work is actually figuring out how to
clean up these data sets in a reliable
way so one of the things that we did was
there are a lot of invalid domains that
we see in our malware data set and so we
wanted to remove an X domain or
non-existent domains that we saw being
queried by malware and dynamic analysis
environments
and the reason why we did this is we
wanted to reduce the effects of domain
generation algorithms and this this was
pretty successful we were able to reduce
that 6.8 million domains down to about
1.3 1 million domains or effective
second-level domains after we removed in
X domains and the other thing we wanted
to do is yes we were looking at malware
resolutions but there's often a lot of
benign traffic that's reached out to buy
malware it's we want to remove popular
domains and Alexa as well as removing
content delivery domains the reason we
remove CDN domains is CD ends can be
used for both good and bad behavior but
distinguishing between the two can be
challenging so we aired on the side of
caution and decided to remove the CDN
domain so that the things we had left
would be more associated with malware
and abusive behavior and then the last
thing was things we couldn't get out of
eat with these whitelist we manually
remove this from a hand curated list
this gave us another slight reduction
down to about 1.2 million eat oldies the
next thing we wanted to do was so spam
is another kind of category of malware
that we sample that we saw and we wanted
to kind of filter out these types of
samples there's a lot of work that's a
lot of great work done on spam and we
didn't want the our results to be
tainted by behavior that was more spam
related than
associate with other types of malware
behavior in our data set so we removed
resolutions from binaries with lots of
MX lookups and we removed also
resolutions from things that from
domains that had male related keywords
we're going to like male bot example
calm or SMTP example comm and this gave
us another nice reduction down to about
three hundred and twenty nine thousand
effective second-level domains after
that and the last thing that we filtered
out is something that is an interesting
artifact of the underlying host
operating system that the Mauer is
actually running on and these are
reverses own delegations so these are
often things that aren't being
explicitly queried by the malware but
are just an artifact of the underlying
environment they're running on and we
wanted to remove these which gave us
another slight reduction down to about
three hundred twenty seven thousand so
ultimately we were able to go from about
seven million unique effective
second-level domains being queried by
malware to about a candidate set of
about three hundred twenty seven
thousand that were most likely very
strongly Corley
with our behavior and so when we looked
at the the evolution of our dataset over
time after doing all the filtering
you'll notice that we see a consistent
growth in the number of samples number
of domains queried and number of IP
addresses that we see and you'll notice
there's a drop in 2014
unfortunately we didn't solve security
that year we just kind of had a
collection issue with our infrastructure
and so when we actually take a look at
this from the perspective of what types
of malware we saw we broke this into a
classification between traditional
malware and potentially unwanted
programs and when we look at the growth
between these two different types of now
or what we see is that by 2015 puppet
actually overtake in traditional malware
in terms of the number of raw samples
that we saw and this actually confirms
and echoes previous work by copy us at
all that shows the same trend but on a
much smaller data set so it was nice
being able to confirm these existing
results with a much larger data set and
a much more diverse set of malware an
additionally other work by Thomas Adel
has showed that Google Safe Browsing
generates roughly three times as many
detections for puppets from malware so
again this is a nice example where we
were able to confirm existing results on
a large data set which is always great
and so another thing we looked at with
really - this this kind of
classification of pop versus malware is
you know are there differences in the
behavior that we saw and yes there were
so one of the things that we saw was
that there were actually more malware
families but the pup families that we
did see tended to have more samples per
family and this was due to greater kind
of binary polymorphism that we saw in
these pup families likely due to evasion
of Av
signatures and the like but we saw a
different kind of behavior with the
traditional malware samples which was
even though they had were sampled we saw
that they tend to have query more
effective second-level domains per
sample indicating a greater what we call
a domain polymorphism and I'll talk more
about that in just a second so what do I
mean by this idea of domain polymorphism
so we saw that most malware samples
all fewer than 10 unique effective
second-level domains this was after
doing all of our filtering and we saw
that most of those each of these were
only created by a single unique malware
sample so what we're seeing here is that
these each of these aren't being reused
across samples we're seeing new
effective second-level domains being
used in different samples so even if a
family had a lot of samples you weren't
likely to see the same domain reused
across this and we even further we saw
that this evasion because of this role
this evasion didn't appear to happen on
the register domain or it appeared to
happen on the register may not be fully
qualified domain name so there weren't a
lot of child labels under these
effective second-level domains so
ultimately what we kind of we're able to
take away from this is that if you're if
you're taking the domains that you're
receiving from these malware feed
through dynamic analysis blacklisting
these domains may do little to prevent
future communication for the new samples
so if you have a sample today that's
clearing a specific domain and you put
that in a blacklist and a new sample
comes out tomorrow it's likely that that
domain won't be effective at preventing
the computer communication and this is
one of the pitfalls for using the
network signal coming from dynamic
analysis for blacklists or other sort of
network preventive measures and another
thing that we looked at was how often do
Mallesons malware query dynamic dns
providers and this shows the top 100
most popular Dyne dns providers that we
saw queried by other samples that we had
in our data set and what we saw is that
unlike the previous case would we saw
the main polymorphism
evasion here happens on the child label
so attackers don't register the
effective second-level domain user
that's owned by the dined DNS provider
so they'll register a label underneath
that domain and that's where the evasion
will happen but this also means that you
can't block that effective second-level
domain because you might block
legitimate behavior as well as benign
behavior so that's that's a challenge
that we have here but one of the
interesting things that we saw that
almost 32 percent of all the samples
that we looked at in our study made
queries to dine DNS providers so they're
heavily used for abuse by malware
authors so if you're looking for abuse
19s is a good place to look especially
if you see you know queries coming from
now
where another thing we looked at was
malware currying vga domains and
nowadays if you call in the filtering
stuff we mentioned we removed in X
domains because of this DJ effect we
wanted to see how many DJ domains we
actually saw in our data set before
filtering and after filtering and so to
do this one of the things that we
noticed was that about 12 and a half
million of them our samples contained at
least in an X domain so if we if we
didn't do the filter we lost the ability
to look for DGA domains and those but
after we after adding some of these back
in we used the DGA archive to look at
approximately 50 million known DGA
domains and what we saw was that before
filtering we saw that about 3 million of
the almost 7 million effective
second-level domains queried by malware
were in VGA archives so almost half of
the domains in our data set were from
DJ's and even after filtering we noticed
that almost 17 percent of the remaining
327,000 domains were in BGA archive as
well so we noticed this trend that DJ's
are widely very very very widely used
across a lot of the malware in our
sample and that's a trend that seems to
be growing and this also has
repercussions on the effectiveness of
blacklisting results from VGA s and the
last kind of thing we're going to look
at is malware clearing spam domains
mention that this is the class that we
filter out because they look different
I'm just going to highlight this last
column here that shows that on average
we saw these spam domains querying or
spam samples creating a lot more domains
that we saw after our filtering these
were querying hundreds or even thousands
of domains which was quite different
behavior than we saw for things that
we're creating domains after doing our
filtering and this is kind of an
interesting reason why we did that but
also the most popular spam related
sample that we saw was over a decade old
which is kind of an interesting result
in and of itself because this suggests
that we're not doing a very good job or
these things are still proliferating on
the internet despite knowing about them
and having you know safeguards to
protect against them so this plot right
here is one of the more interesting
plots and we spent a long time looking
at this trying to make sense of you know
why why some of the things we saw here
with
case so what we're looking here is the
network signal and where we saw it first
so did we see the network signal in from
a malware feed from a public blacklist
or on the network itself and so ideally
what we'd want to see here is that from
zero to the right hand side where were
there positive numbers we want to see a
lot more stuff there this would indicate
that we were seeing things within our
feeds first and then they were showing
up either in public blacklist or in
Pasadena slist rather we saw this
artifact here on the Left which this is
the case where we saw things weeks or
even months on the network before we
actually receive the sample and saw it
from dynamic malware analysis this is
this is problematic because this means
that there's this long window where if
you're relying on the malware before you
take preventive measures you have a long
period of vulnerability here and you're
taking a very reactive measure and this
could be this could be an artifact of
the fact that as we saw malware is using
dynein as providers which they're
probably long-lived but there were there
are a very few number of those effective
second-level domains so that shouldn't
have a huge effect here or this could be
a long set up phase or one other
possibility was this could be the case
where malware authors are actually using
domains that have maybe previously
expired and so you know there this is an
actual case of abuse happening way far
in the past this is a case where the
domain was used for something else and
now it was used for illegitimate
purposes after the expiration so we
tried to account for that by taking our
a set of expired domains and looking to
see whether those domains after we we
filtered and took the little blasting
date after the expiration whether that
change this distribution of Millette so
in figure C down here we see that the
left didn't really change which was
unfortunate that we were hoping that
this would kind of cut that down and
we'd have a better explanation of why
this is happening what we did see was
that it did have an effect it did push
some domains to the right which meant
that we saw the the domain show up in a
malware feed before we saw the new
evidence of abuse happen so that did
that did get rid of some of that that
left hand tail but still existed it was
much larger than we were hoping to see
and then the next thing we looked at was
that you'll notice the left hand tail
and public blacklist this seems to
indicate that you know in a lot of cases
things aren't showing up on public
glasses before they show up in feeds we
do see that happen sometimes but what we
see is much more prevalent is that they
show up and now our feed after they show
up in the pvl or they so we see that
received at the reverse what we want to
see there and this is actually while
this might seem odd this is actually
consistent with previous work the people
would have shown that the domain seen in
public blacklists I've shown up in DNS
on average 384 days before they showed
up in the PBL we're seeing a similar
thing here with with the Mauer feeds and
additionally reputation systems have
also been another example where this
type of behavior has been seen earlier
than with public blacklist and so the
last thing I'm going to look at is this
kind of lifetime of domain so these show
joint distributions of the lifetime and
resolution frequency observed in DNS for
pop Mauer and unclassified domains and
what you'll notice is that malware and
the unknown class look very similar and
they're kind of three pockets here
there's the bottom left top right and
bottom right and these indicate that we
see a lot of malware domains that are
active for a short period of time and
looked up fairly regularly or looked up
for a long period of time fairly
frequently and then the bottom right
hand corner shows that we see some that
are looked up very infrequently over a
long period of time what's particularly
interesting here is how much different
that looks in the pup class here which
seems to be looked up fairly frequently
for a fairly strong period of time and
you'll notice it's bounded between 1000
and 1000 and this makes sense given the
fact that we saw this rise of pup later
in our data set over time so this this
seems to confirm that result and what we
really see here is that all three of
these plots seem to suggest that a lot
of a lot of samples actually seem to
remain active on the internet for
extended period of time
so we need better work done to remediate
these threats and get them off the
network and so some key takeaways from
this work one is that there's a lot of
noise and malware data sets
and filtering it out can be extremely
challenging so we provide kind of a
blueprint that other people could use to
try to filter out these data sets to get
to the more useful information we also
saw that pop is on the rise and exhibit
different behavior than traditional
malware and then we saw that relying on
malware feeds for detection results and
long windows of vulnerability and
potentially limited vectors in since
this is because of things like domain
polymorphism in this lag between seeing
the actual abuse on the network and
actually seeing waiting for the buyer to
show up in an hour feed so there's this
long reactor delay and then the signal
we're getting doesn't necessarily
generalize to new samples and then
lastly one of the benefits of this study
was that we were able to provide
independent verification of previous
results on a large independent data sets
that we had gathered and so this kind of
serves to further verify those results
and with that i'll i guess open up the
questions
[Applause]
we have time for one or two questions
I'll just ask a naive question I'm still
unsure of the difference between malware
and pups can you clarify that sure yeah
so the essentially unwanted program is
might in court
account for things like adware or
spyware or things that don't necessarily
might have a different monetization
technique than traditional malware so
they're not doing the same types of
things but so you know you people might
have you know spyware might not might be
something that somebody bought and it's
not something that's you know being used
by an attacker it might be something
that like you know your mom put on your
your yeah right I have a question on the
on the delay between between observing
the the network network activity and
actually observing the malware samples
so you've made some effort to to exclude
other possibilities yes what I mean what
level of certainty do you have that so
that this is actually as well observing
this delay because we're was slow in
detecting the malware versus some other
possibility also the the network data
sets that we're using were from a close
recursive and an ISP so the the you know
getting other network signal there by
random chances is unusual it would be
really not likely that would be the case
so I mean the fact that we're seeing it
that much earlier indicates that where
something is querying it and if it's not
you know previous infrastructure that
was expired and then something else
happened it suggested it's likely of
being abused by the same malware office
because there was no chain and ownership
between when the abuse was happening and
when we're seeing the first resolutions
so that that's a fairly strong indicator
that it's that it's abuse happening why
it takes us so long to get to them our
feeds it is I mean there are lots of
samples out there so you know having one
of those come in and make it to a feed
it kind of makes sense that that would
take a while all right thank you okay
let's thank the squeaker again
you